Welcome to Dr. David Hawkins Sedona 2002
series, The Way to God.
Lecture 6, Realizing the Root of
Consciousness:
Meditative and Contemplative Techniques.
Originally presented in June of 2002 at
the Sedona Creative Life Center.
I I was never very happy about this
physicality. As I was saying, it's
suddenly at age three out of out of
oblivion
and I'm a great enthusiast of oblivion.
Out of oblivion, there was the shock of
this v thisness. Oh my god, it was
awful.
And uh so we're all set to go.
>> All right. Uh out of happy oblivion,
there was suddenly thisness.
Uh and thisness has been like a plague
ever since.
To get beyond thisness,
this uh physicality which people um
strangely become enamored of. I don't
know. They seem like they suffer from
some kind of insanity that they enjoy
this thing. But
with a great deal of endeavor, you can
get it to be an enjoyable mechanism.
And um so it's a big rag doll that I've
been putting up with all these years.
This week I was 75. So for 72 years I've
putting up with this thing, which has
certainly earned me the karma of getting
rid of it someday.
uh the good karma of getting rid of it
someday. Um so that's somewhat different
than a lot of people look at the whole
situation.
Uh but apparently that came out of some
lifetimes of as a hinyana Buddhist I was
a very devout Buddhist monk and um the
ultimate reality was voidness and
consequently when I went out of body it
went into void and don't remember
anything
don't remember nothing till you come
back in the next lifetime and uh but as
you reach a certain level of awareness
you remember the previous lifetimes and
uh Uh they they all string together like
frankly like it's like this lifetime.
It's it's it's all the same lifetime.
Uh but it was we I was just looking at a
couple of them yesterday cuz something
came up about them. And you saw almost
the flip-flop nature, one lifetime being
this and creating all kinds of negative
bad karma, then the next lifetime
flopping over to undo all that. I said,
"Whoa, that was really very interesting
how they're tied together.
Well, today we're talking about um
let's see what are we talking about
today. Today's lecture is um oh
meditation. Yes.
Today's meditation.
But first we sort of start out by um
you know um validating the reality in
which we are here this morning
in which everything is occurring of its
own.
You realize that nothing is causing
anything else.
That was the first lecture
to transcend the whole illusion of
causality
because that is the whole structure of
the ego.
It sees everything is causing everything
else and becomes entrapped by that.
All the ego mechanisms are laid somehow
on causality.
Something out there is causing me to
feel this way.
um we see oursel as the victims of some
mysterious force called cause
instead of seeing ourself as the context
in which we witness all that. So we
start out the lectures by just recalling
that nothing is causing anything else.
Everything is occurring spontaneously
as the fulfillment of the expression of
its own essence from moment to moment.
So
if we're stuck in the word cause then
we'll move up to cause and then we'll
move beyond cause. If we are going to
stick with the word cause then we see
that there's only one cause for
everything
and that cause is the cause of every
instant.
The cause of the hand being where it is
is the total action of the entire
universe since the beginning of time
manifesting itself via the will of God
by divine ordinance as creation.
And out of creation arises the essence.
And the essence out of the energy of
creation then expresses itself as the
fulfillment of its essence.
The cause of this instant is exactly the
same as the cause of this instant is
exactly the same as the cause of this
instant. And that is the totality of the
entire universe since the beginning of
all of time.
So that every instant is the fulfillment
of the creative potential potential of
God manifesting as the essence of th
that which this is fulfills the
potentiality of its essence which in the
case of a hand is to move forward
seemingly in space. So if we jump the
presumption that there's something
causing it to do that
then we see that with absolute freedom
the universe is merely
like a flower being what it is. You see
the flower
this instant doesn't cause the flower to
grow. This instant it doesn't cause the
flower. flower is unfolding its infinite
potentiality of being a flower has the
fulfillment of its divine design.
Nothing is causing it to do that. The
sun doesn't cause it to do that. The
rain doesn't cause it to do that. The
seed doesn't cause it to do that.
Putting it in your window in a pot
doesn't cause the flower to do that. The
flower is doing it of its own.
It's fulfilling
the destiny, the potential destiny of
its own essence.
Consequently, at every second at which
it is doing that, it is absolutely
perfect. At this moment, it's perfect.
At this moment, it's perfect because
perfection is that it should do this.
And because it is doing that at every
moment, it is the perfect fulfillment of
the will of God.
Therefore, the entire universe stands in
absolute perfection from instant to
instant.
Right.
Thank you, God, for saying that. I mean,
I never could have said that.
That was cool, man.
But that is the way it is.
When you first see that, it lays you
out.
When you first walk into that and it
reveals itself.
If you can function for a few years, you
can't function for some years actually,
some years before one could function
again
because um all is happening of its own.
Well, the freedom that arises from that
realization,
how to how to how to arrive at that
realization
is what we're talking about today. We're
talking about meditation, one of the
great timehonored traditions
and ways to the awareness of the
presence of God.
Now
meditation itself is an enormous
subject.
I'm sure we could fill this whole book
with all the books written on meditation
throughout the centuries.
the great gurus, the great teachers of
meditation, the meditation centers,
the Buddhist traditions, um yoga, the
Indian Aryan traditions
and in the far east of course there's
enormous um
amount of literature and training.
Meditation need not be in the in the
context of any particular religion or
spiritual teaching.
Medit uh friends of ours in Korea, Dr.
Moon has a meditation center. And you
ask her, is it Christian? No. Is it
Buddhist? No. Is it Hindu? No. What is
it? It's a meditation center. She says,
you get it. Oh,
you just go there and meditate. Oh, wow.
In other words, the process itself
then unfolds
through the inner layers of the ego. You
transcend the ego.
All right. So let's talk a little bit
about the various techniques.
Um
many of which of course are well
established in the literature
have uh specific training programs.
Many become very um detailed in posture,
diet, breathing.
Many are accompanied by complicated
breathing mechanisms.
There's all kinds of incredible
meditative techniques.
We're not going to talk about them today
because the world's literature is full
of instructions,
instruction centers, traditions,
postures, breathing exercises,
pranayyana.
We'll talk more about the essence of the
meditative process itself, which is
common to all of them.
And because most of the people here, you
see, it's very neat to be able to shave
your head, leave the world, join a Zen
monastery,
and sit zen
for 10 or 20 years. I love it.
It pulls pulls me. I have to resist it
all the time. It's a natural state. The
natural state. And anything else in a
way is sort of a drag.
and I was the psychiatric consultant to
the Zen uh
monastery in New York. It was up in the
little mountains right near New York
City. I forget where it is. Anyway,
and uh I used to go to the Frisen
Institute in New York City.
Um so meditation itself even you know as
a lifestyle is extremely attractive.
The average person here today is not
able to do that. And
consequently, how can we obtain the
benefits of meditation
uh without um ren without going through
formal renunciation?
And we'll talk a little bit today about
renunciation. Don't let me forget to
talk about renunciation.
Um all right. So what meditative
awareness can we have
walking about and functioning within the
ordinary world?
And so we'll talk about generally two
styles of meditation
and we'll talk about um ways to
transcend the mind.
Uh so it'll be a busy morning. Yes. Come
think of it
now. I started to think again myself. I
say, "Whoa, you got to go through all
that, right?" Yes,
we got all that stuff there. Well,
let's start with a generality that um
there is content
and there is context.
Context, you know, totally changes
content.
And a great deal of
error arises in not being aware of the
relationship of content and context.
What we're looking for in meditation is
how to transcend content and realize
that the self that which we are is the
context.
And how can we do that?
There's two ways. one I call macular
focus which is central focus intense
fixity on the content of aware of the
ego on the content of what you're
looking at and doing
and the other is what I would call
peripheral peripheral vision if we
compare it to vision the macula is that
uh phobia in the back of the retina that
focuses very specifically on details
if you Look at the a fly and then you
focus on the eye of the fly. Then you
are being very specific and focusing on
a very very small concentrated area.
That's sort of macular vision.
Then we have peripheral vision
because although I can see the content
of what is in front of my eyes,
there is a greater generality.
A person who's interested in spiritual
evolution learns
to focus the sense of self,
the sense of awareness,
um the alertness
um progressively more and more to the
peripheral vision.
One becomes quite peripheral
in experiencing the world from moment to
moment.
One is aware of the general context.
Um now the general context out of which
the world seems to arise or appear
uh is silent and invisible.
So the ultimate context then is the
silent invisibility almost the space and
silence out of which experience
which allows experience to be possible.
If it is not for the background of
silence you cannot hear these words.
If it is not for the emptiness and
infinite, you might say no thingness of
space, you would not be able to observe
uh physicality. You couldn't see
buildings or
persons
to be at aware at all times
of the infinite space, the infinite
potentiality
out of which this moment seems to be
arising
is somewhat aligned with the awareness
that all is happening of its own. that
everything is spontaneously
occurring
without any intervention
without any causality.
It's as though there is an infinite
concert in which everything is happening
spontaneously of its own and one is the
witness of what appears to be happening.
This can be done formally in seated
meditation and we'll get to that.
We're trying to talk about how to reach
a higher state of awareness
even though one is functioning in the
world. You begin you begin to witness
that everything is happening of its own
and that there is no nothing causing it
to be that way.
So we be as you transcend cause you you
you then become aware that everything is
happening
spontaneously.
If we sit down to meditate let's say we
sit down to meditate
the problem is almost always the
thinkingness of the mind.
So we'll talk now more about the
meditative process in a formal sense.
You know, Ramana Maharshi always
recommended um that he he always said
you don't have to join a monastery to
become enlightened. You that the
householder can go about his business
and all he has to do is keep in mind in
the back of his mind at all times who am
I?
So
I never agreed with who am I.
The experiential
awareness here is more what am I?
Seemed to me who am I which was not
notoriously successful either as a
mantra.
uh that whom am I focuses
you to look for another illusion,
another
definition, another pronoun of self.
That which is experienced as
the identity with the personal is
transcended is a wheness not a
whesseness.
The wetness has the peculiarity of sense
of self with the capital S but that self
is the allness of everythingness and
it's really beyond whesseness.
Um
some people who had been there to
his ashram even after he died you know
uh had said that there was not a great
deal of success with that method and I
also thought it's due to the whess
rather than the whatness. We'll explain
the wetness today to try and clarify
what I just said. Let's see. Can we turn
on this mystery machine here?
Ah h
all right. So as you either either
you're in seated meditation
or as you're walking about in the world
because as you progress in spiritual
work the two are not different. The two
become the same.
um because all of life because of the
way you recontextualize your life
becomes a meditation.
So on its highest level then a
meditation is merely the manner in which
you contextualize your experience of
aliveness.
If you contextualize
every instant of your existence as a
dedicated dedication to the realization
of God, all of your your entire life
becomes a meditation. So we cannot
separate out meditation as this and the
you is that and this and that.
Meditation then is a way of
contextualizing your life.
Let's say from a greater context. from a
greater context.
What is witnessed then
the body walking around on the stage
which is a peculiarity actually
is merely the content of a field. So
let's look at the field. Let's look at
the field itself. It seems to be warped,
doesn't it?
Can't we pull this open farther? Let's
see.
I don't know how you work this machine.
Anybody know how to rip? I don't know.
How do you make it not do that? Well,
it's crooked. So, there's nothing we can
do about it.
It's crooked. Somebody will know how to
fix that.
And we won't worry about it till
somebody does.
All right. So the progressive fields of
realization
whether you're walking about in a
walking meditation throughout life
or whether you're seated and
cross-legged
doing very specific breathing
picturing the energy flowing up your
spine to the crown chakra and up to the
higher levels
as light
now or whether you're walking around in
the world
the first thing that you experience is
form
and a person sits down and they say well
I can't seem to get it any place with
meditation
because the minute I sit down the mind
the thoughts are racing around the
thoughts the distractions of the world
and so the average person the average
person's life then is focused on thought
form.
The person bewills the fact that no
matter what they do, their mind seems to
be focused on
a passing panorama of endless thoughts
and feelings and form.
So that is the first thing we notice.
Now because this form is endless the
content of thinkingness is endless.
It goes on spontaneously.
The first thing to notice about it is
it's got nothing to do with you because
you can tell it to stop and it won't.
Well, if you were if that's what you
were and you told it to stop, it would
instantly stop.
So you tell your mind stop.
goes right on thinking.
It seems to be quite unruly.
Those are those are the famous ox
hurting pictures. You know, the first
picture shows the ox, the wild ox.
So that's the wild untamed mind. And um
the naive person thinks well I have to
um
deal with that.
No happily you don't have to deal with
the content of mind
because the only thing you have to
notice about it is that what it's doing
it's doing spontaneously.
It's not the content of mind that's
interesting at all. What is of interest
is the process of mind. It's going on of
its own. Had nothing to do with you.
Couldn't care less about you.
You'll say very nasty things about you.
You know what the mind does?
You're guilty. You're weak. You're
you're wasting your money. You're creep.
You can't trust the mind at all. It's
not even your It's not even your friend.
It's not even a friend. I mean, it
doesn't It just goes on and willy-nilly
says all kinds of When it runs out of
thoughts, it'll say
you picture some erotic scene from some
movie when you were a teenager.
It'll think of something horrible about
the future.
Oh my.
When the mind gets threatened with no
thoughts, it really gets wild. It'll
just do anything crazy.
Think of stabbing yourself or something,
you know. It'll just do anything bizarre
to keep going. Well,
so when you look at the mind, then don't
be don't be bothered with it. It's an
endless fantasmagoria.
I like that word, fantasmagoria.
It just proliferates endless BS. You
know what it's doing.
Occasionally, occasionally under very
favorable circumstances with great focus
and effort, you can get it to stop all
that and be logically form a logical
sequence for a short period of time.
and do what's called thinking.
Most of the time it's thoughting. It's
not thinking. It's thoughting and
imaging. All right. So thinking it does
really quite rarely. Should I turn left
at the next corner? It's through
thinking. Now it's not going to think
for another 20 minutes probably. Where
should I park? That's the next time it
thinks. What was it doing during that 20
minutes? It was
Feed fishies in a nitty bitty boo.
That's that's the one my mind used to
like. Feed the fishies in a nitty bitty
boo.
All right. So form then the content is
not of any interest. Now many people
spend endless spiritual lifetimes trying
to change form.
You realize how many spiritual programs
have to do with form. Don't think this,
think that. Recontextualize it this way.
Don't think of its opposite. You know,
prefix it with if but yes or no.
Trying to change form is not going to
work
because the ego, the mind is
uh like the heartbeat destined to do
what it does.
Why should the mind stop thinking then
when that's what it's supposed to do?
All right. So, what does one realize out
of this?
If you watch the content of mind going
by willy-nilly like a mad cap insane
asylum, you realize that you are not the
mind. If you were the mind and you told
it to stop, it could stop.
And we notice then the first most
important thing that's going to take us
out of it is that it's impersonal.
The most stunning thing to learn about
witnessing the content of your mind is
that it's impersonal.
Like the heartbeat, like breathing,
like your toenails growing, it's
impersonal. Doesn't ask you about it.
Your toenails don't say, "Should I grow
this month?
It's a sort of a physiologic spontaneous
activity thinking this. So don't be
disturbed about it because
uh it's doing what it's supposed to do.
You can't really be worried about the
content about it because no matter what
trick you try with the content, it's
smarter than you will and it would trick
you in some other way. You say don't
think about this good doesn't he thinks
about that instead.
All right. So, the first thing you
notice is that it's endless form and
it's unstoppable.
Trying to silence your mind is idiotic.
And millions of people do that all the
time. Trying to go to sleep at night and
they're trying to stop their mind from
thinking. Uh
what you notice is that it's impersonal.
It does what it's doing of its own. H
wow. So you stop identifying with the
content of thought is me. It's not me.
I can put you under hypnosis, program
your mind. You wake up, you think all
that. You think I thought that. You
didn't think that, idiot. I thought it.
All right. So the first thing we can
notice, how do you know what the mind is
thinking?
How do you know? How do you know what
what is this? How do you know what's on
on that channel? You know it because
it's registering. It's registering.
Ah, so we're out of the content of mind
and now and well they say if I'm not the
program
then maybe I'm the BCR. Well, you're
getting closer.
We're aware of what's going on in mind
because it's registering somewhere. It's
registering somewhere in consciousness.
and it's being recognized.
One of the functions of
you see this mind is doing what it's
doing but that's not what's bothering
you. What's bothering you is that you're
registering it. You're aware of it.
You're recognizing it. And who is doing
that?
The watcher is doing that. The
experiencer is experiencing that the
mind is doing all that.
How do you know that the experiencer is
experiencing? Because there's a watcher
experiencing it. And below that there is
awareness.
So the identifications of who I am first
as we sit in meditation or as we go
about the day
is not the content of thought. It's not
the content of feeling or thought or
imaginations or memories.
It has to do with closer with some
impersonal function called registering.
Even the recognition
of if you recognize a monkey as a
monkey, that's not a decision that some
personal you made. That happens of its
own. So that's trained. That's trained.
So these things are trained. They're
impersonal.
Experiencing and watching is also
It's a phenomena occurring of its own.
So you see we we begin withdrawing. It's
like we draw back further and further
from mentalization
more to the field.
So the field is watching experiencing
and we become aware that this is
impersonally happening within a field.
The self, the self is not the content.
The self becomes you become more aware
of the self
as the awareness.
And the awareness is coming out of an
aspect of consciousness. The observer
witnesser. The observer witnesser.
You see, we're we're we're moving the
sense of I
from I am that bad person
that forgot to fill the gas tank and ran
out of gas. How could I be so stupid?
So the naive person identifies then with
the content of thought itself.
The average person is at the effect is
the victim of thinkingness.
The average person is
the victim of thought.
They think that's who I am.
The next wondrous thing is thought
becomes imbued with preciousness.
Thoughts are precious,
wonderful,
and we're enamored of them
because they're mine.
We give thoughts great status because
they're my thoughts.
If they were just those thoughts, they'd
be easy to get rid of, but they're my
thoughts.
The minute we say my thought now it
becomes precious and holy and we genuate
genuine
genuine something really
they become precious
people you hear people say they're
worried that they might lose their
memory. I mean, how lucky could you get?
Wipe out a few years here and there. I
mean, geez. You can always keep a couple
postcards. I mean, if you really want to
remember it.
I can't remember any years I want to
remember. Frankly,
I mean, the passing moment is bad enough
without putting up with 75 years of all
that.
I mean, he right didn't start out too
good right from the beginning. As I told
you, here's his creepy little kid body
in the damn wagon.
Wow. I mean, who wants to be bothered
with that anyway? You're stuck with it.
Not too happy from the first moment to
found out that you exist as a
physicality.
All right.
So you you become more skeptical of
mind. You start to distance yourself
from mind. It becomes an it instead of a
me.
It's a giant step when you realize the
mind is an it. It's not a me. The hell
with you mind. I reject you and disown
you.
Denounce it
as a fraud.
It's a fraud. It comes on and it says
I'm you. kick. Boy, oh boy. Once you get
suckered into that, the ego has really
got you by the end.
Because now it's only a matter of what
happens to go through your mind that
you're the victim of. You go from
strangulation to suffocation to guilt to
shame to anxiety, regret. Maybe you
should kill yourself.
He tells all kinds of people to kill
themselves and they do.
They do. All right. So you don't want to
give it power over yourself. Wow. You
give it power by giving it reality. And
you give it power by calling it me.
By giving it identification as the
reality of the self, the precious
wonderful me. My wonderful feelings.
They become sacred.
The mind becomes God. You worship the
ego mind.
Modern society worships the mind. It's
given up on God and religion
and instead it work it
it worships science.
The salvation of man was once thought to
be the province of God and religion.
Salvation of man has now been allocated
to science
and computers.
science, computers, and bureaucracies.
The government announces a new
bureaucracy every few months. It's going
to solve everything except the next
one's just going to be is going to be
just as incompetent as the last one.
Why? Because the structure the structure
is such that it guarantees failure.
Bureaucracy is one layer of structure on
top of another until finally you become
completely immobilized. People think of
the end of the world is going to be a
big bang. No, the end of the world is
going to come and everything comes to a
stop because the complexity has become
so overwhelming that everything just
succumbs to the sheer complexity.
Eventually, the tax form gets so long
that even if you start on January 1st,
you can't finish it by December 31st and
the tax department stops.
the FBI. I knew we knew what was wrong
with the FBI before it happened. But uh
I I said to Susan, I said, "You under
under this much complexity of
bureaucratic regulations,
you know, even if a bomb was about to go
off in the bathroom, they wouldn't be
able to do anything about it. You got to
get permission from this department and
you got to fill out this form to get
permission. You got to get through the
layers." By that time, the bathroom's
blown up. See?
So the mind then becomes um the tyrant.
The tyrant
and it's it creates a delusion. The
delusion is that I am my thoughts. I am
the mind. I'm it.
That's where my power is. That's where
my destiny is. My memory of mind is more
precious than anything else. And then
you fear what's going to happen in mind
in the future. So mind is really um the
most difficult thing of spiritual
awareness.
We start out with the form we become
aware that we are not the mind. So the
first thing you do with meditation or in
reflection
I'm going to talk today we're talking
about meditation but to a considerable
extent it's reflection and contemplation
because if you do meditation
continuously you can now label it
something else. You can call it
contemplation and re and reflection
which is quite heavily Christian.
Christian doesn't Christianity doesn't
go too much for sitting down, shaving
your head and going home and um focusing
on the tip of your nose. uh Christianity
is more contemplating the truth of the
great spiritual teachers as you go about
your business and instituting them in
your daily affairs to be kind and
considerate and thoughtful
and gentle and patient. Um so the
Christian virtues become
more the field of contemplation in which
one lives one life and by which one
judges one's actions
and it's not really a formal meditation
as such.
We're going to blend the two so that
contemplation becomes the formal
meditation that allows you to meditate
throughout the day no matter what you're
doing just as I'm doing right this
moment.
Oh Lord,
oh this speech that occurs at this
moment is my worship of thee, oh Lord.
Amen.
Were without end. Amen.
Oh,
out of that which I am
out of my worship of thee, oh Lord, I
exist as that which I am at this moment.
So the first realization is that one is
not one's thoughts.
One's thoughts are like a curse. I
shouldn't say that sounds too severe.
One's thoughts are like bad luck.
Bad luck.
You see the core of the ego is
narcissism.
You get this the narcissistic core of
the ego
is the sense of I
coming out of the source of the ego
itself.
It's a sense it's um
it's it's a sense of authority. It's a
sense of um I can't get the right word.
It'll come.
The thinkingness, the naive person
thinks that the thinkingness is who they
are. They become then at the effect of
this thinkingness. They are subject to
it. They are the victim of this
thinkingness. They begin to hate the
content of their own thinkingness. And
they begin to hate themselves because
they think the thinkingness is who they
are. I have bad thoughts.
I told you once before I was brought up
high Episcopal and we went to uh
communion before you could go on
communion Saturday afternoon you had to
go to confession so you waited as long
as possible on Friday afternoon last
confession was 4:00
so there'd be as little time as possible
between confession and communion in the
morning if you go to confession late and
go to early communion the chances of
sinning in the meantime are
statistically much reduced
You lived in fear that this spot on your
soul would appear. You know,
oh Lord, I'm sorry for this. And you do
all the rosary. You do the whole thing.
The our fathers, the whole Mary's. You
keep your eyes focused on the ground
like this. But you should keep careful
control of your thoughts and your mind
that you won't have a sinful thought.
get to 7 o'clock communion. You can make
it probably from 5 on Saturday till 7
o'clock on Sunday morning without a s
spot on your soul which God can see. Oh
Jesus.
And just as you're on your way to church
with the top down in the 29 model A
Ford, you pass a 42 by 96 ft
big advertisement of Jansen swimsuits.
Here's this big blonde lady 42 feet
long.
There goes the other side.
At age six, it wouldn't bother you. But
at 14, it was
32 foot long swimming suit. I'll never
forget.
Nowadays, we would consider fully
dressed compared to, you know, nowadays,
but those days. All right. So, we live
in fear then of the content of mind
because it's labeled with guilt.
Sin and guilt is primarily labeled
mentally. All right. So the first thing
to realize is I am not the content of
mind. You see you look at yourself you
realize you live in terror of your own
mind.
What's our percentage on that? Everybody
live in terror of their mind.
Yeah. Everybody lives in terror of their
mind. Everybody lives in fear and terror
of the mind. What craziness is going to
think of next? What fear? What guilt?
What?
Oh, it's awful.
Dear Lord, protect us from the mind.
Forget about enemies.
Enemies are a nice diversion. They take
you out of your mind. If somebody's
there threatening to kill you, man, it's
cool because I mean, you're out of the
whole sweat and worry thing. You just
got to deal with this guy. You know what
I'm saying?
That's true. when I've been in
life-threatening situations, I mean, you
know, you're out of it.
>> U you're out of it. So, we stopped
registering them with the content of
consciousness. We begin to realize that
form, that processing form is what it
does. It's like a little computer and
you can't shut it off. It's just going
all the time with images and, you know,
goes on all the time. It's not I. I has
to would have to be something um beyond
it in order to witness it.
that the eye would have to at least be
on the level of witness.
Who knows what goes on in the mind and
complains about the mind unless they
were witnessing it and they couldn't
witness it. So what they complain about
is what they're observing but the pain
comes from identifying with it. So the
first thing you do with meditation
either as contemplation as you go about
the day or sitting formal meditation is
to realize to withdraw from the content
of mind and realize that
that which I am is what is witnessing
it. The witnesser the witness the
observer is happening of its own.
The light of consciousness
then is what one begins to identify
with.
One is
that which witnesses the mind. First you
say I'm that which experiences. First
you say I am the mind. You say no I'm
not. I can't be the mind. I must be the
experiencer of the mind. I must be the
witness of the mind. But what is
witnessing and watching doing? Well,
witnessing and watching are also
happening of their own. I want you to
see these things are impersonal. See,
when you identify with mind, you say, "I
am that." That's personal.
It's not personal. It's happening of its
own. You can't stop it from doing that.
Breathing is not personal. Decide you're
going to quit and see how long it works.
You begin to identify then with the
field instead of the content.
You're the space in which all this is
happening.
It is
consciousness itself which is lighting
up the awareness of all this happening.
You realize
that which does not change from moment
to moment. That which does not change
from moment to moment must be what your
reality is. Your reality can't be that
which changes every second because
it would be like a flickering image on
the screen constantly changing
that which is which does not change.
What that which is always present when
you first wake up in the morning
all you're aware of is that you are. If
you watch the waking phenomena
out of oblivion comes awareness
of isness.
If I the minute you start becoming
conscious, if I stop you and say, "What
do you know?" Uh,
I'm awake. What does awake mean?
I'm conscious that I'm conscious.
That's all you're you're conscious that
you're conscious. That's all you're
conscious of. What is your name? Uh,
what's the date? Uh, uh, where you going
today? I don't know. That all comes
later. Don't you know? You have to have
coffee.
The first awareness is that you are.
So
the ultimate then the infinite context
then is existence itself
to be aware of existence. That which I
am is that out of which existence
arises.
Not the content of existence.
Not the content.
Otherwise, you'd be different because
you had a haircut today. You know, you
can't be the content.
The sense of self, the identification of
who am I with meditation and
contemplation, we'll talk more about it
as you know is how the techniques work
progressively.
You no longer say this is I. You no
longer say this is I. You no longer say
this is I. The sense of I
withdraws
to become progressively the field
itself.
Progressively one realizes
that that which I am is the capacity for
consciousness. I'm not even
consciousness.
The infinite capacity
to be conscious. I am prior to
consciousness itself. That which I am is
before consciousness. Consciousness is
willy willy crap stuff
late in the game. Small fry like a
mouse.
That which you are is
beyond consciousness. It's because of
what you are. Consciousness can spring
forth as an awareness
as a vitional awareness.
the sense of self.
Realize that you are beyond
consciousness itself.
If it weren't for what you are,
consciousness couldn't field itself.
Feel couldn't field itself into what you
it has to have existence.
So
don't sell yourself short.
You're the infinite potentiality out of
which consciousness
arises out of which all the rest of this
BS it passes itself off as you due to
the illusion of the ego because the ego
is narcissistic
and it's in love with itself.
You see the ego for what it is.
It thinks you're wonderful.
Your thoughts are wonderful.
Even if they aren't wonderful thoughts,
they're important thoughts.
Cuz your catastrophes are mindboggling.
This exaggeratedness
is the magnification that the ego
creates out of narcissism.
So what holds the whole ego together
then is the that one is enamored of
oneself.
Enamored.
The ego then takes credit for being who
you are.
It also takes credit that it's the
author of your
existence.
It succeeds most of the time.
Most of the time
85% of the population it succeeds big
time.
Big time.
What I think in my what I feel is more
important than all of humanity. Can you
believe the ego can be that big?
Narcissism can grandiosity and
megalomania can reach such a great
dimension. To the average person, it's
not even imaginable
that you could get up front in a in a
world court and and say that you know
what you want for your country is more
important than the lives of all the
countrymen. Say what?
This is not a crime. This is a mental
illness.
A mental illness. So the egotism of the
ego is unlimited.
Unlimited to think I'm not, you know,
God isn't God. I'm God.
Uh
the refusal to surrender the authority
for the source of one's own existence to
God is what gets you there.
All right. So meditation quickly or be
before long brings about a certain
degree of humility.
You realize that that I'm not the
content of thought. In fact, I can't
even manage it for more than a couple
seconds.
The source of the sense of self then
progressively withdraws from
specificity and form becomes
progressively more diffuse more general
becomes the light of consciousness
itself
eventually becomes
the allness out of which the unmanifest
manifests itself as manifestation.
The infinite reality,
the infinite reality
is the infin infinite potentiality.
The power of God is infinite
because God is infinite context.
Out of infinite context arises all power
and the potentiality for existence
in form or nonformm.
And that's what
that's our reality. That's what we are.
the potentiality to become conscious
because you can choose
as you walk about in the world then
there's less and less focus on content.
I'll warn you in advance it gets you
into trouble.
It gets you into trouble sometimes. You
don't know where the hell the light
switch is. I don't know. She said,
"Where is the light switch?" I don't
know. They moved it. How do you work
this fan? I don't know.
Uh because in youth, you're focused on
thingness. You know, all the gadgets,
the electronic gadgets that crowd the
marketplace now are made out made by
insane 24 year olds who are crazy about
the electronics of
and um I mean, you just can't buy a
clock, alarm clock. You know what I'm
saying? You can't just go on off. You
can't buy a radio that just goes on off.
I've got a radio in my waiting room
that's worth its price in gold. It's got
a dial like that and then it's got onoff
volume.
That's it.
I turn it goes on. Then I just go I tune
it to WR FM.
There you go. All set.
Somebody gave me one for Christmas. Oh
my god. It's got an instruction manual
this thick. It's in fine print. Anything
made in Japan or China has that very
fine print.
Push push button A six times. Then push
button B. Wait 3 seconds and push button
and then go 86942.
By doing that, you can set your alarm
clock to go on and off Tuesday,
Thursday, Friday, and Saturday and
alternate weeks on the following weeks.
And I don't know how to use it. I put it
back in the box. I've got boxes full of
wonderful presents made up by 22 year
olds.
Wonderful watches, but I can't figure
out how to use them.
I don't know how to use them. So, what
you do is you catch the nearest
22-year-old and you say, "How do you
turn this thing on?" Yeah.
To them, it's simple. All right.
So that to me is the world of form. The
world of form is mind-boggling complex,
tiring. I mean, I'm tired just to look
at the instruction manual and they say,
"Here's the instruction manual." I go,
"You're supposed to send in a
registration card. I'd never do that. I
It's horrible."
A warranty card and all. If it breaks
down, forget it. You know, I'm not going
to send it back to the company and get
my $17 back. back. I mean, do you know
this thing? Blow a whole afternoon doing
that. Go back and forth the post office.
I was packed this thing up. I want my
$17. Write him a letter, fill out the
form, get it signed an affidavit,
witness. I mean, you know what I'm
saying?
I'm just giving you my warped view of of
what the world calls reality. I want you
to keep in mind that my view is warped,
abnormal according to the world because
the world loves form and loves the
detail of form, you know.
Um,
I get more of the context. I want the
gist of a thing. I can walk into a room
instantly I've got what it's all about.
What everybody's there about, what the
whole scene is about, what the sense of
it is about, what the prevailing energy
field is. Therefore, what to expect,
what's possible, you know, the the
upside, the downside, the potentiality,
what's already happened, what's likely
to happen. You can almost see the future
of it arising. And you can see how it
all arose.
You can see how it all came together
throughout time. and where it is at this
passing moment and you can see where
it's going. That's what you want is the
essence. So you can read essence in one
split second.
We all learn to do that.
Certain neighborhoods in New York City,
if you don't know how to do that, you
ain't going to live long.
You can just tell by the ambiance as you
turn the corner. Oh,
I got to go this way.
You don't know why we call it intuition,
don't we? Mhm. So that which is not in
form within you, as you become
progressively aware of it, you become
more and more what we call intuitive.
You just read it. Um, I mean, I can I
told you before, I can walk remember
walking down 10th Avenue, New York City,
and late at night, and I could tell by
the footsteps behind me, half a block
behind me, I knew from the footsteps
what it was, what it had in mind, what
it intended,
what my fate would be if I didn't read
it right,
and I crossed over the street.
All right? So, the animal learns that.
So that capacity, that innate capacity
to focus on
context instead of content is learned.
You've already got the capacity.
The animal knows it. The animal as it
turns the corner also knows, uh-oh, it
senses the line up in the tree and
walks the other way to live another day.
If it fails to, it's gone.
Bye-bye.
water buffalo. Uh so
we have the capacity then to focus
either centrally when we need to or
peripherally.
With spiritual evolution, one becomes
progressively the field.
One is the field. You understand?
All of us are we are the field here.
where the field out of which
the field then brings forth the
talkingness of the content through the
speaker. You know what I'm saying?
That's happening spontaneously of its
own. Has nothing to do with any personal
self.
I'd have to stop and think, what am I
going to say?
That'd be like looking through the
instruction book on an electronic
gadget. You know what I'm saying? You
could get a general thrust to what we'll
talk about today, but then it happens of
its own because it's happening as a
result of the field and the field is set
by the consciousness level of the people
here and their intention and their
interest.
That's what creates a sense of the
field.
So one becomes aware I'm the field
the infinite potentiality
the Buddha nature the Buddha nature a
lot of people don't understand what the
Buddha nature is they talk about it
the Buddha nature is the unmanifest
the unmanifest potentiality
it is beyond form
but it is not void because it is the
infinite potential potiality out of the
infin infinite potentiality is allness,
not nothingness.
If you go the way of negation, you'll
end up like I did lifetime after a
lifetime in a stupid void and you come
back here wham and you got a freaky body
in the in a wagon to put up with the
physicality, the shock.
No, the ultimate reality is not void.
Nothingness. If it was nothingness, I
wouldn't be back.
I've been in the void.
What is it that witnesses the void?
Who's to talk about void? If void is the
only living reality,
no one would know know of it, wouldn't
they?
If you like brain wipeout, who's going
to tell you that their brain got wiped
out? Nobody. Nothing there.
Because the ultimate reality is the
unmanifest. It becomes manifest. There's
the infin infinite infinite potentiality
of consciousness itself.
which is then capable of all this
content. All this content and
thinkingness.
Let's see if what we said is true.
That depiction
is aligned with God's truth. Resist. We
have permission to ask in front of this
audience. Resist. It's over 999. It's
1,00 1,0001 1,000. is the absolute
understanding of it's the absolute
understanding of which we are capable in
this dimension which was that which we
just said is the absolute infinite
ultimate capacity
of comprehension of one's reality.
It comes out of the realization of the
truth that one is the infinite
infinite potentiality.
So you think start thinking yourself as
the infinite potentiality
to have the experiencer
who temporarily identifying with the
bodiness or some place called Sedona
Sedona or something but that's all just
possible because of the infinite
potentiality.
So here here we have then what we arrive
at just by playing with it in your mind.
You just play with your mind as you get
up in the morning. You just you start
with being
just the infinite space for this day to
happen in. That's what you really are.
See you start out as the unmanifest
which then becomes manifest and says
yes. Oh it's me. I say who are you when
you wake up? I don't know. Uh I mean I'm
I'm George and and what are you doing
today George? Well uh uh
takes you a while to get who you are.
So this state here is not different than
a state which you are already familiar
with. Huh.
Um the capacity to relate to the field
instead of the content of the field.
I don't know if it's good to do that
when when you're driving when you first
start start this.
Maybe it is. I don't know. But having
been a cab driver, you know, you're in
that space and you just automatically,
you know, you just automatically beat
the other guy to the fair staying on the
curb without thinking about it. But um
how can one function in that state?
Well, there may be truthfully so there
is some impairments.
I really don't know how to work those
crazy clocks. And you know what? I don't
care about them
because I I'm not that interested in
what time it is anyway to begin with.
But the world is so you better know what
time it is. So, but you need some kind
of a clock, you know. You need an
oldfashioned clock. You can even wind
the thing. You know, it's
there is perhaps some loss of um detail
of life. However, the potentiality to
appreciate the detail is constantly
there. It's constantly there.
So that's one way. That's the way
starting from peripheral vision,
the everywhereness,
the allness, the beyond timeness. You
see, it has nothing to do with now.
All kinds of books about now. Lord, save
us from now. Thank you, sir.
If there's no then and no when and no
future and no past and there is uh not
any now either.
There's no point to trying to focus on
the moment and now in meditation. People
say, I try to focus on now, but I can't
focus on now. My mind is always thinking
about the past or the future. I said,
well, your mind is always thinking about
the fast the past or the future right
now, isn't it? So you're still in the
now, even if you're thinking about the
past and the future.
But now is just a label we put to a
specific awareness
because let's say because your awareness
happens to be passing this point. It
says this is now, this is now, this is
now, this is now. But that's just a
nominalization. Your mind just made that
up. There isn't any nowness going on,
folks.
But let's not walk around saying we live
in the now. It's a corruption of
reality.
Nobody lives in any now. Show me the now
you live in, idiot.
You don't live any then. You don't live
any future. You don't live any now
either. All those are
time dimensions. Those are all
durations. Those are all depictions.
Those are all nominalizations which
arise up in here. You see, you got to
give it a name. Why do you have to give
a name to whatever is at this second?
You see, and when you get to a certain
level, you don't even call it is
anymore. That's also an absurdity.
There's neither is nor is not.
The conundrum at age three
was existence versus non-existence.
Here's this horrible little body and
this rotten little wagon
and instantly comes the fear.
First of all, the kid couldn't think in
words. This is all non-verbal.
But awareness is aware of this
existence.
Along with existence came instantly fear
of non-existence.
It was apparent that if one is, it could
have come about that one is not would
not have been. You know what I'm saying?
If you could be, it could have happened
that
you're coming into beingness wouldn't
have happened in which case you wouldn't
be
at age three. I'm puzzling existence
versus non-existence. A fear of
non-existence.
Oh boy. Oh boy. So the first thing
existence does is give you a fear of
non-existence.
We see that in the ego is concerned with
death.
If things dies, it's not going to exist
anymore, folks. No such thing's going to
happen.
No such luck.
You not go from existence to
non-existence. You just go to a
different style of existence in which
all these lifetimes string out as one
lifetime.
I went through a couple of them the
other day. Oh my god, I just soon forget
that all together.
But it was
how consciousness evolved through these
various physical physical physicalities,
each one serving a very definite
purpose. And as I say, they tended to
flip-flop. In this one, you did this and
the next lifetime you flip back again to
like undo all that. Oh boy.
All right. So
the way out of all of that, the karmic
constant.
See, because when you're in that
lifetime, you forgot that. See,
you forgot that. Then when you're out,
you remember it again. And wham. Because
as long as one is identifying with form,
then you're going to keep reincarnating.
There's no way beyond it. I can see
that. As long as you think I am anything
specific, that specificness will then
create a new specificness.
Once you realize you're the field of the
infinite potentiality, you're beyond it.
You think you want another lifetime? I
got news for you.
When you get there, you're not going to
like it anywhere. You like this
lifetime. I look back at previous
lifetimes. I didn't like anyone. I'm
better than any other one.
On a certain level, they were all
horrid. On a certain level, they were
all exciting. On a certain level, they
were all everything else.
And I could do without it. Heck, you had
enough lifetimes. I mean, you can do
without them. You just don't have a yen
for another lifetime, folks. Like,
you've gone and seen so many movies.
I'm not interested in movies. I never
watched movies. I mean, I've seen them
all. I've seen every twist and turn and
writer's fantasy about how you can
phrase this, express that. I've seen
every actors and actresses
doing it there and I just don't get it
entertaining anymore.
All right. Enlightenment then would be
the dissolution of the identification
with content.
with content,
with existence as form,
even with existence itself. That which I
am is beyond existence. Existence came
out of that which I am just as
consciousness arose out of that which
you can't be at the effect of anything.
There's nothing causing anything.
Consequently,
anything phrased within the context of
causality cannot have any cannot be the
absolute reality.
In as much as one lifetime does not
karmmically cause the next lifetime. No,
something outside of all of those
lifetimes
tends to bring them into physical
manifestation.
You can't be the content of each
lifetime. You have to be the source out
of which those lifetimes are arising and
one is re- choosing reincarnation.
Contemplation then is just walking about
and you see you can do it right now. You
just be aware. Forget about what the
speaker is talking about. He just
chatters on and talks and talks and the
room is full of what all appears to be
people and all that. And you realize
that the the capacity to be aware of the
phenomena.
So if we look at it phenomenologically
the capacity to be aware of the
phenomena
is what you are. You hold the capacity.
What you are is the capacity to be aware
of any of this. Now you can pay as much
attention to it as you want. You see
that's valitional.
You can either pay attention to it. You
can identify with it or not. and I'm
fine with it.
Even to say what day it is is a
mentation. It's no day right now at all.
There is no day that it is today any
more than there is any month that it is
today or any year that it is today.
Those are all madeups
just wordingnesses
conveniences
in the world of form. That's very
convenient to say. I'll see you
Wednesday. Okay.
If you live in nonform there isn't any
Wednesday
the world says Wednesday you say okay
you say it's Wednesday I'll go on
Wednesday
you can go along with the world world
but it's elective that's the difference
it's elective you're not at the effect
of it otherwise you're suffering from
Monday Tuesdayness Wednesday I mean you
see you end up a
It's very easy to get that you are
beyond that which is in physicality.
The infinite awareness is radiating
forth as
the seeming phenomena.
But you get you're that you're beyond
all that.
You get that you're the field out of
which consciousness arises.
Is that so?
Everybody agree?
We're all the infinite field out of
which consciousness arises.
Not we're not the product of
consciousness.
We're its capacity, its source
out of which consciousness arises.
The manifest arises out of the
unmanifest.
Creation arises out of the unmanifest
and becomes manifest
and what the world calls evolution
which is the appearance that creation
takes
by sequential observation. It seems like
there sequence. The sequence is not in
the out there. The sequence is in the
perception. Sequential perception
creates the illusion of causality.
There are no cause out there at all,
folks.
When I was a kid, I lived out in the
country and the only way to get to
school was to hitchhike 10 below zero.
And
it was a lonely highway and u anyway,
the only hope for a ride was occasional
occasional car
and um occasional truck.
So you'd hear the truck coming about a
mile away. You know, you get all
excited. As the cut truck got closer and
closer, I had a little magical thing I
would do to make the truck stop and pick
me up. I'd go 7777777.
I do that seven times and turn around
seven times and that would make the
truck stop.
So, I do that and then the truck would
spot me. I could hear him hitting the
air bra.
half a mile away, he's starting to hit
the air brakes because on the icy snow,
he better start hitting them early. So,
here's this kid out there with his
books, you know, and uh in those days,
you know, everybody sort of trusted
everybody. Now, nowadays, you think he
was probably a killer or something, but
anyway, in those days, everybody trusted
everybody. So, the truck driver would
pick up this kid staying out in the cold
wind and snow, you know.
But the the idea of magic was of course
that saying seven seven times and then
spinning about on my heels seven times
was going to make this truck stop. You
know
of course when it did then I that
connected the magic even stronger
and once in a while it wouldn't
well
still it happened a lot of the time but
you see how you mind gives causality to
it causality to it. All right. So we
want to get out of that child's world
then magical causality.
The world's belief in causality is
really sort of magic living in the world
of magic
because it doesn't see that what it
takes to create every instant is the
totality of God
as creation throughout all of time.
So we get out of being the content of
consciousness. We become the context of
consciousness. We become the reality out
of which consciousness arises.
So we'll take a break.
>> Okay.
>> Hold this. Check over your thorus.
>> I can't do it with my eyes closed.
>> This is a good check. Resist.
I was This is a bum check and I just use
it for fun every time.
Says insufficient funds anyway.
Just for fun with kinesiology.
Well, our picture is still crooked, but
we've gotten used to it looking at it
this way. And if we changed it, then
everybody have to look at it this way.
There must be some way to make it look
straight. But anyway, we don't care
about that. All right. I want to just go
into a few more specifics about u
meditation and handling
content of mind and things to notice
about it.
If you sit in formal meditation and
focus on the content of mind as it
passes by,
the first thing you notice is it's it's
irrational.
Uh it goes on and on
and then you'll begin to see that the
the thinkingness
is coming about
as a as as a result of several things.
Habit
um boredom
and the idea that uh thoughts are
worthwhile that they serve a purpose. Um
so they're they're entertainment.
They're going to solve problems. It
gives you something. Thinkingness is
something you can do.
Uh people think thinking is worthwhile.
I'm going to sit down and think about
that.
But when you're meditating, you're not
you're not interested in what you're
interested in is getting beyond thought.
There is a field of energy out of which
thinking is is arising.
And so I want to go into a specific
detail about that. Let's say
you're sitting in let's say you're
sitting in in formal meditation
and um the thinkingness is arising of
its own. You'll see it's arising of its
own.
It's coming out of
a desire to think.
The mind wants to think.
Um it's coming out of an energy
If you don't get caught up in the
content of thought,
you end up at a point of observation
where the thinkingness arises and then
it passes away.
I think we said in a previous lecture
like looking out a car window without
focusing on what's going by, but looking
through the same point of the car
window,
everything flicks by. You understand
what I'm saying? You don't like fixate
on on this and watch it and then fixate
on the next. That's the way the mind
usually works. I mean the the Yeah, the
mind and the eyes. It it looks at this
and then it follows it and then it
clicks back this way and it clicks. He's
constantly doing that.
Um
there is a way of focusing on thought of
not moving with the thought, not getting
absorbed in the content, the emotion,
the story of it.
Just witnessing from a fixed point of
observation
that the the thought arises
a specific thought arises out of sort of
an amorphous potentiality
to become a thought.
It gains greater and greater form. It
becomes very very specific. Crosses the
point of aware of of attention
and begins to fade out fade out. It
loses form and disappears.
There is a form of meditation which
which requires
one-pointedness of thought.
This is out of Zen training.
There is a fixity of intention of
one-pointedness of mind. The focus soap
like a razor
on the edge of this moment of focus.
So the thought arises like a like a note
of music arises crests. No sooner does
the note of music crest than the music
is already fading away.
You become aware with this fixity of
intention and focus
that that which is the self is prior to
the thought
that that which one is arises
from
the source. You'll see all the thinking
this is coming out of an energy
and one can begin to release the energy
of the desire
to think.
Let's see how that works. I haven't done
it in some years.
This thought is arising
out of um a formless energy field
uh which begins to gather form
becomes specific as a thought and then
fades away.
One can by fixity of focus
fix on on the instant let's say we'll
use the term instant on the process just
prior to its coming into form.
All right. So in the beginning you start
thinking about old dog Rover and how he
got a glaucoma in his left
car bunkle and they had to take him to
the and then the anesthesia croaked and
the family crying and good old Rover and
Christ now what are we going to do for a
dog? I mean you got this whole long
story
as you meditate you get beyond that and
and you get to see Rover. Okay. I mean,
if you picture Rover's image,
there's a perhaps a slight memory, but
now you get to Roverness itself.
I mean, there's the essence of Roverness
without the whole freaky story that goes
with Roverness. There's just the essence
of Roverness. And u now the name Rover
disappears. You just focus on the
essence
of that dog's beingness and his
lovingness.
You get to the heart of
what was Rover
and now the form is disappearing.
You're getting almost to dogness.
You're getting to animal relatedness.
You're getting to
life identifying with life.
You're getting to an energy that is
prior to the specific of thought itself.
So specific thoughts are coming out of
like a little energy factory,
little energy source, an energy sink,
whatever you call it.
Um,
and one can surrender that to God. So
when it
we didn't talk about renunciation yet
surrender then is renunciation in that
one eventually
lets go of the belief that one is the
source of all that and sees that it is
happening of its own.
one gets lets go of the wantingness of
thinkingness.
Early in the game, you see that
thinkingness all has a payoff.
The way to silence that thinkingness is
to be willing to surrender the payoff of
that thinkingness.
The sad stories,
the excitement,
the erotic titilation, whatever is
associated with that thought, the
willingness to surrender that
the great pleasure of being right.
Judgmentalism,
righteousness.
The downfall of mankind since the
beginning of time has been
righteousness.
Everybody feels righteous in what they
do. Everybody that pulls the trigger on
feel righteous.
Every war is based on righteous.
Everybody's righteous. I don't want to
hear about people's rights and
righteousness.
Give me a break.
All right. So, the mind wants to be
righteous. It wants to manufacture
self-pity,
grief, mourning, anger, rage, delight,
anticipation, fear.
It does a whole melodrama. One has to be
willing to let go the payoff of these
ego positionalities.
You first you discern what is the payoff
of that.
Well, it's the fun of hating those
idiots.
We love to hate people. I mean, it's
fun, isn't it?
They're bad and they deserve it. So
to start this mind, we we witness how it
behaves. Then we see that it's being
sourced. It's being sourced by the
payoff of this thinkingness.
As we get be as we we're willing to
surrender the payoff to God, could you
let go
the pleasure of self-pity and surrender
it to God? Could you? Yeah. Would you?
Okay.
So, there's a constant of letgoingness
of the payoff of this thinkingness
that gives gives the thinkingness less
of an emotional charge.
The willingness to surrender the payoff.
Each negative feeling
is not serving something else. It's
serving itself. The payoff of guilt is
that you get to feel guilty. The payoff
of anger is you get angry.
You get to experience the payoff. The
feeling is the payoff.
People say, "What what do people get out
of hate?" Well, you get hatred, man.
What do you think? That's why we killed
all those kids at school. Bang. Bang.
Bang.
The gratification is the feeling itself.
You see, our society can't find the
answer anything because it's always
trying to psychologize everything and
look for the reason in childhood.
There's no reason in childhood. It's the
glee of it now.
Watch the TV the in the Middle East
throwing rocks at each other. This side
throws rocks at this side. They're
really getting off on that. This side
then throws rocks on that side. They get
off on that, too. Now they both get
indignant. Boy, they're all hot with
indignity. Then they pull both pull out
rifles and they shoot away at each other
and then throw bombs and then they send
in tanks and blast away.
Everybody gets on TV about the poor
little infant, the poor mother crying.
The whole melodrama is such a huge
payoff, man. How can you resist it?
So the mind gets sucked into it and it
can't get out. You don't have to look
for something from childhood to explain
it. The payoff is in the instant of now.
It's right now is the payoff.
The payoff of rage is you get to feel
rage.
Watch those people throwing rocks at
each other. There it's a state of high
glee,
isn't it?
It's got nothing to do with their
childhood. It's got nothing to do with
politics. has got nothing to do with
America being richer and all that crap.
They just love an excuse to throw rocks.
So the payoff is the experience itself.
In meditation, we have to be willing to
surrender the payoff of the experience
itself to God.
Lord God, out of my worship of thee, my
desire and love to reach
and to be of service,
I'm willing to relinquish the payoff of
this emotionality so that I can get
beyond it. That's it.
So that way the thinkingness has less of
an emotional charge because as long as
you're getting off on the charge of the
emotion of the thinkingness, it's not
going to stop.
If you can reduce the emotion behind it
now, it slows down and it becomes more
available for inspection.
So a great deal of what's done in formal
meditation at least in Zen style. One
pointedness of mind is inspection. One
inspects the phenomena of thinkingness.
We know that the minute you inspect the
thing, it already changes.
Um
Mr. Gdatara Mahara said that that when
you start observing the mind it already
begins to change out of observation.
Observation. So the first thing that's
happening in meditation is by the mere
act of observation
you're already altering the content of
consciousness
by virtue of your intention.
to get to the source of this
thinkingness. If you follow this track
of onepointed fixity of observation,
you'll get that all thinkingness is
coming out of a little energy factory
like a little source of a volcano
and one can surrender
the onlogi of the thought before it
takes form. As you keep letting it go,
it starts out with a story about oh good
old Rover. As you let go that that whole
story, it gets down to just a paragraph.
As you let go the paragraph, it gets
down to a sentence. Finally just gets
down to the name Rover.
The willingness to to surrender the
instant a thing arises in consciousness,
finally even Rover starts to dissolve.
You start to think
just before it becomes rover. First it
was long story, sad story. You're
weeping and crying all about Rover. Now
the story is just down to barely
remembering the name Rover. Now it just
comes up as Ro. Then it comes
the image of a dog arises. Dog doesn't
have a name yet. Not even Rover. You
don't allow it to get to the point of
rubberness.
You'll see that the willing to surrender
the intentionality of thinkingness
itself can be surrendered at its very
root.
At its very root at that point the mind
becomes silent and one is that out of
which thinkingness arises.
This is possible scientifically.
How do we focus this guy on this thing?
Ooh,
that takes energy to focus on the world.
I tell you, I mean, focusing on form is
deenergizing. I don't know how people do
it, how they get away with it.
Focusing on form is exhausting. You know
what I mean? You got to pay attention to
what they're saying. Oh, gee,
I'd rather get it. Can you say that in
three words or less?
Anybody wants a conversation with me, if
you can make it in couple of sentences,
I'll be glad to talk to you. If you want
to tell me all about your aunt Matilda
and all what went on and your three
pregnancies and the husbands that came
and went, I really can't handle it.
Let's get to the essence. Truth is very,
very brief. You know, the absolute truth
is absolutely wordless.
So those of you who wish to speak to me
in a wordless style, God bless you.
You just come up to me and you give me
the thought like that and I got it.
Okay. So no, you're okay. You just got
to All right. So you get beyond thinking
this. How can this be? How can you get
beyond thinking this? I mean, are we
talking mysterious fiction or what? Last
night there's a guy on TV history. What
is it? That channel that the guy that
loves to bash spiritual reality.
I don't want to get into him. He's
horrid.
>> That's exciting.
>> He's a pseudocientist. Anyway,
>> here we have we haven't talked about
much about quantum mechanics, but the
book versus force has to do with going
from the linear to the nonlinear
paradigm. nonlinear to nonlinear
in the book I'm finishing now or the one
I just finished I forget which no I
guess the one I'm finishing now I guess
the one I'm finishing now yes is in the
back uh a procise of uh quantum
mechanics for anybody that's interested
in it incredible and wonderful and
exciting subject
anyway
what's interesting about quantum
mechanics is that
as you're all aware as you get to
smaller and smaller submicroscopic subp
particles subatomic
sub electrons subphotonic
reality
that consciousness has an observable
effect. You're all aware of the
Heisenberg principle correct everybody.
Anybody doesn't know what it is.
All right. So we'll give the basic
experiment that gives the whole thing
away. When a atom of matter and one of
antimatter meet, they extinguish each
other and when they do, there's a
discharge of two photons.
Photons head off in different directions
of the universe.
They have no spin to them. However, if
an if a human being looks at one photon,
it instantly begins to spin. At the same
time on the opposite side of the
universe with no connection between the
two whatsoever the other photon begins
to f in exactly the opposite direction
exactly the same instant the mere act of
observation witnessing changes reality.
So that's the space in which prayer is
effective meditation
the space in which that which you hold
in mind tends to manifest.
Energy follows thought. all the
spiritual realities that we know that
prayer is effective that meditation.
Uh
how can I see when I'm standing my own
light? This thing is not working too.
The world I don't know it's such a crazy
place. All right. So we can compare this
is the world of logic the linear reality
of quantum reality. This is the space
out of which the
scient was a program on near-death
experiences. You know, it starts out
very good and then deteriorates to where
he tries to negate that it has any
spiritual reality because his
consciousness is stuck over here in the
Newtonian paradigm.
And although they these people, you
know, profess to be scientists, I say to
them, have you heard of quantum
mechanics?
because they're still coming from you
know 50 years ago if it's not
measurable.
So this is the ordinary reality of
ordinary life. The Newtonian paradigm in
which things are logical,
sequential.
Where is the word cause?
Good gosh, I forgot the word cause. Man,
this is an orderly cause. Everything is
caused logically, predictably. Look,
look back to your childhood to find out
why you do things is reductionist.
It's provable. It's measurable.
Everything is sequential, temporal. You
can figure it out on a computer. It's
solvable by the differential calculus.
It's based on force. Everything is
finished. It's it's a subtle
world uh
you can count on.
It'll also kill you. Anyway,
the discovery of advanced theoretical
physics then has to do with quantum
reality. the quantum and the mathematics
of it is somewhat complicated. You don't
have to go into the shreddinger
equations to understand the quant
infinite quantum potentiality.
But as we get smaller and smaller, this
has to do with the microscopic world.
This is the world of grossness,
grossness.
But you and I are aware that the subtle
feelings of isness, existence, the
subtleties and inferences
um are not on the level of the gross.
They're not on the level of the
measurable.
They don't even direct, you know, they
don't even exist in time or space
because the ultimate reality is
subjective. The ultimate reality is
subjective.
This is
where power resides. Power is in the
context, not in the content. This is the
finished product. This is the end of it
all.
This is the consequence. It ends up as
the Empire State Building. This is the
Empire State Building. Where did the
Empire State Building come from?
The guy was sitting there probably
smoking a camel cigarette back in the
30s.
The tallest building in the world. Whoa.
You know, tallest building in New York
City. Tallest building in the world. And
the thing begins to grow in his mind.
And it grows and it grows. And the more
he thinks about it, the more excited he
gets. And then a design begins to form
in his head. It's all starting over
here. It was poised. It was a
potentiality. It's all uncertain,
purely subjective. It's expansive. It
grows with possibilities. That's
unlimited. He could have made it twice
as tall. Right?
When this is going to arise either in
thought or in the world is stochastic.
It's it's not predictable.
If we knew all these factors and in the
back of the book the current book I'm I
put a in an index in which you can look
at all these factors they all have
mathematical names. So whether it's time
dependent or independent these are two
different shading equations to solve
these two different equations.
As you can see you're dealing with
tensiality.
You're obser you're dealing with things
that are observable but not measurable.
They're comprehensible.
They're not local any place. Where
where's the locality of the Empire State
Building before it become goes into
physicality? It's nowhere. It's diffuse.
It's inter mingled with thoughts of of
New York City and the glamour of the
city and uh the glory of man. And it's a
progressive, imaginative, creative,
free, unpredictable, illogical,
disorderly
infinite potentiality.
There is the infinite potentiality
of context out of which what we call a
real reality arises. It's the infinite
potentiality of consciousness itself.
It's idiotic then for anybody to take a
position that this is unreal and this is
real
because it's only out of the
subjectivity of what they call the
unreal
that you can say that the objective
world exists.
No statement of objectivity
has any validity except as a subjective
reality.
So the absolute infinite reality
is subjectivity.
The presence of God within expresses
itself as the infinite potentiality
out of which arises subjective awareness
is consciousness.
The presence is radically subjective.
It's not out there elsewhere some other
time for other people. The average
religious concept of God is God arose
somewhere back there in time,
spun the dice. Now he's disappeared
up there with his feet up in the easy
chair
waiting for time to end at which time
we're going to have judgment day. Whoa.
Whoa.
So God's waiting elsewhere in time and
space. Heaven. Heaven is up there
someplace.
Astronauts have been up there. They
haven't found any heaven up there.
>> Where is he? God is elsewhere in time
and place.
How can you experience a God which isn't
even here?
Was and will be but is not now. The
judge of God of judgment day. So God
disappears, creates the dice, takes off,
and now the world, how does it keep
going? It goes like billiard balls
supposedly causality.
So the explanation then of what the
world considers reality is over here.
Actually, the explanation is over here.
Here is where the explanation is.
So uh any concept of objectivity then is
a subjective judgment.
There is no such thing as objectivity.
There is only subjectivity.
That's the whole basic of the Heisenberg
principle.
There are not measurables in reality. In
quantum reality, there's only
observables.
You can witness certain things, but you
can't measure them because the minute
you try to measure it, it already
changes. You can't measure the same
thing twice in quantum mechanics.
One one observation totally changes it.
When you go back, it isn't there
anymore.
That opens then for us
uh that we can see
that spiritual work is very very
powerful because it is the subjective
reality out of which observable supposed
reality arises in the first place.
It's encouraging to realize that your
spiritual work is very very powerful.
The spiritual work that you do is very
very powerful. People say, "How can I
get from 150 to 200?" Well, you just
follow
be kind to your neighbor.
So here we have infinite infinite power.
How much power is available in the
quantum potentiality is infinite
infinite infinite
without beginning without end without
limitation without design or form.
Consequently power is infinitely
powerful.