Does enlightenment depend on grace or
intent or devotion? It depends on all of
them. You see, because be to become
interested in enlightenment or spiritual
evolution or salvation,
to be interested in Jesus or Buddha or
any going to church is already great
good karma, is it not?
I mean, 80 87% of the population doesn't
even get that far. 87% of the population
is not devoted to truth
or the pursuit of truth. To merely get
on the map itself is incredible.
We were going through meditation to the
realization that one is the awareness.
One is the space out of which the word
cat arose. The space is blank.
Consciousness is blank.
That consciousness has been likened to a
light because
it's the light of consciousness itself.
You realize that that is the
manifestation
and beyond that is the unmanifest
because consciousness itself arose out
of
an a priority condition.
Out of the darkness arose the light and
out of the light consciousness.
Consciousness striking matter evolved as
life.
That all becomes obvious.
Is intention and devotion sufficient? I
think so because
there's another question here about the
great rays
because um I think it attunes you to the
great rays. Let's ask if there is such a
thing. The great rays as described in
the course of miracles is a spiritual
fact. Resist. We have permission to ask
that resist. I should have asked
permission first.
The god of old.
>> I got old.
>> What were we asking?
>> Permission.
>> About what?
>> Oh, the great race.
>> That's further in the pack here. We're
cheating a little. Oh, there is such a
thing. Resist. What we're talking about
is frequency vibrations over a thousand
resist. We're talking about the
archangels 50,000 over resist. Yeah. So
what happens you see uh your through
your active devotion you begin to attune
yourself to the great powers of heaven.
And so a human being's nervous system
can only handle spiritual energy up to a
certain level. Beyond that it's
exquisite I mean excruciating pain.
Homosspirus has to evolve. The human
nervous system has to evolve to the
point it could carry more powerful
energy and still remain in a physical
body in this planet.
The great rays really in a way mean that
intense spiritual commitment
then attracts the attention of
what should we say in the vernacular
great spiritual beings right who are out
of form out of physicality
whose dominion is enormous and whose
power is enormous.
As we say, what brought me out of hell
was the thought of an archangel. An
archangel heard the thought
that was enough.
So the intreaty, the commitment, the
surrender
does then invoke you might say
the assistance of the great rays not on
a necessary it's not like a personal
basis but as an automatic consequence of
the huge electromagnetic energy field we
call God.
We were going to sort of draw a picture
of what happens.
I'm not a very good artist, but anyway,
here's this big giant electromagnetic
field, and here's all these little
entities in there.
And these little entities all have
different uh
plus or minuses. They've got positive
poles and negative poles.
It's some are bigger than others and
some are wiggly waggly and some have all
kinds of sketchy scratchy things and um
okay so anyway
every little thought feeling that flicks
through your mind already creates a
frequency vibration here within the
overall energy field. You can see how
that that moves with it. Let's say this
electromagnetic field is of infinite
power. If it's of infinite power
then 1 10 trillionth of a microwatt
is already going to be you see whether
we change this to positive or negative
if I change this in the slightest the
whole field is affected is it not that's
the effect of prayer people say what
good is my little prayer
another question that's fingering into
the stack is if
through spiritual should work. We only
move a few points in a lifetime. Is it
worth it?
Well, that's a mindboggling question.
Depends on how much you got in the
market between 2.5 and 3% is not much,
right? If you got a million in there,
it's going to pay for your kids'
graduation. You know, when we said that,
we were saying
all of mankind,
all of mankind, it tends to move. Let's
ask it again and reaffirm it because
that was 1995.
The average we have permission to ask
about this resist.
In an average lifetime, the average
person on the planet today their
consciousness moves ahead. Resist.
That's a relief. It moves ahead more
than on an average three points, four
points, five points, six points.
On an average, the average human being
in a lifetime moves ahead about five
points.
That's just an average.
You have to understand what an average
means.
It means it doesn't apply to you.
It's a statistical
probability.
Now, everybody here, I mean, there's
many people here that have experienced
jumps of hundreds of points in a matter
of seconds.
There's people who have gone, I'm aware
of people uh who have crashed down, lost
100 points, 200 points. People have
crashed from very high to very low also.
So some go from here to there, others go
from here to there. Other people just
hold steady in this lifetime.
You can choose a lifetime where you just
hold steady. You know what I mean? You
just want to peel potatoes and plant
corn and you know enough already. One
lifetime to just sort of solidify where
I'm at and get a breather
ready to hit the road again. The next
one, you can't go through every lifetime
like this one. I'll tell you, I'm not
This will last me quite a while.
Now, we've had people jump a couple
hundred points just during a lecture.
Yeah, let's just ask.
We've had people jump over 200 points in
lecture resist 250, 300.
We had people jump 300 points just in
one lecture. Resist. People in the
lecture will just suddenly jump 300
points and just go, "Uh-huh. Nothing to
it. It's obvious." Okay,
to merely contextualize a thing then
makes it comprehensible. So a lot of
times just a little insight here it
seems like a small insight but it shifts
your perspect your perspective and from
a different perspective it's a snap you
know.
uh so
one's intention so we cannot look at it
like uh watching the stock market every
day. You can't do spiritual work like
well I'm going to check myself out every
day and see if I had five points.
God bless there are naive people that
send me letters weekly. How am I doing
this week? Can I check my calibration
this week? No, that's not what it's
about folks. That's looking for payoff.
Spiritual work is done for its own sake.
For thee, oh God, do I lay down my life
and
live it to the extreme
out of devotion to the
that's all it takes. the rest
is handled.
Um,
somebody questioned my view about the
fetus. I really didn't want to bring up
fetuses here.
I don't know how it arose, but uh,
somebody asked me why. I don't know why.
When you get to heaven, ask. I don't
know.
Makes sense to me. I wouldn't move into
a house until it's uh, looks like it's
built to the point that it's going to
stand. I don't know.
It's just not a suitable
abode, you know, as we just ran across
that by accident. Just we found
interesting things like your level of
consciousness is already present at
birth. The time of your death is already
set and the energy doesn't come into the
embryo until the third month. I mean,
those are just peculiarities, you know.
Don't ask me why the sun, the moon, and
the stars are there. It's just that's
the way it is.
Does it mean anything? thing I don't see
that really means anything one way or
the other. Does it?
It means you got less to worry about.
It's good news in case you didn't. Oh,
it's good news.
All right.
There are people who have very um severe
karmic difficulties,
age population people, all that.
Um
we said that the the visible world of
form is a world of effects. It is not a
world of cause.
What we see materializing is that which
is held in consciousness then taking
form.
The Empire State Building was born in
imagination of the its creator. One day
he's smoking his pipe. He put his feet
up and he said, "Wow, what about the
tallest building in the world right here
on 33rd Street or 32nd,
whatever it is,
out of that vision, out of that
intention, out of that um
aro arose the Empire State Building. But
you see, the Empire State Building was
the outcropping into the physical domain
of that which already pre-existed in
mind. It was consciousness that
conceived of it as inspirational,
symbolic,
uh provided enormous work during the
depression.
Um,
so the Empire State Building, which
curiously enough calibrates at 425,
which is better than the Holy Lands, who
calibrated 130 or something,
you're better meditating
on the 76th floor of the Empire State
Building than you are in,
for some reason, the 102nd floor
calibrates higher than than the 70. What
what is the main uh get off you? 764 or
forget no
864. Anyway, you can take the low
elevator go up to 102nd. For some
peculiar reason, 102nd floor caliber is
higher than the than the lower
observation point. I don't know why
I spoke of the they asked me about the
third eye. The third eye is an esoteric
sort of occult reference
to the chakra system. It means spiritual
discernment.
It means one intuitively sees the
difference between that which is aligned
with God and that which is not.
It's a knowingness that comes on without
any thinkingness.
As you read an apology for evil, you
just know that it's out. Its integrity
is out. You just know its integrity is
out. You can go back with the intellect
and find out why you think it's out, but
it's a knowingness.
It's at first glance you can tell what
they're up to. Huh? It's like intuition.
It's an awareness.
The ability to discern truth from
falsehood is the huge lack of mankind.
Mankind has not evolved to the point of
spiritual awareness that he could tell
at a glance whether a thing is integrous
or not integrous.
That's why he was warned against the
wolf and sheep's clothing. What Jesus
said is you don't have the capacity of
spiritual discernment because your
evolution is not high enough that the
third eye is not open in you. Because
the third eye is not open in you, you
need spiritual masters to tell you the
difference.
You of your own self do not have the
capacity.
The consciousness level of mankind is
into the spleen and the solar plexus
killing and rapacious greed and
hunginess. It finally gets up into the
capacity for lovingness. It gets up to
the capacity for creativity and
talkingness. But spiritual awareness,
the opening of the third eye comes
belatedly late.
By that time many um spiritual aspirants
made some serious mistakes.
This is why we say stick with that which
every mystic throughout every
enlightened being throughout time has
described as truth and don't vary from
it.
Straight and narrow is the path.
There are many carnivals going on on the
side.
esoteric,
other dimensions,
things that are peculiar and unique,
things that sound bizarre.
Think about it. If it sounds bizarre,
you know why? Cuz it's bizarre.
I don't know.
Strange
people get strange messages and then
they start strange belief systems and
they seem to lack no there's no der of
followers. They will follow the most
bizarre and crazy things you can even
imagine. They're still waiting out in
the desert for the UFO to pick them up.
You know what I mean?
Did Jesus Christ say that? The Buddha
say it? Does Krishna say it? Did any of
the great enlightened spiritual masters
of all time say anything about that? No.
Did they say go home and do numerology
and do the
eching and do the tarot cards and get a
channeling from master honky donk on the
other side?
Jesus said, "That's the way I realized
God was I got a channeling from Master
Honky Punk and he told me to park out
there and wait for the UFOs to pick me
up
and he meantime eat nothing but grass."
And I must cross my toes 14 times a day
over hickory nuts. I mean, the bizarre
crap that people believe, they haul into
my office and they mail it to me and I
say,
"Oh, boy.
Straight and narrow is the way."
You don't need anything peculiar. You
don't need anything bizarre.
You don't need anything unique.
All of mankind is in agreement on
certain basic facts. It's so obvious
that you really have to be quite
resistant to not see it. H and then pick
some peculiar little excuse. So the
people who pick these peculiar
deviations from spiritual truth are
really resisting God. It's really a way
of avoiding uh the truth is what what it
is
and they use it as an excuse you know
excuse.
So the third eye then is the capacity
for spiritual discernment.
To me, wickedness is to prey upon the
innocence of the naivity
and distort their capacity to perceive
truth.
That's my definition of wickedness.
s to seduce the innocent
and brainwash them into believing
that which is non-intigorous
to serve your own selfish ends.
That is perversion,
degeneracy.
So, the Astral Circus is out there
waiting for you
and Sedona is right around the corner.
You get an oral reading within a block
of I'll tell you that somebody will
throw the cards for you. Do the ruins.
Throw the throw the They'll throw
something.
Sheep kneebones.
Hey, let's start a school of sheep
kneebones. the sacred sheep kneebones.
Then we can go how it goes back to
ancient Ebiscinia and and manufacture a
whole trip. See?
All right. Um, so the true spiritual
work is more mundane. Sounds mundane.
Doesn't sound exciting, does it? Not
like getting a psychic reading. You know
what I mean?
Psychic reading is so narcissistically
fun. You sit there hearing all about
you.
Tell me about me.
I see you were walking there with the
oxen and then your mother-in-law and you
struck her in the head and then you came
back as a night of the Wow, man. What an
entrancing story.
We even have pet psychics to get up.
We'll take we'll take Kitty for a
reading, honey.
She was once a cat for Queen Nefertiti.
I see that.
Then she ate one of the sacred mice and
had to come back as a
What about love, romance, and sex? Yes,
we don't talk much about that.
First time it's come up.
What is the um part of romantic love,
sexuality, etc. And how would this
affect sages etc.
Well, in the book I'm just finishing, we
do track uh the evolution of man's kind
of consciousness.
It had nothing to do with love for a
long time. It had to do with mating. Had
to do with animal nature. Had to do with
um
I was going to say recreation,
procreation.
The to the story of Estrogeni and
Testeri
Jeie was sitting there one time.
She was just around like an egg
and Teseroni came waggling after her.
Something about you, baby just makes me
wag my tail. I don't know.
Oh god.
One thing we say it's popular. You can
see the population explosion witnesses
the success of Estadrini and Tester
and their love story. Whale love didn't
arise until very recently
in the animal kingdom. You see mating
and then he doesn't want anything to do
with her.
You know what and leave them is the
phrase we use nowadays. And
so the lion after he's done with her, he
takes off and she's got to really
protect the cubs because uh the male
lion will come back and eat him.
So we don't see love in the beginning of
mankind. In the early times of mankind,
even romantic love wasn't there. There
was matingness.
It was late in evolution that romantic
love begins to appear. only a couple
hundred years ago.
The lives of men and women were quite
different. He went out to war and
and get drunk and kill people and be a
hero. She she stayed home and took care
of the hearth and nurtured the babies.
But they didn't really hang out
together. They had nothing in common.
You know what's with babies and cooking
porridge? That's not too cool when he
can be out with the guys hunting the
boores and being a hero, getting notches
on his belt for infidels that he's
killed, etc.
Well, compared to the glories of war,
home life is pretty mundane. So, it
didn't really hang out there.
In fact, love itself didn't really
appear until we see maternal love. So,
love didn't appear until you see the
nurturance of the mother
for the newborn, the mother bird for the
So, survival then depended on the
emergence of love. The dinosaur doesn't
love. It just lays its egg, covers them
up, and takes off. If they survive, they
survive. Had no interest in the matter
whatsoever.
So, we don't see the beginning of love
until we see the maternal instinct.
We could say, well, it served the
survival.
And that's negating the value of a thing
uh by looking at it from
the viewpoint of a projected
intentionality.
What we saw is the beginning of
caringness. Caringness,
caringness in the form of protection and
nurturing.
So that was the emergence of love. We
did not see it in the cold-blooded
reptilian world. You don't see it in the
world of snakes. You don't see it in the
amphibians.
It begins to emerge and it really
emerges in full flower in the mamlian
world with suckling and the mamlon
bonding that goes on. There you see the
beginning of caringness, caressingness,
playfulness.
You see the emergence of love now in the
animal kingdom.
And all of you have cats and dogs and
all are witnessed to the intense
maternalness that can take place. The
mother
cat takes the little kittens and she
jeopardizes her own life, jumps off the
roof and carries her little kitten over
to a safe. That's one of my favorite
pictures. It's out of Life magazine 1986
or something showing this mother with a
little kitten in its mouth and she's
jeopardizing her own life. One mistake
and she's a dead cat. uh to get her
little kitten safely from this roof to a
tree.
So you see the nurturance then of life
beginning to evolve. As time went on,
the matingness between man and woman now
began to take on a different
characteristic.
For a long time, the woman was only
valued for her sexual capacity to
sexually satisfy the male and give him
airs. But she as a person wasn't really
that much of anything. She was just a
concubine
uh a canubial uh pleasure and she had no
great value in and of herself. Men and
women didn't hang out together. He
devalued her. She stewed the pot and all
that. But it was him that went on and
brought home the bear. You know what I'm
saying? And fought the enemies and
conquered the the enemies. So he was the
important one and she was just sort of
the aftermath.
Repopulating the population was really
sort of accidental.
How many uh real guys from those days
you say gee I want to have about four
kids like for what?
No the kids came about and then you
learn to love them.
So we see nurturance but you still don't
see romance.
Romance doesn't come along until about
the time of heraldry. Well, it comes you
see it in ancient Greece and all but uh
the the role of women her status she now
becomes loved for her own sake. She
becomes the equal man.
The woman learned to trade sex for
affection.
She learned to begin to barter. I'm not
going to stay with you unless you're
going to marry me unless you're She
learned to bargain permanency for his
temporary gratification.
And with it, of course, ensure the
survival of the species, the long-term
uh family unit.
Only a couple hundred years ago, people
didn't get married for love. And
certainly in the upper classes, they
didn't get married for love. They got
married for political convenience, for
the alliance of nations, for the unity
of fortunes.
Many parts of the world uh you know your
wife or your your spouse is picked out
for you by your parents and it has to do
with family, money, uh has nothing to do
with romantic love. Romantic love is a
very recent invention.
It's amazing to think that romantic love
is a very recent invention because we
watch it every night on television. We
say of but of course Hollywood's version
of it etc.
But when we look back in history we see
it didn't really exist very long
in the day of heraldry the of chivalry
and feudal times. The knight went out to
slay the enemy
and she gave him a flower. You see, she
gave him the symbol of the value of
femininity.
He then wore that close to his heart.
Now his life was different.
Now his life took on a greater
significance.
Now he wasn't just fighting to be the
hero
but
for the feminine.
So the feminine then really came into
its own,
honored, revered, respected, cherished
and became what we know it how we know
it in today's society
in which that
perception prevails in those who are you
might say more conscious and evolved.
The woman is eval is loved for her
spirit for her inner
self and her sexuality is also valued
as an expression of
her beauty as an expression.
So sexuality then becomes a mode of
expressing
first of all of physicality
because the physical body is a
derivative
of the animal evolution of the
animalness.
Testosterone
still runs the world, repopulates it
and is in my view it is big its biggest
downside.
The biggest difficulty
of human life is testosterone.
Don't quote me, but that's a fact.
It's testosterone that sends all these
idiots out there to kill infidels. To
prove that you're a hero, to slay the
enemy, to prove your worth,
to overpop populate the world to the
point of starvation of whole there's
whole continents that overpop populate
themselves right into absolute
starvation and poverty.
They're on TV every night. the guy with
no job and eight kids and his wife's
pregnant and they're only in their 30s.
They're only in their 30s and they're up
to kid eight.
Now the problem is testosterone
behind all killing savagery.
The Japanese slaughtered all the Chinese
and then king killed 30,000 innocent
people just for the glee of killing.
Just for the glee of killing.
H
so
man ow owns owes his survival to
testosterone
and he owes
ow owes about 90% of his pain to the
same testosterone
and learning how to handle one's
testosterone is the most difficult part
of being a male.
It's also a very difficult part of being
a female
handling his testosterone and
now they find that women need some
testosterone of their own and or else
they got complaints to the doctor you
know.
So how to balance that? How to envision
that? How to keep it in balance?
Therefore, love leads to
uh the capacity for
reverence
for that which is intrinsic and innate
within the spirit of one's
partner.
Can be more than one partner. You can
certainly love many in a lifetime.
So that's part of the evolution of human
consciousness to come out of matingness
into maternal survival
into servitude to the male then
embargoning that servitude for
commitment
then transcending that to
romance. Huh?
Is romance based on first an illusion
and then the illusion wears off and now
you both look raggedy because you see
how it is?
Or was the love reality? Which is which?
Huh?
I always think it's the opposite the way
the world sees it. I think when you
first see that person and flash on them,
that's reality.
That's not illusion. The world says,
"Well, that's illusion." No, that's
reality. You get who they really are
because the naked self is
love itself. You see what they are
and you fall instantly in love with that
energy within them. Then as time goes
on, the ego raises its ugly head and
begins to demean it.
But in the beginning, you really saw
them as they were. You saw their
incredible perfection and beauty.
and stunning handsomeness or whatever it
is that attracted you to that person.
Then the ego comes up with its
self-interest and selfishness and it's
your fault and blame and you forgot the
forks. You ruined the picnic. You forgot
the forks.
You always blame me for everything.
Well, why shouldn't I? You aren't to the
blame for everything all the time.
Yeah, but you're to blame for blaming
me.
You're to blame for blaming me for
blaming you. And there it goes downhill.
So you have to draw back once in a while
and see what was the reality I saw.
It is still there. Of course it's still
there. Of course it's still there.
recapture the love and reverence which
you have for each other's existence.
On the log of calibrated level of
consciousness, we list emotions. Some
are very high and yet and some are
lesser. We got the wrong one on again.
Anyway, how can that be? So, it's become
diff different aspects of our
personality are at different levels. Our
personalities are complex. It's not just
one uni un unitized
uh singularity. It's a complexity. We're
the composite of all our identifications
as we grew up. All the people that
impress us that we wanted to be like the
ego ideal
uh various influences, teachers, people
of inspiration in our life. Uh so we
have different aspects of our
personality at different levels of
emotional development. One aspect of us
can be quite evolved and another quite
childish.
You know the healer in us could be quite
evolved.
The teacher in us, the musician,
the stalwart,
the hero.
Most of us go through lifetimes where we
perfect different aspects.
The warrior
uh and some we recall as you go ahead in
consciousness you begin to intuit it
you know how you got to be that way and
you begin to even start to remember it.
I mean you know very well you did such
and such or you wouldn't be the way you
are about that particular thing. is like
a knowingness begins to take over and
you begin to remember.
So one's overall level of consciousness
could be quite high and still an
emotionality could come up. Well, where
does that emotionality coming out of?
It's probably coming out of the persona.
You know, the persona is that
superficial level of your personality
which is not really what you are. You
know, somebody cuts in you in traffic
and you say, "I got to kill that guy."
Well, you don't really mean that. If I
give you a gun now, say you're going to
kill him and I'm just talking. So,
there's those superficial emotional
reactions, but that isn't who you are.
Who you are is based on your spiritual
decisions.
It's your spiritual the spiritual will.
So, level of consciousness denotes
spiritual decision and will and
alignment. If you are aligned with that
which supports life and supports
integrity and supports that which
respects the sacred and reverences life,
you are in a very high place. Annoyances
will come up, but they don't mean
anything. And don't forget, we're a
karmic inheritance of all the
weirdos that live before this lifetime.
So those little memories come up. I
think sometimes they come up to be
healed, to be recognized, to be
acknowledged
and become they keep us from becoming
egotistical that we're still capable of
making mistakes. Keeps us from being
holier than now. It keeps us from being
judgmental about the sheer humanness of
other people.
and uh compassionate.
Um,
do we have to suffer for what the
dinosaurs did? Well,
some of these reverse cause and effect.
You see, events in the world are the
consequence of what happens in
consciousness. Somebody says, "Well,
what would happen to the consciousness
of mankind if we had a war now?"
Nothing.
Because there's consciousness of mankind
where it is now that would manifest as
war.
It isn't the other way around. So, World
War II did not alter the level of
consciousness of mankind at all. It was
expressing where it was at at the time
that the great majority of the people
would go for what was sold to them.
Well, if consciousness is below 200,
it's pretty easy to sell it that which
is non- integrous.
Don't forget the great avatar said,
"Your third eye is not open yet. You for
your own sake do not know the thing.
That which is good and that which is
wicked between truth and falsehood.
Therefore, you need the guru. You need
the teacher. You need the great avatar.
You need the savior.
until consciousness reaches the third
eye and the Buddha body opens up and
it's clear that which is wicked and that
which is not wicked.
I think we should take a break because
I'm getting uh work out here folks.
You know, this is a great spiritual
group and I love being here and they
come up with all these wonderful
thoughts and uh
I thank you for all the questions. We'll
take a break and then
we'll answer some more some more
questions and then we'll greet people
and sign books and all.
I wasn't done with sexuality.
Oh yeah.
Sexuality like money are things that
every and eating meat are are the three
traditional things that everybody has to
go through when you become a spiritual
aspirin. What about eating meat? What
about sex? What about money? You know,
Ramach Krishna handle it easily. He said
they're all forbidden.
So I decided not to become a Rama
Krishna devote at an early age.
He only took young men. You weren't
allowed to touch money and have sex.
Right? Okay.
Sex like money mean we're talking about
attachments to be run by something to be
run by desires. So sex and money are no
different than any other thing. Um,
desiring this attachment is the same to
what you're attached is really
irrelevant. Whether it's sex or money
doesn't really make any difference.
There is a point in spiritual
development where the the energy begin
the energy of life begins to rise
through the chakras and there may be a
surprising period of life when sex just
sort of drives you crazy. You feel like
hypersexual.
It's because the energy of life which is
rising as it rises energizes each chakra
including the base chakra and of course
then it gets to the heart and love
becomes more predominant. It then it
gets to the third eye and then you're
done with all that but
it's that you're not run by it.
We see you sneaking in late.
It's not being run by it. So the freedom
to enjoy one's biologic heritage of
course is part of the joy of being a
human being. Part of the expression of
the joy of life, the exuberance of life
and um to not be entrapped by it. That's
all. The same with money. We can have
money or not have money. It's all the
same. It's really all the same. Whether
you have lots of it or you don't have
any of it, it's all the same.
You can be very, very rich on Monday,
leave it all on Tuesday, and life is
really not different at all. You're
driving down the highway enjoying life,
and there's the birds and the bees, and
nothing's changed.
Not a thing has changed.
So, it's the attachment to it, the being
run by it. It's okay to have it. It's
okay to not have it.
Somebody asked about sexuality. The sage
at that point, one has just transcended
it. You can either have it or not have
it. That's like money or sex is is it's
great when you have it and it's great
when you don't have it. If you've got a
wonderful dinner cooked for for for
dinner tonight, it's fantastic. And if
you have peanut butter sandwiches, it's
all the same. You know what I mean? So,
the enjoyment of life comes out of the
joy of one's existence from every
moment, not from anything that's out
there. There's nothing out there that
can give you joy. The only thing
something out there can do is satisfy
the desiringness is blocking the
experience of joy. So when you satisfy
that, what happens is that which is
blocking the experience of your own
inner self is removed. Now you feel the
radiance of your own inner self coming
forth as joy and happiness.
You think that the happiness is coming
from the thing you just got. No, the
thing that you just got. shut up that
which was interfering with the
experience of the joy of the presence of
the self within. There's only one source
of joy and that's the presence of God
within.
It's periodically experienced. If you
ascribe
causation to out thereess, then you get
attached to out there.
If the only time you feel joyful is a
sexual conquest, then you get attached
to the out there of it all, the same as
with drugs or any other addiction or
attachment. To be free of it means it's
okay if you have it and it's okay if you
don't. If you have hamburgers, hot dogs,
or peanut butter sandwiches,
it doesn't make any difference because
it's all
the source of joy is eventually
continuous. The sure of joy comes from
the awareness of the source of your own
existence. The presence of God within
you gives you a certain radiance to
one's inner experience.
The inner experience of one's own
existence itself becomes continuously
joyful.
So it doesn't matter what you do out
there. If they say today you die, you
say, "Man, fantastic.
Been looking forward to this for a
lifetime." You know what I'm saying?
You remember going out of body, man? It
was cool. So in other words, everything,
no matter what happens, is fine. They
say you're not dying today. You say,
"Oh, fantastic. I can enjoy another day
of staying alive." Either way, it's all
the same.
Uh,
one surreners the source of joy
from out there to the awareness that its
source is only from within. That comes
about through spiritual evolution.
That makes you independent of such
experiences. If they happen, it's great.
And if they don't happen, it's great.
There's a lot of why questions.
Never ask why.
Why? Because
you understand why is the hypothetical.
The why of anything is the hypothetical.
Why is man what he is? Why is God what
he is? Why does the spirit only come in
the embryo in the third month? Why do a
whole lot of people die in one big
disaster?
You see it's a mind game. Why is a mind
game?
You cannot understand the nonlinear
spiritual reality
from the limitation of Newtonian
paradigm and logic.
The linear cannot explain the nonlinear.
The stretching of it to try to make it
do so ends up with a serious
distortion of spiritual vision.
It's a pseudo explanation
and it's not a reality. It does not ring
true. As plausible as it may sound, it
is not the whess of it.
There are no wise in spiritual reality.
You see the endlessness of why.
I can add any thought, any observation
throughout all of human history and
prefix it with why.
Why the revolution? Why World War II?
Why human beings? Why whites, blacks,
and colors and various hues that we come
in? Why blondes and brunettes? Why blue
eyes and brown eyes? Why two feet? Why
not four feet? You know, why anything?
Why is a question for idiots?
comes from a total insanity.
There is no why to anything, folks.
There's only what is. It is that way.
God doesn't know why either.
God is a giant electromagnetic field
about all this and all this is twizzing
around in there. And you ask him why.
How the heck did I know? It's just the
way it is.
I am what I am and therefore everything
is the way it is and that's sufficient
right
you surrender your will to God you don't
need a why you just accept the isness of
what appears to be and then later on you
find out what appears to be isn't that
way anyway so
for instance why do these various things
in the Bible calibrated this and this I
don't know why
the Old Testament there's three books
that calibrate over 200
Why don't the others? How the hell did I
know? I didn't write the I didn't write
the Old Testament. You know what I mean?
I don't know what this says. Something
about still small voices. I don't know.
And are they speaking about children?
I don't know what it means. Well, the
knowingness of spiritual awareness, I
think, is what they're referring to.
Yes. Yes. Because the knowingness of
spiritual awareness comes about as a
knowingness, a different style of
learning. You see, because of schooling,
we think of linear progressive
schooling. third grade, fourth grade, we
think of of it as a linear progression.
Spiritual knowingness, learningness is
totally different. It comes out of
nothing at all and
and becomes obvious
with no intercert stages. It isn't like
you see a little bit here on Monday.
Wednesday it gets a little clearer.
Friday, ah, now I see it. It's you work
on it over the weekend and Monday you
got it down pat.
No, you're riding a horse and you're
worried about your rump
and all of a sudden it's clear to you
why something is why it is. It's an
idiotic question. So
the still small voice is sort of a
knowingness.
When we were talking about karma, we
said, you know, it's a belief system to
some people. It's not a belief system.
Forget about it.
Forget about karma. Just forget about
it.
It's easier if you know something about
it. But if you know anything about it,
it'll still work out.
May take you a couple hundred thousand
lifetimes more, but it'll work out.
See, because the western world without
the awareness of karma doesn't
understand that every single thought,
move, decision has a consequence.
Has a consequence.
Not a punishment, not not something
negative and horrible, but everything
you do has a consequence whether you
like it or not.
Now the idiot says why?
Because that's the nature of the
universe that everything that happens
has a consequence to the totality of the
whole. See, as we've explained it before
and the whole universe, this this
planet's here and this planet's here.
Now, this planet's being here does not
cause this planet to be here. But if
this planet wasn't here, this planet
wouldn't be where it is.
Each one of us affects the totality of
you might say the density of the whole
as a consequence of which the buoyancy
of all of us is affected.
So each spirit each soul is like a cork
in the sea and as it makes these choices
it rises and falls depending on
its choices the size of the cork and the
density of the sea.
Mhm. Here's
some things I didn't ask about. I'll do
that sometime when I'm home privately.
Uh there's questions about channeling.
You know, some people think that when I
talk I'm channeling. Somebody will say,
"Where do you channel it from?"
In channeling there's a this and a that.
There's a me and a you or this and an
it.
There's two different entities.
Um
channeling to me is risky because you
don't know what's on the other side and
what level of other another dimension
it's coming from. Lower astral, middle,
higher or celestial. You have no idea
unless you're pretty good at
kinesiologic calibration and you can
calibrate the energy of that entity on
the other side. If it was a really high
entity, it wouldn't be doing any
channeling in the first place
cuz no need to control. I'll tell you
something about this world. All the
spiritual information you'll ever need
has already been spoken.
There is nothing more needed than what
has been said. Even what has been said
this day, there's nothing more needed.
Consequently, to search elsewhere is a
way of evading spiritual reality,
spiritual truth.
You don't need a strange name on the
other side telling you weird things.
Yeah. And a lot of it is weird. I'll
tell you, you don't need strange beings
elsewhere.
Don't trust anything unless it's in a
body. Unless you can see it or unless
it's been in the body.
The spiritual real the spiritual truth
that need that the that the human being
needs has already been spoken. Nothing
more is needed. It was spoken thousands
of years ago.
Nothing more is needed.
The course of miracles came about in a
rather unique way. I I knew uh Bill and
I knew uh Helen.
Helen herself, you know, didn't really
believe in the course of miracles. It
was strange. You know, Helen was the
secretary.
She said she got it through inner
dictation. It was not some other entity
elsewhere. She didn't hear it from
elsewhere. It came about as an inner
knowingness.
which came about due to a prior
agreement before she came in this
lifetime. She agreed to take the
interdictation. She called it
interdictation. It came as a progressive
unfolding of a knowingness in a lady who
I will tell you and she would not be
insulted if she were in the audience
right now had about this much spiritual
awareness.
How of that dimension could get such an
incredible uh language of truth is is
mindboggling. But that was her
agreement. She said, "I agreed to be the
um it was innerdictation
came about as a strange form of an inner
knowingness apparently by contract I
would suppose by somebody in some
celestial realm. That would be my
presumption.
sure she herself didn't live by it and
was uh
a different kind of person.
Bill on the other hand, Bill Feford who
worked with her on getting it into
written form was pretty heart kind of a
person, you know.
So it was just she her commitment was to
be the secretary and it just came to her
like an inner dictation and that she
just typed it out as it came into her
head. A rather incredible piece of work
to get in that mode of of uh
transmission. I don't know if anything
else has really been transmitted that
way. But of course I don't read a lot of
things. In fact I don't read anything to
be truthful with you. So I can't be an
expert on that. But uh I did know Helen
and um I knew her quite well. So anyway,
that's how it came about and all we know
is that it calibrates at 600 and that
those who have followed it have
experienced the experiential truth that
lies behind it.
Um
this is another u these are all why
questions. They're coming from some kind
of a why person.
And the person who's addicted to
whininess
who may remain anonymous.
Quiness will lead you downward rather
than upward. It will lead you to greater
and greater illusion.
Because if there is no legitimate answer
to why, the mind will create a facious
one and your mind will be filled with
facious answers to wise. A why is
hypothetical. That which is hypothetical
has no existence in reality.
>> Would you like to answer this?
>> Okay.
>> That which is the hypothetical does not
exist in the real existence. All right.
Okay. You got it. The hypothetical does
not exist in the real. Therefore, you
cannot make spiritual progress by asking
the question why. You can only go
downward into further and further
illusion
because the ego will manufacture an
answer to the why in order to maintain
its hold of your mind. You have to let
go of being addicted to the whess.
The way to get rid of whessiness is to
surrender not knowingness to God.
To become enlightened, you don't have to
know anything.
the willingness to surrender oneself to
God from moment to moment. You don't
have to know anything. There's not a
single why you need to know. Not a one.
Can na karma be nullified?
>> Yeah. 50 bucks.
Write
a check. It's my favorite charity.
That's the way it's done in some places
in this world. Has been traditionally.
Write a check.
Well, we make fun of it, but the writing
of a check is one way that one can and
it's traditionally done to people who've
made great sums of money and become
philanthropic as they got older.
Some people think they're buying trying
to buy their way in heaven. No, it can.
I think it can be legitimate. You begin
to realize that you do owe the world
something back for what it has given
you.
So, it can be more than just gift. It
can also be the real dawning of a
spiritual awareness
because as you get into your 80s, you
begin to realize you really ought to get
serious about this spiritual business.
When they start trying to sell you
burial insurance you get every day in
the mail.
Well, maybe I'll go back to church after
all. I mean, what's to lose? You know
why? Oh, here's another why question.
Why do cathedrals calibrate highly?
Well, we can't answer that.
No, this is really asking, do inanimate
objects, are they calibratable? Yes,
they are. You can calibrate the energy
of locations, people, inventions,
thoughts, feelings. this um structure
here.
Don't forget the intention, spiritual
intention is what sets the level of
consciousness. So the spiritual
intention to glorify God and reflect God
and worship God and to provide a place
for others to worship and acknowledge
the sovereignty of God.
uh the great cathedral then it
represents the collective inspiration of
a whole society, a whole civilization.
Some of those cathedrals are so costly
it really took the earnings of the
entire population for generations to
create it.
Great sacrifice,
whole lifetime spent in worshiping God
by devotion in the form of service. You
might say karma yoga to haul all those
blocks of marble
in the hot sun
for the sake of the glorification of God
in itself is quite a spiritual
act is it not?
So the cathedrals are
the coalition of the concordance of
multiple art forms
uh painting, sculpture, architecture,
music, incense, stained glass windows,
the design of the floors, as you know,
the design of the floors, the way the
squares are set, etc. The mosaic etc.
The Alhhamra which is uh not Christian
the Mhamra calibrates very high anything
that's that represents the collective
devotion of mankind
to reflect the reality of divinity as
best can it can be reflected within our
human domain is respectful worshipful
and sacred.
Then it becomes sanctified by the
prayers of those who have worshiped
there over the
many years. And some of the cathedral, I
mean, I've been in cathedrals that have
been there a thousand years. For a
thousand years, mankind has been on
their knees thanking God,
worshiping God.
And
if not sacred to begin with, they are
certainly sacred by now.
Thousands and thousands of pilgrims over
a thousand years have worshiped there
and they worship with incense
and the beauty of incredible music. The
music that we play here
speaks to me of the presence of God. It
calibrates
740 somewhere around in there. 700
to recognize.
The first way that most people can
recognize God is through beauty. Through
beauty and love. Maternal love is the
first experience you have of God.
You think it's your mother, but it's God
coming through your mother as in the
expressionist maternal love, but it's
your first experience of God.
The joy of life of adolescence is again
the joy of life
is another chance to experience the
presence of God.
And then if one is fortunate, one is
sensitive to beauty and you go into
exquisite states
in nature or in music.
the great moment in music that raises
the hair on the back of your head and or
breaks makes you break forth in tears.
It's not the music. It's the presence of
God as the beauty of music.
So beauty is one of the pathways to God.
And all people spiritually evolved
people appreciate beauty. On the other
hand, they're not attached to it.
You can be just as happy in a wood cabin
as you can in a cathedral.
There's less housework.
Keeping a cathedral neat and clean is a
problem. Huh.
So
um
this is a question about the difference
between power and force which I think we
did cover in the first lecture but we'll
recapitulate.
Power
accomplishes what it does without
intending to by virtue of being what it
is.
Gravity has no intention to lift a
a nail from the floor. I mean magnetism
has no intention of doing that. Gravity
has no intention of pulling an apple out
of the tree.
Gravity, magnetism, the electrostatic
field, the infinite universe
are immensely powerful by virtue of that
which they are.
All they have to do is be there.
Mahatma Gandhi stood there all 90 pounds
of them and defeated the British Empire.
He calibrated 700 at the time and the
British Empire calibrated 178 or 185 or
something.
All Mahatma Gandhi had to do was just
sit there and not eat. And the British
Empire was defeated.
He didn't have to do anything. Gandhi
did not fire a shot.
So power accomplishes effortlessly by
virtue of that which it is. You don't
have to feed it energy. It radiates
energy.
It accomplishes
by virtue of the quality of that which
it is. It doesn't do anything. It
doesn't have any intention.
Those are all coming out of presumption
of the human ego and projected which we
see happening with God.
We see that happening to the image of
God throughout time. All kinds of
foibless and fallacies of the human ego
are projected onto God such as why
questions.
Gravity is what it is and it's immensely
powerful. It does it for millions and
billions of eons without wearing itself
out.
Eon after eon, the universe in its
immense power determines.
Doesn't determine by intention,
but is that which
is the why of it all.
The why of it all is the is of it all.
So power then does what it does by
virtue of its quality.
I mean yes force is something else.
Force goes from here to there. Force
wears itself out. Force as we know from
physics creates counterforce. This side
arms and gets a militia. Automatically
they get a militia. They get ballistic
missiles. They get bombs. They get
atomic bombs and so it escalates.
The Middle East is we shoot you, you
shoot us, then we shoot you, you shoot
us, then you shoot us and we shoot you.
Sort of. So what?
But that's the nature of the game. So
force then exhausts itself. It's
limited. The bullet eventually exhausts
itself because as it goes through the
air, the air creates a counterforce. All
force exhausts itself. The British I
mean the Holy Roman Empire was the
greatest empire that ever existed
as far as length and success and
eventually it just exhausted itself and
the Roman Empire
uh collapsed.
The next great empire was the British
Empire. Ruled a quarter of the people of
the earth.
And when I was young, the thought that
the British Empire could ever come to an
end was not even thinkable.
The British Empire was infinitely
powerful, the greatest navy on earth,
etc. And the crown would consent
continue forever, but it didn't.
Still all that is based on force.
It expends itself, destroys itself. You
have to constantly stoke it. You have to
pour money, more bodies, more slaves,
more energy, more taxes. It dissipates
itself.
The value of spiritual work is that it
takes you out of force into as you go
above 200,
it's not what you do anymore that has
the effect on your life and what
happens. It's what you become.
The very fact that you are there already
changes the nature of the event.
You don't even have to say anything. I
know meetings I've been to where there
was one guy used to sit over in the
corner. He never said anything for
years.
One day he was missing.
I miss this guy who' been sitting there
for years saying nothing.
So obviously his presence was be
speaking something on some in some other
dimension of significance.
People who are more spiritually evolved
than have an effect that radiates out
from them that is invisible, not
discernable, not logical, not traceable.
But the very fact that you are there
already changes the events. It the whole
field changes due to your presence, due
to your prayers, due to your conscious
awareness, due to your inclusion of them
into your thoughts. It already changes
it.
Now, a force cannot prevail against
power.
Why? Because power is invincible.
There's nothing you can do to change the
field of gravity.
You can throw billions of pounds of iron
and steel into the atmosphere and
gravity doesn't change one iota.
The infinite power of God is totally
unaffected by anything that occurs
within the universe.
Love is indestructible.
True love is indestructible.
The lower levels then are ones of force,
violence,
coercion,
therefore of revolt.
How one country can take over another
country with a different language and a
different culture and a different
nationality and a different language and
think they can succeed over long periods
of time is unbelievable.
They aren't you and they're never going
to be you.
And they're never going to accept you're
ruling them. They have a different
color, a different language, different
meaning, different terminology,
different history. How can one country
think it's going to succeed in capturing
another country?
Obviously, it's it's time limited. It's
not yours. Doesn't belong to you. So,
force will not succeed over the long
term.
Force will not succeed over the long
term. If force were more successful than
power, England never would have survived
World War II.
The greatest war machine the world has
ever seen
arose out of an energy of 10 and
whatever it was Hitler was at the time
and it was stood off by Winston
Churchill who calibrated at 510.
It was Britain didn't have a chance
until 510 came up and began to speak for
Britain.
We will fight from the fields. We will
fight from the ditches. We will never
surrender.
510 then was
with a very small air force was up
against the biggest military machine the
world's ever seen
and survived. It did only because of 510
leading the country.
510 was leading the country.
Neville Chamberlain was like 170 or
something. with Neville Chamberlain
Britain would have lost.
So that which has power then energizes
all around it.
That's it energizes all around it.
It radiates forth without limitation.
It doesn't run out of energy. That which
is power is inexhaustible
because it deres its power from
the power of the truth God's truth. You
know
it the source of
power is the truth of the presence of
God. So its source is continuous ongoing
and inexhaustible.
one can keep going forever.
Uh so that's sort of a summary of
difference between
well I've been speaking about it says
please speak about the nature of the
soul. Well, that's what I'm talking
about all day, right?
Beneath thinking this, beneath
feelingness, belief, all ideology,
beneath all of form is that which is
nonform. That which you call me, the
self.
If I take off one leg, you're still me.
If I take off another leg, you're still
me. If I take off an ear, you're still
me. The mirror is not the the me is not
the physical body because we can remove
it piece by piece and you'll still say
I'm me.
Donovan's brain sitting there on things
is I'm still me.
The sense of self then is independent of
physicality.
To know that you know you're not the
physical body.
The sense of self does not change with
thinkingness.
Certainly with as as one gets older,
one's thinking this can totally change
about just about everything. And yet the
sense of I the self is not changed. The
otman, the self, the self with a capital
S.
It seems strange to Christian tradition
to call the presence of God within self
with a capital S.
sounds strange and somewhat foreign to
those who are familiar with foreign
spirit to literature. It is not strange
but to people with a Christian
background it seems strange to call
the s the center of the core of one's
existence
self with a capital S
soul is more acceptable
to experience one's soul then one's
eternal soul as the one's reality would
become closer to common Christian
thinking
As the as the awareness as the reality
unfolds,
there's no difference between that which
you are. There is no difference between
God imminent and God transcendent. Those
are just styles of languaging.
That which is the source of one's own
existence is not different than that
which is the source and the essence of
all of
the universe throughout all of time.
That's the first stunning awareness that
one ever even worried about this about
life seems like the ultimate joke. How
one could have forgotten such an
stunning and obvious reality is rather
startling.
Um,
a lot of funny questions.
um that which shines forth that which
shines forth and gives one a sense of
reality. You see you you accept a sense
of reality of your experience without
question.
Why should you experience that which you
experience as reality?
Is there something out there that would
give it a special sense of reality?
You see how you just assume that as a
given?
That which you're looking for is that
which you overlook because you assume it
as a given. That which you assume as a
given is exactly that which you're
trying to find.
It's like you're so used to living in
space that you fail to recognize space
anymore. You just take space for
granted.
It's miraculous
that one can experience
anything. It's miraculous to have the
capacity to experience.
Does a rock experience?
To be conscious, to be aware, to
experience one's own existence
is already a rather incredible event.
But we take it for granted.
But once one grasps the significance of
that, you realize
to exist and be aware that you exist is
miraculous.
The miracle of one's own existence
of the Lord I am.
Without God, you would not exist in it.
And the source of one's existence is not
different than the core of that which
you are.
So the soul cannot be not God. It can
only be part and parcel of all that
exists
in a particular
expression.
Somebody says, "How can you read without
eyeglasses?" Oh, well that was a funny
one, too.
Yeah, I think I told the story about the
eyeglasses. You know, I had trifogals
and bifogals and I was the squinty kid.
I couldn't see the football coming till
it hit me in the nose. So, I was not a
great football player.
I didn't see it till it was there
already. And uh
I think it was a result of u a number of
illnesses healed themselves
automatically.
But oh well that came about as a
consequence of doing the course of
miracles and in a class one time I was
doing a class on the course of miracles
and I was talking about all the things
that disappeared due to spiritual
reality replacing illusion etc. One
illness after another cleared cleared
cleared themsel due to spiritual work.
So somebody said well how come you still
wear glasses? Well I always wore
glasses. In fact, by that time I had
trifocals,
which are expensive, by the way, $450 or
something. So they said, "Well, if
that's so, then if everything is just a
consequence of what you hold in mind,
how come you still wear glasses and all
these other things heal themselves?" And
I said, "Well, I never thought of it as
an illness. I just thought of it as a
structural defect, you know, like being
short or tall or having a big nose or
something. I thought, well, there's a
defect in the cornea and the retina or
some weird thing in there
and it's mechanical. So, I said, "No, I
never thought of that."
But anyway, as she said that, I thought,
"Well, yes, right." So, I took my
glasses off and I put them in my pocket.
And uh it was difficult driving without
being able to see where you were going.
When I look back at myself now, I marvel
that I did such a thing. But my faith in
God, my faith in the course of miracles,
the faith in the miraculous was
absolute.
I said, "By God, you're right." So I got
in the car. In fact, it was dark out and
I could only see where I needed to see.
It was really bizarre. The whole road
was fog except for like if the edge of
the road was there driving around, you
know, up to up around Jerome and crap
like that. So there's the edge of the
cliff right there.
I would only see what I needed to see
when I needed to see it. So, uh, if I
looked around this room, I wouldn't be
able to see anything. It was all It's
all just gray fuzz. And so, uh, I
somehow went from one place to another
and I would just see what I needed to
see. When I had one time, I had to turn
into Unity Church, make a left turn off
89A,
and just as I needed to make the left
turn, I had no idea where the road was.
I couldn't see it. some cars spotlight
headlights shown right on the turn in
and I just turned over there and went in
there. It was
went to Unity Church for the glass. So
anyway, this I lived that way
and I surrendered to it. I said, "Well,"
and it didn't get any better, by the
way.
The weeks the weeks went by and uh it
just stayed that way. And but
peculiarly, I could see what I needed to
see when I needed to see it.
It's like you could you couldn't see
what you needed to save your life until
you actually had to see it. You know,
you could see the fire extinguisher just
as the fire started, but not before
the timing was exact.
You couldn't anticipate God. You
couldn't. And I learned how to live in
the exact instant of the moment
instead of trying to gain control over
the next instant to ensure your own
survival. his you surrendered your
survival to God.
If the will of God was that you
survived, then you survived. And if it
was otherwise, then you wouldn't. If you
went off the cliff, you went off the
cliff. So if you go off the cliff, you
go off the cliff.
The surrender was absolute.
One day I was standing in the kitchen of
a friend
and standing in the kitchen chattering
away. All of a sudden, I could see
everything. All of a sudden, I could see
the calendar all the way across the room
and read the read the calendar across
the room. It was incredible. And
so I've got boxes full of glasses.
Anyway,
I now use them for reading at times
because it saves energy. I can read
without them, but it's it saves energy
if I've got to read a lot of stuff with
it. So, that was just one experience of
the course of miracles.
Is there any benefit in knowing about
your past lives? Uh, you must have
missed the lecture on karma.
A karmic event in itself. By the way,
I said people who are seriously
spiritually committed, you've only got
so much time and so much energy. So you
really want to use it to the best
purpose available. You don't have all
day every day around the clock to focus
on spiritual work. Most people have a
certain limited amount of time and
energy. You don't want to waste it.
Some degree of karmic research can save
a lot of time, can save a lot of guilt,
save a lot of self-rermination.
Uh once you see how a certain pattern
evolved throughout a series of
lifetimes, you get a certain aha
feeling.
you're okay with it. There's an
acceptance. There's a logical
obviousness about it.
Um when at a certain level of
consciousness, which I think we
calibrate around 600, uh there's a
recall of those lives and the
significance and what they were about
and you see the pattern in this life.
I think everybody is aware of certain
patterns in your life, right? there
certain recurrent patterns and you say,
you know, this can't be just due to
chance.
14 car accidents in a row. There's got
to be something.
You notice a repetitious pattern. You
notice that it follows sort of a
non-logic. Sort of a non-logic. People
say, I keep mirroring the same kind of
person. You know, why is that? People
look for psychological reasons. Well,
the psychological reason is karmic.
So past life regression I think has a
practical use at times inologic research
uh can define a certain lifetime. Very
often you intuit it that that's what
it's about and then you check it out
kinesiology and it says yes it's about
that. So now you feel more okay with it.
You know what I mean?
I think it's uh a matter of efficiency.
You'll probably arrive at the same
understanding sooner or later, but it
can save you many years of suffering
unnecessarily.
Suffering unnecessarily.
You can say, "Why was I addicted in this
lifetime? Why? Why me? Why me? Why me?"
And then you find from karmic research
that you died five or six times out of
addiction. This is your sixth and
seventh. This is your last shot at
sobriety. This time you either surrender
to God or you're going to go down again.
Uh death by addiction. So you see it
makes begins to make sense. So you stop
feeling sorry for yourself. A lot of
resentments are uh disappear.
A lot of explanation feeling sorry for
yourself for certain physical ailments
disappear.
And I've explained some of those in my
own personal past lifetime experiences
uh as they recurred in this lifetime.
You know, you even see it at the time
it's happening. You even see it at the
time of the surgery without anesthesia.
I saw exactly what had happened and how
it had happened in great detail.
There was that took away any feeling of
injustice that people that don't
understand karmic
you might say karmic laws uh are
suffering from a sense of injustice all
the time. They're always entitled and
they're always getting their feelings
hurt and they really have a miserable
life of it all.
And with a little karmic research, you
stop feeling sorry for yourself. Yes,
you were an SOB in a lot of lifetimes
and yes, that is what you did to others.
Oh, okay. That makes it a little easier
to accept, right? All right.
um
the asking for grace. We said that
prayer sec uh
sanctifying one's life by committing it
to God out of reverence for and
thankfulness for one's own existence
uh automatically has a consequence in
the field of consciousness.
In talking about karma, we say spiritual
the spiritual will is what really sets
karmic
balance.
Would a person who calibrates a 700
dream differently? I don't know.
Anything spiritually dedicated
is probably equal to anything else you
do that's spiritually dedicated.
Whether it's rotating a prayer wheel,
whether it's sewing for the poor,
whether it's just doing the most honest
day's work you can do,
whether it's trying to respect mankind
even though at times mankind seems so.
Otherwise
to try to comprehend how can I love Mid
Len, you know what I mean? How can I
forgive this guy? Especially if you a
relative of yours went down in the whole
thing.
How can I overcome this hatred, this
anger, this resentment?
So s even if it isn't our own ego, it's
the collective ego of society that
reflects back to us the necessity for
constant spiritual growth. Huh?
We even if it isn't in our lifetime, we
witness it out there. And certainly TV,
I think, is exhilarated spiritual growth
because you're constantly confronted
with the the projection of the ego out
into the world, expressing itself
uh in the history, the current history
of mankind. It's always projecting
itself out there. And so you have a the
capacity to benefit by by it, but
without actually experiencing it. You
don't have to be there in the Middle
East war and get shot and shoot back and
forth. You can witness it and come to a
way of transcending the whole thing
without actually having to be on the
battlefield. So in a certain way, our
modern lecture uh
our modern media I think speeds up
spiritual work because you're bombarded
with uh spiritual dilemmas and
provocations and
all right
we can't do much more than that with
that today because
there questions we didn't resolve
no why questions. Oh, God bless you.
Is there any questions we did not
resolve because we want to bring it to a
closure and then we'll have people come
up and I'll greet you all and hug you
all and sign any books or anything. Have
someone speak for you. Please.
>> Yes.
>> What does he say?
Uh,
by virtue of what? I don't know.
By virtue of
hitting the absolute bottom, beyond all
bottoms,
beyond all hope.
Once
you get out of the hell of time and
torture and
pain and suffering and all that,
you get to the serious levels of hell
which are beyond time.
The dreadfulness of absolute
hopelessness and aloneeness
completely deserted by God forever
is a horror that cannot be described.
And out of the the abysmal agony which
went on for eons,
the lower levels of hell have nothing to
do with time. You're not there for 5
years or 20 years.
It goes on just like the upper space is
foreverness.
The condemnation is forever.
Out of that came the voice from within.
If there is a God, I ask him to help me.
It came out. The voice came of its own
from within the spirit.
I guess the sincerity of it
uh caught the attention of a passing
archangel
who glanced that away and
an archangel at 50 thou calibrates
50,000 over
just to be noticed in passing probably
totally transforms everything because
that much power is like
100,000 volts and it just in one spark
is totally transformative
but I can't um
I can't tell you any more than the
experience of it the experiential
sequence there was one more and then
we'll go yes
>> spiritual will is what sets calibrated
level of consciousness
what sets your calibrated level of
consciousness is not the act but the
intention behind the act.
The freedom of choice is the one last
freedom one has.
Even in the very depths of hell, there
was still the freedom of choice.
At that point, God could have been
refused forever out of bitterness and
hatred,
and I would have then become a member of
the lower astral.
those who have refused God
live there.
So the freedom of choice was is is
always present. Even as somebody is
chopping you up,
you can transcend the instant.
I respected the valor of the guy as he
killed me.
I really loved him in a way.
I could see
the sincerity and power and total
commitment of the spiritual warrior in
this guy.
I mean, he was for God if it cost him my
life and he knew it was costing his
life. I guaranteed that
and he guaranteed the end of my life.
So, but in the moment of killing each
other,
we like um
respected each other at a very high
level.
I recognized his devotion to God and I
died
complimented that I was killed by
somebody who killed me out of their
devotion to God and he was equally
honored by my killing him. So, we were
of service to each other. You might say
the choices that are available to you to
everyone depends on your level of
evolution of consciousness.
If you trans if you have reached the
point of spiritual nobility,
then that choice to honor the spiritual
commitment of what the world would call
your opponent is open to you. From this
level, you would only hate him. You
understand? So the options that are open
to you reflect the level of your own
development of your own consciousness.
So one reason to evolve in consciousness
is because the choices that are open to
you are not open to people who haven't
reached that point. The choice of
forgiving people is not open.
Majority of mankind doesn't think of
forgiving your enemy. Right?
That's not a prevailing attitude.
Now you hate it for for many
generations, right? Middle East, they
just go on hating each other generation
after generation, century after century
for a thousand years. They don't stop.
So the option to not hate doesn't
apparently is not there with the
exception of individuals within within
there who probably evolve as a result of
all this and say, you know, this is
stupid and now they've got an option to
cop out. But until you get unhooked from
that lower energy field of hatred, if
you're caught in the spleen, you're
caught on the spleen. So to one who is
caught in the spleen, you don't have the
option of loving. It's not within your
capacity.
So the value of spiritually evolved
people to each other is they radiate
that capacity in into your aura. So the
shared aura of spiritually evolved
people brings to you you know you've got
the option of forgiveness no matter how
bad it is you know uh there is no
justified resentment the option to
forgive is cap is capable.
So we'll just say one last thing and
then we'll conclude. All that is
required is already present within you.
The love of God is so powerful, so deep,
so innate
to the very essence of your beingness
that if you find it, you will find that
within yourself there is the power and
the willingness to surrender
all including life itself to God. There
is within yourself already a powerful
devotion.
You say, "I don't have the power to do
that." If you summon it forth within
yourself is already existent.
For thee, oh Lord God, do I lay down my
life in all of its details.
The power of that devotion lies within
all of you and it's the guarantee of
your salvation.