[music]
be
on.
[music]
He
He [singing]
He [singing] be
[music]
>> [music]
>> song.
Give
Give me
Give me [music and singing]
[music]
The
The difficulty
The difficulty with
The difficulty with beauty
is
is that
The difficulty with beauty
is that you
is that you can't
The difficulty with beauty
is that you can't function.
It
It totally
It totally wipes
It totally wipes me
It totally wipes me out.
Going
Going over
It totally wipes me out.
Going over Mingus
Going over Mingus Mountain
It totally wipes me out.
Going over Mingus Mountain this
Going over Mingus Mountain this week,
the
the trees
the trees have
the trees have been
the trees have been so
the trees have been so beautiful.
along
along one
the trees have been so beautiful.
along one curve
along one curve there's
the trees have been so beautiful.
along one curve there's a
along one curve there's a tree
the trees have been so beautiful.
along one curve there's a tree in
stunning
stunning yellow.
stunning yellow. It
stunning yellow. It stands
stunning yellow. It stands out
stunning yellow. It stands out there
like
like the
stunning yellow. It stands out there
like the radiance
like the radiance of
stunning yellow. It stands out there
like the radiance of God
like the radiance of God just
stunning yellow. It stands out there
like the radiance of God just pulling
you
you off
you off the
you off the road
you off the road and
you off the road and you
you off the road and you have
you off the road and you have to
you off the road and you have to pull
over
over the
you off the road and you have to pull
over the side.
over the side. I
you off the road and you have to pull
over the side. I mean
over the side. I mean it
you off the road and you have to pull
over the side. I mean it could
over the side. I mean it could cause
accidents
accidents all
accidents all over.
Today
Today we're
accidents all over.
Today we're talking
Today we're talking about
h
God
God imminent
h
God imminent and
God imminent and God
h
God imminent and God transcendent.
That
That sounds
That sounds very
That sounds very impressive
That sounds very impressive doesn't
That sounds very impressive doesn't it?
I
I had
That sounds very impressive doesn't it?
I had to
I had to write
That sounds very impressive doesn't it?
I had to write something
I had to write something for
That sounds very impressive doesn't it?
I had to write something for the
lecture.
[laughter]
God
God damn
God damn it.
God damn it. And
God damn it. And transcendent.
God damn it. And transcendent. Whoa.
That
That would
God damn it. And transcendent. Whoa.
That would get
That would get you
God damn it. And transcendent. Whoa.
That would get you into
That would get you into divinity
God damn it. And transcendent. Whoa.
That would get you into divinity school
as
as a
as a thesis,
as a thesis, right?
I
I never
as a thesis, right?
I never had
I never had time
as a thesis, right?
I never had time to
I never had time to go
as a thesis, right?
I never had time to go to
I never had time to go to divinity
school.
school. Well,
school. Well, at
school. Well, at one
school. Well, at one time
school. Well, at one time I
school. Well, at one time I wanted
school. Well, at one time I wanted to
school. Well, at one time I wanted to be
a
a unity
school. Well, at one time I wanted to be
a unity minister.
And
And and
And and now
And and now I
And and now I give
And and now I give talks
And and now I give talks at
And and now I give talks at unity
churches
and
and and
and and sermons
and and sermons at
and and sermons at unity
and and sermons at unity church.
and and sermons at unity church. So
and and sermons at unity church. So I
saved
saved myself
and and sermons at unity church. So I
saved myself all
saved myself all that
and and sermons at unity church. So I
saved myself all that trouble
saved myself all that trouble again.
[laughter]
We
We won't
[laughter]
We won't talk
We won't talk about
[laughter]
We won't talk about theology
We won't talk about theology today
[clears throat]
except
except maybe
[clears throat]
except maybe an
except maybe an occasional
[clears throat]
except maybe an occasional reference.
Those
Those who
Those who are
Those who are interested
Those who are interested in
Those who are interested in theology,
you'll
you'll find
Those who are interested in theology,
you'll find that
you'll find that the
Those who are interested in theology,
you'll find that the Encyclopedia
Britannica
Britannica under
Britannica under theology
Britannica under theology is
Britannica under theology is stunningly
brilliant.
really
really excellent.
really excellent. If
really excellent. If you
really excellent. If you want
really excellent. If you want a
really excellent. If you want a review
of
of theology
really excellent. If you want a review
of theology throughout
of theology throughout the
really excellent. If you want a review
of theology throughout the ages,
of theology throughout the ages, the
encyclopedia
encyclopedia is
encyclopedia is really
encyclopedia is really quite
encyclopedia is really quite good.
God
God imminent
encyclopedia is really quite good.
God imminent means
God imminent means the
encyclopedia is really quite good.
God imminent means the realization
God imminent means the realization of
the
the source
the source of
the source of one's
the source of one's own
the source of one's own existence
radiating
radiating forth
as
as your
as your beingness.
Traditionally
Traditionally called
as your beingness.
Traditionally called realization
Traditionally called realization of
as your beingness.
Traditionally called realization of the
self.
Realization
is
is sort
is sort of
is sort of the
is sort of the right
is sort of the right word
is sort of the right word but
is sort of the right word but not
actually.
What
What happens
What happens is
What happens is more
What happens is more a
What happens is more a recognition.
It's
It's more
What happens is more a recognition.
It's more that
It's more that everything
What happens is more a recognition.
It's more that everything you've
It's more that everything you've seen
What happens is more a recognition.
It's more that everything you've seen in
a
a familiar
a familiar way
now
now you
a familiar way
now you see
now you see it
a familiar way
now you see it as
now you see it as a
a familiar way
now you see it as a radiance
now you see it as a radiance of
a familiar way
now you see it as a radiance of its
essence.
It's
It's like
essence.
It's like revealed.
It's
It's recognized.
It's recognized. You
It's recognized. You recognize
It's recognized. You recognize yourself
as
as all
It's recognized. You recognize yourself
as all that
as all that exists,
It's recognized. You recognize yourself
as all that exists, as
as all that exists, as the
It's recognized. You recognize yourself
as all that exists, as the essence
as all that exists, as the essence of
all
all that
all that exists.
Although
Although it's
all that exists.
Although it's a
Although it's a realization,
all that exists.
Although it's a realization, it's
Although it's a realization, it's really
a
a recognition.
It's
It's also
a recognition.
It's also a
It's also a remembrance
a recognition.
It's also a remembrance because
It's also a remembrance because as
a recognition.
It's also a remembrance because as it
shines
shines forth,
shines forth, one
shines forth, one wonders
shines forth, one wonders how
shines forth, one wonders how one
shines forth, one wonders how one could
have
have forgotten
shines forth, one wonders how one could
have forgotten that
have forgotten that [laughter]
some
some terrible
some terrible insanity
some terrible insanity must
some terrible insanity must have
overtaken
overtaken you
that
that you've
that you've forgotten
that you've forgotten who
that you've forgotten who you
that you've forgotten who you are.
that you've forgotten who you are. How
could
could that
that you've forgotten who you are. How
could that be?
could that be? It's
that you've forgotten who you are. How
could that be? It's a
could that be? It's a wonderment.
And
And that
And that you
And that you were
And that you were okay
And that you were okay all
And that you were okay all along,
And that you were okay all along, all
the
the lifetimes
And that you were okay all along, all
the lifetimes that
the lifetimes that you
And that you were okay all along, all
the lifetimes that you worried
the lifetimes that you worried about
everything
everything was
everything was ridiculous.
Your
Your survival
everything was ridiculous.
Your survival is
Your survival is guaranteed
because
because that
because that which
because that which is
because that which is the
because that which is the essence
because that which is the essence of
life
life has
because that which is the essence of
life has neither
life has neither beginning
because that which is the essence of
life has neither beginning nor
life has neither beginning nor ending.
Our
country
country is
Our
country is a
country is a theocracy.
It's
It's theist.
It's theist. No,
It's theist. No, it's
It's theist. No, it's not
It's theist. No, it's not a
It's theist. No, it's not a theocracy.
I'm
I'm sorry.
It's theist. No, it's not a theocracy.
I'm sorry. It's
I'm sorry. It's theistic
It's theist. No, it's not a theocracy.
I'm sorry. It's theistic but
I'm sorry. It's theistic but not
It's theist. No, it's not a theocracy.
I'm sorry. It's theistic but not a
theocracy.
The
The fact
theocracy.
The fact that
The fact that it's
theocracy.
The fact that it's theistic
The fact that it's theistic bothers
theocracy.
The fact that it's theistic bothers some
people
and
and I
people
and I suggest
and I suggest they
people
and I suggest they just
and I suggest they just ignore
people
and I suggest they just ignore it
and I suggest they just ignore it and
people
and I suggest they just ignore it and go
about
about their
about their business,
which
which is
about their business,
which is what
which is what most
about their business,
which is what most people
which is what most people do
about their business,
which is what most people do in
which is what most people do in the
course
course of
course of the
course of the day
course of the day anyway.
course of the day anyway. So
course of the day anyway. So you
course of the day anyway. So you don't
have
have to
course of the day anyway. So you don't
have to make
have to make a
course of the day anyway. So you don't
have to make a big
have to make a big political
course of the day anyway. So you don't
have to make a big political opus
have to make a big political opus about
it.
If
If you
it.
If you don't
If you don't like
it.
If you don't like God
If you don't like God on
it.
If you don't like God on your
If you don't like God on your money,
it.
If you don't like God on your money, you
can
can white
can white it
can white it out.
can white it out. I
can white it out. I guess
you
you can
can white it out. I guess
you can use
you can use foreign
can white it out. I guess
you can use foreign money.
you can use foreign money. You
can white it out. I guess
you can use foreign money. You can
transfer
transfer your
transfer your money
transfer your money into
transfer your money into Frank
transfer your money into Frank to
transfer your money into Frank to other
things
things in
traditionally.
traditionally. Throughout
traditionally. Throughout all
traditionally. Throughout all of
traditionally. Throughout all of time,
man
man has
traditionally. Throughout all of time,
man has been
man has been theistic.
Man
Man has
Man has sought
Man has sought the
Man has sought the source
Man has sought the source of
Man has sought the source of his
existence,
explanation
explanation for
explanation for life,
a
a context
explanation for life,
a context in
a context in which
explanation for life,
a context in which to
a context in which to place
explanation for life,
a context in which to place it.
a context in which to place it. So
explanation for life,
a context in which to place it. So man
has
has struggled
has struggled throughout
has struggled throughout all
has struggled throughout all of
has struggled throughout all of time.
Even
Even primitive
has struggled throughout all of time.
Even primitive tribes,
worship
worship maybe
worship maybe the
worship maybe the god,
worship maybe the god, they
worship maybe the god, they could
worship maybe the god, they could see
God
God in
worship maybe the god, they could see
God in the
God in the bear
worship maybe the god, they could see
God in the bear or
God in the bear or in
worship maybe the god, they could see
God in the bear or in the
God in the bear or in the reindeer.
worship maybe the god, they could see
God in the bear or in the reindeer. They
could
could see
could see God
could see God in
could see God in nature.
could see God in nature. But
could see God in nature. But there
could see God in nature. But there was
always
always this
could see God in nature. But there was
always this constant
always this constant search
could see God in nature. But there was
always this constant search for
always this constant search for God.
And
And as
And as man
And as man became
And as man became more
And as man became more intellectually
sophisticated,
he
he attempted
he attempted to
he attempted to intellectually
he attempted to intellectually define
it.
And
And thus
And thus grew
And thus grew theology
And thus grew theology and
And thus grew theology and religion.
I
I am
And thus grew theology and religion.
I am chairman
I am chairman of
And thus grew theology and religion.
I am chairman of the
I am chairman of the International
And thus grew theology and religion.
I am chairman of the International God
Anti-Defamation
Anti-Defamation League
and
and one
Anti-Defamation League
and one of
and one of my
Anti-Defamation League
and one of my projects
and one of my projects is
Anti-Defamation League
and one of my projects is to
and one of my projects is to defend
Anti-Defamation League
and one of my projects is to defend the
good
good name
good name of
good name of God
good name of God who
good name of God who has
good name of God who has been
good name of God who has been bismerched
throughout
throughout the
good name of God who has been bismerched
throughout the centuries.
He's
He's been
He's been maligned
He's been maligned as
He's been maligned as the
He's been maligned as the great
perpetrator.
[clears throat]
It's
It's necessary
[clears throat]
It's necessary therefore
It's necessary therefore to
[clears throat]
It's necessary therefore to refer
It's necessary therefore to refer to
[clears throat]
It's necessary therefore to refer to the
map
map of
map of consciousness
map of consciousness [snorts]
so
so that
map of consciousness [snorts]
so that we
so that we can
map of consciousness [snorts]
so that we can figure
so that we can figure out
map of consciousness [snorts]
so that we can figure out where
so that we can figure out where God
must
must be.
must be. You
must be. You see,
as
as we
must be. You see,
as we calibrated
as we calibrated the
must be. You see,
as we calibrated the levels
as we calibrated the levels of
consciousness,
consciousness, we
consciousness, we went
consciousness, we went from
consciousness, we went from the
consciousness, we went from the lowest,
most
most destructive
uh
uh the
uh the poisonous
uh the poisonous uh
uh the poisonous uh reptile
uh
uh the
uh the poisonous uh reptile
uh the political
uh the political militant
uh the poisonous uh reptile
uh the political militant who
uh the political militant who blows
uh the poisonous uh reptile
uh the political militant who blows away
thousands
thousands of
thousands of innocent
thousands of innocent people.
thousands of innocent people. We
thousands of innocent people. We come
thousands of innocent people. We come on
up
up through
thousands of innocent people. We come on
up through normal,
up through normal, healthy
thousands of innocent people. We come on
up through normal, healthy people,
loving
loving people,
and
and we
loving people,
and we come
and we come up
loving people,
and we come up to
and we come up to the
loving people,
and we come up to the top.
Now,
Now, it's
Now, it's necessary
Now, it's necessary to
Now, it's necessary to remember
Now, it's necessary to remember that
Now, it's necessary to remember that God
is
is at
Now, it's necessary to remember that God
is at the
is at the top
Now, it's necessary to remember that God
is at the top of
is at the top of the
Now, it's necessary to remember that God
is at the top of the chart
is at the top of the chart and
Now, it's necessary to remember that God
is at the top of the chart and not
is at the top of the chart and not the
bottom.
bottom. [laughter]
That's
That's all
bottom. [laughter]
That's all that's
That's all that's required.
Doesn't
Doesn't that
Doesn't that seem
Doesn't that seem simple?
Doesn't that seem simple? [laughter]
However,
throughout
throughout time,
throughout time, there
throughout time, there are
throughout time, there are forces
throughout time, there are forces that
try
try to
throughout time, there are forces that
try to make
try to make make
throughout time, there are forces that
try to make make the
try to make make the map
throughout time, there are forces that
try to make make the map go
try to make make the map go in
throughout time, there are forces that
try to make make the map go in the
try to make make the map go in the other
direction,
and
and we
direction,
and we see
and we see them
direction,
and we see them in
and we see them in current
direction,
and we see them in current society.
and we see them in current society. 911
was
was the
was the eruption
was the eruption of
was the eruption of God
was the eruption of God is
was the eruption of God is at
was the eruption of God is at this
was the eruption of God is at this end,
folks.
And
And this
And this side
And this side in
And this side in this
And this side in this end,
And this side in this end, we're
And this side in this end, we're going
to
to have
And this side in this end, we're going
to have a
to have a protest
And this side in this end, we're going
to have a protest parade
to have a protest parade to
And this side in this end, we're going
to have a protest parade to remove
to have a protest parade to remove God.
So
So the
So the God
So the God God
So the God God here
So the God God here is
So the God God here is the
So the God God here is the source
So the God God here is the source of
killing
killing all
So the God God here is the source of
killing all Americans
killing all Americans and
So the God God here is the source of
killing all Americans and infidels
killing all Americans and infidels and
God
God knows
God knows what
God knows what all.
They
They knocked
God knows what all.
They knocked off
They knocked off 3,000.
God knows what all.
They knocked off 3,000. They've
They knocked off 3,000. They've only
God knows what all.
They knocked off 3,000. They've only got
300,000
300,000 to
300,000 to go.
300,000 to go. [laughter]
They
They get
300,000 to go. [laughter]
They get busy
They get busy round
300,000 to go. [laughter]
They get busy round the
They get busy round the clock.
300,000 to go. [laughter]
They get busy round the clock. They
can't
can't keep
can't keep up
can't keep up with
can't keep up with the
can't keep up with the birth
can't keep up with the birth rate.
can't keep up with the birth rate. So
can't keep up with the birth rate. So I
I
I want
can't keep up with the birth rate. So I
I want to
I want to tell
can't keep up with the birth rate. So I
I want to tell them
I want to tell them their
can't keep up with the birth rate. So I
I want to tell them their project
I want to tell them their project is
can't keep up with the birth rate. So I
I want to tell them their project is is
limited
limited in
limited in in
limited in in expectation.
However,
However, God
limited in in expectation.
However, God has
However, God has traditionally
been
been depicted
been depicted in
been depicted in a
been depicted in a variety
been depicted in a variety of
been depicted in a variety of extremely
negative
negative ways.
been depicted in a variety of extremely
negative ways. When
negative ways. When I
been depicted in a variety of extremely
negative ways. When I say
negative ways. When I say the
been depicted in a variety of extremely
negative ways. When I say the great
perpetrator,
perpetrator, that's
perpetrator, that's precisely
perpetrator, that's precisely how
perpetrator, that's precisely how God
has
has been
perpetrator, that's precisely how God
has been maligned.
has been maligned. Huh?
In
In July,
In July, we
In July, we went
In July, we went through
about
about 18
In July, we went through
about 18 statements
about 18 statements about
In July, we went through
about 18 statements about the
about 18 statements about the true
nature
nature of
nature of God.
nature of God. And
nature of God. And the
nature of God. And the entire
nature of God. And the entire class
nature of God. And the entire class we
calibrated
calibrated whether
nature of God. And the entire class we
calibrated whether it
calibrated whether it was
nature of God. And the entire class we
calibrated whether it was true
calibrated whether it was true or
nature of God. And the entire class we
calibrated whether it was true or false.
And
And we
And we got
And we got unanimously
unanimous
unanimous agreement
And we got unanimously
unanimous agreement on
unanimous agreement on the
And we got unanimously
unanimous agreement on the nature
unanimous agreement on the nature of
And we got unanimously
unanimous agreement on the nature of God
in
in a
in a normal
in a normal theistic
in a normal theistic society.
in a normal theistic society. Then
the
the authority
in a normal theistic society. Then
the authority for
the authority for government,
in a normal theistic society. Then
the authority for government, for
the authority for government, for rule,
for
for law,
for law, for
for law, for logic,
for
for social
for law, for logic,
for social mores,
for social mores, for
for law, for logic,
for social mores, for ethics
has
has been
that
that God
has been
that God is
that God is the
has been
that God is the source
that God is the source of
has been
that God is the source of our
that God is the source of our existence.
Without
Without it,
Without it, in
Without it, in an
Without it, in an atheistic
Without it, in an atheistic society,
Without it, in an atheistic society, you
have
have chaotic
Without it, in an atheistic society, you
have chaotic rule
have chaotic rule by
Without it, in an atheistic society, you
have chaotic rule by force.
You
You have
You have the
You have the waring
You have the waring tribes.
You
You have
You have the waring tribes.
You have the
You have the disorganization
You have the waring tribes.
You have the disorganization and
You have the disorganization and chaos
of
of a
of a communist
of a communist society.
What
What happens
of a communist society.
What happens when
What happens when God
of a communist society.
What happens when God is
What happens when God is not
acknowledged
acknowledged as
acknowledged as the
acknowledged as the source
acknowledged as the source of
acknowledged as the source of life
acknowledged as the source of life is
you
you end
acknowledged as the source of life is
you end up
you end up with
acknowledged as the source of life is
you end up with totalitarianism.
A
A fascist
A fascist dictator
A fascist dictator will
A fascist dictator will take
A fascist dictator will take the
A fascist dictator will take the place.
Then
Then millions
A fascist dictator will take the place.
Then millions of
Then millions of people
A fascist dictator will take the place.
Then millions of people will
Then millions of people will gather
A fascist dictator will take the place.
Then millions of people will gather in
the
the great
the great squares
the great squares and
the great squares and go
the great squares and go sigh,
the great squares and go sigh, sigh,
sigh.
And
And God
And God is
And God is then
And God is then at
And God is then at the
And God is then at the bottom
And God is then at the bottom of
And God is then at the bottom of the
chart.
chart. When
And God is then at the bottom of the
chart. When God
chart. When God is
And God is then at the bottom of the
chart. When God is put
chart. When God is put at
And God is then at the bottom of the
chart. When God is put at the
chart. When God is put at the bottom
And God is then at the bottom of the
chart. When God is put at the bottom of
the
the chart,
the chart, then
the chart, then godly
the chart, then godly powers
the chart, then godly powers are
the chart, then godly powers are given
to
to the
the chart, then godly powers are given
to the state.
No
No ethics,
no
no basis
No ethics,
no basis for
no basis for human
No ethics,
no basis for human behavior
no basis for human behavior other
No ethics,
no basis for human behavior other than
force.
So
So the
force.
So the levels
So the levels below
force.
So the levels below 200
So the levels below 200 represent
force.
So the levels below 200 represent force
which
which as
which as they
which as they go
which as they go down
which as they go down become
progressively
frankly
frankly demonic.
The
The levels
frankly demonic.
The levels as
The levels as they
frankly demonic.
The levels as they go
The levels as they go up
frankly demonic.
The levels as they go up become
progressively
progressively frankly
progressively frankly more
progressively frankly more heavenly.
We
We presume
progressively frankly more heavenly.
We presume that
We presume that people
progressively frankly more heavenly.
We presume that people want
We presume that people want to
progressively frankly more heavenly.
We presume that people want to move
We presume that people want to move up
the
the chart
the chart to
the chart to heavenly
the chart to heavenly heavenly
the chart to heavenly heavenly peace.
That's
That's idiotic.
the chart to heavenly heavenly peace.
That's idiotic. [laughter]
Most
Most people
Most people do
Most people do not
Most people do not want
Most people do not want peace
Most people do not want peace at
Most people do not want peace at all.
They
They ra
Most people do not want peace at all.
They ra would
They ra would rather
Most people do not want peace at all.
They ra would rather be
They ra would rather be right.
Most people do not want peace at all.
They ra would rather be right. They'd
rather
rather be
rather be right
rather be right than
rather be right than have
rather be right than have peace,
rather be right than have peace, you
know.
know. Uhhuh.
Peace
Peace is
Peace is is
Peace is is a
Peace is is a threat
Peace is is a threat to
Peace is is a threat to many
Peace is is a threat to many people.
They
They say
Peace is is a threat to many people.
They say there's
They say there's nothing
Peace is is a threat to many people.
They say there's nothing happening
around
around here.
around here. We'll
around here. We'll turn
around here. We'll turn on
around here. We'll turn on Eminem.
[laughter]
Then
Then something's
Then something's happening.
Then something's happening. All
Then something's happening. All right.
>> [laughter]
>> Little
>> Little tune
>> Little tune t
>> Little tune t turn
>> Little tune t turn up
>> Little tune t turn up the
>> Little tune t turn up the boom
>> Little tune t turn up the boom box
>> Little tune t turn up the boom box in
the
the car
>> Little tune t turn up the boom box in
the car and
the car and drive
>> Little tune t turn up the boom box in
the car and drive down
the car and drive down the
>> Little tune t turn up the boom box in
the car and drive down the street.
the car and drive down the street. Boom
boom
boom boom
boom boom boom
boom boom boom boom
boom boom boom boom boom.
Okay.
Although
Although peace
Although peace is
Although peace is forever
Although peace is forever within
Although peace is forever within you,
uh
uh people
Although peace is forever within you,
uh people uh
uh people uh are
Although peace is forever within you,
uh people uh are afraid
uh people uh are afraid of
Although peace is forever within you,
uh people uh are afraid of it.
uh people uh are afraid of it. They're
afraid
afraid of
afraid of being
afraid of being wiped
afraid of being wiped out
afraid of being wiped out by
afraid of being wiped out by the
infinite
infinite presence.
afraid of being wiped out by the
infinite presence. And
infinite presence. And so
afraid of being wiped out by the
infinite presence. And so the
infinite presence. And so the ego
afraid of being wiped out by the
infinite presence. And so the ego keeps
up
up its
up its endless
up its endless chatter.
up its endless chatter. it
up its endless chatter. it like
up its endless chatter. it like holds
off
off God
uh
uh as
uh as best
uh as best it
uh as best it can.
It
It makes
uh as best it can.
It makes sense
It makes sense to
uh as best it can.
It makes sense to hold
It makes sense to hold off
uh as best it can.
It makes sense to hold off the
It makes sense to hold off the God
uh as best it can.
It makes sense to hold off the God of
religion.
religion. I
religion. I remember
religion. I remember when
religion. I remember when I
religion. I remember when I became
religion. I remember when I became an
atheist,
atheist, it
religion. I remember when I became an
atheist, it was
atheist, it was a
religion. I remember when I became an
atheist, it was a great
atheist, it was a great relief.
religion. I remember when I became an
atheist, it was a great relief. Frankly,
I
I was
I was a
I was a scrupulous
scrupulously
scrupulously religious
came
came like
came like a
came like a burden.
And
And I
came like a burden.
And I think
And I think I've
came like a burden.
And I think I've told
And I think I've told you
came like a burden.
And I think I've told you before,
I
I used
I used to
I used to dread
I used to dread Saturday
I used to dread Saturday afternoon
I used to dread Saturday afternoon when
you
you went
I used to dread Saturday afternoon when
you went to
you went to confession
I used to dread Saturday afternoon when
you went to confession and
you went to confession and then
I used to dread Saturday afternoon when
you went to confession and then Sunday
morning
morning you
morning you went
morning you went to
morning you went to communion
morning you went to communion and
morning you went to communion and you
weren't
weren't supposed
morning you went to communion and you
weren't supposed to
weren't supposed to have
morning you went to communion and you
weren't supposed to have a
weren't supposed to have a sin
morning you went to communion and you
weren't supposed to have a sin sin
weren't supposed to have a sin sin on
your
your soul
and
and the
your soul
and the sin
and the sin was
your soul
and the sin was supposed
and the sin was supposed to
your soul
and the sin was supposed to be
and the sin was supposed to be like
your soul
and the sin was supposed to be like a
black
black spot
black spot on
black spot on your
black spot on your soul.
black spot on your soul. Well,
black spot on your soul. Well, I
black spot on your soul. Well, I dreaded
that.
that. You
black spot on your soul. Well, I dreaded
that. You imagine
that. You imagine walking
black spot on your soul. Well, I dreaded
that. You imagine walking around
that. You imagine walking around God
black spot on your soul. Well, I dreaded
that. You imagine walking around God is
staring
staring down
staring down at
staring down at this
staring down at this black
staring down at this black sin
staring down at this black sin and
staring down at this black sin and this
black
black spot
staring down at this black sin and this
black spot on
black spot on your
staring down at this black sin and this
black spot on your soul.
So
So you
So you see
So you see the
So you see the fear
So you see the fear of
So you see the fear of God
So you see the fear of God then
So you see the fear of God then the
So you see the fear of God then the fear
of
of God
So you see the fear of God then the fear
of God was
of God was the
So you see the fear of God then the fear
of God was the fear
of God was the fear of
So you see the fear of God then the fear
of God was the fear of punishment.
of God was the fear of punishment. Fear
of
of God
of God as
of God as the
of God as the great
of God as the great punisher,
the
the great
of God as the great punisher,
the great avenger
the great avenger of
of God as the great punisher,
the great avenger of your
the great avenger of your dastardly
wrongs.
You
You got
wrongs.
You got annoyed
You got annoyed with
wrongs.
You got annoyed with your
You got annoyed with your mother.
wrongs.
You got annoyed with your mother. That's
enough
enough to
enough to bang.
Dear
Dear father,
enough to bang.
Dear father, have
Dear father, have you
enough to bang.
Dear father, have you sinned?
Dear father, have you sinned? I
enough to bang.
Dear father, have you sinned? I got
angry
angry at
angry at my
angry at my mother.
angry at my mother. You
angry at my mother. You can
angry at my mother. You can say
angry at my mother. You can say 12
angry at my mother. You can say 12 hill
of
of Marys
angry at my mother. You can say 12 hill
of Marys and
of Marys and 13
angry at my mother. You can say 12 hill
of Marys and 13 [laughter]
our
our fathers
you're
you're getting
our fathers
you're getting angry
you're getting angry at
our fathers
you're getting angry at your
you're getting angry at your mother.
our fathers
you're getting angry at your mother. So
God
God became
God became sort
God became sort of
God became sort of dreadful
scary
and
and when
and when I
and when I became
and when I became an
and when I became an atheist
it
it was
and when I became an atheist
it was a
it was a great
and when I became an atheist
it was a great relief.
Therefore,
Therefore, you
Therefore, you can
Therefore, you can see
Therefore, you can see why
Therefore, you can see why ungodliness
or
or no
Therefore, you can see why ungodliness
or no godliness,
or no godliness, not
Therefore, you can see why ungodliness
or no godliness, not anti-godliness,
or no godliness, not anti-godliness, but
just
just ignoring
just ignoring God
allows
allows you
just ignoring God
allows you greater
allows you greater freedom
because
because that
because that depiction
because that depiction of
because that depiction of God
because that depiction of God is
because that depiction of God is the
great
great oppressor.
People
People who
People who revolt
People who revolt against
People who revolt against God
People who revolt against God are
People who revolt against God are really
not
not revoling
People who revolt against God are really
not revoling against
not revoling against God.
People who revolt against God are really
not revoling against God. The
not revoling against God. The revoling
of
of an
of an image
of an image of
of an image of God
as
as the
of an image of God
as the dreadful
as the dreadful great
of an image of God
as the dreadful great oppressor,
as the dreadful great oppressor, the
ultimate
ultimate threat.
Judgment
Judgment day.
Oh
Oh sinner,
Oh sinner, beware.
Oh sinner, beware. Oh,
Oh sinner, beware. Oh, [laughter]
judgment
judgment day.
Well,
Well, how
Well, how did
Well, how did all
Well, how did all that
Well, how did all that come
Well, how did all that come about?
Well, how did all that come about? And
what
what is
Well, how did all that come about? And
what is the
what is the truth?
Well, how did all that come about? And
what is the truth? Huh?
what is the truth? Huh? What
Well, how did all that come about? And
what is the truth? Huh? What is
what is the truth? Huh? What is the
actual
actual truth?
The
The exit
actual truth?
The exit truth
The exit truth is
actual truth?
The exit truth is that
The exit truth is that man
actual truth?
The exit truth is that man tries
The exit truth is that man tries to
develop
develop an
develop an conceptual
develop an conceptual understanding
develop an conceptual understanding of
God,
God, theological
develop an conceptual understanding of
God, theological truth
God, theological truth as
develop an conceptual understanding of
God, theological truth as best
God, theological truth as best he
develop an conceptual understanding of
God, theological truth as best he can.
The
The instrument
The instrument that
The instrument that he
The instrument that he uses
The instrument that he uses to
The instrument that he uses to do
The instrument that he uses to do that
however
however is
The instrument that he uses to do that
however is the
however is the intellect.
So
So theology
So theology then
So theology then is
So theology then is using
So theology then is using an
So theology then is using an instrument
which
which calibrates
So theology then is using an instrument
which calibrates in
which calibrates in the
So theology then is using an instrument
which calibrates in the 400s.
which calibrates in the 400s. We
So theology then is using an instrument
which calibrates in the 400s. We said
reason,
intellect,
intellect, understanding,
abstract
abstract meaning
abstract meaning is
abstract meaning is the
abstract meaning is the intellect.
So
So you
abstract meaning is the intellect.
So you might
So you might say
abstract meaning is the intellect.
So you might say theology
So you might say theology is
abstract meaning is the intellect.
So you might say theology is the
So you might say theology is the attempt
of
of the
of the intellect
to
to describe
of the intellect
to describe and
to describe and understand
of the intellect
to describe and understand that
to describe and understand that which
incomp
incomp is
incomp is incomprehensible.
incomp is incomprehensible. [laughter]
Uh
Uh let's
incomp is incomprehensible. [laughter]
Uh let's see.
Uh let's see. Theology
incomp is incomprehensible. [laughter]
Uh let's see. Theology is
Uh let's see. Theology is in
incomp is incomprehensible. [laughter]
Uh let's see. Theology is in the
Uh let's see. Theology is in the 400s.
Resist
Resist 420
Resist 420 440
Resist 420 440 450
Resist 420 440 450 460
Resist 420 440 450 460 4
Theology
Theology generally
Resist 420 440 450 460 4
Theology generally runs
Theology generally runs around
Resist 420 440 450 460 4
Theology generally runs around 460.
Theology generally runs around 460. The
theology
theology in
theology in the
theology in the encyclopedia
theology in the encyclopedia bratannica
calibrates
calibrates it
theology in the encyclopedia bratannica
calibrates it over
calibrates it over 450
theology in the encyclopedia bratannica
calibrates it over 450 460
is
is pretty
is pretty high.
is pretty high. 450
is pretty high. 450 460
is pretty high. 450 460 is
is pretty high. 450 460 is pretty
is pretty high. 450 460 is pretty high
understanding
from
from an
from an intellectual
from an intellectual viewpoint.
from an intellectual viewpoint. Hm.
If
If mankind
from an intellectual viewpoint. Hm.
If mankind has
If mankind has been
from an intellectual viewpoint. Hm.
If mankind has been unable
If mankind has been unable to
from an intellectual viewpoint. Hm.
If mankind has been unable to fathom
If mankind has been unable to fathom the
true
true nature
true nature of
true nature of God
true nature of God through
true nature of God through the
intellect,
intellect, then
true nature of God through the
intellect, then he's
intellect, then he's done
true nature of God through the
intellect, then he's done it
intellect, then he's done it through
emotion.
emotion. He's
emotion. He's done
emotion. He's done it
emotion. He's done it through
imagination.
The
The primitive
The primitive tribe
The primitive tribe watches
The primitive tribe watches the
The primitive tribe watches the volcano
erupt
erupt and
The primitive tribe watches the volcano
erupt and presumes
erupt and presumes there
The primitive tribe watches the volcano
erupt and presumes there is
erupt and presumes there is a
The primitive tribe watches the volcano
erupt and presumes there is a goddess
erupt and presumes there is a goddess of
the
the volcano.
So
So to
the volcano.
So to make
So to make the
the volcano.
So to make the volcano
So to make the volcano stop
the volcano.
So to make the volcano stop erupting,
you
you sacrifice
you sacrifice virgins.
In
In volcanic
you sacrifice virgins.
In volcanic countries,
In volcanic countries, they
you sacrifice virgins.
In volcanic countries, they run
In volcanic countries, they run out
you sacrifice virgins.
In volcanic countries, they run out of
virgins
virgins after
virgins after a
virgins after a while.
virgins after a while. [laughter]
Volcano
Volcano keeps
virgins after a while. [laughter]
Volcano keeps going.
Volcano keeps going. They
virgins after a while. [laughter]
Volcano keeps going. They keep
sacrificing
sacrificing virgins.
sacrificing virgins. Whoa.
They
They also
sacrificing virgins. Whoa.
They also sacrificed.
They also sacrificed. They
sacrificing virgins. Whoa.
They also sacrificed. They rip
They also sacrificed. They rip out
sacrificing virgins. Whoa.
They also sacrificed. They rip out the
heart
heart of
heart of young
heart of young men
heart of young men on
heart of young men on the
heart of young men on the altar
heart of young men on the altar also.
heart of young men on the altar also. So
you'll
you'll find
heart of young men on the altar also. So
you'll find that
you'll find that the
heart of young men on the altar also. So
you'll find that the calibration
you'll find that the calibration of
heart of young men on the altar also. So
you'll find that the calibration of the
Incas
Incas and
Incas and people
Incas and people such
Incas and people such as
Incas and people such as that
Incas and people such as that was
Incas and people such as that was not
extremely
extremely high.
Uh
Uh we
Uh we have
Uh we have permission
Uh we have permission to
Uh we have permission to do
Uh we have permission to do the
Uh we have permission to do the Incas
resist.
resist. The
Uh we have permission to do the Incas
resist. The Incas
resist. The Incas were
Uh we have permission to do the Incas
resist. The Incas were over
resist. The Incas were over 200
Uh we have permission to do the Incas
resist. The Incas were over 200 resist.
You
You know,
You know, ripping
You know, ripping out
You know, ripping out the
You know, ripping out the hearts
You know, ripping out the hearts of
maidens
to
to a
to a demonic
to a demonic God
is
is worshiping
to a demonic God
is worshiping God
is worshiping God as
to a demonic God
is worshiping God as the
is worshiping God as the demonic.
to a demonic God
is worshiping God as the demonic. God
is worshiping God as the demonic. God as
the
the demonic.
the demonic. So
the demonic. So the
the demonic. So the history
the demonic. So the history of
the demonic. So the history of religion
throughout
throughout all
the demonic. So the history of religion
throughout all cultures
throughout all cultures has
the demonic. So the history of religion
throughout all cultures has really
throughout all cultures has really been
emerging
emerging from
emerging from the
emerging from the misconception
emerging from the misconception of
emerging from the misconception of God
is
is really
emerging from the misconception of God
is really the
is really the ultimate
emerging from the misconception of God
is really the ultimate demonic.
The
The God
The God of
The God of the
The God of the Old
The God of the Old Testament
The God of the Old Testament is
The God of the Old Testament is very
threatening,
very
very selective,
prone
prone to
very selective,
prone to jealousy,
having
having his
having his nose
having his nose out
having his nose out of
having his nose out of joint,
getting
getting peeled
having his nose out of joint,
getting peeled at
getting peeled at people,
having
having favorites,
making
making promises,
contracts,
partiality,
partiality, and
contracts,
partiality, and exhibiting
partiality, and exhibiting all
contracts,
partiality, and exhibiting all the
partiality, and exhibiting all the human
the
the defects
the defects of
the defects of the
the defects of the human
the defects of the human ego.
So
So Freud,
the defects of the human ego.
So Freud, as
So Freud, as we
the defects of the human ego.
So Freud, as we said,
attacked
attacked that
attacked that and
attacked that and said
attacked that and said that
the
the ancient
attacked that and said that
the ancient gods
the ancient gods are
attacked that and said that
the ancient gods are projections
the ancient gods are projections from
the
the unconscious,
projections
projections of
the unconscious,
projections of hatred
projections of hatred and
the unconscious,
projections of hatred and fear,
primarily
primarily hatred
primarily hatred and
primarily hatred and fear
primarily hatred and fear of
primarily hatred and fear of father
figures,
the
the bad,
the bad, wicked,
the bad, wicked, threatening,
the bad, wicked, threatening, terrifying
fathers
fathers projected
the bad, wicked, threatening, terrifying
fathers projected onto
fathers projected onto God.
He
He then
He then concluded
He then concluded therefore
He then concluded therefore God
He then concluded therefore God did
He then concluded therefore God did not
exist
exist which
He then concluded therefore God did not
exist which was
exist which was an
He then concluded therefore God did not
exist which was an incorrect
nonsecrator.
He
He should
nonsecrator.
He should have
He should have said
nonsecrator.
He should have said the
He should have said the false
nonsecrator.
He should have said the false gods
He should have said the false gods do
not
not exist
not exist but
not exist but he
not exist but he did
not exist but he did not
not exist but he did not really
addressed
addressed address
a
a real
a real god.
a real god. It
a real god. It was
a real god. It was not
a real god. It was not within
a real god. It was not within his
province.
province. As
a real god. It was not within his
province. As you
province. As you remember
a real god. It was not within his
province. As you remember Freud
calibrates
calibrates at
calibrates at 499
which
which is
calibrates at 499
which is means
which is means he
calibrates at 499
which is means he took
which is means he took the
calibrates at 499
which is means he took the intellect
which is means he took the intellect as
far
far as
far as it
far as it can
far as it can go.
far as it can go. So
far as it can go. So he's
far as it can go. So he's not
far as it can go. So he's not to
far as it can go. So he's not to be
faulted
faulted for
far as it can go. So he's not to be
faulted for having
faulted for having failed
far as it can go. So he's not to be
faulted for having failed at
faulted for having failed at that
far as it can go. So he's not to be
faulted for having failed at that level.
Well,
Well, his
Well, his level
Well, his level of
Well, his level of evolution
Well, his level of evolution was
Well, his level of evolution was 499.
And
And he
Well, his level of evolution was 499.
And he made
And he made great
Well, his level of evolution was 499.
And he made great contributions
And he made great contributions to
Well, his level of evolution was 499.
And he made great contributions to the
relief
relief of
relief of suffering.
Many
Many of
relief of suffering.
Many of Freud's
Many of Freud's teachings,
relief of suffering.
Many of Freud's teachings, we
Many of Freud's teachings, we don't
relief of suffering.
Many of Freud's teachings, we don't even
recognize
recognize the
recognize the Freud's
recognize the Freud's teachings.
recognize the Freud's teachings. They
became
became so
recognize the Freud's teachings. They
became so accepted
became so accepted that
recognize the Freud's teachings. They
became so accepted that they
became so accepted that they become
recognize the Freud's teachings. They
became so accepted that they become part
of
of our
of our culture,
of our culture, part
of our culture, part of
of our culture, part of our
psychological
psychological understanding.
You
You can't
You can't watch
You can't watch the
You can't watch the evening
You can't watch the evening no
You can't watch the evening no news
without
without some
You can't watch the evening no news
without some concept
without some concept from
You can't watch the evening no news
without some concept from psychoanalysis
appearing.
The
The killer
appearing.
The killer must
The killer must had
appearing.
The killer must had something
The killer must had something go
appearing.
The killer must had something go wrong
in
in his
in his childhood.
in his childhood. Yeah.
in his childhood. Yeah. He
in his childhood. Yeah. He got
in his childhood. Yeah. He got born.
That's
That's what
in his childhood. Yeah. He got born.
That's what got
He
He had
He had some
He had some pretty
He had some pretty bad
He had some pretty bad karma
He had some pretty bad karma and
came
came out
He had some pretty bad karma and
came out with
came out with a
He had some pretty bad karma and
came out with a little
came out with a little defective
He had some pretty bad karma and
came out with a little defective neuron
new
new neuronal
new neuronal structure.
new neuronal structure. That's
new neuronal structure. That's what's
wrong.
Um
Um they
Um they can't
Um they can't help
Um they can't help it
Um they can't help it because
Um they can't help it because the
neuronal
neuronal structure
Um they can't help it because the
neuronal structure is
neuronal structure is faulty.
Um they can't help it because the
neuronal structure is faulty. The
prefrontal
prefrontal cortex
prefrontal cortex is
prefrontal cortex is faulty.
prefrontal cortex is faulty. Not
prefrontal cortex is faulty. Not because
bad
bad things
prefrontal cortex is faulty. Not because
bad things happened
bad things happened to
prefrontal cortex is faulty. Not because
bad things happened to them
bad things happened to them in
prefrontal cortex is faulty. Not because
bad things happened to them in their
childhood.
childhood. Bad
childhood. Bad things
childhood. Bad things have
childhood. Bad things have happened
childhood. Bad things have happened to
everybody
everybody in
childhood. Bad things have happened to
everybody in this
everybody in this room.
Anybody
Anybody gone
Anybody gone through
Anybody gone through childhood
Anybody gone through childhood without
anything
anything bad
Anybody gone through childhood without
anything bad happening
anything bad happening to
Anybody gone through childhood without
anything bad happening to them?
anything bad happening to them? Let's
see
see your
see your hands.
[laughter]
The
The embarrassing
The embarrassing moments,
The embarrassing moments, the
The embarrassing moments, the chagrin,
being
being falsely
The embarrassing moments, the chagrin,
being falsely accused,
being
being punished
being punished for
being punished for something
being punished for something your
being punished for something your sister
did
did and
being punished for something your sister
did and you
did and you didn't
being punished for something your sister
did and you didn't do.
did and you didn't do. I
being punished for something your sister
did and you didn't do. I mean,
did and you didn't do. I mean, there's
being punished for something your sister
did and you didn't do. I mean, there's a
million
million things,
million things, right?
million things, right? Being
million things, right? Being ganged
million things, right? Being ganged up
on
on the
million things, right? Being ganged up
on the way
on the way home
million things, right? Being ganged up
on the way home and
[clears throat]
[clears throat] given
[clears throat] given a
[clears throat] given a bloody
[clears throat] given a bloody nose.
Endless
Endless things
[clears throat] given a bloody nose.
Endless things happen
Endless things happen to
[clears throat] given a bloody nose.
Endless things happen to people.
People,
People, here's
People, here's the
People, here's the misconception
is
is that
People, here's the misconception
is that bad
is that bad things
People, here's the misconception
is that bad things that
is that bad things that are
People, here's the misconception
is that bad things that are happening
now
now are
now are due
now are due to
now are due to bad
now are due to bad things
now are due to bad things that
now are due to bad things that happened
to
to you
now are due to bad things that happened
to you then.
to you then. No,
now are due to bad things that happened
to you then. No, bad
to you then. No, bad things
now are due to bad things that happened
to you then. No, bad things happening
to you then. No, bad things happening to
you
you then
you then is
you then is and
you then is and now
you then is and now is
you then is and now is all
you then is and now is all for
you then is and now is all for the
you then is and now is all for the same
reason.
reason. Because
you then is and now is all for the same
reason. Because bad
reason. Because bad things
you then is and now is all for the same
reason. Because bad things are
reason. Because bad things are always
happening
happening to
happening to you
happening to you because
happening to you because this
happening to you because this karma
happening to you because this karma is
still
still operative.
The
The karma
The karma that
The karma that gave
The karma that gave you
The karma that gave you a
The karma that gave you a lousy
childhood
childhood is
The karma that gave you a lousy
childhood is the
childhood is the same
The karma that gave you a lousy
childhood is the same karma
childhood is the same karma that
The karma that gave you a lousy
childhood is the same karma that pulls
the
the trigger
the trigger to
the trigger to see
the trigger to see what
the trigger to see what it's
the trigger to see what it's like
the trigger to see what it's like to
kill
kill your
the trigger to see what it's like to
kill your classmates.
kill your classmates. It's
the trigger to see what it's like to
kill your classmates. It's all
kill your classmates. It's all the
the trigger to see what it's like to
kill your classmates. It's all the same
karma.
Therefore,
Therefore, to
karma.
Therefore, to understand
reality,
reality, the
reality, the pathway
reality, the pathway to
reality, the pathway to enlightenment
reality, the pathway to enlightenment to
understand
understand God
reality, the pathway to enlightenment to
understand God both
understand God both imminent
reality, the pathway to enlightenment to
understand God both imminent and
transcendent.
The
The one
transcendent.
The one thing
The one thing we
transcendent.
The one thing we stress
The one thing we stress at
transcendent.
The one thing we stress at the
The one thing we stress at the beginning
of
of every
of every lecture
is
is that
of every lecture
is that the
is that the basic
of every lecture
is that the basic defect
is that the basic defect of
of every lecture
is that the basic defect of the
is that the basic defect of the ego
of every lecture
is that the basic defect of the ego is
its
its belief
its belief in
its belief in causality.
There
There is
its belief in causality.
There is a
There is a this
its belief in causality.
There is a this causing
There is a this causing a
its belief in causality.
There is a this causing a that.
Instead,
Instead, we
Instead, we know
Instead, we know that
Instead, we know that all
Instead, we know that all things
Instead, we know that all things are
becoming
appearing
appearing to
appearing to be
appearing to be that
appearing to be that which
appearing to be that which they
appearing to be that which they appear
out
out of
appearing to be that which they appear
out of the
out of the presence
appearing to be that which they appear
out of the presence of
out of the presence of divinity
appearing to be that which they appear
out of the presence of divinity in
out of the presence of divinity in this
instant.
It's
It's out
instant.
It's out of
It's out of the
instant.
It's out of the now.
out
out of
out of the
out of the now
out of the now that
out of the now that this
out of the now that this that
out of the now that this that you
witness
witness is
out of the now that this that you
witness is arising.
witness is arising. It
out of the now that this that you
witness is arising. It is
witness is arising. It is not
out of the now that this that you
witness is arising. It is not out
witness is arising. It is not out of
out of the now that this that you
witness is arising. It is not out of the
then.
All
All things
then.
All things arise
and
and express
and express themselves
as
as the
and express themselves
as the fulfillment
as the fulfillment of
and express themselves
as the fulfillment of their
as the fulfillment of their karmic
potentiality
as
as it
potentiality
as it opens
as it opens thusly.
It
It is
It is not
It is not because
It is not because it's
It is not because it's caused
It is not because it's caused by
anything
anything anywhere
It is not because it's caused by
anything anywhere else
anything anywhere else in
It is not because it's caused by
anything anywhere else in time
anything anywhere else in time or
It is not because it's caused by
anything anywhere else in time or place.
Unless
Unless you
Unless you realize
Unless you realize that
Unless you realize that you
Unless you realize that you will
Unless you realize that you will always
presume
presume that
Unless you realize that you will always
presume that there
presume that there is
Unless you realize that you will always
presume that there is a
presume that there is a me
Unless you realize that you will always
presume that there is a me in
presume that there is a me in ego
Unless you realize that you will always
presume that there is a me in ego that
is
is the
is the cause
is the cause of
is the cause of what's
is the cause of what's happening.
is the cause of what's happening. You
will
will always
is the cause of what's happening. You
will always presume
will always presume that
is the cause of what's happening. You
will always presume that there's
will always presume that there's a
is the cause of what's happening. You
will always presume that there's a me
causing
causing this
causing this decision.
causing this decision. There's
causing this decision. There's a
causing this decision. There's a me
doing
doing that
causing this decision. There's a me
doing that a
doing that a that
causing this decision. There's a me
doing that a that action.
You
You cannot
You cannot get
You cannot get over
You cannot get over identifying
your
your personal
You cannot get over identifying
your personal self
your personal self with
You cannot get over identifying
your personal self with the
your personal self with the ego
You cannot get over identifying
your personal self with the ego unless
you
you get
you get beyond
you get beyond causality.
Therefore,
Therefore, causality
you get beyond causality.
Therefore, causality is
Therefore, causality is the
you get beyond causality.
Therefore, causality is the biggest
basis
basis for
basis for the
basis for the continuence
basis for the continuence of
basis for the continuence of the
basis for the continuence of the belief
in
in the
basis for the continuence of the belief
in the ego
self.
Everything
Everything is
self.
Everything is happening
Everything is happening spontaneously.
There's
There's nothing
There's nothing causing
There's nothing causing anything
There's nothing causing anything else.
There
There is
There's nothing causing anything else.
There is no
There is no thinker
There's nothing causing anything else.
There is no thinker causing
There is no thinker causing you
There's nothing causing anything else.
There is no thinker causing you to
think.
The
The thinkingness
think.
The thinkingness is
The thinkingness is happening
think.
The thinkingness is happening of
The thinkingness is happening of its
own.
Thinkingness
Thinkingness has
own.
Thinkingness has a
Thinkingness has a life
own.
Thinkingness has a life of
Thinkingness has a life of its
own.
Thinkingness has a life of its own.
Thinkingness
Thinkingness doesn't
Thinkingness doesn't even
Thinkingness doesn't even give
Thinkingness doesn't even give a
Thinkingness doesn't even give a rap
about
about you.
[laughter]
You
You think
[laughter]
You think you're
You think you're thinking
[laughter]
You think you're thinking this
You think you're thinking this is
[laughter]
You think you're thinking this is your
friend.
Let's
Let's all
friend.
Let's all do
Let's all do an
friend.
Let's all do an experiment.
Let's all do an experiment. Let's
friend.
Let's all do an experiment. Let's all
stop
stop thinking
stop thinking when
stop thinking when I
stop thinking when I say
stop thinking when I say stop.
When
When I
stop thinking when I say stop.
When I say
When I say stop,
I
I want
I want everybody
I want everybody to
I want everybody to command
I want everybody to command their
I want everybody to command their mind
to
to stop
I want everybody to command their mind
to stop thinking.
to stop thinking. Stop.
Uh-oh.
Uh-oh. Oh.
>> [laughter]
>> Oh.
>> Oh. Oh.
The
The mind
>> Oh. Oh.
The mind will
The mind will go
>> Oh. Oh.
The mind will go right
The mind will go right on
>> Oh. Oh.
The mind will go right on with
The mind will go right on with it
thinkingness
thinkingness because
thinkingness because it's
thinkingness because it's thinkingness
is
is coming
thinkingness because it's thinkingness
is coming from
is coming from itself.
thinkingness because it's thinkingness
is coming from itself. It's
is coming from itself. It's not
thinkingness because it's thinkingness
is coming from itself. It's not coming
from
from a
from a you.
from a you. There's
from a you. There's a
from a you. There's a you
from a you. There's a you that
from a you. There's a you that decides
that
that your
from a you. There's a you that decides
that your mind
that your mind is
from a you. There's a you that decides
that your mind is going
that your mind is going to
from a you. There's a you that decides
that your mind is going to think.
that your mind is going to think. It
does
does that
does that all
does that all by
does that all by itself.
does that all by itself. Doesn't
does that all by itself. Doesn't give
does that all by itself. Doesn't give a
rap
rap about
does that all by itself. Doesn't give a
rap about you.
Well,
Well, that's
Well, that's quite
Well, that's quite a
Well, that's quite a downer,
Well, that's quite a downer, isn't
Well, that's quite a downer, isn't it?
Your
Your mind
Well, that's quite a downer, isn't it?
Your mind doesn't
Your mind doesn't even
Well, that's quite a downer, isn't it?
Your mind doesn't even care
Your mind doesn't even care about
Well, that's quite a downer, isn't it?
Your mind doesn't even care about you
here.
here. You
here. You thought
here. You thought your
here. You thought your mind
here. You thought your mind was
here. You thought your mind was your
best
best friend.
It's
It's your
It's your mind
It's your mind that's
It's your mind that's going
It's your mind that's going to
It's your mind that's going to get
It's your mind that's going to get you
out
out of
It's your mind that's going to get you
out of the
out of the troubles
It's your mind that's going to get you
out of the troubles in
out of the troubles in the
It's your mind that's going to get you
out of the troubles in the world.
Let's
Let's see
Let's see what
Let's see what happens.
Here's
Here's a
Let's see what happens.
Here's a thought.
Where'
Where' the
Where' the thought
Where' the thought come
Where' the thought come from?
Yeah,
Yeah, I
Where' the thought come from?
Yeah, I drew
Yeah, I drew where
Where' the thought come from?
Yeah, I drew where it
Yeah, I drew where it came
Where' the thought come from?
Yeah, I drew where it came from.
Yeah, I drew where it came from. Where
it
it came
it came from
it came from is
it came from is right
it came from is right here.
Nowhere.
Came
Came from
Came from right
Came from right here.
Came from right here. Nothing.
Nothing
at
at all.
The
The thoughts
at all.
The thoughts come
The thoughts come out
at all.
The thoughts come out of
The thoughts come out of nothingness
and
and looking
and looking for
and looking for the
and looking for the self
and looking for the self within.
and looking for the self within. The
presence
presence of
and looking for the self within. The
presence of God
presence of God within
is
is that
is that which
is that which is
is that which is a
is that which is a priority
is that which is a priority to
is that which is a priority to the
is that which is a priority to the mind.
You
You have
is that which is a priority to the mind.
You have to
You have to catch
is that which is a priority to the mind.
You have to catch it
You have to catch it right
is that which is a priority to the mind.
You have to catch it right before
You have to catch it right before it
thinks.
thinks. Once
thinks. Once it
thinks. Once it thinks,
thinks. Once it thinks, you're
thinks. Once it thinks, you're looking
at
at the
thinks. Once it thinks, you're looking
at the thinking.
You
You have
You have to
You have to look
You have to look and
You have to look and catch
You have to look and catch right
You have to look and catch right be
You have to look and catch right be what
is
is it
You have to look and catch right be what
is it that
is it that exists
You have to look and catch right be what
is it that exists right
is it that exists right before
You have to look and catch right be what
is it that exists right before the
is it that exists right before the mind
starts
starts to
starts to think.
It
It is
starts to think.
It is continuously
It is continuously present.
It's
It's continuously
It's continuously present.
But
But consciousness
It's continuously present.
But consciousness itself
But consciousness itself does
It's continuously present.
But consciousness itself does not
But consciousness itself does not think.
Consciousness
Consciousness itself
is
is like
Consciousness itself
is like space.
Space
Space is
Space is not
Space is not thinking.
Space is not thinking. Space
Space is not thinking. Space is
Space is not thinking. Space is not
doing
doing anything.
But
But it
But it is
But it is out
But it is out of
But it is out of the
But it is out of the potentiality
But it is out of the potentiality of
space
space that
But it is out of the potentiality of
space that the
space that the pageantry
But it is out of the potentiality of
space that the pageantry of
space that the pageantry of life
But it is out of the potentiality of
space that the pageantry of life occurs
allows
allows it
allows it to
allows it to be
allows it to be witnessed.
The
The only
allows it to be witnessed.
The only reason
The only reason you
allows it to be witnessed.
The only reason you can
The only reason you can see
allows it to be witnessed.
The only reason you can see cat
the
the only
the only reason
the only reason you
the only reason you can
the only reason you can see
the only reason you can see cat
the only reason you can see cat is
become
become because
the only reason you can see cat is
become because it's
become because it's coming
the only reason you can see cat is
become because it's coming out
become because it's coming out of
the only reason you can see cat is
become because it's coming out of no
cat.
It's
It's because
cat.
It's because it's
It's because it's against
cat.
It's because it's against the
It's because it's against the background
of
of nothing
of nothing that
of nothing that you
of nothing that you can
of nothing that you can see
of nothing that you can see it.
If
If it
of nothing that you can see it.
If it was
If it was against
of nothing that you can see it.
If it was against the
If it was against the background
of nothing that you can see it.
If it was against the background of
something,
you
you can't
something,
you can't can't
you can't can't see
something,
you can't can't see cat.
[music]
The
The lectures
[music]
The lectures we
The lectures we gave
[music]
The lectures we gave on
The lectures we gave on the
[music]
The lectures we gave on the structure
The lectures we gave on the structure of
the
the ego
were
were because
the ego
were because through
were because through certain
understandings
the
the ego
understandings
the ego begins
the ego begins to
understandings
the ego begins to collapse.
What
What one
What one is
What one is seeking
What one is seeking in
What one is seeking in so-called
self-realization
is
the
the awareness
is
the awareness of
the awareness of one's
is
the awareness of one's identity
the awareness of one's identity with
that
that which
that which exists
prior
prior to
that which exists
prior to thought.
prior to thought. I
that which exists
prior to thought. I am
prior to thought. I am that
that which exists
prior to thought. I am that which
prior to thought. I am that which does
not
not think.
That
That which
not think.
That which I
That which I am
not think.
That which I am doesn't
That which I am doesn't think
not think.
That which I am doesn't think at
That which I am doesn't think at all.
People
People say
People say what
People say what are
People say what are you
People say what are you going
People say what are you going to
People say what are you going to talk
about?
about? I
People say what are you going to talk
about? I have
about? I have the
People say what are you going to talk
about? I have the slightest
about? I have the slightest idea.
People say what are you going to talk
about? I have the slightest idea. So,
about? I have the slightest idea. So, I
read
read the
read the thing.
I'll
I'll tell
read the thing.
I'll tell you
I'll tell you how
read the thing.
I'll tell you how long
I'll tell you how long I
read the thing.
I'll tell you how long I spend
I'll tell you how long I spend thinking
about
about what
about what I'm
about what I'm going
about what I'm going to
about what I'm going to say.
110,000th
110,000th of
about what I'm going to say.
110,000th of a
110,000th of a second
from
from here
from here to
from here to here
from here to here is
from here to here is 110,000th
from here to here is 110,000th of
from here to here is 110,000th of a
second.
110,000
110,000 of
110,000 of a
110,000 of a second
110,000 of a second is
110,000 of a second is how
110,000 of a second is how long
110,000 of a second is how long I
110,000 of a second is how long I got
110,000 of a second is how long I got to
believe
believe what
110,000 of a second is how long I got to
believe what I'm
believe what I'm going
110,000 of a second is how long I got to
believe what I'm going to
believe what I'm going to say.
It
It happens
It happens of
It happens of its
It happens of its own.
Everything
Everything happens
It happens of its own.
Everything happens spontaneously
as
as an
as an expression
as an expression of
as an expression of its
as an expression of its essence.
[snorts]
The
The style
The style of
The style of its
The style of its expression
The style of its expression is
influenced
influenced by
The style of its expression is
influenced by karmic
influenced by karmic propensities.
That's
That's why
That's why we
That's why we spent
That's why we spent a
That's why we spent a lecture
That's why we spent a lecture on
That's why we spent a lecture on karma.
Another
Another difficulty
That's why we spent a lecture on karma.
Another difficulty with
Another difficulty with the
That's why we spent a lecture on karma.
Another difficulty with the western
world
world especially
is
is mankind
world especially
is mankind stumbles
is mankind stumbles along
world especially
is mankind stumbles along not
is mankind stumbles along not only
world especially
is mankind stumbles along not only with
illconceptions
illconceptions and
illconceptions and misconceptions
illconceptions and misconceptions about
the
the nature
illconceptions and misconceptions about
the nature of
the nature of divinity
illconceptions and misconceptions about
the nature of divinity and
the nature of divinity and therefore
illconceptions and misconceptions about
the nature of divinity and therefore of
himself
but
but he's
himself
but he's got
but he's got karmic
himself
but he's got karmic bumps
but he's got karmic bumps and
himself
but he's got karmic bumps and grinds
but he's got karmic bumps and grinds to
deal
deal with
deal with on
deal with on top
deal with on top of
deal with on top of it.
deal with on top of it. [laughter]
We
We said
deal with on top of it. [laughter]
We said last
We said last time
deal with on top of it. [laughter]
We said last time that
We said last time that the
deal with on top of it. [laughter]
We said last time that the newborn
the
the newborns
the newborns you
the newborns you can
the newborns you can calibrate
the newborns you can calibrate their
level
level of
the newborns you can calibrate their
level of consciousness
level of consciousness the
the newborns you can calibrate their
level of consciousness the minute
they're
they're born.
they're born. In
they're born. In fact,
they're born. In fact, the
they're born. In fact, the soul
they're born. In fact, the soul doesn't
enter
enter the
they're born. In fact, the soul doesn't
enter the embryo
enter the embryo till
they're born. In fact, the soul doesn't
enter the embryo till the
enter the embryo till the third
they're born. In fact, the soul doesn't
enter the embryo till the third month.
There's
There's no
There's no point
There's no point mourning
a
a miscarriage
There's no point mourning
a miscarriage in
a miscarriage in the
There's no point mourning
a miscarriage in the first,
a miscarriage in the first, second,
There's no point mourning
a miscarriage in the first, second, and
third
third month
third month because
third month because there's
third month because there's nobody
third month because there's nobody home
yet.
builder
builder builds
builder builds the
builder builds the building.
builder builds the building. Only
builder builds the building. Only at
builder builds the building. Only at a
certain
certain point
builder builds the building. Only at a
certain point can
certain point can you
builder builds the building. Only at a
certain point can you move
certain point can you move in.
Ah
Ah so
from
from that
Ah so
from that moment
from that moment on
Ah so
from that moment on however
from that moment on however you
Ah so
from that moment on however you can
calibrate
calibrate the
calibrate the level
calibrate the level of
calibrate the level of consciousness
calibrate the level of consciousness of
the
the entity
calibrate the level of consciousness of
the entity the
the entity the being
calibrate the level of consciousness of
the entity the being potential
the entity the being potential human.
How
How is
How is it
How is it that
How is it that one
How is it that one comes
How is it that one comes in
How is it that one comes in with
How is it that one comes in with a
calibrated
calibrated level
How is it that one comes in with a
calibrated level of
calibrated level of consciousness
already?
You
You haven't
already?
You haven't even
You haven't even had
already?
You haven't even had a
You haven't even had a human
already?
You haven't even had a human life
You haven't even had a human life yet
already?
You haven't even had a human life yet to
the
to
to the
the
to the average
to the average understanding.
It's
It's because
It's because this
It's because this human
It's because this human life
It's because this human life is
It's because this human life is just
It's because this human life is just a
sequence.
That
That which
That which is
That which is prior
That which is prior to
That which is prior to thinkingness
That which is prior to thinkingness is
awareness
awareness consciousness.
Out
Out of
Out of the
Out of the unmanifest
infinite
infinite potentiality
Out of the unmanifest
infinite potentiality of
infinite potentiality of God
Out of the unmanifest
infinite potentiality of God arises
infinite potentiality of God arises the
manifest.
Out
Out of
manifest.
Out of the
Out of the manifest
manifest.
Out of the manifest arises
consciousness.
Out
Out of
consciousness.
Out of consciousness
Out of consciousness arises
consciousness.
Out of consciousness arises life.
Therefore
Therefore life
Therefore life itself
Therefore life itself is
Therefore life itself is entrance
Therefore life itself is entrance is
divinity
divinity expressed
Therefore life itself is entrance is
divinity expressed as
divinity expressed as beingness
as
as existence.
Life
cannot
cannot be
cannot be destroyed
cannot be destroyed or
cannot be destroyed or killed.
cannot be destroyed or killed. It
cannot be destroyed or killed. It can
only
only change
cannot be destroyed or killed. It can
only change form.
It's
It's like
It's like the
It's like the law
It's like the law of
It's like the law of conservation
It's like the law of conservation of
energy
energy or
It's like the law of conservation of
energy or the
energy or the law
It's like the law of conservation of
energy or the law of
energy or the law of conservation
It's like the law of conservation of
energy or the law of conservation of
matter.
matter. The
matter. The law
matter. The law of
matter. The law of the
matter. The law of the conservation
matter. The law of the conservation of
life
life is
matter. The law of the conservation of
life is that
life is that you
matter. The law of the conservation of
life is that you can
force
force life
force life to
force life to move
force life to move from
force life to move from this
force life to move from this form
force life to move from this form to
that
that form,
but
but you
but you cannot
but you cannot destroy
but you cannot destroy life.
We've
We've said
but you cannot destroy life.
We've said that
We've said that in
but you cannot destroy life.
We've said that in many
We've said that in many ways
but you cannot destroy life.
We've said that in many ways and
We've said that in many ways and we've
expressed
expressed it
expressed it in
expressed it in funny
expressed it in funny ways
expressed it in funny ways and
expressed it in funny ways and esoteric
ways.
We
We said
We said when
We said when you
We said when you swat
We said when you swat a
We said when you swat a fly
We said when you swat a fly it
We said when you swat a fly it doesn't
notice
notice it.
Let's
Let's re
Let's re reaffirm
when
when you
Let's re reaffirm
when you swat
when you swat a
Let's re reaffirm
when you swat a fly
when you swat a fly doesn't
Let's re reaffirm
when you swat a fly doesn't notice
when you swat a fly doesn't notice it.
Resist.
Resist. Goes
Resist. Goes right
Resist. Goes right on
Resist. Goes right on flying.
Resist. Goes right on flying. Resist.
Resist. Goes right on flying. Resist. I
told
told you
Resist. Goes right on flying. Resist. I
told you it
told you it moves
Resist. Goes right on flying. Resist. I
told you it moves from
told you it moves from physicality
Resist. Goes right on flying. Resist. I
told you it moves from physicality into
its
its atheric
its atheric body.
its atheric body. Goes
its atheric body. Goes right
its atheric body. Goes right on
its atheric body. Goes right on flying.
Any
Any of
its atheric body. Goes right on flying.
Any of you
Any of you have
its atheric body. Goes right on flying.
Any of you have been
Any of you have been out
its atheric body. Goes right on flying.
Any of you have been out of
Any of you have been out of body?
its atheric body. Goes right on flying.
Any of you have been out of body? You
realize
realize that
realize that one
realize that one minute
realize that one minute you're
realize that one minute you're laying
realize that one minute you're laying in
the
the sick
realize that one minute you're laying in
the sick bed
the sick bed in
realize that one minute you're laying in
the sick bed in in
the sick bed in in the
realize that one minute you're laying in
the sick bed in in the hospital.
the sick bed in in the hospital. Next
minute
minute you're
minute you're sitting
minute you're sitting up
minute you're sitting up in
minute you're sitting up in the
minute you're sitting up in the room
minute you're sitting up in the room and
watching
watching everything
minute you're sitting up in the room and
watching everything that's
watching everything that's happening.
You
You haven't
You haven't got
You haven't got a
You haven't got a problem
You haven't got a problem in
You haven't got a problem in the
You haven't got a problem in the world.
No
No pain,
You haven't got a problem in the world.
No pain, no
No pain, no nothing.
You haven't got a problem in the world.
No pain, no nothing. No
No pain, no nothing. No problem.
You haven't got a problem in the world.
No pain, no nothing. No problem. Don't
have
have to
have to go
have to go to
have to go to the
have to go to the bathroom.
have to go to the bathroom. All
have to go to the bathroom. All kinds
have to go to the bathroom. All kinds of
advantages.
advantages. No
have to go to the bathroom. All kinds of
advantages. No taxes.
advantages. No taxes. You
have to go to the bathroom. All kinds of
advantages. No taxes. You don't
advantages. No taxes. You don't have
have to go to the bathroom. All kinds of
advantages. No taxes. You don't have to
get
get dressed.
get dressed. Don't
get dressed. Don't have
get dressed. Don't have to
get dressed. Don't have to get
get dressed. Don't have to get up,
get dressed. Don't have to get up, go
get dressed. Don't have to get up, go to
bed.
H.
So
the
the essence
the essence of
the essence of God
the essence of God then
the essence of God then is
the essence of God then is the
the essence of God then is the infinite
unlimited
unlimited context
the essence of God then is the infinite
unlimited context of
unlimited context of the
the essence of God then is the infinite
unlimited context of the entire
universe.
God
God is
universe.
God is the
God is the infinite
universe.
God is the infinite context.
The
The infinite
The infinite context
The infinite context which
The infinite context which out
The infinite context which out of
The infinite context which out of which
the
the entire
The infinite context which out of which
the entire universe
the entire universe arises
is
is an
is an absolute
is an absolute perfect
is an absolute perfect karmic
is an absolute perfect karmic harmonic
balance.
balance. The
is an absolute perfect karmic harmonic
balance. The power
balance. The power of
is an absolute perfect karmic harmonic
balance. The power of God
balance. The power of God is
is an absolute perfect karmic harmonic
balance. The power of God is infinite
like
like a
like a giant
like a giant electromagnetic
like a giant electromagnetic field.
like a giant electromagnetic field. All
that
that exists
like a giant electromagnetic field. All
that exists throughout
that exists throughout any
like a giant electromagnetic field. All
that exists throughout any all
that exists throughout any all of
like a giant electromagnetic field. All
that exists throughout any all of time
anywhere
anywhere in
anywhere in the
anywhere in the universe
anywhere in the universe which
anywhere in the universe which is
constantly
constantly expanding
is
is held
is held in
is held in place
by
by this
is held in place
by this enormous
by this enormous electromagnetic
is held in place
by this enormous electromagnetic field
of
of infinite
of infinite power.
of infinite power. Infinite
of infinite power. Infinite power.
One
One of
of infinite power. Infinite power.
One of the
One of the first
of infinite power. Infinite power.
One of the first things
One of the first things that
of infinite power. Infinite power.
One of the first things that stuns
One of the first things that stuns you
when
when you
when you reach
when you reach a
when you reach a state
when you reach a state called
self-realization
is
is the
is the power
is the power is
is the power is of
is the power is of such
is the power is of such immensity
is the power is of such immensity that
no
no human
is the power is of such immensity that
no human imagination
no human imagination can
is the power is of such immensity that
no human imagination can even
no human imagination can even get
is the power is of such immensity that
no human imagination can even get near
describing
describing it.
Not
Not only
describing it.
Not only is
Not only is the
describing it.
Not only is the beauty
Not only is the beauty incapacitating
and
and stunning
and stunning and
and stunning and overwhelming
and stunning and overwhelming that
and stunning and overwhelming that you
can
can hardly
and stunning and overwhelming that you
can hardly breathe,
but
but the
but the power
but the power is
but the power is so
but the power is so infinite.
The
The idea
but the power is so infinite.
The idea that
The idea that anybody
but the power is so infinite.
The idea that anybody would
The idea that anybody would challenge
the
the power
the power of
the power of God
the power of God is
the power of God is so
the power of God is so funny
the power of God is so funny that
the power of God is so funny that it's
hysterical.
hysterical. It's
the power of God is so funny that it's
hysterical. It's so
hysterical. It's so pathetic.
It's
It's so
It's so pathetic.
It's so pathetic. If
It's so pathetic. If you've
It's so pathetic. If you've ever
It's so pathetic. If you've ever gone
It's so pathetic. If you've ever gone to
a
a huge
It's so pathetic. If you've ever gone to
a huge power
a huge power plant,
It's so pathetic. If you've ever gone to
a huge power plant, one
a huge power plant, one of
It's so pathetic. If you've ever gone to
a huge power plant, one of the
a huge power plant, one of the great
dams,
dams, and
dams, and watch
dams, and watch the
dams, and watch the great
dams, and watch the great turbines
coming
coming out,
and
and watch
and watch the
and watch the electric
and watch the electric power
and watch the electric power pulsing
out,
out, you
and watch the electric power pulsing
out, you know,
out, you know, it's
and watch the electric power pulsing
out, you know, it's so
out, you know, it's so incredible.
Hundreds
Hundreds of
Hundreds of thousands
Hundreds of thousands of
Hundreds of thousands of volts.
If
If you
Hundreds of thousands of volts.
If you just
If you just put
Hundreds of thousands of volts.
If you just put a
If you just put a little
Hundreds of thousands of volts.
If you just put a little hair
If you just put a little hair like
Hundreds of thousands of volts.
If you just put a little hair like that
would
would fry
would fry you.
would fry you. [laughter]
Therefore,
those
those who
those who hate
those who hate God
those who hate God and
those who hate God and oppose
those who hate God and oppose God
those who hate God and oppose God are
pathetic
pathetic and
those who hate God and oppose God are
pathetic and comical.
No
No such
No such thing
No such thing is
No such thing is even
No such thing is even possible.
They
They exist
No such thing is even possible.
They exist in
They exist in two
No such thing is even possible.
They exist in two different
They exist in two different domains.
This
This domain
This domain below
This domain below here
This domain below here is
This domain below here is is
This domain below here is is power.
I
I mean
This domain below here is is power.
I mean is
I mean is force
This domain below here is is power.
I mean is force and
I mean is force and that
This domain below here is is power.
I mean is force and that above
I mean is force and that above it
This domain below here is is power.
I mean is force and that above it is
power.
power. Huh?
Yeah.
Yeah. Now
power. Huh?
Yeah. Now power
Yeah. Now power is
power. Huh?
Yeah. Now power is not
Yeah. Now power is not threatened
power. Huh?
Yeah. Now power is not threatened by
force.
force. Power
force. Power is
force. Power is not
force. Power is not threatened
force. Power is not threatened by
force. Power is not threatened by force.
Reality
Reality is
force. Power is not threatened by force.
Reality is not
Reality is not threatened.
That's
That's what
That's what shocks
That's what shocks people
That's what shocks people when
That's what shocks people when they
That's what shocks people when they say,
"Well,
"Well, what
That's what shocks people when they say,
"Well, what about
"Well, what about aren't
That's what shocks people when they say,
"Well, what about aren't you
"Well, what about aren't you afraid
That's what shocks people when they say,
"Well, what about aren't you afraid of
war?"
war?" And
war?" And I
war?" And I say,
war?" And I say, "War
war?" And I say, "War and
war?" And I say, "War and peace
war?" And I say, "War and peace all
war?" And I say, "War and peace all the
same.
It's
It's all
It's all the
It's all the same
It's all the same thing.
hard
hard to
It's all the same thing.
hard to understand
because
because this
because this is
because this is a
because this is a world
because this is a world of
because this is a world of appearance
and
and the
because this is a world of appearance
and the manifestation
and the manifestation of
because this is a world of appearance
and the manifestation of that
and the manifestation of that which
because this is a world of appearance
and the manifestation of that which is
karmically
karmically necessary
to
to evolve
karmically necessary
to evolve spiritually.
to evolve spiritually. Therefore,
karmically necessary
to evolve spiritually. Therefore, this
is
is a
is a perfect
is a perfect world.
There's
There's no
is a perfect world.
There's no point
There's no point to
is a perfect world.
There's no point to change
There's no point to change one
is a perfect world.
There's no point to change one iota
There's no point to change one iota of
this
this world.
You
You tell
this world.
You tell me
You tell me where
this world.
You tell me where else
You tell me where else you're
this world.
You tell me where else you're going
You tell me where else you're going to
undo
undo your
undo your bad
undo your bad karma.
You
You think
undo your bad karma.
You think of
You think of all
undo your bad karma.
You think of all the
You think of all the cruelty.
undo your bad karma.
You think of all the cruelty. You
You think of all the cruelty. You look
at
at the
at the history
at the history of
at the history of mankind.
at the history of mankind. You
at the history of mankind. You think
at the history of mankind. You think of
all
all the
at the history of mankind. You think of
all the cruelty
all the cruelty that
at the history of mankind. You think of
all the cruelty that has
all the cruelty that has accumulated
here.
You
You think
here.
You think of
You think of the
here.
You think of the karma
You think of the karma of
here.
You think of the karma of the
You think of the karma of the people
that
that put
that put thousands
that put thousands of
that put thousands of people
that put thousands of people to
that put thousands of people to death
that put thousands of people to death in
gas
gas chambers
that put thousands of people to death in
gas chambers and
gas chambers and torture
that put thousands of people to death in
gas chambers and torture them.
Inquisition.
Inquisition. Good
Inquisition. Good God.
The
The amount
Inquisition. Good God.
The amount of
The amount of bad
Inquisition. Good God.
The amount of bad karma
The amount of bad karma that
Inquisition. Good God.
The amount of bad karma that needs
The amount of bad karma that needs to
Inquisition. Good God.
The amount of bad karma that needs to be
undone
undone is
undone is enormous.
undone is enormous. Well,
undone is enormous. Well, where
undone is enormous. Well, where are
undone is enormous. Well, where are you
going
going to
undone is enormous. Well, where are you
going to go
going to go and
undone is enormous. Well, where are you
going to go and do
going to go and do that?
undone is enormous. Well, where are you
going to go and do that? You're
going to go and do that? You're not
going
going to
going to do
going to do it
going to do it in
going to do it in heaven,
going to do it in heaven, I'll
going to do it in heaven, I'll tell
going to do it in heaven, I'll tell you.
Where
Where you
going to do it in heaven, I'll tell you.
Where you smell
Where you smell flowers
going to do it in heaven, I'll tell you.
Where you smell flowers and
Where you smell flowers and listen
going to do it in heaven, I'll tell you.
Where you smell flowers and listen and
sing
sing songs
sing songs and
have
have been
sing songs and
have been kindergarten
have been kindergarten parties
sing songs and
have been kindergarten parties every
day.
I
I don't
day.
I don't think
I don't think so,
day.
I don't think so, folks.
uh
uh the
uh the anguishes
uh the anguishes that
uh the anguishes that I've
uh the anguishes that I've gone
uh the anguishes that I've gone through
in
in my
uh the anguishes that I've gone through
in my life
in my life which
uh the anguishes that I've gone through
in my life which have
in my life which have been
uh the anguishes that I've gone through
in my life which have been considerable
probably
probably about
probably about as
probably about as far
probably about as far as
probably about as far as you
probably about as far as you can
probably about as far as you can go
probably about as far as you can go even
at
at times
didn't
didn't just
didn't just come
didn't just come up
didn't just come up about
didn't just come up about as
didn't just come up about as an
arbitrary
arbitrary sadistic
didn't just come up about as an
arbitrary sadistic god
arbitrary sadistic god that's
didn't just come up about as an
arbitrary sadistic god that's what
arbitrary sadistic god that's what I
thought
when
when I
thought
when I was
when I was a
thought
when I was a teenager
when I was a teenager or
thought
when I was a teenager or whatever
when I was a teenager or whatever it
thought
when I was a teenager or whatever it was
as
as I
as I said
as I said I
as I said I was
as I said I was a
as I said I was a very
as I said I was a very uh
as I said I was a very uh very
as I said I was a very uh very religious
highly
highly religious
and
and one
and one day
and one day it
and one day it came
and one day it came to
and one day it came to me
and one day it came to me as
and one day it came to me as a
and one day it came to me as a great
vision
vision vision,
and one day it came to me as a great
vision vision, a
vision vision, a great
and one day it came to me as a great
vision vision, a great revelation
[sighs]
[sighs] like
[sighs] like the
[sighs] like the opposite
[sighs] like the opposite of
[sighs] like the opposite of what
[sighs] like the opposite of what came
to
to me
[sighs] like the opposite of what came
to me many
to me many years
[sighs] like the opposite of what came
to me many years later
to me many years later in
[sighs] like the opposite of what came
to me many years later in which
to me many years later in which like
unfolded
unfolded before
unfolded before me
unfolded before me an
unfolded before me an awareness
unfolded before me an awareness of
unfolded before me an awareness of the
extent
extent and
unfolded before me an awareness of the
extent and the
extent and the totality
unfolded before me an awareness of the
extent and the totality of
extent and the totality of the
unfolded before me an awareness of the
extent and the totality of the suffering
of
of mankind
of mankind throughout
of mankind throughout all
of mankind throughout all of
of mankind throughout all of time.
of mankind throughout all of time. It
was
was so
of mankind throughout all of time. It
was so staggering.
was so staggering. It
of mankind throughout all of time. It
was so staggering. It it
was so staggering. It it would
of mankind throughout all of time. It
was so staggering. It it would blew
was so staggering. It it would blew me
away.
away. I
away. I didn't
away. I didn't know
away. I didn't know why
away. I didn't know why it
away. I didn't know why it didn't
away. I didn't know why it didn't just
die
die at
away. I didn't know why it didn't just
die at the
die at the moment.
Incredible.
Incredible. the
Incredible. the revelation.
Clockwork
Clockwork Orange
Incredible. the revelation.
Clockwork Orange is
Clockwork Orange is a
Incredible. the revelation.
Clockwork Orange is a comedy
Clockwork Orange is a comedy compared
Incredible. the revelation.
Clockwork Orange is a comedy compared to
what
what really
what really goes
what really goes on
what really goes on in
what really goes on in this
what really goes on in this world.
And
And in
what really goes on in this world.
And in that
And in that instant,
what really goes on in this world.
And in that instant, I
And in that instant, I became
what really goes on in this world.
And in that instant, I became an
atheist.
I
I couldn't
atheist.
I couldn't believe
I couldn't believe any
atheist.
I couldn't believe any god
I couldn't believe any god that
atheist.
I couldn't believe any god that could
allow
allow that
allow that totality
allow that totality of
allow that totality of human
allow that totality of human suffering
throughout
throughout all
allow that totality of human suffering
throughout all of
throughout all of life.
And
And then
And then I
And then I became
And then I became an
And then I became an atheist.
It
It was
And then I became an atheist.
It was a
It was a great
And then I became an atheist.
It was a great relief.
Get
Get rid
Get rid of
Get rid of that
Get rid of that threatening
Get rid of that threatening monster
Get rid of that threatening monster in
the
the sky.
Didn't
Didn't have
Didn't have to
Didn't have to walk
Didn't have to walk around
Didn't have to walk around in
Didn't have to walk around in fear
Didn't have to walk around in fear of
sin.
Spot
Spot on
Spot on my
Spot on my soul.
Didn't
Didn't have
Spot on my soul.
Didn't have to
Didn't have to be
Spot on my soul.
Didn't have to be scared
Didn't have to be scared of
Spot on my soul.
Didn't have to be scared of Jansen
swimming
swimming suit
swimming suit billboards.
It
It would
swimming suit billboards.
It would give
It would give you
swimming suit billboards.
It would give you a
It would give you a wicked
swimming suit billboards.
It would give you a wicked thought.
I
I was
I was pure
I was pure and
I was pure and holy
I was pure and holy that
I was pure and holy that morning
I was pure and holy that morning on
I was pure and holy that morning on the
way
way to
I was pure and holy that morning on the
way to communion.
29 Model
29 Model A
29 Model A Ford
29 Model A Ford with
29 Model A Ford with the
29 Model A Ford with the top
29 Model A Ford with the top down
29 Model A Ford with the top down and
Jesus.
Jesus. Here's
29 Model A Ford with the top down and
Jesus. Here's his
Jesus. Here's his 30
29 Model A Ford with the top down and
Jesus. Here's his 30 foot
Jesus. Here's his 30 foot long
29 Model A Ford with the top down and
Jesus. Here's his 30 foot long Jansson
swimsuit
swimsuit lady
swimsuit lady there.
At
At age
swimsuit lady there.
At age 12,
At age 12, you
swimsuit lady there.
At age 12, you know
At age 12, you know what
swimsuit lady there.
At age 12, you know what a
At age 12, you know what a boy's
swimsuit lady there.
At age 12, you know what a boy's mind
At age 12, you know what a boy's mind is
like.
They
They want
like.
They want to
They want to splat
like.
They want to splat on
They want to splat on my
like.
They want to splat on my soul.
God
God in
God in his
God in his infinite
God in his infinite mercy,
God in his infinite mercy, Lord.
So
So you
God in his infinite mercy, Lord.
So you can
So you can see
God in his infinite mercy, Lord.
So you can see that
So you can see that the
God in his infinite mercy, Lord.
So you can see that the false
So you can see that the false depictions
of
of God
of God are
of God are what
of God are what accounts
of God are what accounts for
of God are what accounts for atheism
of God are what accounts for atheism to
a
a great
of God are what accounts for atheism to
a great degree.
It's
It's just
It's just too
It's just too bloody,
It's just too bloody, too
It's just too bloody, too horrible,
It's just too bloody, too horrible, too
dreadful,
dreadful, too
It's just too bloody, too horrible, too
dreadful, too threatening,
dreadful, too threatening, too
anxietyprovoking.
All
All the
anxietyprovoking.
All the depictions
All the depictions of
anxietyprovoking.
All the depictions of God
All the depictions of God as
anxietyprovoking.
All the depictions of God as being
All the depictions of God as being at
the
the bottom
at
at the
the bottom
at the bottom
at the bottom which
the bottom
at the bottom which have
at the bottom which have infiltrated
religion
religion over
religion over the
religion over the centuries
accounts
accounts for
religion over the centuries
accounts for the
accounts for the religious
religion over the centuries
accounts for the religious wars
accounts for the religious wars the
inquisitions
the
the exquisite
inquisitions
the exquisite sadism
the exquisite sadism and
inquisitions
the exquisite sadism and cruelty
the exquisite sadism and cruelty that
paraded
paraded under
paraded under the
paraded under the banner
paraded under the banner of
paraded under the banner of religion
paraded under the banner of religion and
righteousness
etc.
etc. Huh.
In
In July,
etc. Huh.
In July, we
In July, we went
etc. Huh.
In July, we went through
In July, we went through about
etc. Huh.
In July, we went through about 18
different
different statements
different statements about
different statements about the
different statements about the true
reality
reality of
different statements about the true
reality of God
and
and excluded
and excluded all
and excluded all those
and excluded all those errors.
Those
Those errors
and excluded all those errors.
Those errors came
Those errors came in
and excluded all those errors.
Those errors came in through
misconceptions.
They
They sometimes
misconceptions.
They sometimes came
They sometimes came in,
misconceptions.
They sometimes came in, they
They sometimes came in, they often
misconceptions.
They sometimes came in, they often came
in
in innocently.
However,
However, they
in innocently.
However, they also
However, they also also
in innocently.
However, they also also came
However, they also also came in
in innocently.
However, they also also came in by
design.
design. And
design. And they
design. And they also
design. And they also came
design. And they also came in
design. And they also came in by
design. And they also came in by design.
Book
Book of
design. And they also came in by design.
Book of Revelations
Book of Revelations came
design. And they also came in by design.
Book of Revelations came into
Book of Revelations came into the
design. And they also came in by design.
Book of Revelations came into the New
Testament
Testament by
Testament by design.
Let's
Let's see
Testament by design.
Let's see if
Let's see if that's
Testament by design.
Let's see if that's so.
It
It was
It was by
It was by design.
The
The attack
It was by design.
The attack of
The attack of the
It was by design.
The attack of the demonic,
The attack of the demonic, the
It was by design.
The attack of the demonic, the lower
astral,
astral, on
astral, on that
astral, on that which
astral, on that which is
astral, on that which is holy.
If
If you
astral, on that which is holy.
If you hated
If you hated God,
astral, on that which is holy.
If you hated God, where
If you hated God, where would
astral, on that which is holy.
If you hated God, where would you
If you hated God, where would you go?
You
You wouldn't
You wouldn't go
You wouldn't go to
You wouldn't go to prison.
You wouldn't go to prison. It's
You wouldn't go to prison. It's already
been
been done
You wouldn't go to prison. It's already
been done there.
It's
It's already
It's already been
It's already been done
It's already been done there.
It's already been done there. No,
It's already been done there. No, you
would
would attack
you
you would
you would attack
you would attack the
you would attack the citadels
you would attack the citadels of
holiness.
holiness. That
you would attack the citadels of
holiness. That which
holiness. That which is
you would attack the citadels of
holiness. That which is really
holiness. That which is really a
you would attack the citadels of
holiness. That which is really a threat
to
to the
to the dominion
to the dominion of
to the dominion of that
to the dominion of that which
to the dominion of that which is
to the dominion of that which is ungodly
on
on this
to the dominion of that which is ungodly
on this in
on this in this
to the dominion of that which is ungodly
on this in this plane.
on this in this plane. Yeah.
In
In godly,
In godly, we're
In godly, we're succeeding.
In godly, we're succeeding. right
In godly, we're succeeding. right away
succeeding
succeeding because
In godly, we're succeeding. right away
succeeding because when
succeeding because when we
In godly, we're succeeding. right away
succeeding because when we calibrate
succeeding because when we calibrate the
levels
levels of
levels of consciousness
levels of consciousness we
levels of consciousness we noticed
levels of consciousness we noticed that
they
they stood
levels of consciousness we noticed that
they stood at
they stood at 190
throughout
throughout all
throughout all the
throughout all the Middle
throughout all the Middle Ages
throughout
throughout all
throughout all the Middle Ages
throughout all recent
throughout all recent history
throughout all the Middle Ages
throughout all recent history throughout
the
the last
the last thousand
the last thousand years
the last thousand years the
consciousness
consciousness level
the last thousand years the
consciousness level of
consciousness level of all
the last thousand years the
consciousness level of all of
consciousness level of all of mankind
the last thousand years the
consciousness level of all of mankind at
the
the time
the time of
the time of the
the time of the birth
the time of the birth of
the time of the birth of the
the time of the birth of the Buddha
the time of the birth of the Buddha was
by
by the
by the time
by the time of
by the time of the
by the time of the birth
by the time of the birth of
by the time of the birth of Jesus
by the time of the birth of Jesus Christ
it
it was
by the time of the birth of Jesus Christ
it was 100
where
where what
where what is
where what is that
where what is that fear
mankind
mankind at
where what is that fear
mankind at the
mankind at the time
where what is that fear
mankind at the time of
mankind at the time of the
where what is that fear
mankind at the time of the birth
mankind at the time of the birth of
Christ
Christ calibrated
Christ calibrated at
Christ calibrated at 100
that's
that's all
Christ calibrated at 100
that's all of
that's all of mankind
slowly
slowly slowly
slowly slowly it
slowly slowly it crept
slowly slowly it crept up
slowly slowly it crept up and
slowly slowly it crept up and by
slowly slowly it crept up and by the
year
year 1100
slowly slowly it crept up and by the
year 1100 1200
year 1100 1200 it
slowly slowly it crept up and by the
year 1100 1200 it was
year 1100 1200 it was 190
by
by the
by the year
by the year 1300400
by
by the
by the 1600s
by the 1600s in
by the 1600s in the
by the 1600s in the 1700s
by the 1600s in the 1700s in
by the 1600s in the 1700s in the
by the 1600s in the 1700s in the 1800s
and
and early
by the 1600s in the 1700s in the 1800s
and early 1900s
and early 1900s it
by the 1600s in the 1700s in the 1800s
and early 1900s it stayed
and early 1900s it stayed at
by the 1600s in the 1700s in the 1800s
and early 1900s it stayed at 190.
Well
Well during
Well during that
Well during that time
Well during that time man
Well during that time man was
Well during that time man was evolving.
So
So why
Well during that time man was evolving.
So why wasn't
So why wasn't the
Well during that time man was evolving.
So why wasn't the collect
So why wasn't the collect the
Well during that time man was evolving.
So why wasn't the collect the level
So why wasn't the collect the level of
collective
collective consciousness
collective consciousness of
collective consciousness of mankind
evolving?
Because
Because there's
Because there's lots
Because there's lots that's
Because there's lots that's against
Because there's lots that's against it.
It's
It's evolving.
They
They have
They have their
They have their own
They have their own TV
They have their own TV stations
They have their own TV stations and
their
their own
They have their own TV stations and
their own [laughter]
their own [laughter] TV
They have their own TV stations and
their own [laughter] TV channels
in
in which
in which wickedness
and
and that
in which wickedness
and that which
and that which is
in which wickedness
and that which is denigrates
and that which is denigrates God
in which wickedness
and that which is denigrates God and
and that which is denigrates God and the
reverence
reverence for
reverence for that
reverence for that which
reverence for that which is
reverence for that which is sacred
reverence for that which is sacred and
holy
holy is
reverence for that which is sacred and
holy is celebrated.
It's
It's celebrated
It's celebrated because
It's celebrated because they'll
It's celebrated because they'll tell
It's celebrated because they'll tell you
why
why it's
It's celebrated because they'll tell you
why it's profitable.
why it's profitable. They'll
It's celebrated because they'll tell you
why it's profitable. They'll tell
why it's profitable. They'll tell you
that
Grand
Grand Theft
that
Grand Theft Auto
Grand Theft Auto 3
that
Grand Theft Auto 3 by
Grand Theft Auto 3 by City,
which
which is
which is how
which is how to
which is how to rob,
which is how to rob, kill,
beat
beat up
which is how to rob, kill,
beat up people,
beat up people, become
which is how to rob, kill,
beat up people, become a
beat up people, become a criminal,
have
have a
have a prostitute,
have a prostitute, and
have a prostitute, and then
have a prostitute, and then kill
have a prostitute, and then kill her
have a prostitute, and then kill her so
you
you can
have a prostitute, and then kill her so
you can get
you can get your
have a prostitute, and then kill her so
you can get your money
you can get your money back.
Would
Would you
Would you believe
Would you believe that?
No,
No, that's
Would you believe that?
No, that's not
No, that's not the
Would you believe that?
No, that's not the worst
No, that's not the worst of
Would you believe that?
No, that's not the worst of it.
No, that's not the worst of it. That's
patently
degenerate.
degenerate. That's
patently
degenerate. That's patently
degenerate. That's patently degenerate.
And
And they
And they tell
And they tell you
And they tell you it
And they tell you it sells.
And they tell you it sells. Of
And they tell you it sells. Of course,
vice
vice is
And they tell you it sells. Of course,
vice is always
vice is always sold.
And they tell you it sells. Of course,
vice is always sold. That's
vice is always sold. That's not
And they tell you it sells. Of course,
vice is always sold. That's not exactly
news.
No,
No, that
news.
No, that wasn't
No, that wasn't what
news.
No, that wasn't what was
No, that wasn't what was shopping.
shopping
shopping was
Time
Time magazine
wrote
wrote an
wrote an essay
wrote an essay a
wrote an essay a couple
wrote an essay a couple weeks
wrote an essay a couple weeks ago
extolling
extolling the
wrote an essay a couple weeks ago
extolling the virtues
extolling the virtues of
wrote an essay a couple weeks ago
extolling the virtues of it
extolling the virtues of it as
wrote an essay a couple weeks ago
extolling the virtues of it as a
creative
creative as
creative as creative
creative as creative freedom.
creative as creative freedom. Ah
see
see the
creative as creative freedom. Ah
see the that
see the that which
creative as creative freedom. Ah
see the that which is
negative
negative used
negative used to
negative used to be
negative used to be identified
negative used to be identified as
negative used to be identified as that
which
which is
negative used to be identified as that
which is ugly
which is ugly and
negative used to be identified as that
which is ugly and depraved
which is ugly and depraved and
negative used to be identified as that
which is ugly and depraved and corrupt
etc.
etc. Now
etc. Now it's
etc. Now it's disguised.
etc. Now it's disguised. The
etc. Now it's disguised. The wolf
etc. Now it's disguised. The wolf is
etc. Now it's disguised. The wolf is in
the
the sheep's
etc. Now it's disguised. The wolf is in
the sheep's clothing.
It's
It's called
It's called freedom.
It's called freedom. Freedom,
the
the degradation
It's called freedom. Freedom,
the degradation of
the degradation of freedom
It's called freedom. Freedom,
the degradation of freedom to
the degradation of freedom to license.
And
And it's
And it's used
And it's used for
And it's used for reasons
And it's used for reasons of
And it's used for reasons of obscenity
and
and depravity
And it's used for reasons of obscenity
and depravity and
and depravity and degeneracy.
Well,
Well, it's
Well, it's freedom
Well, it's freedom of
Well, it's freedom of expression.
Well,
Well, isn't
Well, it's freedom of expression.
Well, isn't everything
Ben
Ben L
Ben L is
Ben L is expressing
Ben L is expressing his
Ben L is expressing his political
Ben L is expressing his political views?
What
What the
Ben L is expressing his political views?
What the hell?
What the hell? [laughter]
If
If there's
If there's no
If there's no criteria
If there's no criteria in
If there's no criteria in a
If there's no criteria in a non-theistic
context,
context, there's
If there's no criteria in a non-theistic
context, there's no
context, there's no criteria
If there's no criteria in a non-theistic
context, there's no criteria of
context, there's no criteria of right
and
and wrong,
and wrong, good
and wrong, good or
and wrong, good or bad,
and wrong, good or bad, preferable
versus
versus non-preferable,
is
is only
is only what
is only what makes
is only what makes money.
There's
There's video
is only what makes money.
There's video games
There's video games that
is only what makes money.
There's video games that are
There's video games that are so
is only what makes money.
There's video games that are so beyond
the
the pale
the pale that
the pale that you
the pale that you can't
the pale that you can't even
the pale that you can't even believe
that
that they're
the pale that you can't even believe
that they're actually
that they're actually sold
the pale that you can't even believe
that they're actually sold on
that they're actually sold on the
shelves.
shelves. In
shelves. In fact,
shelves. In fact, some
shelves. In fact, some companies,
shelves. In fact, some companies, I
guess,
guess, are
shelves. In fact, some companies, I
guess, are used
guess, are used to
shelves. In fact, some companies, I
guess, are used to show
guess, are used to show to
shelves. In fact, some companies, I
guess, are used to show to sell
guess, are used to show to sell them.
No,
No, that's
No, that's not
No, that's not what
No, that's not what I'm
No, that's not what I'm worried
No, that's not what I'm worried about
No, that's not what I'm worried about at
all.
all. Not
No, that's not what I'm worried about at
all. Not that
all. Not that I
No, that's not what I'm worried about at
all. Not that I worry
all. Not that I worry about
No, that's not what I'm worried about at
all. Not that I worry about it.
Joining
Joining each
Joining each other
Joining each other up
Joining each other up on
Joining each other up on the
Joining each other up on the street
Joining each other up on the street says
nothing
nothing to
Joining each other up on the street says
nothing to worry
nothing to worry about
Joining each other up on the street says
nothing to worry about that.
nothing to worry about that. Selling
dope
dope and
dope and killing
dope and killing people
dope and killing people and
dope and killing people and all,
dope and killing people and all, that's
run-of-the-mill.
That's
That's the
That's the upper
That's the upper levels
That's the upper levels of
That's the upper levels of hell.
That's
That's games
That's the upper levels of hell.
That's games land.
That's games land. No,
That's the upper levels of hell.
That's games land. No, it
That's games land. No, it gets
That's the upper levels of hell.
That's games land. No, it gets down
That's games land. No, it gets down more
serious
serious when
serious when the
serious when the infection
serious when the infection begins
serious when the infection begins to
distort
distort the
serious when the infection begins to
distort the capacity
distort the capacity to
serious when the infection begins to
distort the capacity to tell
distort the capacity to tell truth
serious when the infection begins to
distort the capacity to tell truth from
falsehood,
the
the holy
falsehood,
the holy from
the holy from the
falsehood,
the holy from the unholy,
the holy from the unholy, and
falsehood,
the holy from the unholy, and the
the holy from the unholy, and the sacred
from
from the
from the profane.
The
The perversion
from the profane.
The perversion is
The perversion is the
from the profane.
The perversion is the perversion
of
of the
of the third
of the third eye
of the third eye of
of the third eye of spiritual
discernment.
If
If you
If you think
If you think that
If you think that which
If you think that which is
If you think that which is wicked
If you think that which is wicked is
good
good and
If you think that which is wicked is
good and and
good and and nothing
If you think that which is wicked is
good and and nothing but
good and and nothing but nothing
If you think that which is wicked is
good and and nothing but nothing but
freedom
freedom and
freedom and just
freedom and just a
freedom and just a game,
freedom and just a game, then
you're
you're in
freedom and just a game, then
you're in worse
you're in worse shape
freedom and just a game, then
you're in worse shape than
you're in worse shape than the
freedom and just a game, then
you're in worse shape than the killer
you're in worse shape than the killer on
the
the streets.
The
The killer
the streets.
The killer on
The killer on the
the streets.
The killer on the streets
The killer on the streets knows
the streets.
The killer on the streets knows what
he's
he's doing
he's doing when
he's doing when he
he's doing when he kills
he's doing when he kills somebody.
He's
He's in
he's doing when he kills somebody.
He's in better
He's in better shape
he's doing when he kills somebody.
He's in better shape than
He's in better shape than the
he's doing when he kills somebody.
He's in better shape than the person
He's in better shape than the person who
does
does it
and
and thinks
does it
and thinks that
and thinks that he's
does it
and thinks that he's just
and thinks that he's just expressing
does it
and thinks that he's just expressing his
political
political freedom.
No,
No, it
political freedom.
No, it was
No, it was a
political freedom.
No, it was a sad
No, it was a sad day
political freedom.
No, it was a sad day when
No, it was a sad day when I
political freedom.
No, it was a sad day when I read
No, it was a sad day when I read that.
Just
Just as
Just as the
Just as the New
Just as the New York
Just as the New York Times
Just as the New York Times wrote
Just as the New York Times wrote an
apology
apology for
Just as the New York Times wrote an
apology for M
apology for M Eminem,
rape
rape your
rape your sister,
rape your sister, kill
rape your sister, kill your
rape your sister, kill your mother,
rape your sister, kill your mother, chop
your
your brother
rape your sister, kill your mother, chop
your brother to
your brother to death,
and
and all
and all the
and all the little
and all the little Gary.
and all the little Gary. So
and all the little Gary. So those
and all the little Gary. So those those
kinds
kinds of
and all the little Gary. So those those
kinds of things
kinds of things are
and all the little Gary. So those those
kinds of things are way
kinds of things are way in
and all the little Gary. So those those
kinds of things are way in the
kinds of things are way in the bottom
here
and
and we
here
and we don't
and we don't really
here
and we don't really worry
and we don't really worry about
here
and we don't really worry about them
because
because they're
because they're easily
because they're easily recognizable.
What
What is
because they're easily recognizable.
What is not
What is not recognizable
is
is the
is the perversion
is the perversion of
is the perversion of logic
is the perversion of logic and
is the perversion of logic and truth
is the perversion of logic and truth to
subserve.
So
So that
So that is
So that is the
So that is the new
So that is the new sheep.
So that is the new sheep. That
So that is the new sheep. That is
So that is the new sheep. That is the
wolf's
wolf's that
So that is the new sheep. That is the
wolf's that is
wolf's that is the
So that is the new sheep. That is the
wolf's that is the new
wolf's that is the new sheep's
So that is the new sheep. That is the
wolf's that is the new sheep's clothing
that
that hides
that hides the
that hides the wolf.
that hides the wolf. The
that hides the wolf. The satanic
that hides the wolf. The satanic is
that hides the wolf. The satanic is easy
to
to see.
that hides the wolf. The satanic is easy
to see. The
to see. The satanic
that hides the wolf. The satanic is easy
to see. The satanic is
to see. The satanic is just
that hides the wolf. The satanic is easy
to see. The satanic is just chopping
people
people up.
people up. killing,
people up. killing, rape,
people up. killing, rape, murder,
people up. killing, rape, murder, drugs,
suicide,
suicide, run-of-the-mill,
cheap
cheap everyday
cheap everyday stuff,
[laughter]
but
but that
but that you
but that you can
but that you can say
but that you can say yes
but that you can say yes or
but that you can say yes or no
but that you can say yes or no to.
but that you can say yes or no to. You
can
can say
but that you can say yes or no to. You
can say yes
can say yes or
but that you can say yes or no to. You
can say yes or no.
can say yes or no. It's
but that you can say yes or no to. You
can say yes or no. It's clear
can say yes or no. It's clear and
obvious
obvious what
obvious what it
obvious what it is.
obvious what it is. No,
obvious what it is. No, it's
obvious what it is. No, it's when
obvious what it is. No, it's when it
subverts
subverts the
obvious what it is. No, it's when it
subverts the third
subverts the third eye,
obvious what it is. No, it's when it
subverts the third eye, your
subverts the third eye, your spiritual
eye.
eye. So,
eye. So, you
eye. So, you cannot
eye. So, you cannot tell
truth
truth from
eye. So, you cannot tell
truth from falsehood
truth from falsehood anymore.
And
And mankind
And mankind cannot
And mankind cannot tell
And mankind cannot tell truth
And mankind cannot tell truth from
falsehood.
And
And that's
And that's why
And that's why the
And that's why the Buddha
And that's why the Buddha said
And that's why the Buddha said there's
only
only one
And that's why the Buddha said there's
only one sin
only one sin that
And that's why the Buddha said there's
only one sin that is
only one sin that is of
And that's why the Buddha said there's
only one sin that is of ignorance.
only one sin that is of ignorance. Jesus
Christ
Christ said
Christ said there's
Christ said there's only
Christ said there's only one
Christ said there's only one sin
Christ said there's only one sin that's
ignorance.
ignorance. Krishna
Christ said there's only one sin that's
ignorance. Krishna said
ignorance. Krishna said there's
Christ said there's only one sin that's
ignorance. Krishna said there's only
ignorance. Krishna said there's only one
sin
sin that's
sin that's ignorance.
They
They also
sin that's ignorance.
They also said
They also said that
sin that's ignorance.
They also said that if
They also said that if your
sin that's ignorance.
They also said that if your intention
They also said that if your intention is
correct,
correct, it
correct, it doesn't
correct, it doesn't make
correct, it doesn't make any
correct, it doesn't make any difference
if
if you're
correct, it doesn't make any difference
if you're if
if you're if you're
correct, it doesn't make any difference
if you're if you're wrong.
Krishna,
Krishna, Jesus,
Krishna, Jesus, Buddha,
Krishna, Jesus, Buddha, they
Krishna, Jesus, Buddha, they all
Krishna, Jesus, Buddha, they all said
Krishna, Jesus, Buddha, they all said if
your
your intention
Krishna, Jesus, Buddha, they all said if
your intention is
your intention is reverence
Krishna, Jesus, Buddha, they all said if
your intention is reverence for
your intention is reverence for that
which
which you
which you hold
which you hold to
which you hold to be
which you hold to be [clears throat]
sacred,
sacred, then
which you hold to be [clears throat]
sacred, then even
sacred, then even if
which you hold to be [clears throat]
sacred, then even if you're
sacred, then even if you're an
which you hold to be [clears throat]
sacred, then even if you're an error,
Krishna
Krishna says
Krishna says you
Krishna says you will
Krishna says you will still
Krishna says you will still be
Krishna says you will still be my
beloved.
And
And Jesus
And Jesus Christ
And Jesus Christ stands
And Jesus Christ stands for
And Jesus Christ stands for the
salvation
salvation of
And Jesus Christ stands for the
salvation of those
salvation of those who
And Jesus Christ stands for the
salvation of those who have
salvation of those who have fallen
And Jesus Christ stands for the
salvation of those who have fallen by
the
the way
the way out
the way out of
the way out of mistakenness.
So
So man's
the way out of mistakenness.
So man's struggle
So man's struggle over
the way out of mistakenness.
So man's struggle over all
So man's struggle over all those
centuries
centuries centuries
why
why was
centuries centuries
why was he
why was he so
centuries centuries
why was he so slow
why was he so slow why
centuries centuries
why was he so slow why did
why was he so slow why did it
centuries centuries
why was he so slow why did it take
why was he so slow why did it take you
500 years
500 years to
500 years to get
500 years to get from
500 years to get from one
500 years to get from one place
500 years to get from one place to
500 years to get from one place to the
next
next I
500 years to get from one place to the
next I mean
next I mean science
500 years to get from one place to the
next I mean science advanced
other
other areas
other areas of
other areas of human
other areas of human knowledge
other areas of human knowledge advanced
what's
what's the
other areas of human knowledge advanced
what's the matter
what's the matter with
other areas of human knowledge advanced
what's the matter with the
what's the matter with the level
other areas of human knowledge advanced
what's the matter with the level of
human
human consciousness
human consciousness it's
human consciousness it's stuck
human consciousness it's stuck at
human consciousness it's stuck at 190
human consciousness it's stuck at 190 in
81 1982
81 1982 198
81 1982 198 1983
from
from the
81 1982 198 1983
from the from
from the from the
81 1982 198 1983
from the from the year
from the from the year 1
81 1982 198 1983
from the from the year 1 1200
from the from the year 1 1200 all
81 1982 198 1983
from the from the year 1 1200 all the
way
way up
way up through
way up through the
way up through the late
way up through the late 1980s
in
in our
way up through the late 1980s
in our recent
in our recent lifetime
way up through the late 1980s
in our recent lifetime it
in our recent lifetime it is
way up through the late 1980s
in our recent lifetime it is at
in our recent lifetime it is at 190
what
what is
what is the
what is the world
what is the world like
what is the world like at
what is the world like at 190
190 is
190 is a
what is the world like at 190
190 is a solar
190 is a solar plexus
what is the world like at 190
190 is a solar plexus pride
190 is a solar plexus pride and
what is the world like at 190
190 is a solar plexus pride and it's
pride
pride pride
pride pride and
pride pride and gain
pride pride and gain the
pride pride and gain the world
pride pride and gain the world I
pride pride and gain the world I grew
pride pride and gain the world I grew up
in
in it
pride pride and gain the world I grew up
in it was
in it was the
pride pride and gain the world I grew up
in it was the bigger
in it was the bigger car
pride pride and gain the world I grew up
in it was the bigger car the
in it was the bigger car the better
pride pride and gain the world I grew up
in it was the bigger car the better job
the
the bigger
the bigger title
the bigger title make
the bigger title make a
the bigger title make a success
the bigger title make a success of
yourself.
yourself. The
the bigger title make a success of
yourself. The rule
yourself. The rule was
the bigger title make a success of
yourself. The rule was success.
Then
Then in
Then in the
Then in the late
Then in the late 80s,
Then in the late 80s, for
Then in the late 80s, for mysterious
reasons,
it
it jumped
it jumped to
it jumped to 207.
The
The world
it jumped to 207.
The world is
The world is now
it jumped to 207.
The world is now on
The world is now on the
it jumped to 207.
The world is now on the road
The world is now on the road to
integrity.
And
And this
integrity.
And this week's
And this week's Fortune
integrity.
And this week's Fortune magazine,
And this week's Fortune magazine, the
front
front of
front of it
front of it is
front of it is all
front of it is all about
front of it is all about integrity.
Integrity
Integrity in
front of it is all about integrity.
Integrity in corporate
Integrity in corporate America.
Integrity.
Integrity. Can
Integrity. Can you
Integrity. Can you imagine
Integrity. Can you imagine Fortune
magazine
magazine having
Integrity. Can you imagine Fortune
magazine having an
magazine having an article
Integrity. Can you imagine Fortune
magazine having an article on
magazine having an article on integrity
in
in America
in America on
in America on the
in America on the front
in America on the front cover
in America on the front cover 10
in America on the front cover 10 years
ago?
ago? What
in America on the front cover 10 years
ago? What a
ago? What a laugh.
in America on the front cover 10 years
ago? What a laugh. You
ago? What a laugh. You know,
integrity
integrity is
integrity is the
integrity is the new
uh
uh paradigm
integrity is the new
uh paradigm and
uh paradigm and we
integrity is the new
uh paradigm and we spoke
uh paradigm and we spoke of
integrity is the new
uh paradigm and we spoke of that.
uh paradigm and we spoke of that. Okay.
So
So God
So God first
So God first sneaks
So God first sneaks into
So God first sneaks into human
So God first sneaks into human life
So God first sneaks into human life uh
here
here on
So God first sneaks into human life uh
here on the
here on the level
So God first sneaks into human life uh
here on the level of
here on the level of integrity,
courage,
courage, the
courage, the power
courage, the power to
courage, the power to admit
courage, the power to admit the
courage, the power to admit the truth.
That's
That's why
courage, the power to admit the truth.
That's why it's
That's why it's nobody
courage, the power to admit the truth.
That's why it's nobody the
That's why it's nobody the the
courage, the power to admit the truth.
That's why it's nobody the the own
that's
that's why
that's why a
that's why a society
that's why a society which
that's why a society which excuses
that's why a society which excuses all
responsibility
responsibility is
that's why a society which excuses all
responsibility is not
responsibility is not integrous.
[snorts]
[snorts] It's
[snorts] It's not
[snorts] It's not integrous.
It's
It's not
[snorts] It's not integrous.
It's not as
It's not as fault
[snorts] It's not integrous.
It's not as fault what
It's not as fault what happened
[snorts] It's not integrous.
It's not as fault what happened to
It's not as fault what happened to him
as
as a
as a kid.
as a kid. That
as a kid. That is
as a kid. That is not
as a kid. That is not integrous.
You
You just
as a kid. That is not integrous.
You just sold
You just sold the
as a kid. That is not integrous.
You just sold the kid
You just sold the kid out.
as a kid. That is not integrous.
You just sold the kid out. You
You just sold the kid out. You just
as a kid. That is not integrous.
You just sold the kid out. You just sold
any
any hope
any hope of
any hope of salvation
any hope of salvation out.
any hope of salvation out. You
any hope of salvation out. You just
any hope of salvation out. You just sold
them
them out
because
because if
because if you're
because if you're just
because if you're just at
because if you're just at the
because if you're just at the effect
because if you're just at the effect of
your
your past,
because if you're just at the effect of
your past, well,
your past, well, nobody
because if you're just at the effect of
your past, well, nobody has
your past, well, nobody has any
responsibility
responsibility for
responsibility for anything,
responsibility for anything, do
responsibility for anything, do they?
Everybody
Everybody has
responsibility for anything, do they?
Everybody has a
Everybody has a past.
Our
Our societyy's
Our societyy's unsophisticated.
Our societyy's unsophisticated. They
think
think it's
Our societyy's unsophisticated. They
think it's just
think it's just just
Our societyy's unsophisticated. They
think it's just just the
think it's just just the past
Our societyy's unsophisticated. They
think it's just just the past of
think it's just just the past of this
lifetime.
lifetime. You
lifetime. You should
lifetime. You should look
lifetime. You should look back
lifetime. You should look back and
lifetime. You should look back and start
remembering
remembering all
lifetime. You should look back and start
remembering all the
remembering all the previous
lifetime. You should look back and start
remembering all the previous lifetimes.
This
This one
This one is
This one is nothing
This one is nothing at
This one is nothing at all.
This one is nothing at all. This
This one is nothing at all. This is
kindergarten.
kindergarten. [laughter]
What
What you
What you did
What you did before,
What you did before, boy.
What you did before, boy. I'll
What you did before, boy. I'll tell
What you did before, boy. I'll tell you.
I
I tell
What you did before, boy. I'll tell you.
I tell you.
I tell you. Anyway,
the
the excuse
the excuse of
the excuse of responsibility.
Well,
Well, we
the excuse of responsibility.
Well, we produce
Well, we produce this
the excuse of responsibility.
Well, we produce this because
Well, we produce this because it
the excuse of responsibility.
Well, we produce this because it sells.
We
We only
We only give
We only give the
We only give the public
We only give the public what
We only give the public what they
We only give the public what they want.
It's
It's not
We only give the public what they want.
It's not his
It's not his fault.
We only give the public what they want.
It's not his fault. Something
It's not his fault. Something happened
to
to him
to him as
to him as a
to him as a kid.
Every
Every monster
to him as a kid.
Every monster that
Every monster that appears
in
in the
in the media
in the media now,
in the media now, instantly
in the media now, instantly an
in the media now, instantly an apologist
gets
gets up
in the media now, instantly an apologist
gets up defending
gets up defending his
in the media now, instantly an apologist
gets up defending his rights
gets up defending his rights and
in the media now, instantly an apologist
gets up defending his rights and trying
to
to blame
to blame it
to blame it on
to blame it on his
to blame it on his childhood.
to blame it on his childhood. It's
amazing.
I
I said,
I said, "As
I said, "As soon
I said, "As soon as
I said, "As soon as this
I said, "As soon as this these
I said, "As soon as this these two
people
people get
I said, "As soon as this these two
people get through
people get through killing
I said, "As soon as this these two
people get through killing 13
people get through killing 13 people,
there'll
there'll be
there'll be a
there'll be a rush
there'll be a rush to
there'll be a rush to to
there'll be a rush to to protect
there'll be a rush to to protect their
their
their legal
there'll be a rush to to protect their
their legal rights,
their legal rights, right?
there'll be a rush to to protect their
their legal rights, right? Didn't
their legal rights, right? Didn't I
predict
predict that?"
predict that?" And
predict that?" And that's
predict that?" And that's exactly
predict that?" And that's exactly what
happened,
happened, right?
predict that?" And that's exactly what
happened, right? Yeah.
happened, right? Yeah. Within
predict that?" And that's exactly what
happened, right? Yeah. Within a
happened, right? Yeah. Within a second,
everybody
everybody wants
everybody wants to
everybody wants to get
everybody wants to get famous
everybody wants to get famous by
protesting.
So,
So, you
So, you see
So, you see the
So, you see the reversal.
So, you see the reversal. You
So, you see the reversal. You see
So, you see the reversal. You see the
reversal.
So,
So, so
So, so the
So, so the modern
the
the modern
wolf
wolf and
wolf and sheep's
wolf and sheep's clothing
is
is coated
wolf and sheep's clothing
is coated in
is coated in a
intellectualism
intellectualism in
intellectualism in an
intellectualism in an ideology
intellectualism in an ideology which
intellectualism in an ideology which is
actually
sophomoric
sophomoric when
sophomoric when you
sophomoric when you look
sophomoric when you look at
sophomoric when you look at it
sophomoric when you look at it doesn't
hold
hold up.
sophomoric when you look at it doesn't
hold up. There's
hold up. There's no
sophomoric when you look at it doesn't
hold up. There's no reality
hold up. There's no reality to
sophomoric when you look at it doesn't
hold up. There's no reality to it
but
but it
but it is
but it is appealing
but it is appealing and
but it is appealing and it
but it is appealing and it tries
but it is appealing and it tries to
but it is appealing and it tries to gain
power.
power. Why
but it is appealing and it tries to gain
power. Why does
power. Why does it
but it is appealing and it tries to gain
power. Why does it try
power. Why does it try to
but it is appealing and it tries to gain
power. Why does it try to gain
power. Why does it try to gain power?
Because
Because it
Because it undermines
Because it undermines integrity.
It
It transfers
Because it undermines integrity.
It transfers power
It transfers power from
Because it undermines integrity.
It transfers power from the
It transfers power from the integrous
Because it undermines integrity.
It transfers power from the integrous to
the
the non-integrous.
That's
That's what
the non-integrous.
That's what the
That's what the struggle
the non-integrous.
That's what the struggle for
That's what the struggle for the
dominion
dominion over
dominion over this
dominion over this world
dominion over this world is
dominion over this world is all
dominion over this world is all about.
After
After all
dominion over this world is all about.
After all these
After all these millennia,
the
the time
the time of
the time of the
the time of the dinosaur
the time of the dinosaur consciousness
of
of life
the time of the dinosaur consciousness
of life on
of life on this
the time of the dinosaur consciousness
of life on this planet
of life on this planet was
the time of the dinosaur consciousness
of life on this planet was 70.
Bin
Bin Laden
Bin Laden is
Bin Laden is 90.
Bin Laden is 90. Hitler
Bin Laden is 90. Hitler is
Bin Laden is 90. Hitler is I
Bin Laden is 90. Hitler is I don't
Bin Laden is 90. Hitler is I don't even
mention
mention it.
And
And finally
And finally in
And finally in the
And finally in the late
And finally in the late 1980s
And finally in the late 1980s it
And finally in the late 1980s it goes
And finally in the late 1980s it goes to
which
which is
which is a
which is a different
which is a different density.
which is a different density. You
which is a different density. You see
the
the buoyancy
which is a different density. You see
the buoyancy of
the buoyancy of life
which is a different density. You see
the buoyancy of life is
the buoyancy of life is different.
which is a different density. You see
the buoyancy of life is different. At
207 that
207 that which
207 that which is
207 that which is non-
207 that which is non- integrous
207 that which is non- integrous begins
to
to pop
207 that which is non- integrous begins
to pop up.
to pop up. You
207 that which is non- integrous begins
to pop up. You know
to pop up. You know heads
207 that which is non- integrous begins
to pop up. You know heads begin
to pop up. You know heads begin to
207 that which is non- integrous begins
to pop up. You know heads begin to roll.
People
People resign
People resign from
People resign from the
People resign from the stock
People resign from the stock market
board
board of
People resign from the stock market
board of directors
board of directors because
People resign from the stock market
board of directors because integrity
board of directors because integrity is
now
now the
now the criteria.
So
So God
now the criteria.
So God sneaks
So God sneaks into
now the criteria.
So God sneaks into society
So God sneaks into society then
now the criteria.
So God sneaks into society then by
So God sneaks into society then by the
focus
focus on
focus on integrity
for
for all
focus on integrity
for all the
for all the religiosity
focus on integrity
for all the religiosity that
for all the religiosity that went
focus on integrity
for all the religiosity that went on
for all the religiosity that went on in
prior
prior history.
prior history. Religiosity.
Religiosity
Religiosity is
prior history. Religiosity.
Religiosity is not
Religiosity is not integrity.
Religiosity
Religiosity is
Religiosity is sometimes
Religiosity is sometimes just
Religiosity is sometimes just uh
Religiosity is sometimes just uh a
self-indulgent
self-indulgent emotionality.
Those
who
who allege
Those
who allege that
who allege that their
Those
who allege that their life
who allege that their life is
Those
who allege that their life is devoted
who allege that their life is devoted to
God
God then
God then must
God then must of
God then must of necessity
become
become integrous.
God then must of necessity
become integrous. Integrous
become integrous. Integrous means
God then must of necessity
become integrous. Integrous means also
to
to stand
to stand the
to stand the willingness
to stand the willingness to
to stand the willingness to stand
to stand the willingness to stand and
to stand the willingness to stand and be
counted
counted for
to stand the willingness to stand and be
counted for the
counted for the truth.
to stand the willingness to stand and be
counted for the truth. The
counted for the truth. The willingness
to
to stand
to stand and
to stand and say
to stand and say no
to stand and say no more.
To
To not
to stand and say no more.
To not take
To not take a
to stand and say no more.
To not take a stand
To not take a stand is
to stand and say no more.
To not take a stand is to
To not take a stand is to join
to stand and say no more.
To not take a stand is to join the
oppressor
oppressor and
oppressor and you
oppressor and you then
oppressor and you then drop
oppressor and you then drop to
oppressor and you then drop to their
level
level of
oppressor and you then drop to their
level of consciousness.
No,
No, we're
No, we're required
No, we're required at
No, we're required at a
No, we're required at a point
No, we're required at a point in
No, we're required at a point in life
No, we're required at a point in life to
say
say no.
So
So it's
So it's integrous
So it's integrous to
So it's integrous to say
So it's integrous to say no.
the
the depictions
So it's integrous to say no.
the depictions of
the depictions of God
So it's integrous to say no.
the depictions of God throughout
time.
time. Then
time. Then we
time. Then we see
time. Then we see man
time. Then we see man has
time. Then we see man has really
time. Then we see man has really been
obsessed
obsessed with
time. Then we see man has really been
obsessed with God.
Strange
Strange gods,
Strange gods, weird
Strange gods, weird gods,
Strange gods, weird gods, but
Strange gods, weird gods, but some
Strange gods, weird gods, but some kind
of
of God
Strange gods, weird gods, but some kind
of God has
of God has existed
Strange gods, weird gods, but some kind
of God has existed in
of God has existed in every
Strange gods, weird gods, but some kind
of God has existed in every society,
what
what we
what we call
what we call primitive
what we call primitive or
what we call primitive or not.
what we call primitive or not. And
what we call primitive or not. And right
up
up to
what we call primitive or not. And right
up to this
up to this present
what we call primitive or not. And right
up to this present day,
up to this present day, the
what we call primitive or not. And right
up to this present day, the definitions
of
of God
of God then
of God then have
of God then have come
of God then have come out
of God then have come out of
of God then have come out of the
intellect
intellect and
of God then have come out of the
intellect and have
intellect and have also
of God then have come out of the
intellect and have also come
intellect and have also come out
of God then have come out of the
intellect and have also come out of
contaminations
contaminations from
contaminations from the
contaminations from the unconscious
and
and have
contaminations from the unconscious
and have also
and have also been
contaminations from the unconscious
and have also been attacked.
The
The true
The true descriptions
The true descriptions of
The true descriptions of God
The true descriptions of God have
The true descriptions of God have have
also
also been
The true descriptions of God have have
also been attacked
also been attacked by
The true descriptions of God have have
also been attacked by those
also been attacked by those energies
which
which are
which are really
which are really ungodly.
Devotion
Devotion to
which are really ungodly.
Devotion to God
Devotion to God means
which are really ungodly.
Devotion to God means what?
Devotion to God means what? It
which are really ungodly.
Devotion to God means what? It means
to
to begin
to begin with
to begin with just
to begin with just a
to begin with just a reverence
to begin with just a reverence for
to begin with just a reverence for life.
The
The reverence
to begin with just a reverence for life.
The reverence for
The reverence for life
to begin with just a reverence for life.
The reverence for life is
The reverence for life is the
to begin with just a reverence for life.
The reverence for life is the awareness
and
and the
and the acknowledgment
and the acknowledgment that
and the acknowledgment that the
and the acknowledgment that the essence
and
and source
and the acknowledgment that the essence
and source of
and source of all
and the acknowledgment that the essence
and source of all life
and source of all life is
and the acknowledgment that the essence
and source of all life is divinity.
Life
Life is
Life is God.
Life is God. God
Life is God. God is
Life is God. God is life.
Therefore,
Therefore, life
Life is God. God is life.
Therefore, life cannot
Therefore, life cannot be
Life is God. God is life.
Therefore, life cannot be destroyed
Therefore, life cannot be destroyed any
more
more than
more than God
more than God can
more than God can be
more than God can be destroyed.
The
The proof
more than God can be destroyed.
The proof of
The proof of the
more than God can be destroyed.
The proof of the existence
The proof of the existence of
more than God can be destroyed.
The proof of the existence of God
The proof of the existence of God is
your
your own
your own existence.
It's
It's a
your own existence.
It's a very
It's a very advanced
your own existence.
It's a very advanced understanding.
It's a very advanced understanding. But
with
with a
with a little
with a little meditation
with a little meditation or
contemplation
contemplation and
with a little meditation or
contemplation and looking
contemplation and looking at
with a little meditation or
contemplation and looking at it,
contemplation and looking at it, you
realize
realize that
realize that nothing
realize that nothing has
realize that nothing has within
realize that nothing has within itself
the
the power
realize that nothing has within itself
the power to
the power to create
realize that nothing has within itself
the power to create its
the power to create its own
realize that nothing has within itself
the power to create its own existence.
All
All it
All it is
would
would either
All it is
would either have
would either have to
All it is
would either have to come
would either have to come out
All it is
would either have to come out of
would either have to come out of nothing
or
or something.
If
If it's
or something.
If it's a
If it's a golf
or something.
If it's a golf ball,
if
if it's
if it's a
if it's a shirt,
if it's a shirt, if
if it's a shirt, if it's
if it's a shirt, if it's a
if it's a shirt, if it's a living,
breathing
breathing human
if it's a shirt, if it's a living,
breathing human being,
doesn't
doesn't suddenly
doesn't suddenly spontaneously
doesn't suddenly spontaneously exist
doesn't suddenly spontaneously exist out
of
of the
doesn't suddenly spontaneously exist out
of the only
of the only thing
doesn't suddenly spontaneously exist out
of the only thing that
of the only thing that can
doesn't suddenly spontaneously exist out
of the only thing that can come
of the only thing that can come into
existence
existence spontaneously
existence spontaneously is
existence spontaneously is form.
It
It can
existence spontaneously is form.
It can go
It can go from
existence spontaneously is form.
It can go from this
It can go from this form
existence spontaneously is form.
It can go from this form to
It can go from this form to that
existence spontaneously is form.
It can go from this form to that form,
but
but it
but it cannot
but it cannot choose
but it cannot choose to
but it cannot choose to create
but it cannot choose to create its
but it cannot choose to create its own
existence.
No
No one
No one here
No one here has
No one here has the
No one here has the power
No one here has the power to
No one here has the power to create
No one here has the power to create his
own
own existence.
Nor
Nor do
Nor do they
Nor do they have
Nor do they have the
Nor do they have the power
Nor do they have the power to
Nor do they have the power to extinguish
it.
existence
existence as
life
life is
existence as
life is in
life is in not
existence as
life is in not extinguishable
life is in not extinguishable to
existence as
life is in not extinguishable to the
ancient
ancient vidas.
ancient vidas. The
ancient vidas. The Buddha,
all
all the
ancient vidas. The Buddha,
all the enlightened
all the enlightened masters
ancient vidas. The Buddha,
all the enlightened masters throughout
time
have
have been
time
have been identical
have been identical identical
time
have been identical identical in
explaining
explaining the
explaining the exact
explaining the exact nature
explaining the exact nature of
explaining the exact nature of that
presence
presence within
verbatim.
verbatim. It
verbatim. It is
verbatim. It is so
verbatim. It is so exact
verbatim. It is so exact that
verbatim. It is so exact that if
somebody
somebody brings
verbatim. It is so exact that if
somebody brings me
somebody brings me a
verbatim. It is so exact that if
somebody brings me a book,
somebody brings me a book, people
verbatim. It is so exact that if
somebody brings me a book, people send
me
me books
me books by
me books by the
me books by the hundreds.
me books by the hundreds. If
me books by the hundreds. If somebody
brings
brings me
me books by the hundreds. If somebody
brings me a
brings me a book
me books by the hundreds. If somebody
brings me a book and
brings me a book and I
me books by the hundreds. If somebody
brings me a book and I look
brings me a book and I look at
me books by the hundreds. If somebody
brings me a book and I look at the
brings me a book and I look at the book,
I
I can
I can look
I can look at
I can look at the
I can look at the book,
I can look at the book, I
I can look at the book, I can
I can look at the book, I can look
I can look at the book, I can look at
one
one sentence,
I can look at the book, I can look at
one sentence, that
one sentence, that p
I can look at the book, I can look at
one sentence, that p person
one sentence, that p person either
I can look at the book, I can look at
one sentence, that p person either knows
it
it or
it or they
it or they don't
it or they don't know
it or they don't know it.
it or they don't know it. It's
immacable.
immacable. It's
it or they don't know it. It's
immacable. It's like
immacable. It's like an
it or they don't know it. It's
immacable. It's like an impremature.
It's
It's like
It's like a
It's like a stamp
It's like a stamp of
It's like a stamp of validity.
The
The presence
It's like a stamp of validity.
The presence within
The presence within the
It's like a stamp of validity.
The presence within the knowingness
The presence within the knowingness of
the
the being
the being is
the being is unmistakable.
Why?
Why? Because
the being is unmistakable.
Why? Because it's
Why? Because it's absolute.
When
When I
When I said
When I said the
The
The power
When I said the
The power of
The power of God
When I said the
The power of God is
The power of God is so
When I said the
The power of God is so overwhelming
The power of God is so overwhelming when
one
one first
one first witnesses
one first witnesses it
you
you and
one first witnesses it
you and that
you and that is
one first witnesses it
you and that is the
you and that is the source
one first witnesses it
you and that is the source of
you and that is the source of its
absoluteness
or
or vice
absoluteness
or vice versa.
The
The absoluteness
The absoluteness and
The absoluteness and the
The absoluteness and the infinite
The absoluteness and the infinite power
are
are one
The absoluteness and the infinite power
are one and
are one and the
The absoluteness and the infinite power
are one and the same.
are one and the same. It
The absoluteness and the infinite power
are one and the same. It leaves
are one and the same. It leaves an
unmistakable
imprint
in
in the
in the aura
in the aura of
in the aura of every
in the aura of every single
in the aura of every single person
in the aura of every single person in
this
this room
in the aura of every single person in
this room forever
this room forever more.
That
That is
That is a
That is a fact.
That
That is
That is a fact.
That is a
Therefore,
Therefore, I
Therefore, I am
Therefore, I am blessed
Therefore, I am blessed by
Therefore, I am blessed by your
Therefore, I am blessed by your presence
that
that I
Therefore, I am blessed by your presence
that I may
that I may share
Therefore, I am blessed by your presence
that I may share it.
that I may share it. [laughter]
The
The pathway
The pathway to
The pathway to salvation
The pathway to salvation and
The pathway to salvation and the
The pathway to salvation and the pathway
to
to enlightenment
The pathway to salvation and the pathway
to enlightenment are
to enlightenment are somewhat
The pathway to salvation and the pathway
to enlightenment are somewhat different
and
and yet
and yet they're
and yet they're the
and yet they're the same.
Religion
is
is ordinarily
is ordinarily practiced
is ordinarily practiced uh
is ordinarily practiced uh throughout
the
the history
is ordinarily practiced uh throughout
the history of
the history of America
is ordinarily practiced uh throughout
the history of America has
the history of America has been
is ordinarily practiced uh throughout
the history of America has been you're
born
born into
born into a
born into a certain
born into a certain religion.
born into a certain religion. You
born into a certain religion. You go
born into a certain religion. You go to
church.
church. You
born into a certain religion. You go to
church. You do
church. You do the
born into a certain religion. You go to
church. You do the best
church. You do the best you
born into a certain religion. You go to
church. You do the best you can
church. You do the best you can to
adhere
adhere to
adhere to it.
You
You try
adhere to it.
You try to
You try to undo
adhere to it.
You try to undo your
You try to undo your sins.
adhere to it.
You try to undo your sins. You
You try to undo your sins. You pray.
adhere to it.
You try to undo your sins. You pray. You
you
you do
you do the
you do the best
you do the best you
you do the best you can.
you do the best you can. And
you do the best you can. And you
you do the best you can. And you know
the
the prognosis
you do the best you can. And you know
the prognosis spiritually
the prognosis spiritually is
you do the best you can. And you know
the prognosis spiritually is very
the prognosis spiritually is very good.
That's
That's a
That's a fact.
to
to just
That's a fact.
to just be
to just be an
That's a fact.
to just be an ordinary
to just be an ordinary god-fearing
religious
religious person
religious person and
religious person and practice
religious person and practice your
religion
religion to
religious person and practice your
religion to the
religion to the best
religious person and practice your
religion to the best of
religion to the best of your
religious person and practice your
religion to the best of your ability
religion to the best of your ability is
uh
uh is
uh is excellent.
uh is excellent. Yeah.
That's
That's all
uh is excellent. Yeah.
That's all that's
That's all that's necessary
uh is excellent. Yeah.
That's all that's necessary for
salvation.
It's
It's all
salvation.
It's all that's
It's all that's necessary
salvation.
It's all that's necessary for
It's all that's necessary for salvation.
Don't
Don't have
Don't have to
Don't have to become
Don't have to become a
Don't have to become a saint.
Don't have to become a saint. You
Don't have to become a saint. You don't
have
have to
Don't have to become a saint. You don't
have to become
have to become an
Don't have to become a saint. You don't
have to become an enlightened
have to become an enlightened mystic.
You
You don't
You don't have
You don't have to
You don't have to become
You don't have to become a
You don't have to become a Buddha.
as
as long
You don't have to become a Buddha.
as long as
as long as it
You don't have to become a Buddha.
as long as it doesn't
as long as it doesn't become
You don't have to become a Buddha.
as long as it doesn't become oppressive.
And
And what
And what happened
And what happened with
And what happened with me
And what happened with me is
And what happened with me is it
And what happened with me is it became
oppressive.
And
And therefore
And therefore I
And therefore I shuck
And therefore I shuck the
And therefore I shuck the whole
And therefore I shuck the whole thing.
And
And when
And therefore I shuck the whole thing.
And when I
And when I was
And therefore I shuck the whole thing.
And when I was an
And when I was an atheist,
And therefore I shuck the whole thing.
And when I was an atheist, from
And when I was an atheist, from the
And therefore I shuck the whole thing.
And when I was an atheist, from the time
I
I rejected
I rejected God
I rejected God as
I rejected God as the
I rejected God as the source
I rejected God as the source of
I rejected God as the source of all
I rejected God as the source of all evil
that
that I
I rejected God as the source of all evil
that I could
that I could see
I rejected God as the source of all evil
that I could see until
that I could see until the
I rejected God as the source of all evil
that I could see until the moment
that I could see until the moment of
that
that stunning
that stunning awareness
many
many years
that stunning awareness
many years later,
many years later, which
that stunning awareness
many years later, which was
many years later, which was like
being
being in
being in the
being in the middle
being in the middle of
being in the middle of a
being in the middle of a lightning
being in the middle of a lightning storm
or
or something,
but
but at least
but at least in
but at least in the
but at least in the middle
but at least in the middle there
but at least in the middle there was
peace.
It's
It's better
It's better to
It's better to have
It's better to have no
It's better to have no God
It's better to have no God than
It's better to have no God than a
It's better to have no God than a wicked
God.
God. Better
to
to have
to have no
to have no god
to have no god than
to have no god than a
to have no god than a wicked
to have no god than a wicked god.
to have no god than a wicked god. At
least
least you
to have no god than a wicked god. At
least you got
least you got some
to have no god than a wicked god. At
least you got some space
least you got some space to
to have no god than a wicked god. At
least you got some space to breathe
least you got some space to breathe and
live.
live. Be
live. Be a
live. Be a human
live. Be a human being
live. Be a human being without
constantly
constantly being
live. Be a human being without
constantly being beset
constantly being beset with
live. Be a human being without
constantly being beset with guilt
constantly being beset with guilt and
fear.
fear. Huh?
fear. Huh? So
fear. Huh? So the
fear. Huh? So the god
fear. Huh? So the god of
fear. Huh? So the god of guilt
fear. Huh? So the god of guilt and
fear. Huh? So the god of guilt and fear
then
then is
fear. Huh? So the god of guilt and fear
then is the
then is the one
that
that has
that has been
that has been the
that has been the nemesis
that has been the nemesis of
that has been the nemesis of man.
that has been the nemesis of man. The
nemesis.
Those
Those who
Those who have
Those who have experienced
Those who have experienced the
Those who have experienced the presence
of
of God
Those who have experienced the presence
of God in
of God in its
Those who have experienced the presence
of God in its unmistakable
of God in its unmistakable absolute
certainty
which
which is
certainty
which is infinite
which is infinite beyond
certainty
which is infinite beyond all
which is infinite beyond all time.
There's
There's no
There's no time
There's no time in
There's no time in which
There's no time in which there
There's no time in which there can
There's no time in which there can be
anything
anything different
There's no time in which there can be
anything different because
anything different because that
There's no time in which there can be
anything different because that which
anything different because that which is
the
the absolute
the absolute is
the absolute is always
the absolute is always and
the absolute is always and exists
the absolute is always and exists now
beyond
beyond time.
the absolute is always and exists now
beyond time. Therefore,
beyond time. Therefore, it's
the absolute is always and exists now
beyond time. Therefore, it's not
beyond time. Therefore, it's not subject
to
to time
to time or
to time or to
to time or to change
to time or to change or
to time or to change or any
to time or to change or any modification
as
as it
to time or to change or any modification
as it is
as it is now.
to time or to change or any modification
as it is now. but
as it is now. but has
to time or to change or any modification
as it is now. but has been,
as it is now. but has been, always
to time or to change or any modification
as it is now. but has been, always will
be,
which
which is
be,
which is just
which is just a
be,
which is just a verbalization.
You
You only
You only have
You only have to
You only have to know
You only have to know it
You only have to know it one
You only have to know it one instant
You only have to know it one instant and
you
you know
You only have to know it one instant and
you know it
you know it forever
You only have to know it one instant and
you know it forever because
you know it forever because that
You only have to know it one instant and
you know it forever because that instant
is
is forever
is forever because
is forever because in
is forever because in that
is forever because in that instant
you're
you're outside
is forever because in that instant
you're outside of
you're outside of time
is forever because in that instant
you're outside of time and
you're outside of time and you're
is forever because in that instant
you're outside of time and you're into
forever.
So
So you
forever.
So you witness
So you witness God
forever.
So you witness God forever.
Therefore,
Therefore, what
Therefore, what is
Therefore, what is witnessed
Therefore, what is witnessed is
unmistakable.
Because
Because it's
Because it's unmistakable,
Because it's unmistakable, it
Because it's unmistakable, it never
varies
varies over
Because it's unmistakable, it never
varies over the
varies over the course
Because it's unmistakable, it never
varies over the course of
varies over the course of time.
No
No mystic
No mystic ever
No mystic ever lied.
You
You pick
No mystic ever lied.
You pick up
You pick up the
No mystic ever lied.
You pick up the radiance
You pick up the radiance of
No mystic ever lied.
You pick up the radiance of the
You pick up the radiance of the truth
No mystic ever lied.
You pick up the radiance of the truth in
that
that book
that book there.
that book there. No
that book there. No mystic
that book there. No mystic ever
that book there. No mystic ever lied.
A
A mystic
that book there. No mystic ever lied.
A mystic [laughter]
the
the idea
the idea of
the idea of a
the idea of a mystic
the idea of a mystic lying
the idea of a mystic lying is
the idea of a mystic lying is sort
the idea of a mystic lying is sort of
chemical.
The
The karma
The karma of
The karma of lying
The karma of lying from
The karma of lying from that
The karma of lying from that level
The karma of lying from that level would
be
be so
The karma of lying from that level would
be so dreadful
be so dreadful and
The karma of lying from that level would
be so dreadful and to
be so dreadful and to be
The karma of lying from that level would
be so dreadful and to be beyond
description.
description. The
description. The thing
description. The thing that
description. The thing that always
surprises
surprises me
description. The thing that always
surprises me about
so-called
so-called false
so-called false gurus
so-called false gurus is
so-called false gurus is when
so-called false gurus is when you
so-called false gurus is when you think
of
of what
so-called false gurus is when you think
of what the
of what the consequences
so-called false gurus is when you think
of what the consequences of
of what the consequences of what
so-called false gurus is when you think
of what the consequences of what you're
doing
doing is,
doing is, it
doing is, it is
doing is, it is so
doing is, it is so staggering
doing is, it is so staggering that
doing is, it is so staggering that they
couldn't
couldn't understand
doing is, it is so staggering that they
couldn't understand the
couldn't understand the nature
doing is, it is so staggering that they
couldn't understand the nature of
couldn't understand the nature of God
doing is, it is so staggering that they
couldn't understand the nature of God or
they
they wouldn't
they wouldn't be
they wouldn't be doing
they wouldn't be doing what
they wouldn't be doing what they're
doing.
To
To understand
To understand the
To understand the nature
To understand the nature of
To understand the nature of God
To understand the nature of God would
To understand the nature of God would be
to
to be
To understand the nature of God would be
to be aware
of
of the
of the absoluteness
of the absoluteness of
of the absoluteness of the
of the absoluteness of the karmic
coherence
coherence of
of the absoluteness of the karmic
coherence of all
coherence of all of
of the absoluteness of the karmic
coherence of all of creation.
That's
That's why
That's why you
That's why you don't
That's why you don't have
That's why you don't have to
That's why you don't have to worry
That's why you don't have to worry about
judgment
judgment day
because
because judgment
because judgment day
because judgment day is
because judgment day is every
because judgment day is every day.
Judgment
Judgment day
because judgment day is every day.
Judgment day is
Judgment day is right
because judgment day is every day.
Judgment day is right now.
Judgment day is right now. Judgment
because judgment day is every day.
Judgment day is right now. Judgment day
is
is continuous.
Judgment
Judgment day,
is continuous.
Judgment day, we
Judgment day, we have
is continuous.
Judgment day, we have permission
Judgment day, we have permission to
is continuous.
Judgment day, we have permission to ask
this
this in
this in front
this in front of
this in front of this
this in front of this audience.
this in front of this audience. This
judgment
judgment day
this in front of this audience. This
judgment day is
judgment day is this
this in front of this audience. This
judgment day is this instant
and
and this
and this instant.
And
And in
and this instant.
And in this
And in this instant
and this instant.
And in this instant forever
judgment
judgment day
judgment day is
judgment day is therefore
judgment day is therefore the
judgment day is therefore the fact
judgment day is therefore the fact that
this
this is
judgment day is therefore the fact that
this is a
this is a giant
judgment day is therefore the fact that
this is a giant electromagnetic
this is a giant electromagnetic field
that
that we
that we call
that we call God.
that we call God. The
that we call God. The infinite
that we call God. The infinite context
out
out of
that we call God. The infinite context
out of which
out of which comes
that we call God. The infinite context
out of which comes all
out of which comes all of
that we call God. The infinite context
out of which comes all of creation
out of which comes all of creation in
its
its infinite
its infinite absolute
its infinite absolute precision
its infinite absolute precision and
power
instantly
instantly responds
instantly responds to
instantly responds to all
instantly responds to all that
instantly responds to all that is
instantly responds to all that is as
instantly responds to all that is as it
comes
comes into
instantly responds to all that is as it
comes into expression.
We
We don't
We don't have
We don't have to
We don't have to worry
We don't have to worry about
We don't have to worry about judgment
day
day because
We don't have to worry about judgment
day because right
day because right now
We don't have to worry about judgment
day because right now is
day because right now is judgment
We don't have to worry about judgment
day because right now is judgment day.
How
How you
How you doing
How you doing right
How you doing right now
How you doing right now is
How you doing right now is about
How you doing right now is about how
you're
you're going
How you doing right now is about how
you're going to
you're going to do,
How you doing right now is about how
you're going to do, right?
you're going to do, right? [laughter]
The
The infinite
The infinite potentiality
The infinite potentiality of
The infinite potentiality of the
The infinite potentiality of the soul
then
is
is the
is the reality
is the reality out
is the reality out of
is the reality out of which
is the reality out of which our
existence
existence arises
is the reality out of which our
existence arises out
existence arises out of
is the reality out of which our
existence arises out of which
existence arises out of which the
is the reality out of which our
existence arises out of which the sense
of
of eye.
of eye. And
of eye. And what's
of eye. And what's surprising
of eye. And what's surprising is
of eye. And what's surprising is that
the
the s
of eye. And what's surprising is that
the s that
the s that the
of eye. And what's surprising is that
the s that the presence
the s that the presence is
more
more I
more I than
more I than what
more I than what you
more I than what you think
more I than what you think of
more I than what you think of as
more I than what you think of as your
eye.
eye. What
more I than what you think of as your
eye. What you
eye. What you think
more I than what you think of as your
eye. What you think of
eye. What you think of of
more I than what you think of as your
eye. What you think of of your
eye. What you think of of your as
more I than what you think of as your
eye. What you think of of your as your
eye
eye is
eye is really
eye is really peripheral
eye is really peripheral to
eye is really peripheral to who
eye is really peripheral to who you
eye is really peripheral to who you are.
It's
It's like
eye is really peripheral to who you are.
It's like thinking
It's like thinking you
eye is really peripheral to who you are.
It's like thinking you your
It's like thinking you your clothes
eye is really peripheral to who you are.
It's like thinking you your clothes or
your
your body
your body or
your body or your
your body or your car
your body or your car or
your body or your car or something.
your body or your car or something. And
then
then suddenly
your body or your car or something. And
then suddenly you
then suddenly you realize,
oh
that's
that's where
oh
that's where my
that's where my eye
oh
that's where my eye is.
that's where my eye is. It's
oh
that's where my eye is. It's the
that's where my eye is. It's the source
out
out of
out of which
out of which my
out of which my sense
out of which my sense of
out of which my sense of eye
out of which my sense of eye you.
out of which my sense of eye you. How
out of which my sense of eye you. How do
you
you know
out of which my sense of eye you. How do
you know that
you know that you
out of which my sense of eye you. How do
you know that you are?
Everybody
Everybody just
Everybody just presumes
Everybody just presumes that.
Everybody just presumes that. How
Everybody just presumes that. How do
Everybody just presumes that. How do you
know
know that
Everybody just presumes that. How do you
know that you
know that you are?
The
The only
The only way
The only way you
The only way you know
The only way you know that
The only way you know that you
The only way you know that you are
is
is by
The only way you know that you are
is by being
is by being what
The only way you know that you are
is by being what you
is by being what you are.
The only way you know that you are
is by being what you are. If
is by being what you are. If I
The only way you know that you are
is by being what you are. If I tell
is by being what you are. If I tell you
you
you are,
you are, won't
you are, won't you
you are, won't you make
you are, won't you make won't
you are, won't you make won't make
you are, won't you make won't make any
sense
sense of
you are, won't you make won't make any
sense of that.
sense of that. I'll
you are, won't you make won't make any
sense of that. I'll say
sense of that. I'll say to
you are, won't you make won't make any
sense of that. I'll say to you,
sense of that. I'll say to you, hey,
you are, won't you make won't make any
sense of that. I'll say to you, hey, you
are.
What
What do
are.
What do you
What do you mean
are.
What do you mean by
What do you mean by that?
are.
What do you mean by that? [laughter]
No,
No, it's
No, it's not
No, it's not conceptual.
No, it's not conceptual. It's
No, it's not conceptual. It's ex
when
when you
No, it's not conceptual. It's ex
when you wake
when you wake up
No, it's not conceptual. It's ex
when you wake up in
when you wake up in the
No, it's not conceptual. It's ex
when you wake up in the morning,
when you wake up in the morning, the
first
first awareness
first awareness is
first awareness is of
first awareness is of existence.
You
You don't
first awareness is of existence.
You don't exist
You don't exist know
first awareness is of existence.
You don't exist know existence
You don't exist know existence is
first awareness is of existence.
You don't exist know existence is what?
You
You don't
You don't even
You don't even know
You don't even know what
You don't even know what gender
You don't even know what gender you
You don't even know what gender you are.
You
You have
You don't even know what gender you are.
You have no
You have no name
You don't even know what gender you are.
You have no name yet.
You have no name yet. All
You don't even know what gender you are.
You have no name yet. All there
You have no name yet. All there is
You don't even know what gender you are.
You have no name yet. All there is is
the
the beginning
the beginning coming
the beginning coming out
the beginning coming out of
the beginning coming out of a
the beginning coming out of a state
the beginning coming out of a state into
you're
you're only
the beginning coming out of a state into
you're only aware
you're only aware that
the beginning coming out of a state into
you're only aware that you
you're only aware that you are.
the beginning coming out of a state into
you're only aware that you are. That's
all.
all. Then
all. Then within
all. Then within a
all. Then within a few
all. Then within a few seconds
all. Then within a few seconds you're
become
become aware
all. Then within a few seconds you're
become aware that
become aware that you
all. Then within a few seconds you're
become aware that you are
become aware that you are in
all. Then within a few seconds you're
become aware that you are in a
become aware that you are in a bed
all. Then within a few seconds you're
become aware that you are in a bed that
there's
there's a
there's a body
there's a body in
there's a body in a
there's a body in a bed.
there's a body in a bed. Then
there's a body in a bed. Then that
there's
there's a
there's a body in a bed. Then that
there's a kitty
there's a kitty there
there's a body in a bed. Then that
there's a kitty there and
there's a kitty there and then
there's a body in a bed. Then that
there's a kitty there and then there's
there's a kitty there and then there's a
room
room and
room and then
room and then there's
room and then there's an
room and then there's an alarm
room and then there's an alarm clock
room and then there's an alarm clock and
this
this body
room and then there's an alarm clock and
this body stumbles
this body stumbles across
room and then there's an alarm clock and
this body stumbles across there
this body stumbles across there and
room and then there's an alarm clock and
this body stumbles across there and now
you're
you're aware
you're aware you
you're aware you have
you're aware you have a
you're aware you have a body.
you're aware you have a body. I
you're aware you have a body. I mean,
you
you see,
you're aware you have a body. I mean,
you see, you
you see, you begin
you're aware you have a body. I mean,
you see, you begin to
you see, you begin to come
you're aware you have a body. I mean,
you see, you begin to come out
you see, you begin to come out of
you're aware you have a body. I mean,
you see, you begin to come out of an
infinite
nonlinear
nonlinear reality
infinite
nonlinear reality into
nonlinear reality into a
infinite
nonlinear reality into a progressively
linear
linear linear
linear linear reality.
linear linear reality. But
linear linear reality. But as
linear linear reality. But as you
linear linear reality. But as you do,
then
then your
linear linear reality. But as you do,
then your definition
then your definition of
linear linear reality. But as you do,
then your definition of yourself
then your definition of yourself starts
coming
coming going
coming going farther
coming going farther and
coming going farther and farther
coming going farther and farther from
the
the truth.
The
The first
The first awareness
The first awareness that
The first awareness that you
The first awareness that you are,
The first awareness that you are, you
should
should have
The first awareness that you are, you
should have stopped
should have stopped there.
The first awareness that you are, you
should have stopped there. [laughter]
You're
You're ahead
You're ahead of
You're ahead of the
You're ahead of the game
You're ahead of the game before
You're ahead of the game before you
You're ahead of the game before you get
out
out of
You're ahead of the game before you get
out of the
out of the bed.
Once
Once you
Once you get
Once you get out
Once you get out of
Once you get out of the
Once you get out of the bed,
Once you get out of the bed, you're
Once you get out of the bed, you're it
goes
goes downhill
Once you get out of the bed, you're it
goes downhill from
goes downhill from there,
Once you get out of the bed, you're it
goes downhill from there, folks.
[laughter]
The
The fax
[laughter]
The fax machines,
The fax machines, the
[laughter]
The fax machines, the phone
The fax machines, the phone calls.
[laughter]
The fax machines, the phone calls. Oh
The fax machines, the phone calls. Oh my
god.
god. No.
god. No. But
god. No. But And
god. No. But And now
god. No. But And now we
god. No. But And now we have
god. No. But And now we have the
god. No. But And now we have the curse
of
of the
god. No. But And now we have the curse
of the internet
of the internet on
god. No. But And now we have the curse
of the internet on top
of the internet on top of
god. No. But And now we have the curse
of the internet on top of that.
of the internet on top of that. It's
god. No. But And now we have the curse
of the internet on top of that. It's bad
enough
enough before.
And
And now
enough before.
And now we
And now we have
enough before.
And now we have another
And now we have another monster
enough before.
And now we have another monster in
And now we have another monster in the
house.
You
You sneak
house.
You sneak him
You sneak him over
house.
You sneak him over at
You sneak him over at night.
house.
You sneak him over at night. You
You sneak him over at night. You look
house.
You sneak him over at night. You look at
it
it this
it this even.
[laughter]
Aren't
Aren't you
Aren't you going
Aren't you going to
Aren't you going to look
Aren't you going to look at
Aren't you going to look at that
Aren't you going to look at that now,
honey?
honey? No,
Aren't you going to look at that now,
honey? No, I
honey? No, I don't
Aren't you going to look at that now,
honey? No, I don't think
honey? No, I don't think so.
After
After I
After I get
After I get home
After I get home from
After I get home from work,
God
God knows
After I get home from work,
God knows what's
God knows what's waiting
After I get home from work,
God knows what's waiting for
God knows what's waiting for you
After I get home from work,
God knows what's waiting for you on
there.
[laughter]
The
The complexity
The complexity of
The complexity of life
The complexity of life so
The complexity of life so obscures
The complexity of life so obscures the
essential
essential realities
that
that we
that we really
that we really need
that we really need um
that we really need um spiritual
meetings,
meetings, commitments,
that we really need um spiritual
meetings, commitments, readings,
meditation,
meditation, all
meditation, all to
meditation, all to just
meditation, all to just recall
meditation, all to just recall the
meditation, all to just recall the truth
of
of who
meditation, all to just recall the truth
of who we
of who we are
meditation, all to just recall the truth
of who we are and
of who we are and what
meditation, all to just recall the truth
of who we are and what this
of who we are and what this is
meditation, all to just recall the truth
of who we are and what this is all
of who we are and what this is all about
and
and that
and that what
and that what we're
and that what we're really
and that what we're really responsible
for
for is
and that what we're really responsible
for is our
for is our intention.
and that what we're really responsible
for is our intention. What
for is our intention. What sets
and that what we're really responsible
for is our intention. What sets karma
then
then is
then is the
then is the spiritual
then is the spiritual will.
The
The spiritual
then is the spiritual will.
The spiritual will.
The spiritual will. A
then is the spiritual will.
The spiritual will. A person
The spiritual will. A person who
sacrifices
sacrifices his
sacrifices his life
sacrifices his life for
sacrifices his life for what
sacrifices his life for what he
understands
understands to
sacrifices his life for what he
understands to be
understands to be God
as
as Krishna
as Krishna says
as Krishna says is
as Krishna says is in
as Krishna says is in a
as Krishna says is in a good
as Krishna says is in a good place.
as Krishna says is in a good place. He
may
may be
as Krishna says is in a good place. He
may be screwed
may be screwed up
as Krishna says is in a good place. He
may be screwed up but
may be screwed up but he
as Krishna says is in a good place. He
may be screwed up but he will
may be screwed up but he will still
as Krishna says is in a good place. He
may be screwed up but he will still be
beloved
beloved by
beloved by me
beloved by me because
beloved by me because I
beloved by me because I know
beloved by me because I know he
beloved by me because I know he did
beloved by me because I know he did it
for
for my
beloved by me because I know he did it
for my sake
for my sake but
beloved by me because I know he did it
for my sake but didn't
for my sake but didn't know
beloved by me because I know he did it
for my sake but didn't know who
for my sake but didn't know who I
beloved by me because I know he did it
for my sake but didn't know who I was.
That's
That's good
That's good news
That's good news folks.
That's good news folks. [laughter]
Well,
there
there are
there are teachings
there are teachings that
there are teachings that are
there are teachings that are the
opposite.
opposite. There
there are teachings that are the
opposite. There are
opposite. There are teachings
there are teachings that are the
opposite. There are teachings that
opposite. There are teachings that say
that
that unless
that unless you
that unless you use
that unless you use a
that unless you use a certain
that unless you use a certain name
that unless you use a certain name for
God
God and
that unless you use a certain name for
God and and
God and and this
that unless you use a certain name for
God and and this that
God and and this that and
that unless you use a certain name for
God and and this that and the
God and and this that and the other
that unless you use a certain name for
God and and this that and the other that
your
your butt
your butt is
your butt is in
your butt is in a
your butt is in a sling.
your butt is in a sling. No,
your butt is in a sling. No, that's
your butt is in a sling. No, that's not
right.
I
I mean,
I mean, God
I mean, God would
I mean, God would have
I mean, God would have to
I mean, God would have to be
I mean, God would have to be stupid.
I mean, God would have to be stupid. You
know
know what
I mean, God would have to be stupid. You
know what I
know what I mean?
I mean, God would have to be stupid. You
know what I mean? You
know what I mean? You know
I mean, God would have to be stupid. You
know what I mean? You know what
know what I mean? You know what a
I mean, God would have to be stupid. You
know what I mean? You know what a kid's
intention
intention is.
intention is. He
intention is. He can
intention is. He can make
intention is. He can make a
intention is. He can make a mistake.
intention is. He can make a mistake. You
know,
I
I make
I make the
I make the coffee
I make the coffee a
I make the coffee a lot
I make the coffee a lot of
I make the coffee a lot of times
I make the coffee a lot of times and
I make the coffee a lot of times and it
goes
goes all
I make the coffee a lot of times and it
goes all over
goes all over the
I make the coffee a lot of times and it
goes all over the floor.
goes all over the floor. I
I make the coffee a lot of times and it
goes all over the floor. I don't
goes all over the floor. I don't know
what's
what's the
what's the matter
what's the matter with
what's the matter with the
I
I push
what's the matter with the
I push all
I push all these
what's the matter with the
I push all these buttons.
I push all these buttons. I
what's the matter with the
I push all these buttons. I do
I push all these buttons. I do all
what's the matter with the
I push all these buttons. I do all the
things.
things. And
things. And next
things. And next thing
things. And next thing I
things. And next thing I know,
things. And next thing I know, it's
things. And next thing I know, it's all
over
over the
things. And next thing I know, it's all
over the floor.
I
I do
I do the
I do the same
I do the same thing
I do the same thing at
I do the same thing at the
I do the same thing at the girls
I do the same thing at the girls ranch.
I
I make
I do the same thing at the girls ranch.
I make the
I make the coffee
I do the same thing at the girls ranch.
I make the coffee there.
I make the coffee there. Friday,
I do the same thing at the girls ranch.
I make the coffee there. Friday, she
said,
said, "Doc,
said, "Doc, it's
said, "Doc, it's all
said, "Doc, it's all over
said, "Doc, it's all over the
said, "Doc, it's all over the floor.
There's
There's a
said, "Doc, it's all over the floor.
There's a little
There's a little thing
said, "Doc, it's all over the floor.
There's a little thing you
There's a little thing you got
said, "Doc, it's all over the floor.
There's a little thing you got to
There's a little thing you got to push
there."
there." God
there." God gez.
I
I got
there." God gez.
I got home.
I got home. Susan
there." God gez.
I got home. Susan says
I got home. Susan says that
there." God gez.
I got home. Susan says that little
doojigy
doojigy at
doojigy at the
doojigy at the end
doojigy at the end of
doojigy at the end of the
doojigy at the end of the telephone
doojigy at the end of the telephone cord
that
that you
doojigy at the end of the telephone cord
that you plug
that you plug in
doojigy at the end of the telephone cord
that you plug in the
that you plug in the thing.
doojigy at the end of the telephone cord
that you plug in the thing. She
that you plug in the thing. She said
doojigy at the end of the telephone cord
that you plug in the thing. She said it
broke.
broke. I
broke. I mean
broke. I mean our
broke. I mean our life
broke. I mean our life is
broke. I mean our life is ruined.
Life
Life came
broke. I mean our life is ruined.
Life came to
Life came to a
broke. I mean our life is ruined.
Life came to a standstill.
Life came to a standstill. You
broke. I mean our life is ruined.
Life came to a standstill. You might
Life came to a standstill. You might as
well
well kill
well kill yourself
well kill yourself cuz
well kill yourself cuz snap
well kill yourself cuz snap at
well kill yourself cuz snap at the
well kill yourself cuz snap at the end
of
of your
well kill yourself cuz snap at the end
of your telephone
of your telephone broke
well kill yourself cuz snap at the end
of your telephone broke off.
[laughter]
Life
Life is
[laughter]
Life is extremely
Life is extremely complex,
[laughter]
Life is extremely complex, you
Life is extremely complex, you know,
extremely
extremely complex.
And
And u
extremely complex.
And u by
And u by the
extremely complex.
And u by the time
And u by the time I
extremely complex.
And u by the time I leave
And u by the time I leave here,
extremely complex.
And u by the time I leave here, I've
And u by the time I leave here, I've had
it
it with
it with this
it with this plane.
it with this plane. I'll
it with this plane. I'll tell
it with this plane. I'll tell you,
it with this plane. I'll tell you, it's
gotten
gotten so
it with this plane. I'll tell you, it's
gotten so complex,
gotten so complex, I
it with this plane. I'll tell you, it's
gotten so complex, I don't
gotten so complex, I don't want
it with this plane. I'll tell you, it's
gotten so complex, I don't want to
gotten so complex, I don't want to deal
with
with anymore.
with anymore. I
with anymore. I can't
with anymore. I can't even
with anymore. I can't even read
with anymore. I can't even read the
instructions
instructions on
with anymore. I can't even read the
instructions on things
instructions on things people
with anymore. I can't even read the
instructions on things people give
instructions on things people give me
for
for Christmas.
for Christmas. You
for Christmas. You pick
for Christmas. You pick it
for Christmas. You pick it out
for Christmas. You pick it out and
for Christmas. You pick it out and you
It's
It's too
for Christmas. You pick it out and you
It's too complex.
People
lose
lose their
People
lose their sense
lose their sense of
People
lose their sense of self.
lose their sense of self. They
People
lose their sense of self. They lose
their
their identity.
their identity. They
their identity. They lose
their identity. They lose the
their identity. They lose the basic
essentials
essentials of
their identity. They lose the basic
essentials of life.
essentials of life. And
their identity. They lose the basic
essentials of life. And that's
essentials of life. And that's why
their identity. They lose the basic
essentials of life. And that's why it's
important
important to
important to constantly
important to constantly come
important to constantly come back
important to constantly come back to
context.
context. The
important to constantly come back to
context. The context
context. The context of
important to constantly come back to
context. The context of life
context. The context of life and
important to constantly come back to
context. The context of life and not
context. The context of life and not get
lost
lost in
lost in the
lost in the content.
You
You get
lost in the content.
You get lost
You get lost in
lost in the content.
You get lost in the
You get lost in the content.
lost in the content.
You get lost in the content. The
You get lost in the content. The overall
context
context is
you
you know
context is
you know what
you know what your
context is
you know what your intention
you know what your intention really
context is
you know what your intention really is.
What
What the
What the intention
What the intention of
What the intention of society
What the intention of society really
What the intention of society really is.
But
But the
What the intention of society really is.
But the intention
But the intention of
What the intention of society really is.
But the intention of that
But the intention of that group
What the intention of society really is.
But the intention of that group that
But the intention of that group that you
vote
vote for
vote for or
vote for or politician,
vote for or politician, you
vote for or politician, you know,
vote for or politician, you know, what
what
what is
vote for or politician, you know, what
what is their
what is their real
vote for or politician, you know, what
what is their real intention?
Um
to
to clarify
Um
to clarify the
to clarify the meaning
Um
to clarify the meaning of
to clarify the meaning of your
Um
to clarify the meaning of your own
to clarify the meaning of your own life,
the
the meaning
the meaning of
the meaning of life
the meaning of life itself,
the meaning of life itself, the
the meaning of life itself, the meaning
of
of human
the meaning of life itself, the meaning
of human life
of human life to
the meaning of life itself, the meaning
of human life to see
of human life to see yourself
the meaning of life itself, the meaning
of human life to see yourself as
of human life to see yourself as part
the meaning of life itself, the meaning
of human life to see yourself as part of
the
the evolution
the evolution of
the evolution of consciousness
the evolution of consciousness since
the evolution of consciousness since the
beginning
beginning of
the evolution of consciousness since the
beginning of time.
to
to give
to give yourself
to give yourself some
um
um slack,
to give yourself some
um slack, some
um slack, some space
to give yourself some
um slack, some space in
um slack, some space in which
to give yourself some
um slack, some space in which to
um slack, some space in which to grow
and
and make
and make mistakes
and make mistakes and
and make mistakes and realize
and make mistakes and realize that
you're
you're still
and make mistakes and realize that
you're still at
you're still at the
and make mistakes and realize that
you're still at the effect
you're still at the effect of
and make mistakes and realize that
you're still at the effect of karma
you're still at the effect of karma as
it
it expresses
it expresses itself
it expresses itself just
it expresses itself just in
it expresses itself just in the
it expresses itself just in the design
of
of the
it expresses itself just in the design
of the human
of the human brain.
it expresses itself just in the design
of the human brain. You
of the human brain. You didn't
it expresses itself just in the design
of the human brain. You didn't design
your
your own
your own brain.
I
I mean,
your own brain.
I mean, if
I mean, if you
your own brain.
I mean, if you don't
I mean, if you don't believe
your own brain.
I mean, if you don't believe in
I mean, if you don't believe in karma,
well,
well, you'll
well, you'll believe
well, you'll believe in
well, you'll believe in the
well, you'll believe in the fact
well, you'll believe in the fact that
you
you um
well, you'll believe in the fact that
you um are
you um are born
well, you'll believe in the fact that
you um are born with
you um are born with something
well, you'll believe in the fact that
you um are born with something in
you um are born with something in the
middle
middle of
middle of your
middle of your skull
middle of your skull that
middle of your skull that you
middle of your skull that you didn't
design.
design. So,
You
You can
You can call
You can call it
You can call it genetics,
You can call it genetics, you
You can call it genetics, you can
You can call it genetics, you can call
it
it inheritance,
You can call it genetics, you can call
it inheritance, you
it inheritance, you can
You can call it genetics, you can call
it inheritance, you can call
it inheritance, you can call it
whatever.
whatever. But
whatever. But we
whatever. But we already
whatever. But we already have
whatever. But we already have a
whatever. But we already have a load
whatever. But we already have a load of
stuff
stuff to
whatever. But we already have a load of
stuff to deal
stuff to deal with
whatever. But we already have a load of
stuff to deal with the
stuff to deal with the minute
whatever. But we already have a load of
stuff to deal with the minute we're
here.
here. So
here. So we
here. So we should
here. So we should have
here. So we should have a
here. So we should have a certain
compassion
compassion for
here. So we should have a certain
compassion for ourself,
compassion for ourself, a
here. So we should have a certain
compassion for ourself, a certain
compassion
compassion for
compassion for other
compassion for other human
compassion for other human beings.
I'm
I'm sure
compassion for other human beings.
I'm sure these
I'm sure these people
compassion for other human beings.
I'm sure these people who
I'm sure these people who these
compassion for other human beings.
I'm sure these people who these suicide
bombers
bombers probably
bombers probably believe
bombers probably believe that
bombers probably believe that they're
doing
doing this
bombers probably believe that they're
doing this for
doing this for God
bombers probably believe that they're
doing this for God and
doing this for God and they're
bombers probably believe that they're
doing this for God and they're going
doing this for God and they're going to
go
go to
go to heaven.
go to heaven. They
go to heaven. They may
go to heaven. They may actually
go to heaven. They may actually believe
it,
which
which is
which is more
which is more demanded
which is more demanded than
which is more demanded than lying
which is more demanded than lying about
him.
him. No.
So
So we
So we develop
So we develop a
So we develop a certain
So we develop a certain compassion
because
because we
So we develop a certain compassion
because we realize
because we realize the
So we develop a certain compassion
because we realize the limitation
because we realize the limitation of
So we develop a certain compassion
because we realize the limitation of the
human
human condition.
human condition. We
human condition. We realize
human condition. We realize that
human condition. We realize that without
divine
divine intervention,
human condition. We realize that without
divine intervention, our
divine intervention, our goose
human condition. We realize that without
divine intervention, our goose is
cooked.
cooked. That's
cooked. That's f
cooked. That's f that's
cooked. That's f that's a
cooked. That's f that's a fact.
cooked. That's f that's a fact. Without
divine
divine intervention,
you're
you're get
you're get it.
you're get it. That
you're get it. That a
you're get it. That a fact.
We
We have
you're get it. That a fact.
We have permission
We have permission to
you're get it. That a fact.
We have permission to ask
We have permission to ask if
you're get it. That a fact.
We have permission to ask if that's
We have permission to ask if that's a
fact
fact or
fact or just
fact or just that
fact or just that is
fact or just that is a
fact or just that is a fact.
fact or just that is a fact. Is
fact or just that is a fact. Is this
Whoa.
Whoa. Without
fact or just that is a fact. Is this
Whoa. Without divine
Whoa. Without divine intervention,
we're
we're goners.
That's
That's why
we're goners.
That's why the
That's why the atheist
we're goners.
That's why the atheist is
That's why the atheist is in
we're goners.
That's why the atheist is in sort
That's why the atheist is in sort of
we're goners.
That's why the atheist is in sort of a
tacky
tacky situation
tacky situation [laughter]
at
at the
tacky situation [laughter]
at the weighing
at the weighing of
tacky situation [laughter]
at the weighing of the
at the weighing of the scales
tacky situation [laughter]
at the weighing of the scales when
at the weighing of the scales when he
faces
faces Osiris.
faces Osiris. You
faces Osiris. You know,
faces Osiris. You know, who's
faces Osiris. You know, who's he
faces Osiris. You know, who's he going
to
to call
faces Osiris. You know, who's he going
to call to
to call to speak
faces Osiris. You know, who's he going
to call to speak for
to call to speak for him?
faces Osiris. You know, who's he going
to call to speak for him? Uh,
to call to speak for him? Uh, anybody?
Anybody
Anybody out
Anybody out there
Anybody out there to
Anybody out there to speak
Anybody out there to speak for
Anybody out there to speak for this
soul?
The
The god
The god of
The god of the
The god of the underworld
The god of the underworld is
The god of the underworld is waiting
The god of the underworld is waiting for
you.
There's
There's times
There's times when
There's times when you
There's times when you need
There's times when you need friends.
There's
There's times
There's times when you need friends.
There's times when
There's times when it
There's times when you need friends.
There's times when it would
There's times when it would be
There's times when you need friends.
There's times when it would be good
There's times when it would be good that
you
you were
you were kind
you were kind to
you were kind to at least
you were kind to at least one
you were kind to at least one person
once.
[laughter]
I
I gave
[laughter]
I gave my
I gave my seat
[laughter]
I gave my seat to
I gave my seat to that
[laughter]
I gave my seat to that pregnant
I gave my seat to that pregnant lady
[laughter]
I gave my seat to that pregnant lady in
the
the subway.
All
All right.
[laughter]
If
If there's
[laughter]
If there's even
If there's even a
[laughter]
If there's even a speck
If there's even a speck of
[laughter]
If there's even a speck of hope.
Salvation
Salvation is
Salvation is possible.
Salvation is possible. Whoa.
Salvation is possible. Whoa. Is
Salvation is possible. Whoa. Is that
right?
If
If there's
If there's even
If there's even a
If there's even a speck
If there's even a speck of
If there's even a speck of hope,
salvation
salvation is
If there's even a speck of hope,
salvation is possible.
salvation is possible. Is
If there's even a speck of hope,
salvation is possible. Is this
what
what a
what a relief?
So
So instead
what a relief?
So instead of
So instead of focusing
what a relief?
So instead of focusing on
So instead of focusing on a
what a relief?
So instead of focusing on a negative
punitive
punitive God
punitive God who
punitive God who is
punitive God who is irrational,
punitive God who is irrational, sort
punitive God who is irrational, sort of
semi-csychotic,
semi-csychotic, paranoid,
punitive God who is irrational, sort of
semi-csychotic, paranoid, sensitive,
overreactive,
partial,
extremely
extremely neurotic
depictions
depictions of
extremely neurotic
depictions of God.
depictions of God. We
extremely neurotic
depictions of God. We have
depictions of God. We have an
extremely neurotic
depictions of God. We have an infinite
presence
which
which guarantees
presence
which guarantees the
which guarantees the absolute
presence
which guarantees the absolute justice
which guarantees the absolute justice of
all
all of
all of life
all of life throughout
all of life throughout all
all of life throughout all of
all of life throughout all of time.
It's
It's the
all of life throughout all of time.
It's the creator
It's the creator and
all of life throughout all of time.
It's the creator and sustainer
It's the creator and sustainer of
all of life throughout all of time.
It's the creator and sustainer of life.
out
out of
out of which
out of which comes
out of which comes the
out of which comes the guarantee
out of which comes the guarantee that
life
life itself
out of which comes the guarantee that
life itself cannot
life itself cannot be
out of which comes the guarantee that
life itself cannot be lost.
One
One one
One one cannot
One one cannot lose
One one cannot lose one's
One one cannot lose one's life.
One one cannot lose one's life. One's
life,
life, the
One one cannot lose one's life. One's
life, the essence
life, the essence of
One one cannot lose one's life. One's
life, the essence of that
life, the essence of that which
One one cannot lose one's life. One's
life, the essence of that which is
life, the essence of that which is the
self
self as
self as it
self as it shines
self as it shines forth
self as it shines forth is
self as it shines forth is beyond
self as it shines forth is beyond all
material,
material, beyond
self as it shines forth is beyond all
material, beyond all
material, beyond all design,
self as it shines forth is beyond all
material, beyond all design, beyond
material, beyond all design, beyond all
structure,
structure, beyond
structure, beyond all
structure, beyond all bodies,
structure, beyond all bodies, beyond
structure, beyond all bodies, beyond all
thoughts.
It
It has
It has no
It has no place
It has no place in
It has no place in time.
It has no place in time. It
It has no place in time. It has
It has no place in time. It has no
structure,
structure, no
It has no place in time. It has no
structure, no form.
structure, no form. That
It has no place in time. It has no
structure, no form. That which
structure, no form. That which you
It has no place in time. It has no
structure, no form. That which you are
is
is invisible
is invisible beyond
is invisible beyond all
is invisible beyond all form
is invisible beyond all form and
indestructible
because
because only
only
only structure
because only
only structure can
only structure can only
because only
only structure can only form
only structure can only form can
because only
only structure can only form can be
destroyed.
If
If that
destroyed.
If that which
If that which you
destroyed.
If that which you are
If that which you are is
destroyed.
If that which you are is beyond
If that which you are is beyond all
destroyed.
If that which you are is beyond all form
then
then you
then you are
then you are indestructible.
And
And one
then you are indestructible.
And one of
And one of the
then you are indestructible.
And one of the coolest
And one of the coolest things
then you are indestructible.
And one of the coolest things when
And one of the coolest things when you
get
get into
get into a
get into a really
get into a really great
get into a really great space
get into a really great space is
get into a really great space is you
realize
realize you're
get into a really great space is you
realize you're in
realize you're in invisible.
get into a really great space is you
realize you're in invisible. It's
realize you're in invisible. It's really
cool
cool when
cool when it
cool when it first
cool when it first hits
cool when it first hits you
cool when it first hits you who
cool when it first hits you who you
cool when it first hits you who you are.
It's
It's totally
cool when it first hits you who you are.
It's totally invisible.
It's totally invisible. Nobody
cool when it first hits you who you are.
It's totally invisible. Nobody can
It's totally invisible. Nobody can see
at
at all.
at all. It's
at all. It's hysterical.
It's
It's like
at all. It's hysterical.
It's like your
It's like your little
at all. It's hysterical.
It's like your little secret.
They
They all
They all think
They all think you're
They all think you're this.
What
What a
They all think you're this.
What a guess.
What a guess. Like
They all think you're this.
What a guess. Like they
What a guess. Like they think
They all think you're this.
What a guess. Like they think you're
this,
this, but
this, but you're
this, but you're really
this, but you're really over
this, but you're really over here.
this, but you're really over here. You
know what
know what I'm
this, but you're really over here. You
know what I'm saying?
[laughter]
Ah,
Ah, yeah.
[laughter]
Ah, yeah. You're
Ah, yeah. You're safely
[laughter]
Ah, yeah. You're safely out
Ah, yeah. You're safely out of
[laughter]
Ah, yeah. You're safely out of the
Ah, yeah. You're safely out of the way.
The
The real
The real you
The real you is
The real you is safely
The real you is safely out
The real you is safely out of
The real you is safely out of the
The real you is safely out of the way.
If
If it
The real you is safely out of the way.
If it gets
If it gets run
The real you is safely out of the way.
If it gets run over
If it gets run over by
The real you is safely out of the way.
If it gets run over by a
If it gets run over by a truck,
The real you is safely out of the way.
If it gets run over by a truck, don't
worry
worry about
worry about it
worry about it at
worry about it at all.
worry about it at all. Let
worry about it at all. Let it
worry about it at all. Let it go
worry about it at all. Let it go over
the
the cliff
worry about it at all. Let it go over
the cliff and
the cliff and uh
worry about it at all. Let it go over
the cliff and uh you'll
the cliff and uh you'll be
worry about it at all. Let it go over
the cliff and uh you'll be surprised
the cliff and uh you'll be surprised at
the
the bottom.
>> [laughter]
>> It's
>> It's terrific.
You've
You've done
>> It's terrific.
You've done it
You've done it before.
>> It's terrific.
You've done it before. And
You've done it before. And as
>> It's terrific.
You've done it before. And as it
happens,
happens, you
happens, you recall
happens, you recall it
happens, you recall it from
happens, you recall it from before,
happens, you recall it from before, too.
You
You recall
happens, you recall it from before, too.
You recall it.
You recall it. Recall.
happens, you recall it from before, too.
You recall it. Recall. You
You recall it. Recall. You The
happens, you recall it from before, too.
You recall it. Recall. You The memory
comes
comes back.
comes back. Oh,
comes back. Oh, yes.
Remember
Remember going
comes back. Oh, yes.
Remember going over
Remember going over the
comes back. Oh, yes.
Remember going over the cliff
Remember going over the cliff in
comes back. Oh, yes.
Remember going over the cliff in the
Andes.
Andes. You
Andes. You remember
Andes. You remember each
Andes. You remember each and
Andes. You remember each and every
Andes. You remember each and every one.
You
You remember
Andes. You remember each and every one.
You remember the
You remember the circumstances.
Some
Some of
Some of them
Some of them were
Some of them were very
Some of them were very funny.
Some of them were very funny. I
Some of them were very funny. I told
Some of them were very funny. I told you
some
some of
Some of them were very funny. I told you
some of the
some of the funny
Some of them were very funny. I told you
some of the funny ones
some of the funny ones here.
I
I killed
I killed him
I killed him for
I killed him for Jesus
I killed him for Jesus and
I killed him for Jesus and he
I killed him for Jesus and he killed
I killed him for Jesus and he killed me
for
for all.
I killed him for Jesus and he killed me
for all. It
for all. It was
I killed him for Jesus and he killed me
for all. It was hysterical,
for all. It was hysterical, you
I killed him for Jesus and he killed me
for all. It was hysterical, you know,
for all. It was hysterical, you know, we
couldn't
couldn't stop
couldn't stop laughing
couldn't stop laughing for
couldn't stop laughing for a
couldn't stop laughing for a couple
centuries
centuries or
couldn't stop laughing for a couple
centuries or whatever
centuries or whatever it
couldn't stop laughing for a couple
centuries or whatever it was.
However,
However, we
However, we both
However, we both serve
However, we both serve God.
We
We both
However, we both serve God.
We both serve
We both serve God
However, we both serve God.
We both serve God and
We both serve God and God
However, we both serve God.
We both serve God and God in
We both serve God and God in his
infinite
infinite mercy
infinite mercy forgives
infinite mercy forgives us
infinite mercy forgives us our
ignorance.
ignorance. And
infinite mercy forgives us our
ignorance. And therefore,
ignorance. And therefore, we
infinite mercy forgives us our
ignorance. And therefore, we have
ignorance. And therefore, we have to
learn
learn our
learn our love
learn our love to
learn our love to love
learn our love to love oursel
learn our love to love oursel and
learn our love to love oursel and to
learn our love to love oursel and to our
our
our fellow
learn our love to love oursel and to our
our fellow human
our fellow human beings
learn our love to love oursel and to our
our fellow human beings despite
our fellow human beings despite all
learn our love to love oursel and to our
our fellow human beings despite all our
limitations.
And
And we'll
limitations.
And we'll take
And we'll take a
limitations.
And we'll take a break.
And we'll take a break. Kieran,
limitations.
And we'll take a break. Kieran, how
about
about some
about some music
about some music while
about some music while we
about some music while we take
about some music while we take a
about some music while we take a break?
[music]
[singing]
>> [music]
[music]
>> song.
[music] Give
[music] Give [singing]
>> song.
[music] Give [singing] me
[singing]
[music]
>> [singing]
>> song.
>> song. [music]
[singing]
[music]
I
I have
[music]
I have to
I have to learn
[music]
I have to learn how
I have to learn how to
[music]
I have to learn how to function
I have to learn how to function in
[music]
I have to learn how to function in that
space.
>> Is
>> Is this
space.
>> Is this thing
>> Is this thing on?
Is
Is this
Is this thing
Is this thing on?
>> Keep
>> Keep going.
Is this thing on?
>> Keep going. No,
>> Keep going. No, she's
Is this thing on?
>> Keep going. No, she's got
>> Keep going. No, she's got it
Is this thing on?
>> Keep going. No, she's got it turned
>> Keep going. No, she's got it turned off.
>> It's
>> It's on.
>> The
>> The forces
>> It's on.
>> The forces of
>> The forces of our
>> It's on.
>> The forces of our divinity
>> The forces of our divinity have
>> It's on.
>> The forces of our divinity have spoken.
Well,
Well, that
Well, that took
Well, that took us
Well, that took us out
Well, that took us out of
Well, that took us out of that
Well, that took us out of that state,
didn't
didn't it?
It's
It's difficult
It's difficult to
It's difficult to function
It's difficult to function as
It's difficult to function as uh
your
your awareness
It's difficult to function as uh
your awareness progresses
one
one finally
one finally reaches
one finally reaches a
one finally reaches a state
one finally reaches a state of
immobilization
and
and uh
and uh I
and uh I advise
and uh I advise everybody
and uh I advise everybody to
and uh I advise everybody to leave
and uh I advise everybody to leave at
that
that point
and uh I advise everybody to leave at
that point [laughter]
you
you can't
you can't get
you can't get a
you can't get a chance
you can't get a chance take
you can't get a chance take it
you can't get a chance take it no
there's
there's karmic
you can't get a chance take it no
there's karmic propensities
there's karmic propensities momentum
that
that may
after
after some
that may
after some here
after some here is
that may
after some here is stir
after some here is stir you
that may
after some here is stir you to
after some here is stir you to moving
about
about again
about again and
about again and learning
about again and learning how
about again and learning how to
about again and learning how to live
about again and learning how to live in
the
the world.
about again and learning how to live in
the world. H
see
see the
see the depictions
see the depictions of
see the depictions of divinity
see the depictions of divinity which
see the depictions of divinity which are
transcendent
transcendent which
see the depictions of divinity which are
transcendent which are
transcendent which are traditional
see the depictions of divinity which are
transcendent which are traditional in
religion
are
are based
religion
are based on
are based on causality
religion
are based on causality and
are based on causality and picture
religion
are based on causality and picture a
linearity
because
because it's
linearity
because it's an
because it's an expression
linearity
because it's an expression of
because it's an expression of the
linearity
because it's an expression of the ego
because it's an expression of the ego as
defined
defined through
defined through the
defined through the intellect.
defined through the intellect. It
defined through the intellect. It sees
things
things in
defined through the intellect. It sees
things in terms
things in terms of
defined through the intellect. It sees
things in terms of temporal
things in terms of temporal sequence
defined through the intellect. It sees
things in terms of temporal sequence and
causality
causality and
causality and therefore
causality and therefore of
causality and therefore of time.
The
The trouble
causality and therefore of time.
The trouble with
The trouble with that
causality and therefore of time.
The trouble with that is
The trouble with that is it
causality and therefore of time.
The trouble with that is it eliminates
God
God as
God as a
God as a reality.
God
God then
God as a reality.
God then becomes
God then becomes an
God as a reality.
God then becomes an historical
God then becomes an historical event
that
that happened
that happened to
that happened to somebody.
that happened to somebody. It's
that happened to somebody. It's always
on
on in
that happened to somebody. It's always
on in some
on in some weird
that happened to somebody. It's always
on in some weird place
on in some weird place on
that happened to somebody. It's always
on in some weird place on the
on in some weird place on the planet
and
and it's
and it's always
and it's always elsewhere
and it's always elsewhere in
and it's always elsewhere in time.
God
God never
and it's always elsewhere in time.
God never comes
God never comes to,
and it's always elsewhere in time.
God never comes to, you
God never comes to, you know,
and it's always elsewhere in time.
God never comes to, you know, somebody
going
going to
going to work
going to work on
going to work on Madison
going to work on Madison Avenue
[laughter]
in
in some
in some remote
in some remote place
in some remote place barefoot
in some remote place barefoot in
in some remote place barefoot in the
sands
sands of
in some remote place barefoot in the
sands of some
sands of some place
in some remote place barefoot in the
sands of some place that
sands of some place that makes
in some remote place barefoot in the
sands of some place that makes it
esoteric
esoteric and
esoteric and you
esoteric and you don't
esoteric and you don't really
esoteric and you don't really identify
with
with the
esoteric and you don't really identify
with the reality
with the reality of
esoteric and you don't really identify
with the reality of it
elsewhere
elsewhere in
elsewhere in time
elsewhere in time and
elsewhere in time and place
elsewhere in time and place and
elsewhere in time and place and often
elsewhere in time and place and often in
a
a strange
elsewhere in time and place and often in
a strange manner.
So
So the
So the humankind
So the humankind doesn't
So the humankind doesn't really
So the humankind doesn't really identify
with
with it.
So the humankind doesn't really identify
with it. What
with it. What humankind
So the humankind doesn't really identify
with it. What humankind tends
with it. What humankind tends to
So the humankind doesn't really identify
with it. What humankind tends to deify
is
is history,
is history, historical
is history, historical events
which
which are
is history, historical events
which are somewhat
which are somewhat interesting
is history, historical events
which are somewhat interesting but
which are somewhat interesting but not
really
not
not really
really
not really because
not really because they
really
not really because they become
not really because they become a
really
not really because they become a block
to
to the
to the awareness
that
that the
to the awareness
that the presence
that the presence of
to the awareness
that the presence of God
that the presence of God is
at
at this
at this very
at this very instant.
The
The presence
at this very instant.
The presence of
The presence of God
at this very instant.
The presence of God is
The presence of God is an
at this very instant.
The presence of God is an alwaysness
The presence of God is an alwaysness in
alwaysness.
alwaysness. It's
alwaysness. It's not
alwaysness. It's not a
alwaysness. It's not a now.
alwaysness. It's not a now. It's
alwaysness. It's not a now. It's not
alwaysness. It's not a now. It's not a
then,
then, nor
alwaysness. It's not a now. It's not a
then, nor is
then, nor is it
alwaysness. It's not a now. It's not a
then, nor is it in
then, nor is it in the
alwaysness. It's not a now. It's not a
then, nor is it in the future.
The
The displacement
The displacement of
The displacement of God
The displacement of God to
The displacement of God to elsewhere
The displacement of God to elsewhere in
time
time and
The displacement of God to elsewhere in
time and place
time and place is
The displacement of God to elsewhere in
time and place is what
time and place is what the
The displacement of God to elsewhere in
time and place is what the downside
time and place is what the downside of
religion.
Came
Came in,
religion.
Came in, rolled
Came in, rolled the
religion.
Came in, rolled the dice,
Came in, rolled the dice, now
religion.
Came in, rolled the dice, now on
judgment
judgment day.
judgment day. Uhoh.
That
That removes
judgment day. Uhoh.
That removes God
That removes God as
judgment day. Uhoh.
That removes God as the
That removes God as the current
judgment day. Uhoh.
That removes God as the current reality.
uh
uh and
uh and source
uh and source of
uh and source of one's
uh and source of one's existence.
The
The recognition
uh and source of one's existence.
The recognition of
The recognition of the
uh and source of one's existence.
The recognition of the presence
The recognition of the presence of
uh and source of one's existence.
The recognition of the presence of God
is
is a
is a radiance
is a radiance that
is a radiance that arises
is a radiance that arises out
is a radiance that arises out of
is a radiance that arises out of the
awareness
awareness of
is a radiance that arises out of the
awareness of right
awareness of right this
is a radiance that arises out of the
awareness of right this instant.
1 10,000th
1 10,000th of
1 10,000th of a
1 10,000th of a second.
In
In 1,000th
1 10,000th of a second.
In 1,000th of
In 1,000th of a
1 10,000th of a second.
In 1,000th of a second,
In 1,000th of a second, one
1 10,000th of a second.
In 1,000th of a second, one comes
In 1,000th of a second, one comes out
1 10,000th of a second.
In 1,000th of a second, one comes out of
this
this and
this and realizes
this and realizes the
this and realizes the alwaysness
this and realizes the alwaysness of
this and realizes the alwaysness of that
which
which always
this and realizes the alwaysness of that
which always is.
The
The mystics
The mystics then
The mystics then emphasizes
the
the realization
The mystics then emphasizes
the realization of
the realization of the
The mystics then emphasizes
the realization of the presence
the realization of the presence of
The mystics then emphasizes
the realization of the presence of God
now
now at
now at this
now at this instant
now at this instant as
now at this instant as the
now at this instant as the ongoingness
out
out of
now at this instant as the ongoingness
out of which
out of which your
now at this instant as the ongoingness
out of which your own
out of which your own existence
now at this instant as the ongoingness
out of which your own existence arises.
There's
There's no
There's no point
There's no point in
There's no point in worshiping
There's no point in worshiping history
and
and places
There's no point in worshiping history
and places people
and places people they
There's no point in worshiping history
and places people they walked
and places people they walked here
There's no point in worshiping history
and places people they walked here they
walked
walked there.
walked there. people
walked there. people were
walked there. people were these
walked there. people were these people
walked
walked and
walked there. people were these people
walked and talked
walked and talked right
walked there. people were these people
walked and talked right now
walked and talked right now calibrate
about
about 1:30
[laughter]
unlikely
unlikely to
unlikely to get
unlikely to get to
unlikely to get to heaven
unlikely to get to heaven in
unlikely to get to heaven in the
unlikely to get to heaven in the holy
lands.
So
So that
So that which
So that which was
So that which was once
So that which was once sacrian
So that which was once sacrian has
So that which was once sacrian has not
been
been corrupted.
No,
God
God is
No,
God is found
God is found in
the
the sacredness,
the sacredness, the
the sacredness, the respect
the sacredness, the respect for
the sacredness, the respect for the
sacredness
sacredness of
the sacredness, the respect for the
sacredness of all
sacredness of all of
the sacredness, the respect for the
sacredness of all of life
sacredness of all of life and
the sacredness, the respect for the
sacredness of all of life and all
sacredness of all of life and all that
exists
exists in
exists in this
exists in this instant.
People
People say,
exists in this instant.
People say, "Well,
People say, "Well, what
exists in this instant.
People say, "Well, what about
People say, "Well, what about the
wicked?
They're
They're the
wicked?
They're the perfect
They're the perfect expression
wicked?
They're the perfect expression of
wickedness.
Why
Why would
wickedness.
Why would you
Why would you want
wickedness.
Why would you want to
Why would you want to change
wickedness.
Why would you want to change them?
[laughter]
They're
They're exactly
[laughter]
They're exactly what
They're exactly what they
[laughter]
They're exactly what they are,
ugly,
ugly, horrible.
[laughter]
Uh
Uh they're
Uh they're the
Uh they're the perfect
Uh they're the perfect expression
Uh they're the perfect expression of
wickedness
so
so that
so that you
so that you can
so that you can see
so that you can see what
so that you can see what it
so that you can see what it is
so that you can see what it is and
so that you can see what it is and you
have
have a
so that you can see what it is and you
have a choice.
The
The great
The great benefit,
The great benefit, the
The great benefit, the great
The great benefit, the great value
The great benefit, the great value of
this
this life
The great benefit, the great value of
this life then
this life then is
The great benefit, the great value of
this life then is it
this life then is it that
The great benefit, the great value of
this life then is it that every
this life then is it that every instant
within
within an
within an infinite
within an infinite complexity
within an infinite complexity of
choices,
choices, a
within an infinite complexity of
choices, a million
choices, a million and
within an infinite complexity of
choices, a million and millions
choices, a million and millions of
choices
choices are
choices are constantly
choices are constantly present,
cintillating,
cintillating, shifting
choices are constantly present,
cintillating, shifting from
cintillating, shifting from moment
choices are constantly present,
cintillating, shifting from moment to
moment
moment so
moment so that
moment so that we
moment so that we trace
moment so that we trace our
moment so that we trace our own
moment so that we trace our own karmic
path.
You
You know,
You know, we
You know, we imprint
You know, we imprint upon
You know, we imprint upon our
You know, we imprint upon our own
You know, we imprint upon our own spirit
the
the record
You know, we imprint upon our own spirit
the record of
the record of all
You know, we imprint upon our own spirit
the record of all that
the record of all that has
You know, we imprint upon our own spirit
the record of all that has befallen
the record of all that has befallen us
and
and what
and what our
and what our response
and what our response has
and what our response has been.
and what our response has been. So
and what our response has been. So the
value
value of
and what our response has been. So the
value of this
value of this life
and what our response has been. So the
value of this life is
that
that instant
that instant to
that instant to instant
we
we constantly
that instant to instant
we constantly choose
we constantly choose and
that instant to instant
we constantly choose and thereby
determine
determine our
determine our own
determine our own future.
determine our own future. It's
determine our own future. It's not
determine our own future. It's not up
determine our own future. It's not up to
some
some arbitrary
determine our own future. It's not up to
some arbitrary judge
some arbitrary judge elsewhere.
Not
Not up
Not up to
Not up to some
Not up to some arbitrary
Not up to some arbitrary judge
elsewhere.
That
That which
That which I'm
That which I'm envisioning
That which I'm envisioning is
That which I'm envisioning is of
That which I'm envisioning is of the
underworld.
underworld. Is
That which I'm envisioning is of the
underworld. Is it
underworld. Is it Cyrus
That which I'm envisioning is of the
underworld. Is it Cyrus is
underworld. Is it Cyrus is of
That which I'm envisioning is of the
underworld. Is it Cyrus is of the
underworld,
underworld, not
underworld, not of
underworld, not of heaven?
Oh,
we
we have
we have lots
we have lots of
we have lots of wonderful
we have lots of wonderful questions.
I
I wish
we have lots of wonderful questions.
I wish I'd
I wish I'd read
we have lots of wonderful questions.
I wish I'd read the
I wish I'd read the section
we have lots of wonderful questions.
I wish I'd read the section on
I wish I'd read the section on theology
in
in the
in the encyclopedia
in the encyclopedia Britannica.
I
I mean,
in the encyclopedia Britannica.
I mean, we've
I mean, we've got
in the encyclopedia Britannica.
I mean, we've got some
I mean, we've got some busters
in the encyclopedia Britannica.
I mean, we've got some busters here,
I'll
I'll tell
I'll tell you.
Some
Some of
I'll tell you.
Some of these
Some of these would
I'll tell you.
Some of these would stagger
[laughter]
and
and I
[laughter]
and I thank
and I thank you
[laughter]
and I thank you for
and I thank you for them.
The
The complexity
The complexity of
The complexity of the
The complexity of the human
The complexity of the human mind
The complexity of the human mind is
stirring
stirring you
The complexity of the human mind is
stirring you know
and
and it
and it all
and it all all
and it all all the
and it all all the thinkingness
and it all all the thinkingness is
arising
arising out
and it all all the thinkingness is
arising out of
arising out of um
it's
it's a
it's a matter
it's a matter of
it's a matter of focus
it's a matter of focus instead
it's a matter of focus instead of
focusing
focusing into
it's a matter of focus instead of
focusing into the
focusing into the whatness
it's a matter of focus instead of
focusing into the whatness of
focusing into the whatness of life.
it's a matter of focus instead of
focusing into the whatness of life. It's
focusing
focusing into
focusing into the
focusing into the source
focusing into the source of
focusing into the source of the
awareness
awareness of
focusing into the source of the
awareness of that
awareness of that life.
focusing into the source of the
awareness of that life. How
awareness of that life. How does
focusing into the source of the
awareness of that life. How does one
come
come into
come into conscious
come into conscious awareness?
The
The source
come into conscious awareness?
The source of
The source of that
come into conscious awareness?
The source of that conscious
The source of that conscious awareness
is
is the
is the self
is the self with
is the self with a
is the self with a capital
is the self with a capital S
is the self with a capital S which
is the self with a capital S which is
not
not different
is the self with a capital S which is
not different than
not different than God.
God
God is
God is everywhere
God is everywhere at
God is everywhere at all
God is everywhere at all times.
Therefore,
Therefore, present
God is everywhere at all times.
Therefore, present within
Therefore, present within you.
God is everywhere at all times.
Therefore, present within you. Huh?
The
The idea
The idea of
The idea of a
The idea of a transcendent
The idea of a transcendent God
The idea of a transcendent God is
The idea of a transcendent God is God
The idea of a transcendent God is God is
elsewhere.
elsewhere. Elsewhere
The idea of a transcendent God is God is
elsewhere. Elsewhere you
elsewhere. Elsewhere you have
The idea of a transcendent God is God is
elsewhere. Elsewhere you have to
elsewhere. Elsewhere you have to seek
God
God elsewhere
God elsewhere or
God elsewhere or hope
God elsewhere or hope for
God elsewhere or hope for him
God elsewhere or hope for him after
death.
That
That makes
That makes God
That makes God inaccessible
That makes God inaccessible and
That makes God inaccessible and and
really
really a
That makes God inaccessible and and
really a non-reality.
really a non-reality. It
That makes God inaccessible and and
really a non-reality. It makes
really a non-reality. It makes God
That makes God inaccessible and and
really a non-reality. It makes God a
belief
belief system.
belief system. It
belief system. It makes
belief system. It makes God
belief system. It makes God a
belief system. It makes God a dogma.
First
First of
belief system. It makes God a dogma.
First of all,
First of all, all
belief system. It makes God a dogma.
First of all, all these
First of all, all these religions
belief system. It makes God a dogma.
First of all, all these religions give
First of all, all these religions give a
name
name to
name to God
name to God and
name to God and then
name to God and then become
name to God and then become proprietary.
[laughter]
that
that which
that which has
that which has no
that which has no name,
that which has no name, they
that which has no name, they put
that which has no name, they put a
that which has no name, they put a name
on
on and
that which has no name, they put a name
on and then
on and then kill
that which has no name, they put a name
on and then kill anybody
on and then kill anybody that
that which has no name, they put a name
on and then kill anybody that doesn't
on and then kill anybody that doesn't go
with
with that
with that name.
with that name. I
with that name. I mean,
with that name. I mean, that's
with that name. I mean, that's really
such
such uh
with that name. I mean, that's really
such uh so
such uh so far
with that name. I mean, that's really
such uh so far from
such uh so far from where
with that name. I mean, that's really
such uh so far from where it's
such uh so far from where it's at,
with that name. I mean, that's really
such uh so far from where it's at, you
know,
uh
that
that which
that which is
that which is innately
that which is innately present
that which is innately present to
that which is innately present to all
that
that exists.
that which is innately present to all
that exists. The
that exists. The very
that which is innately present to all
that exists. The very source
that exists. The very source and
that which is innately present to all
that exists. The very source and essence
of
of life
of life itself
of life itself is
of life itself is nameless,
of life itself is nameless, invisible,
has
has no
of life itself is nameless, invisible,
has no form
has no form parts,
of life itself is nameless, invisible,
has no form parts, [clears throat]
has no form parts, [clears throat] has
no
no motivations,
no motivations, has
no motivations, has no
no motivations, has no axis
no motivations, has no axis to
no motivations, has no axis to grind,
has
has no
no motivations, has no axis to grind,
has no purposes.
The
The karmic
The karmic unity
The karmic unity of
The karmic unity of all
The karmic unity of all of
The karmic unity of all of existence,
The karmic unity of all of existence, as
I
I said,
The karmic unity of all of existence, as
I said, is
I said, is like
The karmic unity of all of existence, as
I said, is like an
I said, is like an infinitely
The karmic unity of all of existence, as
I said, is like an infinitely powerful
field
field which
field which recognizes
field which recognizes and
field which recognizes and records
everything.
everything. Everything
field which recognizes and records
everything. Everything has
everything. Everything has an
field which recognizes and records
everything. Everything has an automatic
consequence,
consequence, not
consequence, not an
consequence, not an arbitrary
consequence, not an arbitrary one,
consequence, not an arbitrary one, not
consequence, not an arbitrary one, not a
moralistic
moralistic judgmental
consequence, not an arbitrary one, not a
moralistic judgmental one.
moralistic judgmental one. It's
automatic.
Every
Every thought
automatic.
Every thought then
Every thought then is
automatic.
Every thought then is like
Every thought then is like a
automatic.
Every thought then is like a minute
particle.
particle. 1
particle. 1 -
particle. 1 - 400
particle. 1 - 400 10
particle. 1 - 400 10 the
particle. 1 - 400 10 the minus
particle. 1 - 400 10 the minus 400
millionth
millionth of
particle. 1 - 400 10 the minus 400
millionth of a
millionth of a watt.
It's
It's like
It's like a
It's like a tiny
It's like a tiny particle
It's like a tiny particle that
It's like a tiny particle that has
It's like a tiny particle that has a
charge
charge and
It's like a tiny particle that has a
charge and a
charge and a configuration.
It's like a tiny particle that has a
charge and a configuration. So
charge and a configuration. So if
everything
everything that
everything that ever
everything that ever existence
everything that ever existence ever
existed
existed radiates
everything that ever existence ever
existed radiates out
existed radiates out at
everything that ever existence ever
existed radiates out at every
existed radiates out at every instant
an
an energy
an energy and
an energy and this
an energy and this energy
an energy and this energy has
an energy and this energy has a
polarity.
It
It either
It either gravitates
It either gravitates to
It either gravitates to the
It either gravitates to the top
It either gravitates to the top of
It either gravitates to the top of the
chart
chart or
It either gravitates to the top of the
chart or the
chart or the bottom
It either gravitates to the top of the
chart or the bottom of
chart or the bottom of the
It either gravitates to the top of the
chart or the bottom of the chart.
It
It has
It has a
It has a charge.
Some
Some charges
It has a charge.
Some charges are
Some charges are stronger
It has a charge.
Some charges are stronger than
Some charges are stronger than other
charges.
You
You can
charges.
You can say
You can say that's
charges.
You can say that's not
You can say that's not fair.
But
But that's
But that's the
But that's the charge
But that's the charge in
But that's the charge in your
But that's the charge in your head.
But that's the charge in your head. You
know,
no,
no, everything
no, everything is
no, everything is innately
no, everything is innately and
absolutely
absolutely fair.
no, everything is innately and
absolutely fair. Why?
absolutely fair. Why? Because
no, everything is innately and
absolutely fair. Why? Because everything
can
can only
can only be
can only be that
can only be that which
can only be that which it
can only be that which it is.
can only be that which it is. You
can only be that which it is. You can't
be
be that
can only be that which it is. You can't
be that which
be that which you
can only be that which it is. You can't
be that which you are
be that which you are not.
Consequently,
Consequently, if
Consequently, if you
Consequently, if you can
Consequently, if you can only
Consequently, if you can only be
Consequently, if you can only be that
which
which you
Consequently, if you can only be that
which you are,
then
then what
then what occurs
then what occurs as
then what occurs as a
then what occurs as a consequence
then what occurs as a consequence of
that
that is
then what occurs as a consequence of
that is absolute
that is absolute perfection.
That
That which
That which is
That which is charged
That which is charged this
That which is charged this way
gravitates
gravitates this
That which is charged this way
gravitates this way
gravitates this way and
That which is charged this way
gravitates this way and this
gravitates this way and this that
That which is charged this way
gravitates this way and this that which
is
is charged
is charged this
is charged this way
is charged this way gravitates
is charged this way gravitates this
is charged this way gravitates this way
automatically
as
as the
as the nature
as the nature of
as the nature of the
as the nature of the expression
as the nature of the expression of
as the nature of the expression of that
which
which it
as the nature of the expression of that
which it is.
What
What could
What could be
What could be more
What could be more divine?
That
That each
What could be more divine?
That each thing
That each thing only
What could be more divine?
That each thing only experiences
That each thing only experiences that
which
which is
which is faded
which is faded to
which is faded to itself.
At
At the
which is faded to itself.
At the same
At the same time,
which is faded to itself.
At the same time, it
At the same time, it has
which is faded to itself.
At the same time, it has at
At the same time, it has at all
which is faded to itself.
At the same time, it has at all times
At the same time, it has at all times at
hand
hand a
hand a means
hand a means of
hand a means of salvation
hand a means of salvation from
hand a means of salvation from those
errors
errors that
hand a means of salvation from those
errors that may
errors that may have
hand a means of salvation from those
errors that may have been
errors that may have been made.
hand a means of salvation from those
errors that may have been made. Huh?
The
The infinite
The infinite mercy
The infinite mercy of
The infinite mercy of God
The infinite mercy of God is
The infinite mercy of God is that
through
through prayer,
The infinite mercy of God is that
through prayer, through
through prayer, through divine
intervention,
intervention, the
intervention, the opportunity
intervention, the opportunity to
transcend
transcend exists
intervention, the opportunity to
transcend exists always
at
at the
at the depths
at the depths of
at the depths of the
at the depths of the pits
at the depths of the pits of
at the depths of the pits of hell
beyond
beyond all
at the depths of the pits of hell
beyond all human
beyond all human imagination,
but
but intuited
but intuited and
but intuited and written
but intuited and written about
but intuited and written about by
but intuited and written about by Dante.
In
In the
but intuited and written about by Dante.
In the pits
In the pits of
but intuited and written about by Dante.
In the pits of the
In the pits of the foreverness
but intuited and written about by Dante.
In the pits of the foreverness of
In the pits of the foreverness of hell
which
which goes
which goes on
which goes on through
which goes on through timeless
which goes on through timeless eons
a
a black
which goes on through timeless eons
a black despair
of
of agony
of agony of
of agony of the
of agony of the soul
of agony of the soul which
of agony of the soul which cannot
of agony of the soul which cannot be
described
in
in the
in the incredible
in the incredible pits
in the incredible pits of
in the incredible pits of hell.
The
The voice
in the incredible pits of hell.
The voice said,
The voice said, "If
in the incredible pits of hell.
The voice said, "If there
The voice said, "If there is
in the incredible pits of hell.
The voice said, "If there is a
The voice said, "If there is a God,
in the incredible pits of hell.
The voice said, "If there is a God, I
ask
ask him
ask him to
ask him to help
ask him to help me.
[sighs]
Then
Then came
Then came forth
Then came forth oblivion.
And
And then
Then came forth oblivion.
And then the
And then the disappearance
Then came forth oblivion.
And then the disappearance of
And then the disappearance of any
Then came forth oblivion.
And then the disappearance of any person
and
and only
and only the
and only the presence
and only the presence of
and only the presence of the
and only the presence of the infinite
essence
essence of
and only the presence of the infinite
essence of all
essence of all that
and only the presence of the infinite
essence of all that is
radiating
radiating forth
radiating forth as
radiating forth as all
radiating forth as all existence
radiating forth as all existence is
radiating forth as all existence is the
source
source and
radiating forth as all existence is the
source and essence
source and essence of
radiating forth as all existence is the
source and essence of all
source and essence of all of
radiating forth as all existence is the
source and essence of all of life.
Beyond
Beyond all
Beyond all time,
Beyond all time, beyond
Beyond all time, beyond all
Beyond all time, beyond all description,
beyond
beyond all
Beyond all time, beyond all description,
beyond all limitation,
beyond all limitation, beyond
Beyond all time, beyond all description,
beyond all limitation, beyond all
intreaty.
So
it
it would
it would seem
it would seem that
salvation
salvation as
it would seem that
salvation as such
salvation as such then
it would seem that
salvation as such then is
salvation as such then is available
even
even at
even at great
even at great depths.
So
So we'll
even at great depths.
So we'll go
So we'll go on
even at great depths.
So we'll go on to
So we'll go on to some
other
other questions.
I
I just
other questions.
I just want
I just want to
other questions.
I just want to say
I just want to say one
other questions.
I just want to say one thing
I just want to say one thing about
spiritual
spiritual practice
spiritual practice so
spiritual practice so I
spiritual practice so I don't
spiritual practice so I don't forget
spiritual practice so I don't forget it.
I
I was
spiritual practice so I don't forget it.
I was say
I was say why
spiritual practice so I don't forget it.
I was say why didn't
I was say why didn't I
spiritual practice so I don't forget it.
I was say why didn't I say
I was say why didn't I say something
about
about spiritual
about spiritual practice
that
that spiritual
about spiritual practice
that spiritual practice
that spiritual practice is
about spiritual practice
that spiritual practice is something
that spiritual practice is something you
do
do as
do as often
do as often and
do as often and as
do as often and as frequently
do as often and as frequently as
possible
and
and the
and the one
and the one that
and the one that I
and the one that I recommend
and the one that I recommend is
and the one that I recommend is not
and the one that I recommend is not is
not
not dissimilar
and the one that I recommend is not is
not dissimilar from
not dissimilar from that
and the one that I recommend is not is
not dissimilar from that recommended
not dissimilar from that recommended by
Ramana
Ramana Maharshi
in
in that
there
there is
there is a
there is a constant
there is a constant letting
there is a constant letting goess
and
and a
there is a constant letting goess
and a constant
and a constant looking
there is a constant letting goess
and a constant looking within
and a constant looking within it's
there is a constant letting goess
and a constant looking within it's It's
a
a matter
a matter of
a matter of focusing.
a matter of focusing. Instead
a matter of focusing. Instead of
focusing
focusing without,
a matter of focusing. Instead of
focusing without, you
focusing without, you focus
a matter of focusing. Instead of
focusing without, you focus within.
What
What is
What is deciding
What is deciding that?
What is deciding that? What
What is deciding that? What is
experiencing
experiencing that?
What is deciding that? What is
experiencing that? If
experiencing that? If there's
What is deciding that? What is
experiencing that? If there's a
experiencing that? If there's a self-
evvaluation
evvaluation going,
evvaluation going, where
evvaluation going, where is
evvaluation going, where is the
self-evaluation
self-evaluation coming
evvaluation going, where is the
self-evaluation coming from?
self-evaluation coming from? In
evvaluation going, where is the
self-evaluation coming from? In other
words,
words, you're
words, you're trying
words, you're trying to
words, you're trying to get
words, you're trying to get to
words, you're trying to get to the
words, you're trying to get to the very
core
core of
words, you're trying to get to the very
core of consciousness
core of consciousness itself.
And
And as
And as one
And as one does
And as one does that,
And as one does that, it
And as one does that, it transforms
everything.
It's
It's like
It's like suddenly
It's like suddenly the
It's like suddenly the black
It's like suddenly the black and
It's like suddenly the black and white
world
world is
It's like suddenly the black and white
world is turned
world is turned on
It's like suddenly the black and white
world is turned on to
world is turned on to technicolor
It's like suddenly the black and white
world is turned on to technicolor and
3D.
3D. You
3D. You see
3D. You see it
3D. You see it as
3D. You see it as you've
3D. You see it as you've never
3D. You see it as you've never realized
it
it before.
3D. You see it as you've never realized
it before. The
it before. The essence
3D. You see it as you've never realized
it before. The essence of
it before. The essence of divinity
shines
shines forth
shines forth as
shines forth as all
shines forth as all of
shines forth as all of existence
and
and it
shines forth as all of existence
and it paralyzes
and it paralyzes you
shines forth as all of existence
and it paralyzes you for
and it paralyzes you for quite
shines forth as all of existence
and it paralyzes you for quite a
and it paralyzes you for quite a long
time.