the willingness to let it all go and go
back up like a cork in the water.
>> Anybody got any other ideas? Why does
some people have to hit such a
incredibly horrible bottom before they
let go? Yes.
>> My thought on that is that
my perception is your body
feel
what what is horrible to me is horrible
to someone else and so I can only deal
with my body I can't deal with I'm not
coming
>> I believe that is so also some people
have the capacity to to experience and
survive suffering of amazing degrees
whereas other people their tolerance is
very very minimal I see patients in the
office over the years you know and their
complaints were I can't imagine why they
would get in a and go and see a doctor
for that. You know what I'm saying?
I feel chilly when it's below zero. I
mean, you know, is that a problem? You
know,
>> my nose runs when I've been on the cold
and I get dandruff. I think, why is this
person seeing a doctor, you know,
>> big deal to them in your reality as
somebody else?
>> That's correct. And each person has
their own threshold. And I suppose you
don't forget don't forget spiritual
training. A lot of spiritual trainings
are very severe. I've been through some
that were, you know, about as far as you
could handle. And it wasn't just EST
either, not going to the bathroom.
Made s seem like a playground. It was
pretty severe. But even, you know, was
the bottom for some people. You remember
those of you who did EST, the fact you
couldn't go to the bathroom when you had
to, you saw people actually laying on
the floor screaming in frenzies and
going into catatonic uh states of uh
shock that they couldn't look at their
watch or
uh not going to the bathroom. That was
the big one. And then
not having any time out for no food.
There's not going to be any lunch. No.
Holy crap. Then there were a bunch of
people on the floor going to, you know,
existential panic. They're going to die
if they didn't eat, etc. So, all
everybody's stuff came up. You know,
like you were saying, there's a great
variety. Some of which to the observer
we would think is ridiculous, but to
them it was really a crisis. I suppose
if you've been beaten up at age 3
months, you're wetting your panties, the
fact you're going to the bathroom is
going to bring up existential terror,
and they're going to go through
something that you won't go through.
All right. So we might say inadvertently
we all create our own bottom.
Inadvertently
we all create our own bottom by either
conscious or unconscious decisions.
And many decisions as you do spiritual
work you become conscious of that you
made them but you' forgotten them or
they're unconscious that you obviously
must. So anything that's going on in
your life, you can presume that was a
choice. Even though you say, "I'd never
never decide that.
I would never decide. I would never
choose so and so." Oh yes, you would
have under the right conditions. I say,
"If you don't choose, I'll blow your
head off." Boy, you just made that
decision in hurry.
right conditions, you make any kind of a
choice, any kind of agreement packed
with
packed PAC with whatever energies may be
tempting you at the moment and later on
in another lifetime you say I never
could have agreed to that. Yes. Mhm.
>> In some cases it seems to me that we
make I know I make unconscious decisions
in the past. Yes.
>> When I was unconscious,
>> right?
>> And and my picture would be that my ego
collaborated with my body in that might
create addictive behaviors that are with
the mind or the body itself.
>> Um so it's collaboration evil in the
body and for the spirit to break through
that you know one first has to be
conscious awake and then you realize
maybe how much ground you lost. So you
know the earlier you can become
conscious you know so I don't know that
you always say I I had to reach this
level
I'm at this level
you know bottom I'm like five inches
from bottom I had no idea
>> it is a very good question because you
do wonder why people say other people
have sort of congenital capacity to
handle greater pain people have a lot
higher higher and lower pain thresholds
which you can test out and some people
have very low pain thresholds.
Um experientially I can tolerate things
that are excruciating beyond probably
95% of the population capacity and
anybody except an idiot would have given
up long before I did. You know
you need it. Uh the other thing is
people are trained uh to handle certain
things. So, if you've been trained to
handle it without flinching, you can
probably stand up there, you know, and
get carved to death and not, you know,
uh, flinch because you've been trained
to do that. All right. So,
we'd say there's been probably some
agreements made to which you are
unaware. So, the best thing would be to
presume that you made that choice and
that you made that agreement. Shall we
see
that would be wise operationally it's
best to presume that that is a choice
and a decision that you made is it
operationally just the fact that you
can't consciously recall it doesn't mean
anything. Anybody's been in
psychoanalysis knows that you made a lot
of decisions that were totally
unconscious and as they go through
psychoanalysis that becomes conscious
and you realized you made that decision
because of the context at the time
because of its meaning at the time.
Uh,
some of these I can't quite make out the
the meaning of the question.
Um,
what would Mother Teresa have said in
Bash's parking lot?
Mother Teresa,
I don't know. I don't speak Hindi.
She probably would have said
and I blessed you my brother.
Uh
>> huh.
>> You understand Mother Teresa? We'll
understand her next month. Next month
we'll be more than mother Teresa because
next
talk is the way to god through devotion
through the heart to you know most of
these lectures we've been approaching it
more like the zen more like um
nonduality
vita or advita whatever you call it
uh I how do you pronounce it
>> adva
like the pickle herring advita
edit pickle tearing, right? Yeah.
All right. So, we've been dissecting the
mind, taking it apart, and uh one of the
reasons we did it in this sequence is
because when the obstacles to love are
removed,
it it's sudden. The way the sudden
enlightenment is you remove all the
obstacles and then you turn up the fire
under the burner and
so everybody be enlightened within 60
days.
We've tried to do it in that way. I
noticed that the course of miracles did
it the same way. I was fascinated by the
course of miracles because before
presenting you with the truth that I am
love and I am spirit and God and I are
one etc. Long before that it first
disassembles the ego. First it takes the
ego out which is going to say this is
nonsense. This wouldn't apply to me. I'm
just a nobody. First it says, you know,
my thoughts don't mean anything. Whoa,
that was a brilliant move. When I saw
that lesson, I said, this is spiritual
genius. This is written by spiritual
genius to see that the sequence should
be to first disassemble the ego before
you present it with spiritual truth.
Religion does it the other way. Presents
you with spiritual truth at a point
where you couldn't possibly grasp that
that's a reality. You got so much guilt,
you couldn't own that for yourself. You
got so much shame you couldn't possibly
do it. You got so much annoyance at God
who's going to punish you later and
you're so scared of him, you hate him.
Religion doesn't have a chance with the
average person. You know, you got to
talk yourself into believing it. And
that's what's called faith
despite all the irrationality of it. You
know, you go with it.
But for a spiritual seeker, then the
correct sequence is to first comprehend
the nature of the ego. How it got to be
that way so that you can own it. You
can't own the ego if you're going to go
into guilt, shame, see it as your enemy,
hate it, fear it, etc. And some
spiritual pathways do that. They set up
the ego as an enemy
uh and reinforce it.
So by familiarity, we we we take the ego
apart, you know, stick by stick like
pickup sticks. We see how it does. This
creates a bifurcation. Then we go back
to the source of the bifurcation.
You surrender that the bifurcation, all
the multiple bifurcations that come off
of that decision now all disappear.
All the algorithms, you know, one choice
creates a duality. Each branch of the
duality now bifrocates until you've got
thousands and thousands of your neurons
all jumping with hate in the bastard.
Then loud and you want to kill him. He's
awful. He's evil. He's terrible. He's
see all that stuff.
The guy doesn't know what he's doing,
does he? He's a mental case, right?
to be brainwashed into the exact
opposite of the spiritual truth, there's
got to be a few nuts and bolts missing.
You understand?
All right. So, if we disassemble the ego
by understanding its structure, so if
you want to take something apart, you
understand how it's put together. If you
understand how it put is put together,
now you can start taking the sticks out
and the structure becomes weaker and
weaker, weaker and weaker. Then you come
in with the fire of the heart. after all
the obstacles have been removed, it
would have already eliminated it or
deterred you from even following the
pathway of devotion.
So the sequence of the lectures we
started with
the basic underpinning of the ego which
is the belief in causality.
We worked our way through how dualistic
thinking arises and how to let go of the
positionality because it only creates a
whole another set of dualities each
branch of which present creates a whole
another set of dualities and you can
pull the pin on the whole bank of it.
See millions of neurons and then you
pull the pin on this one they go silent.
All that chitchat stops.
So that's the reason we've presented
this
in the sequence that it has. So this is
number eight. And I think the way of the
heart is number nine.
And having seen that the obstacles were
all artifacts of mentalization with no
intrinsic reality, we can easily
dispense with them.
In that point, at that point then
spiritual commitment
uh intensity
um what it takes to break the 4-minute
mile now will have a chance to succeed
without all those impediments in their
way.
So first we tried to remove the
obstructions before return of the fire.
That's the reason for the sequence of
the of the lectures.
If you start with you should be loving
God.
If you start with
as many religions do
to love God, the heart of Jesus, the
statues, the whole thing, you feel
compelled
to love on a level which your ego will
not allow you to love at.
If you could love it that degree, you'd
already be there. So it puts, it seems
to me that that is putting a cart in a
horse before you pressure people to
become loving. You have to remove the
obstructions without which they would
automatically become loving because the
presence of God within you expresses
itself as divinity expresses itself as
universal love. So we try to remove the
obstacles
and then lovingness becomes a real
possibility.
Too often it becomes an artificial
self-belief. I hear all kinds of people
tell me how pious they are and how
loving they are. Yeah. Right. Till it
comes to your mother, right?
Till it comes to your mother-in-law,
your ex-wife. Right. The exception start
coming up. So that degree of lovingness
that on which is to uh arrive at is is
obstructed by the ego. So we're trying
to disassemble the ego. All right. So
where is our calibrated levels of
consciousness?
Some spirit keeps whisking them away.
I caught him. There he is.
There you are, sir.
It was me all along. See what I mean?
What's the point of trying to change the
world and look for the chart thief when
he's me?
All right. So, intention. A lot of
spiritual work comes out of the solar
plexus.
It's ambition. Spiritual ambition.
Ambition. So, it's sort of a solar
plexus drive. You see what I'm saying?
It's coming out of the solar plexus. So
a lot of driven kind of spirituality
which some branches of some churches
over time you know displayed to severe
degrees are coming out of the solar
plexus got nothing to do with love. You
see and so you keep you know we we're
going to put you on the rack and keep it
going until you agree to love God.
If the nature of the self with a capital
S within is not different than that
which is love, then to merely remove its
obstacles allows the love to shine
forth. The divinity of the self within
is unmistakable. And as it shines forth,
it begins to radiate much like a much
like the dawn.
As you see, the decision to be loving is
a decision. It's a love. It's not within
the realm of reason. This is logic.
Logic would tell you love that guy. He
should be in jail.
Love him. He's a criminal. I'm saying
reason would tell you
that it's ridiculous to love all these
ways that you're supposed to love. And
then you go to church and you're
supposed to have a loving heart and love
your neighbor as yourself. How can you
love your neighbor as yourself when he's
such a creep?
So you pretend he's not really a creep.
That's a lie. He is a creep.
You run him on the creep index.
He's a creep. Everybody in the
neighborhood thinks he's creep. He is a
creep.
Reason says he is a creep.
I hate him and I feel guilty about
hating him. I feel sad that he I feel
sad that he moved into my neighborhood
and I hate him so much I'm afraid that
he may have retaliatory or homicidal
fantasies towards me which throws me
into paranoia.
However, I'm
out of courage I'm I'm pleased with
myself that I faced up to him and told
him if you don't stop what my calling
I'm going to call the police.
This throws me right back down to
paranoia again. I figure he's going to
You see, reason isn't too much of a help
right here. It keeps throwing us back
and forth into this basket.
All right. So, the willingness to love
no matter what is a count. It's really a
pact you're making with God. It's really
a packact you're making with God.
I choose to be with thy will, oh Lord,
and love unconditionally.
All right? So, this is a choice made by
conscious decision,
not out of logic,
but because you're already evolved
enough
that that contract is now compelling.
Compelling. You realize it's going to
have a big cost. You realize it's going
to make a cost. Anybody who chooses to
be unconditionally loving knows in that
contract
there's going to be a price.
All that which is unloving is going to
come up to be surrendered.
On the other hand, you now get
assistance from dimensions from which
you never got assistance before. Let's
see if that's all.
You have permission to ask this
question. What I just said is so
see contract is not now brought in
powers from other dimensions which you
did not have before.
So when you're trying to become
unconditionally loving from down here in
the ego, you haven't got the power that
it takes to become unconditionally
loving. So you keep falling back into
despair. And you see spiritual histories
throughout time of various saints how
they would go into high state then they
would fall.
Oh my beloved, how could you have
deserted me?
They're in the presence of the bliss of
the presence. And then suddenly it
disappears and they crash into severe
dark knights of the soul.
The dark night of the soul is from
trying to push the envelope. You're
trying to push to unconditional love
when you haven't let go of what is
holding you back from unconditional
love.
Consequently, I tell everybody, "Stop
trying to be loving. Give me a break.
Will you
stop trying to be loving?
You're putting a pressure on me, on you,
on everybody.
Quit trying to be loving. It either
occurs of its own or it does not. In any
force kind of love, it's going to be
artificial. It's going to lack within it
the security system. You see, because
love is going to lead you into dangerous
situations. Without the help of unseen
helpers, you're not going to be able to
handle the seas at that. You understand?
There's no point to force yourself.
Because when the time is ready, it
becomes the way you are automatically.
You walk through the alley, the beetle
is laying on his back. He needs help.
You either squish him.
That was a shock to do that. You squish
him or you say
that's the last time I did it. The idiot
turned back on his back again. I said,
"Jesus, what's the matter with you?" I
put the twig on him again. He went over
on his back again.
I said, "There's some message here I'm
not getting. I'm trying to exert my will
on him and make him choose life. Sure
enough, when I came back in early, he
was dead.
I turned my will to the Beatles will. He
wanted to leave this body and go get
himself a new body cuz the old one's all
worn out. You know what I mean? He
probably went over the other side,
reincarnated another and he's probably
back flying around already. Is he black
flying around already? Let's see.
We have permission to ask this question.
He's back flying around already. By God,
he is. I knew he was going to turn right
around, get reborn in an egg, and be out
there flying again.
See, because you cannot kill life. Life
is not subject to death. That's one of
the most profound things we said in all
these lectures.
Life is not subject to death. Resist.
Life is not subject to death.
Something of its own quality. It takes
something of its own power, its own
quality to kill it. Nothing has the
power to kill life.
You cannot kill anything. You cannot
kill life.
What you can do is block its expression
in this particular form and force it to
choose another form. But you cannot kill
life. Did you ever chop up a bowl of
mercury?
It's illegal nowadays. You're not
allowed to chop up bowls of mercury. But
when I was a kid, you know, dad would
always bring home mercury. And little
kids, you know, you try and pick it up.
And of course, it would instant go like
that and put a knife down it. No matter
what you did, you could not break up
this little pool of mercury. It was just
mysterious and wonderful. Nowadays, it
probably get you arrested. EPA would be
around there ringing your doorbell.
You're getting mercury vapors out into
the world or something. In those days,
there was greater freedom and you could
poison yourself if you wanted, you know.
Or is there something else you don't
have to worry about? Because as we've
demonstrated before
the time of your death is already set.
Let's reaffirm
the time of birth. The exact time of
your death is already karmically set.
Resist.
The style and manner of it is not set.
Correct. The style and the manner of
your death is not set. That you have
many choices. But the timing is already
set.
What can you say about that?
>> It means you're completely and totally
free. And what is set is the time in
karmically set in which you're going to
train change form. You're going to come
out of this form and you're going to go
into a different form where other
choices are awaiting etc. So there's no
point in worrying about what you eat and
how you eat it and what you do at home
because when you're going to leave,
you're going to leave here.
I knew a guy I told you he was his
father was 92 years old and he's
standing on the street corner in
Cottonwood in perfect health. God bless
him. And a cement truck came and smacked
him and mackerel.
He should have kept on drinking the
brandy and smoking cigars and eating the
roast beef. You know what I'm saying?
and his son was saintlike and he said,
"No, I'm not going to sue the cement
company." He said, "That that driver
feels terrible." He was reluctant.
Uh why should I sue him? I thought that
was very evolved
that he accepted it. Um
doing like God's will and he saw the
innocence of the driver. He said the
driver certainly didn't will that the
last the driver said to him until this
morning I think I'll kill an old man on
a street corner. I mean done the other
way
within human error. So our willingness
to forgive others for human error is
part of our own salvation. And as the
son said that to me I got the feeling of
u his spiritual destiny in a way. This
is going to be a saint. I mean he's
almost a saint already.
And you meet saints in your life, you
know, but it's not popular to think of
them as saints, but um there are uh you
can break down on the highway and a
complete stranger will do all kinds of
things for you, run all over, spend
hours in all kinds of trouble. Go get
you a spare tire and drag drag it back
and wake his buddy up and who owns the
tire company and brings it back. This is
all 4 in the morning. You say, "What
could this be?"
Let's see.
We have permission to ask that. That was
an angelic person resist. Yeah. So we
also have angelics.
Who would an angel would do a thing like
that? And I thought, my god, this this
guy is actually an angel in a physical
body.
Some kind of a helper angel. He was
Thank God he was an angel in a in a
physical body.
>> Tell him that
love.
>> You wanted to be killed.
>> Mhm.
>> Didn't I ever tell him that?
Well, people ask these extreme
hypothetical questions, you know, and
after this one, we'll take a quick break
again. What does an enlightened person
do when a rubber is going to blow you
away?
So, I'm going to kill you. What does
enlightened person do? Goes,
bye.
I don't mind being killed. You know, you
shoot out a body and you're in
incredible space. But that loud noise,
man, I just hate that loud noise.
Okay, so let's put our fingers in our
ears and pray for the best and we'll
meet you again after a short break.
People ask some rather specific
questions.
Okay, I need you on this one. We have
permission to do um this resist. We have
permission to do this resist.
Oh, okay.
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
>> Most most of the great teachers
of of recent times
very well known some American mostly
they teach in the high they usually get
in the high 500s. The ideal level for a
teacher would be
um the high 500s it would be the perfect
level.
First of all, lower you don't have
enough power for the power of your words
to go through the ego's resistances.
Beyond 600, you're not very useful. You
you're not used useful in the world.
Beyond 590, you're not very useful in
the world. You can sit there and bless
people as they walk by in a bliss state.
That's about all you can do. And I
recommend that you continue doing that.
If you get blissed out sitting on a
rock, stay there.
I'll tell you what pulls you out of
those high 500 states is love.
Because you have a love relationship
that would be impacted by you sitting on
the rocks out of your love. So that's an
attachment to love.
Love itself. You would it was perfected.
You'd sit on the rock. Okay. So a lot of
the famous teachers, you know, we call
them saints. Um the one who re was
recently canonized
by the Vatican. Um Father Peio.
>> Yeah. Father Peio. I don't speak Latin.
Father Peio.
Anyway, yes. Uh it's probably 580 590.
He very involved. Um very high 500. So
those are the great teachers really are
the high 500. Yananda
um
and the pope is at 570 the Daly Lama's
at 570 to run a huge worldwide church
you can't be much beyond 570 and still
do it see so each one is perfect for
that which he is if you want to be the
great beneficient let's say the current
pope the image he
images is for you people to get together
and share your love and brotherhood and
Christianity with each He's a great
peacemaker.
All right. So to run a great church
should should be in high five 500 570.
Saints are really 570 to 590 595.
Uh so we would expect
saintlike people. Ka yoga I forget. Ka
yoga I think is in the 400s. There's a
word 520 530 540 540. Create yoga is
540. All right.
So let's let's understand what the
calibrations mean. What the calibration
means is
each technique is
for a purpose and appeals to you at a
certain time and therefore it's it's
perfect. To choose a a technique that
calibrates at 800 when you're at 300 is
not going to work.
If you're at 350, I would choose one
about 380 400 or teacher 420 because
you're still getting the basics. It's
important to get the basics and so it's
it's not that 600 is better than it's
not better than it's different then. See
it's different then. Uh so we learn the
basic skills. So your best teacher would
be somebody who appeals to you that you
can bond with who's meaningful to you
uh with whom you feel a certain
compatibility.
Uh so that's the best teacher.
Um
the style that somebody of a much higher
calibration has may not appeal to you at
all. You see so I would choose that
which you feel compatible with. What you
want to know is it integrous. And the
exact calibration doesn't mean anything.
Why? Because you can take a simple
technique, any simple concept or
technique, and if you follow it
relentlessly without one single
emission, never once are you allowed to.
If you follow kindness toward yourself
and all living things, no matter what,
without exception with a fixity of
purpose, that'll take you the whole way.
You understand?
So it isn't so much the calibration of
the teaching as
the degree to which one commits to it.
Easy does it. Live and let live. First
things first. Those are very powerful.
When you put those into operation,
you're going to be at what is the 12step
works? They're 540. Really? What did I
say they were?
>> 540.
>> 540. Yeah. All right. So, even the 12
steps of the 12step programs, if you
follow that relentlessly, you're looking
at 540, which is unconditional love.
Unconditional love is somebody can rip
you off for $20,000 and and
that was yesterday.
What did he do to me today? Nothing.
Unconditional love means no matter what
happens.
But there at 540 you see the
vulnerability for that which is
nonigorous to come into your life. And
so although you have the capacity to
forgive of a headsman, you know, as your
head is there, you're praying for the
guy you shouldn't feel guilty chopping
your head off. That's 540. That's what I
do. That's to chop my head off. I pray
for God.
Okay. So the willingness to forgive the
headsman then is coming from the heart
and it's the fulfillment of the choice
to be loving towards all things no
matter what. You see, it doesn't mean
you got to forgive everybody, but the
headsman you're going to hate or Hitler
you're going to hate. Some you can make
an exception. You cannot make any
exception.
So, it isn't how high the teacher is or
the teaching is, but your commitment to
it. Because what gives it power?
Its power has several sources. One is
your level of commitment to it.
I'm sure in India to turn the prayer
bells relentlessly day after day after
day may seem ridiculous to a western
mind but think of the degree of
commitment
and you have to give money to the church
to do this too you know put your money
in there to crank the bells and the
prayer bells we'd say well that's
ridiculous you know cranking prayer
bells I mean it's got your hear prayer
bells clanking up there in heaven and
give you merit
but think of the amount of dedication to
that then because so anything can be
your way to God. Anything can be your
way to God. Um
so it isn't so the technique tells you
where it fits into an overall
scheme of things but it doesn't tell you
how beneficial it would be to you.
I already told you the truth when you
came in here and none of you got
enlightened that instant did you?
I told you there's nothing happening.
Nobody here and nothing's being said and
there's no mind to hear it or speak it.
I already told you that
that's 1999. That's true. That's fact.
Knowing that it's no help, is it?
Anything makes you feel worse. You know
what I'm saying?
It makes you feel worse.
Uh
how do or could could we live an intense
oh live through intense constant pain of
physicality when we are in the 600s?
Well, you can live through constant
pain. Um physical pain is a thing that
comes up very often and uh
physical pain takes you through all
kinds of learning processes.
Takes you through alternate treatment
methods. It takes you through
acupuncture. It takes you through
hypnosis. It takes you through mantras
and physicalities and prayings and all
kinds of things. And learning how to
disregard it.
Learning how to disregard it.
Um,
see, suffering is one thing. Pain is
another. That's what's really being
asked. There's pain but once you let go
resisting pain I told you how to let go
suffering from pain right remember
>> uh I'll go through once again but
suffering is one thing and pain is
another
when the suffering leaves the pain you
ignore the pain because you're not
suffering from it anymore you understand
suffering means you haven't processed it
out you're resisting it
physical pain one lets go resisting it
stops trying to stop running away from
it trying to avoid it stop trying to
control it if you do that the pain goes
from local to diffuse you can feel like
your whole aura the pain from your
twisted ankle now is everywhere around
you and you keep surrendering to it and
let go resisting to it you can't resist
for even a split second or you feel the
pain again you let go resisting it
continuously within a matter of minutes
it fades out and you get up and walk
away. Nothing to it.
It's just a willingness to do that and
to get through excruciating pain.
You you can't relent for even a split
second or the pain overwhelms you. It
shocks you and almost you almost pass
out from it. So that's what you do. You
let go resisting. So pain is one thing.
Suffering is another. Anybody who's been
in pain and had a narcotic remembers
that they give you a shot of morphine,
the gallbladder, the pain is still
there, but you're not suffering from it
cuz you're in a different space. You are
what you are and the pain is what it is,
but you are not the pain.
So
that's what morphine does for you.
Doesn't eliminate the pain. You say, is
the pain there? Yeah, it's still there.
But you're not suffering from it. So
suffering is one thing. pain is another
um
there's an infinite number of
dimensions. We said that
this really takes us into advanced
theoretical physics and uh quantum
theory to really comprehend. Um at every
instant an infinite number of
potentialities
is you might say becomes
actualizable becomes
actual actual actual I can't say it
at every instant
there is released an infinite number of
potentialities.
Each of those potentialities in turn
release an infinite number of
potentialities which in turn release
releases an infinite number of
potentialities.
There is therefore at all times an
infinite number of dimensions
an infinite number of dimensions.
We have permission to ask that if this
time exists. There is an infinite number
of potent of dimension exist and they
are expanding at an infinite rate.
Resist that is beyond the human
imagination to comprehend.
At every instant an infinite number of
potentialities are releasing an infinite
number of potentialities which each in
turn releases another infinite series of
potentialities.
If I send out 10,000 sparks, each spark
can send out 10,000 more of which each
spark can create 10,000 more. And it
happens at the speed of light.
I see something beyond the speed of
light, but I want to ask about um it
happens beyond the speed of light.
>> Yeah. Because we're only talking this is
within the physical domain. There's an
infinite number of
you see and u theoretical physics
astronomy is discovering there's an
infinite number of galaxies
with an infinite number of planetary
systems and infinite number of galaxies
and the galaxies are expanding f you
know at the speed of light but there are
dimensions beyond the speed of light
which expand and multiply beyond the
speed of Right.
That ought to give those neurons
something to do.
Just to think it has to knock me out of
my chops here.
Yeah. And you hear people thinking
they're greater than God. I think. Yes.
Right. Uh-huh. An infinite number of
dimensions expanding it faster than the
speed of light in an infinite number.
And you're you're you're bigger and more
powerful than that. Okay. been
thanks for that suggestion. But
uh
what can you do if you break into tears
in the presence of beauty?
Uh, get a box of Kleenex is what I
that's that point that you reach in
spiritual evolution
where the innocence, the beauty, and the
holiness of everything knocks you out of
the box. And it's true. It's difficult.
That's why we say a world religious
leader can't really handle it at 580 or
590.
Because at 580 or 590, you're breaking
the tears over everything.
The beauty of the pattern of the rug.
The magnificence of every animal,
every animal that walks by knocks you
out. This morning, I'm looking for kitty
and there's a raccoon just as adorable
as it could be on the edge of the tree.
Whoa. I mean, that raccoon knocked me
out. You know what I'm saying?
He didn't care I was there. He sort of
went into a swoon sort of
just like the deer do when we talk about
the deer. We talked about the deer last
time, didn't we? You see the deer, the
animal gets how much you love it. And
it does not mean you can put your head
in its mouth
cuz it may just love you so much it
could just eat you up, you know. And so
you don't want to attempt it. You don't
want to attempt it and push it love
beyond its capacity.
All right. So the high 500s then are the
realm of the great teachers.
Their intention is
integrous.
Their wish is to
energize the capacity to love in
everyone
to share their insights so that people
can overcome the obstacles to that
lovingness.
And if everybody gets to 540, you've got
no worry. I'll tell you
500 and above, you got no worries with
it. That's right. 500 and over, you got
no worries. uh because that which is
loving gravitates into
as it leaves the body that which is
uh compatible with that lovingness. It
is not attracted to that which is down
there. It is attracted to beauty. You
find in your own life as people get more
evolved, they tend to seek more and more
rural areas, less and less noise, less
and less activity.
Very often life comes to a complete
stop.
The person says I'm not doing anything
in the eyes of the world. And I think
fantastic
cuz that being run by doing this you
know is genulecting at the knee of the
doer within you. The doer is very
useful. The door will take you out of
apathy up through the solar plexus into
rajas into high rajas
and then eventually you go into
tranquility and sattva and at that point
doing this is no longer
a necessity.
Also there's the discovery that there is
no doer doing anything. Doing this is
happening of its own. So you neither
take credit for it nor do you blame
yourself for it.
There is no thinker behind the
thinkingness. The thinkingness is
thinking itself.
The doingness is
the action is activating itself. And you
see that the actions of the body are
like a karmic windup toy. It's all set
to do that. There's no one to take
credit for it
or discredit.
The illusion that there is, you see,
that's the source of the belief in
causality,
that there is a something, a some
person, a who
that is secretly controlling all of
this. This is the old homunculus sitting
in the back of your brain pulling all
the switches.
There is an operations center within the
ego
that integrates an enormously complex
series of functions and I talk about it
I forget I the eye or I I forget which
there is this operations center where
when you look at what the human mind is
asked to do it's no computer could come
anywhere near it
millions of multiple options decided you
um chosen and pathways from instant to
instant all within a feeling is complex
because all decisions, thoughts and
feelings are also filed in the memory
file according to feeling tone.
The complexity is mind-boggling.
Together with unconscious factors,
together with energies within the field
of which you have no knowingness,
together with enormous uh complexity of
programs coming from past karmic
momentum,
no computer could even get near it.
Couldn't could not get near it because
it's not within the realm of logic
because the entire field shifts every
time context shifts in the slightest.
The whole field shifts and nothing that
you're even into is even applicable. The
minute the field shifts a little bit,
it's all nonsensical.
That's the purpose of humor.
Uh never trust anybody who doesn't have
a sense of humor. They're dangerous.
They're killers.
All killers are humorless.
We just stepped on a scorpion in the
back. We were talking about is there
death? There was this big scorpion which
now to me was not integrous because if
you get a scorpion sting on the tail it
can be fatal. You know what I'm saying?
Okay,
that was integrous. Uh, the scorpion is
dead.
This scorpion is dead. Scorpioness is
dead. Is it?
I get what it was. All right. Okay. It
came right out of the lecture, right?
Okay.
All right. So
the decisions that we make uh the
intention behind them is what sets the
karmic energy fuel going.
The same action out of revenge or hatred
uh has a different uh karmic consequence
than let's say
to protect one's integrity. To kill out
of anger, fear, revenge or greed is a
totally different act
than defending one's homeland, let's
say, which you have no no choice. You
have a wife and a family and children.
And the Huns are coming over the horizon
with their sims flashing and u
they always they always kill everybody
they conquer. That was tradition in the
great hordes of history. They always
killed everybody.
You massacred all of them and you took
the loot.
And that's why slavery was an advance in
consciousness because suddenly humans
had a value. Hey, we won't kill them,
we'll sell them.
So whether slavery is one way or slavery
is the other depends on which direction
you look at it.
And as we said in the last lecture, a
slave in in the south of America lived
to be 56 years old. And a slave left in
the wild of Africa where the fellow
tribes would kill you probably lived
about age 28.
So your life was preserved. You got
medical help. You got nutrition. You got
clothing. You got food. You got the
necessities of life instead of being
massacred. You understand?
So you see how everything is shifts
depending on perception. Whether you
shift to the past and look at it towards
the future or project yourself in the
future and look back at the past that's
why to save the world you talk you know
when Ramana Maharashi is saying is that
all you could be working on is your
illusion about your own perceptions
that no such thing exists is an advance
or is it a cruelty depends on how you
look at
To be a slave on a slave ship on a
galley in a state of advanced agony
was what? Horrible.
Yeah, horrible.
And then was taking the great chance
I could leave the body.
I wasn't sure there was a spirit.
I had to let go that which is known. I
am a physicality with the intuitive
suggestion. It was an intuition that one
is a spirit
free as a bird.
So was being chained to a galley a
horrible event or was it a the doorway
to enlightenment? Because that was the
first lifetime of discovery in conscious
memory that one is actually a spirit.
that that which I am rose up out of the
phys physicality.
They had to drag it away.
Sirism, right?
So behind that which you think is um a
thinker, a thinking is a thinker. There
is no thinker there. So you don't have
to worry about the thinker because there
isn't any. You just look at the thinking
itself.
And we try to transcend the blocks to
enlightenment by understanding the
nature of the construction of the ego.
I think we've handled most of these now
and therefore
>> okay I thought we'd finish some other
things I wanted to say. Okay. Is there
more questions before we go on?
>> Yes.
language say I go from here to here.
>> Well, this is something we have
addressed in previous lectures and we
have addressed quite a bit in the books.
A lot of a lot of attention given to in
the books.
How the ego comes into being and how it
gains its structure.
uh
the ego cannot discern the difference
between the an abstract concept and
reality.
That's why an abstract concept is one
thing.
It doesn't have any real concordant
reality. That's really a parallel
confirmation. Doesn't really this does
not flow into this. This flows parallel
to it.
What was the question
>> that in my perception I'm causing this
paper?
>> Oh yes. Yes. Causality. Yes. That
question about has come up before. So we
should go more into causality.
The the the mind thinks in terms of
abstractions
then thinks that if it can be
nominalized
given a word a name therefore it has
existence.
We can call things transformation.
We can we can call them all kinds of
things.
Is such a thing happening in reality?
No, it's happening in my mind.
This is an abstract
conceptualization.
One of the most difficult things about
transcending the mind is
transcending the belief that concepts
um represent
um an an independent reality, some kind
of an objective reality.
If you go out there, no such thing
exists out there. Doesn't exist. You can
look all over the world
and never find causality
because causality exists only as an
abstract concept in your head.
You'll just keep projecting that
abstract concept over and over again
to everything you see. All that means is
you're projecting that thought, that
argument, that
concept onto the world over and over
again.
When I was younger, I always had a hard
time
with homesickness and leaving any place.
And I would mourn it. Even if I lived in
a cardboard box under a bridge that said
Kleenex on it, camp out there for a
couple of weeks, I would mourn it.
I really missed my big Kleenex box. Had
everything arranged in there just the
way I wanted it with the little windows
and cardboard and all, you know.
I had a stone fort as a kid. Then they
came along and moved all the stones.
They're going to make something with it.
I mean,
I always got attached to wherever I
lived.
Home. It was home. Home is where the
heart is. So, my heart would be wherever
I lived.
in the depths of uh not having money,
which is the kind you could call poverty
nowadays, I suppose.
In the depths of not really having any
cash, you could live in some rather
miserable places. And then when you left
them, grieve all over again with
homesickness for a little one and a half
room up on the roof of somebody's house.
That
so it was so painful. It took me a long
time to like it was just like
homesickness. If you ever been homesick,
you know that feeling. So I learned that
that was painful. So if I moved, I would
rent a new place and I would pay the
rent on the old place
so that I could move back there if I
couldn't stand this homesickness. Paid
rent on two places.
If in a couple of months I couldn't
stand it, I could always move back
there. the knowingness that I could move
back if I wanted ease the pain.
This happened over and over again. Every
place I left, I would go through this
pain of loss, heartbreak, like losing a
lover,
uh
you know, it was the homesickness of the
child for instance. So home was a very
very special place.
And one time here I am leaving this huge
estate you know which was really
spectacular really showplace
and as I leave that I realize I'm going
to project that sense of at homeness
onto the next place I go it's in me not
in it.
Each place I lived I projected the sense
of home safety love familiarity.
It came from me.
I'll do it all over again the rest of my
life. If I have to move from where I I
am now, the next place will become
special all over again. Right? Soon as
you move in, you fix it all up and now
it's special.
Got the magic touch of yourself there.
So this the feeling of being at home,
comfort, secure, and all that goes with
homelessness which derives from
childhood got projected onto every place
that you live. You project it there.
It's not there.
If we take a microscope and we take a
whatchamacallit meter and take every
molecule of that home apart, you will
not find feeling at homeness there.
That's from here. You understand?
The same with causality.
Everything you see because you see
sequence in the world, you then your
mind jumps in and projects the concept
causality.
This is causing that. This is causing
that. In reality, what you see is the
sequence of perception
as this, you know, creation unfolds
itself this way.
You understand?
So
there is nothing causing the hand to
unfold.
It has innate within it potentiality.
Then a person says,
"Yes, but isn't there an eye causing it
by intention?"
Today's lecture has to do with how to
transcend duality. That is duality
per se, that there is an eye causing an
it through some magical modality called
causality. And that is the trap of the
mind to believe in the reality of any of
these three factors. First of all,
there's nothing happening out there. Nor
is there causality. Nor is there any
intrinsic independent entity called I to
be causing it. H all things come into
being
by the unfoldment of the potentiality of
creation. And as it is witnessed
sequentially to perception, one one
thinks that this is causing that.
If you take that one point of
observation out of time and space, then
there is no sequence to which you would
be ascribing the magical quality called
causality.
If we back up the movie and you see the
lady running backwards, you say, "What's
causing her to run backwards?" Well,
she's not running backwards.
It's only perception. You see,
you see that the concept happening in
itself is an illusion.
There is nothing happening.
There's nothing happening now.
Something didn't happen a minute ago.
Something is not about to happen now
either.
Why?
All right. You have perception
arbitrarily. I could say we start now
and we end now. That's a happening. Or I
could say no. We'll start now and we'll
keep going there. No, that's a
happening. We could start 9:00 this
morning till 4:00 this this afternoon.
Oh boy, that's a 7-hour happening. Well,
we could start from 9 to 9:01. That was
a happening.
That was happening. Did you catch it? Is
your camera ready? Happening. Happening.
Now that was a happening.
Yokoono used to specialize in
happenings.
a bonfire that would go off with rockets
at midnight on
in these village somewhere. H
she chose to start it there and end it
there. No, I say the happening was when
you set up the bonfire stuff
and the happening continued until after
the police left.
That was a happening.
Now policeman would say it began to
happen after she ran his bonfire. We got
there, caught her hand red-handed.
That's the start of the happening to
him. Then we took him off to jail.
That's the end of the happening. And I
booked her. That's the end of the
happening
to the lawyer. That's only the start of
the happening. She got taken out of
jail. It's a violation of her civil
rights. No, no, it started from there
and it's going on till right now. And I
will defend her in court. She was only
expressing this the first amendment
expressing our freedom to create.
You understand?
We project then this onto the world and
say it's out there whereas it's in here.
Understand?
There is no happening anywhere.
There is no I person causing the
happening.
There is no causality to account for it.
This arm has the potentiality
to do that.
Let's say if I choose a pattern off of
an infinite number of patterns. If I
choose this pattern, this automatically
does this. If I choose this pattern, the
omega does this. If I choose this
pattern, it does this.
A great moment in my life.
So by choice we release certain
potentialities by choice.
But you see within the seed is the whole
program
of it defining its potentiality in terms
of nonlinear potentiality.
See, causality is looking within the
Newtonian linear domain which always
sees a happening with a beginning, a
cause and an end, a consequence, etc.
That's a very limited paradigm of
reality.
It won't take you to the dimensions that
you go to because the minute you get
beyond logic, the 400s, these things are
not even valid questions anymore. Once
you get to the 500s and you're talking
about love, you're talking about
quality. Now it's not measurable.
Doesn't start here and end there. Can't
package it. There's any love meter.
It's beyond definition
by logic.
The person says, "Yes, but I want love
to fit into the comfortable box of
thinkingness and logic."
And so we make feudal attempts. Poetry
probably gets the closest. How do I love
thee? Let me count the ways.
As a kid, I thought, boy, boys don't
like poetry.
How do I love the Let me count the ways.
Give me a break. You know,
8-year-old boy just loathe that kind of
stuff, you know.
So, that which is seen as beautiful and
lovingness is the turnoff. Every
8-year-old says, "Waffle shit." Now,
women and girls like that crap. You know
what I'm saying?
See, so it doesn't even have any
reality. See, it doesn't have any
reality. Or he'd be forced to accept
that it's beautiful and loving. No, he
has choice. All right? So the minute we
get beyond the confines of logic, which
is based on definition.
We're in a different domain. So what
we're doing here is stretching
epistemology. Another one of the ways to
God is to follow epistemology to its
final
ferocious end. And you crash through
from epistemology. How do we know? And
how do we know that we know?
You make a concept called causality. How
do you know that you know what causality
even is? It's just a word. It's just a
tautology. Well, cause is anything you
want to call it, isn't it? It's just t a
u t
the string is taught now
cause is anything you want to call it.
You can say love is the cause of these
people behaving this way. Not the cause.
It's the field.
It's in that field that you're making
certain choices
that are really answerable in a way to
the field of love because that now is
the context of truth and value. Outside
of love, the world of business, we were
talking about it during the break.
Business doesn't give a diddly about
love.
You're not even allowed to engage in
love during lunch breaks,
much less on the premises, please.
Touchyfey
is not, you know, cool in the business
world. Being cool and logical is cool in
the business world.
All right? So, the minute you get out of
the dimension, then we need our scale of
consciousness again. The minute we get
out of the 400s, then
causality becomes less and less
meaningful.
What does it mean up here? It doesn't
mean anything in the field of love and
joy and peace.
It doesn't even come up as a credible
possibility.
Nothing is causing you to feel peace
in this room. There's absolute silence.
Behind all the noise
there's absolute silence. Remove the
noise and then linger with silence.
Correct?
Nothing is causing the silence.
Nothing is causing your existence.
Everything is by free choice.
Out of the unmanifest comes the
manifest.
Out of that all things are created
with the one single essential quality of
existence.
Within that existence
combined with form you have an infinite
series of potentialities.
Nothing is causing it to happen.
So if we put a seedling, a rose seedling
in the sun and give it water and
fertilizer, the sun and the water and
the fertilizer do not cause it to grow.
The
seed does not cause it to grow. Doesn't
cause it. Cause you see is really within
the world of force. The world of power
here is different. From 200 down, we
have the world of force in which one
thing forces something else.
That's not cause. That's force.
Cause you'd have to be divine. Huh?
These things are manifesting.
The choice of that as a potentiality
built within the human is the capacity
to begin to vibrate at the energy of the
kitty's purr, the doggy's wagging tail.
And those are often the first things we
love. That's why we give children pets
and the toys and the fuzzy warm things
because they begin to grasp their
capacity to lovingness. And then they
get attached to that which are they're
loving and they grieve and go into loss.
And then they learn that they can
recreate the same feeling about the next
toy. And then they've transcended the
attachment to love.
The attachment to love which also
becomes a block. And we'll talk about
that more or less next time.
I just want you to see that causality is
an illusion,
a powerful illusion. It's the whole it's
the whole basis of the ego. That's why
it's so powerful and why it takes a lot
of prayer and
inner spiritual work to transcend it.
All of a sudden you see that everything
is happening of its own. Nothing is
causing anything to happen. The world of
phenomena, the universe of creation is
like a giant electromagnetic field. All
things within it have a certain charge,
a certain energy, a certain polarity.
like little iron fail filings with a
north pole and a south pole and a
certain spin and a certain degree of
magn magnetic energy composed of various
elements
and where it is in the space with
billions and billions of others
automatically allows it to move within
the realm of possibilities like the
aurora borealis you see the aurora
borealis is nobody's causing it to do
what it's
The poles of the earth send out that
electromagnetic. And you see everybody's
here seen the Aurora Borealis.
You see how they are they dance the
pattern dances itself spontaneously
as an interaction between that which it
is and the universe in which it is
located. Nothing is causing anything to
happen.
H we spend some time on causality
because it is so intrinsic to the
structure of the ego.
To merely begin to question causality as
some kind of an intrinsic reality
already weakens its power and holding
the ego together.
It already it's already weakened just by
questioning
its authenticity. It has no objective
substantial substantial reality of its
own. The only reality that can be
confirmed is a subjective state called
I. The presence of God within oneself.
The self with a capital S which
illuminates itself into your awareness
as the feeling is that there there is an
I and that I exist.
That's the only reality you actually
know.
Beyond that is all imagination
other than that you exist.
There is no confirmable knowledge that
you can possibly hold.
Everything else then is a hypothetical
possibility. Everything piece of data
the mind holds is a hypothetical
abstraction.
The only verification of reality then is
the state of subjectivity.
The only radically objective truth then
is subjectivity itself.
Without the subjective, no objective
could be said to exist. Because what
would say that it exists?
Only the subjective sense of self says
an objective reality is out there.
All conclusions, all mentations and are
distilled down to a radical sense of
subjectivity
which is the only reality
that can exist.
The presence of God within
shines forth as
self that which I am
and that's the only thing you know is
that you exist.
All the rest is software put on top of
your hardware
other than the fact that you exist.
Nothing else is really knowable.
And all the great imaginations that all
the great eagles through all time have
arrived at calibrate the great books of
the western world, all the greatest
thinkers of all time which I have in a
library at home. Is it the greatest
thinkers of all time lined up from
ancient Greece? The last one on the
series I think is called Freud
and they calibrated 475.
The greatest thinkingness
in the history of the world calibrates
at 475.
The greatest geniuses that have ever
lived, Einstein and Newton, are 499.
You're looking for a reality that's in
the 500s and up.
So I was saying don't look over here
because the world of reason and logic is
not where you're going to find what
you're looking for. Only the power of
love can transport you and in the
nonlinear domain it's obvious what's
obvious. No proof is necessary. It would
be extraneous.
It would have no validity. H
the nearest thing you can get to it from
the world of logic is quantum mechanics
and the infinite quantum potentiality
where you realize that consciousness
alone just by observing something
totally changes its physical expression
is the closest we can get to where logic
and the linear and the nonlinear domain
domains meet. That's as far as reason
and logic can go is quantum mechanics.
And that is the end of that box. And
then you have to try jump to a different
paradigm. So you realize that each of
these is a different paradigm of
reality. What's real in this paradigm is
not real in this paradigm. The people in
this paradigm laugh at this paradigm.
You gave all that up for love. You must
be nuts.
All that money, all that position, all
that property. Huh? Boy, for love. Huh?
For love of God. That's even more
outrageous. Gave it up for love of God.
All right. So, reason and logic can only
take us so far. It cannot really undo
causality. Causality, we said to
transcend it is at about 998 or
something like that.
You almost have to be completely and
fully enlightened to see beyond it. But
to begin to doubt it already what we're
trying to do is lessen its hold on your
ego as you begin to question it. The ego
weakens and the next session is devoted
to the way of the heart. And by that
time the ego is already somewhat
rickety. If you stayed awake through any
of these lectures
it's become ricketetized and
should fall with just a few kisses.
I love you old ego. Good old eagle got
me through kindergarten and all
everywhere, you know. Oh, you said
goodbye to poor eagle.
I said goodbye to the body a lot of
times. That was sad. Would saying
goodbye to the mind. Oh,
do I have to do that? Ah,
it would be sad if it was real and had a
reality and it was a loss, but it's not
a reality and it's not a loss. It's a
gain. So everything you let go of as far
as facious belief system is a is a
freeing a freeing a freedom.
All right. So the way to
the higher spiritual states is a way of
progressive freedom. Progressive
freedom. You see that the belief in
causality is like a chain holding you
down. Holding you down. You're
imprisoned by a belief system. So, we're
trying to weaken these belief systems
and allow the butterfly within you to
fly out.
And as an 8-year-old boy, I think that's
a disgusting analogy.
Butterflies, why do I want to be a
butterfly?
All right, so I think that will conclude
the answers and questions for this
afternoon.
And I thank you all for being here. It's
a great joy. A great honor.
All right.
What you say? Oh, yeah.
I forgot what it was before.
>> Hey,
>> it was Wow, this is a very advanced
group.
We have permission. Is this over? 445,
446, 447, 448, 449, 450, 451, 452, 452,
445 to 452. Seven point.
>> Oh, wow.
That's an enormous jump. You're talking,
you see, we're talking about a
logarithm.
>> 470. What do we say?
>> All right. So that's So when we started
it was 10 * 10 * 10 455 times.
Now it's 10 * 10 * 10
452.
Yeah. Right. So now it's 10 * 10 452.
You'd have to see 452 10 all across the
board and multiply them all against each
other and that's how much we jump. So we
jumped seven times that 7 * 10 10 to the
7th power. So anyway the
the field supports that advancement of
consciousness. The field supports it.
And of course what makes the field
possible is your intention. You know,
there's an enormous amount of spiritual
power in this room and you put it all
together and the buoyancy is enough to
take us all the way.
Here we come.
So, okay. Thank you very much again.
Hallelujah.