Because you're all intellectual enough
in this audience at 4:30 to intellect
instantly sees it. Positionality is a
falsehood. The difference between hot
and cold as you can see is an art
artificial positionality.
So your intellect sees it. But no, the
problem's going to be emotional that you
get grim satisfaction out of everything.
Grim satisfaction
out of martyrdom, out of being wronged.
The more horribly you're wronged, let me
tell you, the bigger the juice,
the more horrible the crime committed
against you, the more stuck you are in
your ego now
because the payoff is big.
The payoff gets bigger and bigger. And
as you evolve spiritually, the tempter
is going to come to you. And the way the
tempter comes to you
is offering an enormous gratification of
a justified position
at a certain consciousness level. The
tempter comes to you. You might say that
which we call quote the tempter and the
quote is present at all times and you're
really constantly under the you're
constantly under the test of the tempter
if you want to call it that. What's the
source of the tempter? The source of the
tempter then is the pleasure one derives
out of one's ego positionalities.
It isn't power over others. It's the
gratification you get out of power over
others.
What the hell do these idiots who
slaughter millions get out of it? They
don't even get to see it, right?
Hey, there's millions of people being
slaughtered and chopped up out there and
and you don't even get to see it. You're
locked up in your office here.
Look what you're missing. Get out there
and slash around in the blood and step
over the bodies. I mean, you're missing
the grim satanic satisfaction.
No, the satisfaction he's getting out of
it is luciferic, not satanic.
Satanic is the expression. But what he's
coming out of is power over others.
Capacity to be God over others. That's
Melissa. Look at his Look at him on TV.
Huh?
The pridefulness of that positionality
is what he's unwilling to relinquish to
God.
Yeah. And that's how you choose the
lower astral
positionality.
All right? So you'll you'll catch the
ego red-handed.
You'll see that it gets a grim. You'll
say, "Oh, I can't possibly be enjoying
this suffering." No, you're not enjoying
the suffering. You're enjoying the juice
you're getting out of the suffering. Get
what I'm saying by juice? The ego feeds
off the juice that it gets out of
what otherwise at least to the intellect
is described as negative.
No sooner
is the town demolished by the flowing
lava than they're rebuilding a new one
exactly in the same place. Is that
right?
No. No sooner does the house slide down
the side of the mountain into the
Pacific Ocean, then they're building a
new one. Exactly the same place. No
sooner do the rivers
flow over the banks in the Midwest and
sweep millions of houses away, they're
instantly building houses as soon as the
mud dries. The ego's
attraction and addiction is to the juice
it gets out of suffering and being
mistreated.
That's the juice
of the far-left political liberal
correct politically correct position is
you can get juice out of any social
reality
by recontextual re recontextualing it.
Why? Because the egotism involved
brings you to a position called
entitlement.
Once you're entitled, everything is an
offense.
Everything is an offense.
Everything is a possible lawsuit.
Everything is publicity
because entitlement then is the
grandiosity of the ego of the infant.
So egoomania is nothing but the
grandiosity of the unbridled infant of
the ego
expecting the world to acknowledge it.
The king baby inside expects the world
to cater to its egocentric position.
Well, the ego the world never heard of
you. And after you've left, it's not
going to miss you. And the idea that
it's going to cater to you while you're
here is about a three-month-old
positionality.
But the juice is derived out of the
indignities and injustices of this
world. It thrives on
all the people that are rude to you.
No sooner did they catch this crazy
butcher of 30 people who chops them up.
And I wouldn't even tell you it's
unspeakable what he did to the remnants
of their bodies.
No sooner does this happen than some
poppyccock jumps up on TV. He's worried
about the civil rights of the sufferer.
Right.
Why? Because he he can milk injustice
out of this. You can see the position of
the winner is always the bad guy. Like
the capitalist is always the bad guy,
right?
Who says that? A guy wearing clothes.
Yes. Where did you get your clothes?
Well, it was manufactured by some
company. Where did the company get his
money? got it from capital, didn't it?
You're walking on a sidewalk. Who made
that sidewalk? Some company made the
sidewalk. You sit in a car. Who made
your car? You open your bottle of milk
in the morning. Where'd you get the
milk? You got it from some company.
Where'd you get the money to buy all
these things that that the people you
hate provided for you? Well, you got it
from the people who hate you hate
because they provided the jobs, right?
So, you see how positionality makes
everything wrong. You know, you can make
the goo goose who lays the golden egg
the bad guy. So, positionality swinging
back and forth and creates the political
spectrum which keeps us entertained.
Everybody,
all the guys in the restaurant in the
morning look forward to opening the
editorial page. You know, they're all
set to go. You know what's today's
outrageous calamity that you can really
discuss with the other guys and how
stupid the government is and all. So we
love when you're honest about it. You
see that you love your ego. You love the
juice you get out of your ego.
See once you admit that truth you've
taken the cover off of it. You love the
ego.
It's your source of juice. It's a source
of all the injustices, the calamities,
the pains, the hatreds.
Where would you be without it?
You'd be stuck with the reality of the
self,
which doesn't buy that crap. Doesn't buy
it at all.
Give me a break. That's that's what God
says when you say, "What you got to say
today, God? Give me a break.
Give me a break. Get enough from all
this human juice.
Take away the TV set." I looked at it
and you're going to have it back. I gave
God a TV set and he said, "I don't want
to look at anymore. It's horrible."
Why? Because it's full of all this juice
that we get out of it. The movies juice
you to death. You know if you if you
calibrate a lot of uh commercials, TV
commercials and a lot of movies, you
know, your mind will go weak about 14
times a minute.
Why? Because we love the fear. We love
the indignation. We love the shock.
So the way to undo the ego then is
radical honesty.
The way of adida is radical truth.
The willingness to let go illusions
including the illusions about illusions.
The source of the ego then is the juice
that we continuously get out of it which
pumps it up. Pumps it up. Pumps it up.
Gives it life. The willingness to
relinquish that. That's what you have to
surrender to God. Not the positionality.
Because the minute you let go, the
secondary gain you're getting out of
that position, the ego, the
positionality will disappear of itself.
You'll laugh at it.
It will let go of itself. So the thing
the thing to search for is what kind of
satisfaction do I get out of that? I get
the satisfaction of being wronged.
Wronged is wonderful, isn't it? Whole
countries go to war and they're wrong.
They're they're writing the wrong of
Versailles. What wrong of Versailles?
The Kaiser did the same thing Hitler did
and lost. Now Hitler says, "Well, that
was an injustice." What injustice?
Nobody asked the Kaiser to invade Europe
and kill people, did they? No. All
right. So, it feeds off that injustice.
The whole German people
40 million people died in World War II.
I was in World War II and it's more of a
reality to me than many younger people.
It was a reality in which 70 million
people died
out of the juice out of the juice of
being wrong. That was the juice of the
National Socialist Party, wasn't it?
It was going to write the wrong of
Versailles and that justified everything
they did
just as bin Laden tries to juice.
It's justified for the have nots to to
hate the hat the halves. That's the
politicalization of it. Vinl is not a
have not. He's a multi-millionaire
which tends to diminish one's credence
and that positionality.
All right. The pleasure that one gets
out of the juice of the ego justifies
everything. It justifies mass murder,
genocide,
if allowed to. The final killer bomb, if
they lost the war, the final killer bomb
was big enough to to eliminate all of
mankind.
All of mankind was going to be
eliminated by the final killer bomb if
Russia lost a nuclear war with the
United States. Luckily, there were
enough Russians to stop them before it
became a reality. But the megalomania
behind it, as you see, is unstoppable.
The difficulty with the reasonable ego
of the western world is it presumes that
other people are going to operate with
the law lawful confines and
reasonableness of the ego. Other people
are not other people totally disregard.
People say, "Well, he wouldn't do that.
It would cost them all his countrymen."
Oh, of course he'd do that. The fact
that he cost them all his countrymen
is cool man.
Kill them all.
So
the weakness of our position as you see
it in the world is the presumption by
the naive that other people are going to
be ruled by reason.
People in this room are the ones who are
most vulnerable to that. The 400s is the
level of reason. We say, "Well, nobody
do that. That's irrational." Why?
There's lots of people in the world that
think that rationality is stupid.
If you want something, you take it, man.
What's the problem?
There's whole cultures. And you know how
that culture thinks?
Well, she left her purse there, so she
deserves it. I treat them all week long.
Monday, Wednesday, Friday, morning.
Well, she deserves She left her purse
there. Of course, I stole it. What do
you expect? I mean, you're talking about
a different reality, right? Different
rules apply.
If I can get away with it, they deserved
it. Is a justification.
We in the 400s, you don't buy that. But
down in the lower part of the world,
that's justified.
They they deserve to die because they're
killable.
Whoa. You realize what that means when
people come from that space?
Because they're killable. That's why
they deserve to die.
The dinosaur doesn't need justification
to eat the smaller animals. He kills it
cuz it's chewable. I guess
all right. So now you you understand a
little bit more about the ego. You don't
have to be afraid of it. You have to be
honest that it's there.
and that it owes its survival to to the
payoff it gets out of its positions.
The payoff, the way to get rid of it is
first be honest about it and admit it.
Yeah, I enjoy
whatever.
Now, am I willing to let that enjoyment
go for some higher purpose?
Well, you can only take the word of
people who have done so whether the
sacrifice is worth it because it does
seem to the ego to sacrifice all of that
glory and fame and justification and
revenge and all is a big sacrifice.
Don't kid yourself to the ego. It is a
big sacrifice.
It is a big sacrifice
to let go being right to let go
not nurturing that wrong to let go of
that hatred.
It is a big sacrifice. Don't pretend
it's a small sacrifice. There's a lot of
pseudo non-genuine spiritual work that
people attempt and it doesn't work. Why?
Because they're unwilling to face the
nitty-gritty the nitty-gritty facts.
Radical truth means you got to take the
mask off everything and be willing to
see it for what it is and now handle it
from the viewpoint of emotional honesty.
There is a big massive payoff
and ego positions or you wouldn't be
sitting here in a body today.
You would have karmically gone off into
the midst of the higher realms.
And therefore the fact that one is back
here in a body again means that one has
uh
sold out spiritual truth for the
gratifications of the ego over and over
again. But in this lifetime it's coming
up to be questioned.
In this lifetime you say was it worth
it?
Is the pres the experience of the
presence of God worth sacrificing all
that I get out of my ego? The answer can
only be accept only be gotten by faith.
Actually
experientially no. Experientially you
got nothing upon which to to say that
giving it up would be a better deal.
Anything in your experience telling you
that giving up the pleasure,
resentments, and hatreds and
satisfactions of winning
is worth it?
Not experientially. No.
Faith. Yes. Fa based on faith. based on
this on the teaching of some
entity who's gone through the whole trip
and tells you that the end result
experience of God is so incredible
beyond all description. So, so beyond
the totality of
all the values of all of mankind
throughout of all history,
all the pleasures and all the values and
all the acquisitions emotionally and
materially of all of mankind throughout
all history
are like a speck compared to the
presence of God. Nothing is even in the
same domain. Therefore, you're asked to
sacrifice that with which you're
familiar
in the hopes of entering a different
domain
and in that domain you have only have
the traveler who's been there. Marco
Polo tells you what the Chinese are like
but you have to take his word for it.
So where the we have the inspiration
then of the spiritual teacher. The value
of the guru is primarily one of
commitment to absolute truth out of
which comes an integrity which is so
profound and convincing
that one buys that integrity.
You see truth cannot be argued. It
cannot be defended and it has no answers
for any argument.
Its authority is absolute.
It is the absoluteness of the presence
that defies any question and against
which any question falls flat because
there is no room for question. That
which is all that is is beyond all
questioning.
To let go and surrender the known for
the unknown.
We call it the Institute for Advanced
Spiritual Research.
Every spiritual aspirant is a
researcher. You have no idea what you're
really going to experience when you let
a certain thing go. You only find it by
doing it. You only find it by doing it.
Just like the explorer,
you can go by the compass, but you don't
really know till you get there that
that's an absolute fact. So each one of
us evolves based on faith. The faith of
the conviction of the integrity of
whatever spiritual teacher or church or
spiritual tradition,
whatever guru, whatever
one's inner direction leads one to that
which
you're able to hang on to with absolute
certainty.
When I was an atheist, I already got the
absolute certainty of the truth of the
Buddha.
I was an atheist at the time and I knew
that what he said was absolutely so.
So the intuitive knowingness was there
many years prior to the validation
experientially.
All right.
That leads us up to the next uh topic
which we'll discuss after lunch because
it's a heavy one and I don't want you to
be hungry when we talk about it.
We want to explore what part does karma
play in all this. Huh? Because
the ego, the mechanisms of the ego, the
positionalities,
what we calibrate as of today as a group
and the kind of things we talk about and
are valid to us today
to avoid the whole subject of karma is
again the fallacy of many religious
positions who say I don't believe in
karma. I don't want anybody to believe
in karma at all. I don't want anybody to
believe in karma. I don't believe in
karma.
Karma is what you are.
You ask, "How do you let go of the ego?"
Well, the ego is the accumulated karma
of all of life, through all of time,
through all of history as it presents
itself now and the reality of that which
you are at this moment.
He says, "I don't believe in karma." And
they tell you then in that case you
don't exist because you got two ears,
two eyes and a nose and a mouth. That
ain't karmic. What is it? I mean you
didn't come up with four ears and three
eyes and two mouths, you know.
So obviously
at this moment then represents the
accumulated energies and effects in form
throughout all of time. You can't
pretend that somehow the evolution of
consciousness throughout all time
throughout all forms of life has somehow
bypassed you and you have magically
escaped karma. No way.
That's a spiritual pride to think that
one is not subject to the laws of the
universe.
One time and then we'll have lunch. one
time in a very advanced state. It was a
very very advanced state came the down
the potential downfall of the guru. A
lot of gurus fall down
at the pass was over 800 820 840 860 850
around 850. All right. So uh
it's another shocking fact you see to be
a radical realist takes a lot of uh
guts. Takes a lot of guts and it takes a
lot of heart.
Um, you got to face radical facts about
things you don't want to face. Many
well-known gurus, if you calibrate their
writings, they're pretty pretty good.
And if you calibrate where they were at
at the height of their spiritual
evolution, you get a very good number.
And if you ask where they are at now,
you may get a very low number. Shock.
Because at each point along the way,
it's like a test comes up that says,
"Oh, yeah.
And um
the students I teach, I want them
prepared for that. First of all, don't
pretend it's not going to happen because
it's going to happen. When you say, "I'm
never going to so and so again," the
next question that comes up in the
universe is, "Oh, yeah.
Oh, yeah. Uh-huh. Yeah, sure." Uh
anyway, this this was a very advanced
state and um it was a state of absolute
purity and
uh
profound state of the presence
as clarity, peace and
non-positionality.
Anyway, in this state
which was nonverbal because thought had
stopped years before that came a
knowingness presented itself. The
knowingness was
now that you have transcended karma, you
know, are no longer answerable to some
otherness call God.
And you realize there is no otherness to
which you are answerable for.
And because you realize you're beyond
all human karma,
you're not answerable in human terms.
All power resides in you. Own it. That
was the temptation.
The ultimate lucatur
power for its own sake.
And the rationale was correct up to a
certain level.
When you truly transcend the ego, you're
not subject to human karma and normal
human karmic terms.
Nor is there some angry god that you're
going to face who's going to get even
with you for being bad and beat you up
and throw you into hell. All that's
So anyway, you've transcended
all that. Now knowing all that, how
about this baby? You are the power.
There comes the luciferic temptation.
And you could see who had said yes and
who had said no.
It was strange. Not all that many been
through. And you could see who said yes
and who said no.
Uh power for its own sake. You say to
yourself, why would that which is called
we call evil by the world's terms, why
would it choose to be that way? It does
it for the payoff
for the sake of power itself. Not
because the power gets you something but
for its own sake.
Just as people were murdered, not for
some motive, looking for psychological
reasons why the thrill killer kills is
really absurd. Got beat up in his
childhood. Yeah, right. Everybody got
beat up in his childhood.
Now he does it for the sake of it
itself. He murdered for the sake of the
thrill of murdering. All right. So the
payoff, the way we surrender the ego
then is we're radically honest. We're
radically honest. We see the payoff we
get out of it. We're radically honest
about whether we're actually willing to
give up that payoff for something
promised but not yet experienced
is that takes faith.
All right. So that sort of answers
some of the questions that that came up
and we will talk more about karma
because there are questions there about
it. What is it really? Uh how far does
it go?
You see the error that was made by that
luciferic energy at that level was it's
true you're beyond
the karma of the ego
but you are not beyond the karma of the
reality of the universe.
You're not beyond the reality of the
karma of God of the reality of the
universe which is far beyond the human
and includes you in it brother.
So if I know what to say to that entity
at the time or what to turn on her and
say and that includes you brother unless
you're greater than the infinite reality
of the infinite creator of universes of
universes out of which your little
silliness arose.
Anyway,
so those are the some things that happen
to you and it's pertinent to karma and
uh we'll talk more about karma later.
Chocolate covered karma
>> speak.
>> Yeah. How do you not revert?
>> Revert
>> and become a reverter.
>> We don't allow reverters in this
audience here.
Well, many things are let go of in
degrees. You see
>> degrees and you have the accumulated
pressure many lifetimes behind many
things. So it's more than just a passing
thought. Sometimes it takes very intense
intention and devotion and um and the
miraculous uh to let it go.
And that's why prayer inter the request
for intercession is traditional to ask
God for help to let let go my addiction
to the pleasure I'm getting out of such
and such a things. E so we ask for
divine help that is uh the pathway of
devotion. Huh? So today we're talking
about
to start with the pathway of mind but we
as the day goes on laps more into the
pathway of devotion. I leave devotion
till late in the afternoon.
You start with devotion, that's the end
of the end of the project. So
because the energy of it comes up and it
wipes out everything. So
u it was severe for I had trouble with
it for a long time. I'd sit in an
airport and one couple would look at
each other uh you know look of a glance
of love and it would just wipe me out
and tears would come up and I just shot
the bliss state you know you get to be
mother so and so you just sit there in a
state of bliss and you can't really say
anything and you just bust people wish
them well because
verbalization is not possible in that
divine state of bliss
To understand spiritual work, it's it's
necessary to know something about karma
and
what is the truth of karma? What does it
really mean?
First of all, it's somewhat stigmatized
amongst Christian circles and others as
being of eastern origin and therefore
foreign and all this and that.
uh karma as a specific religious concept
of course is defined in the dictionary
in a very specific way.
Karma in my understanding is more the
essence of karma
in that all that is the entire universe
in fact all the universes of universes
is one karmic
totality
one karmic symphony
in other words all that ever existed all
that ever
is in thought word or deed
in both the linear and the nonlinear
domains
are part of a total oneness.
To be beyond karma would mean the you
that somehow you've escaped the oneness
of the totality of God and all the
universes which is not likely.
The universe is one
karmic um
unity
in perfect and total balance in every
detail.
All that is is obviously part of the
evolution of all that was at the point
of observation becoming
the fulfillment of its
innate propensity
which was created as part of creation.
Everything is perfect because at every
point it is fulfilling its potentiality
as it is possible for that potentiality
to unfold under the conditions that we
call the present and the next instant it
will again be perfect. So all is perfect
at every instant.
The only way to make it not perfect is
to
contextualize it
in the hypothetical.
But because the hypothetical has no
reality, it does not invalidate the
truth of what was just said. The
hypothetical does not exist.
M
so because the universe is one karmic
unity
and
a continuous state of perfection of the
unfolding of its potentiality.
Nothing can escape karma and still be
part of the universe. So if anything was
beyond karma, you wouldn't know about
it.
So there's no point to worry about it
because you wouldn't you wouldn't exist.
Neither would you.
You cannot be anything this instant
unless you were something the last
instant. Right? Okay.
How does it operate really spiritually
speaking? First of all, the confusion
has to do with um confusing karma with
reincarnation. The reason it's rejected
by Christian uh belief systems is
because of two things. that Jesus Christ
did not talk about it
and specifically
it's referring to embodiment. Embodiment
generally karma is understood by the
common layman as
uh if you're not good you'll become back
as a toad or you were a very good toad
and now you're not a toad anymore.
So it's confused with incarnation.
Karma and incarnation are two different
things.
Reincarnation can be a karmic
potentiality or it may not.
Karma is merely stating that that which
is continuous is continuous and part of
an ongoing oneness.
What it really what it's really saying
spiritually is that
The decisions of the spiritual will
which is really what determines karma
karma in the true meaning of the sense.
The decisions of the spiritual will then
have consequences. Consequences.
These consequences are agreed upon by
all religions. Those who claim they
don't believe in karma, of course they
believe in karma.
Otherwise, why would you avoid sin?
Because after you die, karmically,
you're going to go to other places. So,
they all believe in karma, but they
don't believe in reincarnation. That's
two different things. Karma means that
the consequences of actions
will have an effect in the future. And
of course, Christ taught that you reap
as you sow, etc. So he taught karma but
he did not get into the whole problem of
embodiment.
Karmically embodiment is a very
complicated and tricky question. It may
or may not occur and it may or not be an
option and it may or may not be uh said
yes to. The other thing that people
don't understand about karma is that
there's an infinite
an infinite
number of universes. There's an infinite
number of domains and within an infinite
number of domains there's an infinite
potentiality of inf infinite universes
and these multiply at at an infinite
rate.
Now once you wrap yourself around that
one,
I want to ask a question that's been
bugging me. May I ask this question? I
may ask this question.
Jesus Christ never had any previous
physical incarnations.
I may ask that.
That is a fact. It's just the Buddha
did. Just that's what I thought. I was
driving along the other day and I
thought one reason Jesus Christ didn't
talk about previous embodiment is
because they never had any.
The Buddha however did
and they at about level 600 you recall
them. Not that they're a different
lifetime but it's just like a memory
like you remember
what your teacher said in 8th grade.
So Jesus Christ first of all came
directly from heaven. See, never
incarnated as a physicality, as a human
physicality. Jesus Christ never
incarnated as a physicality before
resist.
Huh. I didn't know that. Well, that's
one thing I like about kinesiology.
You ask these questions and after you've
asked thousands of them, it weaves a
fabric of understanding
that um
is greater in depth and dimension and
and subtly than can be usually
described.
I always thought until this moment that
Jesus Christ didn't go into the subject
of karma specifically past life karma
is because
the ego as it is today is the karma.
Your karma is today's ego. Today's ego
is the compilation of all that's
occurred in the evolution of this
consciousness up to this moment.
Just like a tomato is
this tomato sitting here represents the
evolution of tomatoeness throughout all
of time until it is manifesting as this
tomato. There's no way this tomato can
escape tomato karma because it is tomato
karma. All right. So the ego of today is
nothing but the crystallization and
manifestation
in this lifetime of wall that uh has
been accumulated since the beginning of
time by this particular consciousness
and because they're one and the same I
thought Jesus Christ understanding you
know seeing that that equality there's
no point of talking about past lives and
confusing people
because at the time that he incarnated
in the culture in which he incarnated.
It would have been another excuse to
reject his teaching as outlandish
because in traditional Judaism palize
uh is not is not taught. So he would
have been more out of gear with his
society in which he got himself born. Uh
the Buddha on the other hand uh
not only recal recalled them and was but
but also taught in a society in which
that was common knowledge. That's hardly
that's that's common knowledge in the
far east and in India
that one has had numerous incarnations
and hopefully up the evolutionary tree
and um
all right so then we'd say that every
act of the will every uh ascent of the
spiritual will
is reflected in one's spiritual ual the
vibrational
energy field they call the soul. Yeah.
Now this influences
let's see if what we just said is so
we're going to check everything out. All
right.
That so is it. Thank you. You see I
don't care whether it's so or not.
People usually get a question. How do
you know that what you're doing is
scientifically accurate? I don't frankly
care.
I I am not uh I I really don't care. Nor
do I care if people are unable to do it
or disbelieve in it. It's just it's just
a tool. You understand what I'm saying?
Um but it's an extremelyformational
tool. Extremelyformational.
pretty much like a compass, you know,
and to navigate without a compass is
where mankind has been. Mankind has been
unable to know truth from falsehood.
The inability to know truth from
falsehood is why the millions get
slaughtered generation after generation.
One uh incredible monster after another
as slaughters more millions
and they never lack for followers. Huh?
We can say somehow they never lie for
followers. No matter how insane you are
in this world, you'll get followers.
Yesterday's paper was full of a couple
of crazinesses.
What was that yesterday? Some spiritual
group in Wisconsin
is threatening all the morticians
because they don't believe in in u
inbombing the body. Oh well. Okay. And
the next page, somebody was threatening
birth control places. The ne the next
page was a picture of protesters in
India who were protesting Valentine's
Day
because it's immoral to display
affection in public. So anyway,
you take your pick and of insanity. So
all the only point I'm mentioning is
that any kind of insanity never lacks
for followers.
And uh if you want to kill all the white
people on the planet, you can find lots
of non-white people who join you. And if
you want to kill all the black people,
you can find lots of white people join
you. No matter how bizarre it is, you'll
find endless followers. You know, I'm
thinking of being loud and telling all
these people that their duty is to kill
all Americans and non non-Islamics, you
know.
And then I'm thinking, well, he
succeeded.
He killed off 3,000 and he's only got
285 million to go.
He kills off another 285 million, he
might be in the winning, but I don't
think he will because people propagate
faster than that. So, he can't kill them
off as fast as they even propagate. So,
you know, you'd say this is total
insanity.
Even if they were right, they're wrong.
Uhhuh. So
all right. So the karmic uh situation
then we just want to confirm this so
everybody can witness
uh that um one's karmic uh position is
determined by the agreement of the
spiritual will resist.
All right. So it's the spiritual will
then
the spiritual will which determines
one's karma. That which you
spiritually intend to be the result
is what determines one's karmic fate.
How does the karma operate then? And how
can you say that the justice of God is
absolute?
It's obvious. When you go into a certain
state, it's a condition. Enlightenment
is a condition. It's a it's a what kind
of a condition would you go on? It's a
paradigm.
The ego has one paradigm. And the non
that's the paradigm of linear. The
nonlinear is just a different paradigm.
From this paradigm, this paradigm seems
unreal or outlandish and to the
scientific world not believable.
To this paradigm, this
uh viewpoint
is equally untenable. Anyway,
because the universe is a karmic unity,
you could say that which is the infinite
power
of the unmanifest becomes manifest as
the universe
creates a karmic field let's say
within the absolute reality and infinite
power of God
would be like an enormous
electromagnetic field
and everything is included. within it.
When we explain the difference there
between power and force, force is
something that goes from here to there
and expends energy and therefore comes
to an end.
Power does not require any input of
energy is beyond time and stands there
and holds all within its field
without the requirement of any energy.
And because
it is just the field, everything in it
aligns itself within that field
according to that which it is.
So if you're a little iron magnetic,
little iron filing, then
where you stand in this electromagnetic
field depends on the the strength of
your charge,
your shape of the negative and positive
poles and where they are, etc.
So what you have come become by virtue
of spiritual agreement by virtue of the
spiritual will then has determined the
charge on your spiritual body which as
it separates from the physical body will
automatically gravitate where it is
destined to be by a virtue of that which
it has become.
By virtue of that which it has become,
it will automatically
adjust itself to where it belongs within
the infinite magnetic field of the will
of God. Yeah. Is that simple enough?
It does not require any arbitrary
God or judgment day because the
consequence of that which you are is
automatic
as the consequence of the reality of
that which it is. There's no arbitrary
God who has to sit up there and wait
till you get up there and boy are you
going to get it.
It's absolutely not necessary.
That which chooses and is attracted by
hatred goes to the realms of hatred.
That which is attracted by beauty and
peace and love and divinity
automatically gravitates to it.
Is that an agreement and obvious? Yeah.
That therefore the judgment of God is
absolute and absolutely perfect by the
virtue of the nature of creation itself.
All of creation then in its perfection
guarantees absolute justice.
Nothing and no one will go to any place
other than that which it already is.
Huh? It's pretty clear. Yes.
Like a cork in water. And each one
floats depending on
one's buoyancy and the density of the
water. Salt water is denser.
Therefore, one can refuse
the sovereignty of God and refuse God
and choose the lower astral realms.
God doesn't force you to accept God. Nor
does does God force you to the lower
astral realms. People gravitate towards
hatred
because that is what they have chosen.
We assume because
you know a group in the 400s,
we would assume that a rundown
degenerate looking bar and grill with
drunks lying around the place and vermin
in the place and rats eating the garbage
that the people who go there would love
it when they clean it up and paint it
and put new drapes and Yeah.
and get rid of the rats and
disarm the patrons.
And we all know that's not a fact. The
new owner comes in, cleans up the place,
new drapes, new carpets, deal crowd
doesn't go there at all. They deserve
it.
I remember the electric p electric
electric circus in East Village. That
was the early 60s and it was the
beginning of the psychedelic era and it
was the in place to go.
and uh Andy Warhol and all the elite
intellectual artist artistic types went
to electric circus and um the groups
that litter became famous. They weren't
famous in that thing but that was the
first psychedelic disco
and the walls had just drapes because
they didn't have money for for walls and
stuff.
It was hip, cool, and everybody was
anybody went there. And uh after a year
or two, I forget some new owner bought
it. They closed it up for about two
months while they cleaned it up. Well,
they cleaned it up and now it had
curveal linear beautiful plastic walls
and stuff and nobody went there.
The fact that it was funky was why it
was cool and people liked it. You know
what I'm saying?
They cleaned up the old electric circus
and Fred fell on his butt. Nobody went
there anymore. It was no longer hip.
Wasn't cool. Nobody wanted it. All
right.
So, as amazing as it would be to people
in the 400s,
there are people who prefer uh to be on
the streets and on charge of a treatment
center. And a lot of them, the minute
you let them out, they they will go
right back to the very source of their
own devastation. Right back. Exactly.
Same lifestyle, same same people. Uh
just as the wife goes back to the man
who beats her up and uh she gets a court
order of protection and within 48 hours
she's back with him and then he's beaten
her up again and then so it goes over
and over. The person is attracted to
that which they are karmically destined
for. All right.
So that pretty much takes care of some
of the questions we had there because
it takes the view of God as judge.
You might say the universe judges
absolutely but not in the moral
arbitrary ego understanding of the word
judge which is an arbitrary.
The idea of the of of the judge, the
punitive judge comes from really the Old
Testament. And the Old Testament itself
arises from tribal tribal gods. See, all
the early cultures had tribal gods.
There's the Roman gods and the Greek
gods and they all have great names Zeus
and Athena
and all these various gods and uh they
were supplanted over time as life
evolved. So the some of the early
scriptures still have these
anthropomorphic gods who are
subject to all the fallacies and
foibless of the human ego. The so-called
gods of many ancient c cultures are
nothing but exaggerated humans
subject to the same proclivities of the
ego. jealousy and envy and hatred and
and revenge and vanity and
um
but when you calibrate their energy,
you'll see they're actually mostly
the so-called gods of the lower astral
realms. They're talking about the gods
of the lower astral realms
who rule by
vanity and egotism and revenge and anger
and favoritism. So you're not talking
about the god of the evolution of
consciousness.
You're talking about the
gods of the lower astral realms. Right?
Freud said they're all projections from
the unconscious. Let's see what we say
about it.
Uh the gods of uh that were that I was
talking about are projections on the
unconscious. Resist. Okay. They also
exist as realities and quotes in the
lower astral realms. Resist. Oh, because
they got projected there. Resist. Oh, I
got it. Okay. All right. So, they
originated in the unconscious out of
guilt, fear, anger, hatred, and all
those things.
And they're accepted as realities by a
large part of society.
Large part of society doesn't know
whether God is at where's our other the
other thing. A large part of society
doesn't know which end of this chart God
is at.
Now you talk about spiritual confusion.
>> That's the one. Yes. large parts of
society
and I say large parts very large parts
of society
think God is down here.
I don't know what they think is up
there.
There's one religious group that thinks
that to experience the Buddha nature is
a demon
and that God is down here. So I mean
they if you can't tell the top of the
chart from the bottom of the chart, you
really ought to not try to proilitize
others. I mean, you know,
I mean, you can do damage to your own
karmic potentiality, but to drag others
along with you, I really am not. So
proletizing has never been something
I've been interested in.
Karmic propensity then means that as a
result of whatever
has going on, you start from where
you're at.
Wow. Everybody has to start from where
they're at. And where you are is from
where you was.
All right. So we
Christians who believe in Christian in a
Christian culture, those who believe in
karma have usually be influenced by
Buddha uh things and by own personal
experiences to a qualified uh karmic uh
understanding of karma that uh no doubt
what you do in this lifetime is going to
have right quite profound consequences
in the future which may or may not
include the choice to reincarn incarnate
and the implied purpose of reincarnation
is is the chance to choose again. The
chance to choose again and and many
spiritual teachings do emphasize that
this is a chance to choose again. I
think doesn't the course of miracles
call it that. Yeah. It says uh this
lifetime is nothing but I really have
trouble. I must have some bad wire
karma.
What the course of miracles says about
this is a fact. Resist. People who
incarnate now have chosen to incarnate.
Resist. Oh, they were forced to
incarnate. Resist. No. None of us are
forced to. Wow. I didn't know that we
were given an option to choose again.
Resist. Huh. Many of us choose to undo
by reexperiencing what we did to others.
Resist. Yes. I know my own consciousness
before this event that happened
was uh one that would choose to
experience that which I did to someone
else because I didn't see any other way
to undo it.
So the guilt of that which I did was
sufficient that I was actually willing
to reexperience exactly what I did to
that other person. See, and I gave the
example of
of
not killing somebody that I should have
killed
and going through
a hernia repair without anesthesia
as a karmic undoment of the fact that
having run a sword right through him, I
left him to die of his wounds instead of
having the spiritual courage to kill
him. In that case, I should have out of
mercy put an end to it, but I didn't.
So, in his lifetime, I undid it. Let's
see if that's a fact or not.
Yeah,
that's a fact. Is it? Yeah, it is a
fact.
Uh, so one will get recalls like that
and you can do spiritual research. I
think it's valuable to do karmic
research to clear up any
misunderstandings. One thing you can
clear up with karmic research is
self-pity.
The idea that you're the innocent victim
of all these vicissitudes of life. With
a little karmic research, you will find
you are not the innocent victim of all
these vicissitudes of life. No, that you
have really chosen this. Well, it's a
lot easier to accept the consequences of
your own actions. You say
out of my willingness to
evolve spiritually to
be worthy of heaven, to be worthy of
God's love, to experience the infinite
reality of God. You can respect yourself
that you are actually willing to
reincarnate and go through what you've
gone through again as a human being for
the f mere chance of undoing it and
choosing better. So you can respect
yourself for what yourself you've put
yourself through
and you certainly have undone a lot of
bad karma. So the worse life has been
the better it is. Huh.
Your life's been dreadful.
Boy oh boy. I don't know how you rape.
Well, I earned heaven. I'll tell you.
I've been through quite a bit. And uh so
all right so you can say if I chose this
as an option then why did I choose it?
Because it says you're not forced to
reincarnate. Don't have to. Don't have
to. It's an option. We can choose it.
Um if you could skip the childhood part
of it, you know, wouldn't be so bad.
This time the childhood part was so
boring. I don't know how I got through
it. I thought children are awfully
boring and I look used to look at them.
God my they were so dumb. I mean they
they play these dumb games and
I couldn't wait till I grew up. So I
read Play-Doh in the meantime while I
waited to grow up as you weren't growing
up unless you were this high and I was
only this high. So I just had to sit in
the chair and read Play-Doh by myself.
But I thought childhood was quite
boring. So there wasn't particularly
anything in childhood I need to undo.
And the disasters didn't start till
later in life.
All right. So you can see you may get a
different position about
your physical life this time. It might
give you a different way to maybe
respect yourself instead of killing or
kicking yourself.
Uh instead of kicking yourself or errors
you might say to yourself.
uh you can read to contextualize it that
this was a different way of looking at
it, a different way of learning, a
different choice.
Um and I turned it down this time.
This time you turned down great wealth.
Let's say you lost your shirt in the
stock market.
Oh gee, high-tech stocks are just not
the way to financial heaven, I guess,
right? So
all of us live and learn you know and
this maturity that uh so we try to gain
what we can from this lifetime. So we
can turn this lifetime no matter what
into a plus to extract that which is
spiritually valuable out of every iota
of it. A lot of times you surprise
yourself.
The guy stole a lot of money from you.
Let's say you discover somebody does a
lot of money from you and you want to
get even.
Well,
it helps to find out that karmically you
embezzled a lot out of a lot of people,
a lot of lifetimes and it's payback
time. That makes a lot little easier to
handle right there. Yeah.
And to see that it doesn't really
matter. So the willingness to let every
instant be the past of course closes the
door to all regret about the past.
And the way one's consciousness evolves
then is the willingness to surrender
everything as it arises to live in the
absolute radical reality of the moment
of now
means like listening to music to let go
of the last note
and make room for the next. So each
thing as it arises, you can let go
wanting to change it. And with the
willingness to surrender this instant to
God as it arises
means you don't live on the front of the
wave trying to anticipate the future.
Nor do you live on the back of the wave
trying to cling to the past.
As it is now, it is spoken. As it is
now, it is done. As it is now, it's
acted upon. and you let it be the way it
was. Huh?
Is that simple enough? It's walking on
the edge of the knife.
To walk precisely on the edge of the
knife is what allows you to go through
surgery without anesthesia. Because the
instant you begin to resist the pain, it
becomes excruciating. It's only when you
completely and totally surrender to it,
not call it pain, stop resisting, become
one with whatever the sensation is
without any calling it anything. And all
of a sudden, one transcends it and the
pain disappears.
As though being transported by angels to
a different realm.
I wonder if that degree of surrender
actually
brings angels around or something.
That's what happened. Okay. It was a
definite sensation as though one was
being lifted out of the body by angelic
beings. They were angelic because the
exquisite grace, gentleness and radiance
of love was profound.
Z one was being lifted out of the
physicality and the physicality was
going through all this surgery and
chopping off your thumbs and various
things that were going on and there was
only a feeling of infinite peace and
joy. So that surrendering, that intense
surrender then, well, let's ask that
again. I don't know. I need a different
one of these things, don't I?
The intensity of the surrender finesses
the presence of God expressed as the
angelic resist. Wow. Huh. Didn't know
that. Suspected it, but didn't know know
it for sure. So you see, kinesiology as
we use it is
is a constant earning a learning tool.
It's just a tool that's all. It like
confirms, denies, tells you in the wrong
direction, yeah, it's like looking for
Easter eggs. You're warmer. You're
warmer. You're warmer. You know what I
mean?
You're warmer. Oh, this way, this way.
And it sort of leads your investigation.
Now, karmically, you know, you're beset
by certain problems and questions in
your life. So they tend to press for
expression and for awareness.
The past lives that probably are of any
significance in in one's life, most
people already intuitit them. They will
start out as a joke. Oh, some lifetime I
must have so and so. Usually starts out
as a joke. They don't want anybody to
think that they believe in karma. So
they say, well, in some lifetime I must
have been a pickpocket.
I was a pickpocket in France at one
time. Anyway, I sort of knew that all
along. So you'll find that you would
sort of intuit it or people will mention
to you, you know, you you're like an old
farmer for God's sake. The way you walk
around and look down at the ground, you
know, you know, you just sort of knew
you've been a farmer a lot of lifetimes.
You know what I'm saying?
It's like one, oh, it's very close to
consciousness.
What's the value and the significance of
it? The value and significance is that
it may recontextualize your spiritual
work in this lifetime in a way that is
more less painful.
Uh, facilitate it and broaden one's
understanding of the evolution of
consciousness itself.
It's unlikely that you just came out of
the blue out of some kind of nothingness
and appeared on this planet calibrating
at 4:30. I mean, it's just not a
likelihood,
right? Not a likelihood.
The other interesting observation is
that without some kind of understanding
of karma, there's no explanation of why
it is that various individuals
already have a calibrated level of
consciousness at the moment of birth.
Yeah. How come this baby's born at 2:30,
this one's born at 5:40, this one's born
at 70?
How would you explain that? A fickle god
or careless god? I don't know. I just
rolled the dice and they were some fell
off the table.
Little kids born into they were born
with AIDS and then died of starvation by
age six months. What kind of karma is
that? Huh?
Yeah. born with a calibrated energy of
30,
which is not far from death. They're
born half dead
to a family with no resources, no money,
no food, and all of them have AIDS and
they're on terminal cases of
tuberculosis. The AIDS don't get them.
The TV will
or the nearest warlord will have
slaughtered them anyway. So,
how explain this? Uh, how can you
believe in a just god? uh who determines
all events as though he's arbitrary
and yet have people coming into the
planet on all these various different
levels. Huh?
So let's see. Let's ask again. Let's
just I just want to show you how we how
we do this, you know. Um
karma is the explanation why children
come into this world calibrating at
different levels.
So you see you you like intuitit the
next step in your own spiritual
evolution and and you use conscious
consciousness techniques such as
kinesiology to affirm or deny them. Why?
Because you begin to trust your own
spiritual inspiration.
See the presence of God within you
expresses itself as spiritual
inspiration which is what leads you into
spiritual pathways and attending
lectures and studying books and doing
mantras and all that. It's coming from a
spiritual intuition
inspiration.
It's not personal. So you can't
compliment yourself that you're
spiritually oriented nor can you attack
yourself that you aren't.
Consciousness itself is impersonal.
Everybody has it. Awareness is
impersonal. Everybody has it.
The presence of the self is ubiquitous
in everybody.
So it's it's not something you can rate
yourself one way or the other. It's like
you hear the call and you become
responsive to it and now you become
curious about spiritual matters. You
become interested in overcoming defects
because
your polarity is such in the gravity
field of
the universe of God that you are
attracted to the light. So once one is
attracted to the light,
one is attracted to the light by virtue
of all the spiritual decisions that have
been made in the past. So that your
karmic propensity now is to be attracted
in this direction.
Most people who are seriously
spiritually devoted accept that as
normal and uh think well isn't everybody
that way. Doesn't everybody uh want to
go to church and become a
give up sin and become a better person
and go to heaven? No.
That uh
naive altogether
we see that 78% of the population
prefers it the other way. they will
consciously choose
uh
that which leads in the other direction.
When given a choice, they will
consciously choose it.
That is also partly because of what they
have been up to that point. So that you
can't really berate anybody for what
they are at this point
because what they are now is a
consequence of what they have been. Huh?
And to many people it would seem that
the option of a different choice is not
open to them.
If you're out at sea and shipwrecked at
sea, it's not an option to drink pure
water because there isn't any. And uh
many of the
adolescents I see who come off the
streets,
uh a better choice is not really an
option to it's not within their
conscious options. You know, when you go
to make a choice, you have a certain
number of options. And these kids don't
have these three options.
You either fight and kill or you're a
coward and go down. So, they've got one
choice. They got one choice.
It doesn't condone on them that they
could leave uh their present
environment. It's not a possibility.
So, it's almost as though the positive
options themselves are earned.
The positive option is not there unless
you've earned
earned the option of a positive option
you might say. Does that make any sense?
All right. How about questions?
Having answered all the questions of the
universe
according to Ramana Maharshi the eye oh
the seat of the heart is in the right
side of the chest I don't know that's
puzzled people for that's puzzled lots
of people and nobody's ever answered it
satisfactory he said it was in one side
of the chest he don't forget he was
talking about he talked about the sheets
the seven sheets he was talking about
uh the various levels of the aura which
have different languaging depending on
the spiritual tradition from which you
speaking in the far east or the near
east or wherever.
Anyway, he's apparently talking about um
a heart within the heart chakra
as expressed in one of the sheets.
So, I'm not aware of what he meant by
it. And it puzzled many of his
followers.
Many people asked and I forgot what his
literal answer was
that let's see. Well, we'll ask it
today. I don't know what the answer is
either. Um what he meant was
the spiritual heart resist that the
spiritual heart is positioned in a
certain way within
the um etheric body resist. He's talking
about the position of the heart
chakra within the atheric body resist
and that it's not concordant with the
physical body resist.
All right. So, he's saying it's not
concordant
anatomically with the physical body.
I once saw that I only saw auras briefly
in my lifetime and it was with a lady
who knew how to see auras and I said, "I
can't see auras." She says, "Oh, anybody
can see orasures. Here, sit down." And
she described to me, it's a very famous
person, too, by the way. You know her
name. Anyway, she told me how you uh see
auras and she said, "You look right over
the head there and don't focus on their
head and uh and you'll see." And then
she showed me where to look and how to
look. And by God, there was one.
Well, I didn't know if it was just
suggestion. Don't forget, I'm
scientifically trained, you know, and I
know about suggestions. So, I'm saying
to myself, "Well, this is suggestion."
So, I thought I'll test her out. For one
thing, when I saw this aura, it was like
gray like this and it was very lopsided.
I thought, well, it's not auras the way
they are in pictures look like halos or
something. This person sitting there and
here's this gray aura and it's way over
this way over this right ear.
And I said, "Where do you see the ura?"
She says, "It's way over his right ear."
I said, "Okay, I am seeing him."
Well, your fantasy would be that
everybody's aura looks very neat like an
artist drawing right around the body.
You see, but here there here was this
guy's head all I mean the the energy
fuel was way over like that. So, I don't
know. I'm just trying to I'm just
speculating on what Ramano meant by
that. Uh I don't think it was anything
important. I don't think he would I
forget whether he said to meditate on it
or not but uh I I didn't get that it was
of any critical
importance
um how can you how can you um verify the
validity of your findings uh such I
suppose in kinesiology or whatever or in
one's work.
That's sort of the hypothetical asking
the hypothetical. So, it's not really
answerable in a radical logical way. Uh
but
sub
the experience of one existence is
purely subjective
and there is no escape from the from
subjectivity.
So to ask somebody for what might be
considered objective from a certain
intellectual hypothetical viewpoint
doesn't really have any reality even if
it was answerable
because
the experience of myself Susan and the
audience simultaneously is that we use a
certain technique to verify the yes or
no of various things but to some degree
we already know the answer and all we're
looking for is some external
verification for the purpose of
demonstration really and for showing how
this technique can be used to further
spiritual progress and gain access to
information. Don't forget the
information that we talk about in these
lectures and write about etc. Most of it
has never been known in the history of
mankind. Not known certainly in a
verifiable way. uh maybe some sheaman
had a dream vision of it or somebody had
a hallucination of it but nobody has
really contextualized it in a totally
comprehensible way so as to make it
assimilable and um verifiable.
So I think the value of what we uh do is
you see if you get an answer that's
outside the expected realm or outside of
even the possible the outside of
possibility it requires an explanation
and occasionally we get an outrageous
response. Well it doesn't mean the
response is wrong. It means that you
don't comprehend it. A lot of times you
have to completely rephrase the
question.
The uh sometimes the question is already
begging the answer and you'll get a
refusal.
Uh it's funny but consciousness is
extremely bright.
And uh we'll outsmart when you think
you're outsmarting it, you find you
didn't get away with it.
And many a time we did it one time in
front of an audience when and I've cited
this example before when we asked uh
Carl Young's uh energy is over 520 and
we got to know well we've done it
hundreds of times I know what Carl
Young's energy is and she couldn't
understand it and I couldn't understand
it well we said it is well he's dead so
it couldn't be could it said no when we
said it was we got a yes so just
phrasing one word Carl Young is over
520. Obvious the answer is no. But we
were careless because we've answered
that. We've asked that question so many
times. So you have to be careful how you
now the whole thing has to be internally
consistent.
In other words, if you spent a few weeks
with us and saw us do hundreds and
hundreds of of things, you begin to see
a fabric of truth form itself which is
internally consistent. Now, at this
time,
we were going to sit this way and that
way. Maybe we should have set the other
way. Never mind. The main
after at this time, I've done over
255,000 calibrations. 260,000 265,000
270,000 275,000 280,000
290,000 over 300,000 calibrations over
290,000 calibrations. 294
294,000 calibrations.
Well, if you've looked at 294,000 rocks
and examined them under a microscope,
you begin to get a feeling for geology.
What shale and what ain't shale. I mean,
you know, you begin to get what uh so
just the sheer experience of it, I
think, is interesting. When I first saw
kinesiology, I had already gone into
that infinite paradigm we call nonlinear
and which religiously is called the
presence of God.
So when I first saw it, I was already
seeing it from a different paradigm of
reality. The whole audience was within
the linear
Newtonian domain. What they saw was a
local phenomena and what I saw was a
non-local phenomena. We both witnessed
the same event. To me it was obviously
the answer uh the non-local answer of
the nature coming from the nature of
consciousness itself
and the rest of the audience thought it
was the reaction of the body's
physiology to a turnup
you Some people thought well you know
they presumed um
but it was very clearly a nonlinear
impersonal response. has nothing to do
with the questioner. It had nothing to
do with the
person of the who was uh was being the
subject
and it was obviously the connection
between the invisible nonlinear domain
and
uh the consciousness of mankind is
expresses itself through the nervous
system.
So in our cell was
infinite non-local impersonal
and was a response of consciousness
itself to the presence of truth.
Italy we first we called it true versus
false but that is not correct and I
think in power versus force we said it
was true versus false but in eye of the
eye we corrected that it's not true
versus tr false it's true versus not
true
there is no opposite to truth
uh truth is either present or not if
truth is present like u then you go
strong if truth is not present because
it has no existence. So non that which
is not real has no existence.
Consciousness therefore does not respond
to it because it is only um belief
system in your head with no reality.
So there is no such thing in the
universe aseness.
There's either yes or the absence of
yes.
That's a very profound spiritual
understanding
because it destroys the artifact of the
polarity of the opposites
and we use as the analogy of that when
you throw the switch on electricity is
present in the wire.
Electricity is either present or not
present. There is no condition known as
offness.
So the duality of the ego is that off
and on are opposites.
There is no opposite to God. There is no
opposite to truth. There is no opposite
to existence.
So when I hit the duality at age three
and again later resolved at maybe age 60
of existence versus non-existence, the
fallacy of it made me laugh. There is
there is only existence.
And you can see the absurdity of asking
whether or not non non-existence exists.
Non-existence is not an ab not an
option. Just like absence is not an
option. You see something is either
present or not present. There is no
condition called absence. You know what
I mean? We can't send absence into this
room and fill it up. After we all leave
here, we'll send in absence. Absence is
not has no existence.
You either there's either hearness or
not heariness. But there is no such
thing as absence.
But the ego's belief in that which is
unreal is the cause of the human
dilemma. That there is an opposite to
God, that there is an opposite to
existence.
The nearest o not opposite the the
nearest thing to non-existence is
oblivion
and that's so to see that is to solve
the ancient dilemma of the Buddha
fallacy there's errors in all religions
and the one in Buddhism
is the misunderstanding of the absolute
infinite as void
and in its mistransation The void
becomes a state to be
desired
uh and achieved by the pathway of
negation.
Actually non-existence is not a
possibility.
Voidness as nothingness is not a
Voidness is absence of form or content
is the absolute reality. But if one
believes that the absolute reality
to be achieved is the Buddha nature as
voidness is though voidness is a
condition
a reality condition
leads one uh into the state of the void
and when you leave the body you go into
oblivion.
Then because that's not a reality you
can't stay in it.
because you can't stay in it. You find
yourself back at age three in a little
wooden wagon wagon stunned by the fact
that you exist again.
That's the fallacy of the Hinyana
pathway
certain branch of the Hinyana pathway.
The misunderstanding
that that which has no existence can
exist as non-existence. You see the
fallacy of it even within the realm of
logic.
But when spoken by a guru with gongs,
shaved head, incense sitting on a tiger
rag, a tiger skin, one assumes this is
the ultimate authority.
One worships it, deifies it, and not
become sought after. God is
non-existence.
That's an impossible coin. You cannot
get past that one
until
what do we say 850. At 8:50 you passed
into that doorway.
The purpose of all that is to try to uh
unhook the power of
positionality creating a duality which
is the block to enlightenment.
If you see that only existence exists,
if you see that only heat exists, if you
see that in the supposed gradations
between light and darkness, there is
only the one and that is light and that
darkness has no independent existence,
then you're halfway to enlightenment
because those are the great obstacles.
Any questions?
Look at the 3x5 card.
>> Ah,
okay. Do you go
>> consciousness is not personal? What does
it mean? We earn the chance
for better opportunities for for better
choices.
It's like consciousness is the field.
The field karma is still content.
One has not escaped content yet. To go
beyond karma means to have escaped the
limitation of content.
Consciousness
is infinite context.
It has no form
like the sky.
Karma would be like a cloud has still
has form.
It hangs loose within the sky.
It's within the sky.
So karma then would be the consequence
of one's
spiritual decisions
has an influence on the shape of the
cloud. But consciousness is like the
sky. The field of consciousness which is
impersonal is unaffected by the cloud.
But where the cloud goes in the sky will
depend on its shape, size, consistency,
humidity, barometric pressure
and many things. Yes.
You see in the meditative uh technique
to realize the presence of God, one goes
back from
identifying with
the content of consciousness
to the field in which
to the field itself to realize that I am
not the content of the mind.
I am that uh upon which the mind is
playing.
See,
it's like I'm the receiver and not the
notes of the music. The receiver remains
the same no matter what music is playing
on it.
You all of a sudden jump from
identifying with the content. I am those
thoughts, words, images and memories to
I am that which empowers them to become
known.
So you become the knower of the field.
You become the witness.
You become at a certain level the
experiencer. Beyond the experiencer is
the witness and the observer.
The witness and the observer. and the
experiencer arise out of an impersonal
field. You can realize these things are
impersonal because witnessing
witnessing and observing is not uh
within you. You cannot shut it on and
off at will. If it's who you were, you
could shut it on and off, but it's not
who you are.
Behind the witness observer experiencer
is an impersonal allp prevailing field
of consciousness itself.
Even consciousness is not aware of its
own existence except uh for the field of
awareness. So you you identify you stop
identifying with the movie and you begin
to see one can witness the movie only
because
that upon which it is being projected as
formless.
You begin so you you withdraw your
investment in identification of self as
form and content of memory and
experience.
You see yourself as that which is beyond
form.
That you are the field upon which form
reveals itself as form.
You witness that the self is impersonal
because consciousness
doesn't shift no matter what you think
about it or say about it or try to do
with it. It's just there throughout the
day.
If one is awake, you're conscious. How
do you know you're conscious? Because
you're aware that you're conscious. And
awareness, awareness itself is also
impersonal.
Awareness itself is also impersonal.
So you go back through the substratum.
You're going back to God manifest as
existence, the awareness of existence.
And there you transcend temporality
because that quality which you sense has
no beginning and no end. Yeah.
Eventually you get back to God not only
as manifest but as unmanifest. Out of
the manifest. Unmanifest arises.
The unmanifest is traditionally in
Christianity called the Godhead. Out of
Godhead of the unmanifest arises God as
manifest.
Out of which arises the universe. M and
that all makes sense then as you in
meditation went in withdraw from the
identification with the movie uh to see
that it is except for consciousness
there would be no awareness of the movie
and that consciousness is what prevails
and the content of the movie is eancent.
Therefore, one is one one is is one
spiritually evolves, one is less and
less
prone to investing in that which is
transitory
because it's
the transitoriness of that which is
temporary becomes increasingly
obvious.
Every acquisition someday later will be
a problem in disposition.
Everything you acquire someday you will
now have the task of disposing of. So
you spend all day acquiring it. It's
going to take you two weeks to dispose
of it. All has to be reboxed, sold at
garage sales, transported, wholesaliled,
retailed, willed to somebody.
But in other words, that which is
transitory becomes less and less of
value. That which is permanent.
Therefore, spiritual work itself becomes
more and more value because one realizes
its permanency.
Once you've made a certain spiritual
decision and see through certain
spiritual illusions, that which you see
is permanent. that which you see has a
profound effect on one's karma that
becomes incorporated into
there is a Korean I think who wrote a
book called omniology and uh he gave
sort of the
you might say the anatomy of that which
is uh of the nonlinear as paradoxical as
that may sound the the spirit body has
within it a sort of like a karma body.
It would be like a computer,
a computer chip. So the spirit then is
like a computer chip,
but the computer chip of a different
domain in which everything leaves an
imprint throughout all of time.
So when we do kinesiologic research, we
can go anywhere in time, anywhere in in
in place, and we can pull out
information that nobody has had access
to. Nobody's ever had access to most of
the things we in fact on this stage a
lot of times we've asked things nobody's
ever asked and nobody's ever gotten an
answer nor
if they got an answer would they have
any way of verifying that the truth of
that answer
we asked did Jesus Christ ever have
previous physical incarnations anybody
ever asked that you ever hear of I never
heard of it myself
came out of the blue and it came out of
the blue to ask it here and now you know
what I'm saying
we thought about And I don't know that
necessarily means anything except it's
another piece in a puzzle when you put
it all together about your knowledge of
uh Krishna and Buddha and Christ and all
the great ones. It you begin to get a a
sense of what the spiritual reality of
that entity is and how it impacts your
life and then how it impacts all of
society.
What's the next question? What's my
sense of Ken Wilbur? He's a very bright
guy.
Ken Wilbur wrote holographic universe,
right?
>> Uh he wrote anyway the most best known
is the holographic universe. My guess
would be he's in the high power 400s as
a consequence. Came over. We have
permission in front of this audience.
exists he's over 460 or 70 480 45 85 he
would be high 400s because that's very
advanced understanding he has of the
nature of the universe and uh and how it
operates that it is a holographic unity
and um he also escapes the trap of
causality I think we talked in our last
lecture about causality we haven't
mentioned it again this time
that because this is on this side of the
universe. Therefore, this is where it is
on this side of the universe. But this
is not causing that to be over there. Do
you understand that?
In holographic universe
um it has to do with um the nature of u
you see things don't not come about as a
result of the ego's belief in causality.
They come about as a result of the
manifestation of
creation as it
evolves into the providence of
perception in what seems to be a
sequential
seems to be sequential.
As creation unfolds, nothing is causing
anything. You understand? It's beyond
causality.
Each thing is
is what it is and that completely
answers. There's no questions to be
answered.
Each thing is totally that which it is
and requires no cause. So the cause is
really a tautology. It's really the
hypothetical absurdity to say what is
causing this. It's the linear Newtonian
paradigm which presumes an invisible
thing called cause.
Just like it presumes behind thinking
this there's a thinker. Behind doing
this there's a doer.
Behind acting there's an actor. There is
no actor behind the actor. Nor is there
a doer behind doing this.
There is no thinker behind the
thinkingness. There's no speaker behind
the speakingness. speaking as speaking
of its own as the unfoldment of the
potentiality the infinite potentiality
of the evolution of humanity in
consciousness as it is expressed in this
entity
that's fact he said thank you
I'd hate to have found that that was not
right and repeated with a correction I'd
have to recall what I said
but it is a
Because each moment as speakingness is
speaking itself which is what it's
doing.
There isn't any speaker speakerness
behind it. There's no speaker behind the
speakingness. is speaking. This is
speaking itself
because the expression of life then at
this instant
in the gravity of field of this audience
manifesting through this entity speaks
back to you as this speakingness because
it's all happening spontaneously. You
understand? Everything is happening of
its own as an expression of that which
it is.
Which is why I don't sound like a bell.
Because the voice box is what
speakingness speaks to. See, but there
is no fantased
and therefore there's no cause behind
what you see
as
the unfoldment of God as form.
I promised you this morning I would uh
unearth the fallacy behind uh Thomas
Aquinus's uh proofs of the existence of
God through tracing back cause to first
cause. One of the famous arguments
there's four of them. One of the famous
ones is tracing back cause through a se
sequence of causes to find the prime
cause. The idea is if you trace back a
bunch of billiard balls, you'll find the
billiard ball that starts the whole
bunch going. Except when you get there,
there ain't no billiard ball there.
There's a Q. Oh, a Q stick. You don't
find another billion ball.
So if you go from cause C, cause B,
cause A, and look for the primary cause,
you're not going to find any primary
cause because there isn't any primary
cause there.
There's no cause
what you find is source. So the fallacy,
the argument is you think in an infinite
sequence that you're always going to
find another one of the same thing. No.
What happens is it changes quality.
Changes quality.
Let's take uh water. We we'll use the
thermometer.
You see at 212 water is a gas. Below 212
water is a liquid.
Below 32, water is a solid. Well, you've
got solid, liquid, and gas. And yet at
the same time, it's all H2O. The
essential nature of water has not
changed at all, but its quality has
changed considerably. Its quality. The
significance of the calibrated levels of
consciousness is because it's not just
quantitative.
It's true. These are logarithms. These
are logarithms.
But at each stage here these energy
fields which dominate consciousness
change quality
and there in lies both their blessing at
the top side and their curse at the
lower side because this may be only two
points lower than this but this one will
kill you. It changes its quality.
Changes its quality.
So it's the change of quality not just
the quantity. So the logarithmic numbers
uh denote levels of power
but as they change they change quality.
So
the nonlinear cannot be you know
accurately described from the viewpoint
of the linear.
I think in the book I just wrote I
compared the you cannot compare
um
lead with platinum by comparing their
atomic weights because the quality of
platinum and lead are completely
different.
Lead is relatively inert whereas a
milligram of platinum can catalyze tons
of ore. You can get tons and tons of ore
out of one just milligram of platinum
because it doesn't get used up in the
process. Lead is inert. You can put lead
someplace and it doesn't do anything for
a few hundred years.
It's slow on the uptake. Lead is, you
know,
any questions out there
that things change their quality as they
go up or down the scale? Yes.