So,
So, it's
So, it's wonderful
So, it's wonderful that
So, it's wonderful that you're
So, it's wonderful that you're all
So, it's wonderful that you're all here
today.
Today,
Today, we're
Today, we're going
Today, we're going to
Today, we're going to talk
Today, we're going to talk about
Today, we're going to talk about that
which
which cannot
Today, we're going to talk about that
which cannot be
which cannot be spoken
Today, we're going to talk about that
which cannot be spoken about.
This
This is
This is going
This is going to
This is going to be
This is going to be an
This is going to be an experiment.
This is going to be an experiment. I
don't
don't give
This is going to be an experiment. I
don't give you
don't give you any
This is going to be an experiment. I
don't give you any guarantee
don't give you any guarantee about
This is going to be an experiment. I
don't give you any guarantee about what
will
will happen
will happen today
will happen today because
will happen today because I
don't
don't know
will happen today because I
don't know myself.
Today,
Today, we're
Today, we're talking
Today, we're talking about
Today, we're talking about the
Today, we're talking about the pathway
of
of love.
which
which is
which is extraordinarily
which is extraordinarily powerful
and
and is
which is extraordinarily powerful
and is quite
and is quite capable
which is extraordinarily powerful
and is quite capable of
and is quite capable of sweeping
which is extraordinarily powerful
and is quite capable of sweeping all
capacity
capacity to
capacity to function
capacity to function aside.
We
We have
capacity to function aside.
We have great
We have great hopes
capacity to function aside.
We have great hopes that
We have great hopes that that
capacity to function aside.
We have great hopes that that will
We have great hopes that that will not
happen
happen early
happen early in
happen early in the
happen early in the lecture.
the
the uh
Amna
Amna Shaya
tape
tape that
Amna Shaya
tape that we
tape that we were
Amna Shaya
tape that we were listening
tape that we were listening to
calibrates
calibrates at
calibrates at 740
and
and it's
calibrates at 740
and it's difficult
and it's difficult to
calibrates at 740
and it's difficult to function
and it's difficult to function and
calibrates at 740
and it's difficult to function and also
be
be in
be in that
be in that energy
be in that energy field.
It's
It's not
be in that energy field.
It's not wise
It's not wise to
be in that energy field.
It's not wise to drive
It's not wise to drive a
be in that energy field.
It's not wise to drive a car
It's not wise to drive a car anyway.
So
So you're
So you're aware
So you're aware that
So you're aware that everything
So you're aware that everything is
happening
happening of
So you're aware that everything is
happening of its
happening of its own
So you're aware that everything is
happening of its own as
happening of its own as an
So you're aware that everything is
happening of its own as an expression
happening of its own as an expression of
divinity
which
which is
divinity
which is the
which is the allness,
the
the totality
the totality of
the totality of all
the totality of all that
the totality of all that exists.
The
The realization
the totality of all that exists.
The realization that
The realization that one's
the totality of all that exists.
The realization that one's own
The realization that one's own existence
is
is due
is due to
is due to the
is due to the the
is due to the the constant
is due to the the constant presence
is due to the the constant presence of
divinity.
divinity. Contrary
to
to the
to the unenlightened
to the unenlightened view,
to the unenlightened view, the
to the unenlightened view, the divinity
created
created a
threw
threw the
threw the dice
threw the dice somewhere
threw the dice somewhere back
threw the dice somewhere back in
threw the dice somewhere back in history
and
and then
threw the dice somewhere back in history
and then disappeared
and
and is
and is waiting
and is waiting for
and is waiting for you
and is waiting for you somewhere
until
until that
and is waiting for you somewhere
until that awesome
until that awesome day
and is waiting for you somewhere
until that awesome day called
until that awesome day called judgment
day
day is
day is a
day is a terrifying
misconception
misconception of
day is a terrifying
misconception of reality.
misconception of reality. It's
day is a terrifying
misconception of reality. It's because
of
of the
of the presence
of the presence of
of the presence of God.
of the presence of God. Right
of the presence of God. Right now,
one's
one's existence
of the presence of God. Right now,
one's existence from
one's existence from instant
of the presence of God. Right now,
one's existence from instant to
one's existence from instant to instant
is
is is
is is dependent
is is dependent completely
is is dependent completely on
is is dependent completely on the
presence
presence of
is is dependent completely on the
presence of God.
So,
So, one
So, one could
So, one could say
So, one could say that
So, one could say that that
So, one could say that that which
So, one could say that that which one
considers
considers to
So, one could say that that which one
considers to be
considers to be oneself,
So, one could say that that which one
considers to be oneself, the
considers to be oneself, the ego
is
is the
is the content
and
and God
is the content
and God is
and God is the
is the content
and God is the ultimate
and God is the ultimate context.
So
So self
So self with
So self with a
So self with a small
So self with a small S
So self with a small S is
So self with a small S is the
So self with a small S is the contents.
Self
Self with
So self with a small S is the contents.
Self with a
Self with a large
So self with a small S is the contents.
Self with a large S
Self with a large S is
So self with a small S is the contents.
Self with a large S is the
Self with a large S is the context.
Enlightenment
Enlightenment is
Enlightenment is merely
Enlightenment is merely identifying
progressively
with
with the
with the infinite
self
self and
with the infinite
self and realizing
self and realizing that
with the infinite
self and realizing that one
self and realizing that one is
with the infinite
self and realizing that one is all
self and realizing that one is all that
is
is forever.
In
In the
is forever.
In the first
In the first lecture,
is forever.
In the first lecture, we
In the first lecture, we said
is forever.
In the first lecture, we said that
In the first lecture, we said that in
every
every lecture,
every lecture, we
every lecture, we affirm
every lecture, we affirm that
every lecture, we affirm that one
every lecture, we affirm that one of
every lecture, we affirm that one of the
most
most important
every lecture, we affirm that one of the
most important pieces
most important pieces of
every lecture, we affirm that one of the
most important pieces of information
most important pieces of information to
realize
is
is that
realize
is that there
is that there is
realize
is that there is no
is that there is no such
realize
is that there is no such thing
is that there is no such thing as
realize
is that there is no such thing as cause
in
in the
in the world.
That
That that
in the world.
That that is
That that is an
in the world.
That that is an abstraction.
That
That the
That the whole
That the whole basis
That the whole basis of
That the whole basis of the
That the whole basis of the ego
That the whole basis of the ego is
That the whole basis of the ego is based
on
on the
That the whole basis of the ego is based
on the premise
on the premise of
That the whole basis of the ego is based
on the premise of cause.
Cause
Cause is
Cause is based
Cause is based on
Cause is based on duality.
Cause
Cause is
Cause is based on duality.
Cause is the
Cause is the belief
Cause is based on duality.
Cause is the belief that
Cause is the belief that there
Cause is based on duality.
Cause is the belief that there is
Cause is the belief that there is a
Cause is based on duality.
Cause is the belief that there is a this
causing
causing a
causing a that
separate
separate in
causing a that
separate in time
separate in time and
causing a that
separate in time and place.
If
If there
If there has
If there has to
If there has to be
If there has to be a
If there has to be a this
If there has to be a this causing
everything,
then
then there
then there has
then there has to
then there has to be
then there has to be a
then there has to be a this
then there has to be a this causing
whatever
whatever you
then there has to be a this causing
whatever you think
whatever you think you
then there has to be a this causing
whatever you think you are.
And
And that's
And that's how
And that's how the
And that's how the ego
maintains
maintains some
And that's how the ego
maintains some semblance
maintains some semblance of
And that's how the ego
maintains some semblance of belief.
There
There must
There must be
There must be an
There must be an actor
There must be an actor behind
There must be an actor behind your
actions.
actions. There
There must be an actor behind your
actions. There must
actions. There must be
There must be an actor behind your
actions. There must be a
actions. There must be a speaker
There must be an actor behind your
actions. There must be a speaker behind
your
your speaking.
There's
There's got
your speaking.
There's got to
There's got to be
your speaking.
There's got to be a
There's got to be a doer
your speaking.
There's got to be a doer behind
There's got to be a doer behind your
your
your doings.
And
And therefore,
your doings.
And therefore, the
And therefore, the illusion
your doings.
And therefore, the illusion that
And therefore, the illusion that there
is
is a
is a this
is a this causing
is a this causing a
is a this causing a that
is a this causing a that is
is a this causing a that is the
is a this causing a that is the main
block.
It
It is
It is also
It is also the
It is also the whole
It is also the whole basis
It is also the whole basis of
It is also the whole basis of science.
And
And uh
I
I was
I was read
I was read I
I was read I was
I was read I was looking
I was read I was looking at
I was read I was looking at a
I was read I was looking at a book
somebody
somebody sent
I was read I was looking at a book
somebody sent me
uh
uh putting
uh putting together
uh putting together advanced
uh putting together advanced quantum
mechanics
in
in brain
in brain function
and
and you
in brain function
and you see
and you see how
in brain function
and you see how linearity
and you see how linearity strains
in brain function
and you see how linearity strains and
strains
strains and
strains and strains
strains and strains to
strains and strains to reach
strains and strains to reach that
strains and strains to reach that which
is
is really
strains and strains to reach that which
is really nonlinear.
book
book is
book is calibrates
book is calibrates at
book is calibrates at 465.
Trying
Trying to
book is calibrates at 465.
Trying to push
Trying to push the
book is calibrates at 465.
Trying to push the concept
Trying to push the concept of
book is calibrates at 465.
Trying to push the concept of cause
Trying to push the concept of cause to
its
its ultimate
its ultimate and
its ultimate and make
its ultimate and make it
its ultimate and make it fit
its ultimate and make it fit a
its ultimate and make it fit a realm
its ultimate and make it fit a realm in
which
which there
its ultimate and make it fit a realm in
which there is
which there is no
its ultimate and make it fit a realm in
which there is no cause
which there is no cause is
its ultimate and make it fit a realm in
which there is no cause is quite
which there is no cause is quite a
difficult
difficult task.
Uh
Uh so
difficult task.
Uh so anyway,
today
today we're
today we're going
today we're going to
today we're going to it's
today we're going to it's today
today we're going to it's today is
today we're going to it's today is like
a
a bird
today we're going to it's today is like
a bird trying
a bird trying to
today we're going to it's today is like
a bird trying to describe
a bird trying to describe to
today we're going to it's today is like
a bird trying to describe to you
a bird trying to describe to you what
today we're going to it's today is like
a bird trying to describe to you what a
bird
bird is
bird is like.
bird is like. The
bird is like. The only
bird is like. The only thing
bird is like. The only thing that
bird is like. The only thing that can
describe
describe what
bird is like. The only thing that can
describe what a
describe what a bird
bird is like. The only thing that can
describe what a bird is
describe what a bird is like
bird is like. The only thing that can
describe what a bird is like is
describe what a bird is like is a
bird is like. The only thing that can
describe what a bird is like is a not
bird.
If
If you're
bird.
If you're not
If you're not a
bird.
If you're not a bird,
If you're not a bird, you
bird.
If you're not a bird, you can
If you're not a bird, you can describe
what
what a
what a bird
what a bird is
what a bird is like.
what a bird is like. But
what a bird is like. But if
what a bird is like. But if you
what a bird is like. But if you are
what a bird is like. But if you are a
bird,
bird, what
what a bird is like. But if you are a
bird, what can
bird, what can you
what a bird is like. But if you are a
bird, what can you say
bird, what can you say about
what a bird is like. But if you are a
bird, what can you say about it?
I
I go
I go from
I go from tree
I go from tree to
I go from tree to tree
I go from tree to tree and
I go from tree to tree and I
I go from tree to tree and I eat
I go from tree to tree and I eat worms.
End
End the
I go from tree to tree and I eat worms.
End the story,
End the story, you
I go from tree to tree and I eat worms.
End the story, you know.
You
You just
You just are
You just are that
You just are that which
You just are that which you
You just are that which you are.
You just are that which you are. And
You just are that which you are. And uh
the
the realization
You just are that which you are. And uh
the realization of
the realization of that
You just are that which you are. And uh
the realization of that can
the realization of that can sometimes
take
take you
take you out
take you out of
take you out of the
take you out of the world
take you out of the world quite
take you out of the world quite a
take you out of the world quite a bit.
We
We weren't
take you out of the world quite a bit.
We weren't even
We weren't even sure
take you out of the world quite a bit.
We weren't even sure how
We weren't even sure how we
take you out of the world quite a bit.
We weren't even sure how we were
We weren't even sure how we were going
to
to get
to get here
to get here this
to get here this morning,
to get here this morning, but
to get here this morning, but we
to get here this morning, but we got
here
here with
to get here this morning, but we got
here with the
here with the help
to get here this morning, but we got
here with the help of
here with the help of friends
to get here this morning, but we got
here with the help of friends and
here with the help of friends and police
escort
escort through
escort through traffic.
escort through traffic. Yes.
So
today
today we're
today we're talking
today we're talking about
today we're talking about love.
today we're talking about love. The
first
first eight
today we're talking about love. The
first eight lectures
first eight lectures were
today we're talking about love. The
first eight lectures were really
preparatory
because
because we
preparatory
because we can
because we can talk
preparatory
because we can talk about
because we can talk about the
preparatory
because we can talk about the ego.
because we can talk about the ego. We
can
can describe
can describe it
can describe it first
can describe it first of
can describe it first of all
transcending
transcending duality
can describe it first of all
transcending duality to
transcending duality to non-duality
involves
involves quite
involves quite a
involves quite a deal
involves quite a deal of
involves quite a deal of learning
involves quite a deal of learning in
involves quite a deal of learning in a
way
way and
involves quite a deal of learning in a
way and um
way and um of
involves quite a deal of learning in a
way and um of course
way and um of course we
involves quite a deal of learning in a
way and um of course we can
way and um of course we can get
involves quite a deal of learning in a
way and um of course we can get let
way and um of course we can get let go
of
of that
of that learning
of that learning when
of that learning when the
of that learning when the state
of that learning when the state itself
prevails.
But
But the
But the we've
But the we've tried
But the we've tried to
But the we've tried to cover
But the we've tried to cover the
But the we've tried to cover the main
blocks
blocks to
But the we've tried to cover the main
blocks to love
blocks to love as
But the we've tried to cover the main
blocks to love as the
blocks to love as the ultimate
realization
by
by taking
realization
by taking apart
by taking apart the
realization
by taking apart the ego
by taking apart the ego seeing
realization
by taking apart the ego seeing how
by taking apart the ego seeing how it's
constructed
constructed basically
constructed basically dualistically
constructed basically dualistically due
to
to positionalities.
These
These positionalities
These positionalities are
These positionalities are due
These positionalities are due to
These positionalities are due to common
belief
belief systems
These positionalities are due to common
belief systems which
belief systems which really
These positionalities are due to common
belief systems which really arise
originally
originally from
originally from the
originally from the animal
originally from the animal kingdom.
So
So it's
originally from the animal kingdom.
So it's not
So it's not necessary
originally from the animal kingdom.
So it's not necessary to
So it's not necessary to feel
originally from the animal kingdom.
So it's not necessary to feel guilty
about
about so-called
about so-called having
about so-called having an
about so-called having an ego
about so-called having an ego and
about so-called having an ego and coats
because
because we
about so-called having an ego and coats
because we inherit
because we inherit it
about so-called having an ego and coats
because we inherit it from
because we inherit it from worms
about so-called having an ego and coats
because we inherit it from worms and
birds
birds and
birds and other
birds and other things
birds and other things which
birds and other things which are
inherited
inherited the
birds and other things which are
inherited the brain.
inherited the brain. And
birds and other things which are
inherited the brain. And see
inherited the brain. And see as
birds and other things which are
inherited the brain. And see as the
animal
animal evolves,
animal evolves, as
animal evolves, as consciousness
evolves,
evolves, it
animal evolves, as consciousness
evolves, it first
evolves, it first appears
animal evolves, as consciousness
evolves, it first appears on
evolves, it first appears on the
animal evolves, as consciousness
evolves, it first appears on the planet
as
as animal
to
to the
as animal
to the animal
to the animal is
as animal
to the animal is only
to the animal is only interested
as animal
to the animal is only interested in
survival.
survival. And
survival. And to
survival. And to survival,
survival. And to survival, it
survival. And to survival, it has
survival. And to survival, it has to
find
find its
survival. And to survival, it has to
find its way
find its way around
survival. And to survival, it has to
find its way around in
find its way around in a
survival. And to survival, it has to
find its way around in a physical
domain.
domain. And
domain. And it
domain. And it operates
domain. And it operates out
domain. And it operates out of
domain. And it operates out of a
domain. And it operates out of a this
and
and a
domain. And it operates out of a this
and a that.
and a that. If
domain. And it operates out of a this
and a that. If there's
and a that. If there's a
domain. And it operates out of a this
and a that. If there's a worm
and a that. If there's a worm there
domain. And it operates out of a this
and a that. If there's a worm there and
you're
you're a
you're a bird
you're a bird here,
you're a bird here, you
you're a bird here, you got
you're a bird here, you got to
you're a bird here, you got to gauge
you're a bird here, you got to gauge the
distance
distance between
you're a bird here, you got to gauge the
distance between here
distance between here and
you're a bird here, you got to gauge the
distance between here and the
distance between here and the worm.
Well,
Well, you
Well, you have
Well, you have to
Well, you have to know
Well, you have to know direction,
distance,
distance, timing
and
and the
and the same
and the same mechanisms
and the same mechanisms are
and the same mechanisms are still
inherent
inherent in
and the same mechanisms are still
inherent in our
inherent in our brain.
So
So the
So the origin
So the origin of
So the origin of thinking
So the origin of thinking dualistically
is
is really
So the origin of thinking dualistically
is really within
is really within the
So the origin of thinking dualistically
is really within the animal
is really within the animal domain.
The
origin
origin of
The
origin of the
origin of the feeling
The
origin of the feeling states
origin of the feeling states of
The
origin of the feeling states of the
fields
fields of
fields of consciousness,
fields of consciousness, we
fields of consciousness, we need
fields of consciousness, we need that
one
one up
fields of consciousness, we need that
one up here
one up here somewhere.
um
um are
um are also
um are also in
um are also in the
um are also in the animal
um are also in the animal domain.
um are also in the animal domain. Huh.
They
They all
um are also in the animal domain. Huh.
They all have
They all have to
um are also in the animal domain. Huh.
They all have to do
They all have to do with
um are also in the animal domain. Huh.
They all have to do with survival.
So,
So, we
So, we should
So, we should put
So, we should put this
So, we should put this up
So, we should put this up and
So, we should put this up and make
So, we should put this up and make it
So, we should put this up and make it go
onto
onto the
So, we should put this up and make it go
onto the screen
onto the screen there.
So, we should put this up and make it go
onto the screen there. Huh.
onto the screen there. Huh. Goes
So, we should put this up and make it go
onto the screen there. Huh. Goes on
there
there somehow.
Wow.
Thank
Thank you,
Thank you, Lord.
I
I said
Thank you, Lord.
I said my
I said my functioning
Thank you, Lord.
I said my functioning today
I said my functioning today is
Thank you, Lord.
I said my functioning today is totally
up
up to
up to God
up to God because
up to God because I
up to God because I have
up to God because I have no
up to God because I have no capacity
up to God because I have no capacity to
function
function whatsoever
up to God because I have no capacity to
function whatsoever today.
I
I welcome
I welcome in
I welcome in a
I welcome in a state
I welcome in a state of
I welcome in a state of total
non-functioning
non-functioning and
I welcome in a state of total
non-functioning and therefore
whatever
whatever happens
whatever happens is
whatever happens is I've
whatever happens is I've got
whatever happens is I've got nothing
whatever happens is I've got nothing to
do
do with.
whatever happens is I've got nothing to
do with. So
do with. So I
whatever happens is I've got nothing to
do with. So I will
do with. So I will not
whatever happens is I've got nothing to
do with. So I will not take
do with. So I will not take any
whatever happens is I've got nothing to
do with. So I will not take any blame
for
for anything
for anything that
for anything that happens
for anything that happens here.
The
The most
for anything that happens here.
The most difficult
The most difficult lecture
for anything that happens here.
The most difficult lecture and
The most difficult lecture and I
for anything that happens here.
The most difficult lecture and I don't
know
know if
know if we'll
know if we'll be
know if we'll be able
know if we'll be able to
know if we'll be able to do
know if we'll be able to do it
know if we'll be able to do it or
know if we'll be able to do it or not
but
but we'll
know if we'll be able to do it or not
but we'll attempt
but we'll attempt it.
know if we'll be able to do it or not
but we'll attempt it. So
but we'll attempt it. So today
know if we'll be able to do it or not
but we'll attempt it. So today will
but we'll attempt it. So today will be
an
an experiment
an experiment to
an experiment to see
an experiment to see if
an experiment to see if one
an experiment to see if one can
an experiment to see if one can be
an experiment to see if one can be that
which
which you
an experiment to see if one can be that
which you are
which you are and
an experiment to see if one can be that
which you are and also
which you are and also talk
an experiment to see if one can be that
which you are and also talk about
which you are and also talk about it.
The
The capacity
The capacity to
The capacity to function
The capacity to function in
The capacity to function in the
The capacity to function in the world
for
for many
The capacity to function in the world
for many years
for many years was
The capacity to function in the world
for many years was occasioned
for many years was occasioned by
The capacity to function in the world
for many years was occasioned by first
well
well it
well it didn't
well it didn't I
well it didn't I withdrew
well it didn't I withdrew and
well it didn't I withdrew and avoiding
the
the world
well it didn't I withdrew and avoiding
the world is
the world is how
well it didn't I withdrew and avoiding
the world is how the
the world is how the world
well it didn't I withdrew and avoiding
the world is how the world yeah
the world is how the world yeah by
well it didn't I withdrew and avoiding
the world is how the world yeah by not
going
going there
going there and
going there and um
going there and um returning
going there and um returning to
going there and um returning to a
going there and um returning to a small
town
town then
going there and um returning to a small
town then the
town then the capacity
going there and um returning to a small
town then the capacity to
town then the capacity to function
going there and um returning to a small
town then the capacity to function and
gradually
gradually gradually
gradually gradually returned
by
by some
gradually gradually returned
by some kind
by some kind of
gradually gradually returned
by some kind of intention
by some kind of intention that
gradually gradually returned
by some kind of intention that came
by some kind of intention that came from
elsewhere
and
and the
elsewhere
and the capacity
and the capacity to
elsewhere
and the capacity to function
and the capacity to function in
elsewhere
and the capacity to function in the
world
um
um even
world
um even till
um even till now
world
um even till now is
um even till now is occasioned
world
um even till now is occasioned by
uh
uh humor.
It
It was
uh humor.
It was discovered
It was discovered that
uh humor.
It was discovered that humor
It was discovered that humor would
uh humor.
It was discovered that humor would allow
you
you to
you to relate
you to relate to
you to relate to the
you to relate to the world
you to relate to the world and
you to relate to the world and still
you to relate to the world and still be
in
in that
you to relate to the world and still be
in that inner
in that inner state.
And
And therefore
And therefore my
And therefore my usual
And therefore my usual style
And therefore my usual style socially
has
has to
And therefore my usual style socially
has to do
has to do with
And therefore my usual style socially
has to do with humor
has to do with humor because
And therefore my usual style socially
has to do with humor because the
has to do with humor because the world
is
is an
is an endless
is an endless um
is an endless um comedy
and
and uh
is an endless um comedy
and uh in
and uh in which
is an endless um comedy
and uh in which everything
and uh in which everything gets
converted
converted to
converted to its
converted to its opposite
converted to its opposite totally
confused
confused and
converted to its opposite totally
confused and misrepresented
and
and uh
and uh and
and uh and much
and uh and much habaloo
and uh and much habaloo is
and uh and much habaloo is made
and uh and much habaloo is made about
that
that see
and uh and much habaloo is made about
that see in
that see in which
and uh and much habaloo is made about
that see in which cause
that see in which cause and
and uh and much habaloo is made about
that see in which cause and effect
that see in which cause and effect uh
perpetrator
perpetrator victim
perpetrator victim are
perpetrator victim are totally
perpetrator victim are totally reversed
which
which I'm
perpetrator victim are totally reversed
which I'm describing
which I'm describing in
perpetrator victim are totally reversed
which I'm describing in the
which I'm describing in the book
perpetrator victim are totally reversed
which I'm describing in the book I
which I'm describing in the book I the
impact
impact of
impact of the
impact of the luciferic.
impact of the luciferic. Everybody's
concerned
concerned about
impact of the luciferic. Everybody's
concerned about the
concerned about the impact
impact of the luciferic. Everybody's
concerned about the impact of
concerned about the impact of the
satanic
satanic war,
satanic war, rape,
satanic war, rape, killing,
satanic war, rape, killing, murder,
blood,
blood, and
satanic war, rape, killing, murder,
blood, and grime
blood, and grime and
satanic war, rape, killing, murder,
blood, and grime and stuff
blood, and grime and stuff like
satanic war, rape, killing, murder,
blood, and grime and stuff like that.
More
More subtle
More subtle and
More subtle and more
More subtle and more powerful
More subtle and more powerful really
More subtle and more powerful really as
luciferic,
luciferic, which
More subtle and more powerful really as
luciferic, which distorts
and
and reverses
and reverses uh
and reverses uh things
and reverses uh things in
and reverses uh things in such
and reverses uh things in such a
and reverses uh things in such a way
and reverses uh things in such a way as
to
to confuse
and reverses uh things in such a way as
to confuse reality
to confuse reality so
and reverses uh things in such a way as
to confuse reality so you
to confuse reality so you can't
and reverses uh things in such a way as
to confuse reality so you can't see
reality
reality anymore.
reality anymore. It's
reality anymore. It's the
reality anymore. It's the luciferic
reality anymore. It's the luciferic that
opens
opens the
reality anymore. It's the luciferic that
opens the door
opens the door to
reality anymore. It's the luciferic that
opens the door to the
opens the door to the satanic.
reality anymore. It's the luciferic that
opens the door to the satanic. That's
how
how war
how war comes
how war comes about.
how war comes about. First,
how war comes about. First, you
how war comes about. First, you have
how war comes about. First, you have to
confuse
confuse the
how war comes about. First, you have to
confuse the people
confuse the people as
how war comes about. First, you have to
confuse the people as to
confuse the people as to who's
how war comes about. First, you have to
confuse the people as to who's the
perpetrator
perpetrator and
perpetrator and who's
perpetrator and who's the
perpetrator and who's the victim.
And
And that
perpetrator and who's the victim.
And that opens
And that opens the
perpetrator and who's the victim.
And that opens the door.
And
And then
And then through
And then through the
And then through the door
And then through the door comes
And then through the door comes the
satanic
satanic with
And then through the door comes the
satanic with its
satanic with its guns
And then through the door comes the
satanic with its guns and
satanic with its guns and its
And then through the door comes the
satanic with its guns and its murder
satanic with its guns and its murder and
it's
it's killing.
it's killing. And
it's killing. And but
it's killing. And but first
it's killing. And but first you
it's killing. And but first you have
it's killing. And but first you have to
repair
repair the
it's killing. And but first you have to
repair the few
repair the few with
it's killing. And but first you have to
repair the few with a
repair the few with a luciferic.
One
One of
One of the
One of the um
One of the um purposes
One of the um purposes luciferic
One of the um purposes luciferic is
One of the um purposes luciferic is it's
very
very profitable.
That's
That's why
deep
deep pockets
That's why
deep pockets are
deep pockets are traditionally
That's why
deep pockets are traditionally demonized
in
in our
in our society.
Eat
Eat too
in our society.
Eat too many
Eat too many hamburgers.
in our society.
Eat too many hamburgers. It's
Eat too many hamburgers. It's their
fault
fault they
fault they sold
fault they sold them
fault they sold them to
fault they sold them to you.
I'm
I'm overweight.
fault they sold them to you.
I'm overweight. I
I'm overweight. I mean,
fault they sold them to you.
I'm overweight. I mean, you
I'm overweight. I mean, you see
fault they sold them to you.
I'm overweight. I mean, you see the
perpetrator
perpetrator and
perpetrator and the
perpetrator and the victim.
perpetrator and the victim. Yeah.
perpetrator and the victim. Yeah. The
perpetrator
perpetrator is
perpetrator and the victim. Yeah. The
perpetrator is really
perpetrator is really the
perpetrator and the victim. Yeah. The
perpetrator is really the guy
perpetrator is really the guy who
perpetrator and the victim. Yeah. The
perpetrator is really the guy who eats
too
too much
too much and
too much and the
too much and the victim
too much and the victim is
too much and the victim is really
too much and the victim is really But
now
now we're
too much and the victim is really But
now we're going
now we're going to
too much and the victim is really But
now we're going to turn
now we're going to turn around.
too much and the victim is really But
now we're going to turn around. See,
now we're going to turn around. See, so
you
you see
you see that
you see that happening
you see that happening all
you see that happening all the
you see that happening all the time
you see that happening all the time with
war.
war. You
you see that happening all the time with
war. You see
war. You see that
you see that happening all the time with
war. You see that war
war. You see that war is
you see that happening all the time with
war. You see that war is always
war. You see that war is always preceded
by
by the
by the luciferic
by the luciferic distortion
by the luciferic distortion that
by the luciferic distortion that Oh,
those
those guys
by the luciferic distortion that Oh,
those guys aren't
those guys aren't that
by the luciferic distortion that Oh,
those guys aren't that bad.
those guys aren't that bad. We
by the luciferic distortion that Oh,
those guys aren't that bad. We don't
have
have to
have to make
have to make any
have to make any preparation
have to make any preparation for
have to make any preparation for it.
They
They aren't
have to make any preparation for it.
They aren't that
They aren't that bad.
Yeah,
Yeah, right.
Yeah, right. They
Yeah, right. They aren't
Yeah, right. They aren't that
Yeah, right. They aren't that bad.
That
That cost
Yeah, right. They aren't that bad.
That cost 70
That cost 70 million
Yeah, right. They aren't that bad.
That cost 70 million people
That cost 70 million people in
Yeah, right. They aren't that bad.
That cost 70 million people in World
That cost 70 million people in World War
II.
II. 70
II. 70 million
II. 70 million people.
II. 70 million people. They
II. 70 million people. They aren't
II. 70 million people. They aren't that
bad.
bad. No,
II. 70 million people. They aren't that
bad. No, sir.
Well,
Well, they
Well, they were.
Well, they were. So
Well, they were. So the
Well, they were. So the denial
Well, they were. So the denial you
Well, they were. So the denial you know
and
and the
Well, they were. So the denial you know
and the reversal
and the reversal of
Well, they were. So the denial you know
and the reversal of so
and the reversal of so therefore
Well, they were. So the denial you know
and the reversal of so therefore the
world
world is
world is an
world is an endless
world is an endless comedy
world is an endless comedy and
world is an endless comedy and if
world is an endless comedy and if you
can
can stay
world is an endless comedy and if you
can stay in
can stay in the
world is an endless comedy and if you
can stay in the comedy
can stay in the comedy of
world is an endless comedy and if you
can stay in the comedy of it
can stay in the comedy of it you
world is an endless comedy and if you
can stay in the comedy of it you can
still
still be
still be in
still be in very
still be in very good
still be in very good place
still be in very good place within
yourself
yourself and
still be in very good place within
yourself and still
yourself and still function
still be in very good place within
yourself and still function within
yourself and still function within the
world.
The
The pathway
world.
The pathway of
The pathway of the
world.
The pathway of the heart
The pathway of the heart of
world.
The pathway of the heart of course
The pathway of the heart of course is
one
one of
one of the
one of the great
one of the great traditions.
one of the great traditions. What
one of the great traditions. What we've
been
been talking
one of the great traditions. What we've
been talking about
been talking about up
one of the great traditions. What we've
been talking about up to
been talking about up to now
one of the great traditions. What we've
been talking about up to now is
primarily
primarily the
primarily the pathways
primarily the pathways through
uh
uh non-duality.
The
The pathways
The pathways through
The pathways through non-duality.
The pathways through non-duality. We've
been
been talking
The pathways through non-duality. We've
been talking in
been talking in terms
The pathways through non-duality. We've
been talking in terms that
been talking in terms that are
The pathways through non-duality. We've
been talking in terms that are familiar
to
to students
to students of
to students of Zen
to students of Zen and
to students of Zen and Buddhism
to students of Zen and Buddhism and
traditionally
traditionally non-duality.
And
And the
And the pathway
And the pathway of
And the pathway of devotion
And the pathway of devotion through
And the pathway of devotion through the
heart
heart takes
And the pathway of devotion through the
heart takes the
heart takes the form
And the pathway of devotion through the
heart takes the form of
karma
karma yoga
karma yoga devoting
karma yoga devoting all
karma yoga devoting all one's
karma yoga devoting all one's actions
karma yoga devoting all one's actions to
God
God and
karma yoga devoting all one's actions to
God and devotion
God and devotion in
karma yoga devoting all one's actions to
God and devotion in which
God and devotion in which Christianity
probably
probably p
probably p is
probably p is the
probably p is the most
probably p is the most prominent
probably p is the most prominent in
probably p is the most prominent in the
world
world today
prominent
prominent teacher
prominent teacher traditionally
prominent teacher traditionally of
prominent teacher traditionally of the
way
way of
prominent teacher traditionally of the
way of the
way of the heart
prominent teacher traditionally of the
way of the heart and
way of the heart and mother
prominent teacher traditionally of the
way of the heart and mother Teresa
way of the heart and mother Teresa would
be
be let
be let us
be let us say
be let us say an
be let us say an example
be let us say an example example
be let us say an example example of
be let us say an example example of the
unconditional
unconditional love.
There's
There's many
There's many um
There's many um programs
There's many um programs available
There's many um programs available to
everyone
uh
uh of
uh of which
uh of which uh
uh of which uh the
uh of which uh the 12step
uh of which uh the 12step programs
uh of which uh the 12step programs uh
the
the course
uh of which uh the 12step programs uh
the course of
the course of miracles
uh of which uh the 12step programs uh
the course of miracles and
the course of miracles and these
uh of which uh the 12step programs uh
the course of miracles and these are
the course of miracles and these are all
the
the all
the all pathways
the all pathways of
the all pathways of love.
the all pathways of love. These
the all pathways of love. These are
the all pathways of love. These are all
the
the pathways
the all pathways of love. These are all
the pathways of
the pathways of love.
The
The willingness
The willingness to
The willingness to forgive
The willingness to forgive and
The willingness to forgive and forget.
Let
Let bygones
The willingness to forgive and forget.
Let bygones be
Let bygones be bygones.
And
And then
And then the
And then the course
And then the course of
And then the course of miracles
And then the course of miracles takes
you
you even
And then the course of miracles takes
you even beyond
you even beyond that.
And then the course of miracles takes
you even beyond that. So
you even beyond that. So the
And then the course of miracles takes
you even beyond that. So the 12step
programs
programs take
programs take you
programs take you to
programs take you to unconditional
programs take you to unconditional love
which
which is
programs take you to unconditional love
which is the
which is the ultimate
programs take you to unconditional love
which is the ultimate aim
which is the ultimate aim of
Christianity.
Um
taught
taught by
taught by Jesus
taught by Jesus Christ
taught by Jesus Christ to
taught by Jesus Christ to love
taught by Jesus Christ to love your
enemy
enemy as
taught by Jesus Christ to love your
enemy as yourself
enemy as yourself to
taught by Jesus Christ to love your
enemy as yourself to forgive
enemy as yourself to forgive them.
Unconditional
Unconditional love
Unconditional love towards
Unconditional love towards all
Unconditional love towards all that
exists
calibrates
calibrates at
calibrates at 540.
Traditionally,
Traditionally, if
calibrates at 540.
Traditionally, if you
Traditionally, if you get
calibrates at 540.
Traditionally, if you get to
Traditionally, if you get to love,
calibrates at 540.
Traditionally, if you get to love, you
don't
don't have
don't have to
don't have to worry
don't have to worry because
don't have to worry because as
don't have to worry because as you
don't have to worry because as you leave
the
the body,
don't have to worry because as you leave
the body, you
the body, you will
don't have to worry because as you leave
the body, you will go
the body, you will go to
don't have to worry because as you leave
the body, you will go to that
the body, you will go to that which
don't have to worry because as you leave
the body, you will go to that which you
are,
are, which
are, which is
are, which is lovingness
are, which is lovingness in
are, which is lovingness in a
are, which is lovingness in a heavenly
state.
How
How to
How to arrive
How to arrive at
How to arrive at those
How to arrive at those stages?
So
So the
How to arrive at those stages?
So the first
So the first lectures
How to arrive at those stages?
So the first lectures we
So the first lectures we gave
How to arrive at those stages?
So the first lectures we gave were
trying
trying to
trying to take
trying to take apart
trying to take apart the
trying to take apart the obstructions
trying to take apart the obstructions to
love
love so
trying to take apart the obstructions to
love so that
love so that once
trying to take apart the obstructions to
love so that once you
love so that once you remove
trying to take apart the obstructions to
love so that once you remove their
underpinnings
underpinnings when
underpinnings when they
underpinnings when they come
underpinnings when they come up
underpinnings when they come up as
underpinnings when they come up as an
obstacle,
obstacle, they're
underpinnings when they come up as an
obstacle, they're much
obstacle, they're much easier
underpinnings when they come up as an
obstacle, they're much easier to
obstacle, they're much easier to let
underpinnings when they come up as an
obstacle, they're much easier to let go
of
of because
of because you
of because you realize
of because you realize that
what
what you're
of because you realize that
what you're talking
what you're talking about
of because you realize that
what you're talking about in
what you're talking about in these
obstacles
obstacles to
obstacles to love
obstacles to love are
obstacles to love are always
perceptions.
perceptions. How
obstacles to love are always
perceptions. How you
perceptions. How you perceive
obstacles to love are always
perceptions. How you perceive something.
So
So if
So if we
So if we see
So if we see how
So if we see how the
So if we see how the ego
So if we see how the ego puts
So if we see how the ego puts together
perception,
perception, we
So if we see how the ego puts together
perception, we can
perception, we can disassemble
So if we see how the ego puts together
perception, we can disassemble it
perception, we can disassemble it when
that
that block
that block comes
that block comes up
and
and you
that block comes up
and you realize
and you realize for
that block comes up
and you realize for instance
all
all the
all the pathways
all the pathways of
all the pathways of love
all the pathways of love talk
all the pathways of love talk about
forgiveness
forgiveness but
all the pathways of love talk about
forgiveness but forgiveness
forgiveness but forgiveness truly
all the pathways of love talk about
forgiveness but forgiveness truly is
forgiveness but forgiveness truly is not
possible
possible if
possible if you
possible if you continue
possible if you continue to
possible if you continue to see
possible if you continue to see somebody
as
as bad,
possible if you continue to see somebody
as bad, evil,
as bad, evil, wicked
uh
uh at
uh at fault.
It's
It's only
uh at fault.
It's only when
It's only when you
uh at fault.
It's only when you can
It's only when you can remove
uh at fault.
It's only when you can remove your
It's only when you can remove your own
projections
projections and
projections and your
projections and your own
projections and your own perceptions
and
and not
projections and your own perceptions
and not label
and not label them
projections and your own perceptions
and not label them as
and not label them as anything
projections and your own perceptions
and not label them as anything that
and not label them as anything that you
realize
realize that
realize that basically
realize that basically they
realize that basically they are
realize that basically they are innocent
that
that they
realize that basically they are innocent
that they don't
that they don't know
realize that basically they are innocent
that they don't know any
that they don't know any better.
realize that basically they are innocent
that they don't know any better. So
that they don't know any better. So that
way
way you
way you can
way you can stop
way you can stop hating
way you can stop hating them.
way you can stop hating them. You
way you can stop hating them. You can
forgive
forgive them
way you can stop hating them. You can
forgive them for
forgive them for not
way you can stop hating them. You can
forgive them for not knowing
forgive them for not knowing them.
way you can stop hating them. You can
forgive them for not knowing them. So
forgiveness
forgiveness is
forgiveness is not
forgiveness is not really
forgiveness is not really possible
forgiveness is not really possible until
really
really you
forgiveness is not really possible until
really you know
really you know a
forgiveness is not really possible until
really you know a certain
really you know a certain degree
forgiveness is not really possible until
really you know a certain degree you
transcend
um
um dualistic
transcend
um dualistic perception
um dualistic perception which
transcend
um dualistic perception which labels
everything
everything as
everything as good
everything as good and
everything as good and bad
everything as good and bad deserving
everything as good and bad deserving and
undeserving
etc.
So
So the
etc.
So the doorway
So the doorway to
etc.
So the doorway to unconditional
lovingness
lovingness is
lovingness is sort
lovingness is sort of
lovingness is sort of the
lovingness is sort of the dawning
lovingness is sort of the dawning on
lovingness is sort of the dawning on you
that
that everything
lovingness is sort of the dawning on you
that everything is
that everything is innocent.
lovingness is sort of the dawning on you
that everything is innocent. Everything
is
is innocent.
is innocent. Some
is innocent. Some are
is innocent. Some are conscious,
is innocent. Some are conscious, some
are
are not
is innocent. Some are conscious, some
are not conscious.
are not conscious. That's
is innocent. Some are conscious, some
are not conscious. That's the
difference.
Unconscious
Unconscious innocence
difference.
Unconscious innocence will
Unconscious innocence will kill
difference.
Unconscious innocence will kill you
Unconscious innocence will kill you in
the
the name
the name of
the name of Allah
and
and unconscious
the name of Allah
and unconscious innocence
will
will kill
Islamics
Islamics for
will kill
Islamics for Jesus.
Islamics for Jesus. And
will kill
Islamics for Jesus. And I
Islamics for Jesus. And I told
will kill
Islamics for Jesus. And I told you
Islamics for Jesus. And I told you about
the
the lifetime
the lifetime where
the lifetime where I
the lifetime where I killed
the lifetime where I killed killed
the lifetime where I killed killed uh
the lifetime where I killed killed uh we
were
were both
the lifetime where I killed killed uh we
were both crusaders.
were both crusaders. And
the lifetime where I killed killed uh we
were both crusaders. And uh
were both crusaders. And uh he
the lifetime where I killed killed uh we
were both crusaders. And uh he was
were both crusaders. And uh he was there
for
for Allah
for Allah and
for Allah and I
for Allah and I was
for Allah and I was there
for Allah and I was there for
for Allah and I was there for Jesus.
And
And uh
for Allah and I was there for Jesus.
And uh as
And uh as we
for Allah and I was there for Jesus.
And uh as we killed
And uh as we killed each
for Allah and I was there for Jesus.
And uh as we killed each other
And uh as we killed each other in
for Allah and I was there for Jesus.
And uh as we killed each other in a
mackerel,
we
we went
mackerel,
we went out
we went out of
mackerel,
we went out of body
we went out of body and
mackerel,
we went out of body and both
we went out of body and both burst
mackerel,
we went out of body and both burst into
hysteria.
hysteria. It
hysteria. It was
hysteria. It was so
hysteria. It was so funny.
hysteria. It was so funny. It
hysteria. It was so funny. It was
hysterical.
I'll
I'll never
I'll never forget
I'll never forget it.
I'll never forget it. I
I'll never forget it. I said,
I'll never forget it. I said, "Jesus,
I'll never forget it. I said, "Jesus, I
did
did it
I'll never forget it. I said, "Jesus, I
did it for
did it for Jesus."
I'll never forget it. I said, "Jesus, I
did it for Jesus." He
did it for Jesus." He said, "I
I'll never forget it. I said, "Jesus, I
did it for Jesus." He said, "I did
did it for Jesus." He said, "I did it
for
for Allah.
Well,
Well, it
for Allah.
Well, it was
Well, it was an
for Allah.
Well, it was an important
Well, it was an important point.
for Allah.
Well, it was an important point. We
Well, it was an important point. We both
knew
knew it
knew it too
knew it too that
knew it too that we
knew it too that we transcended
knew it too that we transcended a
knew it too that we transcended a really
max
uh
uh point
uh point of
uh point of the
uh point of the evolution
uh point of the evolution of
consciousness.
consciousness. So,
uh point of the evolution of
consciousness. So, uh
consciousness. So, uh periodically
throughout
throughout time
throughout time we've
throughout time we've been
throughout time we've been buddies.
throughout time we've been buddies. You
know,
know, when
throughout time we've been buddies. You
know, when he
know, when he needs
throughout time we've been buddies. You
know, when he needs somebody
know, when he needs somebody to
throughout time we've been buddies. You
know, when he needs somebody to kill
know, when he needs somebody to kill me
or
or I
or I need
or I need somebody
or I need somebody to
or I need somebody to kill,
or I need somebody to kill, he
volunteers
volunteers and
or I need somebody to kill, he
volunteers and we
volunteers and we do
or I need somebody to kill, he
volunteers and we do each
volunteers and we do each other
or I need somebody to kill, he
volunteers and we do each other in
volunteers and we do each other in and
transcend
transcend that
transcend that level.
So,
So, that's
transcend that level.
So, that's love
So, that's love of
transcend that level.
So, that's love of the
So, that's love of the highest
transcend that level.
So, that's love of the highest kind.
If
If it
If it helps
If it helps you
If it helps you reach
If it helps you reach enlightenment,
of
of course,
If it helps you reach enlightenment,
of course, you
of course, you can't
If it helps you reach enlightenment,
of course, you can't do
of course, you can't do it
If it helps you reach enlightenment,
of course, you can't do it that
of course, you can't do it that way,
you've
you've got
you've got to
you've got to give
you've got to give them
you've got to give them a
you've got to give them a fierce
you've got to give them a fierce fight
or
or it's
you've got to give them a fierce fight
or it's not
or it's not real.
you've got to give them a fierce fight
or it's not real. So,
or it's not real. So, within
you've got to give them a fierce fight
or it's not real. So, within this
or it's not real. So, within this world,
you
you see,
you see, all
you see, all those
you see, all those things
you see, all those things to
you see, all those things to us
you see, all those things to us are
very,
very, very
you see, all those things to us are
very, very real.
very, very real. And
you see, all those things to us are
very, very real. And if
very, very real. And if they're
you see, all those things to us are
very, very real. And if they're not
very,
very, very
very, very real.
very, very real. Cuz
very, very real. Cuz if
very, very real. Cuz if you
very, very real. Cuz if you realize
very, very real. Cuz if you realize this
is
is a
very, very real. Cuz if you realize this
is a game
is a game board,
very, very real. Cuz if you realize this
is a game board, it's
is a game board, it's not
very, very real. Cuz if you realize this
is a game board, it's not very
is a game board, it's not very real
very, very real. Cuz if you realize this
is a game board, it's not very real to
you
you anymore.
you anymore. And
you anymore. And you
you anymore. And you can't
you anymore. And you can't get
you anymore. And you can't get the
lesson
lesson out
you anymore. And you can't get the
lesson out of
lesson out of it
you anymore. And you can't get the
lesson out of it that
lesson out of it that you
you anymore. And you can't get the
lesson out of it that you were
lesson out of it that you were seeking.
You've
You've got
You've got to
You've got to actually
You've got to actually be
You've got to actually be terrified
You've got to actually be terrified of
death
death in
You've got to actually be terrified of
death in order
death in order to
You've got to actually be terrified of
death in order to walk
death in order to walk through
You've got to actually be terrified of
death in order to walk through death.
Once
Once you
Once you realize
Once you realize it's
Once you realize it's a
Once you realize it's a game,
Once you realize it's a game, you
Once you realize it's a game, you can't
do
do that
Once you realize it's a game, you can't
do that anymore.
All
All right.
So,
So, we're
All right.
So, we're going
So, we're going to
All right.
So, we're going to talk
So, we're going to talk about
All right.
So, we're going to talk about love
So, we're going to talk about love to
the
the degree
the degree that
the degree that we're
the degree that we're able
the degree that we're able to
the degree that we're able to talk
the degree that we're able to talk about
love
love today.
the degree that we're able to talk about
love today. And
love today. And if
the degree that we're able to talk about
love today. And if love
love today. And if love takes
the degree that we're able to talk about
love today. And if love takes over,
love today. And if love takes over, we
may
may or
may or may
may or may not
may or may not continue
may or may not continue talking
may or may not continue talking about
love.
As
As those
As those states,
As those states, it's
As those states, it's best
As those states, it's best to
As those states, it's best to have
As those states, it's best to have close
friends
friends around
As those states, it's best to have close
friends around you
friends around you if
As those states, it's best to have close
friends around you if you're
friends around you if you're really
going
going into
going into spiritual
going into spiritual work.
going into spiritual work. Seriously,
it's
it's advisable
going into spiritual work. Seriously,
it's advisable to
it's advisable to have
going into spiritual work. Seriously,
it's advisable to have family,
it's advisable to have family, friends,
be
be in
be in an
be in an ashramm
be in an ashramm or
be in an ashramm or at least
be in an ashramm or at least have
spiritual
spiritual friends
be in an ashramm or at least have
spiritual friends who
spiritual friends who are
be in an ashramm or at least have
spiritual friends who are able
spiritual friends who are able to
be in an ashramm or at least have
spiritual friends who are able to be
spiritual friends who are able to be of
assistance
assistance should
assistance should you
assistance should you become
incapacitated,
incapacitated, which
assistance should you become
incapacitated, which is
incapacitated, which is quite
assistance should you become
incapacitated, which is quite possible.
Yeah.
And
And uh
Yeah.
And uh sometimes
And uh sometimes you
Yeah.
And uh sometimes you don't
And uh sometimes you don't know
Yeah.
And uh sometimes you don't know how
you're
you're going
you're going to
you're going to get
you're going to get here,
you're going to get here, but
you're going to get here, but your
friends
friends put
you're going to get here, but your
friends put you
friends put you in
you're going to get here, but your
friends put you in a
friends put you in a car
you're going to get here, but your
friends put you in a car and
friends put you in a car and they
you're going to get here, but your
friends put you in a car and they put
coffee
coffee in
coffee in your
coffee in your hand
coffee in your hand and
coffee in your hand and they
coffee in your hand and they drive
coffee in your hand and they drive you
here.
here. So
coffee in your hand and they drive you
here. So that's
here. So that's how
coffee in your hand and they drive you
here. So that's how you
here. So that's how you get
coffee in your hand and they drive you
here. So that's how you get here.
here. So that's how you get here. And
then
then Nico
then Nico meets
then Nico meets you
then Nico meets you at
then Nico meets you at the
then Nico meets you at the door.
then Nico meets you at the door. It's
better
better to
then Nico meets you at the door. It's
better to have
better to have somebody
then Nico meets you at the door. It's
better to have somebody at least
better to have somebody at least over
200 lb
200 lb who
200 lb who weighs
200 lb who weighs through
200 lb who weighs through the
200 lb who weighs through the crowd.
200 lb who weighs through the crowd. So
assistance
assistance appears
200 lb who weighs through the crowd. So
assistance appears magically
assistance appears magically uh
200 lb who weighs through the crowd. So
assistance appears magically uh you
know.
know. All right.
know. All right. So
know. All right. So we're
know. All right. So we're going
know. All right. So we're going to
know. All right. So we're going to talk
about
about the
know. All right. So we're going to talk
about the various
about the various understandings
know. All right. So we're going to talk
about the various understandings of
about the various understandings of love
and
and the
and the various
and the various reflections
and the various reflections of
and the various reflections of love
because
because most
and the various reflections of love
because most people
because most people are
and the various reflections of love
because most people are more
because most people are more loving
and the various reflections of love
because most people are more loving in
more
more ways
more ways than
more ways than they
more ways than they realize.
Uh
Uh they're
more ways than they realize.
Uh they're unconscious
Uh they're unconscious of
more ways than they realize.
Uh they're unconscious of it.
Uh they're unconscious of it. This
more ways than they realize.
Uh they're unconscious of it. This the
other
other day
other day somebody
I
I was
other day somebody
I was polishing.
I was polishing. There
other day somebody
I was polishing. There was
I was polishing. There was this
other day somebody
I was polishing. There was this chrome
around
around the
around the top
around the top of
around the top of the
around the top of the stove
around the top of the stove and
around the top of the stove and it
around the top of the stove and it was
clean
clean but
around the top of the stove and it was
clean but not
clean but not really
around the top of the stove and it was
clean but not really shiny.
clean but not really shiny. So
around the top of the stove and it was
clean but not really shiny. So I
clean but not really shiny. So I took
around the top of the stove and it was
clean but not really shiny. So I took a
steel
steel wool
steel wool and
steel wool and I
steel wool and I started
steel wool and I started scrubbing
steel wool and I started scrubbing it
like
like that
steel wool and I started scrubbing it
like that and
like that and then
steel wool and I started scrubbing it
like that and then it
like that and then it shown
steel wool and I started scrubbing it
like that and then it shown like
like that and then it shown like that
and
and I
and I said
and I said now
and I said now you
and I said now you see
and I said now you see it
and I said now you see it shines
and I said now you see it shines with
love.
So
So love
So love takes
So love takes many
So love takes many forms
So love takes many forms doesn't
So love takes many forms doesn't it?
Duty
Duty uh
So love takes many forms doesn't it?
Duty uh commitment
Duty uh commitment uh
So love takes many forms doesn't it?
Duty uh commitment uh caringness
Duty uh commitment uh caringness about
everything.
Yeah.
Yeah. I
everything.
Yeah. I know.
Yeah. I know. Love
everything.
Yeah. I know. Love for
Yeah. I know. Love for your
everything.
Yeah. I know. Love for your body.
Yeah. I know. Love for your body. You
know,
know, you've
know, you've got
know, you've got to
know, you've got to love
know, you've got to love this
know, you've got to love this thing.
know, you've got to love this thing. And
uh
uh if
know, you've got to love this thing. And
uh if you
uh if you don't,
know, you've got to love this thing. And
uh if you don't, your
uh if you don't, your wife
know, you've got to love this thing. And
uh if you don't, your wife complains
bitterly
bitterly that
bitterly that you
bitterly that you don't
bitterly that you don't look
bitterly that you don't look nice.
bitterly that you don't look nice. So,
if
if you
bitterly that you don't look nice. So,
if you fail
if you fail it,
bitterly that you don't look nice. So,
if you fail it, somebody
if you fail it, somebody will
bitterly that you don't look nice. So,
if you fail it, somebody will remind
if you fail it, somebody will remind you
to
to feed
to feed it
to feed it and
to feed it and all
to feed it and all the
to feed it and all the things
to feed it and all the things that
necessarily
necessarily go
to feed it and all the things that
necessarily go with
necessarily go with it.
So,
So, love
So, love takes
So, love takes many
So, love takes many many
So, love takes many many expressions.
So, love takes many many expressions. It
takes
takes the
So, love takes many many expressions. It
takes the form
takes the form of
So, love takes many many expressions. It
takes the form of caringness.
See,
See, we
See, we we
See, we we look
See, we we look at
See, we we look at love
See, we we look at love as
See, we we look at love as some
See, we we look at love as some maybe
advanced
advanced state
See, we we look at love as some maybe
advanced state and
advanced state and oh,
See, we we look at love as some maybe
advanced state and oh, we're
advanced state and oh, we're not
See, we we look at love as some maybe
advanced state and oh, we're not there
yet.
yet. No,
yet. No, that's
yet. No, that's not
yet. No, that's not so
yet. No, that's not so love
yet. No, that's not so love is
yet. No, that's not so love is constant
in
in our
yet. No, that's not so love is constant
in our life.
in our life. See,
yet. No, that's not so love is constant
in our life. See, because
in our life. See, because nobody
yet. No, that's not so love is constant
in our life. See, because nobody is
completely
completely at
completely at one
completely at one level
completely at one level or
completely at one level or another.
completely at one level or another. See,
let's
let's you
completely at one level or another. See,
let's you say,
let's you say, well,
completely at one level or another. See,
let's you say, well, this
let's you say, well, this guy's
completely at one level or another. See,
let's you say, well, this guy's at
let's you say, well, this guy's at 125,
so
so he
so he can't
so he can't know
so he can't know what
so he can't know what this
so he can't know what this is
so he can't know what this is like.
so he can't know what this is like. No,
certain
certain aspects
so he can't know what this is like. No,
certain aspects of
certain aspects of them
so he can't know what this is like. No,
certain aspects of them do.
certain aspects of them do. And
so he can't know what this is like. No,
certain aspects of them do. And and
those
those aspects
those aspects show
those aspects show up
those aspects show up in
those aspects show up in certain
those aspects show up in certain aspects
of
of life.
those aspects show up in certain aspects
of life. So,
of life. So, we
those aspects show up in certain aspects
of life. So, we begin
of life. So, we begin to
those aspects show up in certain aspects
of life. So, we begin to nurture
of life. So, we begin to nurture those
aspects
aspects and
aspects and appreciate
aspects and appreciate those
aspects and appreciate those aspects
aspects and appreciate those aspects of
life.
And
And which
And which is
And which is love
And which is love is
And which is love is taking
And which is love is taking a
And which is love is taking a form
And which is love is taking a form not
usually
usually labeled
And which is love is taking a form not
usually labeled at
usually labeled at love.
And which is love is taking a form not
usually labeled at love. You
usually labeled at love. You see
And which is love is taking a form not
usually labeled at love. You see in
usually labeled at love. You see in our
world
world love
world love you
world love you know
world love you know denotes
world love you know denotes romance.
Denotes
Denotes here
world love you know denotes romance.
Denotes here and
Denotes here and there.
world love you know denotes romance.
Denotes here and there. Denotes
Denotes here and there. Denotes a
world love you know denotes romance.
Denotes here and there. Denotes a me
loving
loving you
loving you and
loving you and a
loving you and a you
loving you and a you loving
loving you and a you loving me.
And
And that
loving you and a you loving me.
And that kind
And that kind of
loving you and a you loving me.
And that kind of love
And that kind of love can
loving you and a you loving me.
And that kind of love can be
And that kind of love can be lost.
loving you and a you loving me.
And that kind of love can be lost. It
can
can be
can be won
can be won or
can be won or gained
can be won or gained or
can be won or gained or lost
can be won or gained or lost or
can be won or gained or lost or taken
away
away from
can be won or gained or lost or taken
away from you.
away from you. And
can be won or gained or lost or taken
away from you. And so
away from you. And so that's
can be won or gained or lost or taken
away from you. And so that's a
away from you. And so that's a different
kind
kind of
kind of love
kind of love than
kind of love than spiritual
kind of love than spiritual love,
kind of love than spiritual love, which
is
is the
kind of love than spiritual love, which
is the awareness
is the awareness of
a
a reality
a reality that
a reality that is
a reality that is within
a reality that is within you
a reality that is within you at
a reality that is within you at all
times.
So
So in
So in reality,
So in reality, love
So in reality, love is
So in reality, love is a
So in reality, love is a way
So in reality, love is a way of
So in reality, love is a way of being
So in reality, love is a way of being in
the
the world.
So in reality, love is a way of being in
the world. Love
the world. Love is
So in reality, love is a way of being in
the world. Love is actually
the world. Love is actually a
So in reality, love is a way of being in
the world. Love is actually a style,
the world. Love is actually a style, a
way
way of
way of being.
way of being. It's
way of being. It's a
way of being. It's a way
way of being. It's a way of
way of being. It's a way of holding
yourself
yourself and
way of being. It's a way of holding
yourself and life
yourself and life and
way of being. It's a way of holding
yourself and life and every
yourself and life and every aspect
way of being. It's a way of holding
yourself and life and every aspect of
life
life within
life within an
life within an overall
life within an overall context.
life within an overall context. And
life within an overall context. And that
overall
overall context
life within an overall context. And that
overall context gives
overall context gives it
life within an overall context. And that
overall context gives it a
overall context gives it a different
meaning,
meaning, significance,
a
a different
meaning, significance,
a different appearance.
a different appearance. Huh?
It
It is
It is just
It is just as
It is just as important
It is just as important to
It is just as important to polish
It is just as important to polish the
chromium
as
as it
as it is
as it is to
as it is to save
as it is to save the
as it is to save the life
as it is to save the life of
as it is to save the life of somebody
dying
dying by
as it is to save the life of somebody
dying by the
dying by the side
as it is to save the life of somebody
dying by the side of
dying by the side of the
as it is to save the life of somebody
dying by the side of the street.
dying by the side of the street. You
understand?
understand? It's
understand? It's just
understand? It's just that
understand? It's just that capacity
takes
takes this
understand? It's just that capacity
takes this form
takes this form here.
understand? It's just that capacity
takes this form here. It
takes this form here. It turns
understand? It's just that capacity
takes this form here. It turns over
takes this form here. It turns over the
beetle
beetle that's
beetle that's on
beetle that's on its
beetle that's on its back
beetle that's on its back here.
beetle that's on its back here. Here
beetle that's on its back here. Here it
saves
saves somebody
beetle that's on its back here. Here it
saves somebody who's
saves somebody who's leading
beetle that's on its back here. Here it
saves somebody who's leading by
saves somebody who's leading by the
beetle that's on its back here. Here it
saves somebody who's leading by the side
of
of the
of the street
of the street and
of the street and calls
of the street and calls 911.
And
And here
of the street and calls 911.
And here it
And here it helps
of the street and calls 911.
And here it helps you
And here it helps you in
of the street and calls 911.
And here it helps you in the
And here it helps you in the door
of the street and calls 911.
And here it helps you in the door so
And here it helps you in the door so you
can
can get
can get through.
can get through. You
can get through. You see
can get through. You see what
can get through. You see what I'm
saying?
saying? So
can get through. You see what I'm
saying? So it's
saying? So it's that
can get through. You see what I'm
saying? So it's that it's
saying? So it's that it's that
can get through. You see what I'm
saying? So it's that it's that capacity,
that
that willingness
that willingness to
that willingness to be
that willingness to be that
that willingness to be that to
that willingness to be that to the
world.
One
One has
One has no
One has no idea
One has no idea of
One has no idea of how
One has no idea of how that
One has no idea of how that is
One has no idea of how that is going
One has no idea of how that is going to
be
be expressed.
It
It may
It may be
It may be explaining
It may be explaining something
It may be explaining something to
somebody.
somebody. It
It may be explaining something to
somebody. It may
somebody. It may be
It may be explaining something to
somebody. It may be um
somebody. It may be um telling
It may be explaining something to
somebody. It may be um telling them
somebody. It may be um telling them how
to
to get
to get to
to get to 33rd
to get to 33rd and
to get to 33rd and form.
to get to 33rd and form. Then
to get to 33rd and form. Then you
to get to 33rd and form. Then you say
how
how do
to get to 33rd and form. Then you say
how do you
how do you get
to get to 33rd and form. Then you say
how do you get to
how do you get to 33rd
to get to 33rd and form. Then you say
how do you get to 33rd and
how do you get to 33rd and form
to get to 33rd and form. Then you say
how do you get to 33rd and form from
here?
here? You
here? You see
you
you go
here? You see
you go here
you go here and
here? You see
you go here and you
you go here and you go
here? You see
you go here and you go there
you go here and you go there and
here? You see
you go here and you go there and you
then
then you
then you can't
then you can't get
then you can't get to
then you can't get to 33rd
then you can't get to 33rd and
then you can't get to 33rd and form
then you can't get to 33rd and form from
here.
You
You can't
You can't get
You can't get to
You can't get to there
You can't get to there from
You can't get to there from here.
You can't get to there from here. No.
So
So we
You can't get to there from here. No.
So we see
So we see that
You can't get to there from here. No.
So we see that love
So we see that love takes
You can't get to there from here. No.
So we see that love takes um
So we see that love takes um a
You can't get to there from here. No.
So we see that love takes um a thousand
different
different forms
different forms often
different forms often unrecognized
different forms often unrecognized as
what
what it
different forms often unrecognized as
what it is.
what it is. As
different forms often unrecognized as
what it is. As one
what it is. As one gets
different forms often unrecognized as
what it is. As one gets more
what it is. As one gets more spiritually
committed
committed and
committed and advanced,
committed and advanced, you
committed and advanced, you know,
committed and advanced, you know, you
begin
begin to
committed and advanced, you know, you
begin to recognize
begin to recognize its
committed and advanced, you know, you
begin to recognize its expression
begin to recognize its expression and
you
you begin
you begin to
you begin to see
you begin to see love
you begin to see love everywhere.
And
And as
you begin to see love everywhere.
And as you
And as you get
you begin to see love everywhere.
And as you get into
And as you get into certain
you begin to see love everywhere.
And as you get into certain states,
And as you get into certain states, the
beauty
beauty and
beauty and perfection
beauty and perfection of
beauty and perfection of all
beauty and perfection of all things
and
and the
beauty and perfection of all things
and the the
and the the constant
beauty and perfection of all things
and the the constant presence
and the the constant presence of
beauty and perfection of all things
and the the constant presence of love
becomes
becomes somewhat
becomes somewhat staggering.
At
At that
becomes somewhat staggering.
At that point,
At that point, it
becomes somewhat staggering.
At that point, it may
At that point, it may be
becomes somewhat staggering.
At that point, it may be somewhat
difficult
difficult to
difficult to function
difficult to function in
difficult to function in the
difficult to function in the world
because
because everything
reflects
reflects this
reflects this beauty
reflects this beauty and
consequently
consequently one
reflects this beauty and
consequently one has
consequently one has a
reflects this beauty and
consequently one has a tendency
consequently one has a tendency to
reflects this beauty and
consequently one has a tendency to break
into
into tears.
So
So as
into tears.
So as you
So as you get
into tears.
So as you get into
So as you get into let's
into tears.
So as you get into let's say
So as you get into let's say the
into tears.
So as you get into let's say the high
500s
500s there's
500s there's a
500s there's a phase
500s there's a phase a
500s there's a phase a phase
500s there's a phase a phase in
500s there's a phase a phase in which
you
you cry
500s there's a phase a phase in which
you cry all
you cry all the
500s there's a phase a phase in which
you cry all the time
people
people think
people think you're
people think you're sad
people think you're sad and
people think you're sad and it's
people think you're sad and it's quite
the
the opposite.
It's
It's because
It's because everything
It's because everything is
It's because everything is so
It's because everything is so exquisitly
beautiful
beautiful that
It's because everything is so exquisitly
beautiful that the
beautiful that the beauty
It's because everything is so exquisitly
beautiful that the beauty of
beautiful that the beauty of the
beauty
beauty of
beauty of love.
beauty of love. So
beauty of love. So beauty
beauty of love. So beauty and
beauty of love. So beauty and love
beauty of love. So beauty and love are
one
one in
beauty of love. So beauty and love are
one in the
one in the same
beauty of love. So beauty and love are
one in the same thing.
That
That which
That which is
That which is loving
That which is loving is
That which is loving is beautiful.
That which is loving is beautiful. That
which
which is
That which is loving is beautiful. That
which is beautiful
which is beautiful is
That which is loving is beautiful. That
which is beautiful is an
which is beautiful is an expression
That which is loving is beautiful. That
which is beautiful is an expression of
love.
love. Because
love. Because divinity
love. Because divinity as
love. Because divinity as it
love. Because divinity as it expresses
itself
itself in
love. Because divinity as it expresses
itself in perfection
in
in the
in the lower
in the lower levels
in the lower levels one
in the lower levels one doesn't
in the lower levels one doesn't see
perfection.
perfection. What
in the lower levels one doesn't see
perfection. What does
perfection. What does one
in the lower levels one doesn't see
perfection. What does one see
perfection. What does one see in
in the lower levels one doesn't see
perfection. What does one see in the
lower
lower levels?
lower levels? One
lower levels? One sees
one
one sees
lower levels? One sees
one sees all
one sees all of
lower levels? One sees
one sees all of this
one sees all of this down
lower levels? One sees
one sees all of this down here
one sees all of this down here because
these
these are
these are all
these are all your
these are all your own
these are all your own projections.
You
You constantly
these are all your own projections.
You constantly see
You constantly see that
these are all your own projections.
You constantly see that there's
You constantly see that there's nothing
worth
worth anything
worth anything in
worth anything in the
worth anything in the world.
worth anything in the world. Uh
worth anything in the world. Uh you
worth anything in the world. Uh you see
that
that everything
worth anything in the world. Uh you see
that everything is
that everything is sad.
Here
Here you
Here you see
Here you see everything
Here you see everything is
Here you see everything is frightening.
Uh
Uh here
Here you see everything is frightening.
Uh here you
Uh here you want
Here you see everything is frightening.
Uh here you want everything.
Uh here you want everything. Here
Here you see everything is frightening.
Uh here you want everything. Here you're
mad
mad about
mad about everything.
Here
Here you're
mad about everything.
Here you're arrogant
Here you're arrogant about
mad about everything.
Here you're arrogant about everything.
And
And then
And then so
And then so you
And then so you don't
And then so you don't give
And then so you don't give to
And then so you don't give to get
And then so you don't give to get the
lecture
lecture and
And then so you don't give to get the
lecture and give
lecture and give the
And then so you don't give to get the
lecture and give the lecture
lecture and give the lecture until
And then so you don't give to get the
lecture and give the lecture until you
get
get the
get the courage.
I
I said
get the courage.
I said this
I said this morning
get the courage.
I said this morning we're
I said this morning we're going.
get the courage.
I said this morning we're going. No,
I said this morning we're going. No, she
said
said this
said this morning
said this morning we're
said this morning we're going
and
and here
said this morning we're going
and here if
and here if you
said this morning we're going
and here if you get
and here if you get here
said this morning we're going
and here if you get here or
and here if you get here or you
said this morning we're going
and here if you get here or you don't
it's
it's all
it's all the
it's all the same.
Life
Life doesn't
it's all the same.
Life doesn't depend
Life doesn't depend on
it's all the same.
Life doesn't depend on one
Life doesn't depend on one thing
it's all the same.
Life doesn't depend on one thing or
another.
another. So
another. So neutrality
another. So neutrality you
another. So neutrality you really
another. So neutrality you really reach
by
by detaching
another. So neutrality you really reach
by detaching from
by detaching from things.
Yesterday
Yesterday Kitty
Yesterday Kitty of
Yesterday Kitty of course
Yesterday Kitty of course every
Yesterday Kitty of course every lecture
I
I give
Yesterday Kitty of course every lecture
I give you
I give you the
Yesterday Kitty of course every lecture
I give you the recent
I give you the recent thing
Yesterday Kitty of course every lecture
I give you the recent thing on
I give you the recent thing on kitty.
So,
So, Orange
So, Orange Kitty
So, Orange Kitty uh
So, Orange Kitty uh to
So, Orange Kitty uh to to
So, Orange Kitty uh to to be
So, Orange Kitty uh to to be dramatic
gets
gets jealous
So, Orange Kitty uh to to be dramatic
gets jealous of
gets jealous of this
So, Orange Kitty uh to to be dramatic
gets jealous of this affair
gets jealous of this affair and
So, Orange Kitty uh to to be dramatic
gets jealous of this affair and the
gets jealous of this affair and the day
before
before yesterday
before yesterday afternoon
before yesterday afternoon disappeared.
The
The whole
before yesterday afternoon disappeared.
The whole staff,
The whole staff, everybody,
before yesterday afternoon disappeared.
The whole staff, everybody, everybody
instead
instead of
instead of preparing
instead of preparing for
instead of preparing for the
instead of preparing for the lecture
instead of preparing for the lecture is
scattered
scattered all
instead of preparing for the lecture is
scattered all over
scattered all over the
instead of preparing for the lecture is
scattered all over the landscape
scattered all over the landscape looking
for
for the
for the kitty
and
and there
for the kitty
and there was
and there was a
for the kitty
and there was a screen
and there was a screen a
for the kitty
and there was a screen a big
and there was a screen a big hole
for the kitty
and there was a screen a big hole on
and there was a screen a big hole on the
screen.
screen. That's
screen. That's how
screen. That's how Kitty
screen. That's how Kitty got
screen. That's how Kitty got out.
screen. That's how Kitty got out. So
anyway,
anyway, Kitty
screen. That's how Kitty got out. So
anyway, Kitty was
anyway, Kitty was found
screen. That's how Kitty got out. So
anyway, Kitty was found and
anyway, Kitty was found and the
screen. That's how Kitty got out. So
anyway, Kitty was found and the day
anyway, Kitty was found and the day was
saved.
But
But you
saved.
But you know,
But you know, as
saved.
But you know, as everybody
But you know, as everybody was
saved.
But you know, as everybody was out
But you know, as everybody was out there
calling
calling Kitty
calling Kitty Kitty,
calling Kitty Kitty, Kitty
calling Kitty Kitty, Kitty doesn't
calling Kitty Kitty, Kitty doesn't come
to
to his
calling Kitty Kitty, Kitty doesn't come
to his name.
to his name. So,
calling Kitty Kitty, Kitty doesn't come
to his name. So, but
to his name. So, but it
calling Kitty Kitty, Kitty doesn't come
to his name. So, but it keeps
to his name. So, but it keeps people
looking
looking for
looking for a
looking for a kitty
looking for a kitty feeling
looking for a kitty feeling good.
Actually,
Actually, the
looking for a kitty feeling good.
Actually, the kitty
Actually, the kitty was
looking for a kitty feeling good.
Actually, the kitty was discovered
Actually, the kitty was discovered by
one
one of
one of the
one of the people
one of the people we
one of the people we work
one of the people we work with
one of the people we work with closely.
And
And u
I
I forgot
I forgot what
I forgot what I
I forgot what I was
I forgot what I was talking
I forgot what I was talking about.
So
So it
I forgot what I was talking about.
So it was
So it was necessary
I forgot what I was talking about.
So it was necessary to
So it was necessary to re-release
I forgot what I was talking about.
So it was necessary to re-release on
Kitty.
Kitty. In
Kitty. In other
Kitty. In other words,
Kitty. In other words, let
Kitty. In other words, let Kitty
Kitty. In other words, let Kitty go
Kitty. In other words, let Kitty go and
let
let go
Kitty. In other words, let Kitty go and
let go any
let go any attachment
Kitty. In other words, let Kitty go and
let go any attachment to
let go any attachment to Kitty.
Kitty. In other words, let Kitty go and
let go any attachment to Kitty. And
let go any attachment to Kitty. And so
if
if Kitty
if Kitty was
if Kitty was found,
if Kitty was found, it
if Kitty was found, it was
if Kitty was found, it was wonderful.
And
And if
if Kitty was found, it was wonderful.
And if Kitty
And if Kitty was
if Kitty was found, it was wonderful.
And if Kitty was not
And if Kitty was not found,
if Kitty was found, it was wonderful.
And if Kitty was not found, it
And if Kitty was not found, it was
if Kitty was found, it was wonderful.
And if Kitty was not found, it was okay.
And
And um
And um so
And um so you
And um so you see
And um so you see those
And um so you see those losses,
And um so you see those losses, what
And um so you see those losses, what we
look
look at
And um so you see those losses, what we
look at as
look at as losses
And um so you see those losses, what we
look at as losses are
look at as losses are all
And um so you see those losses, what we
look at as losses are all opportunities
to
to let
to let go
to let go of
to let go of attachments.
to let go of attachments. So
to let go of attachments. So yesterday
to let go of attachments. So yesterday I
had
had a
to let go of attachments. So yesterday I
had a chance
had a chance to
to let go of attachments. So yesterday I
had a chance to let
had a chance to let go
to let go of attachments. So yesterday I
had a chance to let go of
had a chance to let go of any
to let go of attachments. So yesterday I
had a chance to let go of any attachment
that
that has
that has developed
that has developed over
that has developed over the
that has developed over the years
that has developed over the years with
Kitty.
So
So if
So if Kitty
So if Kitty was
So if Kitty was lost,
So if Kitty was lost, it
So if Kitty was lost, it was
So if Kitty was lost, it was okay.
So if Kitty was lost, it was okay. And
if
if Kitty
So if Kitty was lost, it was okay. And
if Kitty was
if Kitty was found,
So if Kitty was lost, it was okay. And
if Kitty was found, it
if Kitty was found, it was
So if Kitty was lost, it was okay. And
if Kitty was found, it was very
if Kitty was found, it was very good.
So
So we
So we see
So we see to
So we see to move
So we see to move up,
So we see to move up, we
So we see to move up, we we
So we see to move up, we we move
So we see to move up, we we move into
willingness.
Okay.
Okay. The
Okay. The whole
Okay. The whole spiritual
Okay. The whole spiritual direction
Okay. The whole spiritual direction is
based
based on
Okay. The whole spiritual direction is
based on willingness.
based on willingness. the
Okay. The whole spiritual direction is
based on willingness. the willingness
based on willingness. the willingness to
let
let go
let go of
let go of attachments
let go of attachments such
let go of attachments such as
let go of attachments such as I
let go of attachments such as I did
let go of attachments such as I did with
Kitty
Kitty yesterday
let go of attachments such as I did with
Kitty yesterday just
Kitty yesterday just to
let go of attachments such as I did with
Kitty yesterday just to make
Kitty yesterday just to make sure
let go of attachments such as I did with
Kitty yesterday just to make sure I
wasn't
wasn't attached
wasn't attached to
wasn't attached to Kitty.
The
The willingness
wasn't attached to Kitty.
The willingness to
uh
make
make the
uh
make the sacrifices
make the sacrifices that
uh
make the sacrifices that are
make the sacrifices that are necessary,
the
the willingness
the willingness to
the willingness to apply
the willingness to apply that
the willingness to apply that which
the willingness to apply that which you
learn.
So
So all
So all all
So all all of
So all all of spiritual
So all all of spiritual direction
So all all of spiritual direction then
depends
depends on
So all all of spiritual direction then
depends on a
depends on a certain
So all all of spiritual direction then
depends on a certain willingness
depends on a certain willingness and
So all all of spiritual direction then
depends on a certain willingness and the
probably
probably the
probably the most
probably the most important
probably the most important willingness
is
is the
probably the most important willingness
is the willingness
is the willingness to
probably the most important willingness
is the willingness to surrender
is the willingness to surrender things
to
to God.
So
So people
to God.
So people say
So people say willingness
to God.
So people say willingness about
So people say willingness about what?
The
The willingness
The willingness to
The willingness to surrender
The willingness to surrender things
because
because the
The willingness to surrender things
because the obstacles
because the obstacles to
The willingness to surrender things
because the obstacles to love
because the obstacles to love are
The willingness to surrender things
because the obstacles to love are all
attachments
attachments to
attachments to that
attachments to that which
attachments to that which is
attachments to that which is unloving
and
and the
attachments to that which is unloving
and the willingness
and the willingness to
attachments to that which is unloving
and the willingness to surrender
and the willingness to surrender them
and
and let
and let go
and let go of the
and let go of the attachment.
So
So the
and let go of the attachment.
So the pathway
So the pathway of
and let go of the attachment.
So the pathway of devotion
So the pathway of devotion then
and let go of the attachment.
So the pathway of devotion then is
So the pathway of devotion then is a
willingness
willingness to
willingness to constantly
willingness to constantly surrender
anything
anything and
willingness to constantly surrender
anything and everything.
anything and everything. It
willingness to constantly surrender
anything and everything. It becomes
extreme.
The
The willingness
extreme.
The willingness to
The willingness to sacrifice
extreme.
The willingness to sacrifice all
The willingness to sacrifice all one's
positions,
positions, titles,
positions, titles, money.
Let
Let go
positions, titles, money.
Let go of
all
all that
all that this
all that this world
all that this world has
all that this world has to
all that this world has to offer.
limousines
limousines and
all that this world has to offer.
limousines and estates
limousines and estates and
all that this world has to offer.
limousines and estates and titles
limousines and estates and titles and
membership
membership in
membership in great
membership in great societies
membership in great societies etc
membership in great societies etc and
walk
walk away
membership in great societies etc and
walk away from
walk away from all
membership in great societies etc and
walk away from all of
walk away from all of it.
So
So that
So that is
So that is a
So that is a classic
So that is a classic stage
So that is a classic stage in
So that is a classic stage in spiritual
development
what
what do
what do we
what do we call
what do we call it
what do we call it where
what do we call it where you
what do we call it where you let
what do we call it where you let go
what do we call it where you let go of
everything
everything in
what do we call it where you let go of
everything in the
everything in the world
what do we call it where you let go of
everything in the world walk
everything in the world walk away
what do we call it where you let go of
everything in the world walk away from
it
it renunciation.
it renunciation. Yeah.
it renunciation. Yeah. So
it renunciation. Yeah. So we
it renunciation. Yeah. So we then
it renunciation. Yeah. So we then come
to
to willingness
it renunciation. Yeah. So we then come
to willingness will
to willingness will eventually
it renunciation. Yeah. So we then come
to willingness will eventually take
to willingness will eventually take you
to
to renunciation.
Renunciation
Renunciation takes
to renunciation.
Renunciation takes the
Renunciation takes the form
to renunciation.
Renunciation takes the form classically
in
in some
in some pathways
as
as literally
in some pathways
as literally renouncing
as literally renouncing the
in some pathways
as literally renouncing the world,
literally
literally walking
literally walking away
literally walking away from
literally walking away from the
literally walking away from the world,
moving
moving out
literally walking away from the world,
moving out to
moving out to the
literally walking away from the world,
moving out to the middle
moving out to the middle of
literally walking away from the world,
moving out to the middle of nowhere
and
and living
and living on
and living on a
and living on a cot
and living on a cot with
and living on a cot with a
and living on a cot with a box,
and living on a cot with a box, a
candle,
candle, and
and living on a cot with a box, a
candle, and trucking
candle, and trucking manure
at
at 40
at 40 bucks
at 40 bucks a
at 40 bucks a truckload.
at 40 bucks a truckload. That's
hysterical.
And
And um
And um anyway,
And um anyway, it
And um anyway, it can
And um anyway, it can take
And um anyway, it can take the
And um anyway, it can take the form
And um anyway, it can take the form of
the
the willingness
And um anyway, it can take the form of
the willingness to
the willingness to renounce
And um anyway, it can take the form of
the willingness to renounce everything.
And
And most
And most people
And most people who've
And most people who've been
And most people who've been at
And most people who've been at spiritual
work
work for
And most people who've been at spiritual
work for some
work for some time
And most people who've been at spiritual
work for some time have
work for some time have usually
And most people who've been at spiritual
work for some time have usually let
everything
everything go
everything go several
everything go several times.
You
You walk
everything go several times.
You walk away
You walk away from
everything go several times.
You walk away from it
You walk away from it all.
everything go several times.
You walk away from it all. Start
You walk away from it all. Start from
zilch.
zilch. And
zilch. And as
zilch. And as time
zilch. And as time goes
zilch. And as time goes on,
zilch. And as time goes on, it
zilch. And as time goes on, it begins
zilch. And as time goes on, it begins to
accumulate
accumulate around
zilch. And as time goes on, it begins to
accumulate around you
accumulate around you again.
zilch. And as time goes on, it begins to
accumulate around you again. And
accumulate around you again. And so
zilch. And as time goes on, it begins to
accumulate around you again. And so you
then
then you
then you go
then you go through
then you go through another
then you go through another big
then you go through another big letting
go.
Sometimes,
Sometimes, like
Sometimes, like right
Sometimes, like right now,
Sometimes, like right now, because
Sometimes, like right now, because I'm
writing
writing and
Sometimes, like right now, because I'm
writing and I'd
writing and I'd like
Sometimes, like right now, because I'm
writing and I'd like certain
writing and I'd like certain references
that
that I
that I vaguely
that I vaguely remember
that I vaguely remember from
that I vaguely remember from somewhere
in
in time,
that I vaguely remember from somewhere
in time, but
in time, but usually
that I vaguely remember from somewhere
in time, but usually book
in time, but usually book readers
that I vaguely remember from somewhere
in time, but usually book readers who
live
live in
live in the
live in the 400s
live in the 400s want
live in the 400s want references
live in the 400s want references in
live in the 400s want references in the
back
back with
live in the 400s want references in the
back with page
back with page numbers
live in the 400s want references in the
back with page numbers and
back with page numbers and stuff.
live in the 400s want references in the
back with page numbers and stuff. You
know,
know, you
know, you can't
know, you can't just
know, you can't just tell
know, you can't just tell them
know, you can't just tell them uh
know, you can't just tell them uh the
apherisms
apherisms of
know, you can't just tell them uh the
apherisms of Paneli
apherisms of Paneli or
know, you can't just tell them uh the
apherisms of Paneli or something
apherisms of Paneli or something like
that,
that, they
that, they want
that, they want to
that, they want to know
that, they want to know published
that, they want to know published by
what
what page.
Anyway,
Anyway, they're
Anyway, they're missing
Anyway, they're missing the
Anyway, they're missing the whole
Anyway, they're missing the whole point
of
of it,
Anyway, they're missing the whole point
of it, but
of it, but the
Anyway, they're missing the whole point
of it, but the if
of it, but the if you
Anyway, they're missing the whole point
of it, but the if you get
of it, but the if you get the
Anyway, they're missing the whole point
of it, but the if you get the point
of it, but the if you get the point of
it,
it, you
it, you don't
it, you don't look
it, you don't look at
it, you don't look at any
it, you don't look at any references.
But
But anyway,
So
So renunciation
So renunciation then
So renunciation then can
So renunciation then can take
So renunciation then can take the
So renunciation then can take the form
of
of walking
So renunciation then can take the form
of walking away
of walking away from
So renunciation then can take the form
of walking away from everything.
of walking away from everything. I
So renunciation then can take the form
of walking away from everything. I threw
up
up my
up my whole
up my whole spiritual
up my whole spiritual library.
Walked
Walked away
up my whole spiritual library.
Walked away from
Walked away from it
up my whole spiritual library.
Walked away from it all.
Walked away from it all. Walked
up my whole spiritual library.
Walked away from it all. Walked away
from
from my
from my medical
from my medical library.
from my medical library. Walked
from my medical library. Walked away
from
from all
from my medical library. Walked away
from all those
from all those things.
from my medical library. Walked away
from all those things. And
from all those things. And now
from my medical library. Walked away
from all those things. And now when
from all those things. And now when I
need
need a
need a reference,
need a reference, I
need a reference, I I
need a reference, I I have
need a reference, I I have to
need a reference, I I have to have
need a reference, I I have to have Sonia
look
look it
need a reference, I I have to have Sonia
look it up
look it up on
need a reference, I I have to have Sonia
look it up on the
look it up on the internet.
I
I mean,
I mean, I
I mean, I remember
I mean, I remember what
I mean, I remember what it's
I mean, I remember what it's about
I mean, I remember what it's about and
it's
it's just
I mean, I remember what it's about and
it's just a
it's just a point
I mean, I remember what it's about and
it's just a point I
it's just a point I want
I mean, I remember what it's about and
it's just a point I want to
it's just a point I want to make
I mean, I remember what it's about and
it's just a point I want to make in
it's just a point I want to make in a
reference.
reference. But
reference. But now
reference. But now they
reference. But now they expect
reference. But now they expect it
reference. But now they expect it in
reference. But now they expect it in the
reference.
reference. So
reference. But now they expect it in the
reference. So having
reference. So having let
reference. But now they expect it in the
reference. So having let go
reference. So having let go all
reference. But now they expect it in the
reference. So having let go all one
spiritual
spiritual library,
spiritual library, all
spiritual library, all one's
spiritual library, all one's pictures
spiritual library, all one's pictures of
Jesus
Jesus and
spiritual library, all one's pictures of
Jesus and all
Jesus and all that
spiritual library, all one's pictures of
Jesus and all that stuff,
Jesus and all that stuff, you
spiritual library, all one's pictures of
Jesus and all that stuff, you know,
Jesus and all that stuff, you know, you
walk
walk away
walk away from
walk away from all
walk away from all that
walk away from all that as
walk away from all that as it's
trappings.
trappings. Trappings,
walk away from all that as it's
trappings. Trappings, you
trappings. Trappings, you say
walk away from all that as it's
trappings. Trappings, you say that's
trappings. Trappings, you say that's all
trappings,
trappings, incense
trappings, incense and
trappings, incense and sandals
trappings, incense and sandals and
pictures
pictures of
trappings, incense and sandals and
pictures of Jesus
pictures of Jesus and
trappings, incense and sandals and
pictures of Jesus and Buddhas
pictures of Jesus and Buddhas and
trappings, incense and sandals and
pictures of Jesus and Buddhas and all
that
that stuff.
that stuff. Throw
that stuff. Throw them
that stuff. Throw them all
that stuff. Throw them all out.
that stuff. Throw them all out. They
throw
throw out
that stuff. Throw them all out. They
throw out Buddhas
throw out Buddhas and
that stuff. Throw them all out. They
throw out Buddhas and Jesus
throw out Buddhas and Jesus and
everybody.
They're
They're just
everybody.
They're just pictures.
They're just pictures. They
everybody.
They're just pictures. They just
depictions.
depictions. They're
depictions. They're they're
depictions. They're they're not
depictions. They're they're not the
depictions. They're they're not the real
thing.
thing. You
depictions. They're they're not the real
thing. You know
thing. You know what
depictions. They're they're not the real
thing. You know what I'm
thing. You know what I'm saying?
depictions. They're they're not the real
thing. You know what I'm saying? So
thing. You know what I'm saying? So you
walk
walk away
walk away from
walk away from it
walk away from it and
walk away from it and you
walk away from it and you feel
walk away from it and you feel clean
walk away from it and you feel clean and
pure
pure and
walk away from it and you feel clean and
pure and wonderful,
but
but then
but then you
but then you got
but then you got to
but then you got to have
but then you got to have something
but then you got to have something to
drive
drive around
but then you got to have something to
drive around in.
drive around in. So
but then you got to have something to
drive around in. So then
drive around in. So then you
but then you got to have something to
drive around in. So then you get
drive around in. So then you get a
but then you got to have something to
drive around in. So then you get a car.
Then
Then you
Then you got
you
you have
Then you got
you have to
you have to have
Then you got
you have to have a
you have to have a garage
Then you got
you have to have a garage for
you have to have a garage for the
Then you got
you have to have a garage for the car.
Unless
Unless you
Unless you want
Unless you want to
Unless you want to go
Unless you want to go shopping
Unless you want to go shopping every
day,
day, you
Unless you want to go shopping every
day, you got
day, you got to
Unless you want to go shopping every
day, you got to have
day, you got to have a
Unless you want to go shopping every
day, you got to have a refrigerator.
day, you got to have a refrigerator. So
you
you all
you all this
you all this stuff
you all this stuff begins
you all this stuff begins to
you all this stuff begins to accumulate
again
and
and you
and you say,
and you say, "I
and you say, "I don't
and you say, "I don't know
and you say, "I don't know how
and you say, "I don't know how I'm
and you say, "I don't know how I'm going
to
to do
and you say, "I don't know how I'm going
to do it
to do it in
and you say, "I don't know how I'm going
to do it in this
to do it in this world."
and you say, "I don't know how I'm going
to do it in this world." cuz
to do it in this world." cuz you
and you say, "I don't know how I'm going
to do it in this world." cuz you you
know
know you
know you forgot
know you forgot you
know you forgot you got
know you forgot you got this
know you forgot you got this thing
know you forgot you got this thing here
and
and uh
know you forgot you got this thing here
and uh it's
and uh it's entertaining
know you forgot you got this thing here
and uh it's entertaining but
and uh it's entertaining but it
know you forgot you got this thing here
and uh it's entertaining but it has
certain
certain needs
certain needs like
certain needs like like
certain needs like like the
certain needs like like the kitty
certain needs like like the kitty you
got
got to
certain needs like like the kitty you
got to give
got to give it
certain needs like like the kitty you
got to give it food
got to give it food in
certain needs like like the kitty you
got to give it food in the
got to give it food in the morning
certain needs like like the kitty you
got to give it food in the morning I
feed
feed the
feed the kitty
feed the kitty and
feed the kitty and I
feed the kitty and I feed
feed the kitty and I feed this
feed the kitty and I feed this here
feed the kitty and I feed this here I
have
have my
feed the kitty and I feed this here I
have my coffee
have my coffee kitty
feed the kitty and I feed this here I
have my coffee kitty has
have my coffee kitty has the
feed the kitty and I feed this here I
have my coffee kitty has the food
have my coffee kitty has the food so
we're
we're both
we're both happy
if
if you
we're both happy
if you don't
if you don't do
we're both happy
if you don't do that
if you don't do that it
we're both happy
if you don't do that it falls
if you don't do that it falls over
you
you get
you get weak
sometimes
sometimes I
you get weak
sometimes I say
sometimes I say to
you get weak
sometimes I say to Susie
sometimes I say to Susie I
you get weak
sometimes I say to Susie I said
sometimes I say to Susie I said I'm
you get weak
sometimes I say to Susie I said I'm so
weak
weak I
weak I can't
weak I can't even
weak I can't even walk
weak I can't even walk from
weak I can't even walk from here
weak I can't even walk from here to
there
said
said well
said well If
said well If you
said well If you eat
said well If you eat something
said well If you eat something that
would
would help.
I
I still
I still find
I still find it
I still find it hard
I still find it hard to
I still find it hard to believe
I still find it hard to believe that
I still find it hard to believe that you
have
have to
I still find it hard to believe that you
have to eat
have to eat something.
I still find it hard to believe that you
have to eat something. I
have to eat something. I really
I still find it hard to believe that you
have to eat something. I really don't.
And
And days
And days like
And days like today,
And days like today, I
And days like today, I just
And days like today, I just live
And days like today, I just live on
liquids
liquids and
And days like today, I just live on
liquids and food.
liquids and food. It's
And days like today, I just live on
liquids and food. It's horrible.
liquids and food. It's horrible. So,
And days like today, I just live on
liquids and food. It's horrible. So, um
what
what were
what were we
what were we talking
what were we talking about?
what were we talking about? We
what were we talking about? We were
talking
talking about
what were we talking about? We were
talking about renunciation.
talking about renunciation. Okay.
what were we talking about? We were
talking about renunciation. Okay. So,
renunciation
renunciation then
uh
uh meanings
renunciation then
uh meanings let
uh meanings let means
renunciation then
uh meanings let means letting
uh meanings let means letting go
renunciation then
uh meanings let means letting go of
worldliness.
worldliness. Worldliness,
worldliness. Worldliness, craving,
wanting.
wanting. So
worldliness. Worldliness, craving,
wanting. So you're
wanting. So you're trying
worldliness. Worldliness, craving,
wanting. So you're trying to
wanting. So you're trying to transcend
the
the solar
the solar plexus.
the solar plexus. Wanting
the solar plexus. Wanting things
the solar plexus. Wanting things is
coming
coming out
the solar plexus. Wanting things is
coming out of
coming out of the
the solar plexus. Wanting things is
coming out of the solar
coming out of the solar plexus.
the solar plexus. Wanting things is
coming out of the solar plexus. I
coming out of the solar plexus. I want
this.
this. I
this. I want
this. I want that.
this. I want that. You
this. I want that. You I
this. I want that. You I mean
this. I want that. You I mean Walmarts
is
is the
cathedral
cathedral of
cathedral of wantingness.
I
I love
cathedral of wantingness.
I love Walmarts.
I love Walmarts. You
cathedral of wantingness.
I love Walmarts. You walk
I love Walmarts. You walk down.
cathedral of wantingness.
I love Walmarts. You walk down. Yeah.
I love Walmarts. You walk down. Yeah. I
always
always talk
always talk about
always talk about Walmarts
always talk about Walmarts because
always talk about Walmarts because it's
our
our new
always talk about Walmarts because it's
our new cathedral.
There's
There's a
There's a certain
There's a certain divinity
There's a certain divinity there.
There's a certain divinity there. It's
God
God expressed
There's a certain divinity there. It's
God expressed as
God expressed as everything
There's a certain divinity there. It's
God expressed as everything you
God expressed as everything you could
want.
want. God
want. God says,
want. God says, "You
want. God says, "You want
want. God says, "You want all
want. God says, "You want all these
things?
things? Here
want. God says, "You want all these
things? Here they
things? Here they are."
want. God says, "You want all these
things? Here they are." You
things? Here they are." You know,
Walmart
Walmart is
Walmart is a
Walmart is a present
Walmart is a present from
Walmart is a present from God
Walmart is a present from God to
Walmart is a present from God to the
solar
solar plexus
Walmart is a present from God to the
solar plexus of
solar plexus of humanity.
Walmart is a present from God to the
solar plexus of humanity. And
not
not just
not just the
not just the solar
not just the solar plexus,
not just the solar plexus, but
not just the solar plexus, but you
not just the solar plexus, but you got
to
to keep
not just the solar plexus, but you got
to keep this
to keep this thing
not just the solar plexus, but you got
to keep this thing going.
to keep this thing going. Means
not just the solar plexus, but you got
to keep this thing going. Means you
to keep this thing going. Means you got
to
to wash
to wash it,
to wash it, you
to wash it, you got
to wash it, you got to
to wash it, you got to get
to wash it, you got to get soap,
to wash it, you got to get soap, you
to wash it, you got to get soap, you got
to
to get
to wash it, you got to get soap, you got
to get things
to get things to
to wash it, you got to get soap, you got
to get things to put
to get things to put the
to wash it, you got to get soap, you got
to get things to put the soap
to get things to put the soap in,
to wash it, you got to get soap, you got
to get things to put the soap in, you
have
have to
have to have
have to have refrigerators,
have to have refrigerators, all
have to have refrigerators, all that
stuff.
stuff. So
have to have refrigerators, all that
stuff. So Walmart
stuff. So Walmart is
have to have refrigerators, all that
stuff. So Walmart is uh
stuff. So Walmart is uh very
have to have refrigerators, all that
stuff. So Walmart is uh very helpful
stuff. So Walmart is uh very helpful to
survival.
And
And uh
survival.
And uh I
And uh I always
survival.
And uh I always speak
And uh I always speak well
survival.
And uh I always speak well of
And uh I always speak well of Sam.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So renunciation
All right. So renunciation then
All right. So renunciation then takes
the
the form
All right. So renunciation then takes
the form of
the form of letting
All right. So renunciation then takes
the form of letting go
the form of letting go of
All right. So renunciation then takes
the form of letting go of what
the form of letting go of what the
All right. So renunciation then takes
the form of letting go of what the world
chases
chases after.
chases after. Success,
chases after. Success, money,
chases after. Success, money, power,
these
these are
chases after. Success, money, power,
these are very
these are very important.
See
See the
See the things
See the things that
See the things that you
See the things that you do
See the things that you do at
See the things that you do at what
See the things that you do at what you
what
what you
See the things that you do at what you
what you consider
what you consider beginning
See the things that you do at what you
what you consider beginning levels
what you consider beginning levels of
spirituality.
spirituality. Oh
spirituality. Oh no,
spirituality. Oh no, they're
spirituality. Oh no, they're not
beginning.
beginning. That's
spirituality. Oh no, they're not
beginning. That's the
beginning. That's the test
spirituality. Oh no, they're not
beginning. That's the test at
beginning. That's the test at the
spirituality. Oh no, they're not
beginning. That's the test at the end.
The
The last
The last lecture
The last lecture we're
The last lecture we're going
The last lecture we're going to
The last lecture we're going to give
The last lecture we're going to give you
what
what the
The last lecture we're going to give you
what the test
what the test is
The last lecture we're going to give you
what the test is like
what the test is like at
The last lecture we're going to give you
what the test is like at the
what the test is like at the end.
The last lecture we're going to give you
what the test is like at the end. The
test
test at
test at the
test at the end
test at the end had
test at the end had been
test at the end had been learned
test at the end had been learned early
in
in the
test at the end had been learned early
in the game.
in the game. I'd
test at the end had been learned early
in the game. I'd let
in the game. I'd let go
test at the end had been learned early
in the game. I'd let go any
in the game. I'd let go any desire
test at the end had been learned early
in the game. I'd let go any desire for
power.
Somebody
Somebody said,
power.
Somebody said, "You
Somebody said, "You want
power.
Somebody said, "You want power?"
Somebody said, "You want power?" I
power.
Somebody said, "You want power?" I say,
"What
"What for?
"What for? It's
"What for? It's a
"What for? It's a drag."
You
You try
"What for? It's a drag."
You try being
You try being president
"What for? It's a drag."
You try being president of
You try being president of the
"What for? It's a drag."
You try being president of the United
States
States or
States or the
States or the pope,
States or the pope, man.
States or the pope, man. I
If
If you
States or the pope, man. I
If you live
If you live 24
States or the pope, man. I
If you live 24 hours,
If you live 24 hours, it's
States or the pope, man. I
If you live 24 hours, it's because
If you live 24 hours, it's because of
the
the security
the security around
the security around you.
the security around you. I
the security around you. I mean,
the security around you. I mean, you
know,
know, there's
the security around you. I mean, you
know, there's nothing
know, there's nothing worse
the security around you. I mean, you
know, there's nothing worse than
know, there's nothing worse than having
power.
power. So,
power. So, when
power. So, when that
power. So, when that temptation
power. So, when that temptation comes
power. So, when that temptation comes at
the
the end,
power. So, when that temptation comes at
the end, you've
the end, you've refused
power. So, when that temptation comes at
the end, you've refused it
the end, you've refused it years
power. So, when that temptation comes at
the end, you've refused it years before.
You
You laugh
You laugh at
You laugh at the
You laugh at the Lucifer
You laugh at the Lucifer temptation.
All
All power
You laugh at the Lucifer temptation.
All power is
All power is yours.
You laugh at the Lucifer temptation.
All power is yours. Claim
All power is yours. Claim it.
You laugh at the Lucifer temptation.
All power is yours. Claim it. What
All power is yours. Claim it. What are
you,
you, Joker?
Lucifer's
Lucifer's best
you, Joker?
Lucifer's best shot.
So
So those
So those things
So those things that
So those things that will
So those things that will come
So those things that will come to
So those things that will come to you
later
later under
So those things that will come to you
later under a
later under a different
So those things that will come to you
later under a different form
and
and very
and very profoundly
and very profoundly powerful
and very profoundly powerful as
and very profoundly powerful as they
come
come when
and very profoundly powerful as they
come when you
come when you get
and very profoundly powerful as they
come when you get very
come when you get very very
and very profoundly powerful as they
come when you get very very advanced
these
these things
these things are
these things are going
these things are going to
these things are going to come
these things are going to come back
these things are going to come back to
you.
you. So
these things are going to come back to
you. So these
you. So these lessons
these things are going to come back to
you. So these lessons we
you. So these lessons we learn
these things are going to come back to
you. So these lessons we learn here
you. So these lessons we learn here are
powerfully
powerfully important.
If
If you
powerfully important.
If you can
If you can let
powerfully important.
If you can let go
If you can let go of
powerfully important.
If you can let go of the
If you can let go of the kitty
powerfully important.
If you can let go of the kitty you
If you can let go of the kitty you can
let
let go
let go of
let go of anything.
After
After I
let go of anything.
After I let
After I let go
let go of anything.
After I let go of
After I let go of Kitty,
let go of anything.
After I let go of Kitty, Kitty
After I let go of Kitty, Kitty Gors
reappeared
and
and found
reappeared
and found by
and found by uh
reappeared
and found by uh friends
and found by uh friends and
reappeared
and found by uh friends and people
and found by uh friends and people we
work
work with
work with and
work with and love.
So
So renunciation
work with and love.
So renunciation is
So renunciation is really
work with and love.
So renunciation is really an
So renunciation is really an inner.
work with and love.
So renunciation is really an inner. See,
when
when you
when you renounce
when you renounce the
when you renounce the world,
that's
that's u
when you renounce the world,
that's u put
that's u put it
when you renounce the world,
that's u put it where
that's u put it where your
when you renounce the world,
that's u put it where your mouth
that's u put it where your mouth is.
when you renounce the world,
that's u put it where your mouth is. Put
your
your duke
your duke swap
your duke swap and
your duke swap and let's
your duke swap and let's see
your duke swap and let's see if
your duke swap and let's see if you're
just
just saying
your duke swap and let's see if you're
just saying that
just saying that or
your duke swap and let's see if you're
just saying that or if
just saying that or if you
your duke swap and let's see if you're
just saying that or if you really
just saying that or if you really mean
it.
it. Can
it. Can you
it. Can you really
it. Can you really walk
it. Can you really walk away
it. Can you really walk away from
it. Can you really walk away from it
all?
all? And
it. Can you really walk away from it
all? And when
all? And when I
it. Can you really walk away from it
all? And when I first
all? And when I first came
it. Can you really walk away from it
all? And when I first came to
all? And when I first came to Sedona,
most
most waiters
most waiters and
most waiters and people
most waiters and people around
most waiters and people around here
most waiters and people around here were
people
people who
most waiters and people around here were
people who had
people who had done
most waiters and people around here were
people who had done that.
people who had done that. This
most waiters and people around here were
people who had done that. This was
people who had done that. This was a
mecca
mecca for
mecca for the
mecca for the spiritually
mecca for the spiritually inspired
and
and the
mecca for the spiritually inspired
and the population
and the population was
mecca for the spiritually inspired
and the population was three
and the population was three or
mecca for the spiritually inspired
and the population was three or 4
thousand.
thousand. And
thousand. And u
most
most of
thousand. And u
most of the
most of the waiters
thousand. And u
most of the waiters and
most of the waiters and stuff
thousand. And u
most of the waiters and stuff in
most of the waiters and stuff in the
restaurants
restaurants had
restaurants had once
restaurants had once been
restaurants had once been president
restaurants had once been president of
so
so and
restaurants had once been president of
so and so
so and so corporation
restaurants had once been president of
so and so corporation and
Sedana
Sedana was
Sedana was full
Sedana was full of
Sedana was full of people
Sedana was full of people who
Sedana was full of people who were
Sedana was full of people who were once
wealthy,
wealthy, powerful,
Sedana was full of people who were once
wealthy, powerful, all
wealthy, powerful, all kinds
Sedana was full of people who were once
wealthy, powerful, all kinds of
wealthy, powerful, all kinds of titles
and
and said
and said hell
and said hell with
and said hell with it.
and said hell with it. No,
and said hell with it. No, they
and said hell with it. No, they walked
around
around in
and said hell with it. No, they walked
around in sandals
around in sandals and
and said hell with it. No, they walked
around in sandals and long
around in sandals and long hair
and said hell with it. No, they walked
around in sandals and long hair and
around in sandals and long hair and went
home
home all
home all day
and
and their
home all day
and their family
and their family thought
home all day
and their family thought they'd
and their family thought they'd gone
nuts
nuts and
nuts and uh
nuts and uh you
nuts and uh you better
nuts and uh you better see
nuts and uh you better see a
nuts and uh you better see a doctor.
nuts and uh you better see a doctor. So
the
the spiritual
nuts and uh you better see a doctor. So
the spiritual madness
the spiritual madness can
nuts and uh you better see a doctor. So
the spiritual madness can take
the spiritual madness can take you
nuts and uh you better see a doctor. So
the spiritual madness can take you over
and
and you
and you walk
and you walk away
and you walk away from
and you walk away from everything.
and you walk away from everything. And
I've
I've done
and you walk away from everything. And
I've done it
I've done it a
and you walk away from everything. And
I've done it a couple
I've done it a couple times,
and you walk away from everything. And
I've done it a couple times, walked
I've done it a couple times, walked away
from
from it
from it all.
Then
Then it
from it all.
Then it comes
Then it comes to
from it all.
Then it comes to you
Then it comes to you and
from it all.
Then it comes to you and it's
Then it comes to you and it's more
pristine
pristine understanding
pristine understanding that
pristine understanding that renunciation
is
is an
pristine understanding that renunciation
is an internal
is an internal affair.
pristine understanding that renunciation
is an internal affair. Renunciation
means
means the
means the willingness
means the willingness to
means the willingness to surrender
within
within yourself
your
your cherished
your cherished positionalities
and
and more
your cherished positionalities
and more importantly
and more importantly to
your cherished positionalities
and more importantly to surrender
and more importantly to surrender the
juice
juice you
juice you get
juice you get out
juice you get out of
juice you get out of these
positionalities.
See
See the
See the reason
See the reason you
See the reason you can't
See the reason you can't transcend
See the reason you can't transcend the
ego
ego is
See the reason you can't transcend the
ego is because
ego is because you
See the reason you can't transcend the
ego is because you get
ego is because you get such
See the reason you can't transcend the
ego is because you get such wonderful
juice
juice out
juice out of
juice out of it.
juice out of it. Being
juice out of it. Being mad,
juice out of it. Being mad, being
juice out of it. Being mad, being angry,
being
being furious,
juice out of it. Being mad, being angry,
being furious, being
being furious, being right,
juice out of it. Being mad, being angry,
being furious, being right, being
being furious, being right, being just.
You
You watch
You watch the
You watch the Middle
You watch the Middle East,
You watch the Middle East, the
You watch the Middle East, the glee
You watch the Middle East, the glee with
which
which they
You watch the Middle East, the glee with
which they kill
which they kill each
You watch the Middle East, the glee with
which they kill each other.
which they kill each other. I
You watch the Middle East, the glee with
which they kill each other. I mean,
which they kill each other. I mean, they
love
love it.
love it. You
love it. You know what
love it. You know what I
love it. You know what I mean?
love it. You know what I mean? Like
love it. You know what I mean? Like an
idiot,
idiot, you're
love it. You know what I mean? Like an
idiot, you're going
idiot, you're going to
love it. You know what I mean? Like an
idiot, you're going to go
idiot, you're going to go over
love it. You know what I mean? Like an
idiot, you're going to go over there
with
with a
with a peace
with a peace peace
with a peace peace thing.
with a peace peace thing. The
with a peace peace thing. The first
thing
thing going
with a peace peace thing. The first
thing going to
thing going to do
with a peace peace thing. The first
thing going to do is
thing going to do is kill
with a peace peace thing. The first
thing going to do is kill you
thing going to do is kill you because
any
any idiot
any idiot who
any idiot who goes
any idiot who goes there
any idiot who goes there with
any idiot who goes there with his
any idiot who goes there with his peace
is
is going
any idiot who goes there with his peace
is going to
is going to ruin
any idiot who goes there with his peace
is going to ruin the
is going to ruin the whole
any idiot who goes there with his peace
is going to ruin the whole game.
is going to ruin the whole game. There
isn't
isn't a
isn't a single
isn't a single person
isn't a single person there
isn't a single person there that
isn't a single person there that is
interested
interested in
isn't a single person there that is
interested in peace.
interested in peace. Except
isn't a single person there that is
interested in peace. Except the
peacemongers
who
who get
peacemongers
who get all
who get all their
peacemongers
who get all their publicity
who get all their publicity and
peacemongers
who get all their publicity and power
from
from selling
from selling everybody
from selling everybody peace.
Yeah,
Yeah, right.
Kill
Kill them
Kill them pieces,
Kill them pieces, man.
Kill them pieces, man. They're
Kill them pieces, man. They're ruining
our
our business.
I
I mean,
I mean, the
I mean, the whole
I mean, the whole racket
I mean, the whole racket is
I mean, the whole racket is based
I mean, the whole racket is based on
anything
anything but
I mean, the whole racket is based on
anything but peace.
anything but peace. And
I mean, the whole racket is based on
anything but peace. And you
anything but peace. And you want
I mean, the whole racket is based on
anything but peace. And you want to
anything but peace. And you want to come
in
in and
in and blow
in and blow their
in and blow their whole
in and blow their whole racket?
Like
Like asking
in and blow their whole racket?
Like asking Dillinger
Like asking Dillinger to
in and blow their whole racket?
Like asking Dillinger to give
Like asking Dillinger to give up
in and blow their whole racket?
Like asking Dillinger to give up crime?
I
I mean,
I mean, what
I mean, what would
I mean, what would he
I mean, what would he do
I mean, what would he do without
I mean, what would he do without Robin
Banks?
Banks? You
I mean, what would he do without Robin
Banks? You know what
Banks? You know what I'm
I mean, what would he do without Robin
Banks? You know what I'm saying?
Robin
Robin Banks
Robin Banks was
Robin Banks was dealing
Robin Banks was dealing to
Robin Banks was dealing to his
Robin Banks was dealing to his whole
thing,
thing, right?
Robin Banks was dealing to his whole
thing, right? And
thing, right? And after
Robin Banks was dealing to his whole
thing, right? And after these
thing, right? And after these miraculous
escapes,
escapes, what
escapes, what was
escapes, what was he
escapes, what was he doing
escapes, what was he doing within
escapes, what was he doing within 48
hours?
hours? He
escapes, what was he doing within 48
hours? He was
hours? He was robbing
escapes, what was he doing within 48
hours? He was robbing a
hours? He was robbing a bank.
escapes, what was he doing within 48
hours? He was robbing a bank. I'll
hours? He was robbing a bank. I'll say
to
to these
to these bank
to these bank robbers,
to these bank robbers, "What'd
to these bank robbers, "What'd you
to these bank robbers, "What'd you do
with
with the
to these bank robbers, "What'd you do
with the last
with the last money
to these bank robbers, "What'd you do
with the last money you
with the last money you had?
to these bank robbers, "What'd you do
with the last money you had? 3
with the last money you had? 3 days
to these bank robbers, "What'd you do
with the last money you had? 3 days ago,
they
they got
they got 48,000.
they got 48,000. 2
they got 48,000. 2 days
they got 48,000. 2 days ago,
they got 48,000. 2 days ago, they
they got 48,000. 2 days ago, they got
14,000.
14,000. I
they got 48,000. 2 days ago, they got
14,000. I mean,
14,000. I mean, have
they got 48,000. 2 days ago, they got
14,000. I mean, have you
14,000. I mean, have you spent
they got 48,000. 2 days ago, they got
14,000. I mean, have you spent it
14,000. I mean, have you spent it all
they got 48,000. 2 days ago, they got
14,000. I mean, have you spent it all or
what?
Are
Are you
what?
Are you broke?"
No.
No. Robin
No. Robin Banks
No. Robin Banks is
No. Robin Banks is what
No. Robin Banks is what he
No. Robin Banks is what he does.
No. Robin Banks is what he does. That's
who
who he
No. Robin Banks is what he does. That's
who he is.
who he is. That's
No. Robin Banks is what he does. That's
who he is. That's his
who he is. That's his thing,
No. Robin Banks is what he does. That's
who he is. That's his thing, you
who he is. That's his thing, you know.
So
So you're
So you're going
So you're going to
So you're going to hold
So you're going to hold up
So you're going to hold up a
So you're going to hold up a parade
So you're going to hold up a parade that
says
says stop
So you're going to hold up a parade that
says stop robbing
says stop robbing banks.
Yeah.
Yeah. Right.
The
The way
Yeah. Right.
The way we
The way we transcend
Yeah. Right.
The way we transcend the
The way we transcend the limitations
Yeah. Right.
The way we transcend the limitations of
the
the ego
the ego and
the ego and its
the ego and its positionalities
the ego and its positionalities is
the ego and its positionalities is it
gets
gets such
the ego and its positionalities is it
gets such a
gets such a tren
the ego and its positionalities is it
gets such a tren tremendous
gets such a tren tremendous payoff.
the ego and its positionalities is it
gets such a tren tremendous payoff. And
this
this is
this is where
this is where willingness
this is where willingness really
this is where willingness really comes
in.
The
The willingness
The willingness to
The willingness to be
The willingness to be honest
The willingness to be honest with
yourself
yourself that
The willingness to be honest with
yourself that the
yourself that the reason
The willingness to be honest with
yourself that the reason you
yourself that the reason you cling
The willingness to be honest with
yourself that the reason you cling to
this
this is
this is because
this is because of
this is because of the
this is because of the payoff
this is because of the payoff you're
getting
getting out
this is because of the payoff you're
getting out of
getting out of it.
this is because of the payoff you're
getting out of it. It's
getting out of it. It's hard
this is because of the payoff you're
getting out of it. It's hard to
getting out of it. It's hard to admit
that
that you
that you like
that you like hating
that you like hating people.
First
First of
that you like hating people.
First of all,
First of all, they
that you like hating people.
First of all, they deserve
First of all, they deserve it.
And
And hating
And hating them
And hating them is
And hating them is a
And hating them is a secret
And hating them is a secret way
And hating them is a secret way of
And hating them is a secret way of sort
of
of getting
And hating them is a secret way of sort
of getting even
of getting even with
And hating them is a secret way of sort
of getting even with them.
of getting even with them. You
And hating them is a secret way of sort
of getting even with them. You having
the
the little
the little hate
the little hate thoughts
the little hate thoughts out
the little hate thoughts out there.
the little hate thoughts out there. They
win
win their
the little hate thoughts out there. They
win their way
win their way through
the little hate thoughts out there. They
win their way through and
win their way through and stab
the little hate thoughts out there. They
win their way through and stab the
person.
person. You
person. You say,
person. You say, "Oh,
person. You say, "Oh, I
person. You say, "Oh, I want
person. You say, "Oh, I want to
person. You say, "Oh, I want to think
person. You say, "Oh, I want to think of
that.
that. That's
person. You say, "Oh, I want to think of
that. That's like
that. That's like a
person. You say, "Oh, I want to think of
that. That's like a witch
that. That's like a witch would
person. You say, "Oh, I want to think of
that. That's like a witch would think
that."
that." But
that." But that's
that." But that's what
that." But that's what you're
that." But that's what you're up
that." But that's what you're up to,
aren't
aren't you?
that." But that's what you're up to,
aren't you? Little
aren't you? Little stabbing
that." But that's what you're up to,
aren't you? Little stabbing thoughts.
Grief.
Grief. People
Grief. People hang
Grief. People hang on
Grief. People hang on to
Grief. People hang on to grief
Grief. People hang on to grief for
lifetimes.
About
About everything
About everything that's
About everything that's possible
About everything that's possible that
die
die has
About everything that's possible that
die has died
die has died around
About everything that's possible that
die has died around me.
die has died around me. How
About everything that's possible that
die has died around me. How long
die has died around me. How long you
going
going to
going to hang
going to hang on
going to hang on to
going to hang on to the
going to hang on to the grief
going to hang on to the grief about
that?
that? I'll
going to hang on to the grief about
that? I'll tell
that? I'll tell you
going to hang on to the grief about
that? I'll tell you how
that? I'll tell you how long
going to hang on to the grief about
that? I'll tell you how long to
that? I'll tell you how long to keep
going to hang on to the grief about
that? I'll tell you how long to keep it.
About
About one
About one second.
About one second. Let
About one second. Let it
About one second. Let it go
About one second. Let it go the
About one second. Let it go the instant
happens.
Just
Just let
Just let it
Just let it go.
Just let it go. Surrender
Just let it go. Surrender it
Just let it go. Surrender it completely
and
and totally
Just let it go. Surrender it completely
and totally to
and totally to God
Just let it go. Surrender it completely
and totally to God the
and totally to God the instant
Just let it go. Surrender it completely
and totally to God the instant it
happens.
Huh?
Why?
Why? Because
Why? Because you
Why? Because you develop
Why? Because you develop the
Why? Because you develop the capacity
Why? Because you develop the capacity to
do
do that.
Why? Because you develop the capacity to
do that. So
do that. So the
Why? Because you develop the capacity to
do that. So the reason
do that. So the reason for
Why? Because you develop the capacity to
do that. So the reason for spiritual
training
training then
is
is you
training then
is you develop
is you develop a
training then
is you develop a powerful
is you develop a powerful capacity
training then
is you develop a powerful capacity to
let
let go
let go of
let go of anything
and
and you
let go of anything
and you never
and you never know
let go of anything
and you never know when
and you never know when it's
let go of anything
and you never know when it's going
and you never know when it's going to
come
come up.
come up. So
come up. So and
come up. So and so
come up. So and so just
come up. So and so just died.
You
You just
come up. So and so just died.
You just let
You just let go
come up. So and so just died.
You just let go that
You just let go that instant.
come up. So and so just died.
You just let go that instant. The
You just let go that instant. The minute
you
you the
you the minute
you the minute the
you the minute the phone
you the minute the phone message
you the minute the phone message comes
in,
you
you let
you let it
you let it go.
You
You don't
you let it go.
You don't grieve
You don't grieve about
you let it go.
You don't grieve about it
You don't grieve about it 30
you let it go.
You don't grieve about it 30 years
later.
later. You
later. You don't
later. You don't celebrate
later. You don't celebrate every
anniversary
anniversary of
later. You don't celebrate every
anniversary of the
anniversary of the death
later. You don't celebrate every
anniversary of the death of
anniversary of the death of Cuckoo,
later. You don't celebrate every
anniversary of the death of Cuckoo, your
little
little bird.
little bird. Then
little bird. Then the
little bird. Then the next
little bird. Then the next two
little bird. Then the next two weeks
later,
later, it's
little bird. Then the next two weeks
later, it's you
later, it's you got
little bird. Then the next two weeks
later, it's you got to
later, it's you got to celebrate
little bird. Then the next two weeks
later, it's you got to celebrate the
birth
birth of
birth of Uncle
birth of Uncle Lou.
birth of Uncle Lou. And
birth of Uncle Lou. And then
birth of Uncle Lou. And then a
birth of Uncle Lou. And then a month
later,
later, it's
birth of Uncle Lou. And then a month
later, it's a
later, it's a time
birth of Uncle Lou. And then a month
later, it's a time to
later, it's a time to to
birth of Uncle Lou. And then a month
later, it's a time to to celebrate
later, it's a time to to celebrate the
death
death of
death of a
death of a Then
death of a Then your
death of a Then your mother's
death of a Then your mother's death
comes
comes up.
death of a Then your mother's death
comes up. The
comes up. The anniversary
death of a Then your mother's death
comes up. The anniversary of
comes up. The anniversary of all
death of a Then your mother's death
comes up. The anniversary of all this
as
as you
as you get
as you get older
as you get older and
as you get older and older,
as you get older and older, the
whole
whole calendar
as you get older and older, the
whole calendar is
whole calendar is the
as you get older and older, the
whole calendar is the anniversaries
whole calendar is the anniversaries of
crap.
We're
We're going
crap.
We're going to
We're going to keep
crap.
We're going to keep pumping
We're going to keep pumping 911
crap.
We're going to keep pumping 911 forever.
We
We already
We already we
We already we already
We already we already got
We already we already got December
We already we already got December 5th,
right?
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Then
>> Okay. Then you
>> Okay. Then you got
>> Okay. Then you got 1776.
>> Okay. Then you got 1776. We
>> Okay. Then you got 1776. We got
>> Okay. Then you got 1776. We got the
>> Okay. Then you got 1776. We got the end
of
of World
>> Okay. Then you got 1776. We got the end
of World One.
of World One. Then
>> Okay. Then you got 1776. We got the end
of World One. Then we
of World One. Then we got
>> Okay. Then you got 1776. We got the end
of World One. Then we got November
of World One. Then we got November 11th.
Don't
Don't forget
Don't forget November
Don't forget November 11th
Don't forget November 11th at
Don't forget November 11th at 11:00
Don't forget November 11th at 11:00 a.m.
When
When I
Don't forget November 11th at 11:00 a.m.
When I grew
When I grew up,
Don't forget November 11th at 11:00 a.m.
When I grew up, November
When I grew up, November 11th,
Don't forget November 11th at 11:00 a.m.
When I grew up, November 11th, 11:00
a.m.
a.m. was
a.m. was Armistice
a.m. was Armistice Day.
a.m. was Armistice Day. We
a.m. was Armistice Day. We all
a.m. was Armistice Day. We all held
a.m. was Armistice Day. We all held our
heart.
There's
There's a
There's a beautiful
There's a beautiful value
There's a beautiful value to
There's a beautiful value to it.
There's a beautiful value to it. I'm
just
just talking
There's a beautiful value to it. I'm
just talking about
just talking about the
There's a beautiful value to it. I'm
just talking about the diamond
just talking about the diamond side
There's a beautiful value to it. I'm
just talking about the diamond side of
it.
it. It's
it. It's one
it. It's one thing
it. It's one thing to
it. It's one thing to give
it. It's one thing to give respect
it. It's one thing to give respect and
send
send love
it. It's one thing to give respect and
send love to
send love to all
it. It's one thing to give respect and
send love to all those
send love to all those people
and
and to
and to do
and to do so
out
out of
and to do so
out of reverence.
All
All right?
We're
We're talking
All right?
We're talking about
We're talking about the
All right?
We're talking about the fact
We're talking about the fact that
All right?
We're talking about the fact that what
makes
makes these
makes these things
makes these things tenacious
is
is first
makes these things tenacious
is first of
is first of all
makes these things tenacious
is first of all you're
is first of all you're trained
makes these things tenacious
is first of all you're trained in
is first of all you're trained in them.
Your
Your mind
Your mind thinks
Your mind thinks this
Your mind thinks this way.
Your mind thinks this way. But
Your mind thinks this way. But after
you're
you're aware
Your mind thinks this way. But after
you're aware that
you're aware that you're
Your mind thinks this way. But after
you're aware that you're trained
you're aware that you're trained in
Your mind thinks this way. But after
you're aware that you're trained in them
and
and your
and your mind
and your mind thinks
and your mind thinks this
and your mind thinks this way
and your mind thinks this way and
and your mind thinks this way and you
see
see the
and your mind thinks this way and you
see the absurdity
see the absurdity of
and your mind thinks this way and you
see the absurdity of the
see the absurdity of the idea
and your mind thinks this way and you
see the absurdity of the idea of
causality,
causality, you'll
causality, you'll find
causality, you'll find that
causality, you'll find that your
causality, you'll find that your mind
still
still wants
causality, you'll find that your mind
still wants to
still wants to do
causality, you'll find that your mind
still wants to do this.
still wants to do this. And
causality, you'll find that your mind
still wants to do this. And you
still wants to do this. And you see,
causality, you'll find that your mind
still wants to do this. And you see, why
is
is my
is my mind
is my mind still
is my mind still doing
is my mind still doing that
is my mind still doing that when
is my mind still doing that when I
is my mind still doing that when I know
better?
better? And
is my mind still doing that when I know
better? And a
better? And a spiritual
is my mind still doing that when I know
better? And a spiritual student
better? And a spiritual student usually
goes
goes into
goes into that.
goes into that. I
goes into that. I know
goes into that. I know better.
goes into that. I know better. How
goes into that. I know better. How come
I'm
I'm still
goes into that. I know better. How come
I'm still hating
I'm still hating that
goes into that. I know better. How come
I'm still hating that guy
I'm still hating that guy and
goes into that. I know better. How come
I'm still hating that guy and want
I'm still hating that guy and want to
get
get even
get even with
get even with him?
get even with him? Why
get even with him? Why did
get even with him? Why did I
get even with him? Why did I give
get even with him? Why did I give him
the
the finger?
I
I told
I told you
I told you the
I told you the pleasure.
I told you the pleasure. I
I told you the pleasure. I got
I told you the pleasure. I got the
I told you the pleasure. I got the first
and
and only
I told you the pleasure. I got the first
and only time
and only time I
I told you the pleasure. I got the first
and only time I ever
and only time I ever did
I told you the pleasure. I got the first
and only time I ever did it
and only time I ever did it in
I told you the pleasure. I got the first
and only time I ever did it in my
and only time I ever did it in my life.
It
It was
It was terrific.
It was terrific. I
It was terrific. I can
It was terrific. I can see
It was terrific. I can see why
It was terrific. I can see why those
guys
guys are
It was terrific. I can see why those
guys are out
guys are out there
It was terrific. I can see why those
guys are out there throwing
guys are out there throwing stones
It was terrific. I can see why those
guys are out there throwing stones at
the
the Jews
the Jews and
the Jews and the
the Jews and the Jews
the Jews and the Jews are
the Jews and the Jews are throwing
the Jews and the Jews are throwing at
the
the Arabs
the Jews and the Jews are throwing at
the Arabs and
the Arabs and everybody's
the Jews and the Jews are throwing at
the Arabs and everybody's wanting
the Arabs and everybody's wanting to
kill
kill each
kill each other.
kill each other. I
kill each other. I mean,
kill each other. I mean, it's
kill each other. I mean, it's terrific.
Take
Take that.
I
I mean,
I mean, that's
I mean, that's a
I mean, that's a high
I mean, that's a high like
I mean, that's a high like uh
beats
beats riding
I mean, that's a high like uh
beats riding buck
beats riding buck and
I mean, that's a high like uh
beats riding buck and Broncos.
beats riding buck and Broncos. You
what
what I
what I mean?
what I mean? Got
what I mean? Got more
what I mean? Got more drama.
what I mean? Got more drama. You
what I mean? Got more drama. You see
those
those guys
what I mean? Got more drama. You see
those guys out
those guys out there
what I mean? Got more drama. You see
those guys out there at
those guys out there at a
what I mean? Got more drama. You see
those guys out there at a rodeo
and
and there's
and there's a
and there's a whole
and there's a whole bunch
and there's a whole bunch of
and there's a whole bunch of them
sitting
sitting behind
and there's a whole bunch of them
sitting behind me
sitting behind me and
and there's a whole bunch of them
sitting behind me and they
sitting behind me and they they've
and there's a whole bunch of them
sitting behind me and they they've all
their
their own
their own casts.
All
All of
their own casts.
All of them
All of them cast.
their own casts.
All of them cast. They've
All of them cast. They've all
their own casts.
All of them cast. They've all got
all
all cripping
all cripping up
all cripping up from
all cripping up from from
all cripping up from from riding
all cripping up from from riding riding
these
these bulls,
all cripping up from from riding riding
these bulls, you
these bulls, you know.
all cripping up from from riding riding
these bulls, you know. Can't
these bulls, you know. Can't wait
all cripping up from from riding riding
these bulls, you know. Can't wait to
these bulls, you know. Can't wait to get
on
on the
on the next
on the next one.
The
The juice
on the next one.
The juice you
The juice you get
on the next one.
The juice you get off
The juice you get off of
on the next one.
The juice you get off of that,
The juice you get off of that, you
on the next one.
The juice you get off of that, you know.
I
I mean,
I mean, the
I mean, the guy's
I mean, the guy's got
I mean, the guy's got he's
I mean, the guy's got he's had
I mean, the guy's got he's had six
fractures
fractures over
I mean, the guy's got he's had six
fractures over the
fractures over the last
I mean, the guy's got he's had six
fractures over the last five
fractures over the last five years
riding
riding bulls,
and
and he's
riding bulls,
and he's going
and he's going to
riding bulls,
and he's going to get
and he's going to get right
riding bulls,
and he's going to get right back
and he's going to get right back on
riding bulls,
and he's going to get right back on the
next
next bull.
Oh
Oh my
next bull.
Oh my gosh.
Extreme
Extreme sports,
Extreme sports, huh?
All right.
All right. So
Extreme sports, huh?
All right. So willingness
All right. So willingness then
Extreme sports, huh?
All right. So willingness then because
that's
that's one
that's one really
that's one really important
that's one really important aspect
that's one really important aspect of
love.
love. It's
that's one really important aspect of
love. It's willingness
love. It's willingness is
that's one really important aspect of
love. It's willingness is going
love. It's willingness is going to
really
really take
really take you
really take you up
really take you up here
really take you up here because
willingness
willingness is
really take you up here because
willingness is going
willingness is going to
give
give you
give you the
give you the motivation
give you the motivation to
give you the motivation to accept
things.
It's
It's also
It's also going
It's also going to
It's also going to take
It's also going to take you
It's also going to take you past
It's also going to take you past reason
which
which is
It's also going to take you past reason
which is the
which is the big
It's also going to take you past reason
which is the big roadblock.
The
The big
The big roadblock.
The big roadblock. Most
The big roadblock. Most of
The big roadblock. Most of the
The big roadblock. Most of the people
that
that go
The big roadblock. Most of the people
that go into
that go into spiritual
The big roadblock. Most of the people
that go into spiritual work
that go into spiritual work are
The big roadblock. Most of the people
that go into spiritual work are usually
in
in the
in the 400
in the 400 I
in the 400 I mean
in the 400 I mean many
in the 400 I mean many of
in the 400 I mean many of them
in the 400 I mean many of them the
in the 400 I mean many of them the 10
lectures
lectures like
in the 400 I mean many of them the 10
lectures like this
lectures like this are
in the 400 I mean many of them the 10
lectures like this are usually
lectures like this are usually in
in the 400 I mean many of them the 10
lectures like this are usually in the
400s
400s in
400s in which
400s in which reason
400s in which reason brings
400s in which reason brings them
400s in which reason brings them here
and
and now
400s in which reason brings them here
and now reason
and now reason becomes
400s in which reason brings them here
and now reason becomes the
and now reason becomes the block
400s in which reason brings them here
and now reason becomes the block because
very
very few
very few people
very few people to
very few people to get
very few people to get to
very few people to get to love
we
we said
very few people to get to love
we said love
we said love to
very few people to get to love
we said love to transcend
we said love to transcend the
very few people to get to love
we said love to transcend the 400s
we said love to transcend the 400s is
accomplished
accomplished by
accomplished by about
accomplished by about 4%
accomplished by about 4% of
accomplished by about 4% of the
population
population 4%.
accomplished by about 4% of the
population 4%. Whoa.
population 4%. Whoa. To
accomplished by about 4% of the
population 4%. Whoa. To get
population 4%. Whoa. To get to
unconditional
unconditional love
unconditional love is
unconditional love is 0.4%.
0.4%.
0.4%. Where's
unconditional love is 0.4%.
0.4%. Where's the
0.4%. Where's the numbers
unconditional love is 0.4%.
0.4%. Where's the numbers that
0.4%. Where's the numbers that go
unconditional love is 0.4%.
0.4%. Where's the numbers that go on
0.4%. Where's the numbers that go on all
this
this stuff?
this stuff? Oh,
this stuff? Oh, here
this stuff? Oh, here they
this stuff? Oh, here they are.
4%.
At
At 540.4%.
Wow.
So
So we
So we talk
So we talk about
So we talk about love
So we talk about love a
So we talk about love a lot
So we talk about love a lot but
So we talk about love a lot but as
So we talk about love a lot but as a
So we talk about love a lot but as a to
realize
realize uh
So we talk about love a lot but as a to
realize uh one's
realize uh one's identity
So we talk about love a lot but as a to
realize uh one's identity as
realize uh one's identity as that
So we talk about love a lot but as a to
realize uh one's identity as that which
is
is the
is the source
is the source of
is the source of life
is the source of life itself
is
is not
is the source of life itself
is not all
is not all that
is the source of life itself
is not all that easy
is not all that easy to
I
I would
I would not
I would not say
I would not say achieve
I would not say achieve but
I would not say achieve but that
I would not say achieve but that easy
I would not say achieve but that easy to
realize
and
and therefore
and therefore I
and therefore I I
and therefore I I I
and therefore I I I mentioned
and therefore I I I mentioned the
and therefore I I I mentioned the things
that
that I
and therefore I I I mentioned the things
that I think
that I think can
and therefore I I I mentioned the things
that I think can be
that I think can be useful
and therefore I I I mentioned the things
that I think can be useful that
that I think can be useful that are
generally
generally available
generally available not
generally available not everybody
generally available not everybody can
generally available not everybody can go
off
off and
generally available not everybody can go
off and join
off and join the
generally available not everybody can go
off and join the Nashim.
off and join the Nashim. Not
generally available not everybody can go
off and join the Nashim. Not everybody
can
can walk
can walk away
can walk away from
can walk away from their
can walk away from their family
can walk away from their family and
their
their job
can walk away from their family and
their job etc.
So
So how
So how can
So how can this
So how can this do
So how can this do go
So how can this do go then?
So how can this do go then? So
So how can this do go then? So the
willingness
willingness to
So how can this do go then? So the
willingness to let
willingness to let go
So how can this do go then? So the
willingness to let go of
positionalities,
positionalities, the
positionalities, the willingness
positionalities, the willingness to
surrender
not
not the
not the things
not the things themselves
not the things themselves but
not the things themselves but the
attachment
attachment to
not the things themselves but the
attachment to the
attachment to the things
not the things themselves but the
attachment to the things themselves.
attachment to the things themselves. You
don't
don't have
don't have to
don't have to give
don't have to give up
don't have to give up your
don't have to give up your Cadillac.
Um
Um but
don't have to give up your Cadillac.
Um but you
Um but you let
don't have to give up your Cadillac.
Um but you let go
Um but you let go of
don't have to give up your Cadillac.
Um but you let go of its
Um but you let go of its former
don't have to give up your Cadillac.
Um but you let go of its former meaning
to
to you.
You
You let
to you.
You let go
You let go striving
to you.
You let go striving for
You let go striving for success
to you.
You let go striving for success because
to
to realize
to realize the
to realize the truth
to realize the truth is
to realize the truth is the
to realize the truth is the is
to realize the truth is the is the
epitome
epitome of
to realize the truth is the is the
epitome of success.
epitome of success. To
to realize the truth is the is the
epitome of success. To realize
epitome of success. To realize the
to realize the truth is the is the
epitome of success. To realize the truth
of
of where
of where you
of where you are.
So
So renunciation
of where you are.
So renunciation then
So renunciation then means
of where you are.
So renunciation then means eventually
So renunciation then means eventually an
inner
inner renunciation.
the
the the
inner renunciation.
the the willingness
the the willingness to
inner renunciation.
the the willingness to let
the the willingness to let go
inner renunciation.
the the willingness to let go of
insisting
insisting that
insisting that if
insisting that if a
insisting that if a thing
insisting that if a thing is
insisting that if a thing is isn't
logical,
logical, it
insisting that if a thing is isn't
logical, it can't
logical, it can't be
insisting that if a thing is isn't
logical, it can't be true
logical, it can't be true and
insisting that if a thing is isn't
logical, it can't be true and all
logical, it can't be true and all these
kind
kind of
kind of positionalities.
The
The willingness
kind of positionalities.
The willingness to
The willingness to then
kind of positionalities.
The willingness to then uh
The willingness to then uh let
kind of positionalities.
The willingness to then uh let go
The willingness to then uh let go of
everything
everything that
everything that stands
everything that stands in
everything that stands in the
everything that stands in the way
everything that stands in the way of
love.
As
As we
As we do
As we do that,
As we do that, we
As we do that, we find
As we do that, we find that
As we do that, we find that uh
As we do that, we find that uh the
things
things that
As we do that, we find that uh the
things that keep
things that keep coming
As we do that, we find that uh the
things that keep coming up
things that keep coming up that
As we do that, we find that uh the
things that keep coming up that block
things that keep coming up that block us
from
from love
from love then
from love then are
from love then are feelings.
from love then are feelings. And
from love then are feelings. And these
feelings
feelings are
from love then are feelings. And these
feelings are based
feelings are based on
from love then are feelings. And these
feelings are based on certain
perceptions,
ways
ways of
perceptions,
ways of seeing
ways of seeing things,
perceptions,
ways of seeing things, ways
ways of seeing things, ways of
interpreting
interpreting them.
Conditionalities
Conditionalities that
interpreting them.
Conditionalities that we've
Conditionalities that we've been
brainwashed
brainwashed into
and
and ask,
brainwashed into
and ask, am
and ask, am I
brainwashed into
and ask, am I willing
and ask, am I willing to
brainwashed into
and ask, am I willing to surrender
and ask, am I willing to surrender that
to
to God?
Would
Would I
to God?
Would I rather
Would I rather be
to God?
Would I rather be right
Would I rather be right or
to God?
Would I rather be right or would
Would I rather be right or would I
rather
rather realize
rather realize the
rather realize the presence
rather realize the presence of
rather realize the presence of God?
So
So willingness
rather realize the presence of God?
So willingness then
So willingness then always
rather realize the presence of God?
So willingness then always puts
So willingness then always puts up
the
the untruth
the untruth against
the untruth against the
the untruth against the truth.
the untruth against the truth. And
the untruth against the truth. And I
ask,
ask, are
the untruth against the truth. And I
ask, are you
ask, are you willing
the untruth against the truth. And I
ask, are you willing to
ask, are you willing to let
the untruth against the truth. And I
ask, are you willing to let this
ask, are you willing to let this go?
To
To be
To be unwilling
To be unwilling to
To be unwilling to let
To be unwilling to let go
To be unwilling to let go attachment
To be unwilling to let go attachment to
Kitty
Kitty would
To be unwilling to let go attachment to
Kitty would mean
Kitty would mean grief,
To be unwilling to let go attachment to
Kitty would mean grief, wouldn't
Kitty would mean grief, wouldn't it?
You'd
You'd be
You'd be setting
You'd be setting yourself
You'd be setting yourself up
You'd be setting yourself up for
You'd be setting yourself up for grief.
I
I lose
You'd be setting yourself up for grief.
I lose the
I lose the cat.
You'd be setting yourself up for grief.
I lose the cat. Lose
I lose the cat. Lose the
You'd be setting yourself up for grief.
I lose the cat. Lose the cat.
I lose the cat. Lose the cat. Tonight's
going
going to
going to be
going to be awful.
going to be awful. Tomorrow
going to be awful. Tomorrow I
going to be awful. Tomorrow I won't
going to be awful. Tomorrow I won't be
able
able to
going to be awful. Tomorrow I won't be
able to lecture.
able to lecture. I'm
going to be awful. Tomorrow I won't be
able to lecture. I'm just
able to lecture. I'm just going
going to be awful. Tomorrow I won't be
able to lecture. I'm just going to
able to lecture. I'm just going to be
grieving
grieving and
grieving and weeping
grieving and weeping and
grieving and weeping and nashing
grieving and weeping and nashing my
teeth.
teeth. Right?
So
So you
So you see
So you see the
So you see the un
So you see the un unwillingness
So you see the un unwillingness then
So you see the un unwillingness then is
what
what sets
So you see the un unwillingness then is
what sets you
what sets you up
So you see the un unwillingness then is
what sets you up for
what sets you up for this.
You
You say
You say to
You say to yourself,
You say to yourself, am
You say to yourself, am I
You say to yourself, am I willing
You say to yourself, am I willing to
You say to yourself, am I willing to set
myself
myself up
You say to yourself, am I willing to set
myself up for
myself up for this
You say to yourself, am I willing to set
myself up for this or
myself up for this or let
You say to yourself, am I willing to set
myself up for this or let it
myself up for this or let it go?
You say to yourself, am I willing to set
myself up for this or let it go? Now
that
that makes
that makes it
that makes it a
that makes it a little
that makes it a little more
that makes it a little more real,
doesn't
doesn't it?
If
If you're
If you're willing
If you're willing to
If you're willing to let
If you're willing to let it
If you're willing to let it go
If you're willing to let it go for
If you're willing to let it go for some
airy
airy fairy
If you're willing to let it go for some
airy fairy sounding
airy fairy sounding thing
If you're willing to let it go for some
airy fairy sounding thing like
airy fairy sounding thing like the
presence
presence of
presence of God,
presence of God, which
presence of God, which sounds
presence of God, which sounds good,
presence of God, which sounds good, but
who
who knows
presence of God, which sounds good, but
who knows what
who knows what that
presence of God, which sounds good, but
who knows what that is.
But
But you
But you might
But you might be
But you might be willing
But you might be willing to
But you might be willing to let
But you might be willing to let it
But you might be willing to let it go
because
because if
But you might be willing to let it go
because if you
because if you don't,
But you might be willing to let it go
because if you don't, this
because if you don't, this is
But you might be willing to let it go
because if you don't, this is where
you're
you're going
you're going to
you're going to end
you're going to end up.
you're going to end up. End
you're going to end up. End up
down
down the
you're going to end up. End up
down the scale
down the scale suffering
you're going to end up. End up
down the scale suffering from
you
you see
you see wantingness
you see wantingness is
you see wantingness is an
you see wantingness is an endless
suffering,
suffering, isn't
you see wantingness is an endless
suffering, isn't it?
suffering, isn't it? Because
wantingness,
wantingness, the
wantingness, the constant
wantingness, the constant wanting
wantingness, the constant wanting things
is
is constantly
wantingness, the constant wanting things
is constantly setting
is constantly setting you
wantingness, the constant wanting things
is constantly setting you up
is constantly setting you up with
desire.
desire. You're
desire. You're always
desire. You're always wanting
desire. You're always wanting something.
I
I only
desire. You're always wanting something.
I only have
I only have one
desire. You're always wanting something.
I only have one want
I only have one want left
desire. You're always wanting something.
I only have one want left in
I only have one want left in the
desire. You're always wanting something.
I only have one want left in the world.
I
I keep
I keep it
I keep it there.
I keep it there. I
I keep it there. I cherish
I keep it there. I cherish it.
One
One worldly
I keep it there. I cherish it.
One worldly want.
He
He said,
He said, "God,
He said, "God, can't
He said, "God, can't I
He said, "God, can't I have
He said, "God, can't I have just
He said, "God, can't I have just one?
I
I don't
He said, "God, can't I have just one?
I don't really
I don't really have
He said, "God, can't I have just one?
I don't really have it,
I don't really have it, but
He said, "God, can't I have just one?
I don't really have it, but I
I don't really have it, but I have
He said, "God, can't I have just one?
I don't really have it, but I have a
picture
picture of
picture of it.
And
And I
picture of it.
And I carefully
And I carefully nurture
picture of it.
And I carefully nurture this
And I carefully nurture this wamp
because
because I'm
because I'm afraid
because I'm afraid if
because I'm afraid if it
because I'm afraid if it disappears,
you
you become
because I'm afraid if it disappears,
you become invisible.
Keeps
Keeps you
Keeps you here
Keeps you here to
Keeps you here to some
Keeps you here to some degree.
Keeps you here to some degree. You
Keeps you here to some degree. You need
one
one want
Keeps you here to some degree. You need
one want and
one want and one
Keeps you here to some degree. You need
one want and one attachment.
one want and one attachment. Something
I
I was
I was showing
I was showing people
I was showing people a
I was showing people a picture
I was showing people a picture of
I was showing people a picture of it
yesterday.
yesterday. Anyway,
the
the willingness
the willingness to
the willingness to renounce
the willingness to renounce it.
the willingness to renounce it. Am
the willingness to renounce it. Am I
willing
willing to
the willingness to renounce it. Am I
willing to renounce
willing to renounce it?
the willingness to renounce it. Am I
willing to renounce it? Yes.
In
In fact,
In fact, it
In fact, it just
In fact, it just went.
In fact, it just went. Well,
In fact, it just went. Well, okay.
In fact, it just went. Well, okay. Okay.
Uh,
all right.
all right. So,
all right. So, what
all right. So, what we're
all right. So, what we're developing
all right. So, what we're developing is
the
the spiritual
all right. So, what we're developing is
the spiritual muscles
so
so that
so that when
so that when you
so that when you need
so that when you need them,
they're
they're there.
so that when you need them,
they're there. As
they're there. As I
so that when you need them,
they're there. As I step
they're there. As I step over
so that when you need them,
they're there. As I step over the
rattlesnake,
there
there I
rattlesnake,
there I am
there I am on
rattlesnake,
there I am on the
there I am on the top
rattlesnake,
there I am on the top of
there I am on the top of Schnebly
rattlesnake,
there I am on the top of Schnebly Hill.
I
I was
I was looking
I was looking at
I was looking at a
I was looking at a big
I was looking at a big place
I was looking at a big place there.
And
And as
I was looking at a big place there.
And as I
And as I step
I was looking at a big place there.
And as I step over
And as I step over it,
I was looking at a big place there.
And as I step over it, good
And as I step over it, good God
almighty,
almighty, there
almighty, there is
almighty, there is the
almighty, there is the hugest
almighty, there is the hugest rattler
you
you ever
almighty, there is the hugest rattler
you ever saw.
you ever saw. Good
almighty, there is the hugest rattler
you ever saw. Good lord.
H.
H. And
H. And in
H. And in that
H. And in that instant
H. And in that instant there
H. And in that instant there was
H. And in that instant there was letting
go
go at
H. And in that instant there was letting
go at absolute
go at absolute death
H. And in that instant there was letting
go at absolute death depth
go at absolute death depth and
H. And in that instant there was letting
go at absolute death depth and absolute
letting
letting goess.
letting goess. All
letting goess. All fear
letting goess. All fear disappeared.
letting goess. All fear disappeared. All
all
all perception
letting goess. All fear disappeared. All
all perception of
all perception of it
letting goess. All fear disappeared. All
all perception of it as
all perception of it as a
letting goess. All fear disappeared. All
all perception of it as a possible
all perception of it as a possible enemy
or
or it
or it and
or it and in
or it and in his
or it and in his place
or it and in his place there
or it and in his place there was
or it and in his place there was a
profound
profound stillness
or it and in his place there was a
profound stillness and
profound stillness and peace
or it and in his place there was a
profound stillness and peace that
profound stillness and peace that was
infinitely
infinitely powerful.
The
The presence
infinitely powerful.
The presence of
The presence of love
infinitely powerful.
The presence of love of
The presence of love of presence
infinitely powerful.
The presence of love of presence of
The presence of love of presence of God
is
so
so powerful
is
so powerful it
so powerful it sweeps
is
so powerful it sweeps away
so powerful it sweeps away everything.
And
And so
And so the
And so the snake
And so the snake is
And so the snake is held
And so the snake is held there
suspended.
suspended. It's
And so the snake is held there
suspended. It's like
suspended. It's like that
And so the snake is held there
suspended. It's like that can't
suspended. It's like that can't move.
That
That profound
That profound state
That profound state of
That profound state of peace,
That profound state of peace, the
stillness
stillness of
That profound state of peace, the
stillness of the
stillness of the presence
That profound state of peace, the
stillness of the presence of
stillness of the presence of God
That profound state of peace, the
stillness of the presence of God holds
all
all within
all within itself
and
and nothing
all within itself
and nothing can
and nothing can withstand
all within itself
and nothing can withstand it.
So
So when
So when you
So when you need
So when you need it,
So when you need it, when
So when you need it, when you
So when you need it, when you need
So when you need it, when you need it,
that
that capacity
So when you need it, when you need it,
that capacity was
that capacity was already
So when you need it, when you need it,
that capacity was already perfected
that capacity was already perfected to
completely
completely let
completely let go
completely let go totally
completely let go totally at
completely let go totally at all
completely let go totally at all at
great
great depth.
And
And otherwise
And otherwise I
And otherwise I wouldn't
And otherwise I wouldn't be
And otherwise I wouldn't be here
And otherwise I wouldn't be here today
cuz
cuz a
And otherwise I wouldn't be here today
cuz a snake
cuz a snake would
And otherwise I wouldn't be here today
cuz a snake would have
cuz a snake would have just
And otherwise I wouldn't be here today
cuz a snake would have just done
cuz a snake would have just done a
And otherwise I wouldn't be here today
cuz a snake would have just done a snake
thing
thing and
thing and I
thing and I just
thing and I just do
thing and I just do my
thing and I just do my human
thing and I just do my human thing
thing and I just do my human thing and
you
you know
we
we both
we both would
we both would have
we both would have been
we both would have been in
we both would have been in trouble
we both would have been in trouble you
know
so
so a
so a higher
so a higher state
so a higher state prevailed
so a higher state prevailed h
so a higher state prevailed h so
so a higher state prevailed h so you
never
never know
so a higher state prevailed h so you
never know when
never know when you're
so a higher state prevailed h so you
never know when you're going
never know when you're going to
so a higher state prevailed h so you
never know when you're going to need
this
this capacity
you
you have
this capacity
you have to
you have to be
this capacity
you have to be and
you have to be and and
this capacity
you have to be and and one
you have to be and and one meditative
this capacity
you have to be and and one meditative uh
con
con style
con style is
con style is to
con style is to look
con style is to look at
con style is to look at all
con style is to look at all the
con style is to look at all the things
uh
uh in
con style is to look at all the things
uh in your
uh in your life
con style is to look at all the things
uh in your life and
uh in your life and keep
con style is to look at all the things
uh in your life and keep surrendering
what
what what
what what there
what what there is
what what there is about
what what there is about it.
what what there is about it. Aversion
what what there is about it. Aversion or
attachment.
So
So this
So this is
So this is the
So this is the willingness
So this is the willingness to
So this is the willingness to surrender
attachments
attachments and
So this is the willingness to surrender
attachments and aversions.
Do
Do I
Do I really
Do I really care
Do I really care if
Do I really care if the
Do I really care if the rattlesnake
kills
kills me?
Do I really care if the rattlesnake
kills me? To
kills me? To tell
Do I really care if the rattlesnake
kills me? To tell you
kills me? To tell you the
Do I really care if the rattlesnake
kills me? To tell you the truth,
kills me? To tell you the truth, no.
No.
No. Why
No. Why not
No. Why not now?
No. Why not now? I
No. Why not now? I mean
No. Why not now? I mean later
No. Why not now? I mean later it's
certain.
certain. So
No. Why not now? I mean later it's
certain. So why
certain. So why not
No. Why not now? I mean later it's
certain. So why not now?
certain. So why not now? But
No. Why not now? I mean later it's
certain. So why not now? But the
difference
difference of
difference of the
difference of the body
difference of the body any
difference of the body any day.
difference of the body any day. uh
whether
whether it's
difference of the body any day. uh
whether it's today
whether it's today or
difference of the body any day. uh
whether it's today or tomorrow
whether it's today or tomorrow doesn't
really
really make
really make any
really make any difference
that
that capacity
really make any difference
that capacity then
that capacity then to
really make any difference
that capacity then to surrender
that capacity then to surrender to
really make any difference
that capacity then to surrender to let
go
is
is a
go
is a is
is a is a
go
is a is a form
is a is a form of
go
is a is a form of love.
is a is a form of love. See
go
is a is a form of love. See we
is a is a form of love. See we call
go
is a is a form of love. See we call love
a
a calibrated
a calibrated level
a calibrated level of
a calibrated level of consciousness
a calibrated level of consciousness but
actually
actually all
a calibrated level of consciousness but
actually all these
actually all these things
a calibrated level of consciousness but
actually all these things from
actually all these things from here
a calibrated level of consciousness but
actually all these things from here up
are
are all
are all forms
are all forms of
are all forms of love.
are all forms of love. This
are all forms of love. This is
are all forms of love. This is love
are all forms of love. This is love in
the
the in
are all forms of love. This is love in
the in the
the in the form
are all forms of love. This is love in
the in the form of
the in the form of the
are all forms of love. This is love in
the in the form of the capacity
the in the form of the capacity to
are all forms of love. This is love in
the in the form of the capacity to tell
the
the truth
the truth about
the truth about yourself.
That's
That's why
the truth about yourself.
That's why being
That's why being sensitive
the truth about yourself.
That's why being sensitive is
That's why being sensitive is a
the truth about yourself.
That's why being sensitive is a very
indicative
indicative that
indicative that you
indicative that you need
indicative that you need help.
If
If you
indicative that you need help.
If you get
If you get offended
indicative that you need help.
If you get offended by
If you get offended by things,
indicative that you need help.
If you get offended by things, feel
uncomfortable
uncomfortable about
uncomfortable about them,
uncomfortable about them, you
uncomfortable about them, you better
uncomfortable about them, you better see
your
your doctor
because
because if
because if you
because if you really
because if you really accept
because if you really accept who
because if you really accept who you
are,
are, nothing
because if you really accept who you
are, nothing can
are, nothing can make
because if you really accept who you
are, nothing can make you
are, nothing can make you feel
uncomfortable.
uncomfortable. Nothing
uncomfortable. Nothing can
uncomfortable. Nothing can be
uncomfortable. Nothing can be uh,
you
you know,
uncomfortable. Nothing can be uh,
you know, injurious
you know, injurious to
uncomfortable. Nothing can be uh,
you know, injurious to your
you know, injurious to your self-esteem
because
because if
because if you're
because if you're quite
because if you're quite evolved,
because if you're quite evolved, you
don't
don't have
because if you're quite evolved, you
don't have any
don't have any self-esteem.
How
How can
How can injure
How can injure people
How can injure people injure
How can injure people injure your
self-esteem
self-esteem when
How can injure people injure your
self-esteem when you
self-esteem when you don't
How can injure people injure your
self-esteem when you don't have
self-esteem when you don't have any?
I
I said
I said if
I said if what
I said if what do
I said if what do you
I said if what do you need
I said if what do you need self-esteem
for?
Does
Does a
Does a bird
Does a bird need
Does a bird need self-esteem
Does a bird need self-esteem to
Does a bird need self-esteem to fly?
Does a bird need self-esteem to fly? It
doesn't
doesn't need
Does a bird need self-esteem to fly? It
doesn't need this
doesn't need this self-esteem.
Does a bird need self-esteem to fly? It
doesn't need this self-esteem. I
doesn't need this self-esteem. I mean,
this
this is
this is an
this is an pertinance
this is an pertinance that
this is an pertinance that you
this is an pertinance that you pass
around
around to
this is an pertinance that you pass
around to yourself.
There's
There's always
There's always somebody
There's always somebody in
There's always somebody in the
There's always somebody in the news
There's always somebody in the news 6:30
who's
whose
whose sensitivities
whose sensitivities have
whose sensitivities have been
whose sensitivities have been offended.
I
I mean,
whose sensitivities have been offended.
I mean, you
I mean, you can't
whose sensitivities have been offended.
I mean, you can't live
I mean, you can't live in
whose sensitivities have been offended.
I mean, you can't live in this
I mean, you can't live in this world
without
without offending
without offending somebody's
without offending somebody's sensitivity
nowadays.
You
You get
You get up
You get up and
You get up and give
You get up and give the
You get up and give the lady
You get up and give the lady a
You get up and give the lady a se
You get up and give the lady a se her
seat.
seat. You
You get up and give the lady a se her
seat. You feel
seat. You feel that
You get up and give the lady a se her
seat. You feel that she
seat. You feel that she feels
You get up and give the lady a se her
seat. You feel that she feels offended
because
because you're
because you're insulting
because you're insulting her
because you're insulting her that
feminine
feminine is
because you're insulting her that
feminine is weaker
feminine is weaker than
because you're insulting her that
feminine is weaker than male
feminine is weaker than male or
something.
something. If
something. If you
something. If you hold
something. If you hold the
something. If you hold the door,
something. If you hold the door, if
something. If you hold the door, if you
don't
don't hold
something. If you hold the door, if you
don't hold the
don't hold the door,
something. If you hold the door, if you
don't hold the door, so
don't hold the door, so I
something. If you hold the door, if you
don't hold the door, so I mean
don't hold the door, so I mean you're
offending
offending somebody
offending somebody no matter
offending somebody no matter what
offending somebody no matter what you
do.
do. You
offending somebody no matter what you
do. You see
do. You see nothing.
So
So every
So every night
So every night somebody's
So every night somebody's offended
So every night somebody's offended by
something.
What
What was
What was it
What was it this
What was it this week?
What was it this week? This
What was it this week? This week
What was it this week? This week there
was
was a
What was it this week? This week there
was a group
was a group in
What was it this week? This week there
was a group in Berkeley
was a group in Berkeley that
What was it this week? This week there
was a group in Berkeley that might
was a group in Berkeley that might be
offended
offended if
offended if they
offended if they showed
offended if they showed the
offended if they showed the red,
offended if they showed the red, white,
and
and blue
offended if they showed the red, white,
and blue on
and blue on the
offended if they showed the red, white,
and blue on the campus.
to
to celebrate
to celebrate 9/11.
to celebrate 9/11. There
to celebrate 9/11. There was
to celebrate 9/11. There was a
to celebrate 9/11. There was a group
that
that politically
to celebrate 9/11. There was a group
that politically felt
that politically felt people
to celebrate 9/11. There was a group
that politically felt people might
that politically felt people might be
offended
offended by
offended by showing
offended by showing the
offended by showing the red,
offended by showing the red, white,
offended by showing the red, white, and
blue
blue on
offended by showing the red, white, and
blue on the
blue on the campus.
offended by showing the red, white, and
blue on the campus. So,
blue on the campus. So, you
offended by showing the red, white, and
blue on the campus. So, you can
blue on the campus. So, you can be
offended
offended by
offended by the
offended by the flag.
offended by the flag. You
offended by the flag. You can
offended by the flag. You can be
offended
offended by
offended by the flag. You can be
offended by anything.
offended by anything. And
offended by the flag. You can be
offended by anything. And lots
offended by anything. And lots of
offended by the flag. You can be
offended by anything. And lots of people
are
are offended
are offended by
are offended by God
are offended by God or
are offended by God or any
are offended by God or any mention
thereof.
That's
That's right.
That's right. They
That's right. They have
That's right. They have a
That's right. They have a political
group,
group, don't
That's right. They have a political
group, don't they?
group, don't they? I
That's right. They have a political
group, don't they? I forget
group, don't they? I forget all
That's right. They have a political
group, don't they? I forget all about
that.
that. Remove
that. Remove God
that. Remove God from
that. Remove God from everything.
that. Remove God from everything. Eurus
something
something or
that. Remove God from everything. Eurus
something or other
something or other in
that. Remove God from everything. Eurus
something or other in in
something or other in in blank.
that. Remove God from everything. Eurus
something or other in in blank. We
something or other in in blank. We trust
the
the United
the United States
the United States Treasury.
We
We call
the United States Treasury.
We call you
We call you Constitution.
the United States Treasury.
We call you Constitution. We'll
We call you Constitution. We'll have
the United States Treasury.
We call you Constitution. We'll have to
rewrite
rewrite that
rewrite that equality
rewrite that equality of
rewrite that equality of man
rewrite that equality of man is
guaranteed
guaranteed by
rewrite that equality of man is
guaranteed by the
guaranteed by the divinity
rewrite that equality of man is
guaranteed by the divinity blank.
guaranteed by the divinity blank. We
have
have to
have to delete
have to delete divinity
have to delete divinity of
have to delete divinity of his
origination
and
all
all right.
and
all right. So
all right. So try
and
all right. So try to
all right. So try to pretend
and
all right. So try to pretend um
when
when you
when you totally
when you totally accept
when you totally accept the
when you totally accept the reality
when you totally accept the reality of
who
who you
when you totally accept the reality of
who you are,
who you are, you
when you totally accept the reality of
who you are, you can't
who you are, you can't be
when you totally accept the reality of
who you are, you can't be offended.
You're
You're fat.
You're fat. So
You're fat. So they
You're fat. So they can
You're fat. So they can call
You're fat. So they can call you
You're fat. So they can call you any
name
name they
You're fat. So they can call you any
name they want
name they want to.
You're fat. So they can call you any
name they want to. Shorty,
name they want to. Shorty, four
You're fat. So they can call you any
name they want to. Shorty, four eyes,
dumbbell,
dumbbell, right?
Somebody
Somebody calls
dumbbell, right?
Somebody calls you
Somebody calls you a
dumbbell, right?
Somebody calls you a liar.
Somebody calls you a liar. Tell
dumbbell, right?
Somebody calls you a liar. Tell them
Somebody calls you a liar. Tell them I'm
the
the best
the best liar
the best liar on
the best liar on the
the best liar on the planet.
the best liar on the planet. You
the best liar on the planet. You want
the best liar on the planet. You want to
harm
harm me?
the best liar on the planet. You want to
harm me? I'm
harm me? I'm worth
the best liar on the planet. You want to
harm me? I'm worth a
harm me? I'm worth a fortune.
Yeah,
Yeah, you're
Yeah, you're bad
Yeah, you're bad looking.
Yeah, you're bad looking. I
Yeah, you're bad looking. I say
Yeah, you're bad looking. I say every
time
time I
Yeah, you're bad looking. I say every
time I look
time I look in
Yeah, you're bad looking. I say every
time I look in the
time I look in the morning,
Yeah, you're bad looking. I say every
time I look in the morning, I
time I look in the morning, I I
Yeah, you're bad looking. I say every
time I look in the morning, I I call
911.
911. I
911. I think
911. I think I
911. I think I look
911. I think I look at
911. I think I look at myself
911. I think I look at myself in
911. I think I look at myself in the
mirror
mirror and
911. I think I look at myself in the
mirror and I
mirror and I call
911. I think I look at myself in the
mirror and I call 911.
mirror and I call 911. I
911. I think I look at myself in the
mirror and I call 911. I mean,
mirror and I call 911. I mean, I'm
911. I think I look at myself in the
mirror and I call 911. I mean, I'm so
ugly.
You
You say
ugly.
You say to
You say to yourself,
ugly.
You say to yourself, the
You say to yourself, the reason
ugly.
You say to yourself, the reason I
You say to yourself, the reason I have
all
all these
all these problems
all these problems in
all these problems in life
all these problems in life is
all these problems in life is cuz
all these problems in life is cuz I'm
all these problems in life is cuz I'm so
stupid
stupid and
all these problems in life is cuz I'm so
stupid and I'm
stupid and I'm so
all these problems in life is cuz I'm so
stupid and I'm so ugly.
That's
That's true.
It's
It's cuz
That's true.
It's cuz I'm
It's cuz I'm stupid.
That's true.
It's cuz I'm stupid. Well,
It's cuz I'm stupid. Well, all right.
You
You see,
You see, once
You see, once you
You see, once you accept
You see, once you accept the
You see, once you accept the possible
downside
downside of
You see, once you accept the possible
downside of everything,
uh,
uh, nobody
uh, nobody can
uh, nobody can offend
uh, nobody can offend you.
You're
You're greedy.
uh, nobody can offend you.
You're greedy. Yeah,
You're greedy. Yeah, I
uh, nobody can offend you.
You're greedy. Yeah, I am
You're greedy. Yeah, I am greedy.
uh, nobody can offend you.
You're greedy. Yeah, I am greedy. I'm
Mr.
Mr. Green,
Mr. Green, man.
Mr. Green, man. Give
Mr. Green, man. Give me
Mr. Green, man. Give me what
Mr. Green, man. Give me what I
Mr. Green, man. Give me what I want.
Mr. Green, man. Give me what I want. You
know what
know what I
Mr. Green, man. Give me what I want. You
know what I mean?
know what I mean? You
Mr. Green, man. Give me what I want. You
know what I mean? You just
know what I mean? You just become
Mr. Green, man. Give me what I want. You
know what I mean? You just become that
which
which people
which people say
which people say you
which people say you are.
which people say you are. You're
impervious.
impervious. There's
which people say you are. You're
impervious. There's nothing
impervious. There's nothing you
which people say you are. You're
impervious. There's nothing you can
impervious. There's nothing you can say.
Uh-huh.
So,
So, you
Uh-huh.
So, you see,
So, you see, we
Uh-huh.
So, you see, we can't
So, you see, we can't make
Uh-huh.
So, you see, we can't make neuroticism
the
the law
the law of
the law of the
the law of the land.
the law of the land. You're
the law of the land. You're not
the law of the land. You're not going
the law of the land. You're not going to
be
be able
the law of the land. You're not going to
be able to
be able to not
the law of the land. You're not going to
be able to not offend
be able to not offend somebody.
the law of the land. You're not going to
be able to not offend somebody. See,
because
because some
because some people
because some people are
because some people are going
because some people are going to
because some people are going to be
offended
offended if
because some people are going to be
offended if you
offended if you do,
because some people are going to be
offended if you do, and
offended if you do, and some
because some people are going to be
offended if you do, and some people
offended if you do, and some people are
going to
going to be
going to be offended
going to be offended if
going to be offended if you
going to be offended if you don't.
Consequently,
Consequently, you're
going to be offended if you don't.
Consequently, you're always
Consequently, you're always going
going to be offended if you don't.
Consequently, you're always going to
offend
offend somebody,
offend somebody, so
offend somebody, so live
offend somebody, so live with
offend somebody, so live with it.
You're
You're offended
offend somebody, so live with it.
You're offended when
You're offended when you
offend somebody, so live with it.
You're offended when you go
You're offended when you go through
offend somebody, so live with it.
You're offended when you go through the
line
line in
line in the
line in the airport,
line in the airport, so
line in the airport, so be
line in the airport, so be offended.
line in the airport, so be offended. I
mean,
mean, if
line in the airport, so be offended. I
mean, if it's
mean, if it's your
line in the airport, so be offended. I
mean, if it's your problem,
mean, if it's your problem, if
line in the airport, so be offended. I
mean, if it's your problem, if you're
offended,
offended, that's
offended, that's the
offended, that's the law
offended, that's the law of
offended, that's the law of the
offended, that's the law of the land
right
right now.
offended, that's the law of the land
right now. So
context
context then
context then h
so
so truth
context then h
so truth then
so truth then what
context then h
so truth then what we
so truth then what we call
context then h
so truth then what we call truth
so truth then what we call truth which
is
is usually
is usually discontent
depends
depends on
is usually discontent
depends on context.
depends on context. What's
is usually discontent
depends on context. What's truth
depends on context. What's truth today
is
is not
is not truth
is not truth tomorrow.
What's
What's appropriate
is not truth tomorrow.
What's appropriate today
What's appropriate today is
is not truth tomorrow.
What's appropriate today is not
appropriate
appropriate tomorrow.
appropriate tomorrow. What's
appropriate tomorrow. What's appropriate
in
in this
appropriate tomorrow. What's appropriate
in this circumstance
in this circumstance is
appropriate tomorrow. What's appropriate
in this circumstance is not
in this circumstance is not appropriate
in
in that
in that circumstance.
in that circumstance. You
in that circumstance. You see
in that circumstance. You see what
in that circumstance. You see what I'm
saying?
The
The difficulty
The difficulty then
The difficulty then with
The difficulty then with one
irrationality
irrationality is
The difficulty then with one
irrationality is it
irrationality is it doesn't
The difficulty then with one
irrationality is it doesn't understand
that
that meaning
comes
comes out
that meaning
comes out of
comes out of context
that meaning
comes out of context not
comes out of context not just
that meaning
comes out of context not just content.
So
So the
So the political
So the political position
So the political position that
So the political position that is
causing
causing most
So the political position that is
causing most the
causing most the aggravations
So the political position that is
causing most the aggravations in
causing most the aggravations in society
right
right now
right now is
right now is the
right now is the inability
right now is the inability to
right now is the inability to discern
that
that context
right now is the inability to discern
that context totally
that context totally changes
right now is the inability to discern
that context totally changes content.
What's
What's suitable
What's suitable in
What's suitable in peace
What's suitable in peace is
What's suitable in peace is not
What's suitable in peace is not the
What's suitable in peace is not the same
as
as suitable
What's suitable in peace is not the same
as suitable in
as suitable in war.
What's suitable in peace is not the same
as suitable in war. what's
as suitable in war. what's suitable
uh
uh in
uh in the
uh in the inner
uh in the inner city
uh in the inner city streets
uh in the inner city streets is
uh in the inner city streets is not
suitable
suitable in
uh in the inner city streets is not
suitable in Park
suitable in Park Avenue
uh in the inner city streets is not
suitable in Park Avenue and
suitable in Park Avenue and site.
uh in the inner city streets is not
suitable in Park Avenue and site. So
what
what is
what is appropriate
what is appropriate shifts
what is appropriate shifts depending
what is appropriate shifts depending on
context
context who
what is appropriate shifts depending on
context who when
context who when the
what is appropriate shifts depending on
context who when the totality
context who when the totality of
what is appropriate shifts depending on
context who when the totality of the
universe.
universe. So
universe. So context
universe. So context is
universe. So context is really
universe. So context is really the
totality
totality of
universe. So context is really the
totality of the
totality of the whole
universe. So context is really the
totality of the whole history
totality of the whole history of
universe. So context is really the
totality of the whole history of the
entire
entire universe.
entire universe. And
entire universe. And if
entire universe. And if people
entire universe. And if people are
entire universe. And if people are going
to
to insist
entire universe. And if people are going
to insist on
to insist on looking
entire universe. And if people are going
to insist on looking for
to insist on looking for a
entire universe. And if people are going
to insist on looking for a cause,
to insist on looking for a cause, you
tell
tell the
tell the cause
tell the cause of
tell the cause of it
tell the cause of it is
tell the cause of it is the
tell the cause of it is the totality
tell the cause of it is the totality of
the
the entire
tell the cause of it is the totality of
the entire universe
the entire universe throughout
tell the cause of it is the totality of
the entire universe throughout all
the entire universe throughout all of
time.
time. And
time. And that's
time. And that's why
time. And that's why this
time. And that's why this little
time. And that's why this little piece
of
of dust
time. And that's why this little piece
of dust is
of dust is sitting
time. And that's why this little piece
of dust is sitting right
of dust is sitting right where
time. And that's why this little piece
of dust is sitting right where it
of dust is sitting right where it is,
you
you know,
you know, and
you know, and trying
you know, and trying to
you know, and trying to pin
you know, and trying to pin it
you know, and trying to pin it on
you know, and trying to pin it on me,
man.
man. Forget
you know, and trying to pin it on me,
man. Forget it.
It's
It's the
It's the universe's
It's the universe's fault.
I'll
I'll be
It's the universe's fault.
I'll be some
I'll be some lawyer,
It's the universe's fault.
I'll be some lawyer, wouldn't
I'll be some lawyer, wouldn't I?
It's the universe's fault.
I'll be some lawyer, wouldn't I? I'd
love
love to
love to be
love to be a
love to be a lawyer.
love to be a lawyer. I'd
love to be a lawyer. I'd love
love to be a lawyer. I'd love to
love to be a lawyer. I'd love to be
love to be a lawyer. I'd love to be a
lawyer,
lawyer, man.
love to be a lawyer. I'd love to be a
lawyer, man. I
lawyer, man. I just
because
because I
because I can
because I can see
because I can see the
because I can see the lack
because I can see the lack of
because I can see the lack of logic
because I can see the lack of logic and
it's
it's always
because I can see the lack of logic and
it's always one
it's always one of
because I can see the lack of logic and
it's always one of confusing
it's always one of confusing content,
taking
taking content
taking content out
taking content out of
taking content out of context
taking content out of context and
confusing
confusing the
taking content out of context and
confusing the two.
confusing the two. You
taking content out of context and
confusing the two. You see
confusing the two. You see what
taking content out of context and
confusing the two. You see what I'm
saying?
And
And assuming
saying?
And assuming causes
And assuming causes when
saying?
And assuming causes when there
And assuming causes when there is
saying?
And assuming causes when there is no
such
such cause
such cause in
such cause in the
such cause in the universe
such cause in the universe anyway.
such cause in the universe anyway. All
right.
right. the
such cause in the universe anyway. All
right. the willingness
right. the willingness to
such cause in the universe anyway. All
right. the willingness to let
right. the willingness to let go
such cause in the universe anyway. All
right. the willingness to let go all
blocks
blocks then.
blocks then. So
blocks then. So this
blocks then. So this is
blocks then. So this is a
blocks then. So this is a form
blocks then. So this is a form of
blocks then. So this is a form of love.
This
This is
blocks then. So this is a form of love.
This is the
This is the courage
blocks then. So this is a form of love.
This is the courage to
This is the courage to accept
blocks then. So this is a form of love.
This is the courage to accept the
This is the courage to accept the truth
of
of who
of who you
of who you are.
of who you are. Yeah.
of who you are. Yeah. I
of who you are. Yeah. I have
of who you are. Yeah. I have a
of who you are. Yeah. I have a certain
problem
problem and
of who you are. Yeah. I have a certain
problem and I'm
problem and I'm going
of who you are. Yeah. I have a certain
problem and I'm going to
problem and I'm going to go
of who you are. Yeah. I have a certain
problem and I'm going to go to
problem and I'm going to go to a
of who you are. Yeah. I have a certain
problem and I'm going to go to a 12step
meeting
meeting about
meeting about it.
meeting about it. I
meeting about it. I told
meeting about it. I told lady
meeting about it. I told lady that
meeting about it. I told lady that in
the
the office
meeting about it. I told lady that in
the office this
the office this this
meeting about it. I told lady that in
the office this this week.
the office this this week. I
meeting about it. I told lady that in
the office this this week. I thought
the office this this week. I thought she
was
was going
was going to
was going to buck
was going to buck me
was going to buck me on
was going to buck me on it
was going to buck me on it and
was going to buck me on it and she
was going to buck me on it and she said,
"Oh,
"Oh, I'm
was going to buck me on it and she said,
"Oh, I'm going
"Oh, I'm going to
was going to buck me on it and she said,
"Oh, I'm going to go
"Oh, I'm going to go start
was going to buck me on it and she said,
"Oh, I'm going to go start going
"Oh, I'm going to go start going back
was going to buck me on it and she said,
"Oh, I'm going to go start going back to
meetings."
meetings." I
meetings." I Whoa.
meetings." I Whoa. Thank
meetings." I Whoa. Thank you,
meetings." I Whoa. Thank you, Lord.
meetings." I Whoa. Thank you, Lord. I
have
have to
meetings." I Whoa. Thank you, Lord. I
have to argue
have to argue with
meetings." I Whoa. Thank you, Lord. I
have to argue with her.
have to argue with her. So,
meetings." I Whoa. Thank you, Lord. I
have to argue with her. So, a
have to argue with her. So, a lot
meetings." I Whoa. Thank you, Lord. I
have to argue with her. So, a lot of
people
people hit
people hit bottom
people hit bottom here.
people hit bottom here. This
people hit bottom here. This is
people hit bottom here. This is where
you
you hit
people hit bottom here. This is where
you hit bottom.
you hit bottom. All
people hit bottom here. This is where
you hit bottom. All this
you hit bottom. All this stuff
people hit bottom here. This is where
you hit bottom. All this stuff here
you hit bottom. All this stuff here has
taken
taken you
taken you to
taken you to the
taken you to the point
taken you to the point that
taken you to the point that it's
taken you to the point that it's not
working
working anymore.
taken you to the point that it's not
working anymore. And
working anymore. And suddenly
taken you to the point that it's not
working anymore. And suddenly you
working anymore. And suddenly you become
quite
quite open.
quite open. Quite
quite open. Quite open.
quite open. Quite open. And
quite open. Quite open. And neutra
quite open. Quite open. And neutra would
mean,
mean, yeah,
quite open. Quite open. And neutra would
mean, yeah, I
mean, yeah, I don't
quite open. Quite open. And neutra would
mean, yeah, I don't care
mean, yeah, I don't care if
quite open. Quite open. And neutra would
mean, yeah, I don't care if I
mean, yeah, I don't care if I go
quite open. Quite open. And neutra would
mean, yeah, I don't care if I go to
mean, yeah, I don't care if I go to the
meetings
meetings or
meetings or I
meetings or I do
meetings or I do go
meetings or I do go to
meetings or I do go to the
meetings or I do go to the meetings.
meetings or I do go to the meetings. If
you
you say
meetings or I do go to the meetings. If
you say I
you say I should
meetings or I do go to the meetings. If
you say I should go
you say I should go to
meetings or I do go to the meetings. If
you say I should go to the
you say I should go to the meetings,
then
then I'm
then I'm willing
then I'm willing because
then I'm willing because I
then I'm willing because I accept
then I'm willing because I accept that
then I'm willing because I accept that I
got
got a
then I'm willing because I accept that I
got a problem
got a problem and
then I'm willing because I accept that I
got a problem and I
got a problem and I understand
then I'm willing because I accept that I
got a problem and I understand that
got a problem and I understand that and
eventually
eventually out
eventually out of
eventually out of lovingness.
eventually out of lovingness. So
eventually out of lovingness. So the
reason
reason to
eventually out of lovingness. So the
reason to continue
reason to continue it
eventually out of lovingness. So the
reason to continue it really
reason to continue it really is
eventually out of lovingness. So the
reason to continue it really is out
reason to continue it really is out of
lovingness
lovingness for
lovingness for yourself
lovingness for yourself and
lovingness for yourself and others.
lovingness for yourself and others. All
right.
right. So
lovingness for yourself and others. All
right. So this
right. So this this
lovingness for yourself and others. All
right. So this this is
right. So this this is the
lovingness for yourself and others. All
right. So this this is the great
right. So this this is the great block
though.
though. This
though. This is
though. This is the
though. This is the great
though. This is the great block
though. This is the great block that
though. This is the great block that uh
we
we said
though. This is the great block that uh
we said 22%
we said 22% of
though. This is the great block that uh
we said 22% of the
we said 22% of the population
though. This is the great block that uh
we said 22% of the population crosses
this
this line
this line here.
this line here. 87%
this line here. 87% is
this line here. 87% is down
this line here. 87% is down here.
this line here. 87% is down here. 87%
can't
can't use
this line here. 87% is down here. 87%
can't use kinesiology
can't use kinesiology to
this line here. 87% is down here. 87%
can't use kinesiology to tell
can't use kinesiology to tell the
this line here. 87% is down here. 87%
can't use kinesiology to tell the truth
about
about anything.
about anything. It
about anything. It doesn't
about anything. It doesn't work
about anything. It doesn't work for
them.
them. H
well
well um
all
all right.
well um
all right. The
all right. The willingness
well um
all right. The willingness to
all right. The willingness to surrender
all
all the
all the blocks
all the blocks to
all the blocks to love
all the blocks to love then
all the blocks to love then are
all the blocks to love then are really
what
what spiritual
all the blocks to love then are really
what spiritual work
what spiritual work is
all the blocks to love then are really
what spiritual work is about.
what spiritual work is about. You
all the blocks to love then are really
what spiritual work is about. You don't
have
have to
have to seek
have to seek love.
have to seek love. You
have to seek love. You don't
have to seek love. You don't have
have to seek love. You don't have to
learn
learn about
have to seek love. You don't have to
learn about love.
learn about love. You
have to seek love. You don't have to
learn about love. You don't
learn about love. You don't have
have to seek love. You don't have to
learn about love. You don't have there's
nothing
nothing required
nothing required about
nothing required about love
nothing required about love because
nothing required about love because when
the
the blocks
nothing required about love because when
the blocks that
the blocks that prevent
nothing required about love because when
the blocks that prevent it
the blocks that prevent it are
nothing required about love because when
the blocks that prevent it are removed,
it
it comes
it comes in
it comes in like
it comes in like a
it comes in like a tsunami.
it comes in like a tsunami. It
it comes in like a tsunami. It just
wipes
wipes you
it comes in like a tsunami. It just
wipes you out.
wipes you out. And
it comes in like a tsunami. It just
wipes you out. And anybody
wipes you out. And anybody who's
it comes in like a tsunami. It just
wipes you out. And anybody who's been
wipes you out. And anybody who's been in
that
that bliss
that bliss state
that bliss state knows
it's
it's ultra
that bliss state knows
it's ultra powerful.
it's ultra powerful. It
that bliss state knows
it's ultra powerful. It just
it's ultra powerful. It just takes
that bliss state knows
it's ultra powerful. It just takes over
and
and wipes
and wipes out
and wipes out anything
and wipes out anything that
and wipes out anything that is
and wipes out anything that is not
and wipes out anything that is not love.
what
what somebody
and wipes out anything that is not love.
what somebody did
what somebody did to
and wipes out anything that is not love.
what somebody did to you
seems
seems to
seems to be
seems to be a
seems to be a reason
seems to be a reason to
seems to be a reason to hate
seems to be a reason to hate them.
seems to be a reason to hate them. The
willingness
willingness to
seems to be a reason to hate them. The
willingness to let
willingness to let it
seems to be a reason to hate them. The
willingness to let it go.
willingness to let it go. We're
seems to be a reason to hate them. The
willingness to let it go. We're going
willingness to let it go. We're going to
do
do a
do a lecture
do a lecture on
do a lecture on karma
do a lecture on karma too
do a lecture on karma too because
do a lecture on karma too because once
you
you know
do a lecture on karma too because once
you know these
you know these are
do a lecture on karma too because once
you know these are all
you know these are all ways
do a lecture on karma too because once
you know these are all ways of
you know these are all ways of undoing
the
the blocks
the blocks to
the blocks to enlightenment.
the blocks to enlightenment. The
the blocks to enlightenment. The karmic
propensity
propensity then
the blocks to enlightenment. The karmic
propensity then you
propensity then you begin
the blocks to enlightenment. The karmic
propensity then you begin to
propensity then you begin to suspect
the blocks to enlightenment. The karmic
propensity then you begin to suspect is
why
why you
why you can't
why you can't let
why you can't let go
why you can't let go of
why you can't let go of this
why you can't let go of this particular
thing.
thing. after
why you can't let go of this particular
thing. after much
thing. after much prayer,
why you can't let go of this particular
thing. after much prayer, after
thing. after much prayer, after much
uh
uh psychotherapy,
uh psychotherapy, after
uh psychotherapy, after much
uh psychotherapy, after much everything
you
you can
uh psychotherapy, after much everything
you can do,
you can do, it
uh psychotherapy, after much everything
you can do, it is
you can do, it is still
uh psychotherapy, after much everything
you can do, it is still stuck
you can do, it is still stuck there.
uh psychotherapy, after much everything
you can do, it is still stuck there. And
um
um therefore,
um therefore, I
um therefore, I think
um therefore, I think the
um therefore, I think the next
um therefore, I think the next lecture
is
is on
um therefore, I think the next lecture
is on karma
is on karma in
um therefore, I think the next lecture
is on karma in which
is on karma in which we're
um therefore, I think the next lecture
is on karma in which we're going
is on karma in which we're going to
um therefore, I think the next lecture
is on karma in which we're going to use
kinesiology
kinesiology to
kinesiology to to
kinesiology to to pick
kinesiology to to pick up
kinesiology to to pick up what
kinesiology to to pick up what what
kinesiology to to pick up what what the
block
block is.
kinesiology to to pick up what what the
block is. Now
block is. Now that
kinesiology to to pick up what what the
block is. Now that you
block is. Now that you can
kinesiology to to pick up what what the
block is. Now that you can see
block is. Now that you can see what
kinesiology to to pick up what what the
block is. Now that you can see what it
is,
is, it's
is, it's easy
is, it's easy to
is, it's easy to let
is, it's easy to let it
is, it's easy to let it go.
is, it's easy to let it go. But
is, it's easy to let it go. But when
is, it's easy to let it go. But when you
don't
don't know
is, it's easy to let it go. But when you
don't know what
don't know what it
is, it's easy to let it go. But when you
don't know what it is
don't know what it is that's
is, it's easy to let it go. But when you
don't know what it is that's holding
don't know what it is that's holding it
there,
there, you're
there, you're sort
there, you're sort of
there, you're sort of up
there, you're sort of up against
there, you're sort of up against the
block.
So
So the
So the love
So the love then
So the love then is
So the love then is a
So the love then is a style
So the love then is a style a
So the love then is a style a way
So the love then is a style a way of
being
being and
So the love then is a style a way of
being and it's
being and it's a
So the love then is a style a way of
being and it's a way
being and it's a way of
So the love then is a style a way of
being and it's a way of being
being and it's a way of being with
yourself
yourself out
yourself out of
yourself out of compassion
yourself out of compassion for
yourself out of compassion for yourself.
You're
You're willing
yourself out of compassion for yourself.
You're willing to
You're willing to let
yourself out of compassion for yourself.
You're willing to let go
You're willing to let go the
yourself out of compassion for yourself.
You're willing to let go the things
You're willing to let go the things that
bring
bring you
bring you pain.
So
So instead
bring you pain.
So instead of
So instead of going
bring you pain.
So instead of going from
So instead of going from the
bring you pain.
So instead of going from the bottom
So instead of going from the bottom up,
we
we can
we can start
we can start from
we can start from the
we can start from the top
we can start from the top top
we can start from the top top down.
we can start from the top top down. out
of
of compassion
we can start from the top top down. out
of compassion for
of compassion for yourself.
we can start from the top top down. out
of compassion for yourself. Then
of compassion for yourself. Then you're
willing
willing to
willing to let
willing to let go
willing to let go of
willing to let go of that
willing to let go of that which
willing to let go of that which brings
you
you pain,
willing to let go of that which brings
you pain, suffering,
you pain, suffering, guilt,
brings
brings it
brings it to
brings it to yourself
brings it to yourself and
brings it to yourself and others.
brings it to yourself and others. Out
brings it to yourself and others. Out of
love
love for
brings it to yourself and others. Out of
love for yourself,
out
out of
out of love
out of love for
out of love for oneself,
out of love for oneself, out
out of love for oneself, out of
compassion
compassion for
out of love for oneself, out of
compassion for oneself,
out
out of
out of compassion
out of compassion for
out of compassion for myself,
I'm
I'm not
out of compassion for myself,
I'm not going
I'm not going to
out of compassion for myself,
I'm not going to allow
I'm not going to allow myself
out of compassion for myself,
I'm not going to allow myself to
I'm not going to allow myself to fall
into
into the
into the pit.
of
of being
into the pit.
of being so
of being so linked
into the pit.
of being so linked to
of being so linked to something
into the pit.
of being so linked to something that
of being so linked to something that if
it
it leaves
it leaves I
it leaves I will
it leaves I will then
it leaves I will then go
it leaves I will then go into
it leaves I will then go into grief
out
out of
it leaves I will then go into grief
out of compassion.
So
So that
So that loving
So that loving lovingness
So that loving lovingness now
So that loving lovingness now takes
So that loving lovingness now takes the
form
form of
So that loving lovingness now takes the
form of an
form of an attitude
So that loving lovingness now takes the
form of an attitude towards
form of an attitude towards yourself
So that loving lovingness now takes the
form of an attitude towards yourself and
your
your own
your own life
your own life and
your own life and those
your own life and those around
your own life and those around you.
your own life and those around you. I
don't
don't want
your own life and those around you. I
don't want to
don't want to put
your own life and those around you. I
don't want to put her
don't want to put her in
your own life and those around you. I
don't want to put her in the
don't want to put her in the position
your own life and those around you. I
don't want to put her in the position of
tending
tending to
tending to a
tending to a grieving
cat
cat pup
cat daddy.
All right.
All right. So
cat daddy.
All right. So out
All right. So out of
cat daddy.
All right. So out of compassion
All right. So out of compassion for
everything
everything then
everything then our
everything then our willingness
everything then our willingness to
everything then our willingness to let
things
things go.
everything then our willingness to let
things go. We
things go. We do
everything then our willingness to let
things go. We do it
things go. We do it all
everything then our willingness to let
things go. We do it all the
things go. We do it all the time
everything then our willingness to let
things go. We do it all the time as
things go. We do it all the time as a
style
style of
style of life.
One
One expression
style of life.
One expression of
One expression of love
style of life.
One expression of love then
One expression of love then is
style of life.
One expression of love then is devotion.
And
And in
And in spiritual
And in spiritual work
And in spiritual work that
And in spiritual work that devotion
becomes
becomes more
And in spiritual work that devotion
becomes more and
becomes more and more
And in spiritual work that devotion
becomes more and more intense.
becomes more and more intense. It
finally
finally reaches
finally reaches the
finally reaches the point
finally reaches the point where
finally reaches the point where it's
willing
willing to
finally reaches the point where it's
willing to let
willing to let anything
finally reaches the point where it's
willing to let anything go
willing to let anything go that
finally reaches the point where it's
willing to let anything go that stands
in
in the
in the way.
So
So we
in the way.
So we may
So we may think
in the way.
So we may think it's
So we may think it's the
in the way.
So we may think it's the small
So we may think it's the small things
that
that we're
that we're letting
that we're letting go
that we're letting go of.
that we're letting go of. We
that we're letting go of. We say,
that we're letting go of. We say, "Well,
I
I let
that we're letting go of. We say, "Well,
I let go
I let go of
my
my favorite
my favorite sneakers
my favorite sneakers and
my favorite sneakers and uh
my favorite sneakers and uh it
my favorite sneakers and uh it seems
trivial."
trivial." Oh
my favorite sneakers and uh it seems
trivial." Oh no.
trivial." Oh no. The
my favorite sneakers and uh it seems
trivial." Oh no. The capacity
trivial." Oh no. The capacity let
my favorite sneakers and uh it seems
trivial." Oh no. The capacity let go
trivial." Oh no. The capacity let go of
your
your favorite
your favorite sneakers
your favorite sneakers and
your favorite sneakers and not
your favorite sneakers and not grieve
about
about them
your favorite sneakers and not grieve
about them or
about them or be
your favorite sneakers and not grieve
about them or be angry
about them or be angry at
your favorite sneakers and not grieve
about them or be angry at somebody
stealing
stealing them
stealing them or
stealing them or something.
capacity
capacity to
stealing them or something.
capacity to surrender
capacity to surrender your
stealing them or something.
capacity to surrender your sneakers
capacity to surrender your sneakers is
going
going to
going to be
going to be one
going to be one of
going to be one of the
going to be one of the last
going to be one of the last things
going to be one of the last things right
before
before enlightenment.
Why
Why is
Why is that?
Why is that? It's
Why is that? It's because
you
you have
Why is that? It's because
you have that
you have that capacity
Why is that? It's because
you have that capacity to
you have that capacity to let
Why is that? It's because
you have that capacity to let go.
you have that capacity to let go. Huh?
You
You try
You try and
You try and get
You try and get some
You try and get some people
You try and get some people to
You try and get some people to let
You try and get some people to let go
You try and get some people to let go of
something.
something. It's
You try and get some people to let go of
something. It's really
something. It's really something.
You try and get some people to let go of
something. It's really something. You
just
just cannot
just cannot pry
just cannot pry them
just cannot pry them loose.
just cannot pry them loose. You
just cannot pry them loose. You know,
you're
you're going
just cannot pry them loose. You know,
you're going to
you're going to go
just cannot pry them loose. You know,
you're going to go to
you're going to go to jail
just cannot pry them loose. You know,
you're going to go to jail if
you're going to go to jail if you
just cannot pry them loose. You know,
you're going to go to jail if you don't
do
do it.
do it. You're
do it. You're going
do it. You're going to
do it. You're going to everybody's
do it. You're going to everybody's going
to
to leave
do it. You're going to everybody's going
to leave you.
to leave you. You're
do it. You're going to everybody's going
to leave you. You're going
to leave you. You're going to
do it. You're going to everybody's going
to leave you. You're going to die
to leave you. You're going to die of
do it. You're going to everybody's going
to leave you. You're going to die of it.
They
They won't
They won't let
They won't let go.
They won't let go. It's
They won't let go. It's like
They won't let go. It's like they're
They won't let go. It's like they're in
a
a spasm.
They won't let go. It's like they're in
a spasm. You
a spasm. You know,
all
all right.
all right. The
all right. The capacity
all right. The capacity to
all right. The capacity to learn
all right. The capacity to learn to
all right. The capacity to learn to let
things
things go.
all right. The capacity to learn to let
things go. You've
things go. You've learned
all right. The capacity to learn to let
things go. You've learned to
things go. You've learned to small
things.
things. Could
things. Could you
things. Could you let
things. Could you let go
things. Could you let go of
things. Could you let go of being
things. Could you let go of being mad
things. Could you let go of being mad at
that
that guy
things. Could you let go of being mad at
that guy for
that guy for cutting
things. Could you let go of being mad at
that guy for cutting in
that guy for cutting in in
things. Could you let go of being mad at
that guy for cutting in in front
that guy for cutting in in front of
things. Could you let go of being mad at
that guy for cutting in in front of you
in
in traffic?
in traffic? That's
in traffic? That's a
in traffic? That's a wonderful
in traffic? That's a wonderful example.
Every
Every day
in traffic? That's a wonderful example.
Every day you
Every day you get
in traffic? That's a wonderful example.
Every day you get all
Every day you get all these
in traffic? That's a wonderful example.
Every day you get all these spiritual
opportunities.
Say,
Say, "Go
opportunities.
Say, "Go ahead,
Say, "Go ahead, man.
opportunities.
Say, "Go ahead, man. It's
Say, "Go ahead, man. It's all
opportunities.
Say, "Go ahead, man. It's all right.
Say, "Go ahead, man. It's all right. Go
ahead."
S
S so
ahead."
S so then
S so then after
ahead."
S so then after a
S so then after a while
after
after a
after a while
after a while you
after a while you let
after a while you let go
after a while you let go of
after a while you let go of the
after a while you let go of the so
after a while you let go of the so and
you
you say
after a while you let go of the so and
you say oh
you say oh well
we'll
we'll get
we'll get there
we'll get there the
we'll get there the same
we'll get there the same time
we'll get there the same time anyway
we'll get there the same time anyway you
know
know rationality
we'll get there the same time anyway you
know rationality you
know rationality you only
we'll get there the same time anyway you
know rationality you only I'm
know rationality you only I'm only
we'll get there the same time anyway you
know rationality you only I'm only going
to
to get
to get there
to get there 3
to get there 3 seconds
to get there 3 seconds later
to get there 3 seconds later big
to get there 3 seconds later big deal
you
you know
to get there 3 seconds later big deal
you know so
you know so then
to get there 3 seconds later big deal
you know so then you
you know so then you train
to get there 3 seconds later big deal
you know so then you train it
you know so then you train it with
to get there 3 seconds later big deal
you know so then you train it with logic
see
see you're
see you're trying
see you're trying to
see you're trying to think
see you're trying to think so
see you're trying to think so I
see you're trying to think so I you
see you're trying to think so I you let
go
go of
see you're trying to think so I you let
go of all
go of all this
see you're trying to think so I you let
go of all this stuff
go of all this stuff about
see you're trying to think so I you let
go of all this stuff about him
go of all this stuff about him I
see you're trying to think so I you let
go of all this stuff about him I decided
not
not to
not to kill
not to kill him
and
and uh
not to kill him
and uh he's
and uh he's not
not to kill him
and uh he's not really
and uh he's not really causing
not to kill him
and uh he's not really causing me
and uh he's not really causing me any
problem
problem with
problem with pride
problem with pride that
problem with pride that he's
problem with pride that he's a
problem with pride that he's a better
driver
driver than
problem with pride that he's a better
driver than I
driver than I am.
problem with pride that he's a better
driver than I am. You're
driver than I am. You're all
problem with pride that he's a better
driver than I am. You're all the
driver than I am. You're all the way
problem with pride that he's a better
driver than I am. You're all the way up
to
to reason.
to reason. Reason
to reason. Reason says,
to reason. Reason says, "Ah,
to reason. Reason says, "Ah, couple
to reason. Reason says, "Ah, couple of
seconds
seconds this
to reason. Reason says, "Ah, couple of
seconds this way,
seconds this way, a
to reason. Reason says, "Ah, couple of
seconds this way, a couple
seconds this way, a couple seconds
to reason. Reason says, "Ah, couple of
seconds this way, a couple seconds that
way.
way. It's
way. It's all
way. It's all the
way. It's all the same."
way. It's all the same." You
way. It's all the same." You know
way. It's all the same." You know what
way. It's all the same." You know what I
mean?
Uh,
Uh, but
Uh, but we're
Uh, but we're getting
Uh, but we're getting there.
Uh, but we're getting there. So,
Uh, but we're getting there. So, we're
developing
developing the
Uh, but we're getting there. So, we're
developing the tools
developing the tools and
Uh, but we're getting there. So, we're
developing the tools and the
developing the tools and the techniques.
The
The most
The most powerful
The most powerful thing
The most powerful thing you'll
The most powerful thing you'll need
The most powerful thing you'll need is
really
really powerful
The most powerful thing you'll need is
really powerful capacities
in
in the
in the one-pointedness
in the one-pointedness of
in the one-pointedness of mind
in the one-pointedness of mind to
go
go the
in the one-pointedness of mind to
go the whole
go the whole way
in the one-pointedness of mind to
go the whole way in
go the whole way in non-duality
in the one-pointedness of mind to
go the whole way in non-duality and
go the whole way in non-duality and Zen
and
and advanced
and advanced Buddhism.
This
This is
and advanced Buddhism.
This is a
This is a capacity
and advanced Buddhism.
This is a capacity that
This is a capacity that you
and advanced Buddhism.
This is a capacity that you learn
This is a capacity that you learn and
then
then when
then when you
then when you really
then when you really need
then when you really need it
then when you really need it because
you're
you're going
then when you really need it because
you're going to
you're going to run
then when you really need it because
you're going to run into
you're going to run into tests
then when you really need it because
you're going to run into tests that
you're going to run into tests that are
really
really quite
really quite powerful,
really quite powerful, stronger
really quite powerful, stronger than
what
what you
really quite powerful, stronger than
what you think,
both
both overt
both overt and
both overt and not
both overt and not so
both overt and not so overt.
Because
Because as
both overt and not so overt.
Because as you
Because as you move
both overt and not so overt.
Because as you move ahead,
Because as you move ahead, that
both overt and not so overt.
Because as you move ahead, that which
Because as you move ahead, that which is
made
made uncomfortable
made uncomfortable or
made uncomfortable or displaced
made uncomfortable or displaced in
made uncomfortable or displaced in its
control
control over
made uncomfortable or displaced in its
control over and
control over and influence
made uncomfortable or displaced in its
control over and influence over
control over and influence over mankind
begins
begins to
begins to get
begins to get annoyed
begins to get annoyed that
begins to get annoyed that you're
begins to get annoyed that you're moving
out
out of
begins to get annoyed that you're moving
out of that
out of that domain
begins to get annoyed that you're moving
out of that domain and
out of that domain and threatening
begins to get annoyed that you're moving
out of that domain and threatening their
domain.
And
And so
domain.
And so you
And so you start
domain.
And so you start getting
And so you start getting the
domain.
And so you start getting the challenges
and
and um
and um when
and um when the
and um when the challenges
and um when the challenges come
and um when the challenges come up,
that's
that's when
and um when the challenges come up,
that's when you
that's when you need
and um when the challenges come up,
that's when you need the
that's when you need the tools.
So
So spiritual
So spiritual work
So spiritual work then
So spiritual work then out
So spiritual work then out of
So spiritual work then out of love
So spiritual work then out of love and
compassion
compassion for
So spiritual work then out of love and
compassion for yourself
compassion for yourself and
So spiritual work then out of love and
compassion for yourself and out
compassion for yourself and out of
So spiritual work then out of love and
compassion for yourself and out of love
for
for God,
for God, devotion
for God, devotion to
for God, devotion to God,
for God, devotion to God, you
for God, devotion to God, you develop
these
these strengths,
for God, devotion to God, you develop
these strengths, these
these strengths, these capacities,
for God, devotion to God, you develop
these strengths, these capacities, this
discernment
and
and eventually
discernment
and eventually it's
and eventually it's like
discernment
and eventually it's like a
and eventually it's like a knife.
discernment
and eventually it's like a knife. You
can
can cut
can cut through
can cut through anything.
You
You can
can cut through anything.
You can lose
You can lose anything
can cut through anything.
You can lose anything and
You can lose anything and everything.
Disconnect
Disconnect parents,
Disconnect parents, grandparents,
country,
lovers,
lovers, wives,
lovers, wives, children,
dogs,
dogs, cats,
lovers, wives, children,
dogs, cats, houses,
dogs, cats, houses, titles,
lovers, wives, children,
dogs, cats, houses, titles, anything.
In
In an
In an instant,
In an instant, it's
In an instant, it's gone.
So
So that
In an instant, it's gone.
So that laserlike
So that laserlike onepointedness
In an instant, it's gone.
So that laserlike onepointedness of
So that laserlike onepointedness of mind
and
and the
and the willingness
and the willingness to
and the willingness to cut
and the willingness to cut through
anything
anything no
and the willingness to cut through
anything no matter
anything no matter what
and the willingness to cut through
anything no matter what it
anything no matter what it is
is
is what's
is what's going
is what's going to
is what's going to be
is what's going to be needed
is what's going to be needed at
is what's going to be needed at a
is what's going to be needed at a later
date.
date. So
is what's going to be needed at a later
date. So we
date. So we perfect
is what's going to be needed at a later
date. So we perfect it
date. So we perfect it every
is what's going to be needed at a later
date. So we perfect it every day.
date. So we perfect it every day. We
perfect
perfect that
perfect that capacity.
So
So that's
perfect that capacity.
So that's a
So that's a form
perfect that capacity.
So that's a form of
So that's a form of love.
perfect that capacity.
So that's a form of love. All
So that's a form of love. All of
spiritual
spiritual work
spiritual work is
spiritual work is a
spiritual work is a form
spiritual work is a form of
spiritual work is a form of love.
We
We surrender
spiritual work is a form of love.
We surrender it
We surrender it all
spiritual work is a form of love.
We surrender it all as
We surrender it all as a
spiritual work is a form of love.
We surrender it all as a form
We surrender it all as a form of
devotion.
Out
Out of
devotion.
Out of my
Out of my love
devotion.
Out of my love for
Out of my love for thee,
devotion.
Out of my love for thee, oh
Out of my love for thee, oh Lord,
devotion.
Out of my love for thee, oh Lord, I
Out of my love for thee, oh Lord, I let
go
go my
go my attachment
to
to so
go my attachment
to so and
to so and so
go my attachment
to so and so or
to so and so or I
go my attachment
to so and so or I surrender
to so and so or I surrender it
go my attachment
to so and so or I surrender it to
to so and so or I surrender it to thee.
The
The willing
The willing to
The willing to let
The willing to let go
The willing to let go of
The willing to let go of anything
The willing to let go of anything and
everything
everything to
The willing to let go of anything and
everything to God.
In
In the
In the end,
In the end, you're
In the end, you're asked
In the end, you're asked to
In the end, you're asked to let
In the end, you're asked to let go
In the end, you're asked to let go all
of
of it,
In the end, you're asked to let go all
of it, even
of it, even physicality.
Even
Even physicality.
And
And of
Even physicality.
And of course
And of course the
Even physicality.
And of course the ultimate
And of course the ultimate one
Even physicality.
And of course the ultimate one which
we'll
we'll talk
we'll talk about
we'll talk about at
we'll talk about at the
we'll talk about at the end
we'll talk about at the end of
we'll talk about at the end of lectures
uh
uh is
we'll talk about at the end of lectures
uh is is
uh is is the
we'll talk about at the end of lectures
uh is is the willingness
uh is is the willingness to
we'll talk about at the end of lectures
uh is is the willingness to give
uh is is the willingness to give up
we'll talk about at the end of lectures
uh is is the willingness to give up what
you
you think
you think is
you think is the
you think is the source
you think is the source of
you think is the source of life
you think is the source of life itself
and
and you're
you think is the source of life itself
and you're asked
and you're asked to
you think is the source of life itself
and you're asked to give
and you're asked to give up
you think is the source of life itself
and you're asked to give up life
and you're asked to give up life for
you think is the source of life itself
and you're asked to give up life for God
and
and you
and you see
and you see that
and you see that the
and you see that the ego
and you see that the ego is
and you see that the ego is coming
and you see that the ego is coming to
its
its end
and you see that the ego is coming to
its end but
its end but you
and you see that the ego is coming to
its end but you don't
its end but you don't know
and you see that the ego is coming to
its end but you don't know it's
its end but you don't know it's just
and you see that the ego is coming to
its end but you don't know it's just the
ego
ego you
ego you think
ego you think it's
ego you think it's you
ego you think it's you and
ego you think it's you and the
willingness
willingness to
ego you think it's you and the
willingness to surrender
willingness to surrender life
ego you think it's you and the
willingness to surrender life itself
willingness to surrender life itself as
you
you understand
you understand it
you understand it to
you understand it to God
you understand it to God is
you understand it to God is going
you understand it to God is going to
you understand it to God is going to be
require
require all
you understand it to God is going to be
require all the
require all the strengths
you understand it to God is going to be
require all the strengths that
require all the strengths that you've
learned.
So
So devotion
learned.
So devotion then
So devotion then is
learned.
So devotion then is a
So devotion then is a one-pointed
um
willingness
willingness willingness
um
willingness willingness and
willingness willingness and it
um
willingness willingness and it becomes
tested
tested all
tested all the
tested all the time.
The
The expression
tested all the time.
The expression of
The expression of God
tested all the time.
The expression of God as
The expression of God as the
tested all the time.
The expression of God as the of
The expression of God as the of love
tested all the time.
The expression of God as the of love as
devotion
devotion then
devotion then becomes
devotion then becomes the
devotion then becomes the core
devotion then becomes the core of
Christianity
Christianity and
devotion then becomes the core of
Christianity and many
Christianity and many other
devotion then becomes the core of
Christianity and many other forms
Christianity and many other forms of
devotion
devotion whether
devotion whether as
devotion whether as Zen
devotion whether as Zen meditation.
So
So in
devotion whether as Zen meditation.
So in strict
So in strict meditation
devotion whether as Zen meditation.
So in strict meditation then
So in strict meditation then it's
devotion whether as Zen meditation.
So in strict meditation then it's really
one's
one's devotion
one's devotion that
one's devotion that carries
one's devotion that carries you
one's devotion that carries you through
um
the
the practice
the practice of
the practice of meditation.
the practice of meditation. It
the practice of meditation. It can
the practice of meditation. It can keep
you
you sitting
the practice of meditation. It can keep
you sitting there
you sitting there for
the practice of meditation. It can keep
you sitting there for eight
you sitting there for eight hours
nonstop.
nonstop. No
nonstop. No problem.
nonstop. No problem. Can
nonstop. No problem. Can you
nonstop. No problem. Can you sitting
there
there 12
nonstop. No problem. Can you sitting
there 12 hours
there 12 hours non-stop?
It
It can
It can keep
It can keep you
It can keep you sitting
It can keep you sitting there
It can keep you sitting there until
It can keep you sitting there until you
don't
don't know
It can keep you sitting there until you
don't know what
don't know what happened,
It can keep you sitting there until you
don't know what happened, but
don't know what happened, but you
apparently
apparently fell
apparently fell over
apparently fell over from
apparently fell over from dehydration
apparently fell over from dehydration or
something.
something. Could
apparently fell over from dehydration or
something. Could be
something. Could be a
apparently fell over from dehydration or
something. Could be a couple
something. Could be a couple days
apparently fell over from dehydration or
something. Could be a couple days later.
You
You have
You have me
You have me no
You have me no memory
You have me no memory of
You have me no memory of it.
That
That capacity
You have me no memory of it.
That capacity then
That capacity then becomes
You have me no memory of it.
That capacity then becomes perfected
That capacity then becomes perfected and
it
it is
it is a
it is a way
it is a way of
it is a way of devotion
it is a way of devotion to
it is a way of devotion to your
it is a way of devotion to your own
spiritual
spiritual evolution.
one
one becomes
one becomes devoted
one becomes devoted to
one becomes devoted to the
one becomes devoted to the evolution
one becomes devoted to the evolution and
you
you see
one becomes devoted to the evolution and
you see that
you see that this
one becomes devoted to the evolution and
you see that this is
you see that this is a
one becomes devoted to the evolution and
you see that this is a commitment
you see that this is a commitment to
one becomes devoted to the evolution and
you see that this is a commitment to God
and
and to
and to all
and to all the
and to all the higher
and to all the higher beings
and to all the higher beings that
and to all the higher beings that are
calling
calling you
and to all the higher beings that are
calling you to
calling you to do
and to all the higher beings that are
calling you to do so.
calling you to do so. People
and to all the higher beings that are
calling you to do so. People say,
calling you to do so. People say, "How
do
do I
do I know
do I know I'm
do I know I'm going to
do I know I'm going to be
do I know I'm going to be enlightened
someday
someday or
do I know I'm going to be enlightened
someday or something?"
someday or something?" Well,
do I know I'm going to be enlightened
someday or something?" Well, I
someday or something?" Well, I tell
them,
them, "If
them, "If you
them, "If you weren't
them, "If you weren't destined
them, "If you weren't destined to
them, "If you weren't destined to be
enlightened,
enlightened, you
them, "If you weren't destined to be
enlightened, you wouldn't
enlightened, you wouldn't be
them, "If you weren't destined to be
enlightened, you wouldn't be in
enlightened, you wouldn't be in this
lecture."
Nobody
Nobody except
lecture."
Nobody except somebody
Nobody except somebody who's
lecture."
Nobody except somebody who's destined
Nobody except somebody who's destined to
be
be enlightened
be enlightened would
be enlightened would even
be enlightened would even be
be enlightened would even be here.
Who
Who would
be enlightened would even be here.
Who would be
Who would be at
be enlightened would even be here.
Who would be at a
Who would be at a class
be enlightened would even be here.
Who would be at a class on
Who would be at a class on how
be enlightened would even be here.
Who would be at a class on how to
Who would be at a class on how to drive
a
a speedboat?
a speedboat? Only
a speedboat? Only people
a speedboat? Only people are
a speedboat? Only people are going
a speedboat? Only people are going to
get
get a
a speedboat? Only people are going to
get a speedboat
get a speedboat and
a speedboat? Only people are going to
get a speedboat and nobody
get a speedboat and nobody else
a speedboat? Only people are going to
get a speedboat and nobody else going
get a speedboat and nobody else going to
be
be there.
By
By definition,
be there.
By definition, the
By definition, the people
be there.
By definition, the people who
By definition, the people who are
interested
interested in
interested in enlightenment
interested in enlightenment are
interested in enlightenment are the
people
people are
interested in enlightenment are the
people are going
people are going to
interested in enlightenment are the
people are going to become
people are going to become enlightened.
I
I mean,
I mean, that's
I mean, that's how
I mean, that's how you
I mean, that's how you get
I mean, that's how you get there,
I mean, that's how you get there, isn't
it?
Unless
Unless you're
Unless you're one
Unless you're one of
Unless you're one of those
Unless you're one of those drop
Unless you're one of those drop off
Unless you're one of those drop off the
cliff
cliff enlightenments
Unless you're one of those drop off the
cliff enlightenments that
cliff enlightenments that happen,
Unless you're one of those drop off the
cliff enlightenments that happen, too.
And
And you,
And you, it's
And you, it's just
And you, it's just as
And you, it's just as you
And you, it's just as you go
And you, it's just as you go over
And you, it's just as you go over the
side,
side, you
And you, it's just as you go over the
side, you completely
side, you completely and
And you, it's just as you go over the
side, you completely and totally
surrender
surrender everything
surrender everything to
surrender everything to God.
surrender everything to God. You
surrender everything to God. You go
surrender everything to God. You go into
an
an incredible
surrender everything to God. You go into
an incredible state.
Mhm.
Much
Much to
Mhm.
Much to your
Much to your dismay,
Mhm.
Much to your dismay, you
Much to your dismay, you wake
Mhm.
Much to your dismay, you wake up
Much to your dismay, you wake up 4
Mhm.
Much to your dismay, you wake up 4 days
later
later in
later in the
later in the hospital.
Everybody's
Everybody's saying,
later in the hospital.
Everybody's saying, "Oh,
Everybody's saying, "Oh, it's
later in the hospital.
Everybody's saying, "Oh, it's so
wonderful
wonderful you're
wonderful you're still
wonderful you're still alive."
wonderful you're still alive." You're
going,
"Man,
"Man, I
"Man, I was
"Man, I was in
"Man, I was in heaven."
"Man, I was in heaven." And
"Man, I was in heaven." And he
"Man, I was in heaven." And he and
"Man, I was in heaven." And he and they
resuscitated
resuscitated me.
"Man, I was in heaven." And he and they
resuscitated me. Thanks
resuscitated me. Thanks a
"Man, I was in heaven." And he and they
resuscitated me. Thanks a lot.
Yeah.
Yeah. Took
Yeah. Took me
Yeah. Took me around
Yeah. Took me around that
Yeah. Took me around that bliss.
Yeah. Took me around that bliss. I'm
really
really happy
Yeah. Took me around that bliss. I'm
really happy about
really happy about that.
Yes.
Yes. Well,
Yes. Well, well,
Yes. Well, well, it
Yes. Well, well, it makes
Yes. Well, well, it makes the
Yes. Well, well, it makes the family
happy.
happy. They're
Yes. Well, well, it makes the family
happy. They're happy
happy. They're happy now.
Yes. Well, well, it makes the family
happy. They're happy now. He's
happy. They're happy now. He's breathing
again.
again. Okay.
Good
Good for
again. Okay.
Good for your
Good for your ne.
again. Okay.
Good for your ne. Oh,
Good for your ne. Oh, look.
again. Okay.
Good for your ne. Oh, look. He's
breathing
breathing again.
breathing again. Mother.
Oh,
Oh, golly.
breathing again. Mother.
Oh, golly. Any
Oh, golly. Any of
breathing again. Mother.
Oh, golly. Any of you
Oh, golly. Any of you had
breathing again. Mother.
Oh, golly. Any of you had near-death
experiences
experiences know
experiences know that
experiences know that the
experiences know that the humor
experiences know that the humor of
experiences know that the humor of that
one.
one. So,
experiences know that the humor of that
one. So, it's
one. So, it's possible
experiences know that the humor of that
one. So, it's possible to
one. So, it's possible to stay
experiences know that the humor of that
one. So, it's possible to stay in
one. So, it's possible to stay in a
experiences know that the humor of that
one. So, it's possible to stay in a very
good
good state
good state all
good state all the
good state all the time.
good state all the time. I
good state all the time. I mean,
good state all the time. I mean, one
good state all the time. I mean, one of
the
the expressions
good state all the time. I mean, one of
the expressions of
the expressions of love
good state all the time. I mean, one of
the expressions of love is
the expressions of love is humor.
Why?
Why? Because
Why? Because humor
Why? Because humor recontextualizes
all
all of
Why? Because humor recontextualizes
all of life
all of life in
Why? Because humor recontextualizes
all of life in such
all of life in such a
Why? Because humor recontextualizes
all of life in such a way
all of life in such a way that
Why? Because humor recontextualizes
all of life in such a way that you
all of life in such a way that you can
handle
handle it
handle it without
handle it without resorting
handle it without resorting to
handle it without resorting to any
handle it without resorting to any of
the
the lower
handle it without resorting to any of
the lower levels.
the lower levels. There's
handle it without resorting to any of
the lower levels. There's nothing
the lower levels. There's nothing to
handle it without resorting to any of
the lower levels. There's nothing to be
angry
angry about
angry about if
angry about if you
angry about if you if
angry about if you if you
angry about if you if you see
angry about if you if you see that
angry about if you if you see that it's
sort
sort of
angry about if you if you see that it's
sort of absurd.
sort of absurd. You
angry about if you if you see that it's
sort of absurd. You know what
sort of absurd. You know what I
angry about if you if you see that it's
sort of absurd. You know what I mean?
Oh
Oh god,
Oh god, I
Oh god, I don't
Oh god, I don't even
Oh god, I don't even see
Oh god, I don't even see it
Oh god, I don't even see it anyway.
It's
It's a
Oh god, I don't even see it anyway.
It's a way
It's a way of
Oh god, I don't even see it anyway.
It's a way of staying
It's a way of staying in
Oh god, I don't even see it anyway.
It's a way of staying in the
It's a way of staying in the world
to
to recontextualize
to recontextualize things.
to recontextualize things. Um
to recontextualize things. Um what
to recontextualize things. Um what is
it?
it? It's
to recontextualize things. Um what is
it? It's comparing
it? It's comparing the
to recontextualize things. Um what is
it? It's comparing the context
it? It's comparing the context of
reality
reality with
reality with the
reality with the content
reality with the content of
reality with the content of appearance.
And
And you
reality with the content of appearance.
And you see
And you see the
reality with the content of appearance.
And you see the absurdity
And you see the absurdity of
reality with the content of appearance.
And you see the absurdity of the
comparison
comparison I
comparison I guess.
Uh
Uh so
comparison I guess.
Uh so that
Uh so that humor
comparison I guess.
Uh so that humor is
Uh so that humor is one
comparison I guess.
Uh so that humor is one style
Uh so that humor is one style and
comparison I guess.
Uh so that humor is one style and people
who
who become
who become spiritually
who become spiritually evolved
who become spiritually evolved often
become
become quite
who become spiritually evolved often
become quite comical
become quite comical because
who become spiritually evolved often
become quite comical because they
become quite comical because they uh
wear
wear the
wear the world
wear the world lightly
wear the world lightly you
wear the world lightly you know
wear the world lightly you know like
wear the world lightly you know like a
garment
garment and
wear the world lightly you know like a
garment and everything
garment and everything sort
wear the world lightly you know like a
garment and everything sort of
garment and everything sort of becomes
comical
and
and um
you
you know
you know because
you know because of
you know because of the
you know because of the contrast
you know because of the contrast with
reality
reality the
you know because of the contrast with
reality the absurdity.
reality the absurdity. So
you know because of the contrast with
reality the absurdity. So it's
reality the absurdity. So it's the
absurdity.
absurdity. It's
absurdity. It's the
absurdity. It's the theater
absurdity. It's the theater of
absurdity. It's the theater of the
absurd
absurd that
absurdity. It's the theater of the
absurd that is
absurd that is comical
absurdity. It's the theater of the
absurd that is comical and
absurd that is comical and uh
yeah
people
people don't
yeah
people don't expect
people don't expect that.
yeah
people don't expect that. They
people don't expect that. They expect
piety.
piety. Well
piety
piety is
profound.
profound. And
profound. And the
profound. And the difficulty
profound. And the difficulty I
profound. And the difficulty I had
profound. And the difficulty I had this
morning
morning was
profound. And the difficulty I had this
morning was I
morning was I didn't
profound. And the difficulty I had this
morning was I didn't know
morning was I didn't know if
profound. And the difficulty I had this
morning was I didn't know if I
morning was I didn't know if I was
profound. And the difficulty I had this
morning was I didn't know if I was going
to
to function
to function because
in
in a
to function because
in a state
in a state of
to function because
in a state of bliss
in a state of bliss you
to function because
in a state of bliss you see
in a state of bliss you see as
to function because
in a state of bliss you see as you
in a state of bliss you see as you let
go
go all
go all these
go all these things
go all these things um
go all these things um progressively
life
life becomes
go all these things um progressively
life becomes more
life becomes more beautiful
go all these things um progressively
life becomes more beautiful more
harmonious
harmonious the
harmonious the miraculous
harmonious the miraculous takes
harmonious the miraculous takes care
harmonious the miraculous takes care of
everything.
Um
a
a sense
Um
a sense of
a sense of inner
Um
a sense of inner joy
a sense of inner joy yeah
Um
a sense of inner joy yeah begins
a sense of inner joy yeah begins to
arise
arise becomes
arise becomes so
arise becomes so severe
arise becomes so severe that
arise becomes so severe that it
arise becomes so severe that it can
arise becomes so severe that it can be
ecstatic.
Uh
Uh in
Uh in a
Uh in a state
Uh in a state of
Uh in a state of ecstasy
Uh in a state of ecstasy you
Uh in a state of ecstasy you really
cannot
cannot function
Uh in a state of ecstasy you really
cannot function in
cannot function in the
Uh in a state of ecstasy you really
cannot function in the world.
In
In a
In a state
In a state of
In a state of high
In a state of high joy
In a state of high joy you
In a state of high joy you can't
In a state of high joy you can't really
function
function in
In a state of high joy you can't really
function in the
function in the world.
In a state of high joy you can't really
function in the world. And
function in the world. And in
In a state of high joy you can't really
function in the world. And in the
function in the world. And in the state
of
of bliss
um
you
you just
you just sit
you just sit there.
I
I thought
you just sit there.
I thought maybe
I thought maybe I'll
you just sit there.
I thought maybe I'll just
I thought maybe I'll just bless
everybody
everybody today
everybody today but
everybody today but I
and
and they
everybody today but I
and they should
and they should get
everybody today but I
and they should get out
and they should get out of
everybody today but I
and they should get out of it
and they should get out of it with
everybody today but I
and they should get out of it with the
help
help of
help of people
help of people because
help of people because this
help of people because this morning
help of people because this morning I
thought
thought oh
help of people because this morning I
thought oh wow
thought oh wow I
help of people because this morning I
thought oh wow I mean
thought oh wow I mean yeah
help of people because this morning I
thought oh wow I mean yeah the
thought oh wow I mean yeah the state
help of people because this morning I
thought oh wow I mean yeah the state you
know
know so
having
having been
know so
having been with
having been with it
know so
having been with it for
having been with it for some
know so
having been with it for some years
having been with it for some years one
learns
learns how
learns how to
sort
sort of
learns how to
sort of be
sort of be with
learns how to
sort of be with it
sort of be with it more
learns how to
sort of be with it more or
sort of be with it more or less
learns how to
sort of be with it more or less but
sort of be with it more or less but then
at
at times
at times it
at times it becomes
at times it becomes quite
at times it becomes quite profound
at times it becomes quite profound it
cannot
cannot be
at times it becomes quite profound it
cannot be denied
cannot be denied and
at times it becomes quite profound it
cannot be denied and it
cannot be denied and it just
at times it becomes quite profound it
cannot be denied and it just wipes
cannot be denied and it just wipes you
out
that's
that's why
out
that's why it's
that's why it's good
out
that's why it's good to
that's why it's good to have
out
that's why it's good to have friends
that
that know
that know what
that know what you're
that know what you're about
that know what you're about that
that know what you're about that friends
that
that understand
that know what you're about that friends
that understand it.
that understand it. If
that know what you're about that friends
that understand it. If you
that understand it. If you associate
with
with spiritual
with spiritual groups,
with spiritual groups, you
with spiritual groups, you know,
with spiritual groups, you know, when
with spiritual groups, you know, when I
was
was a
with spiritual groups, you know, when I
was a psych
was a psych psychiatrist
with spiritual groups, you know, when I
was a psych psychiatrist for
was a psych psychiatrist for the
with spiritual groups, you know, when I
was a psych psychiatrist for the for
some
some years,
some years, many
some years, many years
some years, many years for
some years, many years for the
some years, many years for the Episcopal
Dasis,
Dasis, the
some years, many years for the Episcopal
Dasis, the Catholic
Dasis, the Catholic Dasis,
some years, many years for the Episcopal
Dasis, the Catholic Dasis, uh
Dasis, the Catholic Dasis, uh the
Catholic
Catholic nuns,
Catholic nuns, the
Catholic nuns, the Zen
Catholic nuns, the Zen monastery,
Catholic nuns, the Zen monastery, uh
Catholic nuns, the Zen monastery, uh the
ministry
for
for many
for many years
for many years and
for many years and um
for many years and um I
for many years and um I had
for many years and um I had to
for many years and um I had to discern
the
the difference
for many years and um I had to discern
the difference between
the difference between these
for many years and um I had to discern
the difference between these states.
the difference between these states. Is
this
this guy
this guy in
this guy in the
this guy in the state
this guy in the state of
this guy in the state of samadei
this guy in the state of samadei or
this guy in the state of samadei or is
he
he catatonic?
He
He came
He came down
He came down from
He came down from the
He came down from the Zen
He came down from the Zen monastery.
Borderline
Borderline schizophrenia
He came down from the Zen monastery.
Borderline schizophrenia is
Borderline schizophrenia is not
He came down from the Zen monastery.
Borderline schizophrenia is not a
Borderline schizophrenia is not a good
condition
condition which
condition which to
condition which to start
condition which to start uh
condition which to start uh a
condition which to start uh a Zen
meditation
meditation because
condition which to start uh a Zen
meditation because uh
meditation because uh pretty
condition which to start uh a Zen
meditation because uh pretty soon
meditation because uh pretty soon things
start
start talking
start talking to
start talking to you
start talking to you and
start talking to you and flying
start talking to you and flying around.
Is
Is this
start talking to you and flying around.
Is this a
Is this a state
start talking to you and flying around.
Is this a state of
Is this a state of ecstasy,
start talking to you and flying around.
Is this a state of ecstasy, true
spiritual
spiritual ecstasy,
or
or is
spiritual ecstasy,
or is it
or is it religious
spiritual ecstasy,
or is it religious mania?
or is it religious mania? Hard
spiritual ecstasy,
or is it religious mania? Hard to
differentiate.
Um
Um because
differentiate.
Um because religious
Um because religious ecstasy,
differentiate.
Um because religious ecstasy, I'm
Um because religious ecstasy, I'm sure
differentiate.
Um because religious ecstasy, I'm sure I
can
can think
can think of
can think of moments
can think of moments if
can think of moments if my
can think of moments if my life
can think of moments if my life went
can think of moments if my life went if
a
a psychiatrist
can think of moments if my life went if
a psychiatrist had
a psychiatrist had examined
can think of moments if my life went if
a psychiatrist had examined me
a psychiatrist had examined me would
have
have probably
have probably ordered
have probably ordered thorazine.
So
So that
have probably ordered thorazine.
So that was
So that was really
have probably ordered thorazine.
So that was really my
So that was really my function.
have probably ordered thorazine.
So that was really my function. Does
So that was really my function. Does he
need
need thorazine
need thorazine or
need thorazine or should
need thorazine or should we
need thorazine or should we all
need thorazine or should we all u
need thorazine or should we all u bow
need thorazine or should we all u bow to
him?
him? You
need thorazine or should we all u bow to
him? You know
him? You know what
need thorazine or should we all u bow to
him? You know what I'm
him? You know what I'm saying?
need thorazine or should we all u bow to
him? You know what I'm saying? Because
those
those high
those high states
those high states can
those high states can be
those high states can be very
those high states can be very very
powerful.
powerful. Ecstasy
those high states can be very very
powerful. Ecstasy and
powerful. Ecstasy and joy.
those high states can be very very
powerful. Ecstasy and joy. And
powerful. Ecstasy and joy. And the
those high states can be very very
powerful. Ecstasy and joy. And the one
that
that uh
that uh takes
that uh takes us
that uh takes us out
that uh takes us out of
that uh takes us out of the
that uh takes us out of the world,
that uh takes us out of the world, the
one
one that
that uh takes us out of the world, the
one that took
one that took us
that uh takes us out of the world, the
one that took us out
one that took us out this
that uh takes us out of the world, the
one that took us out this morning
one that took us out this morning was
that uh takes us out of the world, the
one that took us out this morning was um
bliss.
bliss. Huh.
bliss. Huh. Satan
the
the presence
bliss. Huh. Satan
the presence becomes
the presence becomes so
bliss. Huh. Satan
the presence becomes so profound
the presence becomes so profound that
one
really
really becomes
one
really becomes immobilized
really becomes immobilized by
one
really becomes immobilized by it.
So
So let's
So let's hear
So let's hear that.
Kieran.
Kieran. Karen,
let's
let's hear
let's hear something
let's hear something that
let's hear something that calibrates
around
around 7:40.
7:40.
You
You got
7:40.
You got it
You got it over
7:40.
You got it over there.
You got it over there. Yeah.
See
See the
See the purposes
See the purposes of
See the purposes of the
See the purposes of the church,
See the purposes of the church, the
beauty,
beauty, the
See the purposes of the church, the
beauty, the sanctity,
the
music
and
and the
and the mantras,
and the mantras, the
and the mantras, the pageantry,
and the mantras, the pageantry, the
stained
stained glass
and the mantras, the pageantry, the
stained glass windows,
stained glass windows, the
and the mantras, the pageantry, the
stained glass windows, the incense.
She
Oh
my
my sh
Oh
Oh nash.
Oh no.
Oh no. She
my she
Oh
my
my she
Oh
my
my she
Oh
my
my she
Oh
my
my she
Home
she
might
oh
my
my she
Home.
She
>> Well,
>> Well, you
She
>> Well, you try
>> Well, you try and
She
>> Well, you try and figure
>> Well, you try and figure out
She
>> Well, you try and figure out how
>> Well, you try and figure out how to
She
>> Well, you try and figure out how to rig
your
your computer
your computer in
your computer in that
your computer in that state,
your computer in that state, huh?
What
What computer?
uh
uh that's
uh that's 7:40
and
and it
uh that's 7:40
and it makes
and it makes you
uh that's 7:40
and it makes you weep
and it makes you weep and
uh that's 7:40
and it makes you weep and immobilizes
you
you in
you in a
you in a state
you in a state of
you in a state of exquisite
exquisite
exquisite beauty.
you in a state of exquisite
exquisite beauty. The
exquisite beauty. The exquisite
you in a state of exquisite
exquisite beauty. The exquisite beauty
of
of the
of the presence
of the presence of
of the presence of God.
Um
Um and
of the presence of God.
Um and so
Um and so you
of the presence of God.
Um and so you can
Um and so you can see
of the presence of God.
Um and so you can see why
Um and so you can see why you
of the presence of God.
Um and so you can see why you need
friends
friends because
friends because if
friends because if you
friends because if you go
friends because if you go into
friends because if you go into that
state
state profoundly,
you
you really
you really can't
you really can't function.
And
And so
you really can't function.
And so we'll
And so we'll take
you really can't function.
And so we'll take a
And so we'll take a break
you really can't function.
And so we'll take a break now
And so we'll take a break now that
you really can't function.
And so we'll take a break now that we
can't
can't function.
If
If you
can't function.
If you allow
If you allow that
can't function.
If you allow that state
If you allow that state to
can't function.
If you allow that state to continue,
If you allow that state to continue, you
have
have to
have to stop
have to stop lecturing.
have to stop lecturing. You
have to stop lecturing. You can
have to stop lecturing. You can see
have to stop lecturing. You can see it
immobilizes
immobilizes you.
>> Some
>> Some of
>> Some of these
>> Some of these questions
>> Some of these questions are
>> Some of these questions are very
>> Some of these questions are very funny.
Very
Very funny.
We'll
We'll start
We'll start with
We'll start with the
We'll start with the first
We'll start with the first one.
The
The answer
We'll start with the first one.
The answer to
The answer to this
We'll start with the first one.
The answer to this is
The answer to this is no.
This
This is
This is this
This is this is
This is this is a
This is this is a question
This is this is a question by
This is this is a question by a
good-hearted
good-hearted soul.
Isn't
Isn't everyone
Isn't everyone who
Isn't everyone who is
Isn't everyone who is not
Isn't everyone who is not in
Isn't everyone who is not in this
Isn't everyone who is not in this room
also
also destined
Isn't everyone who is not in this room
also destined for
also destined for enlightenment?
No.
Yeah.
Miss
Miss these
Miss these lectures
Miss these lectures and
Miss these lectures and you've
Miss these lectures and you've had
Miss these lectures and you've had it.
You
You know
Miss these lectures and you've had it.
You know what
You know what I'm
Miss these lectures and you've had it.
You know what I'm saying?
No,
No, it's
No, it's an
No, it's an interesting
No, it's an interesting question
No, it's an interesting question because
it
it brings
No, it's an interesting question because
it brings up
it brings up other
No, it's an interesting question because
it brings up other dimensions
by
by um
by um ruled
by um ruled by
by um ruled by entities
by um ruled by entities um
um
um who
by um ruled by entities um
um who hate
um who hate God,
by um ruled by entities um
um who hate God, refuse
um who hate God, refuse God
by um ruled by entities um
um who hate God, refuse God and
consciously
consciously refuse
consciously refuse God.
consciously refuse God. The
consciously refuse God. The lower
consciously refuse God. The lower aster
regions
regions are
consciously refuse God. The lower aster
regions are those
regions are those who
consciously refuse God. The lower aster
regions are those who hate
regions are those who hate God,
consciously refuse God. The lower aster
regions are those who hate God, refuse
God
when
when given
God
when given the
when given the opportunity
God
when given the opportunity to
when given the opportunity to choose
God
when given the opportunity to choose God
have
have said
have said no
and
and they
have said no
and they perpetuate
and they perpetuate um
have said no
and they perpetuate um for
and they perpetuate um for eons
have said no
and they perpetuate um for eons and
and they perpetuate um for eons and uh
that's
that's what
that's what rules
that's what rules astral
that's what rules astral domains
that's what rules astral domains is
those
those who
that's what rules astral domains is
those who refuse
those who refuse God
that's what rules astral domains is
those who refuse God and
those who refuse God and deny
that's what rules astral domains is
those who refuse God and deny God
and
and therefore
and therefore they
and therefore they are
and therefore they are not
and therefore they are not destined
and therefore they are not destined for
enlightenment.
enlightenment. Yeah.
So,
one
one of
So,
one of the
one of the forms
So,
one of the forms of
one of the forms of love
So,
one of the forms of love that
one of the forms of love that we
So,
one of the forms of love that we didn't
get
get a
get a chance
get a chance to
get a chance to talk
get a chance to talk about
get a chance to talk about this
get a chance to talk about this morning
is
is the
get a chance to talk about this morning
is the classic
is the classic yoga
get a chance to talk about this morning
is the classic yoga of
is the classic yoga of karma
get a chance to talk about this morning
is the classic yoga of karma yoga.
is the classic yoga of karma yoga. You
know,
know, the
know, the the
know, the the great
know, the the great yoga
u
u through
know, the the great yoga
u through the
u through the heart
know, the the great yoga
u through the heart through
u through the heart through non-duality
through
through mind.
Third
Third the
through mind.
Third the third
Third the third great
through mind.
Third the third great one
Third the third great one which
characterizes
characterizes Christianity
characterizes Christianity and
characterizes
characterizes in
characterizes Christianity and
characterizes in fact
characterizes in fact all
characterizes Christianity and
characterizes in fact all spiritually
motivated
motivated people
motivated people is
motivated people is um
motivated people is um karma
motivated people is um karma yoga
motivated people is um karma yoga the
the the
the the yoga
motivated people is um karma yoga the
the the yoga of
the the yoga of service.
And
And Krishna
And Krishna speaks
And Krishna speaks of
And Krishna speaks of that
And Krishna speaks of that um
it
it brings
And Krishna speaks of that um
it brings up
it brings up something
And Krishna speaks of that um
it brings up something extremely
important
important that
important that what
important that what spiritual
important that what spiritual work
important that what spiritual work is
really
really about
is
is a
is a recontextualization
is a recontextualization of
is a recontextualization of your
is a recontextualization of your entire
of
of your
is a recontextualization of your entire
of your whole
of your whole life
is a recontextualization of your entire
of your whole life and
of your whole life and everything
is a recontextualization of your entire
of your whole life and everything in
of your whole life and everything in it.
So
So devotion,
So devotion, the
So devotion, the pathway
So devotion, the pathway of
So devotion, the pathway of love
So devotion, the pathway of love is
sanctifying
all
all of
all of your
all of your life
all of your life in
all of your life in all
all of your life in all of
all of your life in all of its
all of your life in all of its details
and
and all
all of your life in all of its details
and all of
and all of its
all of your life in all of its details
and all of its expressions
as
as an
as an expression
as an expression of
as an expression of love
as an expression of love to
as an expression of love to God
as an expression of love to God and
as an expression of love to God and to
all
all that
as an expression of love to God and to
all that exists.
So,
So, as
So, as you
So, as you take
So, as you take that
So, as you take that little
So, as you take that little ring
So, as you take that little ring off
So, as you take that little ring off the
top
top of
So, as you take that little ring off the
top of your
top of your stove
So, as you take that little ring off the
top of your stove that
top of your stove that goes
So, as you take that little ring off the
top of your stove that goes around
top of your stove that goes around the
burner
burner there
burner there and
burner there and you
burner there and you take
burner there and you take the
burner there and you take the steel
burner there and you take the steel wall
and
and you
burner there and you take the steel wall
and you really
and you really polish
burner there and you take the steel wall
and you really polish it
and you really polish it so
burner there and you take the steel wall
and you really polish it so it
and you really polish it so it shines,
you
you do
you do so
you do so because
you do so because everything
you do so because everything that
you do so because everything that exists
exists
exists because
you do so because everything that exists
exists because innately
exists because innately it's
you do so because everything that exists
exists because innately it's divine.
Once
Once you
Once you see
Once you see the
Once you see the divinity
Once you see the divinity of
Once you see the divinity of all
Once you see the divinity of all things,
watering
watering the
Once you see the divinity of all things,
watering the garden,
watering the garden, shining
Once you see the divinity of all things,
watering the garden, shining your
watering the garden, shining your shoes,
all
all are
all are equal.
all are equal. All
all are equal. All are
all are equal. All are done
all are equal. All are done as
so
so as
all are equal. All are done as
so as a
so as a devoted
all are equal. All are done as
so as a devoted being
so as a devoted being all
all are equal. All are done as
so as a devoted being all your
so as a devoted being all your actions
become
become those
become those of
become those of devotion
become those of devotion to
become those of devotion to ser
become those of devotion to ser of
service
service to
become those of devotion to ser of
service to others.
service to others. Service
become those of devotion to ser of
service to others. Service to
service to others. Service to God.
Service
Service to
Service to others
Service to others is
Service to others is service
Service to others is service to
Service to others is service to God.
Without
Without the
Service to others is service to God.
Without the dozen
Without the dozen or
Service to others is service to God.
Without the dozen or so
Without the dozen or so people
Service to others is service to God.
Without the dozen or so people it
Without the dozen or so people it took
to
to set
to set up
to set up this
to set up this conference
to set up this conference who
to set up this conference who all
to set up this conference who all did
to set up this conference who all did it
out
out of
to set up this conference who all did it
out of devotion
out of devotion until
to set up this conference who all did it
out of devotion until hours
out of devotion until hours of
to set up this conference who all did it
out of devotion until hours of the
night.
night. Aren't
night. Aren't you
night. Aren't you ever
night. Aren't you ever going
night. Aren't you ever going to
night. Aren't you ever going to go
night. Aren't you ever going to go to
bed?
Uh
Uh it
Uh it couldn't
Uh it couldn't happen.
Uh it couldn't happen. So
Uh it couldn't happen. So their
Uh it couldn't happen. So their devotion
and
and behind
Uh it couldn't happen. So their devotion
and behind their
and behind their work,
Uh it couldn't happen. So their devotion
and behind their work, the
and behind their work, the endless
Uh it couldn't happen. So their devotion
and behind their work, the endless phone
calls,
calls, the
calls, the endless
calls, the endless faxes,
calls, the endless faxes, the
calls, the endless faxes, the endless
letters,
answering
answering all
answering all that's
answering all that's required
answering all that's required to
answering all that's required to just
put
put it
answering all that's required to just
put it together
put it together is
answering all that's required to just
put it together is rather
put it together is rather a
answering all that's required to just
put it together is rather a staggering
amount
amount of
amount of work.
So
So um
amount of work.
So um their
So um their devotion.
amount of work.
So um their devotion. So
So um their devotion. So the
amount of work.
So um their devotion. So the commitment
then
then to
then to God
then to God is
then to God is a
then to God is a devotional
then to God is a devotional statement
that
that I
then to God is a devotional statement
that I am
that I am what
then to God is a devotional statement
that I am what I
that I am what I am
then to God is a devotional statement
that I am what I am and
that I am what I am and all
then to God is a devotional statement
that I am what I am and all that
that I am what I am and all that I
then to God is a devotional statement
that I am what I am and all that I do
that I am what I am and all that I do is
for
for thy
for thy sake
for thy sake oh
for thy sake oh Lord.
Not
Not that
for thy sake oh Lord.
Not that God
Not that God needs
for thy sake oh Lord.
Not that God needs it.
People
People think
People think worship
People think worship and
People think worship and all
People think worship and all that
sacrifice
sacrifice is
People think worship and all that
sacrifice is giving
sacrifice is giving something
People think worship and all that
sacrifice is giving something to
sacrifice is giving something to God.
guilt,
guilt, penance,
guilt, penance, wearing
guilt, penance, wearing ashcloth
guilt, penance, wearing ashcloth and
ashes,
ashes, ash
guilt, penance, wearing ashcloth and
ashes, ash ashes,
ashes, ash ashes, and
guilt, penance, wearing ashcloth and
ashes, ash ashes, and crawling
ashes, ash ashes, and crawling on
guilt, penance, wearing ashcloth and
ashes, ash ashes, and crawling on your
knees
knees till
knees till they
knees till they bleed
knees till they bleed across
knees till they bleed across the
cobblestones,
cobblestones, which
knees till they bleed across the
cobblestones, which we've
cobblestones, which we've all
knees till they bleed across the
cobblestones, which we've all done
cobblestones, which we've all done in
some
some lifetime.
Uh,
Uh, doesn't
some lifetime.
Uh, doesn't turn
Uh, doesn't turn God
some lifetime.
Uh, doesn't turn God on,
man.
man. I
man. I get
man. I get off
man. I get off on
man. I get off on suffering.
man. I get off on suffering. You
man. I get off on suffering. You know
what
what I
man. I get off on suffering. You know
what I mean?
what I mean? What
man. I get off on suffering. You know
what I mean? What is
what I mean? What is it?
man. I get off on suffering. You know
what I mean? What is it? Weird.
No,
No, it's
No, it's because
No, it's because in
No, it's because in our
No, it's because in our own
No, it's because in our own belief
system
system then
uh
uh our
uh our understanding
uh our understanding of
uh our understanding of God
uh our understanding of God or
misunderstanding
misunderstanding of
uh our understanding of God or
misunderstanding of God
misunderstanding of God is
uh our understanding of God or
misunderstanding of God is that
misunderstanding of God is that we
uh our understanding of God or
misunderstanding of God is that we do
this
this out
this out of
this out of devotion
this out of devotion to
this out of devotion to God.
this out of devotion to God. So
to
to you
this out of devotion to God. So
to you know
to you know you
this out of devotion to God. So
to you know you become
to you know you become a
this out of devotion to God. So
to you know you become a true
to you know you become a true spiritual
seeker
seeker you
seeker you really
seeker you really are
seeker you really are sanctifying
seeker you really are sanctifying your
whole
whole life
seeker you really are sanctifying your
whole life and
whole life and everything
seeker you really are sanctifying your
whole life and everything in
whole life and everything in it
seeker you really are sanctifying your
whole life and everything in it to
whole life and everything in it to God
and
and to
and to the
and to the service
and to the service of
and to the service of truth
and to the service of truth you
and to the service of truth you know
and to the service of truth you know and
that
that which
makes
makes the
makes the presence
makes the presence of
makes the presence of God
makes the presence of God more
makes the presence of God more apparent
to
to others.
When
When you
When you sanctify
When you sanctify all
When you sanctify all that
When you sanctify all that you
When you sanctify all that you do,
When you sanctify all that you do, then
you
you take
When you sanctify all that you do, then
you take it
you take it out
When you sanctify all that you do, then
you take it out of
you take it out of you
When you sanctify all that you do, then
you take it out of you take
you take it out of you take it
When you sanctify all that you do, then
you take it out of you take it from
you take it out of you take it from the
mundane
mundane into
mundane into a
mundane into a different
mundane into a different realm.
You
You because
mundane into a different realm.
You because you're
You because you're putting
mundane into a different realm.
You because you're putting it
You because you're putting it in
mundane into a different realm.
You because you're putting it in a
different
different context.
And
And power
different context.
And power comes
And power comes out
different context.
And power comes out of
And power comes out of context.
different context.
And power comes out of context. It's
And power comes out of context. It's the
context
context that
context that gives
context that gives all
context that gives all that
context that gives all that exists
context that gives all that exists is
power.
power. It's
context that gives all that exists is
power. It's out
power. It's out of
context that gives all that exists is
power. It's out of context
power. It's out of context that
context that gives all that exists is
power. It's out of context that you
survive
survive from
survive from moment
survive from moment to
survive from moment to moment.
Once
Once you
survive from moment to moment.
Once you see
Once you see uh
survive from moment to moment.
Once you see uh once
Once you see uh once well
survive from moment to moment.
Once you see uh once well in
Once you see uh once well in a
survive from moment to moment.
Once you see uh once well in a in
Once you see uh once well in a in a
near-death
near-death experience,
near-death experience, you
near-death experience, you become
near-death experience, you become aware
of
of that
near-death experience, you become aware
of that that
of that that that
near-death experience, you become aware
of that that that which
of that that that which you
near-death experience, you become aware
of that that that which you are
of that that that which you are is
near-death experience, you become aware
of that that that which you are is is
always
always existence
always existence and
always existence and it's
always existence and it's survival
always existence and it's survival was
never
never threatened
always existence and it's survival was
never threatened in
never threatened in the
always existence and it's survival was
never threatened in the first
never threatened in the first place
always existence and it's survival was
never threatened in the first place and
all
all the
all the worries
all the worries you
all the worries you ever
all the worries you ever had
all the worries you ever had were
ridiculous.
If
If karmically
If karmically when
If karmically when you
If karmically when you leave
If karmically when you leave this
If karmically when you leave this world
is
is already
If karmically when you leave this world
is already set,
is already set, which
If karmically when you leave this world
is already set, which it
is already set, which it is,
If karmically when you leave this world
is already set, which it is, then
obviously
obviously you
obviously you had
obviously you had to
obviously you had to get
obviously you had to get there.
obviously you had to get there. In
obviously you had to get there. In order
to
to die
obviously you had to get there. In order
to die at
to die at a
obviously you had to get there. In order
to die at a prescribed
to die at a prescribed point
obviously you had to get there. In order
to die at a prescribed point in
to die at a prescribed point in time,
you
you must
you must have
you must have survived
you must have survived long
you must have survived long enough
you must have survived long enough to
get
get there.
you must have survived long enough to
get there. So
get there. So you
you must have survived long enough to
get there. So you can
get there. So you can quit
you must have survived long enough to
get there. So you can quit worrying
about
about survival
about survival because
about survival because between
about survival because between now
about survival because between now and
the
the time
about survival because between now and
the time you
the time you die,
about survival because between now and
the time you die, your
the time you die, your survival
about survival because between now and
the time you die, your survival is
guaranteed.
That's
That's a
guaranteed.
That's a true
That's a true statement.
guaranteed.
That's a true statement. Resist.
That's a true statement. Resist. That's
a
a true
a true statement.
Between
Between now
a true statement.
Between now and
Between now and the
a true statement.
Between now and the time
Between now and the time you
a true statement.
Between now and the time you die,
Between now and the time you die, your
survival
survival is
survival is guaranteed.
survival is guaranteed. So
survival is guaranteed. So stop
survival is guaranteed. So stop worrying
about
about it.
Whether
Whether you
Whether you go
Whether you go from
Whether you go from this
Whether you go from this or
Whether you go from this or go
Whether you go from this or go from
that,
that, it's
Whether you go from this or go from
that, it's irrelevant,
that, it's irrelevant, isn't
Whether you go from this or go from
that, it's irrelevant, isn't it?
that, it's irrelevant, isn't it? I
Whether you go from this or go from
that, it's irrelevant, isn't it? I mean,
when
when you
when you go
when you go over
when you go over a
when you go over a cliff
when you go over a cliff or
when you go over a cliff or and
whatever,
it
it doesn't
it doesn't really
it doesn't really make
it doesn't really make any
it doesn't really make any difference.
Huh?
We've
We've said
We've said that
We've said that before
We've said that before that
We've said that before that the
We've said that before that the time
We've said that before that the time of
your
your death
We've said that before that the time of
your death is
your death is already
We've said that before that the time of
your death is already karmically
destined
destined from
destined from the
destined from the moment
destined from the moment of
destined from the moment of your
destined from the moment of your birth.
Huh?
>> Let's
>> Let's ratify
>> Let's ratify that.
>> Let's ratify that. That
>> Let's ratify that. That is
>> Let's ratify that. That is still
>> Let's ratify that. That is still true.
Still
Still true
>> to
>> to know
>> to know that
>> to know that when
>> to know that when you
>> to know that when you leave
>> to know that when you leave here
>> to know that when you leave here is
already
already preset.
>> to know that when you leave here is
already preset. You
already preset. You can
>> to know that when you leave here is
already preset. You can quit
already preset. You can quit worrying
about
about it.
about it. You
about it. You know,
why
why on
about it. You know,
why on why
why on why don't
about it. You know,
why on why don't you
why on why don't you do
about it. You know,
why on why don't you do this,
why on why don't you do this, you
about it. You know,
why on why don't you do this, you live
longer.
longer. Do
longer. Do that,
longer. Do that, you'll
longer. Do that, you'll live
longer. Do that, you'll live longer.
longer. Do that, you'll live longer. I
mean,
mean, it's
longer. Do that, you'll live longer. I
mean, it's absurd.
mean, it's absurd. How
longer. Do that, you'll live longer. I
mean, it's absurd. How you
mean, it's absurd. How you going
longer. Do that, you'll live longer. I
mean, it's absurd. How you going to
mean, it's absurd. How you going to get
out
out of
out of this
out of this world,
out of this world, folks?
I
I mean,
out of this world, folks?
I mean, they
I mean, they close
out of this world, folks?
I mean, they close all
I mean, they close all the
out of this world, folks?
I mean, they close all the door.
I mean, they close all the door. You
can't
can't die
can't die of
can't die of this.
can't die of this. You
can't die of this. You can't
can't die of this. You can't die
can't die of this. You can't die of
that.
that. I
can't die of this. You can't die of
that. I mean,
that. I mean, what's
can't die of this. You can't die of
that. I mean, what's going
that. I mean, what's going to
can't die of this. You can't die of
that. I mean, what's going to happen?
You're
You're going
You're going to
You're going to become
You're going to become immortal.
You're going to become immortal. Can
You're going to become immortal. Can you
imagine
imagine what
You're going to become immortal. Can you
imagine what you're
imagine what you're going
You're going to become immortal. Can you
imagine what you're going to
imagine what you're going to look
You're going to become immortal. Can you
imagine what you're going to look like
when
when you're
when you're 150?
when you're 150? I
when you're 150? I mean,
like
like all
when you're 150? I mean,
like all these
like all these guys
when you're 150? I mean,
like all these guys killing
like all these guys killing themselves
for
for God
and
and then
for God
and then they're
and then they're going
for God
and then they're going to
and then they're going to get
for God
and then they're going to get 70
versions
versions when
versions when they
versions when they get
versions when they get there.
versions when they get there. I
versions when they get there. I always
joke.
joke. Yeah,
versions when they get there. I always
joke. Yeah, but
joke. Yeah, but they're
versions when they get there. I always
joke. Yeah, but they're 900
joke. Yeah, but they're 900 years
versions when they get there. I always
joke. Yeah, but they're 900 years old.
Heaven
Heaven is
Heaven is not
Heaven is not really
Heaven is not really a
Heaven is not really a bordello,
Heaven is not really a bordello, you
know.
All
All right.
All right. So,
All right. So, humor
All right. So, humor about
All right. So, humor about it
All right. So, humor about it is
All right. So, humor about it is better
than
than being
All right. So, humor about it is better
than being angry,
than being angry, uh
All right. So, humor about it is better
than being angry, uh being
than being angry, uh being vicious.
All right. So, humor about it is better
than being angry, uh being vicious. Uh
you
you know,
you know, because
you know, because uh
you know, because uh humor
you know, because uh humor is
you know, because uh humor is a
you know, because uh humor is a form
you know, because uh humor is a form of
compassion.
You
You understand
You understand that
You understand that people
You understand that people who
You understand that people who are
innocent
innocent are
You understand that people who are
innocent are easily
innocent are easily misled.
You understand that people who are
innocent are easily misled. They're
easily
easily taken
easily taken over
easily taken over by
that
that which
easily taken over by
that which is
that which is ungodly.
easily taken over by
that which is ungodly. And
that which is ungodly. And the
easily taken over by
that which is ungodly. And the most
common
common way
common way to
common way to take
common way to take over
common way to take over that
common way to take over that which
common way to take over that which is
God,
God, you
common way to take over that which is
God, you know,
God, you know, the
common way to take over that which is
God, you know, the most
God, you know, the most common
common way to take over that which is
God, you know, the most common way
God, you know, the most common way is
common way to take over that which is
God, you know, the most common way is to
to
to claim
to claim the
to claim the name
to claim the name of
to claim the name of God
to claim the name of God in
to claim the name of God in in
to claim the name of God in in in
to claim the name of God in in in the
and
and then
to claim the name of God in in in the
and then be
and then be up
to claim the name of God in in in the
and then be up to
and then be up to something
to claim the name of God in in in the
and then be up to something horrible,
but
but do
but do it
but do it in
but do it in the
but do it in the name
but do it in the name of
but do it in the name of God.
So
So anyway,
but do it in the name of God.
So anyway, that
So anyway, that which
but do it in the name of God.
So anyway, that which usurps
So anyway, that which usurps the
but do it in the name of God.
So anyway, that which usurps the name
So anyway, that which usurps the name of
God
God has
God has its
God has its own
God has its own karma
God has its own karma to
God has its own karma to u
God has its own karma to u count
God has its own karma to u count for.
And
And that
God has its own karma to u count for.
And that was
And that was why
God has its own karma to u count for.
And that was why the
And that was why the first
God has its own karma to u count for.
And that was why the first question
And that was why the first question we
got
got was
got was no
people
people who
got was no
people who do
people who do that
got was no
people who do that are
people who do that are not
got was no
people who do that are not destined
people who do that are not destined for
enlightenment
enlightenment to
rape
rape the
enlightenment to
rape the innocent
rape the innocent spiritually
enlightenment to
rape the innocent spiritually innocent
with
with that
with that which
with that which is
with that which is facious
with that which is facious and
with that which is facious and leads
with that which is facious and leads in
the
the opposite
with that which is facious and leads in
the opposite direction
the opposite direction must
with that which is facious and leads in
the opposite direction must have
the opposite direction must have a
with that which is facious and leads in
the opposite direction must have a karma
too
too horrible
too horrible to
too horrible to think
too horrible to think about.
too horrible to think about. I
too horrible to think about. I don't
want
want to
too horrible to think about. I don't
want to even
want to even think
too horrible to think about. I don't
want to even think about
want to even think about it.
Um
Um then
Um then we
Um then we get
Um then we get very
Um then we get very specific
Um then we get very specific questions
spirituality
spirituality then
Um then we get very specific questions
spirituality then to
spirituality then to be
Um then we get very specific questions
spirituality then to be a
spirituality then to be a seeker
Um then we get very specific questions
spirituality then to be a seeker to
spirituality then to be a seeker to be
um
um devote
um devote whatever
um devote whatever you
um devote whatever you want
um devote whatever you want to
um devote whatever you want to call
um devote whatever you want to call it
to
to be
um devote whatever you want to call it
to be a
to be a monk
um devote whatever you want to call it
to be a monk to
to be a monk to be
um devote whatever you want to call it
to be a monk to be a
to be a monk to be a layman
um devote whatever you want to call it
to be a monk to be a layman to
to be a monk to be a layman to u
walk
walk about
walk about in
walk about in a
walk about in a contemplative
walk about in a contemplative state.
walk about in a contemplative state. No
matter
matter what
walk about in a contemplative state. No
matter what you
matter what you do
it's
it's because
it's because you've
it's because you've contextualized
it's because you've contextualized your
life
life in
it's because you've contextualized your
life in a
life in a different
it's because you've contextualized your
life in a different manner.
Once
Once you
Once you context,
Once you context, once
Once you context, once you've
Once you context, once you've sanctified
your
your own
Once you context, once you've sanctified
your own life
your own life and
Once you context, once you've sanctified
your own life and I
your own life and I surrender
Once you context, once you've sanctified
your own life and I surrender my
your own life and I surrender my life
Once you context, once you've sanctified
your own life and I surrender my life to
thee,
thee, oh
thee, oh Lord,
you
you can
thee, oh Lord,
you can talk
you can talk about
thee, oh Lord,
you can talk about love,
you can talk about love, but
thee, oh Lord,
you can talk about love, but once
you can talk about love, but once when
it
it takes
it takes over,
it takes over, you
it takes over, you can't
it takes over, you can't talk
it takes over, you can't talk anymore.
Um
Um the
it takes over, you can't talk anymore.
Um the surrender
Um the surrender to
it takes over, you can't talk anymore.
Um the surrender to God
Um the surrender to God at
it takes over, you can't talk anymore.
Um the surrender to God at great
Um the surrender to God at great depth
is
is overwhelming
is overwhelming and
that
that was
is overwhelming and
that was what
that was what brought
is overwhelming and
that was what brought on
that was what brought on the
is overwhelming and
that was what brought on the state
that was what brought on the state that
occurred
occurred in
occurred in 1965
and
and swept
occurred in 1965
and swept away
and swept away everything
for
for many
for many years.
Yeah.
Um,
we'll
we'll go
Um,
we'll go back
we'll go back to
Um,
we'll go back to some
we'll go back to some specific
questions.
questions. Let's
questions. Let's see.
You
You lose
questions. Let's see.
You lose your
You lose your sense
questions. Let's see.
You lose your sense of
You lose your sense of humor.
questions. Let's see.
You lose your sense of humor. You're
gone.
Oh,
Oh, now
gone.
Oh, now I'm
Oh, now I'm better.
gone.
Oh, now I'm better. Okay.
That's
That's right.
That's right. Not
That's right. Not everybody's
That's right. Not everybody's going
That's right. Not everybody's going to
get
get enlightened.
That's right. Not everybody's going to
get enlightened. Not
get enlightened. Not you,
That's right. Not everybody's going to
get enlightened. Not you, boy.
Ah,
Ah, okay.
Ah, okay. Now
Ah, okay. Now we're
Ah, okay. Now we're back
Ah, okay. Now we're back in
Ah, okay. Now we're back in the
Ah, okay. Now we're back in the ranch
book.
book. Well,
Ah, okay. Now we're back in the ranch
book. Well, we
book. Well, we as
Ah, okay. Now we're back in the ranch
book. Well, we as we
book. Well, we as we get
Ah, okay. Now we're back in the ranch
book. Well, we as we get asked
book. Well, we as we get asked a
Ah, okay. Now we're back in the ranch
book. Well, we as we get asked a lot
book. Well, we as we get asked a lot of
a
a lot
a lot of
a lot of details,
a lot of details, specific
a lot of details, specific gurus,
specific
specific uh
a lot of details, specific gurus,
specific uh books.
We're
We're working
We're working now.
We're working now. We
We're working now. We just
We're working now. We just finished.
We're working now. We just finished. I
Sonia,
Sonia, God
We're working now. We just finished. I
Sonia, God bless
Sonia, God bless her,
We're working now. We just finished. I
Sonia, God bless her, um
is
is uh
is uh finishing
is uh finishing the
is uh finishing the we
is uh finishing the we hope
is uh finishing the we hope the
is uh finishing the we hope the next
is uh finishing the we hope the next the
final
final manuscript.
And
And um
I
I don't
And um
I don't know
I don't know what
And um
I don't know what I
I don't know what I was
And um
I don't know what I was talking
I don't know what I was talking about.
Oh
Oh yes.
Oh yes. And
Oh yes. And then
Oh yes. And then after
Oh yes. And then after we
Oh yes. And then after we finish
Oh yes. And then after we finish that,
we're
we're already
Oh yes. And then after we finish that,
we're already halfway
we're already halfway through
Oh yes. And then after we finish that,
we're already halfway through another
book
book in
book in which
book in which we
book in which we do
book in which we do about
book in which we do about a
book in which we do about a thousand
calibrations
because
because uh
because uh first
because uh first of
because uh first of all,
because uh first of all, library's
because uh first of all, library's got
the
the time
because uh first of all, library's got
the time to
the time to do
because uh first of all, library's got
the time to do them.
the time to do them. You
because uh first of all, library's got
the time to do them. You know,
the time to do them. You know, you
because uh first of all, library's got
the time to do them. You know, you got
to
to go
to go to
to go to work,
to go to work, you
to go to work, you got
to go to work, you got family
to go to work, you got family and
to go to work, you got family and kids,
you
you can't
to go to work, you got family and kids,
you can't just
you can't just stand
to go to work, you got family and kids,
you can't just stand around
you can't just stand around calibering
stuff
stuff all
stuff all day.
stuff all day. And
stuff all day. And um
and
and then
stuff all day. And um
and then people
and then people don't
stuff all day. And um
and then people don't have
and then people don't have faith
stuff all day. And um
and then people don't have faith in
their
their own
their own capacity.
their own capacity. They
their own capacity. They want
their own capacity. They want u
confirmation.
confirmation. So
their own capacity. They want u
confirmation. So we're
confirmation. So we're doing
their own capacity. They want u
confirmation. So we're doing about
thousand
thousand calibrations
thousand calibrations of
thousand calibrations of things
thousand calibrations of things that
thousand calibrations of things that we
think
think would
thousand calibrations of things that we
think would be
think would be of
thousand calibrations of things that we
think would be of interest.
think would be of interest. It's
thousand calibrations of things that we
think would be of interest. It's like
you're
you're going
you're going from
you're going from black
you're going from black and
you're going from black and white
you're going from black and white into
technicolor.
technicolor. When
you're going from black and white into
technicolor. When you
technicolor. When you add
you're going from black and white into
technicolor. When you add calibrations
to
to everything
to everything that
to everything that ever
to everything that ever occurred
from
from the
to everything that ever occurred
from the pure
from the pure great
to everything that ever occurred
from the pure great pyramids
from the pure great pyramids to
to everything that ever occurred
from the pure great pyramids to all
from the pure great pyramids to all the
great
great cathedrals
great cathedrals to
great cathedrals to the
great cathedrals to the great
great cathedrals to the great composers
to
to all
great cathedrals to the great composers
to all the
to all the great
great cathedrals to the great composers
to all the great philosophers,
scientists,
works
works of
scientists,
works of art,
works of art, music,
scientists,
works of art, music, not
works of art, music, not only
scientists,
works of art, music, not only throughout
history
history but
history but contemporary,
history but contemporary, you
history but contemporary, you get
history but contemporary, you get a
totally
totally different
history but contemporary, you get a
totally different understanding
totally different understanding of
history but contemporary, you get a
totally different understanding of life
and
and its
and its expressions.
Totally
Totally different
and its expressions.
Totally different understanding,
Totally different understanding, much
greater
greater depth.
greater depth. You
greater depth. You finally
greater depth. You finally go,
greater depth. You finally go, "Oh,
greater depth. You finally go, "Oh, I
see.
see. Oh,
greater depth. You finally go, "Oh, I
see. Oh, I
see. Oh, I see.
greater depth. You finally go, "Oh, I
see. Oh, I see. Oh,
see. Oh, I see. Oh, I
greater depth. You finally go, "Oh, I
see. Oh, I see. Oh, I see."
So
So we
So we feel
So we feel that
So we feel that it's
So we feel that it's a
So we feel that it's a great
So we feel that it's a great just
So we feel that it's a great just going
over
over the
So we feel that it's a great just going
over the numbers
um
just
just to
um
just to read
just to read through
um
just to read through the
just to read through the numbers
um
just to read through the numbers you
just to read through the numbers you go
through
through an
through an aha
through an aha experience.
The
The first
through an aha experience.
The first time
The first time I
through an aha experience.
The first time I was
The first time I was I
through an aha experience.
The first time I was I was
The first time I was I was at
through an aha experience.
The first time I was I was at the
The first time I was I was at the time
through an aha experience.
The first time I was I was at the time a
teacher
teacher of the
teacher of the course
teacher of the course of
teacher of the course of miracles
teacher of the course of miracles and
teacher of the course of miracles and I
had
had a
teacher of the course of miracles and I
had a secretary
had a secretary back
teacher of the course of miracles and I
had a secretary back east
had a secretary back east and
teacher of the course of miracles and I
had a secretary back east and we
had a secretary back east and we were
comparing
comparing she
comparing she was
comparing she was making
comparing she was making a
comparing she was making a list
comparing she was making a list of
comparing she was making a list of ego
positions
positions and
comparing she was making a list of ego
positions and uh
positions and uh their
comparing she was making a list of ego
positions and uh their spiritual
corollary
corollary and
corollary and as
corollary and as she
corollary and as she was
corollary and as she was typing
corollary and as she was typing it
corollary and as she was typing it up
she
she went
corollary and as she was typing it up
she went into
she went into oblitation.
She
She never
She never she
She never she wasn't
She never she wasn't even
She never she wasn't even interested
She never she wasn't even interested in
the
the subject.
She never she wasn't even interested in
the subject. She
the subject. She said,
She never she wasn't even interested in
the subject. She said, "I
the subject. She said, "I just
god
god bless
god bless her
god bless her heart."
god bless her heart." And
god bless her heart." And uh
she
she was
god bless her heart." And uh
she was my
she was my secretary
god bless her heart." And uh
she was my secretary back
she was my secretary back east
god bless her heart." And uh
she was my secretary back east for
she was my secretary back east for some
20 years.
20 years. So
20 years. So um
20 years. So um anyway,
20 years. So um anyway, she
20 years. So um anyway, she just
20 years. So um anyway, she just blissed
out
out um
20 years. So um anyway, she just blissed
out um just
out um just from
20 years. So um anyway, she just blissed
out um just from the
out um just from the material.
So
I
I feel
So
I feel it
I feel it would
So
I feel it would be
I feel it would be greatly
So
I feel it would be greatly valuable.
We're
We're trying
We're trying to
We're trying to figure
We're trying to figure out
We're trying to figure out how
We're trying to figure out how to
We're trying to figure out how to write
it
it without
We're trying to figure out how to write
it without hurting
it without hurting anybody's
We're trying to figure out how to write
it without hurting anybody's feelings.
But
But I
But I don't
But I don't know
But I don't know that's
But I don't know that's going
But I don't know that's going to
But I don't know that's going to be
possible.
possible. We
But I don't know that's going to be
possible. We could
possible. We could just
But I don't know that's going to be
possible. We could just stick
possible. We could just stick the
But I don't know that's going to be
possible. We could just stick the dead
people,
people, but
people, but they
people, but they got
people, but they got descendants.
people, but they got descendants. You
know,
know, my
people, but they got descendants. You
know, my great
know, my great great
people, but they got descendants. You
know, my great great great
know, my great great great grandfather
was.
So
So anyway,
was.
So anyway, how
So anyway, how to
was.
So anyway, how to express
So anyway, how to express that?
So
So there
So there are
So there are so
So there are so many
So there are so many books
So there are so many books I
So there are so many books I we've
advised
advised you
So there are so many books I we've
advised you go
advised you go through
So there are so many books I we've
advised you go through your
advised you go through your spiritual
library,
library, see
library, see what
library, see what makes
library, see what makes you
library, see what makes you go
library, see what makes you go strong,
see
see what
library, see what makes you go strong,
see what makes
see what makes you
library, see what makes you go strong,
see what makes you go
see what makes you go weak.
library, see what makes you go strong,
see what makes you go weak. And
see what makes you go weak. And those
that
that make
that make you
that make you go
that make you go weak,
that make you go weak, throw
that make you go weak, throw them
that make you go weak, throw them away
and
and leave
that make you go weak, throw them away
and leave them
and leave them in
that make you go weak, throw them away
and leave them in a
and leave them in a pile,
that make you go weak, throw them away
and leave them in a pile, but
and leave them in a pile, but don't
throw
throw them
throw them out
throw them out right
throw them out right away.
throw them out right away. Leave
throw them out right away. Leave them
there
there for
throw them out right away. Leave them
there for a
there for a week
throw them out right away. Leave them
there for a week because
there for a week because you
throw them out right away. Leave them
there for a week because you walk
there for a week because you walk by
them
them every
them every day,
them every day, you
them every day, you finally
them every day, you finally get
them every day, you finally get it.
them every day, you finally get it. Wow,
I
I see
them every day, you finally get it. Wow,
I see what
I see what the
them every day, you finally get it. Wow,
I see what the difference
I see what the difference is.
them every day, you finally get it. Wow,
I see what the difference is. You
I see what the difference is. You know,
uh
uh all
uh all the
uh all the end
uh all the end times
uh all the end times uh
uh all the end times uh books
uh all the end times uh books and
uh all the end times uh books and all,
you
you know,
uh all the end times uh books and all,
you know, all
you know, all that
uh all the end times uh books and all,
you know, all that kind
you know, all that kind of
uh all the end times uh books and all,
you know, all that kind of stuff
you know, all that kind of stuff is
uh all the end times uh books and all,
you know, all that kind of stuff is all
over
over here.
over here. See,
over here. See, those
over here. See, those things
over here. See, those things which
over here. See, those things which are
eternal
eternal truths.
over here. See, those things which are
eternal truths. Um
you
you can
you can tell
you can tell that
you can tell that that
you can tell that that which
you can tell that that which is
you can tell that that which is true
you can tell that that which is true has
been
been agreed
you can tell that that which is true has
been agreed upon
been agreed upon by
you can tell that that which is true has
been agreed upon by every
been agreed upon by every enlightened
being
being throughout
being throughout all
being throughout all of
being throughout all of time.
being throughout all of time. There's
absolutely
absolutely no
being throughout all of time. There's
absolutely no disagreement
absolutely no disagreement about
anything
between
between all
anything
between all enlightened
between all enlightened beings.
anything
between all enlightened beings. It's
always
always been
always been exactly
always been exactly the
always been exactly the same.
always been exactly the same. Anything
that
that varies
always been exactly the same. Anything
that varies from
that varies from that
always been exactly the same. Anything
that varies from that is
that varies from that is not
always been exactly the same. Anything
that varies from that is not the
that varies from that is not the truth.
And
And we
And we make
And we make that
And we make that rather
And we make that rather specific
And we make that rather specific in
And we make that rather specific in the
book
book we
And we make that rather specific in the
book we just
book we just finished.
And we make that rather specific in the
book we just finished. But
book we just finished. But I
And we make that rather specific in the
book we just finished. But I thought
book we just finished. But I thought the
next
next book
next book where
next book where we
next book where we calibrate
next book where we calibrate about
next book where we calibrate about a
thousand
thousand things
next book where we calibrate about a
thousand things tells
thousand things tells you
next book where we calibrate about a
thousand things tells you where
thousand things tells you where it
next book where we calibrate about a
thousand things tells you where it all
is.
is. Now
is. Now everything
is. Now everything doesn't
is. Now everything doesn't have
is. Now everything doesn't have to
is. Now everything doesn't have to be
is. Now everything doesn't have to be a
thousand
thousand to
is. Now everything doesn't have to be a
thousand to be
thousand to be useful.
is. Now everything doesn't have to be a
thousand to be useful. You
thousand to be useful. You know
is. Now everything doesn't have to be a
thousand to be useful. You know what
thousand to be useful. You know what I'm
saying?
If
If you're
saying?
If you're down
If you're down here,
saying?
If you're down here, something
If you're down here, something that
calibrates
calibrates at
calibrates at 180
calibrates at 180 is
calibrates at 180 is going
calibrates at 180 is going to
calibrates at 180 is going to be
calibrates at 180 is going to be very
good.
good. You
calibrates at 180 is going to be very
good. You know
good. You know what
calibrates at 180 is going to be very
good. You know what I'm
good. You know what I'm saying?
calibrates at 180 is going to be very
good. You know what I'm saying? If
you're
you're in
you're in apathy,
you're in apathy, if
you're in apathy, if you
you're in apathy, if you can
you're in apathy, if you can get
you're in apathy, if you can get up
you're in apathy, if you can get up to
wanting
wanting something,
uh,
uh, you've
uh, you've made
uh, you've made a
uh, you've made a big
uh, you've made a big move
uh, you've made a big move out
uh, you've made a big move out of
uh, you've made a big move out of the
waste
waste basket,
crawling
crawling across
crawling across on
crawling across on your
crawling across on your bare
crawling across on your bare knees,
beating
beating yourself,
falling
falling over,
crying
crying all
falling over,
crying all the
crying all the time,
falling over,
crying all the time, quivering,
crying all the time, quivering, laying
there
there paralyzed
there paralyzed with
there paralyzed with fear.
If
If you
there paralyzed with fear.
If you can
If you can get
there paralyzed with fear.
If you can get pissed
If you can get pissed about
there paralyzed with fear.
If you can get pissed about something,
you're
you're going
you're going to
you're going to at least
you're going to at least move
you're going to at least move your
you're going to at least move your body
in
in some
you're going to at least move your body
in some kind
in some kind of
you're going to at least move your body
in some kind of a
in some kind of a positive
you're going to at least move your body
in some kind of a positive direction
because
because you
because you know
because you know how
because you know how to
because you know how to win
because you know how to win and
because you know how to win and get
because you know how to win and get out
of
of this
because you know how to win and get out
of this freaking
of this freaking state
because you know how to win and get out
of this freaking state you're
of this freaking state you're in.
Don't
Don't forget
Don't forget whole
Don't forget whole continents
Don't forget whole continents live
Don't forget whole continents live here.
Whole
Whole continents
Don't forget whole continents live here.
Whole continents are
Whole continents are born
Don't forget whole continents live here.
Whole continents are born in
Whole continents are born in this
Don't forget whole continents live here.
Whole continents are born in this level
down
down here.
down here. Whole
down here. Whole continents.
down here. Whole continents. The
down here. Whole continents. The whole
continent
continent of
down here. Whole continents. The whole
continent of Africa.
continent of Africa. Whole
down here. Whole continents. The whole
continent of Africa. Whole continent
calibrates
calibrates like
calibrates like 70
calibrates like 70 or
calibrates like 70 or something.
calibrates like 70 or something. You're
born
born with
calibrates like 70 or something. You're
born with AIDS
born with AIDS to
calibrates like 70 or something. You're
born with AIDS to povertystricken
drugaddicted
drugaddicted parents
drugaddicted parents who
drugaddicted parents who desert
drugaddicted parents who desert desert
you
you and
drugaddicted parents who desert desert
you and don't
you and don't feed
drugaddicted parents who desert desert
you and don't feed you
you and don't feed you and
drugaddicted parents who desert desert
you and don't feed you and you
you and don't feed you and you die
starvation
starvation at
starvation at age
starvation at age six
starvation at age six months.
starvation at age six months. Whole
continents
continents live
starvation at age six months. Whole
continents live that
continents live that way.
starvation at age six months. Whole
continents live that way. whole
continents,
continents, whole
continents, whole countries.
You
You know,
we
we live
we live in
we live in a
we live in a civilized
we live in a civilized society
we live in a civilized society that
calibrates
calibrates around
we live in a civilized society that
calibrates around 430
calibrates around 430 and
we live in a civilized society that
calibrates around 430 and we
calibrates around 430 and we think
that's
that's what's
that's what's normal.
that's what's normal. That's
that's what's normal. That's what's
normal
normal for
that's what's normal. That's what's
normal for us,
normal for us, but
that's what's normal. That's what's
normal for us, but it
normal for us, but it is
that's what's normal. That's what's
normal for us, but it is definitely
normal for us, but it is definitely not
what's
what's what's
what's what's normal
what's what's normal for
what's what's normal for other
what's what's normal for other people.
All right.
All right. So,
what's what's normal for other people.
All right. So, we
All right. So, we thought
what's what's normal for other people.
All right. So, we thought I
All right. So, we thought I wanted
what's what's normal for other people.
All right. So, we thought I wanted to
for
for these
for these lectures
for these lectures I
for these lectures I had
for these lectures I had I
for these lectures I had I wanted
for these lectures I had I wanted to
make
make a
for these lectures I had I wanted to
make a map
make a map map
for these lectures I had I wanted to
make a map map of
make a map map of the
for these lectures I had I wanted to
make a map map of the world.
make a map map of the world. you
for these lectures I had I wanted to
make a map map of the world. you know,
make a map map of the world. you know, I
had
had Europe
had Europe and
had Europe and I
had Europe and I had
had Europe and I had South
had Europe and I had South America
had Europe and I had South America and
had Europe and I had South America and I
took
took out
had Europe and I had South America and I
took out some
took out some atlas
had Europe and I had South America and I
took out some atlas and
took out some atlas and it
had Europe and I had South America and I
took out some atlas and it didn't
took out some atlas and it didn't uh
copy
copy very
copy very good
copy very good off
copy very good off the
copy very good off the copy
copy very good off the copy machine,
copy very good off the copy machine, but
I
I thought
copy very good off the copy machine, but
I thought the
I thought the different
copy very good off the copy machine, but
I thought the different countries
I thought the different countries of
copy very good off the copy machine, but
I thought the different countries of the
world
world and
world and continents
world and continents and
world and continents and what
world and continents and what is
world and continents and what is the
calibrated
calibrated level
world and continents and what is the
calibrated level of
calibrated level of those
world and continents and what is the
calibrated level of those the
calibrated level of those the energies
of
of those
of those various
of those various societies,
of those various societies, those
various
various countries,
of those various societies, those
various countries, it
various countries, it gives
of those various societies, those
various countries, it gives you
various countries, it gives you quite
of those various societies, those
various countries, it gives you quite an
understanding
understanding of
understanding of the
understanding of the of
understanding of the of of
understanding of the of of politics.
Without
Without without
understanding of the of of politics.
Without without those
Without without those calibrations,
understanding of the of of politics.
Without without those calibrations, you
don't
don't really
don't really understand
don't really understand politics
don't really understand politics because
you're
you're coming
don't really understand politics because
you're coming at
you're coming at it
don't really understand politics because
you're coming at it from
you're coming at it from your
don't really understand politics because
you're coming at it from your position.
You
You know,
You know, uh,
You know, uh, you're
You know, uh, you're not
You know, uh, you're not your
You know, uh, you're not your position
is
is not
You know, uh, you're not your position
is not what
is not what prevails
You know, uh, you're not your position
is not what prevails elsewhere
is not what prevails elsewhere in
You know, uh, you're not your position
is not what prevails elsewhere in this
world
world at
world at all.
world at all. Not
world at all. Not at
world at all. Not at all.
world at all. Not at all. Not
world at all. Not at all. Not at
world at all. Not at all. Not at all.
I've
I've been
world at all. Not at all. Not at all.
I've been in
I've been in places
world at all. Not at all. Not at all.
I've been in places in
I've been in places in the
world at all. Not at all. Not at all.
I've been in places in the country
I've been in places in the country where
a
a whole
a whole family
a whole family of
a whole family of 20
a whole family of 20 lives
a whole family of 20 lives in
a whole family of 20 lives in a
a whole family of 20 lives in a couple
of
of cardboard
a whole family of 20 lives in a couple
of cardboard boxes
of cardboard boxes put
a whole family of 20 lives in a couple
of cardboard boxes put together
of cardboard boxes put together with
string
string and
string and they
string and they take
string and they take turns
string and they take turns sleeping
string and they take turns sleeping in
it
it and
string and they take turns sleeping in
it and digging
it and digging up
string and they take turns sleeping in
it and digging up roots.
Uh,
Uh, they
Uh, they do
Uh, they do not
Uh, they do not live
Uh, they do not live in
Uh, they do not live in your
Uh, they do not live in your world
Uh, they do not live in your world at
all.
So,
So, I
So, I thought,
So, I thought, you
So, I thought, you know,
So, I thought, you know, the
So, I thought, you know, the different
countries
countries and
So, I thought, you know, the different
countries and continents
countries and continents and
So, I thought, you know, the different
countries and continents and about
countries and continents and about where
they're
they're at.
they're at. It
they're at. It gives
they're at. It gives you
they're at. It gives you an
understanding
understanding of
they're at. It gives you an
understanding of why
understanding of why we
they're at. It gives you an
understanding of why we you
understanding of why we you see
they're at. It gives you an
understanding of why we you see to
understanding of why we you see to be
they're at. It gives you an
understanding of why we you see to be um
political
political diplomat,
political diplomat, you
political diplomat, you really
political diplomat, you really have
political diplomat, you really have to
understand
understand these
political diplomat, you really have to
understand these things.
understand these things. The
political diplomat, you really have to
understand these things. The terrible
mistakes
mistakes we
mistakes we make
mistakes we make militarily
mistakes we make militarily and
diplomatically
diplomatically and
mistakes we make militarily and
diplomatically and politically
diplomatically and politically is
mistakes we make militarily and
diplomatically and politically is a
total
total failure
total failure to
total failure to comprehend
total failure to comprehend where
total failure to comprehend where these
other
other people
total failure to comprehend where these
other people are
other people are at.
total failure to comprehend where these
other people are at. They're
other people are at. They're not
anywhere
anywhere at
anywhere at what
anywhere at what you're
anywhere at what you're talking
anywhere at what you're talking about.
That's
That's the
anywhere at what you're talking about.
That's the trouble
That's the trouble with
anywhere at what you're talking about.
That's the trouble with academic
That's the trouble with academic views
of
of things
of things and
of things and politically
of things and politically correct
of things and politically correct things
because
because you
of things and politically correct things
because you live
because you live in
of things and politically correct things
because you live in an
because you live in an air
of things and politically correct things
because you live in an air furry
because you live in an air furry world
that
that you
that you know
that you know people
that you know people don't
that you know people don't live
that you know people don't live there.
Yeah.
Yeah. People
that you know people don't live there.
Yeah. People also
Yeah. People also have
that you know people don't live there.
Yeah. People also have bodies.
Yeah. People also have bodies. They
forget
forget that.
forget that. Anyway,
forget that. Anyway, the
forget that. Anyway, the rancher
forget that. Anyway, the rancher book.
Let's
Let's see.
forget that. Anyway, the rancher book.
Let's see. Do
Let's see. Do we
forget that. Anyway, the rancher book.
Let's see. Do we have
Let's see. Do we have permission
forget that. Anyway, the rancher book.
Let's see. Do we have permission to
Let's see. Do we have permission to do
that?
I'm
I'm familiar
that?
I'm familiar with
I'm familiar with the
that?
I'm familiar with the rancher
I'm familiar with the rancher book.
that?
I'm familiar with the rancher book. I
think
think years
think years ago
think years ago rancher
think years ago rancher we
think years ago rancher we have
permission.
permission. It's
think years ago rancher we have
permission. It's over
permission. It's over 200
think years ago rancher we have
permission. It's over 200 was
permission. It's over 200 was it?
think years ago rancher we have
permission. It's over 200 was it? Thank
god
god it's
god it's over
god it's over 300.
god it's over 300. 350.
god it's over 300. 350. All
god it's over 300. 350. All right.
god it's over 300. 350. All right. It's
in
in the
god it's over 300. 350. All right. It's
in the high
in the high 300.
god it's over 300. 350. All right. It's
in the high 300. So
in the high 300. So you
god it's over 300. 350. All right. It's
in the high 300. So you see
in the high 300. So you see each
god it's over 300. 350. All right. It's
in the high 300. So you see each of
these
these teaching
these teaching methods
these teaching methods is
these teaching methods is appropriate
for
for certain
these teaching methods is appropriate
for certain levels.
for certain levels. We
these teaching methods is appropriate
for certain levels. We said
for certain levels. We said there's
these teaching methods is appropriate
for certain levels. We said there's no
really
really higher
really higher lower
really higher lower levels
really higher lower levels because
you're
you're learning
really higher lower levels because
you're learning tools
you're learning tools and
really higher lower levels because
you're learning tools and these
you're learning tools and these tools
are
are useful
are useful when
are useful when you're
are useful when you're at
are useful when you're at 800
are useful when you're at 800 just
are useful when you're at 800 just like
they're
they're useful
are useful when you're at 800 just like
they're useful when
they're useful when you're
are useful when you're at 800 just like
they're useful when you're at
they're useful when you're at 200.
are useful when you're at 800 just like
they're useful when you're at 200. So
if
if your
if your own
if your own calibrations
if your own calibrations are
if your own calibrations are in
if your own calibrations are in here,
let's
let's say
if your own calibrations are in here,
let's say you
let's say you go
if your own calibrations are in here,
let's say you go to
let's say you go to let's
if your own calibrations are in here,
let's say you go to let's say
let's say you go to let's say your
if your own calibrations are in here,
let's say you go to let's say your life
is
is is
is is horrible
is is horrible and
is is horrible and you
is is horrible and you decide
is is horrible and you decide to
is is horrible and you decide to quit
drinking,
drinking, you
is is horrible and you decide to quit
drinking, you go
drinking, you go to
is is horrible and you decide to quit
drinking, you go to a
drinking, you go to a uh
is is horrible and you decide to quit
drinking, you go to a uh you
drinking, you go to a uh you take
is is horrible and you decide to quit
drinking, you go to a uh you take the
first
first step
first step that
first step that takes
first step that takes you
first step that takes you over
first step that takes you over 200
first step that takes you over 200 right
there.
You
You say
You say 200
You say 200 won't
You say 200 won't take
You say 200 won't take you
You say 200 won't take you all
You say 200 won't take you all the
You say 200 won't take you all the way
to
to enlightenment.
You say 200 won't take you all the way
to enlightenment. Oh
to enlightenment. Oh yeah,
You say 200 won't take you all the way
to enlightenment. Oh yeah, it
to enlightenment. Oh yeah, it will
because
because without
because without courage,
because without courage, you're
because without courage, you're not
going
going to
because without courage, you're not
going to take
going to take any
because without courage, you're not
going to take any of
going to take any of these
because without courage, you're not
going to take any of these other
going to take any of these other steps.
Each
Each one
Each one of
Each one of these
Each one of these is
Each one of these is a
Each one of these is a brick.
Each one of these is a brick. is
Each one of these is a brick. is a
brick.
brick. So
Each one of these is a brick. is a
brick. So none
brick. So none of
Each one of these is a brick. is a
brick. So none of them
brick. So none of them is
Each one of these is a brick. is a
brick. So none of them is really
brick. So none of them is really higher
than
than the
than the other.
than the other. This
than the other. This is
than the other. This is the
than the other. This is the way
than the other. This is the way the
calibrated
calibrated scale
than the other. This is the way the
calibrated scale ca
calibrated scale ca came
than the other. This is the way the
calibrated scale ca came out
calibrated scale ca came out and
than the other. This is the way the
calibrated scale ca came out and I
calibrated scale ca came out and I had
uh
uh it
uh it just
uh it just came
uh it just came out
uh it just came out you
uh it just came out you know
uh it just came out you know by
questioning
questioning and
uh it just came out you know by
questioning and this
questioning and this is
uh it just came out you know by
questioning and this is the
questioning and this is the way
uh it just came out you know by
questioning and this is the way it
questioning and this is the way it came
out.
These
These things
out.
These things are
These things are very
out.
These things are very very
These things are very very necessary
without
without the
without the capacity
without the capacity to
without the capacity to face
without the capacity to face the
without the capacity to face the truth
about
about yourself
without the capacity to face the truth
about yourself uh
about yourself uh you're
without the capacity to face the truth
about yourself uh you're not
about yourself uh you're not going
without the capacity to face the truth
about yourself uh you're not going to
move
move up
move up any
move up any higher.
move up any higher. All
move up any higher. All right.
move up any higher. All right. So,
move up any higher. All right. So, here
we
we have
move up any higher. All right. So, here
we have something
we have something that
move up any higher. All right. So, here
we have something that calibrates
we have something that calibrates in
move up any higher. All right. So, here
we have something that calibrates in the
300s.
300s. And
so,
so, to
300s. And
so, to move
so, to move out
300s. And
so, to move out of
so, to move out of here,
300s. And
so, to move out of here, all
so, to move out of here, all this
300s. And
so, to move out of here, all this stuff
up
up here
up here is
up here is meaningless.
up here is meaningless. Meaningless.
up here is meaningless. Meaningless. I
read
read this
up here is meaningless. Meaningless. I
read this very
read this very area
up here is meaningless. Meaningless. I
read this very area book
read this very area book last
up here is meaningless. Meaningless. I
read this very area book last night.
read this very area book last night. I
just
just skimmed
just skimmed through
just skimmed through it
just skimmed through it in
just skimmed through it in a
just skimmed through it in a hurry
just skimmed through it in a hurry to
see
see what
just skimmed through it in a hurry to
see what I
see what I could
just skimmed through it in a hurry to
see what I could get
see what I could get out
just skimmed through it in a hurry to
see what I could get out of
quantum
quantum mechanics
quantum mechanics and
quantum mechanics and its
quantum mechanics and its application
quantum mechanics and its application to
consciousness.
consciousness. And
quantum mechanics and its application to
consciousness. And there
consciousness. And there wasn't
quantum mechanics and its application to
consciousness. And there wasn't anything
of
of any
of any use
of any use in
of any use in there.
of any use in there. It
of any use in there. It was
of any use in there. It was it
calibrated
calibrated around
of any use in there. It was it
calibrated around 450.
calibrated around 450. Well,
of any use in there. It was it
calibrated around 450. Well, I
calibrated around 450. Well, I know
of any use in there. It was it
calibrated around 450. Well, I know all
that.
that. That's
that. That's just
that. That's just you
that. That's just you know
that. That's just you know uh
intellectualism
intellectualism and
that. That's just you know uh
intellectualism and logic
intellectualism and logic and
that. That's just you know uh
intellectualism and logic and computers
in
in mathematics.
in mathematics. The
in mathematics. The mathematics
in mathematics. The mathematics of
consciousness
consciousness is
in mathematics. The mathematics of
consciousness is one
consciousness is one thing.
in mathematics. The mathematics of
consciousness is one thing. The
consciousness
consciousness is
consciousness is something
consciousness is something totally
different
different uh
consciousness is something totally
different uh to
different uh to which
consciousness is something totally
different uh to which you
different uh to which you cannot
consciousness is something totally
different uh to which you cannot apply
mathematics
mathematics actually.
mathematics actually. But
mathematics actually. But I'm
mathematics actually. But I'm looking
for
for that
mathematics actually. But I'm looking
for that interface
for that interface between
mathematics actually. But I'm looking
for that interface between the
for that interface between the linear
and
and the
and the nonlinear
which
which was
and the nonlinear
which was the
which was the point
and the nonlinear
which was the point of
which was the point of writing
and the nonlinear
which was the point of writing power
versus
versus force.
versus force. And
versus force. And again
versus force. And again it
versus force. And again it in
versus force. And again it in the
conclusion
conclusion of
versus force. And again it in the
conclusion of I
conclusion of I I
versus force. And again it in the
conclusion of I I have
conclusion of I I have a
versus force. And again it in the
conclusion of I I have a little
conclusion of I I have a little um
appendix
appendix at
appendix at the
appendix at the at
appendix at the at the
appendix at the at the end
appendix at the at the end on
appendix at the at the end on um
appendix at the at the end on um quantum
mechanics
mechanics because
appendix at the at the end on um quantum
mechanics because the
mechanics because the quantum
potentiality
potentiality is
potentiality is that
potentiality is that space
potentiality is that space where
potentiality is that space where from
the
the viewpoint
potentiality is that space where from
the viewpoint of
the viewpoint of common
potentiality is that space where from
the viewpoint of common logic
the viewpoint of common logic you
potentiality is that space where from
the viewpoint of common logic you can
see
see that
see that that
see that that which
see that that which is
see that that which is not
see that that which is not to
see that that which is not to which
logic
logic is
see that that which is not to which
logic is not
logic is not applicable
see that that which is not to which
logic is not applicable uh
logic is not applicable uh can
see that that which is not to which
logic is not applicable uh can also
exist
exist because
exist because that
exist because that which
exist because that which is
exist because that which is hardcore
scientism
scientism denies
exist because that which is hardcore
scientism denies anything
scientism denies anything other
exist because that which is hardcore
scientism denies anything other than
scientism denies anything other than a
linear
linear reality
linear reality could
linear reality could exist
linear reality could exist and
linear reality could exist and I
linear reality could exist and I want
linear reality could exist and I want to
show
show that
linear reality could exist and I want to
show that a
show that a contr
contr
contr the
contr the very
contr the very reason
contr the very reason you
contr the very reason you say
contr the very reason you say that
contr the very reason you say that is
because
because of
contr the very reason you say that is
because of that
because of that which
contr the very reason you say that is
because of that which is
because of that which is nonlinear
contr the very reason you say that is
because of that which is nonlinear which
is
is dominating
is dominating your
is dominating your consciousness
is dominating your consciousness and
which
which you're
is dominating your consciousness and
which you're not
which you're not going
is dominating your consciousness and
which you're not going to
which you're not going to find
is dominating your consciousness and
which you're not going to find out
which you're not going to find out with
mathematics
mathematics you
mathematics you only
mathematics you only find
mathematics you only find it
mathematics you only find it out
mathematics you only find it out through
meditation
um
let's
let's see
um
let's see I
let's see I don't
um
let's see I don't know
let's see I don't know if
um
let's see I don't know if I
let's see I don't know if I can
um
let's see I don't know if I can answer
that
that one
that one or
I
I don't
that one or
I don't think
I don't think so.
that one or
I don't think so. Um
the
the the the
the the the method
the the the method of
the the the method of kinesiology
the the the method of kinesiology as
the the the method of kinesiology as I
said
said we're
the the the method of kinesiology as I
said we're not
said we're not kinesiologists.
It's
It's only
It's only um
It's only um a
It's only um a technique
It's only um a technique that
It's only um a technique that we
It's only um a technique that we use
It's only um a technique that we use for
the
the sake
It's only um a technique that we use for
the sake of
the sake of spiritual
It's only um a technique that we use for
the sake of spiritual research
the sake of spiritual research uh
It's only um a technique that we use for
the sake of spiritual research uh and
for
for comprehending
for comprehending the
for comprehending the nature
for comprehending the nature of
for comprehending the nature of life
for comprehending the nature of life and
uh
illuminating
illuminating things
illuminating things that
illuminating things that for
illuminating things that for which
illuminating things that for which there
is
is no
illuminating things that for which there
is no other
is no other tool
illuminating things that for which there
is no other tool possible.
uh
uh and
uh and we
uh and we do
uh and we do somewhat
uh and we do somewhat review
uh and we do somewhat review it
uh and we do somewhat review it each
time
time each
uh and we do somewhat review it each
time each lecture.
time each lecture. The
uh and we do somewhat review it each
time each lecture. The two
time each lecture. The two people
uh and we do somewhat review it each
time each lecture. The two people have
to
to be
to be over
to be over 200.
to be over 200. The
to be over 200. The uh
to be over 200. The uh purpose
to be over 200. The uh purpose of
to be over 200. The uh purpose of the
question
question has
to be over 200. The uh purpose of the
question has to
question has to be
to be over 200. The uh purpose of the
question has to be integrous.
question has to be integrous. You
to be over 200. The uh purpose of the
question has to be integrous. You make
it
it in
it in the
it in the form
it in the form of
it in the form of a
it in the form of a statement
it in the form of a statement and
it in the form of a statement and before
you
you do
it in the form of a statement and before
you do it
you do it you
it in the form of a statement and before
you do it you ask
you do it you ask if
it in the form of a statement and before
you do it you ask if you
you do it you ask if you have
it in the form of a statement and before
you do it you ask if you have permission
to
to do
to do it.
to do it. You
to do it. You say
to do it. You say I
to do it. You say I have
to do it. You say I have permission
to do it. You say I have permission to
do
do this
to do it. You say I have permission to
do this and
do this and then
to do it. You say I have permission to
do this and then the
do this and then the person
to do it. You say I have permission to
do this and then the person resists
and
and not
and not not
and not not infrequently
and not not infrequently you
and not not infrequently you get
and not not infrequently you get a
and not not infrequently you get a no.
You
You know
and not not infrequently you get a no.
You know we
You know we got
and not not infrequently you get a no.
You know we got a
You know we got a no
and not not infrequently you get a no.
You know we got a no this
You know we got a no this morning.
and not not infrequently you get a no.
You know we got a no this morning. We'll
get
get a
get a no.
get a no. If
get a no. If you're
get a no. If you're curious
get a no. If you're curious and
get a no. If you're curious and you've
got
got time,
get a no. If you're curious and you've
got time, you
got time, you can
get a no. If you're curious and you've
got time, you can research
got time, you can research the
get a no. If you're curious and you've
got time, you can research the reason
for
for the
for the no.
for the no. A
for the no. A lot
for the no. A lot of
for the no. A lot of times
for the no. A lot of times we're
for the no. A lot of times we're in
for the no. A lot of times we're in a
hurry.
hurry. We
for the no. A lot of times we're in a
hurry. We just
hurry. We just want
for the no. A lot of times we're in a
hurry. We just want a
hurry. We just want a yes
for the no. A lot of times we're in a
hurry. We just want a yes or
hurry. We just want a yes or no
for the no. A lot of times we're in a
hurry. We just want a yes or no for,
let's
let's say,
let's say, should
let's say, should we
let's say, should we turn
let's say, should we turn left
let's say, should we turn left or
let's say, should we turn left or right?
You
You know,
let's say, should we turn left or right?
You know, I
You know, I don't
let's say, should we turn left or right?
You know, I don't need
You know, I don't need to
let's say, should we turn left or right?
You know, I don't need to know
You know, I don't need to know the
reason
cuz
cuz this
reason
cuz this one
cuz this one leads
reason
cuz this one leads to
cuz this one leads to the
reason
cuz this one leads to the pits.
cuz this one leads to the pits. I
reason
cuz this one leads to the pits. I don't
need
need to
need to know
need to know that.
need to know that. I
need to know that. I just
need to know that. I just say,
need to know that. I just say, should
make
make a
need to know that. I just say, should
make a left
make a left turn.
need to know that. I just say, should
make a left turn. Yes,
make a left turn. Yes, I
need to know that. I just say, should
make a left turn. Yes, I make
make a left turn. Yes, I make a
need to know that. I just say, should
make a left turn. Yes, I make a left
turn.
turn. So,
turn. So, but
turn. So, but if
turn. So, but if you
turn. So, but if you have
turn. So, but if you have time,
turn. So, but if you have time, you
turn. So, but if you have time, you can
research
research the
turn. So, but if you have time, you can
research the reason
research the reason for
turn. So, but if you have time, you can
research the reason for the
research the reason for the no.
Uh,
Uh, sometimes
Uh, sometimes couples
Uh, sometimes couples are
Uh, sometimes couples are not
Uh, sometimes couples are not good
Uh, sometimes couples are not good with
each
each other.
Uh, sometimes couples are not good with
each other. I
each other. I don't
Uh, sometimes couples are not good with
each other. I don't know
each other. I don't know why
Uh, sometimes couples are not good with
each other. I don't know why marital
couples,
couples, we
couples, we just
couples, we just haven't
couples, we just haven't hadn't
couples, we just haven't hadn't had
couples, we just haven't hadn't had time
to
to research
couples, we just haven't hadn't had time
to research why
to research why that
couples, we just haven't hadn't had time
to research why that is.
to research why that is. Uh
couples, we just haven't hadn't had time
to research why that is. Uh sometimes
to research why that is. Uh sometimes a
couple
couple have
couple have to
couple have to find
couple have to find a
couple have to find a third
couple have to find a third party
couple have to find a third party and
with
with them
couple have to find a third party and
with them they're
with them they're fine.
couple have to find a third party and
with them they're fine. There's
with them they're fine. There's methods
of
of doing
of doing it
of doing it by
of doing it by yourself.
Um
Um let's
of doing it by yourself.
Um let's see.
Um let's see. Uh
of doing it by yourself.
Um let's see. Uh doing
Um let's see. Uh doing it
of doing it by yourself.
Um let's see. Uh doing it by
Um let's see. Uh doing it by yourself
of doing it by yourself.
Um let's see. Uh doing it by yourself is
is
is uh
is uh is
is uh is an
is uh is an okay
is uh is an okay we
is uh is an okay we have
is uh is an okay we have permission
is uh is an okay we have permission to
ask
ask this
is uh is an okay we have permission to
ask this is
ask this is an
is uh is an okay we have permission to
ask this is an okay
ask this is an okay way
is uh is an okay we have permission to
ask this is an okay way of
ask this is an okay way of doing
is uh is an okay we have permission to
ask this is an okay way of doing it.
Resist
Resist and
Resist and it
Resist and it is
Resist and it is reasonably
Resist and it is reasonably reliable.
If
If it's
Resist and it is reasonably reliable.
If it's an
If it's an important
Resist and it is reasonably reliable.
If it's an important question,
If it's an important question, I
Resist and it is reasonably reliable.
If it's an important question, I would
double
double check
double check it
double check it with
double check it with kinesiology
double check it with kinesiology resist.
Okay.
Okay. Okay.
double check it with kinesiology resist.
Okay. Okay. So,
Okay. Okay. So, everybody
double check it with kinesiology resist.
Okay. Okay. So, everybody knows
Okay. Okay. So, everybody knows this
method
method here,
method here, the
method here, the so-called
method here, the so-called thumb
method here, the so-called thumb and
middle
middle finger
method here, the so-called thumb and
middle finger in
middle finger in which
method here, the so-called thumb and
middle finger in which you
middle finger in which you hold
method here, the so-called thumb and
middle finger in which you hold it
middle finger in which you hold it as
tight
tight as
tight as you
tight as you can.
tight as you can. Now,
tight as you can. Now, you
tight as you can. Now, you picture
um
um Jesus
tight as you can. Now, you picture
um Jesus Christ.
You
You try
You try to
You try to break
You try to break you
You try to break you try
You try to break you try you
You try to break you try you see
You try to break you try you see with
this
this if
You try to break you try you see with
this if you
this if you can
You try to break you try you see with
this if you can break
this if you can break it.
You try to break you try you see with
this if you can break it. Now,
this if you can break it. Now, I'm
You try to break you try you see with
this if you can break it. Now, I'm going
to
to hold
to hold in
to hold in in
to hold in in mind
to hold in in mind uh
to hold in in mind uh somebody
to hold in in mind uh somebody who's
been
been on
to hold in in mind uh somebody who's
been on TV
been on TV a
to hold in in mind uh somebody who's
been on TV a lot
been on TV a lot lately.
to hold in in mind uh somebody who's
been on TV a lot lately. I've
been on TV a lot lately. I've been
to hold in in mind uh somebody who's
been on TV a lot lately. I've been loud.
I
I don't
I don't know.
I don't know. Bin
I don't know. Bin Lad
I don't know. Bin Lad makes
I don't know. Bin Lad makes you
I don't know. Bin Lad makes you go
I don't know. Bin Lad makes you go weak.
I
I know
I don't know. Bin Lad makes you go weak.
I know why.
I know why. Anyway,
I don't know. Bin Lad makes you go weak.
I know why. Anyway, uh
I know why. Anyway, uh so
I don't know. Bin Lad makes you go weak.
I know why. Anyway, uh so that's
I know why. Anyway, uh so that's a
technique
technique you
technique you can
technique you can use
technique you can use by
technique you can use by yourself.
Um
and
and then
and then we
and then we found
and then we found that
and then we found that 10%
and then we found that 10% of
and then we found that 10% of the
general
general population
and then we found that 10% of the
general population can't
general population can't do
and then we found that 10% of the
general population can't do it.
general population can't do it. Is
and then we found that 10% of the
general population can't do it. Is that
right?
right? Let's
right? Let's see.
right? Let's see. 10%
right? Let's see. 10% of
right? Let's see. 10% of u
right? Let's see. 10% of u people
right? Let's see. 10% of u people who
were
were entitled
right? Let's see. 10% of u people who
were entitled to
were entitled to do
right? Let's see. 10% of u people who
were entitled to do it
were entitled to do it are
right? Let's see. 10% of u people who
were entitled to do it are unable
were entitled to do it are unable to
right? Let's see. 10% of u people who
were entitled to do it are unable to do
it.
it. Resist.
it. Resist. Huh.
it. Resist. Huh. And
it. Resist. Huh. And that's
it. Resist. Huh. And that's due
it. Resist. Huh. And that's due to
it. Resist. Huh. And that's due to some
stranges
stranges about
it. Resist. Huh. And that's due to some
stranges about their
stranges about their chi
it. Resist. Huh. And that's due to some
stranges about their chi energy
stranges about their chi energy resist.
And
And that
And that chi
And that chi energy
And that chi energy has
And that chi energy has to
And that chi energy has to do
And that chi energy has to do with
karma.
karma. Has
And that chi energy has to do with
karma. Has to
karma. Has to do
And that chi energy has to do with
karma. Has to do something
karma. Has to do something with
And that chi energy has to do with
karma. Has to do something with karma.
So
So karmically,
So karmically, we
So karmically, we don't
So karmically, we don't have
So karmically, we don't have time
So karmically, we don't have time to
research
research it
So karmically, we don't have time to
research it today,
research it today, but
So karmically, we don't have time to
research it today, but karmically
some
some people
some people have
some people have some
some people have some problem
some people have some problem with
some people have some problem with their
chi
chi energy.
Uh
Uh that
Uh that about
Uh that about 10%
Uh that about 10% of
Uh that about 10% of those
Uh that about 10% of those who
Uh that about 10% of those who are
entitled
entitled to
Uh that about 10% of those who are
entitled to do
entitled to do kinesiology
Uh that about 10% of those who are
entitled to do kinesiology are
entitled to do kinesiology are unable
Uh that about 10% of those who are
entitled to do kinesiology are unable to
do
do it.
do it. So
within
within those
do it. So
within those limitations.
within those limitations. Um
do it. So
within those limitations. Um the
within those limitations. Um the other
thing
thing um
thing um about
thing um about spirituality
thing um about spirituality is
thing um about spirituality is that
thing um about spirituality is that you
want
want to
thing um about spirituality is that you
want to know
want to know specific
thing um about spirituality is that you
want to know specific things
want to know specific things about
things
things that
things that are
things that are very
things that are very applicable
things that are very applicable in
things that are very applicable in a
very
very wide
things that are very applicable in a
very wide variety
very wide variety of
things that are very applicable in a
very wide variety of uh
very wide variety of uh expressions.
And
And sometimes
And sometimes people
And sometimes people use
And sometimes people use it
And sometimes people use it to
And sometimes people use it to to
And sometimes people use it to to ask
questions
questions that
And sometimes people use it to to ask
questions that are
questions that are really
And sometimes people use it to to ask
questions that are really sort
questions that are really sort of
irrelevant.
irrelevant. You
irrelevant. You know
irrelevant. You know what
irrelevant. You know what I
irrelevant. You know what I mean?
We
We were
irrelevant. You know what I mean?
We were going
We were going to
irrelevant. You know what I mean?
We were going to use
We were going to use it
irrelevant. You know what I mean?
We were going to use it to
We were going to use it to find
irrelevant. You know what I mean?
We were going to use it to find Kitty
yesterday,
yesterday, but
yesterday, but Kitty
yesterday, but Kitty showed
yesterday, but Kitty showed up.
I
I asked
yesterday, but Kitty showed up.
I asked the
I asked the Holy
yesterday, but Kitty showed up.
I asked the Holy Spirit
I asked the Holy Spirit to
yesterday, but Kitty showed up.
I asked the Holy Spirit to find
I asked the Holy Spirit to find Kitty.
And
And sure
And sure enough,
And sure enough, Lou
And sure enough, Lou popped
And sure enough, Lou popped up
And sure enough, Lou popped up and
And sure enough, Lou popped up and there
was
was Kitty.
And sure enough, Lou popped up and there
was Kitty. He
was Kitty. He found
And sure enough, Lou popped up and there
was Kitty. He found Kitty
was Kitty. He found Kitty and
And sure enough, Lou popped up and there
was Kitty. He found Kitty and Susan
decid
decid realized
decid realized where
decid realized where it
decid realized where it was.
decid realized where it was. She
decid realized where it was. She says,
"Oh,
"Oh, I
decid realized where it was. She says,
"Oh, I know
"Oh, I know where
decid realized where it was. She says,
"Oh, I know where it
"Oh, I know where it is.
decid realized where it was. She says,
"Oh, I know where it is. Be
"Oh, I know where it is. Be signed
decid realized where it was. She says,
"Oh, I know where it is. Be signed so
and
and so's
and so's house."
and so's house." And
and so's house." And Lou
and so's house." And Lou went
and so's house." And Lou went over
there.
there. Sure
and so's house." And Lou went over
there. Sure enough,
there. Sure enough, there
and so's house." And Lou went over
there. Sure enough, there it
there. Sure enough, there it was.
And
And then
And then also
And then also we
And then also we got
And then also we got a
And then also we got a present
And then also we got a present of
And then also we got a present of a
little
little of
And then also we got a present of a
little of a
little of a bunch
And then also we got a present of a
little of a bunch of
little of a bunch of books
And then also we got a present of a
little of a bunch of books on
little of a bunch of books on kitties.
So
So somehow
So somehow kittiness,
So somehow kittiness, you
So somehow kittiness, you know,
So somehow kittiness, you know, just
sort
sort of
So somehow kittiness, you know, just
sort of that
sort of that energy
So somehow kittiness, you know, just
sort of that energy field
sort of that energy field coales
discovered
discovered kitty
discovered kitty and
discovered kitty and at
discovered kitty and at the
discovered kitty and at the same
discovered kitty and at the same time
somebody
somebody said
discovered kitty and at the same time
somebody said here's
somebody said here's a
discovered kitty and at the same time
somebody said here's a present
somebody said here's a present for
discovered kitty and at the same time
somebody said here's a present for you.
I
I opened
I opened it.
I opened it. It
I opened it. It was
I opened it. It was four
I opened it. It was four little
I opened it. It was four little books
I opened it. It was four little books on
kitties.
It's
It's just
It's just sort
It's just sort of
It's just sort of funny.
Uh
Uh so
It's just sort of funny.
Uh so that's
Uh so that's the
It's just sort of funny.
Uh so that's the one
Uh so that's the one you
It's just sort of funny.
Uh so that's the one you can
Uh so that's the one you can use
It's just sort of funny.
Uh so that's the one you can use from
yourself.
Now
Now the
yourself.
Now the question
Now the question about
yourself.
Now the question about President
Now the question about President Bush
comes
comes up.
comes up. I
comes up. I I
comes up. I I do
comes up. I I do a
comes up. I I do a lot
comes up. I I do a lot of
comes up. I I do a lot of radio
comes up. I I do a lot of radio programs
and
and um
comes up. I I do a lot of radio programs
and um we're
and um we're going
comes up. I I do a lot of radio programs
and um we're going to
and um we're going to do
comes up. I I do a lot of radio programs
and um we're going to do one
and um we're going to do one in
comes up. I I do a lot of radio programs
and um we're going to do one in November
in
in Scottdale.
in Scottdale. Let's
in Scottdale. Let's see.
in Scottdale. Let's see. We
in Scottdale. Let's see. We got
in Scottdale. Let's see. We got one
in Scottdale. Let's see. We got one in
October
October we're
in Scottdale. Let's see. We got one in
October we're going
October we're going to
in Scottdale. Let's see. We got one in
October we're going to do
October we're going to do at
in Scottdale. Let's see. We got one in
October we're going to do at the
October we're going to do at the Church
of
of Agape
of Agape which
of Agape which is
of Agape which is in
of Agape which is in LA.
of Agape which is in LA. Then
of Agape which is in LA. Then November
we're
we're going
of Agape which is in LA. Then November
we're going to
we're going to do
of Agape which is in LA. Then November
we're going to do one
we're going to do one in
of Agape which is in LA. Then November
we're going to do one in Scottdale
with
with uh
with uh Mishka
with uh Mishka Productions
with uh Mishka Productions which
with uh Mishka Productions which is
with uh Mishka Productions which is uh
associated
associated with
with uh Mishka Productions which is uh
associated with Hey
associated with Hey Hay
with uh Mishka Productions which is uh
associated with Hey Hay House.
Um
Um and
Um and I
Um and I do
Um and I do a
Um and I do a number
Um and I do a number of
Um and I do a number of u
Um and I do a number of u radio
Um and I do a number of u radio programs
and
and a
Um and I do a number of u radio programs
and a lot
and a lot of
Um and I do a number of u radio programs
and a lot of them
and a lot of them are
Um and I do a number of u radio programs
and a lot of them are fun.
and a lot of them are fun. Now,
Um and I do a number of u radio programs
and a lot of them are fun. Now, these
interviewers
interviewers are
interviewers are fun
interviewers are fun people
interviewers are fun people and
interviewers are fun people and they
have
have a
interviewers are fun people and they
have a comical
have a comical way
interviewers are fun people and they
have a comical way of
have a comical way of expressing
interviewers are fun people and they
have a comical way of expressing things.
So,
So, a
So, a week
So, a week or
So, a week or two
So, a week or two ago,
So, a week or two ago, we
So, a week or two ago, we did
So, a week or two ago, we did a
So, a week or two ago, we did a radio
and
and a
So, a week or two ago, we did a radio
and a TV
and a TV one
So, a week or two ago, we did a radio
and a TV one right
and a TV one right after
So, a week or two ago, we did a radio
and a TV one right after that.
and a TV one right after that. And
So, a week or two ago, we did a radio
and a TV one right after that. And um
anyway,
anyway, we
anyway, we had
anyway, we had a
anyway, we had a good
anyway, we had a good time
anyway, we had a good time with
anyway, we had a good time with it.
anyway, we had a good time with it. But
this
this this
anyway, we had a good time with it. But
this this question
this this question about
anyway, we had a good time with it. But
this this question about President
this this question about President Bush
comes
comes up
comes up all
comes up all the
comes up all the time.
comes up all the time. And
comes up all the time. And um
comes up all the time. And um you
comes up all the time. And um you can
tell
tell the
comes up all the time. And um you can
tell the the
tell the the political
comes up all the time. And um you can
tell the the political slant
tell the the political slant of
comes up all the time. And um you can
tell the the political slant of the
tell the the political slant of the uh
you
you know
you know the
you know the radio
you know the radio interviewer
you know the radio interviewer whoever
it
it is
you know the radio interviewer whoever
it is you
it is you know
you know the radio interviewer whoever
it is you know um
it is you know um you
you know the radio interviewer whoever
it is you know um you know
it is you know um you know it's
you know the radio interviewer whoever
it is you know um you know it's sort
it is you know um you know it's sort of
like
like tell
like tell us
like tell us why
like tell us why President
like tell us why President Bush
like tell us why President Bush is
like tell us why President Bush is wrong
you
you know
so
you
you shouldn't
so
you shouldn't ask
you shouldn't ask a
so
you shouldn't ask a question
you shouldn't ask a question with
kinesiology
kinesiology unless
kinesiology unless you're
kinesiology unless you're prepared
kinesiology unless you're prepared for
the
the answer.
kinesiology unless you're prepared for
the answer. Prepared
the answer. Prepared for
kinesiology unless you're prepared for
the answer. Prepared for the
the answer. Prepared for the answer.
Sometimes
Sometimes I
Sometimes I get
Sometimes I get letters
Sometimes I get letters from
Sometimes I get letters from people,
what
what do
Sometimes I get letters from people,
what do you
what do you think
Sometimes I get letters from people,
what do you think about
what do you think about guru
Sometimes I get letters from people,
what do you think about guru Baba
what do you think about guru Baba so
Sometimes I get letters from people,
what do you think about guru Baba so and
so?
so? Well,
so? Well, I
so? Well, I know
so? Well, I know from
so? Well, I know from just
so? Well, I know from just looking
so? Well, I know from just looking at
him
him and
so? Well, I know from just looking at
him and picking
him and picking up
so? Well, I know from just looking at
him and picking up his
him and picking up his energy,
so? Well, I know from just looking at
him and picking up his energy, he's
about
about 140.
about 140. So,
about 140. So, so
about 140. So, so am
about 140. So, so am I
about 140. So, so am I am
about 140. So, so am I am I
about 140. So, so am I am I going
about 140. So, so am I am I going to
answer
answer this
about 140. So, so am I am I going to
answer this and
answer this and upset
about 140. So, so am I am I going to
answer this and upset this
answer this and upset this person
about 140. So, so am I am I going to
answer this and upset this person who's
going
going to
going to lie
going to lie awake
going to lie awake and
going to lie awake and you
going to lie awake and you think
going to lie awake and you think he's
given
given everything
going to lie awake and you think he's
given everything away
given everything away for
going to lie awake and you think he's
given everything away for Boba
given everything away for Boba so
going to lie awake and you think he's
given everything away for Boba so and
given everything away for Boba so and so
and
and the the
and the the guy
and the the guy calibrates
and the the guy calibrates at
and the the guy calibrates at 140
or
or what
and the the guy calibrates at 140
or what should
or what should I
and the the guy calibrates at 140
or what should I do?
or what should I do? So,
as
as far
as far as
as far as President
as far as President Bush,
as far as President Bush, let's
as far as President Bush, let's say
as far as President Bush, let's say we
said
said that
as far as President Bush, let's say we
said that the
said that the pre
as far as President Bush, let's say we
said that the pre the
said that the pre the the
as far as President Bush, let's say we
said that the pre the the office
said that the pre the the office of
as far as President Bush, let's say we
said that the pre the the office of the
presidency
presidency runs
presidency runs around
presidency runs around 450.
Uh
Uh Roosevelt
presidency runs around 450.
Uh Roosevelt was
Uh Roosevelt was like
presidency runs around 450.
Uh Roosevelt was like 499.
Um
Um to
Um to run
Um to run a
Um to run a go
Um to run a go to
Um to run a go to run
Um to run a go to run a
Um to run a go to run a government,
Um to run a go to run a government, you
should
should really
Um to run a go to run a government, you
should really be
should really be in
Um to run a go to run a government, you
should really be in about
should really be in about the
Um to run a go to run a government, you
should really be in about the mid
should really be in about the mid 400s.
If
If you
If you get
If you get too
If you get too high,
If you get too high, you're
If you get too high, you're going
If you get too high, you're going to
Einstein's
Einstein's 499
If you get too high, you're going to
Einstein's 499 and
Einstein's 499 and Einstein
If you get too high, you're going to
Einstein's 499 and Einstein wouldn't
Einstein's 499 and Einstein wouldn't be
too
too good
too good at
too good at running
too good at running a
too good at running a government,
too good at running a government, you
know.
know. So,
too good at running a government, you
know. So, you
know. So, you need
too good at running a government, you
know. So, you need to
know. So, you need to be
too good at running a government, you
know. So, you need to be around
know. So, you need to be around 450.
That's
That's where
That's where Bush
That's where Bush is
That's where Bush is around
That's where Bush is around 450
That's where Bush is around 450 460.
That
That is
That's where Bush is around 450 460.
That is capable.
That is capable. That's
That's where Bush is around 450 460.
That is capable. That's logic.
That is capable. That's logic. That's
reason.
Uh
it's
it's sane.
it's sane. It
it's sane. It uh
it's sane. It uh is
it's sane. It uh is geared
it's sane. It uh is geared to
it's sane. It uh is geared to this
world.
world. It's
it's sane. It uh is geared to this
world. It's not
world. It's not off
it's sane. It uh is geared to this
world. It's not off in
world. It's not off in La La Land,
nor
nor is
nor is it
nor is it into
nor is it into uh
nor is it into uh the
nor is it into uh the spleen
nor is it into uh the spleen or
nor is it into uh the spleen or even
personal
personal ambition,
nor is it into uh the spleen or even
personal ambition, which
personal ambition, which would
nor is it into uh the spleen or even
personal ambition, which would be
personal ambition, which would be the
solar
solar plexus.
solar plexus. No,
solar plexus. No, it's
solar plexus. No, it's an
solar plexus. No, it's an it's
solar plexus. No, it's an it's integris.
Don't
Don't forget
solar plexus. No, it's an it's integris.
Don't forget that
Don't forget that which
solar plexus. No, it's an it's integris.
Don't forget that which is
Don't forget that which is over
solar plexus. No, it's an it's integris.
Don't forget that which is over 200.
It's
It's integris.
It's integris. So,
It's integris. So, here's
It's integris. So, here's where
It's integris. So, here's where we
It's integris. So, here's where we would
want
want the
It's integris. So, here's where we would
want the presidents
want the presidents to
It's integris. So, here's where we would
want the presidents to be
want the presidents to be around
It's integris. So, here's where we would
want the presidents to be around here.
If
If he
If he gets
If he gets too
If he gets too much
If he gets too much up
If he gets too much up here,
If he gets too much up here, he's
If he gets too much up here, he's not
going
going to
If he gets too much up here, he's not
going to be
going to be useful
If he gets too much up here, he's not
going to be useful anymore.
going to be useful anymore. He's
If he gets too much up here, he's not
going to be useful anymore. He's going
to
to be
to be like
to be like the
to be like the pope,
Mother
Mother Teresa.
to be like the pope,
Mother Teresa. You
Mother Teresa. You can't
to be like the pope,
Mother Teresa. You can't have
Mother Teresa. You can't have Mother
Teresa
Teresa running
Teresa running about
Teresa running about government.
Teresa running about government. You
know what
know what I'm
Teresa running about government. You
know what I'm saying?
know what I'm saying? You
Teresa running about government. You
know what I'm saying? You got
know what I'm saying? You got to
Teresa running about government. You
know what I'm saying? You got to be
know what I'm saying? You got to be with
this
this world
this world and
this world and its
this world and its political
this world and its political realities.
So,
So, to
this world and its political realities.
So, to be
So, to be appropriate,
this world and its political realities.
So, to be appropriate, you
So, to be appropriate, you have
this world and its political realities.
So, to be appropriate, you have to
So, to be appropriate, you have to be
appropriate
appropriate to
appropriate to where
appropriate to where you
appropriate to where you are.
appropriate to where you are. We're
appropriate
appropriate to
appropriate to where you are. We're
appropriate to where
appropriate to where you
appropriate to where you are. We're
appropriate to where you are.
appropriate to where you are. So
appropriate to where you are. We're
appropriate to where you are. So that's
why
why one
why one number
why one number is
why one number is not
why one number is not better
why one number is not better than
another
another number.
I
I remember
I remember going
I remember going into
I remember going into a
I remember going into a boxing
I remember going into a boxing ring
I remember going into a boxing ring one
time
time in
I remember going into a boxing ring one
time in 1945
time in 1945 or
I remember going into a boxing ring one
time in 1945 or whenever
time in 1945 or whenever it
I remember going into a boxing ring one
time in 1945 or whenever it was.
time in 1945 or whenever it was. I
I remember going into a boxing ring one
time in 1945 or whenever it was. I went
aboard
aboard this
aboard this ship
aboard this ship in
aboard this ship in the
aboard this ship in the mind
aboard this ship in the mind sweeper
hazardous
hazardous duty
aboard this ship in the mind sweeper
hazardous duty in
hazardous duty in the
aboard this ship in the mind sweeper
hazardous duty in the South
hazardous duty in the South Pacific
aboard this ship in the mind sweeper
hazardous duty in the South Pacific and
a
a young
a young guy
a young guy who's
a young guy who's still
a young guy who's still a
a young guy who's still a friend
a young guy who's still a friend of
mine,
mine, Jim
a young guy who's still a friend of
mine, Jim Jimmy
mine, Jim Jimmy Sanders.
a young guy who's still a friend of
mine, Jim Jimmy Sanders. Uh
mine, Jim Jimmy Sanders. Uh anyway,
there
there was
there was only
there was only 18
there was only 18 of
there was only 18 of us
there was only 18 of us on
there was only 18 of us on this
there was only 18 of us on this crew,
you
you know,
there was only 18 of us on this crew,
you know, mind
you know, mind sweeper.
there was only 18 of us on this crew,
you know, mind sweeper. Anyway,
you know, mind sweeper. Anyway, I
there was only 18 of us on this crew,
you know, mind sweeper. Anyway, I come
ashore
ashore and
ashore and these
ashore and these guys
ashore and these guys had
ashore and these guys had got
ashore and these guys had got tattoos,
earrings,
earrings, and
ashore and these guys had got tattoos,
earrings, and stuff.
earrings, and stuff. And
ashore and these guys had got tattoos,
earrings, and stuff. And I
earrings, and stuff. And I mean,
ashore and these guys had got tattoos,
earrings, and stuff. And I mean, they're
grizzly
grizzly looking
grizzly looking guys.
grizzly looking guys. They've
grizzly looking guys. They've been
grizzly looking guys. They've been out
of
of sea
grizzly looking guys. They've been out
of sea for
of sea for a
grizzly looking guys. They've been out
of sea for a while.
of sea for a while. So,
grizzly looking guys. They've been out
of sea for a while. So, this
of sea for a while. So, this guy
grizzly looking guys. They've been out
of sea for a while. So, this guy says,
"Uh,
"Uh, hey,
"Uh, hey, shorty."
"Uh, hey, shorty." That
"Uh, hey, shorty." That was
"Uh, hey, shorty." That was my
"Uh, hey, shorty." That was my name,
henceforth
henceforth Shorty
and
and or
and or four
and or four eyes.
and or four eyes. Anyway,
and or four eyes. Anyway, I
and or four eyes. Anyway, I took
and or four eyes. Anyway, I took my
glasses
glasses off.
and or four eyes. Anyway, I took my
glasses off. Shorty
glasses off. Shorty says,
and or four eyes. Anyway, I took my
glasses off. Shorty says, "Uh,
glasses off. Shorty says, "Uh, you
and or four eyes. Anyway, I took my
glasses off. Shorty says, "Uh, you know
how
how to
how to box?"
how to box?" I
how to box?" I says,
how to box?" I says, "Well,
how to box?" I says, "Well, I
how to box?" I says, "Well, I had
how to box?" I says, "Well, I had uh
lessons
lessons with
how to box?" I says, "Well, I had uh
lessons with u
lessons with u Richie
how to box?" I says, "Well, I had uh
lessons with u Richie Mitchell,
lessons with u Richie Mitchell, who
how to box?" I says, "Well, I had uh
lessons with u Richie Mitchell, who was
the
the former
the former middleweight
the former middleweight champion
the former middleweight champion of
the former middleweight champion of the
world
world in
the former middleweight champion of the
world in Milwaukee.
world in Milwaukee. As
the former middleweight champion of the
world in Milwaukee. As a
world in Milwaukee. As a kid,
the former middleweight champion of the
world in Milwaukee. As a kid, I
world in Milwaukee. As a kid, I was
always
always getting
always getting beat
always getting beat up.
always getting beat up. So,
always getting beat up. So, my
grandfather
grandfather took
always getting beat up. So, my
grandfather took me
grandfather took me to
always getting beat up. So, my
grandfather took me to Richie
grandfather took me to Richie Mitchell's
gym
gym and
gym and said,
gym and said, "Teach
gym and said, "Teach them
gym and said, "Teach them how
gym and said, "Teach them how to
gym and said, "Teach them how to fight."
You
You know,
gym and said, "Teach them how to fight."
You know, I
I
I was
I was never
I was never interested
I was never interested in
I was never interested in fighting
I was never interested in fighting and
all
all this
I was never interested in fighting and
all this gruesome
all this gruesome wrestling
I was never interested in fighting and
all this gruesome wrestling crap
all this gruesome wrestling crap that
kids
kids did.
kids did. I
kids did. I mean,
kids did. I mean, I
kids did. I mean, I thought
kids did. I mean, I thought kids
kids did. I mean, I thought kids were
disgusting
disgusting when
kids did. I mean, I thought kids were
disgusting when I
disgusting when I was
kids did. I mean, I thought kids were
disgusting when I was a
disgusting when I was a kid.
kids did. I mean, I thought kids were
disgusting when I was a kid. And
disgusting when I was a kid. And um
kids did. I mean, I thought kids were
disgusting when I was a kid. And um I
was
was picking
was picking their
was picking their nose
was picking their nose and
was picking their nose and they
was picking their nose and they wanted
to
to stick
was picking their nose and they wanted
to stick their
to stick their gooey
was picking their nose and they wanted
to stick their gooey fingers
to stick their gooey fingers in
was picking their nose and they wanted
to stick their gooey fingers in your
to stick their gooey fingers in your eye
as
as they
as they wrestle
as they wrestle you
as they wrestle you and
as they wrestle you and they
as they wrestle you and they they
as they wrestle you and they they were
sweaty.
sweaty. Oh
as they wrestle you and they they were
sweaty. Oh my
sweaty. Oh my god.
as they wrestle you and they they were
sweaty. Oh my god. Anyway,
sweaty. Oh my god. Anyway, these
horrible
horrible kids.
horrible kids. So
horrible kids. So he
horrible kids. So he says,
horrible kids. So he says, "You
horrible kids. So he says, "You got
horrible kids. So he says, "You got to
teach
teach him
horrible kids. So he says, "You got to
teach him how
teach him how to
horrible kids. So he says, "You got to
teach him how to box."
teach him how to box." So
horrible kids. So he says, "You got to
teach him how to box." So I
teach him how to box." So I went
horrible kids. So he says, "You got to
teach him how to box." So I went to
Richie
Richie Mitchell
Richie Mitchell and
Richie Mitchell and I
Richie Mitchell and I was
Richie Mitchell and I was a
Richie Mitchell and I was a a
Richie Mitchell and I was a a mosquito
weight.
weight. Flyweight
Richie Mitchell and I was a a mosquito
weight. Flyweight was
weight. Flyweight was the
Richie Mitchell and I was a a mosquito
weight. Flyweight was the smallest
weight. Flyweight was the smallest I
was
was mosquito
was mosquito weight.
was mosquito weight. So
was mosquito weight. So I
was mosquito weight. So I learned
was mosquito weight. So I learned how
was mosquito weight. So I learned how to
box
box and
was mosquito weight. So I learned how to
box and um
box and um after
was mosquito weight. So I learned how to
box and um after I
box and um after I learned
was mosquito weight. So I learned how to
box and um after I learned how
box and um after I learned how to
was mosquito weight. So I learned how to
box and um after I learned how to box
box and um after I learned how to box I
I
I was
I was in
I was in you
I was in you know
I was in you know we
I was in you know we had
I was in you know we had choir
I was in you know we had choir practice
two
two nights
I was in you know we had choir practice
two nights a
two nights a week
I was in you know we had choir practice
two nights a week I
two nights a week I was
I was in you know we had choir practice
two nights a week I was in
two nights a week I was in the
I was in you know we had choir practice
two nights a week I was in the choir.
two nights a week I was in the choir. I
was
was an
was an acolyte
was an acolyte and
was an acolyte and I
was an acolyte and I and
was an acolyte and I and I
was an acolyte and I and I when
was an acolyte and I and I when the
bishop
bishop walked
was an acolyte and I and I when the
bishop walked around
bishop walked around I
was an acolyte and I and I when the
bishop walked around I went
bishop walked around I went by
was an acolyte and I and I when the
bishop walked around I went by his
bishop walked around I went by his side
and
and held
and held his
and held his robes
and held his robes and
and held his robes and did
and held his robes and did the
and held his robes and did the incense
and
and all
and held his robes and did the incense
and all and
and all and I
and held his robes and did the incense
and all and I sang
and all and I sang Pilus
and held his robes and did the incense
and all and I sang Pilus Angelicus
and all and I sang Pilus Angelicus this
boy
boy soprano
in
in a
boy soprano
in a great
in a great cathedral
boy soprano
in a great cathedral with
in a great cathedral with incense
boy soprano
in a great cathedral with incense and
stained
stained glass
stained glass and
stained glass and I'll
stained glass and I'll tell
stained glass and I'll tell you
stained glass and I'll tell you if
stained glass and I'll tell you if that
don't
don't bring
stained glass and I'll tell you if that
don't bring tears
don't bring tears to
stained glass and I'll tell you if that
don't bring tears to your
don't bring tears to your eyesoo
stained glass and I'll tell you if that
don't bring tears to your eyesoo just
knocked
knocked me
knocked me out.
knocked me out. I
knocked me out. I don't know.
knocked me out. I don't know. I
knocked me out. I don't know. I kept
singing.
singing. Uh
knocked me out. I don't know. I kept
singing. Uh anyway,
singing. Uh anyway, I'm
knocked me out. I don't know. I kept
singing. Uh anyway, I'm just
reminiscing.
I
I forget
reminiscing.
I forget what
I forget what I
reminiscing.
I forget what I was
I forget what I was telling
reminiscing.
I forget what I was telling you
I forget what I was telling you for.
>> Boxing.
>> Boxing. Boxing.
>> Boxing. Boxing. Boxing.
>> Huh?
>> Boxing.
>> Boxing. Yes.
>> Boxing. Yes. Well,
>> Boxing.
>> Boxing. Yes. Well, I
>> Boxing. Yes. Well, I learned
>> Boxing.
>> Boxing. Yes. Well, I learned how
>> Boxing. Yes. Well, I learned how to
>> Boxing.
>> Boxing. Yes. Well, I learned how to box.
So,
So, I
So, I was
So, I was a
So, I was a mosqu.
So, I was a mosqu. And
So, I was a mosqu. And the
So, I was a mosqu. And the way
So, I was a mosqu. And the way I
So, I was a mosqu. And the way I I
So, I was a mosqu. And the way I I won
after
after that
So, I was a mosqu. And the way I I won
after that after
after that after that,
So, I was a mosqu. And the way I I won
after that after that, the
after that after that, the first
So, I was a mosqu. And the way I I won
after that after that, the first thing
after that after that, the first thing I
won,
won, the
won, the first
won, the first fight
won, the first fight after
won, the first fight after that,
won, the first fight after that, I
won, the first fight after that, I won.
And
And I
won, the first fight after that, I won.
And I was
And I was so
won, the first fight after that, I won.
And I was so fast
And I was so fast that
won, the first fight after that, I won.
And I was so fast that he
And I was so fast that he didn't
won, the first fight after that, I won.
And I was so fast that he didn't know
what
what hit
what hit him.
what hit him. And
what hit him. And I
what hit him. And I always
what hit him. And I always hit
what hit him. And I always hit him
what hit him. And I always hit him in
the
the nose.
what hit him. And I always hit him in
the nose. sprang
the nose. sprang like
what hit him. And I always hit him in
the nose. sprang like that
the nose. sprang like that and
what hit him. And I always hit him in
the nose. sprang like that and then
the nose. sprang like that and then I
was
was out
was out before
was out before he
was out before he could
was out before he could hit
was out before he could hit me
was out before he could hit me and
was out before he could hit me and he
get
get a
was out before he could hit me and he
get a bloody
get a bloody nose
was out before he could hit me and he
get a bloody nose in
get a bloody nose in the
was out before he could hit me and he
get a bloody nose in the fight.
get a bloody nose in the fight. So
was out before he could hit me and he
get a bloody nose in the fight. So that
was
was pretty
was pretty pretty
was pretty pretty good.
was pretty pretty good. I
was pretty pretty good. I don't
was pretty pretty good. I don't know
was pretty pretty good. I don't know why
I
I told
was pretty pretty good. I don't know why
I told you
I told you the
was pretty pretty good. I don't know why
I told you the story,
I told you the story, but
>> huh
>> huh Jimmy.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So
>> huh Jimmy.
>> Yeah. So yeah,
>> Yeah. So yeah, he
>> huh Jimmy.
>> Yeah. So yeah, he said,
>> Yeah. So yeah, he said, "Oh
>> huh Jimmy.
>> Yeah. So yeah, he said, "Oh yes."
>> Yeah. So yeah, he said, "Oh yes." So
anyway,
anyway, I
anyway, I learned
anyway, I learned how
anyway, I learned how to
anyway, I learned how to box.
anyway, I learned how to box. So
anyway, I learned how to box. So I
anyway, I learned how to box. So I go
anyway, I learned how to box. So I go in
the
the Navy
anyway, I learned how to box. So I go in
the Navy and
the Navy and Jimmy
anyway, I learned how to box. So I go in
the Navy and Jimmy Sanders
the Navy and Jimmy Sanders says
anyway, I learned how to box. So I go in
the Navy and Jimmy Sanders says to
the Navy and Jimmy Sanders says to you,
"Hey
"Hey Shorty,"
"Hey Shorty," that
"Hey Shorty," that was
"Hey Shorty," that was my
"Hey Shorty," that was my name
thereafter.
thereafter. You
"Hey Shorty," that was my name
thereafter. You say,
thereafter. You say, "You
"Hey Shorty," that was my name
thereafter. You say, "You can't
thereafter. You say, "You can't be
"Hey Shorty," that was my name
thereafter. You say, "You can't be too
sensitive
sensitive about
sensitive about things."
sensitive about things." And
sensitive about things." And um
sensitive about things." And um he
sensitive about things." And um he says,
"You
"You you
sensitive about things." And um he says,
"You you not
"You you not a
sensitive about things." And um he says,
"You you not a box?"
"You you not a box?" I
sensitive about things." And um he says,
"You you not a box?" I says,
"You you not a box?" I says, "Yeah."
sensitive about things." And um he says,
"You you not a box?" I says, "Yeah." He
says,
says, "Uh,
says, "Uh, oh,
says, "Uh, oh, I
says, "Uh, oh, I said,
says, "Uh, oh, I said, "Yeah,
says, "Uh, oh, I said, "Yeah, I
says, "Uh, oh, I said, "Yeah, I took
lessons
lessons with
says, "Uh, oh, I said, "Yeah, I took
lessons with Richie
lessons with Richie Mitchell."
says, "Uh, oh, I said, "Yeah, I took
lessons with Richie Mitchell." Wow.
lessons with Richie Mitchell." Wow. He
says,
says, "Well,
says, "Well, go
says, "Well, go tell
says, "Well, go tell him,
says, "Well, go tell him, go
says, "Well, go tell him, go around,
says, "Well, go tell him, go around, you
know."
know." So,
says, "Well, go tell him, go around, you
know." So, we
know." So, we go
says, "Well, go tell him, go around, you
know." So, we go like
know." So, we go like this,
says, "Well, go tell him, go around, you
know." So, we go like this, one
know." So, we go like this, one shot
says, "Well, go tell him, go around, you
know." So, we go like this, one shot and
I
I was
I was unconscious.
Hit
Hit me
I was unconscious.
Hit me once.
Hit me once. Later,
I was unconscious.
Hit me once. Later, I
Hit me once. Later, I found
I was unconscious.
Hit me once. Later, I found out
Hit me once. Later, I found out he
I was unconscious.
Hit me once. Later, I found out he was
Hit me once. Later, I found out he was a
champion
champion of
champion of the
champion of the third
champion of the third fleet.
He
He was
champion of the third fleet.
He was the
He was the most
champion of the third fleet.
He was the most fearsome
He was the most fearsome boxer
champion of the third fleet.
He was the most fearsome boxer I've
He was the most fearsome boxer I've ever
seen.
seen. He
seen. He was
seen. He was ferocious
seen. He was ferocious and
seen. He was ferocious and fast.
seen. He was ferocious and fast. God
bless
bless him.
seen. He was ferocious and fast. God
bless him. Anyway,
bless him. Anyway, we're
seen. He was ferocious and fast. God
bless him. Anyway, we're still
bless him. Anyway, we're still friends.
So
So after
So after not
So after not hearing
So after not hearing from
So after not hearing from these
So after not hearing from these people
for
for for
So after not hearing from these people
for for 50
for for 50 years
So after not hearing from these people
for for 50 years my
for for 50 years my my
So after not hearing from these people
for for 50 years my my uh
for for 50 years my my uh mates
So after not hearing from these people
for for 50 years my my uh mates on
for for 50 years my my uh mates on the
ship
ship after
ship after 50
ship after 50 years
ship after 50 years after
ship after 50 years after the
ship after 50 years after the war
ship after 50 years after the war is
over
over all
ship after 50 years after the war is
over all of
over all of a
ship after 50 years after the war is
over all of a sudden
over all of a sudden I
ship after 50 years after the war is
over all of a sudden I started
over all of a sudden I started hearing
from
from them.
from them. Isn't
from them. Isn't that
from them. Isn't that 50
from them. Isn't that 50 years
from them. Isn't that 50 years and
suddenly
suddenly got
from them. Isn't that 50 years and
suddenly got some
suddenly got some guy
from them. Isn't that 50 years and
suddenly got some guy calls
suddenly got some guy calls me
from them. Isn't that 50 years and
suddenly got some guy calls me and
suddenly got some guy calls me and says
are
are you
are you Dave?
are you Dave? Yeah.
are you Dave? Yeah. Are
are you Dave? Yeah. Are you
are you Dave? Yeah. Are you shorty?
are you Dave? Yeah. Are you shorty? I
said
said yeah
I'm
I'm still
I'm still short.
I'm still short. Yeah.
I'm still short. Yeah. He
I'm still short. Yeah. He said
he
he told
I'm still short. Yeah. He said
he told me
he told me who
I'm still short. Yeah. He said
he told me who I
he told me who I was
I'm still short. Yeah. He said
he told me who I was and
he told me who I was and we
I'm still short. Yeah. He said
he told me who I was and we both
he told me who I was and we both broke
into
into tears.
So
So everybody
into tears.
So everybody that
So everybody that then
into tears.
So everybody that then we
So everybody that then we found
into tears.
So everybody that then we found each
other
other and
other and as
other and as each
other and as each one
other and as each one would
other and as each one would call
other and as each one would call we
would
would always
other and as each one would call we
would always break
would always break into
other and as each one would call we
would always break into tears.
would always break into tears. I
other and as each one would call we
would always break into tears. I would
break
break into
break into tears,
break into tears, the
break into tears, the guy
break into tears, the guy at
break into tears, the guy at the
break into tears, the guy at the other
end
end break
break into tears, the guy at the other
end break into
end break into tears.
You
You see
You see because
You see because that
You see because that love
You see because that love that
You see because that love that love
there
there was
You see because that love that love
there was beyond
there was beyond all
You see because that love that love
there was beyond all time.
there was beyond all time. So
You see because that love that love
there was beyond all time. So one
characteristic
characteristic of
characteristic of love
characteristic of love you
characteristic of love you see
characteristic of love you see is
characteristic of love you see is that
which
which your
characteristic of love you see is that
which your your
which your your your
characteristic of love you see is that
which your your your mates
which your your your mates back
characteristic of love you see is that
which your your your mates back in
which your your your mates back in the
World
World War
World War II
World War II there
World War II there was
World War II there was a
World War II there was a love
World War II there was a love there
World War II there was a love there that
was
was incredible
World War II there was a love there that
was incredible and
was incredible and it
World War II there was a love there that
was incredible and it lasted
was incredible and it lasted forever.
Lasted
Lasted forever
Lasted forever 50
Lasted forever 50 years
Lasted forever 50 years you
Lasted forever 50 years you didn't
Lasted forever 50 years you didn't hear
from
from and
Lasted forever 50 years you didn't hear
from and it
from and it was
Lasted forever 50 years you didn't hear
from and it was like
from and it was like yesterday.
Lasted forever 50 years you didn't hear
from and it was like yesterday. you're
breaking
breaking the
breaking the tears.
breaking the tears. So
breaking the tears. So that
breaking the tears. So that commitment
to
to love
breaking the tears. So that commitment
to love then
to love then is
breaking the tears. So that commitment
to love then is uh
to love then is uh beyond
breaking the tears. So that commitment
to love then is uh beyond time
to love then is uh beyond time uh
breaking the tears. So that commitment
to love then is uh beyond time uh beyond
a
a sailing.
a sailing. I
a sailing. I don't
a sailing. I don't care
a sailing. I don't care what
a sailing. I don't care what he's
a sailing. I don't care what he's done
in
in the
a sailing. I don't care what he's done
in the meantime.
in the meantime. Uh
a sailing. I don't care what he's done
in the meantime. Uh it's
in the meantime. Uh it's all
a sailing. I don't care what he's done
in the meantime. Uh it's all irrelevant.
It's
It's only
It's only the
It's only the reality
It's only the reality of
It's only the reality of the
reconnection
reconnection with
It's only the reality of the
reconnection with uh
reconnection with uh love
It's only the reality of the
reconnection with uh love as
reconnection with uh love as a
It's only the reality of the
reconnection with uh love as a state
reconnection with uh love as a state of
mind.