Welcome to Dr. David Hawkins Sedona 2002
series, The Way to God. Lecture 7, the
nature of divinity versus religious
fallacy.
Originally presented July 13th, 2002 at
the Sedona Creative Life Center.
Well,
we've resumed today. U today we're
representing our rights. We're we're
declaring the rights of God and and
protecting God's good name. And we're
here in the name of protecting the good
name of God today
who has been much maligned over the
thousands of years. blamed for
everything. Catastrophes,
earthquakes, floods, drought,
and uh because of God, we can't picnic
in the woods around Sedona right now.
The drought,
but it never dawned on primitive man
that, you know, the sort of ancient
makers of ancient gods that these things
went on before mankind existed.
It's time to blame God for human
catastrophe when humans weren't even
here yet and earthquakes were going on
and uh floods and fires were going on.
So
it states, you know, the pre
pre-Christian history was rooted in a
in conceptions of God that are pretty
much anthropomorphic in which God uh
takes the blame for everything. sort of
a dualistic perception of God which
persists to this common day and um still
causes consternation.
Time magazine a few weeks ago on his
cover expressed the degree of that
consternation which still exists.
So I'm glad today we have
representatives of various religions,
various religious orders. Uh, we have
theology students from the University of
Michigan and I better watch myself.
Better watch myself. So
anyway, the next book we're doing um
we're calibrating the energies of um the
greatest theologians of history and
calibrating what the level of truth of
uh of um
all the religions, branches of religion,
spiritual groups, teachers, historical
scriptures, etc.
And um if I'm still living, it'll be
published in a year or two.
In fact, as a matter of fact, I guess
today today's uh lecture uh did stir up
certain energies in the universe and uh
but we escaped the lightning and we
drove between it and here we are. So
well when you talk about the absolute
truth of God, you can see that you
jeopardize a great deal on this planet
whose survival is based on
not on the truth of God but on the
falsification of the truth of God. Uh
that's their power base, their financial
base, gets them the publicity, gets
those bucks from all you listeners out
there in TV land.
So anyway,
I forgot what the lecture was on today.
Now, was it
was on uh
what the heck was on religion or
something? I don't know what
spirituality. Oh, yes. Well, it was
misprinted on the schedule, so we won't
be saying what it was anyway because it
said, what did it say? Spiritual truth
versus religious following. It's
supposed to be religious fallacy. Well,
it's all following fallacy. It's all the
same or we'd all be enlightened, right?
Also, something different we'll do today
is we'll um we'll have the group as a
group we'll write. We're I'm finishing a
book called I
and um
see sometimes people think you know from
some of the questions we get in the mail
people think that um Susan and I make
these things up you know and and what we
find is whatever we believe in.
Well, the kinesiologic method of
ascertaining truth of differentiating
truth from falsehood arose over 20 years
in which we groups many times this size.
All of us did kinesiology. You know, we
all divide up into ones and twos and we
would have a thousand people do it at
once. And we did that all over the world
many, many times.
But those who have not witnessed any of
those things, I thought today we'll do
something like we did over the years.
And we'll do it with this group here.
And uh these are statements that are
going in the new book. And we're going
to check them out and make sure they're
true before we put them in there. Okay?
cuz this is sort of a rattle bone rattle
your bone statement of spiritual reality
and it's going to shake up people and we
want to make sure that we're not lying.
God really is awful. You ought to be
scared of him. You know what I mean?
That did come up this morning, didn't
it? Mhm. Uh
it came up this morning. Suddenly I felt
a huge shot of
um like an attack of immense fear coming
up.
Wow. It was a big one and coming up from
the collective unconscious. So we're
going to check ourselves out today. We
want to demonstrate how we verify these
things. Um they they come from this
consciousness as a knowingness and then
to express it in the world takes
languaging
expression in uh literary form and then
what we do is we verify the truth of the
statement. What's obvious to me may not
be expressed correctly for one thing.
Uh and we have made mistakes in the
book. We got there was two commas out,
one semicolon.
People are really picky. We get letters
and then they show you you're missing a
colon right there. I thought, oh my god,
we're missing a colon right there. So,
we thought we'd be more met more
meticulous in our research.
So, we have some mind-boggling
statements here. uh as I say as a god's
right rights activist I feel it's my
duty to make these declarations on
behalf of deity and try and clear up his
his uh his image in the public eye
his reputation reputation has suffered
over the centuries we're going to try
and clear that up
um
so although I'm a god God's rights
activist. Uh it it's jcular, but it was
quite quite a storm we we we got hit by
this morning, was it not?
Okay. So, now we're going to verify
everything we say today. Let's show you
how it works. And we can have the whole
crowd. We're going to verify 21
statements about the reality of God,
which are absolutely mind-boggling.
And we're all going to verify them
forever on tape
for history.
So, I thought that would be something
fun to do that we've never done before
is write the book together
>> and uh and we'll put up these
propositions and then these propositions
may bring up questions. And so, we're
going to answer these questions directly
instead of waiting till the end of the
program
because um when you make declarations of
truth, it always brings up that which is
untrue. services, you know, triggers it
up for examination and verification and
um
um whether the God who really hates you
is true or not. You know what I'm
saying? That comes right up.
Whether you should be scared of God or
or not. See?
Uh so that came up today. Came up. Let's
see where it came up from. Um what I
felt was um tremendous um fear. resist.
>> Mhm. Came up from the collective
unconscious resist
came up as um
the totality of the error of uh the
misunderstanding of God resist. Yeah.
Right. So
it actually what had to do with um page
time magazine resist. Okay. The
unconscious fear of the apocalypse is
what we've heard this morning. Resist.
Yeah, if you don't think that was a
strong one, it came up like
incumbent in the human psyche for 2,000
years.
It had a lot of energy.
Um, let's see what happens to the
consciousness of mankind. The
consciousness of mankind is uh I think
was was over 20 was 207. It's now over
208, 209, 210. It's now a 209.
209.5.
No, 209. 209. Oh, I thought I'd squeeze
an extra half a point. That means
somebody out there is not paying
attention. That half a point. You better
wake up.
as we see in in the book, the reason I'm
talking about this now is because I'm
just finishing this book in which we
sort of trace the evolution of
uh creation um the
dawning of the light of God as
consciousness.
The evolution of that consciousness
throughout all of time and throughout
all all time on this planet. It's
evolution through the various life forms
which takes us through all the theories
of evolution and creation which we've
pretty much settled with this crowd
before that evolution and creation are
one and the same thing. So we're going
to verify all these things as we go
along. Right? You don't have to stand up
for everyone. You're going to be worn
out in no time.
Evolution and creation are one and the
same thing. This Thank you.
What we reaffirm with each lecture
is the absolute reality
that all things
are what they are
by virtue of the divinity of their
creation
which is continuous
and it is the presence of God that
accounts for all existence
at every instant. Is this
right?
Because the old conception was God was
the great roller of the dice who appears
in Genesis disappears and isn't going to
show up again until judgment day. In the
meantime, you're on your own.
Good luck
because all you have to go by is some
historical documents and scriptures
which sort of rattle your teeth when you
really look at them. You know, this is
the first time in history there's really
been any kind of valid uh spiritual
research. Is that a fact?
That's a fact. Yeah.
There's never been a tool to really do
spiritual research. There's been
historical research in which you crawl
through the deserts looking for old
scriptures and deciphering the
undeciphable which you find on the sides
of tombs and various hidden places.
or you find relics or you find bones or
you find validation that
such and such a community did live
thousands of years ago. That's
archaeologic. That's history and
research. It's not has nothing to do
with spiritual reality.
Theology is the study of the nature of
uh religion as it evolved over the
millennia and of course is an extremely
interesting
subject in and of itself. I could have
easily have become a theologian.
I got straight A in theology at a Jesuit
university. That should get you in the
door right without me in the door. Good
for you. And uh
anyway, at the time I was an atheist,
but that didn't bother my understanding
of theology.
It had nothing to do with my study of
theology. Uh and I respect theology and
uh and you can define that the limit of
theology. So we don't want to stress
theology beyond which it is equipped to
go because theology and science are
somewhat similar in that they're both in
the 400s. And once you get up to about
496 or 498, you can't go farther with
it. You can't really go farther with
science
or theology because that's as far as the
intellect will take you. I read a very
ariodite paper.
Um I don't suppose I should mention his
name although I have it in the
bibliography of the book. um most area
paper I've read yet on the relationship
of consciousness
and advanced theoretical physics quantum
theory. Um
now this is a very impressive
that paper is about as high as you can
go with science physist. Yeah. See he's
up at four and that that paper we should
not mention his name. Correct. Correct.
Okay. Anyway, that paper he's very
well-known writer a very advanced
researcher in the nature of science and
consciousness
and science and see science is one way
to approach consciousness and I've
spoken at their conferences a couple of
times it's a very areaike group the only
difficulty is science can only take you
to the high 400s and um the reality the
spiritual realities really don't show up
with any strong indication until you get
into the 500s. So there's there's a
block and uh
as I read this this paper it's extremely
ariodite. It's beyond my capacity to
comprehend the mathematics of quantum
mechanics.
Um but what I got the feeling I got was
that the intellect is being pushed to
the almost painful limit of where it can
go you know and um I've read a number of
those things and I hear them at science
and consciousness kinds of conferences
and um
you know my psyche is also in the 400s
and it's very impressed when it says uh
And then I have the ultimate solution.
always you put a line under all of this,
you put infinity under there and there
you go.
You always come up with the same answer.
The that which is not comprehensible.
So, so the difficulty with science and
advanced theoretical physics is it takes
us right to the door. And what we
suspected and what we've said before is
that quantum potentiality is the doorway
that infinite quantum potentiality is
the infinite doorway of infinite
infinite potentiality.
Yes. So they're correct that is the
doorway
except with science you can't go through
the doorway. So what science does is
take us up and this is very arodite and
very impressive and uh it always makes
me want to go back to school and study
quantum mechanics and math. I like
quantum mechanics. I don't like the math
that goes with it.
But it does take you right up to the
door, but it doesn't take you through
the door.
To get through the door, you got to
jump. Even Einstein Einstein's 499, you
have to jump through the to the 500s.
Um,
and so the intellect takes you as far as
it can go.
I respect theology because it's um I
find it very fascinating and u
uh I could really spend a couple of
years just going to a theological
seminary. I just love doing that. So if
I had another lifetime or two, I would
just blow a hole on just going to
theological seminary and writing up
theological treatises.
become professor something or other
schnap and hoofer at some university.
They always have wonderful names like
that. Call him schnap and hoofer.
I'm just sir Dr. Doctor. I don't have
any great title like Schnappenhofer.
All right.
So I thought we would start with then
discussing the reality of God and um and
try and nail it down.
I mean, nobody has ever nailed it down,
much less publicly. The there's
exhortations.
I I watch some of these preachers.
They're they're wonderful. They're
dramatic. Uh they have great dramatic
ability
and they um they're very impassionate
and um if I was a follower of theirs,
I'd probably be very enthusiastic
follower.
All right. So, how can we verify then
what has been bandied about? See, if you
look up theology, encyclopedia botanica,
it runs quite a few pages. I mean, a lot
of theologians, a lot has been said
going back to ancient Greece.
And um it takes you into philosophy and
metaphysics and of course the crux of it
is epistemology. So those of you who are
intellectuals know that the crux of
theology then really ends up in the hard
problems the hard problem of
epistemology
and epistemology can only take you to
the door. Epistemology can only take you
to the door. Epistemology can only take
you the truth of epistemology can only
take you to 499.
Is that that's correct? Yeah, it does.
It only takes you to 499. Why is that?
because you're still in mind and mind
intrinsically in order to be mind has to
be dualistic. So the reason theology,
epistemology, philosophy,
advanced theoretical physics, quantum
mechanics can't take you through the
door
is because they're all dualistic systems
of knowingness. They're all dualistic.
There's a this and a that. There's a me
and a there's there's a the self and
that which is known which is different
than the self. So all of these will take
us right to the door but they won't take
us through the door. Some other quality
is required.
I think a study of theology gives you
very great respect for the human
intellect. I mean the way um God
transcendent versus God imminent is
discussed in all the various world's
religions is quite uh impressive and I
find it quite fascinating. But what you
really what you're really understanding
through this study is how the human mind
works. What you end up with as a
straight A student in theology,
epistemology, advanced theoretical
physics and quantum mechanics is an
extremely advanced and sophisticated
understanding of how the human mind
works.
That's where it takes you right to the
door.
However, that drive that takes a person
through the door, I think if correctly
recontextualized, has the power to take
you through the door. Anybody who spends
their whole life getting right up to the
door, anybody home,
is there God? Is there reality? Anybody
who spends their whole life straining to
get there is certainly got enough
momentum and motivation to break through
the door. And it only requires
unblocking unblocking that door.
So today I thought we we will go some
we're going to make some
statements about God and see if they're
verifiable. And then I thought we might
even do kinesiology today. We'll do ones
and twos and we'll present some of these
to the entire audience.
It isn't just the two of us at home
sneakily
trying to prove that God exists or
something. You know what I mean?
Well, she believes it. I believe it. So,
the kinesiology, you know, because
people question kinesiology.
Uh and so we'll make a few comments
about that today too. You see,
kinesiology itself calibrates at 600.
Kinesiology is at the doorway between
the ego and the non-ego, between the
duality and non-duality.
So it stands like a guardian at the
door. Kinesiology itself as a science
calibrates its reliability. The truth is
uh kinesiology itself calibrates exactly
at 600 resist. Wow. 600 is exactly where
you shift from ego into enlightenment.
So it's a critical level.
Um
therefore kinesiology is is difficult.
People try to grasp it intellectually. I
said, "Don't try to grasp it
intellectually. When you stab yourself,
it bleeds." That's good enough, isn't
it? When you stand in the sun, you in
the sun, you get warm. When you stand in
the rain, you get wet. That's all you
got to know about it.
If you ask the most feudal question to
ask about anything is why?
Because the ultimate reality there is no
why.
There is no why.
Therefore, all these are based on a
fallacy. The first fallacy is that of
duality
which is built into languaging and logic
and conceptualization itself.
What was the second one?
I forget what the second one.
Therefore to arrive at truth is totally
subjective.
So what logic and all these things are
looking for is
by a means of duality to try and
discover the nature of that which is
non-dualistic. Non-dualistic
it can't be done.
There's a chapter I'm writing calling
the final blocks to the door doorway
because at the doorway at 600 when you
walk through you can't take duality with
you. You cannot take any baggage with
you. All that you've ever known, think,
believe in, can mentalize about,
conceptualize about, you cannot take
with you.
It has to be left at the door because at
that point mind disappears.
You can't take the content of mind with
you. When mind disappears, it dissolves
with the mind.
So all of that you have accumulated uh
is at that point useless.
It's useful to get to the door, but then
at that door one has to drop it.
So we're going to make some interesting
statements and we're going to do
kinesiology.
Uh, I thought we're going to divide up
into ones and twos.
There's a fun thing to do. We haven't
done that since kindergarten. Every
Let's all divide into ones and twos.
One, two. Just go down the row. You're
one. You're one. Everybody should know
whether they're a one or a two. You know
what I mean? In this world,
we haven't done group kiology with this
group. Fun to do.
>> If you know, if you're watch
The beginning of wisdom is to know
whether you are one or not.
>> Okay? And we will charge the we will the
first experiment we will do uh just uh
we're going to do a quick rough one so
that when we go down these uh questions
most of you're all familiar with
kinesiology and she and I will do it and
then uh and then I'm not going to teach
it anymore. Any more questions on
kinesiology will be stuffed back in your
mouth and you will be turned around in
that direction
and never to be returned through the
door.
All right. So I'm going to be the
doctor. So number ones are going to be
the doctor. We're not going to spend too
long at this, but I want us to know
enough to validate all of this in
public. Okay. I'm going to be I'm number
one. So I'm the doctor. You're number
two. You're the patient. I have
permission to to do this with you.
Resist. I make a statement. I have
permission to do this with you. All
right. I use one little finger. See? Now
when she pushes back, she only pushes
down with enough to resist me. If I put
down three 3 oz, she only needs 3 and 12
o to withstand me. She doesn't need 5
lbs. You see, the biggest problem we see
with kinesiology is nothing makes them
go negative because they're resisting
gravity. They think they're still in a
tree and if they let go, they're going
to fall out of the tree. This is what's
going on unconsciously in the back of
your head. We were watching it last
night on TV on the Animal Channel. And
here's this primate up in the and you
can see he's starting to slip. You can
see all his anti-gravity muscles flex.
So that's what happens when people we
say picture Ben Lden. They start to go
weak and then suddenly their
anti-gravity comes back back up. They
think they're an ape in a tree. So
you're not an ape in a tree. If you let
this arm go, it you will not fall out of
the tree. All right, I'm going to push
down with about 3 oz.
That That was 3 oz resist. That was 2 oz
resistant. That's 1 oz resistance. We
can do it with a very small. See, she's
small and weak.
I'm small and weak. That's why I only
put down push it down with two ounces.
All right. Two or three ounces. See? So,
you only have to resist enough to keep
it from, you know what I mean? You only
have to keep the paper enough to keep it
from folding down. That's all. You don't
need five pounds to turn the edge of
this paper. You understand?
We see people doing it like, you know,
he's uh you're not in the you're not in
the ring. So, all right. So, I make a
statement. I try to keep extraneous
things like beautiful music uh and stuff
like that out of the space. Okay. We
have permission to do this uh
exercise with this audience. We just
Thank you. All right. So, just one
finger, a couple ounces. She resists.
Now, if you've done this a lot of times,
you can tell almost the instant. As I
ask her the question, if the answer is
no, she can she you can almost feel a
run of energy. You know the answers.
Before your arm even goes weak, you
already got that. It's it's very
sensitive
when done correctly. When done correctly
by people who are who are integrous,
this is 100%
unreliable. He said, right? when it's
state when the statement is made as a
positive statement by people who
themselves are integrous. The other
thing to make it work is you both got to
be over 200.
Um been loud can't use it.
That should fix some teaching.
Take that old Ben. No. Anyway,
the purpose of the question has to be
integrous. Okay. The purpose our purpose
this morning is integrous. Our purpose
is to you to to demonstrate um an
integrous method of discerning truth
from falsehood
for the good of mankind. Is it okay? So
all right. So it's okay for us to do it.
It's okay for us to ask these kinds of
questions. It's okay for us to do it in
front of this audience. You can't just
presume it's okay to do with this
audience.
So we get we get permission. All right.
Now I just make a simple statement and I
want to make one right out of the thing
here.
And then we'll all do the same arms.
We'll start out first the ones will be
the doctors and twos will be the
patients and after everybody everybody's
got that we're going to turn it around.
Now for an audience that hasn't done it
before together. We haven't never done
it all together as an audience. Uh
let's see what we were going to ask.
There's something else you got to ask
about it. Well, I don't remember what it
is.
It was critical but that's all
>> permission to ask a question and then
>> yes okay so we'll ask permission so
first we'll have ones oh I know uh I
want to see if she's a suitable subject
with me not not everybody's suitable
with each other we found that what 10%
of people have some alteration of
theirqi energy and they're not really
good at kinesiology there's other
methods of doing
or you get your friends say, "Should I
buy that new Cadillac or not?" You know,
anyway, um not everybody's suitable.
Uh and Lou, Lou sent me where where's
Lou? There's Lou. Uh L sent me uh you
know bringing it up to date that um
uh first of all if um first of all if
only
18% of the population is suitable to do
this where does that leave us right to
begin with. Uh so we'd have to say that
at the time this was 78% of the time.
That to begin with only about 22% of the
population
is is allowed to do it. Of that 22%
not everybody's matchable. A lot of
times husbands and wives for reasons we
haven't had time to research. Uh
something about their chi energy. Can't
always do it with each other. They can
do it with somebody else.
Um,
so that we know about 10% of the
population isn't going to work for
reasons of peculiarities of their energy
system. And we know that it's not going.
So how what percentage of the population
is uh is able to do this? What did you
say on that?
>> Huh?
>> We No, we ended up with the with the
percentage that could could do it.
>> 20%.
>> All right. So
>> that could
>> that could Yes. All right. So it is
limited which I didn't know when I first
wrote power versus force to really only
one out of five people in the in the
population. I didn't really know that.
Uh I knew that it didn't work if the
question was non-intigorous.
Um but I didn't realize how limited it
was. So it's really uh its greatest
advantage then is for integrous use by
integrous people for integrous purposes.
Um all right so we we want to say let's
say you're on the audience I'm one
you're two hi too.
>> Um we're suitable to work together.
Resist. Okay. I want you to picture Mr.
Bin Laden. Now resist. Thank you. I want
you to picture Jesus Christ. Resist.
Okay. I want you to picture something or
someone you love. Resist. I want you to
picture.
Well, we won't even picture him.
He's too bad to picture. We don't want
to pick the
All right. So, we just want to get that
you're suitable.
Your purpose, you know, you you see
purpose is set by intention. Intention.
Um, so the intention is integrous. The
intention of be being here is integrous.
The intention of listening to lecture.
So, let's do ones and twos. Everybody
get up. Number one's the doctor. Number
two is the patient. Just uh meet each
other. Uh just test out the suitability.
It's okay for us. Okay. We're going to
do the whole bunch at once.
This is fun.
>> Okay. Now you can switch. Uh doctors and
patients switch if you want.
>> Doctors and patients can switch you if
they like. Ones become twos and twos
become ones.
>> What a party. All the ones become twos
and the twos become ones.
>> Maybe it's time to be quiet and restate
that.
>> Oh, they'll get it. They'll get it.
All right.
Okie do.
>> Okay. We'll just have quiet for a
second.
>> What? partner.
>> Uh if you if you got somebody you're
working with that is not working with,
switch partners.
Anybody who's not working, put it up
your hands and we'll just switch switch
with each other. Sometimes it's the
chemistry. We haven't had time to
research it, but very often couples,
husbands and wives for some reason is
the worst. And people are having trouble
finding a partner. Put up your hand.
We'll we'll play uh
musical chairs. Okay. Musical chairs. is
goes, "Okay, everybody switched. You got
to play doctor. You got to play patient.
People who people who go strong with
evil see me afterwards."
All right. So, that's good.
I want to do it as a public statement
verifiable by
spiritual audience.
Okay. Over 90% have it. 92% 94%.
93% have 94%
93% as high as we're going to get. Okay.
Okay. There's a Okay. There's one other
trick. Oo.
I better not do it with this microphone
on, but I'd like everybody to do the
thyus stump. You smile, think of
somebody you love, and go.
All right.
It's over 93% 94% 95% 96% 97% 98% 99 98%
still 2% U.
>> That's okay.
>> All right, we got it up to 98%.
2% I don't know you screwed up some
listening to the wrong music on the way
here or something.
The time of stump usually clears it up.
That was, you know, Dr. John Diamond
wrote that and I've extolled its virtue.
I can't do it with the microphone on
because I'll blow your ears out here.
But you know, you go h
and simulating the thamus gland at the
same time. All right. So now this is a
suitable audience. We get that it's 98%
accurate right now.
And the other 2% you see me after.
Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> All right. Now, all right. Here's what
we're going to do now.
Um you affirm that love makes you go
strong, truth makes you go strong, that
which is unloving, that which is facious
makes you go weak. And we have 98%
concordance here which in this audience
randomly picked however united by
spiritual intention. That's very very
good. All right. Um
well this sounds very ariodite. I should
have read this before. My god this is
great stuff.
I didn't know theological students were
going to be here.
We'll sit down for a second and then
I'll read you this preamble.
This is the way it's going to come out
in the book. So when you get if you ever
get a copy,
which I'm happy to send anybody to one
to for merely participating,
uh
we're going to have these statements in
there. It's going to be, you know,
important chapter.
Despite uh the disagreements over the
centuries uh about sacred scriptures of
various religions,
collectively there is a verifiable
authentic source of man's knowledge of
the nature of divinity
which is actually quite impressive in
their unonymity and concordance.
There emerges then a substratum of
irreducible truth verified in all
cultures throughout all times by those
that we call mystics sages.
We now have a recently discovered
calibration technique verifying truth
from falsehood
so as to be able to
reaffirm
spiritual reality
and end up with sort of a modern-day
theology
which we will call this new religion
spirituality.
Spirituality is that religious
discipline in which the that which is
provably the truth has been extracted
historically, subjectively and
experimentally. See, because the source
of my own knowledge is all three.
The states that appeared of their own
accord.
Uh then later on studying and finding a
way of objective verification
and that we see this the subjective
theoretical
subjectivity of
people who have experienced the presence
of God has been exactly the same
throughout all cultures throughout all
histories throughout all millennia. It's
always been the same. Therefore,
anything that varies from that requires
explanation instead of the other way
around. Well, traditional religion put
it the other way around. Oh, no.
Scripture is what is the authority and
the mystic had better be beaten and
burned until they changed their mind and
come around to the truth as the church
saw it.
All right.
There is therefore available by a
sophisticated intellect subjectively,
objectively, historically a core of
absolute validity that transcends all
positionalities.
And all positionalities are maneuverings
for advantage or gain.
The only reason you can believe the
mystic is because there's no advantage
or gain to it.
All things are subject s sub s sub s sub
s sub s sub s sub s sub s sub s sub s
sub suspect if there is gain or
advantage
in as much as one has all there is to
have knows all there is to know and is
all what is possible to be there's
hardly any gain the world can dangle in
front of you like water already
oh golly
uh so we're going to start out and we're
going to verify these uh statements
which will now become the famous Sedona
declaration in the defense of the good
name of God.
I'll read the first one and we're going
to ask whether this is the truth or not.
So, you'll have to all be quiet and then
I'll say we'll test it. We'll test it.
Okay, everybody get doctors and patients
get no ones and twos. Get ready. We're
going to hit the hit it hard.
All right. We're going to we're going to
make irreducible statements about the
essential nature of God uh as as
as my own understanding and experience
as well as theologically verifiable.
These are going to be statements in
which we're going to settle it for
mankind forever. Okay? So that's why
you're here this morning. All right.
First statement. God is both manifest as
the totality and allness of creation and
unmanifest as the Godhead, the infinite
potentiality in source. Quote in
parenthesis voidness prior to form that
is a fact resist
that is absolute truth. The level of thy
truth is over 900 980 999 1,000. That is
absolute truth to the degree that it's
noble in mankind. So everybody
all do it at once.
You can say we have permission to ask
that. We have permission to ask ask that
of your partner. We have permission to
ask this now in this this setting.
The statement just heard is 100% true.
Resist.
statement is true at the level of truth
that we calibrate at 1,00 resist. Okay.
>> All right. It's verifiable at the
maximum degree of truth that is possible
for a human to verify.
That's statement number one. Does
anybody argue with that?
God help you. Anyway,
oh dear.
Okay. Statement number two.
God is infinite beyond time, space,
locality, and without beginning or end.
Resist. That's true. Resist.
The level of truth is 1,000. Resist.
Thank you.
Without beginning or end. You see what I
mean?
God is, these are commonly stated in
theology, but we will prove it for
ourself. God is omnipresent.
God is omnipresent. God is the same as
allness,
omnipotent,
and omniscience. Is it
those statements are verifiable and
true? They don't depend on anybody's
opinion.
God is the source and substrate of
consciousness, awareness, knowingness,
and sensience
resist.
Okay, everybody test that's true. That
statement is true.
Okay, if anybody gets no, don't hesitate
because we'll check it out.
Yeah.
>> All right. Nose go off to the side and
we'll check you out later.
Oh golly. All right. Now, this is very
interesting having to do with uh
science. God is the sole source of life.
Resist.
God is the sole source of the energy of
life. Resist.
All right.
>> See, creation comes from the top down,
but evolution goes from the bottom up.
So, life can appear as a worm.
All worms leave now.
Okay. Uh so now let's test this.
Sometimes what we do we test all the you
see you have to have internal
consistency. If this is true then
we will test its opposite. Life arose u
accidentally as a spontaneous
interaction of chemistry. Resist. All
right. There goes science. Goodbye.
Goodbye science as the source of life.
Huh.
We're going to just confirm this
evolution.
We have permission to ask this.
Evolution occurs within consciousness
which then manifests as form. Is this
you see the reason there's a missing
link? Because there isn't any missing
link in form. You see because creation
is continuous.
Each billiard ball is continuously
created to be what it is.
What we see is the branching of a
branch. But the evolution of it's the
evolution of consciousness, the
evolution of the species occurs on the
invisible level of the domain of
consciousness. That's where the shift of
in the evolution of form because you see
the form includes aesthetics.
When you just think how the eye
uh works, you see it just didn't
accidentally learn how to blink on
itself. I mean, who the heck would have
thought of that? You know what I mean?
Consciousness
saw that construction and by holding it
in mind, it manifests as an eye. Is
this? All right. So, the eye didn't just
grow up accidentally. You see? All
right. That's enough science for today.
God is the source of evolution and
creation, which are identical and ever
continuous and ongoing until this
moment. Resist.
Yeah, creation is
what does creation look like? Creation
looks like a room full of people testing
each other with kinesiology. Don't you
see the unfolding of of everybody is
becoming
the potentiality of their own fulfilling
the potentiality of their own essence.
That's all that's happening. All right.
So
God is the source and essence of peace,
love, stillness and beauty. Resist.
Okay,
we're going to have fun when we get
through this serious list.
God is beyond all universes, all
materiality,
all galaxies, and yet the source of all
that is. Resist.
Okay. See, when you see God as source
rather than cause, you have a whole
different ballgame of theology.
Take that back to Michigan.
The reason that the reason theology gets
stuck in this piece of epistemology and
the reason advanced theoretical physics
gets stuck is because this is still
seeing things in terms of causality.
Causality is a dualistic deception.
There's a this causing of that. There is
no this causing that. The essence of
that which is the source of all
existence opens itself like this. It's
really merely revealing the truth of
that which it is. Nothing is causing
anything.
As the rose unfolds, nothing is causing
it to unfold.
It's the the form is dependent on
prevailing conditions, sunlight, water,
etc. But it is not the sunlight and all
that's causing the flower to unfold.
is the essence of the flower is
intrinsic to its creation
and it's merely revealing to you that
which it is because that's how creation
manifests itself in that which we've
perceive as the present reality.
That truth is 1,000 resistance.
Okay. But what just spoken is the
absolute truth. Okay.
All right.
God is the sole source of existence and
the potentiality of beingness is true.
resist.
>> Just say your partner that's true and
resist. And you can swap partners if one
of you has a doubt.
If there's any imbeciles here that have
Okay, now we're getting more
sophisticated. God is the ultimate
context of which the universe and all
that exists is the content exist.
Out of the unmanifest
arises the manifest
expressing itself as the entire
universe. And of course all the
universes are without end because
everything that is created uh by the
creator contains the same essence as the
creator.
Consequently,
each universe that is created out of the
fact that that is innate to its own
essence is creating an infinite series
of infinite universes which are creating
infinite universes which are creating
infinite universes because that is their
essence.
That's the true resistance. Whoa, boggle
myself there a second.
All right.
So it's it's critically different in
theology to understand the interesting
cause and source. You see the error in
the classic
uh theologian who's the basic classic
theologian in Catholicism Thomas
Aquinus. You see the well Aristotle also
did the same thing. When you go back
through an endless series of causes,
this cause, you know, p you're looking
for the primary cause, there's the error
to think that the primary in a series is
the same as as the sequence of the
series. No, the source of the series is
not the same as the series. It's of a
different class. In fact, it's a categor
category logic error to resume
that. There's one great big billiard
ball that created all the rest of the
billyard balls in the universe.
What makes the first billiard ball move
is a non-billyard ball. Wow. Right.
So trying to find God call God as the
primary cause of all causes
then is a logic error made by Aristotle
and made by most theologian sense.
The beginning of a series is something
that is not of that series. You got that
reality.
For this to exist, something that it is
not is the beginning of the series. So
in looking for the primary cause, you
don't look for a cause. You look instead
for the source. Huh? The source requires
no explanation because it is not in a
series of causes.
Oh, I'm knocking myself out here this
morning. What is this?
It's because I have to read my own
writing and it's on yellow paper. All
the things.
>> You know how
>> Okay, we'll get more ariodite again.
>> God is the a priority a priority
formless source of existence within all
form exist.
Within the illusion of form is nonform
which is the essence of form. Without
nonform no form could exist. That's true
or
>> can you repeat that?
>> No.
Um,
God is not within the preview of the
provable or the intellect. Resist
that which is provable by the intellect
or reason could by definition not be
God. Resist
the God that you can prove by the
intellect then cannot possibly be God
because that which is beyond the
intellect is not provable by the
intellect. So you would all you could
prove by the intellect is the concept of
God that you can prove with the
intellect.
For God to be God, it would have to meet
certain requirements. So you can prove
the intellectual position about God, but
that has nothing to do with the
existence of God.
Okay?
God is the source and essence of the
subjective state of Iess called
enlightenment. Read this.
So what the spiritual student is looking
for then is God imminent? God as the
self with a capital S. God as the
essence out of which one's own existence
is continuously
arising. didn't arise 75 years ago.
It's arising right this moment.
My birth is happening continuously.
My existence is continuously sustained.
Just like a water fountain holds up a
rubber ball. See, it's being held up
continuously. It isn't the water that
came out this faucet 8 minutes ago
that's holding up the ball. It's the
presence of God now that is holding up
the ball on top of the fountain. The
minute you shut off the fountain, the
ball drops.
Oh Lord. Amen.
Scared myself there.
That's why we call it the eye of the eye
because you're really talking the third
eye. You're really talking about the
third eye of the Buddha body, third eye
of the ethnic body. the realization
of the I as um anyway God is the radical
subjectivity of self-realization with a
capital S is it
all right so this is the this is the way
of uh that that
we're going to talk about the way
through the heart you know maybe the
lecture after Nick so if I can get
through that lecture
uh now we're preparing the the way
God is the radical subjectivity. So the
realization of the self is a radically
subjective state. That's why it's
difficult to see. We're so used to space
being around us. We don't notice space.
When you walk in room, you notice all
these objects. If I ask you how much
space was there, what space?
There isn't any space there. Nobody
noticed the space because we're so we
take for granted the presence of the
self without really realizing its true
nature.
God is descriptively
both imminent and transcendent.
And those two terms are merely
artifacts of vocabulary exist. There's
not two different gods, imminent and
transcendent.
Well, you think that's this sounds
trivial. This is a sophisticated
audience and this would seem obvious to
you, but there's a lot of world great
religion. There is no God imminent and a
God transcendent. So we can't say God is
both because to say both is already the
same logical error.
Okay.
The human experience of the presence of
God is the same in all ages, all
cultures, all localities resist.
Experience of the presence of God is
absolutely the same in everyone. You go
back in the ancient Aryan sages, their
description is the same.
You see, the reason we want to nail this
down is because anybody who anything
that dies from this is going to have to
explain themsel.
We will put them through the
Inquisition. We have our own little
rack.
God is in it and transcend it. Okay.
Thank you. All right.
The effect on human consciousness of the
experience of the presence of God is
subject subjectively transformative
and identical throughout human history
and is verifiable
and in the present time by a calibration
technique of level of consciousness
exist.
>> All right,
that's what brought up the negative
energy this morning. We already got hit
by it.
Truth then to claim itself as truth has
to withstand the test of truth. If you
sell me it floats, I want to put it in
water. If it sinks to the bottom, I want
my money back.
The Now listen to this one carefully.
Okay, this is going to be a long one.
Get ready. Okay,
>> here's a long one. The essence of God
does not include human frailties such as
partiality, controllingness,
duality,
judgmentalism, vindictive,
retaliation,
wrath, righteous anger, resentment,
vanity, limitation, arbitrariness,
revenge, jealousy,
vulnerability or locality. That is 100%
correct statement.
Well, that puts us in variance with a
couple thousand years of spiritual
religious tradition, don't it?
Let's do them once by one. The essence
of God does not include the human
frailties such as partiality. Resist.
Partiality is a frailty of the human
ego. Resist. For God to have partiality,
he couldn't be God. He'd have to be a
sort of don't.
All right.
God is not the essence of God does not
include judgmentalism. Resist
wrath,
righteous anger, vanity,
limitation,
partiality, location, and ethnic
favoritism. resist.
God has no favorite geography. Resist.
No holy lands.
>> Here, you're going to let everyone sit
down. You're going to they're going to
get tired of this.
>> All right, we're going to We're almost
done.
Uh
the variabilities of the depictions of
defininity of divinity reflect the
variabilities of human perception and
the human ego. resist.
When the obstacles of human mentation,
emotionality and ego structure from
which they arise are transcended.
The self with capital S is God imminent.
The divinity within shines forth as the
essence of one's own sense of eye. As
the self capital resist
the self shines forth just as the sun
shines forth when the clouds are
removed. Resist.
Okay.
God is the context and source of the
karmic unity of all of creation. Resist.
All right. So that's enough of an
exercise for this morning.
That should earn us breakfast in a space
in the
therefore the way to God is merely
through the affirmation of truth and not
to be distracted by these side avenues.
Um because what came up this morning
came up out of the collective
unconscious.
That was the collective unconscious of
the totality of the fear of God and
mankind resist. It was like
a ferocious fire going through the
nervous system. And I just intuited wow
that's what we brought up this morning
because this lecture what we're
challenging is you can see what we're
challenging correct
and the tenacious hole that has within
the history of mankind.
The reality of the truth of nature God
has remained the same throughout all
ages in all cultures. It's always been
described the same. Therefore, any
variations from it would have to require
some explanation and in understanding.
And with kinesiology, we've tracked down
the sources of error, you know,
historically in many different cultures
in various times. And the thing about
doing spiritual research is you come up
with astonishing discoveries that
nobody's discovered before. Why? Because
it's never been done before. It's the
first time a telescope has been
uh pointed at at the heavens and we
discovered there's galaxies out there
and all kinds of astonishing things.
I'm holding in mind a question. Resist.
Permissible. Resist.
Uhoh. I'm holding in mind a statement.
Resist. It's permissible um to
demonstrate it in front of this
audience. Resist. Oh well, we'll find
out that one later. Anyway, sometimes we
find out astonishing things and it says
no, not yet. I don't know why.
I guess other information has to be
provided first.
Um
so the lecture has been sort of
sequential preparation of an
understanding a way of approaching
spiritual reality a way of approaching
spiritual work
a way of transcending the ego by
understanding its nature and not by
attacking it.
Um and people are always asking in
letters you know how can I advance
myself spirit spiritually and the and
the basic essence of it is always the
same and that is one's devotion to the
truth.
One's devotion to the truth transcends
all obstacles.
Let's see if that's a fact. That's a
fact. wants devotion to the truth then
overcomes all obstacles
and um
and sometimes people will write a letter
also that they don't understand certain
things and because there's such a huge
volume of letters they can't all be
answered and u and so what we generally
say then is is a letter that most almost
over 90% of the questions that are being
presented resolve themselves with a f
little further a reflection
uh of the information that's been
provided. It takes a certain amount of
time to grow. You know what I'm saying?
And a lot of times people will come up
with a question that you know it took me
20 years of meditation to even get to
the edge of that answer and they want it
tomorrow. you know I say well now
so there's a certain maturity a certain
um in other words the growth factor you
know the growth factor and each person
evolves at their own
uh rate of development and that rate of
development is absolutely correct for
that person and that's why we got to
know resist
that's how we got to know this thank you
okay some individuals in the group could
be handled it 40% 50% 60%.
Okay. All right. So
therefore some preparation of
spiritually advanced work has to be done
um to become um
an intense spiritual aspirin.
There's a certain level at which the
desire to reach the ultimate state is
like a driving force that takes over
everything. At that point, you leave
much to the constonation of the world,
everything.
And they think you've lost your mind.
And um hopefully you have.
And uh it takes them years to recover.
They don't even some never recover. But
anyway, it's not comprehensible to the
ordinary person what could have happened
to you that made such a difference.
Even such a thing as an out-of- body
experience is not comprehensible. A lot
of people a near-death experience,
those flashes of stillness when you
suddenly feel the presence
are not comprehens comprehensible to the
inlet.
the state that came on
uh at age 36 or 37, I forget what it
was. Uh there's no there was no one to
speak to about it for 30 years. I mean,
who you going to talk to about it?
Nobody.
So
these states which are really really
inwardly private um become validated by
reading about them, knowing about them,
hearing other people speak of them. I
think each one of us uh when we share
our own spiritual experience strengthens
that of others that we share a
collective strength and and that
sharingness of strength and experience
uh reaffirms.
Why is that uh uh why does it work that
way? Because we live in a world in which
all such uh experience is negated. It's
negated and the validity of it is in
question
intrinsic to the nature of language
itself. Intrinsic to the language of
nature nature of science and logic.
Right now the god of our culture is
science. Um in ancient days man looked
to religion for answers looked to God
for answers.
Look to God for salvation.
after many centuries of studying the
sort of uh god of gods of negativity and
not getting too far with it uh and going
through the inquisition and various
other tough times
tough times. mankind uh be now looks to
science looks to science looks to the
future because logic says most of relig
you'll see is based on the history of
certain individuals experiences
uh thousands of years ago or perhaps
reinforced by in the last decades his
reaffirmations
but it very often ends up as um a great
emphasis on the irrelevant
You know, like the Buddha said, "They'll
make no images of me." And the Buddha
is, of course, the most frequently
created image on the planet. There's
more Buddhist soul than any other image
or statue of anything.
Oh, golly.
So there's a great deal of uh emphasis
on history, location,
uh things that are really tribal,
ethnic, cultural
peculiarities then become in included in
these religions
and now become part of sacred scripture
and religious practice.
um to the point that it eclipses the
truth out of which it ostensibly
originally arose.
You know, whether you wear a turban or
you don't wear a turban. What the hell's
that got to do with the presence of God
in the absolute reality of infinite
reality? I don't know. But in today's
world, I just wouldn't wear a turban and
trying to get on Transorld Airlines. I
mean, it's just not as it's just not
smart. You know what I mean?
I mean, I I prayed for his rights. He's
got his rights. And yeah, if they want
to put it down to the game, I'll go out
there and cheer for them. But it isn't
really using your head. Well, the idea
is that God will be offended if you
don't wear a turban. Is that the idea of
it? What is it? God hates people without
a haircut or what? What is it?
In other words, that which is totally
irrelevant to the reality of God and the
presence of God as the truth within
yourself
is the point of emphasis. The whole
point of emphasis now is whether you
wear a turban or you don't wear a
turban. You know I mean how ridiculous
can you get? You know what I'm talking
about?
Whether you eat meat on Fridays, whether
you eat fish on Fridays.
I used I grew up dreading to to to eat
meat by mistake on a Friday. What if I
eat a hamburger and then suddenly
realize God is Friday
high which is like Catholic you know.
Anyway, in those days all such things,
you know, you forgot a day of
obligation. Holy mackerel. You know, I
mean, and I've already related to you
have the dreadfulness of confession on
Saturday afternoon.
And I would go for confession for those
who haven't heard it, as late as
possible on Saturday afternoon because
you weren't supposed to sin between
confession and having communion, holy
communion. So, the trick was you
arranged to go for confession, you know,
father, I've sinned, etc.
and uh as late as possible on Saturday
and you go to the earliest mass you can
get to on Saturday and quick after
communion and now if you now if you sin
it's not going to be so bad I mean you
made it you made it
and I told you the dreadful morning on
the way to church and it was probably
1930 something rather and here was this
giant billboard with a Jansson swimming
suit ad and here's this voluuptuous
blonde and this swimming suit and a
sinful thought began knocking at the
at age 12. You know what I'm talking
about? Testosterone raging through your
bloodstream. And there's this 32 foot
long lady and I'm on my way to
communion.
Life was a nightmare. I'll tell you,
Christianity in the 30s was scary. You
know, it's
it's no wonder I became an atheist. I
mean any sensible intelligent person
would become an atheist and that's what
I did
just the constant fear of guilt. It
isn't, you know, it isn't just guilt.
It's the fear of guilt, you know. Uh,
and many people as they get more
spiritually evolved, they're, you know,
they're not really really afraid of
consequences. They're afraid of things
out there. They're afraid of their own
inner reaction to it. If I know this,
I'm going to be hung with guilt. You
know what I'm saying?
Shall I steal the pen from the bank or
not? Well, if I do, I'm going to be
stuck with guilt. Every time I look at
the pen, I'm going to feel a pang of
guilt. It's not worth the guilt.
Then where you become inwardly you you
become your own guru within because now
you're really on the when you don't
steal a pen because you're afraid of
you're afraid of your own sense of guilt
that would arise as a result you're on
your on your way. You are responsible
for yourself morally, ethically and
spiritually and you've reached integrity
because retigrity is always blaming it
on something out there. Once you cross
over integrity, calibrate level 200. Now
you you own the responsibility
and uh you begin to see the source of
guilt is going to arise out of yourself
not because there's a spot on your soul
and God's going to punish you. So
between late Saturday afternoon and
Sunday morning, there was the fear that
this sin would appear and it was
explained by the by the preacher that it
it would appear as a spot on your soul.
So, I walked around dreading this
invisible soul where all these spots
would be appearing
and God spotting all these black spots
on your soul as you walk by, you know,
and of course that would lead to a fear
of judgment day and the fearful God of
traditional religion which everyone
fears
until they realize the true nature of
God.
So we should take a break. Uh give God a
rest and u
and I think we might do some questions
on it because some people are doing
kinesiology had some questions. We'll do
some questions if there's any doubt
about the validity of what we did the uh
the degree of truth that we reach.
You know what we did this morning is
really never been done in the history of
mankind. No group has ever collectively
simultaneously
verified in the most arodite way we know
to verify truth
the reality of God and the spiritual
reality
which we're all seeking. It's never been
done before
and I thank you all for the effort. So
we'll take a break
the black holes and reemerges new
universes
in different time dimensions just
uh
if we don't resume in time we'll be late
for
We'll be late for the lunch break.
Oh god.
Yeah, we'll wait till everybody settle.
Okay.
Well, we have some fun questions this
morning. Um
there there there was there there was an
old joke.
>> Yep.
There was an old joke many years ago.
And here here we have this joke
reappearing.
There was an old joke we used to tell in
college. You know, the student jumps up
at the back of the
question period. He says, "Teacher, did
you say the universe is coming to an end
in 50 billion years?" He said, "Yes."
The prince says, "Yes." He is. Thank
God. I thought you said 50 million.
We have that question in new form. Some
people say that a large planet, planet
X, is on a trajectory into the solar
system. Let's see if that's a fact.
That's a fact that people say that
resist.
>> There is a planet X on its way into our
solar system. Resist. It will
cause major Earth changes. Resist.
It won't cause.
Planet X is on a trajectory into the our
solar system. That's a fact. Resist.
It will cause major earth changes.
Resist
for the future.
If it continues its present trajectory,
it would hypothetically
cause major earth changes. Resist. No,
it won't.
Okay. As I say,
if All right. Even if this is so
at its present rate projected into the
future, we're talking millions of years
resistant. As I say, we can relax and uh
finish making payments on your car.
There's plenty of time.
Yeah.
Well, there's a lot of fun questions. If
any more questions you wind up, we'll do
them verbally, too. Uh, one interesting
question was, how do you get through the
door of the 500s? And that is actually a
chapter that I'm uh have have been
writing on. It has to do with um how do
you transcend um the experience of
reality without deciphering without
channeling it through the intellect?
Well, the 500s,
where's our calibrated levels of
consciousness? We need that just for
reference.
Yeah. Well, we'll just put that on
there. Yeah, that's the one we want.
Um
how do we get
Hey, you got it.
>> First crack here. Let me see.
>> We have some kind of
angle.
What's happening here?
>> Something mysterious is happening.
How is it going to work?
>> I'll figure it out.
Money. Put money on it.
There you go.
It can't be doing what it's doing. It's
not possible.
>> I have it angled so that you can see it
and
>> Oh, don't angle it. Let's unangle it.
Got to unangle it. How did you angle it?
>> Because you can't see the
>> Yeah. Well, no. Reduce the angle. That's
all. There you got it.
Okay.
>> Well, I don't know. These are new fangle
gadgets and
>> Oh, everyone's
>> I don't know how they work anyway.
>> Forget it.
>> All right, we don't care about it
anyway.
>> Where is the 500s?
Here it is. Uh-oh. What does it say
there?
>> Oh, that's the doorway to the 500s.
Reason will only take you so far.
And then
lovingness,
devotion,
reverence
leads to an inner revelation.
And traditionally
the methods of doing that, the way of
doing it
has been
prayer, devotion, meditation,
the appreciation of beauty.
This morning I was playing um
incredibly beautiful uh CD.
Whatever happened to that CD?
Oh,
is it playable?
>> No, we don't know yet.
>> Uh yeah. Anyway, if that can play, it'd
be fine. Um at the end of it is music
that is so incredibly beautiful that if
I didn't turn it off, I would have
gotten here this morning.
Literally,
it was so It takes you into
Oh, that must be around 700. Let's see.
That must be around 700. Okay. Um, so
Incredible Beauty is another way. Um,
>> uh, it's a tape that, um,
Niko and Betty gave us.
Um, ashaya and um but then at the end of
it it goes off into some incredibly
beautiful music after the chanting stops
and the music is so incredible that you
transcend. So
transcend the intellect.
When the hair goes up in the back of
your head and you begin to weep with
beauty, you're over 500
because the intellect doesn't go that
far.
you have to leave the 400s.
When I traveled in Europe, I traveled
from one cathedral to the other and um
go from Westminister Abbey to uh
Shark to um
Notredam.
So the trip through Europe is is from
one cathedral to the other.
Um,
people said, "Why do you plan your trip
to Europe based on the cathedrals?"
Because that to me is the epitome of
their civilization. Great cathedrals
all calibrated around 700.
When you walk into Shark and if the the
him choir is practicing at the same
time, it's difficult to keep walking
because you almost swoon with beauty.
You turn around, you look at the blue
window.
The rear sh is a very famous blue. It's
never been reduplicated. And
it's so exquisitly beautiful that you
almost go weak with it. So
that's one way to transcend 500 in the
400s is
the pursuit of beauty. Um
the chanting of that let's calibrate. I
didn't calibrate that.
Uh, permission to calibrate that.
If I over 500, 550, 560, 570, 580, 590,
600. Oh,
over 650, over 680.
You do that.
>> She's doing that. Stop that.
>> Let's do it again.
over 760
ohm over 780
over 790.
This is over 800 of the presence of God
within
over 800.
There's another way over 500.
Let's all do an omen.
Oh,
I want to get the calibration of the
zoom is over 600, 650, 700, 720, 740,
760.
The zoom is over 750, 760.
That is over is 750.
So that's the experience of what 750 is
like.
You're walking through the woods by
yourself and suddenly time comes to a
stop.
The incredible beauty of everything
shines forth. You look at every
everything is absolute incredible
beauty.
That happens in the high five00s too. It
makes it very hard to function because
you're always breaking out tears
and
high 500s difficult to function in the
world. The cryingness of the saint.
People who live in monasteries is
traditional. Um at a certain stage it's
hard to stop. You can cry for a couple
years.
I cried for several years. It was
impossible. I'd be in an airport and a
couple would sit there and they'd look
at each other with a glance of love and
it would just
that if they weren't loving was okay. I
can make it.
She looks at him like that look and wow
I'm gone.
Incredible beauty does the same thing,
right? We've all been at a symphony or a
concert or
uh something by Pacini.
The Mimi is dying in Pacini, you know,
labe
all of a sudden
there's a silence and then suddenly the
orchestra comes in with a chime like
like that and you realize maybe he sings
out and God just goes right.
What is that note of M Pini? Is that
over 500? 560 580 580.
>> It blows right out. Um,
so I still cry in La Boy and um I've
seen La Boy many times. Um, but when he
realizes
Marello, what his name is, realizes that
Mimi has just died,
then you hear like the soaring of the
soul
as it soarses.
And uh, so we'll stop talking about
that. The voice won't continue.
So the incredible beauty shines forth
and uh
we have a lecture after this one on
devotion. How we're going to get through
that I have no idea because this kind of
thing happens all the time. But um
the presence of beauty
devotion to that beauty, the
what then becomes revealed is the
divinity, the exquisite perfection of
the presence of God manifesting.
And now you're allowed to see that
beauty.
Beauty is different than pretty. Um
the revelation is that the essence of
beauty itself, the perfection, the
radiance, the energy of beauty is your
awareness. It's your awareness of the
presence of God within all that exists.
As that becomes permanent, you see it
everywhere. You walk down an alleyway in
the city of New York
which the world would see in a very
derogatory
manner
and it looks like a painting by a French
impressionist. Here's the garbage can
and here's the dead rat
and here's the tangled measure of so and
so and it's just incredibly beautiful.
It's like a canvas, a perfect canvas in
which the intrinsic beauty of everything
shines forth because there is no
superimposition of intellectualism,
goodness, badness, ideas of beauty and
ugliness.
So beauty
because beauty is inherent in
everything.
And in the book I'm finishing I talk
about Kleenex then and uh seeing the
beauty of um when when you're going to
the bathroom and you put and you see a
piece of Kleenex sitting there and it
suddenly strikes you. It's incredible
beauty. You know you're getting there.
First time happened to you was an air it
was in an airplane and you're sitting
there doing your business and you look
at here's this Kleenex and it's like
this incredible I described you before
like a Georgia O'Keeffe painting you see
the sheer essence of beauty in all that
exists.