Nothing is causing anything else.
Nothing is causing anything.
All comes into existence by divine
ordination.
Each thing expresses the fulfillment of
its essence.
In the unfolding, everything is at its
state of perfection at this moment.
This is a perfect flower unfolding.
It is still a perfect flower unfolding
perfectly. Still unfolding perfectly.
So you've received the perfection of all
of creation.
When you see the perfection of all of
creation,
you see that the criminal is being the
perfect criminal as he goes bang.
He is the perfect criminal, is he not?
You can be it and say, "Oh, but
shouldn't this world be peaceful without
criminals?"
But then what would you do without
criminals?
>> You'd have to create a whole another
world in which there's lots of criminals
and horrible people and stuff,
wouldn't you?
If the purpose of the world is an
infinite
choices, if it's sort of a purgatorial
paradise,
if you destroy the quality of the world
of it is, you'd have to go create a
whole another one.
Where can you walk into a hail of
bullets unless there's the war? Right?
How could you learn to forgive if there
were nothing to forgive? Right?
Of course, as the mira course of
miracles points out, once you see it
correctly, there is nothing to forgive.
And that dissolves the whole issue.
Nobody's going to eat those flower
petals. I'll eat them. Okay.
The personality I grew up with was
aesthetic.
Aesthetic. Introvert.
Introvert. Aesthetic.
Ectomorph.
Ectomorphs are thin and nervous. Don't
eat much.
and they shut off the lights all the
time. Save electric.
People visit you and say, "Look, I
brought you lunch." You say, "I don't
need lunch. I've got a banana in the
refrigerator.
That's enough till tomorrow, isn't it?"
So, h
I wanted to complete what we were
talking about this morning.
that you know all that needs to be known
for the whole way
because you may consider yourself even a
beginner
and find yourself suddenly and
unexpectedly at the final door. Can
happen just like that and it can happen
happen from the pits of hell.
You went to a couple lectures, somebody
told you way to meditate. Next thing you
know,
there you are.
It's never too soon to be prepared
because the doorway opens and if you
fail it,
the consequence is rather severe. May
take many a lifetime to recover.
One was presented with the opportunity
of being at one with God and once
said no to it.
It's crushing crushing.
Therefore
to know
what you need to know.
He would say why tell us this early in
the game. It's not early in the game.
It's not early in the game for anybody
here.
Nobody was early in the game would even
be here.
Would scare the pants off of them.
That's why I open all my books with a
dedication Gloria and excelsius deal. If
you can get past that page,
then the book's for you.
And sort of a qualifier.
Glory and exaltious deal. My god, man.
What is this guy? Some kind of a weirdo?
Take this book away, Genevieve.
No, only so I already have a guard at
the beginning of the book. See,
and also a caveat.
Those who are spiritually timid
or committed to some rigid religion
might be well upset by the contents of
what follows and it would be advisable
for them not to read it.
Although many of the things could be
considered conflictual, I think we've
contextualized them in such a way that
they are not conflictual. You
understand? And we just discovering that
there's multiple heavens.
So all you have to do is change the word
exclusive and you're okay with
everybody.
All right? So there comes a time when
one is confronted
with the knowingness. With the
knowingness it's all non-verbal.
The higher demands are all nonverbal.
There's nobody there. There's no words.
There's no concepts. But there is a
knowingness.
And up comes the knowingness.
The last and final step is facing you.
And the requirement
is to die. H that is the requirement.
Unless the fear of absolute
death arises, that isn't the final door
because you still have hope left.
Yeah. But when that is eliminated, then
there's no way out and one is confronted
with
the absoluteness.
The things that come that are operative
at that point
would be the energy field of the teacher
in whom you have great faith. It tells
you how to walk through that because
that teacher has walked through it.
Therefore, the conviction of the truth
of the inner experience
is a very firm
rock-like and you feel its
rock-likeness.
It was rock-like
that knowingness still because few go
through everyone is going through leaves
that conviction there.
There's that rocklike knowingness to
walk through all fear no matter what.
But the fear is quite intense
because it is death.
It is death.
And something else is needed
within yourself
already exists
that which is willing to lay down its
life for God.
That's not something you acquire,
something you have to develop.
It's something you locate within
yourself
because that question will come up over
and over again in the spiritual pathway.
Am I willing to surrender this to God?
Am I willing to surrender that to God?
And you will then locate within yourself
that there is a capacity to lay anything
down for God.
If Krishna Buddha Jesus stood here and
said, "Would you lay down your life for
me?"
You would say, "Yes, oh Lord." Do you
find within yourself
that which would say yes, oh Lord, to
that request?
If you do that, you will finesse that
knowingness from yourself
because it is already within the self.
It's wise to come to know that within
yourself to know that it's there and
then you can call upon it because now at
the final door you have the profound
strength and conviction. That is
strength.
The strength of the truth of God
affirmed by those who have walked
through it.
That's the pathway of non-duality.
And
but then combined with it is the power
of devotion.
So the heart and the mind are one at
that point.
The devotion
that within you which is willing to lay
down its life for God,
locate that within yourself. Now
when you don't need it
because the final moment arises
unannounced,
unannounced.
No way of knowing.
In fact, quite unexpected.
You're driving down the highway.
Suddenly you see the come car coming at
you. There's a loud screaming metal. You
feel an agonizing pain in the your neck
as your neck breaks
you. There's the moment right there. It
just opened itself. Unexpected,
unprepared for.
Nobody said meditate for the next 3
hours. It's going to arrive at noon.
You're on your way to pick up the kids
from school.
Unexpected suddenness.
You hear of a new meditative technique,
you thought that sounds kinky. I think
I'll try it.
Anja buuja buuja anjabuja anabuja. And
all of a sudden it opens up. It's just
so there's no warning. That's why I tell
you now early in the game. It's not
really it's late in the game.
Delayed. I should have told you the
first lecture, but I thought my sc
would have scared everybody out. Yeah, I
better save that for number 12. You know
what I mean? But you're going to have to
die in the end. No, no, I signed up for
that course.
That's what the feeling is. Because the
ego is stronger, it's it defies
everything. The ego is just unbelievable
the tricks and the and it's learned this
over you know huge expanses speaking
from a temporal perceptual viewpoint
it's learned it over huge expanses of
time how to survive
and now
it faces extin extinction
in this particular consciousness
and it struggles for survival Without
me, you will die.
That's what it's going to tell you.
Without me, I am your life. I am the
source of your life.
I'm the core of your existence.
Surrender me and you're dead.
And there's where you need the
conviction.
You reach within yourself.
For thee, oh Lord, do I lay down my life
itself.
And then you summon forth the very core
of devotion
because there is within you already
that which loves God more than the
personal self.
It already exists.
and you summon it forth.
So the power of devotion is the pathway
the uh the pathway of devotion the
pathway of non-duality
and the pathway of service to others as
you saw all these people come up that it
is their joy to serve you just it is my
joy to serve you.
It brings me in ecstatic state which I
can't allow to develop
or this talk will end.
I tried to stay away from the devotional
and cuz it brings all of it to a close.
All right, we wanted to answer some
questions now today.
Um, and I do want to thank all the
people who work round the clock 7 days a
week who call you or you can call them
at any time who will drop everything and
do anything for you.
And they may seem like trivial things,
but when you're
in need need of an espresso, you need an
espresso.
There's some very funny questions here.
I don't understand that one.
I don't understand that one either.
All right. So, somebody asked about the
course of miracles. You know, there's a
number of pathways. All of them
terrific.
The 12 steps are perfect.
In fact, to reach enlightenment, all you
need is step three and step 11. And the
12 step course. Third step is
willingness to surrender your life to
God. And the 11th step is sought through
prayer and meditation to ask God's will
for me. Those two is all you need the
whole way.
Those two will suffice. There's only
about the course of miracles we said to
calibrate around 600. It comes from I
think what would be called celestial
realms.
Uh probably about the same level as uh
the white brotherhood. And uh so the
higher celestial realms have contact
with humans
special arrangements usually a karmic uh
commitment and agreement.
The only thing the only thing that I
object to in the course of miracles is
the one is the one lesson
uh trust your brother
that has to be taken with a proviso.
You heard what I said this morning.
>> Trust your brother.
I think it's true in the celestial
realm. I don't think it's too trustable
in this realm. That one has to be
modified for this world. Yes, that's the
only error in it. You know, of course,
the miracle didn't calary to thousand,
calary to 600. So, you know, it's not
all that can be said about everything.
Yes. Because the downside of the
lovingness
is that um
not being able or willing or the two
together to see that the tiger if
provoked can still kill you, you know,
and to still love the person despite
that. despite that.
So, I'd say trust your brother
and keep an eye on HIM
on a certain level. However, it is true
that people will rise to be
that which you see them as
people will rise to the expectation. So
on a certain level it is true and on the
highest level of course it's true
because it doesn't make any sense.
There's no me to trust and no you to
trust because that is
viewing separation as a reality. There
is no me that trusts you because there's
only the one self. So the course is that
that's the only quiggly part I would say
about the course.
I have to stand up all this time. I'm
going to fall down here in a minute.
That's cuz I have to read. I can't do
two things at once. Stand up
and read. I can sit down and read or I
can stand up. But to stand up and read
is difficult. Oh my goodness. All right,
I better start talking fast.
Oh,
all that I teach is
experiential.
Nothing that I teach is from elsewhere
other than that which I quote as being
from elsewhere.
Yeah,
I have permission to ask this question.
Resist. The answer is yes. Resist. Okay.
So
the conviction, the conviction then the
power, the vibration of a teacher who
has experienced it the whole way is
and that it is the absolute
subjectivity
of self-realization. See
self-realization
which is another term one might use
is radically subjective.
It is radical subjectivity.
The realization of the truth of the
mystic.
The truth of God imminent
rather than transcendent.
The mystic is the one who experiences
the reality of divinity
as the core and the essence of life,
the core and essence of one's existence,
one's creation
and the reality of that which you are.
It reveals itself
and that
brings about the absoluteness
of the certainty
which is the source of the vibrational
frequency.
The so-called grace of the guru is
nothing but
the vibrational frequency of the
absolute certainty
because it is that absolute certainty
that is needed at the great and final
moment
the guru that you picture at that point.
It better not calibrate 180. I'll
truth goes for a big voice boy ain't
going to give it away.
>> So all right. Uhhuh.
Now I think we've already explained um
actually with all these questions here
we've already explained them all. Only
you don't realize that we've explained
them all.
Now we really need this calibrated scale
of consciousness again to answer some of
these questions.
Um
as we said the numeric scale is not a
better than scale.
It's each each level is perfect for its
assignment.
The scale below it would be deficient.
the scale above it would not even make
it attractive or interesting. So it has
to be something to do your excellent
best
is to be at that which you are
calibrated for. Now the movement of the
level through the levels of calibrations
has to do with
spiritual realization and work and the
evolution of consciousness
as it is potentiated by your own
commitment.
The spiritual pathway is really a way of
contextualizing your life. It's not a
matter of where anyone is on a scale.
Besides, as I've told you,
the doorway can open at any time.
You think, well, I got to go through all
this here. I ain't even in bliss yet.
How could I get enlightened?
Because you can go from here all the way
to there. Tenth of a second.
It was a tenth of a second.
It was an eternity
of agony.
Eons.
The lower depths of hell are like the
higher levels beyond all time.
Alwayness. The alwaysness.
The unendingness,
the agony is forever
and there is no hope.
And all last vestages of hope are
removed.
And now you know you're in for the real
agony.
After an eon or so,
suddenly
the door opens.
Just don't think just cuz you're in hell
that it can't happen.
Moments of hell, moments of agony,
moments of doubt, moments of anger. The
doorway can open at any time. All the
spiritual work that you do then prepares
for the final pathway
happily.
Usually it is more gradual person
becomes more and more loving more and
more forgiving.
uh usually it's rather gradual
and those states also as I pointed out
have their vulnerability
in the 500s one's vulnerability is one's
naive
you can be blissed out in a very high
state and then also
get hit by that which is non integrous
is in an unprepared area and crashed
down again and now it's horrible because
you've been in a higher state.
All right. So, nevertheless, the karmic
merit that you have earned through
commitment and devotion to spiritual
inner work etc.
It comes to your rescue
happily.
The way through then is is straight to
face whatever is coming up. Surrender it
to God. Surrender up your reservations
about it.
Whatever is required. The way is
straight through. And as you get to each
level, each level is capped by a
consideration.
Each level feels good as you emerge into
it.
But then as you float up through that
level,
the reason that 500 is not 600 is
between 500 and 600
there's dualities
holding you into that position.
So on the one hand it feels incredible.
The move from here to here, each move up
is incredible. But each each level
itself then represents a limitation of
that which is beyond it.
So I think
a great guru at a thousand
is marvelous to the viewpoint of a
populace where 85% is below even
contemporary
as compared to the possibilities of the
spiritual universe. It's probably
kindergarten.
And is that
whatever my awareness might be?
I'm sure it's of a kindergarten level to
higher energies. You know, when we say
an archangel is 50,000 and over,
what could we possibly be? Even if in
the so in the view of other people who
are not as evolved the college education
seems you know pretty impressive but to
a postd doctoral researcher
doctor 8 is just you know jacks for
openers.
So
everything therefore is relative is
significant depends on how you
contextualize it.
We all um are grateful and thankful that
we are on a spiritual pathway. That is
the most difficult task of all that
people think in terms of calibration.
Now the the calibration these are just
the automatic consequences.
If you head due east and keep your
compass in this direction, sooner or
later you're going to pass this island
and that that island and eventually
you're going to get your goal. The
hardest thing about all of spirituality
is to get your compass set on a
spiritual goal. 85% of the population
sneers at it, right? It's just
ridiculous. It's absurd and etc. To even
be on the spiritual pathway is already
the greatest karma there is. That is the
greatest gift. The rest is automatic
because once you get bit by the bug,
you don't have much choice about it.
Once you get bit by the spiritual bug,
the way home is certain. You know, you
may get lost here and there for a few
lifetimes or wandering around. But
that's irrelevant
because the the pathway is going to pull
you. So we said you're not propelled by
your past, you're attracted by your
future. And you set your future by your
choice and design and by your spiritual
agreement.
So what happens then? And of course in
quantum mechanics, you know, there's no
past, present or future.
There is no such a thing as a sequence
of past, present, and future. In the
infinite quantum potentiality,
the future precedes the present.
You understand what I'm saying?
Because you've already chosen the future
and activated it in the now. The future
is what's acting activating you now.
You understand?
>> Okay.
So everyone here is being pulled by the
infinite potentiality which you have
already chosen and committed to or you
wouldn't be here.
You'd be at the ball game.
So everyone should relax that the way is
certain. Enlightenment is certain for
everybody here or you wouldn't be here.
Huh?
The future then is what is activating
you in the present.
Huh? That make sense now?
>> Because of what you've already chosen.
You've already chosen that out of the
quantum potentiality. You have an
infinite number of choices. But you've
chosen that.
That is now what is attracting you. like
a magnet to the future,
dragging you through all that you have
to go through,
giving up chocolate and everything.
I gave up chocolate for God.
That's I got this halo.
I remember when I gave up chocolate for
God.
Totally let it go. Thank God it was
gone.
I was free as a bird. I never thought of
chocolate. I didn't want chocolate. The
heck with chocolate.
>> I had a whole bunch of people out from
the course of miracles to a place that I
was staying at at the time and big
place. And guess what? They brought
big sheet cakes of chocolate cake.
Chocolate. I had chocolate everywhere.
When I didn't want chocolate, didn't
need chocolate. Couldn't care less about
chocolate.
And I've lived in a chocolate world ever
since. So
I don't need or want chocolate.
I'm the side boy at home. There's three
or four different kinds of chocolate.
And guess what Miss Lovely made for me
this weekend?
Chocolate fudge.
So
what you let go of comes comes into you.
And and that's the trouble with
abundance. You see
that's the trouble with abundance is uh
when you don't want anything anymore
there there it just pours in from all
over.
Okay. So, this question has arisen
before. I think I already answered it
earlier today that the ego can grab on
to the numeric scale and think, well,
I'm 480 and they're 460, so I'm better.
But, you know, the ego can do that with
anything. And it does do that with
everything all the time. That's the
quality of the ego, which you then
project onto everything. And of course
we can do it on a scale of consciousness
but we can do it on anything else. So
that's just a propensity of the of the
ego and one of the things we have to
relinquish is the desire to be better
than others because
there is no such thing and better in
what meaning of the word better etc.
Okay. Are there spiritual differences
between men and women?
Oh my, this is a damn
leave this one right there.
Oh, here was a springer. Honey, did you
know this was in here?
Well,
Okay,
>> I'm allowed to ask this question.
There are spiritual differences between
men and women. He said, "No, no
differences."
Not. Yeah. You know, the essential
reality obviously would have to be the
same. However, the way they manifest
tends to be perhaps different because it
reflects cultural influences.
It is permissible in our culture for
women to be intuitive
to call upon the nonlinear side of their
awareness.
It is not so okay for men to do that.
Is not so okay. And um
a man has to be somewhat more evolved to
give himself permission
uh to call upon his intuitive side, you
know. So in our culture,
the woman is more free to be intuitive
and therefore she perfects perfects that
side. I think she perfects that side.
As a psychiatrist, I'm speaking now. She
perfects that side
before the man does.
That's a fact. Yeah. The man who is
mature and not challenged by the
feminine
begins to then look at her as a teacher
of the intuitive side of life
just as she looks to him to the doing
this side of of success in the world and
all.
So she learns traits that were once
considered masculine and he learns
traits that were once considered
feminine. The secure adult, the secure
male uh
acknowledges
that quality, in fact calls upon it and
admires it. He says, "Wow, that must be
terrific to just know something out of
the blue like that. How do you know
that?" She, "I don't know. I just know
it." He says, "Wow, that's pretty cool."
You know, and he begins to see that it's
perhaps a valuable tool, especially when
she's been right six or eight times. and
he's
he's lost on every single stock he
bought. And
honey, I don't think that company's
going to hold up. But his reason tells
him it will. She says, "I don't know. I
just get a funny feeling that's not
going to work out."
So he begins to see that she has some
kind of a other avenue of knowingness
and knowledge and he begins to admire
that and say how do you get to be that
way? And so he begins to listen to her
and she teaches him then how that
happens and he begins to respect it and
develop that in his own in his own self.
And so you have the amalgamation then of
the feminine and the masculine on the
psychological level within the mature
individual of either sex. Each side
begins to admire the other and say,
"Wow, I see the advantage of that. Teach
me how that works." So
in the end, the man and the woman admire
and support each other. As I say, I
think their qualities spring forth
depending on the particular culture.
uh they don't calibrate differently.
They are the same.
Uh
and you can take um
you can view things differently than I
do.
Everyone has a right to be wrong.
Now the question is the woman's
intuition is sometimes wrong. Well,
sure. We all get hunches that are turn
out to be incorrect, you know. Anyway,
that is I think a quality that we learn
in spiritual work, you know, uh a
sensitivity to an inner knowingness
and that again is a skill. I think a
skill
which is learned from experience.
Some of these questions we've answered
many times before. If you read the book,
they easily answered himself.
Isn't the cal the calibrated level of
consciousness due to the belief system
of the person involved? And actually the
answer is no. And we've demonstrated
this many times because you don't have
to express what it is. You can hold it
silently. And you'll see I often do it
with her. I'll say what I'm holding in
mind is is a fact. She doesn't know what
I'm holding in mind. So obviously her
belief system can have nothing to do
with the answer.
Um
we're talking about condundolini energy.
the spiritual energy as it begins to
flow up as you get in the into the 500s,
you feel this energy running up your
spine and um it's exquisite.
It flows up
well in this case it flew up it it
flowed up the whole back. Although in
the spiritual esoteric literature it's
described as
running up a special channel the sashumi
or some fancy name.
Uh and then anyway the energy is
exquisite and in that that's usually the
high 500s and um this aura of love is
very powerful.
It also is capable of um paranormal
phenomena what the roll calls paranormal
and that may last for some years.
In this case it lasted I don't know
maybe 5 years or something and which one
is clairvoyant clar audient
um you have what whatever is that called
where you touch this you know exactly
who it is and why they put it there and
you know the name of the person and you
see them. What is that called something?
But those various things come and go and
uh they're surprising at first. You can
u fix electrical equipment. Picture it
as being fixed. It fixes uh turn strobe
lights on and off. All kinds of fantasy
tricks with it and and um but those u
come and go. Those are phenomena of the
field. Also the miraculous is common
place. The miraculous is continuous
almost. what you hold in mind manifests
and healings take place. All kinds of
miraculous phenomena
and it lasted uh five or six years. It
was continuous, quite strong. And that
was the same time this energy was
flowing up
flowing into the brain and exquisite
pleasure pleasurable sensation in the
body and in the brain and it would just
flow down and then as I've described
elsewhere for some unknown reason it
would flow out usually to some disaster
in the area and this like the healing
energy would flow into the disaster and
the cars wheels would still be turning
and uh this energy would flow into it
and have profound effects. The
miraculous was uh the consequence of
that field.
It has nothing to do with me or anybody
else or you. Somebody says so and so
performs miracles. So and so doesn't
perform miracles. The field does it
doesn't the field doesn't consult you at
all. It just does what it does without
asking.
You know what I And the roses would
suddenly turn red and you just witness
it. You know, you don't see it. You
don't think, "Oh, gee, I wish those
roses could turn red and they make it
happen." No, no, this thing. It all
happens of its own. Those are the
so-called classic cities spelled s i d h
i s of which one is best. Oh, I forgot
to forewarn people about that also. Not
to become enamored of that, not to think
it's you. When it's real, you realize
it's I mean it it it's very apparent
that it's not you. It's the field and
the field is not the personal self.
There's no valition valition at all. One
doesn't decide, gee, I think I'll help
this poor old crippled lady get healed
and walk up and walk away. It doesn't
happen that way. You're sitting there
looking at the clock. The old lady sits
down. She's all crippled up, can barely
walk. This energy just does what it
does. She gets up smiling and walks away
fine. Nobody asked you at all.
You were not consulted. So
those are the cities but they can be
pursued for their own glamour for their
own if the ego I don't see how that
would happen because they don't really
happen till your ego is pretty much gone
but uh I I guess in some the residual
ego grabs onto this and begins to try to
own it and and become a professional u
at at the thing anyway. So those things
come and go and they're not to be uh
they're just to be witnessed and if
you're curious about it, you can ask
somebody who's been through it and
they'll just tell you it comes and goes.
It's very uh entertaining while it
happens. I mean, it's really
entertaining. Uh
you can drive into a big parking lot and
know exactly where the one space is,
right? You can park in front of Lincoln
Center and find the one only parking
space on the street. Right in front of
Lincoln Center, number one, right next
to Lincoln Center. Probably the only
parking space within a square mile of
New York City. Then you just go and park
right there. It's like nothing. You knew
it all along.
Uh Course of Miracles tends to lead you
into that state, by the way. Okay. Are
there any uh other courses similar to
the course of miracles? The only reason
I mention that is because I'm familiar
with the course. I'm familiar with of
course many other ways. All the
spiritual pathways take you through, you
know, the the legitimate ones take you
through the same thing. Whether it's
unity or science of mind, they're all
dealing in basic spiritual realities.
Now the thing about a spiritual reality
is not so much what what the statement
of the reality is but the practice of
doing it.
So that brings us to the next most
important thing.
H radical devotional non-duality.
Gee that's impressive isn't it?
Radical
devotional non-duality. Oh boy. Oh yeah.
What is really implied is that the
commitment reaches such an intensity
that it's nonstop. People say, "How do
you really reach a very advanced state
of consciousness?"
The desire, the the commitment seems to
increase in intensity.
And then there's a point where you
realize
that you are going to sacrifice anything
that is required and you're going to
make a run for it.
All obstacles are put aside.
This is when the family is certain
you've gone crazy.
You leave everything
and now the spiritual work is continuous
nonstop. There's a fixity of focus.
People say I've tried this method, that
method, and no, they didn't try it. They
dabbled at it. Because if you do it
continuously with an absoluteness, a
ferocity,
then you'll transcend whatever level
that is that you were at when you
started that.
If you absolutely and totally surrender
every thought, feeling, attitude,
positionality as it arises,
you see it arising out of nothingness.
You see it cresting as a thought, idea,
feeling and the willingness to surrender
that to God as it arises.
First the wave comes up and it completes
the whole story.
Pearl Oano, how you got run over by the
car, tears come to your eyes as you
remember. You got this whole s story
here.
The willingness to let go all that
sentimentality,
all that ming around in the past.
willingness to let it go. So the story
shortens. You start to think of poor old
Ricky getting hit by the car. And then
you start to think of poor Ricky. Then
when you get more to the present
before it's Ricky the good old golden
retriever, it's just dogness starts
coming up. And then before it's even
dog,
you can feel it's an energy potential
coming out of a source of thinkingness
itself.
Out of the void, out of the nothingness,
out of the blankness, out of the silence
arises this like fountain of
thinkingness which gradually takes its
form as a thought, then an image, good
old dog, good old rover, and then the
whole sad story evolves out of it.
When you ride the crest of the wave,
it's pretty much like surfing. You stay
on the crest of the wave. If you get
behind the crest of the wave, you get
drowned in the past. If you get ahead of
the wave, you get hit from the butt. So,
you're going to ride the crest of the
wave.
There nothing keeping you on the west
crest of the wave than being on the
crest of the wave.
especially if there's severe
consequences like an electric shock if
you get off the quest of the wave.
So we can train spiritual people with
this technique and if they get off it
okay
instantly you catch his mind trying to
anticipate the next shock. I got him
already. I know what his mind's doing.
He's trying to anticipate the next
shock. So, he's trying to get ahead of
the wave. So, he I won't hit the button,
but I'm going to hit the button cuz he's
trying to get ahead of the wave.
So, it's a self
motivated
technique.
When it's done intensely, it can be a
formal meditation in which one perfects
this technique. With the perfecting of
the technique then
without disturbing the sat in the world
Buddhist call sator without disturbing
the state one can then get up and walk
around and maintain the state in the
beginning if you open your eyes the
state disappears. Satori disappears in
the beginning. It's only possible when
your eyes are shut. Formal meditation.
As you perfect this letting goess, then
the state maintains even though you open
your eyes.
There's an inner silence in which one is
above the crest of the wave.
And it maintains even though one opens
one's eyes.
As it becomes more established,
one can get up, uncross one's legs, open
one's eyes and walk about the room and
the state continues.
All these have different names in
Sanskrit.
Anybody here born in Sanskrit? Nobody.
So we won't speak sanskrites because
there's nobody here from Sanskrit.
But they all have great names, classical
names in Sanskrit.
The condition becomes established then
as a permanent
way of being with the energy of life
and eventually becomes independent of
any effort
whatsoever.
That's the value of the contemplative
way of focusing on context. So as you
walk around the world there's a letting
go of the content. So what we're talking
about is disappearing
content. We're talking about the
disappearing of content and the content
is the product of the ego
and as that is surrendered one becomes
the context and realizes one always was
the context. Okay. So either in a
meditative state in a contemplative
state one does the same thing when lets
go wanting to change things as they
arise wanting to edit them wanting to
take a position about them wanting to
devise an opinion about them wanting to
have a feeling about it.
Finally all things are surrendered as
they arise and you walk about like you
do in the woods. Mostly in the woods,
you're not going from one little Well,
yeah, people do. They do that, don't
they? They go from one little object to
another. Oh, god. Look at this acorn.
Look at this squirrel. I guess they just
stay fixed right here in the center and
go from content to content.
Generally, a more meditative person gets
the space, the infinite peace and space
of nature. And that's why many people
prefer to meditate in nature because
it's easier to focus on context. There's
no television going. There's no
conversation.
There's no other people. There's no
traffic. There's no distractions to pull
you back into
the linear domain.
So to transcend then one's
identification with the ego. We let go
of this form. And then what happens is
the power of the context transforms.
The more we let go of the content, the
greater is the effect of the context.
It's the power of context then that is
responsible for our existence.
The ego would have you believe that it
is the source of your continued
existence,
but it's not. We exist in spite of the
ego, not because of it.
What keeps you afloat is your buoyancy.
And the buoyancy
is your relative energy as compared to
the field. The field is so powerful like
a giant force of gravity that it
sustains you. And you think, well, it's
my flailing in the water that's what's
keeping me afloat. What's keeping you
afloat is the specific gravity of salt
water,
not your flailing around in the water.
You understand? So it is safe to let it
go. It is safe to let it go. And this
letting goeness of the belief systems of
the ego are always accompanied by fear
that if I let this go, then the fear
comes up. That's why you hang on to it.
So by the time you get to the final
doorway, you will have had a lot of
experience in facing fear, surrendering
that fear, facing fear, surrendering
that fear. Each level of consciousness
then
as you enter it is marvelous and and and
wonderful and then at the other end you
get again you see it's kept by fear.
You see that fear is now becomes the
block. So again you walk through the
next fear. So anybody who's done a very
any very intensive meditation is aware
of that the sense of self reaches a
certain point and suddenly fear arises
and one feels like pulling back to the
previous identification of who you are.
The feeling if you let go at this point
you're going to become not me not you're
going to lose yourself lose your sense
of self. So that sense of losing
who I am, my identity, my sense of self
arises over and over at each level. Each
one of these levels is capped by if I
let that go, I won't be me.
Yeah.
Therefore, the role of faith in
spiritual work, there's blind faith and
then there is more advanced faith.
There's the faith of naivity which leads
many down the road to destruction.
Misplay faith is uh the dark side's
greatest weapon.
Every great killer of humans.
Yeah.
To have faith in that which is in error
is deadly. So faith in and of itself
is not a virtue.
It's a stupidity
unless you know what it is you have
faith in.
If you calibrated Mallovich,
if you calibrated Hitler or if you
calibrated Stalin, you calibrate Bin
Laden, I would not advise having faith
in them.
And yet many do. Isn't that correct?
Whole nations put faith in the
megalomaniac over and over and over
again.
In one lifetime, I don't remember how
many put their whole nations put their
faith in a megalomaniac who sees to it
that his entire nation is destroyed out
of his megalomania. And he will say they
deserve it. They deserve it cuz they
lost the war. All Germans deserve to
die.
Hitler wanted to burn down all Germany,
didn't he? They don't deserve to live
because they lost the war.
No, faith is scary. You have to have
know what you're having faith in. So,
you can only trust those who have gone
before who verified
that the ice is okay to walk on there.
I wouldn't put faith in thin ice. So, a
lot of people do. And uh that's why not
too many people reach the ultimate goal.
One has to qualify
uh what that is that you're putting
faith in faith however has a different
meaning. It means
faith in it really means conviction.
All right for faith in the form of
conviction
the absolute certainty that one is
following that which is absolutely the
truth.
That's a different kind of faith. Faith
in the proven. Oh, that's different.
Faith in the proven. But I would not put
faith in that which is unproven.
Faith in the proven.
How is surrendering everything to God
different from passivity? Oh, that's a
clever question.
It's a psychological question actually.
Um,
surrendering. What is one surrendering?
That's a good question. One is
surrendering willfulness. One is
surrendering one's will.
Passivity.
Passivity
uh is down here.
This is passivity.
The failure to take action where action
is called for.
Apathetic.
And there are some spiritual techniques
that lead people into apathy.
They think they're detached. They're not
detached. They're apathetic.
There's a group in Sedona.
They walk into a restaurant and
waitresses all go.
They never leave a tip for the waitress.
They think that's wanting wanting
people's approval, you know,
instead of seeing it as gratitude and
love and acknowledgement,
you see. So, it's a miscalculation of
what it's about. All right? So, um no,
uh it would seem like passivity,
but it seems like passivity only to ego.
You see, what is surrendered is the
willfulness, the spiritual will. And so
all spiritual work is really
surrendering one's will to God. One's
will to God. I want this side to win. I
want that side to win. You know,
uh so there's a willfulness. So what one
is surrendering is one's willfulness
that the world should be different than
it is. There is absolutely no reason at
all that the world should be different
than it is.
There's not one single reason this world
should or needs to be different than it
is.
Should it be different than you perceive
it? Well, that's different.
So, the best thing to do is not change
the world, but change how you perceive
it. Think all the work you save
yourself.
If this is the great school, why do you
want to take it down? We just have to
build another school anywhere.
God evolves along with human
consciousness. Isn't he lucky?
Happily his good luck is is that uh yeah
no
I think what the person means is our
comprehension our understanding our
awareness of the reality of God. Yes it
very definitely evolves with human
consciousness as we see over on the left
hand side here.
Yeah, God does improve.
God's going to throw you in hell. He
hates you because you're a sinner. He
condemns you to eternal damnation. Here
he you're so distasteful. He doesn't
want anything to do with you. Here he's
just punitive. He's only interested in
punishing people. And here he denies
himself to you. You call out for him. Oh
God, help me.
cuz you're just a worm. So
here he gets even with you for screwing
up.
Here he couldn't care less. Here's the
god of indifference. Sort of the Sartra.
Sort of Sartra. Ser calibrates about 220
or something. Anyway, uh he couldn't
care less. That's God is an indifferent.
God is like space. If you're there,
that's fine. If you're not there, it's
fine. Space couldn't care less.
Here we start getting into freedom,
courage, the courage of choice. In other
words, here we see opportunity,
support, inspiration,
absolutely merciful.
For God not to be merciful, he would
have to be judgmental. to be judgmental,
he would have to suffer from dualistic
perceptual distortions.
If he suffered from dualistic perceptual
distortions, he couldn't be God. And if
he isn't God, you don't have to be
afraid. So, anything that's
anything that is judgmental, you can
forget about because he's as bad as you
are. In fact, you're probably higher
than he is.
So these horrible gods that wait for you
coming out of ancient scriptures are,
you know, from the unconscious
anthropomorphic projections,
at least at least God is inspirational
and hopeful. Yeah.
And because you're at least merciful to
that which lives, you can presume God is
at least as high and evolved as you are.
Anybody can forgive your mother-in-law
or your his ex-wife or whatever.
All right. And as you do this, you
finally come into wisdom. The difficulty
with which we see in politics mainly is
in in in its impact on life is that it's
correct as far as content go but it what
negates it is the context.
You know everybody's out with a parade
about their freedoms. I'm a taxpayer.
I'm free to picnic in the woods. That's
my right. They're entitled. They have
rights. My right to picnic in the woods
except when there's a drought. No,
you're not allowed to picnic in the
woods during a drought when there's
extreme fire danger and millions of
acres are already burning and houses are
burning. No. So
all such things then are subject to
content. It's only so under certain
conditions. That's sort of the basis of
situational ethics. A thing is ethical
or unethical under what conditions?
That which is pedestrian ethics then
fails to reach the point of wisdom
because the point of wisdom what's the
difference between the intelligent and
wisdom.
Uh well wisdom where is wisdom?
Wisdom
I don't know where he went. Wisdom is up
here. Okay. Okay.
All right. Wisdom then takes into takes
into account context. context, the
foolishness of the youth that did it or
the culture in which he comes, you know,
totally changes the meaning and
significance of that thing. For this
person to do it, it would be heinous.
For this person to do it, it's probably,
you know, it's stupidity. So, we
constantly modify it. And to pretend
that that is not so is the pitfall of
certain political positions which don't
see that in times of war things are
different than times of peace, in times
of drought. You're right. As a picnicer
is different, you know,
if nonlinear dynamics is a product of
the 400s, it isn't. So that answers that
question.
The intellectual construction in
describing it, yes, is in languaging. Um
however the nonlinear dynamics um is a
whole field itself. Spiritual reality
you understand is the subjective world
in which we live. We talk objectively
about things out there in precise
language and all but we don't live
there. Where we live is in the instant
to instant
contact with our own subjectivity.
Life is experienced on the subjective
level of consciousness itself and
nowhere else.
Why? Because you cannot experience it
elsewhere. The only instrument available
to you to experience your own existence
is consciousness itself.
Were it not for consciousness, there
would be nothing to know science and
make any declaration about it because
there would be nothing that registers
its existence
and believes in it. So therefore
all absolute reality is subjective only.
That which consider is considered
objective is a positionality.
It's a perceptual definition.
All that ego perceives is really a
tautology.
It is what it is because you say it is
what it is. It's like every we all
commonly vote that it means that. But
tomorrow we could change the vote. Now
it doesn't mean that anymore because it
has no independent reality.
That which is real. You cannot change
its degree of reality by voting on it.
You see by common agreement we say this
means that and this is valuable. Now
then a decade later we say that's not
valuable now and this is illegal now
what is the white brotherhood I'm not a
an expert on such things other people
are uh I'm mainly familiar with only one
volume and that is the volume on glamour
it's uh I think from the higher
celestial realms they are evolved
teachers they calibrate quite Okay.
And then again, there's a downside to it
where there's a lot of oo and ah about
it all and all that. You know, the
truths that are transmitted should stand
on their own. Stand on their own.
I was telling you this morning about the
seduction of the facious teachers,
spiritual teachers is a glamour. a
glamour the same as Hollywood, the same
as all the hype, you know, all the
glitter and is glamour.
Uh, the White Brotherhood did a book on
glamour. He said it was channel by Alice
Bailey.
The book on glamour is excellent.
It is useful.
It Oh, I see. It is um it describes
glamour as an energy resist
of an energy that we project resist.
Okay. All right. It describes glamour as
the attraction the energy of attraction
of certain things. So it's useful
and all all these teachings are useful
within their own context. All of them
are useful. That the attraction of
certain things is almost like an energy
that gets it's almost like a glue that
gets stuck on them or a scentation that
gets shined upon them. And they're not
intrinsic to what the cintillating light
illuminates.
That which is glamorized by
dramatization
is not the same as what you think it is.
It's an exaggeration. So the value of
that is that we exaggerate certain
things because they become
uh over
valued.
There's other questions here I can't
answer because I'm not a expert on the
um
esoteric.
It's not necessary to become an expert
in the esoteric uh to become very
spiritually advanced. It can be, you
know, an entrancement of its own right.
There's endless books. There's endless
channelings. There's endless treatises.
And what what one gets into is other
domains. The So, you know, the energy
fields of the inner plains and all,
all of them are quite interesting.
And if you find somebody that studied
them for 20 years and become
enlightened, then I'd pay attention to
them. I never have.
It's not really the pathway to
enlightenment.
I'm not saying it's not so, but it's a
distraction. Many things are not so and
are distractions and dead ends in and of
themselves.
One then sounds aryodite. You can use
many fancy terms and all kinds of
Sanskrit and
uh elegant languaging for the field of
energies only.
Is that necessary to know?
No,
not necessary to know. Did the Buddha
Buddha teach about it? No. Did Christ
teach about it? No. Did Krishna teach
about it? No. Well, if the great avatars
of history, the greatest teachers ever
lived, have not taken the time and the
energy to explain this to us, then it's
probably not too necessary to know it is
all I can figure.
Krishna said, "Listen, you better learn
all this crap or you're never going to
get up here."
By God, we'd all pour over, wouldn't we?
But I don't know. He doesn't say
anything about ether ific bodies or
energy fuels or any of that stuff.
Jesus had a heck of a time. Okay.
Yourself.
They had a hell of a time. Once you get
over 600, no, 700,
start to be very difficult.
And we've alluded to that. the aches and
the pains as you're attacked by the
demons and those that hate God and don't
want to see human power dominated by
spiritual truth and rather keep control
of you
and take a dislike to you
and uh it's a good know it's very handy
the Buddha would have done better if
he'd known kinesiology
I told him that you why don't you learn
kinesiology for Hey, get on there.
He said, "No, it can be done without
kinesiology." I said, "Be my guest." All
right.
Now, we only need to know what's
necessary to know. And and it's not that
it's harmful to know these other things,
but to be aware that they're
distractions. They're distractions.
Don't forget, most of them are
perceptions. You're back into the level
of form. Even though you're talking
about energy fields which are
non-physical,
form also prevails in the non-physical.
So form can take a physicality but it
can also be a non-physicality such as a
concept or
you know various astral realms and all.
How is it determined which individuals
gravitate to which levels of
consciousness? uh is this material you
know no we explained that in an earlier
lecture it's more like uh gravity you
see the spiritual will which is the
focus of one's karma
oh when spiritual decisions then are
encapsulated you might say imprinted in
the uh transistor what do they call it
in computer work you know that registers
everything
>> whatever it
every decision. Then you see we live in
a purgatorial realm of an infinite
number of instant to instant choices and
decisions. Each one of these influences
the power of our energy field. The
atheric
the higher spiritual bodies instantly
reflect every choice.
Um, this determines
where our position is in the overall,
you might call it, gravitational field
of consciousness. So, it's like
consciousness is an infinite
gravitational field of infinite power.
And one of the staggering things you see
when you go through the final doorway,
not only the exquisite beauty, the
incredible peace,
but the infinite power.
If one could intuit it the amount of
power it takes to keep every molecule
and every atom together in the entire
universe, the power is so immense, it's
beyond comprehension.
So this you it's reveal the omnipotence
of God is self-revealing
when that within this and I always
compare it to an electromagnetic field
within electromagnetic field then every
little molecule by its choice or
decision influences its polarity its
size its molecular structure so you
choose this now this little arm is out
now I choose that now your gravity pole
moves up to your north pole and your
south pole
Every little choice affects your
configuration and the polarity switches
around as you choose yes and no against
the various options.
Now that is going to determine where you
go in the overall electromagnetic field.
Don't forget this field is ultra
powerful,
infinitely powerful.
Everything you've ever done is said
throughout all the evolution of your
consciousness and all its
reincarnations, if they were physical or
not, or within the astral realms, every
decision and choice now influences your
polarity, the intensity of your charge,
your configuration,
and you automatically gravitate to the
field with which you're concordant.
Is this field here attracted to this
field? No, it hates it. Is this field
here attracted to this field? No. These
feel fields automatically gravitate into
that with which they are congruent.
Therefore, the justice of God is
absolute
because each and everyone completely and
totally themsel determines their
ultimate face faith via their own choice
and by no other.
There is no arbitrary God that has to
see to it. See to it that you go to bad
places.
That's a fact.
Each one automatically.
So when you leave the body at first you
may not even notice it but one is
gravitatedly
attracted to
that with which you are concordant.
So there's no point to feeling badly
about people that go out the bottom of
the box.
Life hasn't changed any.
Everybody hates everybody and kills
everybody here. You go out of body and
there you are in a room where everybody
hates everybody and kills everybody.
It's wonderful. I mean right at home. So
good.
H
can you imagine somebody dedicated to a
life of excitement and danger and drugs
and
and gangster rap and wrap being stoned
all the time driving fast cars and being
cool.
He goes out of body and finds himself in
a place where everybody's singing hymns.
Man, this is hell. Get me out of here.
Get me back where dudes are cool, man.
You know what I mean?
It was scary, Maggie. I I went to
this place and woo, they're all spooky.
I mean, they were doing hymns and they
had incense around and beautiful
Oh, man.
It was really scary.
Go and tell your doctor about it,
Herman. What do you suppose happened,
doctor? Well, I don't know what
happened. So,
what you consider desire?
So, we create your own eventual
potentiality, do you not? By that which
you desire and aspire to. Those who
aspire to heaven and have like a faith
that if they do the best they can from
moment to moment it will all come about.
Why should their faith be not be
fulfilled? You've already chosen your
own future. Have you not?
So why should you experience other than
that which you've chosen? So so you
might say the justice of God is
absolute.
That which is destined to go here goes
here. It doesn't go here and it doesn't
go there.
If you're destined to go here, this
would be like hell and this would be
like hell, wouldn't it?
Everything floats around Gazer and makes
a buzzing noise. You say, "This is
weird, man.
Take me back to good old New York City."
You know what I'm saying?
I like the sound of the L, you know?
All right. So, we don't have to worry
then because we're only going to
experience that which we already are
because there isn't anything else.
I've already answered all these.
Better break.
I've already answered all these. No. Oh,
she's been hiding these from me. All
right. All right, we're going to take
another break and then after that I'm
going to talk to people who want to
speak to me individually.
In the 12 lectures I've tried to provide
either the n the information, the
knowledge or the tools to reach that
knowledge of your own.
I've tried to make it complete and
adequate. First remove the barriers of
the ego.
Define its structure.
Just the knowingness begins to weaken
the ego. and then bring up techniques to
bring in higher and higher truth. Now
that the ego's been weakened, first we
weaken the ego, then we start pulling in
the higher energies and what to do all
the way to the very end beyond which
nothing exists.
So we'll take a break and then I'll be
happy to greet people and I want to
thank you. This has been magnificent, a
wonderful year.
see what she has to say about it.
Oh, she's improved also.
Well, we always calibrate the energy
field of this group, you know, before
and after, you know, and then we share
it with the group, you know, with the
today. The energy field, the group went
up over 20, 25, 30, oh my god, 35. The
energy field, this group today went up
over 40, 45. Oh my god, a miracle. So,
oh my god,
unbelievable. Okay, in the past, the
group usually went up 10 each time.
Today, it was 40. 40 poops.
So, I give a
I love you all for hearing what I had to
say and for God.
That is a staggering figure. You
>> tell us what the numbers were.
>> Um I don't remember now.
>> What we're interested in is the shift. I
think we started out higher than we were
in the past. 440 or something.
>> No.
No, no, 440. We started out at 440.
>> 445. We started out a little over 440.
The group shot up 40 points. That's uh
credible.
You know, that's a statistical average.
Some people here went up probably a
couple hundred points. Some go up 150 in
a shot like that. And some people
probably feel worse.
If that's what it all, I'm going back to
the streets, boy.
Oh, loud. Holy holy stuff.
I know. Some people here just went way
up. You know, I saw it. I saw the light
go up on them. So, it's the direction
that we're going, not how far we are.
It's just we're all committed the same
direction. So, we all came onto this
planet about the same time together.
We're all going to be living what seems
individually, but actually this group,
you know, moves on to another domain.
You know, we probably evolved through
many lifetimes together, you know. So,
We will all be
>> together for a me though. Solelu
Hallelujah.
Hallelu