So this savage unrelenting
uh
you see the per unconsciously the person
is afraid of losing their soul to hell
out of fear of the damnation of your
soul to hell. hell for sin. You will put
yourself through unbelievable exquisite
agony.
That's the truth. Is it? My god, it's
the truth. I know cuz I lived it and
agonized over it and discovered it in my
own unconscious and had to undo it and
it took a lot of spiritual work because
that's deeply rooted and confounded by
certain interpretations of religion that
suffering is good for the soul and uh
okay so the enemy is not some external
god uh who gets off on exterminating
people in the most painful way possible.
uh but it's in yourself.
So I recently discovered that
configuration in the collective
that um only by pain and suffering and
pain can you save your soul.
So this looks to pain and suffering as
the savior.
It's the reversal of Christianity in a
way.
Your savior is pain and suffering.
Because the more pain and suffering, the
more God's wrath will be assuaged.
And your pain and suffering is therefore
saving your soul. Cuz I ask, why would
anybody put themsel through years and
years of so much intense agony? It just
makes no sense.
The dread and fear of one's soul being
thrown into eternal damnation
is a terror
and that is the grip that the old
Freudian super ego has on you
and there's a whole archetype in the
unconscious that energizes that.
All right.
So prayer and meditation on that the
willingness to forgive oneself
u and the undoingness of that the
willingness to be merciful toward
yourself and towards
anyone and everyone
in psychoanalysis we all you know I did
psycho analysis and I had a classical
psychoanalysis
very successful very brilliant analyst
and very successful analysis
>> and a psycho analytic training, you're
trained to always approach the patient
from the side of the super ego. Before
you start pulling up what's in the
unconscious,
you first ameliorate the super ego,
which is the conscience.
Otherwise, the patient's going to be
attacked. But so if you bring up
incestuous wishes,
but you still have a
fierce and malignant super ego, the
person's going to go into a suicidal
depression. You know what I'm saying?
So
with a patient's positive transference,
you begin to amilarate their savage
super ego. How could I have done that?
They're they want to die on the floor
because they made a faux paw in society.
You've got to start. So you start
working on this savage super ego. You
don't want to expose them to the
executioner
because when you start pulling up what's
in the id making a pile in society is
pretty minimal.
uh you know the death wishes you have
towards people, the teachers you wish
would die and stuff you wait that stuff
comes up.
So you have to amilarate the severity of
your own conscience and see that it's
irrational.
It's not God. Nobody thinks that the
savage super ego and a big massive sense
of guilt means they're holy. No, it
means you're neurotic.
You need a good analyst.
I had some forbidden thought. I remember
I was laying on the couch and uh I was
shaking with just terror came up you
know and just now what I said I can't
talk. He said what is it terror
terror?
And the terror was a forbidden thought
coming up. Huh? Forbidden thought coming
up. So, I projected onto my analyst, you
know, the savage killer. See?
And I'll never forget the time I broke
through my classic obsessivecompulsive
phobic anxiety disorder for which I was
seeing him every day, plus being a
training analyst 5 days a week all the
way from New York City into his office
on East 88 Third Street.
And uh the terror got bigger and bigger
and bigger. Oh my god. You know, people
nowadays it's stylish to put down Freud.
You should lay on the couch every day
for a couple of months and see how much
you put down Freud. Anyway, you lay on
the couch and all of a sudden all this
stuff comes out of nowhere. He hasn't
said anything or done anything to bring
it up.
I started getting phobic. I couldn't go
through a tunnel. I couldn't go over a
bridge.
I claustrophobia. I couldn't get on an
elevator. I couldn't be in crowds and I
couldn't be by myself. I couldn't go
under the river or over the river.
And his name was Dr. Omesis. I said,
"Good God." I said, "I'm getting worse.
This analysis is making worse." He was
making great progress. Wonderful.
Wonderful. You know what I mean? The
anxiety attacks. I'm breaking out all
over. I don't know how I function in
those days. I was a resident in
psychiatry. Oh my god, I love them. And
so anyway, the the day of great terror
came and I could couldn't breathe. I lay
on the couch and just sheer terror and
he says, "What's going on?" I said,
"Well, do you have any dreams?" Yes. I
told him this dream. I said, "I'm in
this dream and there's some woman in the
background
and uh I don't know if I was flirting
with her or what." I said, "Then a lion
jumped on me and began to kill me." And
then the terror, I mean, I really had
anxiety attack on the couch. It was
awful. He said, "What does a lion make
you think of?" I said, "Jesus says, I
don't know, a lion." My mind went blank,
blank. He says, "What's my name?" I
said, "It's Lionel Overseey." That was
the name of my analyst. He was professor
at Columbia. Anyway, his name was
Lionel. He said, "Who would the lion
be?" And he realized that here was the
terrifying
castrating father figure. He was going
to kill me for having edible attractions
to some female within his province or
something. So, people put down for it. I
say, "You go lay on the couch for a year
or two and see what happens.
So this terror this terror then arises
the lies and wait.
How afraid should you be of your super
ego, your conscience, the the judge, the
savage sadistic aspect.
If you look at what your worst
punishment for anybody would be, that's
what it's saving up for you.
You think every sinner should be
executed. everybody then execution is
what is waiting for you because every
one of your killer thoughts there's a
lot of people you wish dead when you
think of all the lifetimes you've lived
and all the people you've killed and
wish dead I mean there's a multitude
right
oh boy in a second you can think of half
a dozen people you wish dead already you
know what I mean
so the super ego says you're a murderer
and you got to suffer up in And so
suffering then is a way of uh trying to
uh ameliorate God
u offset his feared punishment by
punishing yourself.
So we have to give up uh worship of
pain, suffering, sickness and disease
and realize that the god of reality you
know
uh feels sorry for people. He feels
sorry for people. Yeah. Sorry for just
the way I was speaking.
The pain and suffering then is super is
self-imposed and it's the ego can be
very vicious. Huh? When we see what the
ego is capable of doing to other people
blowing them up 3,000 at a time,
then you can't it's not beyond
credibility that your own super ego uh
can be quite savage. Therefore, I
believe the course of miracles, things
that that assuage the conscience, stop
feeling guilty on seeing things as
mistakes, seeing things as ignorance.
So,
the shepherd then who's looking after
your little lambs, your little lambs are
susceptible. That's all the little parts
of you that are vulnerable to attack by
guilt, thinking that if you kill
yourself and kill all your little lambs
that God will be pleased.
God of the Old Testament was pleased,
didn't they? And they killed the little
lambs. And the more innocent, the little
sacrifice,
you South America and all these tribes,
you see how sacrifice of the innocent
was the way to assuage God, wasn't it?
It had to be a virgin. It had to be a
baby lamb.
The slaying of innocence
is how you please God. You see what a
massive distortion of reality that is.
That's a 180, right? Let's see if that's
180.
What we described as a 180 resistance.
It's a 180 degree reversal of the truth.
And it holds sway over masses of
mankind.
and feels very threatened
very threatened by truth.
Okay.
Yes. And what can we blame on the human
brain? That's a good question. I like
blaming a lot on human brain. Uh it's
one of my favorites. I mean, it's a very
defective instrument. It doesn't
remember to take the keys to the office.
It doesn't remember how to turn this
thing on or off. Is this thing on? I
don't know. I can't remember whether it
was on or off. I forgot how to turn it
on or off. I have a new air conditioner
at home with a 5600 BTU. Goes through
the wall. And they said, "And it has a
remote." Uh-oh. Famous.
You can set it for every other Tuesday,
third Thursdays.
If you're 20 years old, it's probably a
turn on. U
I finally have gotten on off.
>> I tell you, and I don't even touch the
remote.
So, this has something to do with the
brain.
Well, there's a lot of questions really
in this. Uh, how come we're born with a
genetically defective brain to begin
with? How come we're born with a
consciousness that doesn't know truth
from falsehood?
We're born with an innate vulnerability
in the nature of consciousness itself,
which is a priority to the mind, the
brain.
Then you're born with a brain
that barely knows left from right. What
a lot of people think is very airy
edition is you know jacks for openers
amongst geniuses
those are just jacks for openers
real genius thinks that's
stupid so
even the most advanced brain
doesn't even know
you need it's no you know what from his
elbow
that's stupifying isn't
So that's the vulnerability that the
shepherd has to take responsibility.
All these innocent lambs within you are
all vulnerable, easily programmable,
impressionable
and programmed by the past and now I
would imagine it's one's karmic
uh the karmic the evolution of the
consciousness of mankind. The karma of
the evolution of consciousness of
mankind is what determines the kind of
brain we inherit exist. Okay. So we've
inherited it is really brilliant. It's
also a genius.
We've inherited an incredibly complex
and very advanced as far as the rest of
human mankind animal world. So on the
positive side we've got an incredible
computer that can do things that that is
really mindboggling.
Not only that, not just reason, but it
can create such incredible beauty. Such
incredible beauty. The great operas, the
great symphonies, the great composers,
the PA. I calibrated the piano. Was it
700, wasn't it? Yeah. Uh, so the mind of
man is capable of incredible feats, of
incredible beauty and great
magnificence,
great personal sacrifice out of love.
Um, so its upside is that it's capable
of taking you all the way to a thousand.
My presumption is after a thousand you
don't need it. In fact, it's probably a
hindrance below it.
I don't want a brain after a thousand.
Do you? No. I want to be rid of it.
Yeah. So, all right. So you might say by
the evolution of consciousness, mankind
has earned karmically now the right to
have a brain and all the benefits of the
brain. But every gift is also a
limitation is it not?
Uh just like the 400s are a gift as
compared to the 200s but it's already a
limitation to get to the 500s. So the
human brain is certainly
I would say useful to us at a certain
point in the evolution of our
consciousness and and not useful after a
certain level. Not useful probably the
human brain is quite a
hold back at a certain level. You have
to get rid of it. Have to transcend the
human brain. So that way means we have
to transcend physicality
uh to and that's what heaven is about is
heaven going from physicality to more
advanced consciousness in which
material physicality no longer plays a
important element.
The evolution of consciousness then
demands a comparable physicality.
Just as the dinosaur,
the dinosaur was the perfect physicality
to express consciousness level 70. Let's
see what Tyrannosaurus Rex was at.
Tyrannosaurus Rex, your permission is
just was over 60. Over 65, 70.
Tyrannosaurus Rex was at 70.
Well, okay.
There are people in the news that
calibrate at 70.
They make big news.
You take a reptile and put them in a
human body and let them loose with some
bombs and boy, you got trouble.
Golly.
All right. So,
so the human brain, yes, is genetically
defective.
And that's one of the reasons we have to
be merciful towards oursel and others.
No matter how badly the other people
screw up, when the chips are really
down, you really have to you end up
forgiving them. Why? Because you you see
they either couldn't you either didn't
know any better or they couldn't even if
they did know.
and that everyone is pretty much
operating at
the level of which they are capable
every instant. You can criticize anybody
by holding their behavior up against the
hypothetical and everybody will fail
because you can hypothetical,
you know, is a dime a dozen. You know,
he should have known better. He should
have remembered that. You should have
gotten an A. You should have remembered
not to turn the corner that fast. You
should have remembered to put the gas in
before we left on the trip to
Cincinnati.
Uh all those should is the hypothetical.
So compared to the hypothetical, all of
us fail. Nobody in this room can live up
to the hypothetical. So the hypothetical
becomes the weapon becomes a weapon
really of hostility towards others.
Nobody can live up to the hypothetical.
So we can only forgive people for being
where they are at the moment. And
hypothetically five years down the road
they will remember to do whatever it is
but remember empty the garbage. But at
this point they don't remember to empty
the garbage.
Uh fixation and obsession. Yes. Fixation
obsession are solar plexus.
Uh fixation obsession comes out of the
solar plexus. Addiction comes out of the
solar plexus. Obsession to thoughts.
Obsession to rituals. Obsessions and
compulsions are primarily solar plexus.
They are not heart. I mean that's not
love nor is it spiritual wisdom. Uh
neither is it hate. It's not coming out
of the spleen. Uh so it's really a
fixation uh in the in the solar plexus.
Uh how to transcend the 500s to the
600s. We're going to finish these
questions and then we'll take a break
again. Uh
actually you do it pretty much the same
way. The high 500s are unmistakable. The
high 500s, life becomes transformed.
Happens to a lot of people do the course
of miracles. You see them go into a
state. The miraculous becomes the common
place.
You think of a parking space. As you get
there, the car pulls out and there you
are. You park right next to Lincoln
Center.
Uh, everybody, you love everybody.
You're in love with everybody.
Everything looks beautiful. Everybody
radiates. All the men look handsome and
all the women look beautiful. All
animals are charming. Every street scene
is like a French movie is so so
central park Sunday afternoon is so
beautiful.
The beautiful ladies walking the
children and everything is exquisite and
the high 500s is a wonderful place to
be. And how do you get from there beyond
the 600s?
I never asked myself the question.
It happens of its own.
It can happen suddenly or slowly. You
begin to Oh, I know how it works. Uh,
you begin to get glimpses of it. You
begin to get glimpses of it. As you get
into the five five00s,
it's not hard to get the high five00s. I
mean, it's hard, but it's not hard. Hey,
you just do the chorus of miracles
assiduously, pray up a storm, forgive
everybody and everything
and uh be loving in all regards at every
instant. Uh and life transforms itself
like that.
Then the 600s I think begin. Yes. They
open they begin to open the window opens
to it and then it closes. You're walking
through the woods and suddenly there's
that absolute stillness and the present.
There's a sense of a presence one knows
when one's in the presence of God.
It doesn't stay though in the beginning
very often it doesn't stay. And in the
classic spiritual literature
um the saint will bemoan how the beloved
came and then deserted them left them in
despair. how they soared on the wings
and then uh dropped because that which
was infinitely loving now has the power
to handle it
its challenge its challenge that which
is not loving and so it summons up that
which is not loving and to be healed. So
that's the classic spiritual saying that
love brings up non-love. If you do a
workshop on love, what you're going to
be bringing up is all the that would
blocks the love. Correct. Think about
all of a sudden all the people you hate
come up.
You do a class on forgiveness. All the
people you Yeah. Golly.
Um
and some of these are questions that are
a little bit on the esoteric side. I
don't know. I've never asked them. Uh
uh I'll ask them maybe during the break
and I'll give you an answer to them.
Uh
this these are more esoteric. Uh
the esoteric what is the source of the
esoteric? Don't forget there are other
dimensions in this what we call re what
we call reality. It's only one of an
infinite number of dimensions.
What we call our world and reality is
one of an infinite number of dimensions.
There is no limit to the number of
dimensions.
Classically they be be called the they
be called the inner plains the celestial
levels
the lower levels have are called lower
astral lower middle upper astral
celestial extraterrestrial they they've
got different descriptive terms
we know that mankind is discovered over
the centuries by lucinogenic drugs by
dreams by shamanistic experiences by
vision and
uh by the experience of others etc. that
there are multiple dimensions with
different multiple types of energies and
beings in these multiple dimensions.
All we know is that the best spiritual
teaching is not that they're unreal but
that you're not equipped to go there and
do therefore don't you're not equipped
to handle a Ouija board. You're not
equipped. Nobody in this room is
equipped to handle in a Ouija board.
Nobody's here is equipped to handle what
that which is unvisible and unknown.
As intriguing and clever and glamorizing
as it may be, there's nothing more
intriguing than master blah blah talking
to you from some realm giving you the
inner secrets of ancient mysteries. Oh,
give me a break.
Sedona is the home of ancient mysteries
by bottle of this and that being
channeled by someplace
and as you come into town there's second
readings on every billboard. Right? So
it doesn't say it's wrong. It doesn't
say it's bad. It just says you're not
equipped to go there. You really are
poking into realms of which you have no
awareness of who it is on the other
side. So, I had a spiritual teacher one
time. He says, "If you can't see them
and hear them in a body, avoid them."
Because every spiritual truth that you
ever need to hear in your entire
lifetime has already been spoken by
human beings and bodies.
There's no great mystical truth spoken
by Baba. Somebody
at midnight in the middle of a desert
wait for the aliens to pick him up.
You don't need it.
The basic things to reach enlightenment
are really only half a dozen a number,
aren't they? The willingness to forgive,
the realization of limitations of the
intellect,
devotion to divinity, the respect for
the sacred,
the onepointedness and fixity of mind,
the transcend all obstacles,
the willingness to be
loving as a way of being in the world
rather than some kind of emotional give
and take. I love you now you love me and
if you don't love me I'll be mad at you
and kill you etc. Not an emotional give
and take but a way of being in the
world. You only need to know about have
a dozen of things but you need to know
from master Googleheimr on the other
side the ancient mystery of what
it's usually some symbols or numbers or
strange name you know with a mystical
magical quality. So this is the mystical
magical and its intrigue which is one of
the sheep you got to watch is glamour.
It's called glamour. The glamour of the
myst mystical. The glamour of the
secret. The glamour of being initiated
into the secret mystery and rituals of
the um daras.
And for another 5,000 you can become a
master Hamdara
and which will give you the real secret
symbols.
All right, we're going to take a break
and during that break, anybody want
secret symbols? I'm selling them for
$150.
>> I get all kinds of wonderful presents
from people.
>> Here's a little sign.
>> Oh, here's the one here.
One of these lectures. Uh,
one of these lectures I wandered off
into previous lifetimes and uh, you
know, they're pretty vivid and each one
is very real and as real as this
lifetime, but no more. And then this and
so anyway, somebody friend of ours here
made a poster with all the previous
lifetimes that I described. Here's one
where I I I had a a lance and uh I
skewered this guy right through the
groin and uh uh I reexperienced the
karma of that having hernia repair with
no anesthesia and in the middle of that
I um apologized for not killing him.
That was really the karmic uh the moral
defect was I didn't have the courage to
kill him, put him out of his defect. So
here he is that lifetime and um I was
talking today about the cathedral chart
in the blue window and that's where this
this comes from the blue window of the
shark cathedral and he picked it up and
put it in.
And here was a lifetime as a slave here.
I've been the pirate
too cheap to feed him and u
so uh in this lifetime I'm at the wars
and um suffering what it is to be a
slave. And uh in that lifetime, you
know, when I couldn't take any more, I
suddenly it was like an enlightened
state came in. Suddenly I realized I
could let go of this life. I'm not
trapped at all. So I let go of it and
died. Screw you. There I am. Free as a
body. You're free to exit anytime you
want. Whoa.
So there's the galley where I was a
slave. There I was.
And I was reading advanced theoretical
physics a learned text. It's something
about one of the variables that you deal
with is one minus 300 billionth of a
pixel or so I thought that would be a
tixel
tiny tiny moment of time. How small does
a moment of time have to be before
you're beyond time? So anyway, those are
the lifetimes. So that was the meaning
of this uh pirates hat because in that
lifetime I wasn't about to spend the
money to bring those poor people back to
port I'll tell you all my profit going
down their throats and
so heck with the food and water. So
that's the ultimate of greed. Huh? Greed
where even the life of others much less
their happiness or their comfort is
immaterial.
And we see that in the daily news,
right? That's even every evening's uh
newspaper.
>> Earth.
Ah to the great Arg.
Welcome to the great Arg.
Arg.
All right. What about sensuality and
sexuality as barriers to enlightenment?
Yes. Should they be invited? Uh those
are rather traditional things that every
spiritual uh aspirant has to look at. uh
greed, money, uh work, uh fame, fortune,
sensuality, sexuality,
uh all the body's uh activities.
Um there there is a phase there is a
phase of self um detachment from all
these things in which one learns how to
surrender, let go of
uh cravingness in all of its forms.
Um
I did a tape on how to lose weight uh in
which I explained that in some detail.
Um
the you you let go. It's it's pretty
much the same as letting go resisting
pain. You know you you fall down, you
twist your ankle. Uh what you do is you
instantly don't label it pain. Don't
call it anything.
Let go. resisting whatever is whatever
the experiencing of it is without
calling it anything.
And the complete and total surrendering
to the experience of whatever it is
that's going on
brings the pain from the ankle up into
the aura. You can feel the pain leaves
your ankle and you're surrounded by the
pain. If you're surrounded by the pain
that was once local, you know you're
doing it right. Then as the pain leaves
here and becomes generalized, you can
tell it's in your aura. Uh you you
continue letting go resisting it and by
doing that you disappear it and within
four or five minutes you get up and walk
away.
Should have been in a splint. Should
have been seeing the doctor about a
sprained ankle and said you get up and
walk away. All right. So it's somewhat
the same with all the the physical
attachments uh to eating and sex and uh
the cravingness for excitement etc.
These these are all things that and and
the desire for money and fame and
fortune and good looks and great
physique and beauty and all these
things. Um, but they're all things that
your your willingness to surrender them
to God. And I've addressed it in greater
detail in in eye of the eye. Uh, and
perhaps again in the book I you pretty
much follow the same techniques you you
do with meditation
in which you let go resisting it. And as
you let go resisting it, you see the
magic. Each of these things has become
imbued with a specialness. Each of these
things has to become imbued with
specialness.
A magical
means of achieving something.
It isn't it isn't sensuality is the
attachment to sensuality.
It isn't sexuality. It's the attachment
to it. Of course, Ramach Krishna and
many other spiritual orders prohibit
sexuality and such things. sensuality in
any of its forms and demand an aesthetic
um renunciate type of a lifestyle.
I have nothing against that and I myself
have gone through a that type of a a
renunciation in which you leave the
world and all of its all that it values.
It isn't just the things themselves. One
thing I like about Alice Bailey's books
is the one on glamour
uh that it isn't the thing itself. It's
the specialness with which it has become
imbued. The Hollywood extravaganz uh
bigger than life uh blowing it up beyond
that which it is.
Each of these things then becomes
special to us. And as we let go
resisting them,
let go the attachment to them, the
question always eventually comes up
about one's willingness to surrender it
to God.
There's a method.
>> Yeah.
You see, I understand his language. You
don't.
That's God speak for Right on.
All right. So, it's the drivenness of
these things that you become the slave.
You're entrapped by them. These are
mainly solar plexus. Uh it isn't the
sexuality. It's the attachment to the
sexuality, the specialness of it, uh the
glamour of it. Um
all of these pleasures are transitory.
How long does it take to eat a
chocolate? You know, not very long.
Bang. It's gone, right? An orgasm is an
orgasm. It comes and goes. And a second
later, it's over already. And uh
what you were expecting is left already.
You know what I mean? You spend 6 months
dreaming about it and 22 seconds later
it's gone.
And for this you sacrificed all your
hard-earned money
all those months out at sea.
And this little bimbo in the Hong Kong
said, "Do you pay me money now?
Oh, well there goes 30 seconds.
>> All right. For that 30 seconds, people
are willing to spend a whole lifetime in
prison. Right.
All right. So, these things are
traditionally addressed and uh almost
every spiritual group has its own
approach to it.
Uh my own advisement is to follow the
traditional way of nonattachment.
No attachment,
no resistance
to not resist it nor be attached to it.
Um so it becomes it no longer runs you.
Uh could it prevent enlightenment? Yes,
it does at a certain point certainly. Um
and that's why Ramach Krishna, you know,
forbid his young devotees to even touch
money. No sex, no money.
I my only disagreement with that is I
don't think it's the sex or the money. I
think it's the um attachment to it. I
think we calibrated money and it's 200
and I think we calibrate six and it's
210 or something. So it isn't like they
have an intrinsic negative energy.
the the attach it's the attachment to
it. Let's see. Let's just do it for the
fun of the audience. Huh? Uh money. We
have permission to calibrate money.
Resist. Money is over 200 210. You know
the money is about 205 about the same as
the CIA and the Internal Revenue
Service. They're
all peculiarly all the big government
agencies calibrated 205.
205. That means they're integrous
because
the law demands it, I think. You know
what I mean? But they're not gracious.
Gracious is up in the 300s, you know.
205 to take your order. You forgot to
fill out the bottom line. Back of the
line. I mean, they're doing their
function.
What was the other one? Money and sex.
Okay. We have permission to do sex
resist. Heterosexuality resists is over
200. Let's see. Sex per se is over 200.
205 205 yeah uh it's a pro physicality a
procreative
and of course what we we didn't ask
about the emotional relationship in sex
which can be of course in the 500s
um it can be the you know the time which
you're really exchanging in adoration
for each other in the 500s and the
recognition of the presence of God and
each other for which you are thankful so
it could be a worship
uh moment, a worshipful
and you thank God for
the physicality and the the chance to uh
exchange love in that form. So
sensuality and sexuality are not themsel
in and of themselves.
Um
it it's good to it's good to um be
beyond them because if you reach when
you reach a certain level of uh
evolution of consciousness uh you can
become very powerfully attracted to
members of attractive to members of the
opposite sex.
And don't just think because you're old
and ugly that don't have it.
Old and ugly turns a lot of people on.
For one thing, you're safe. There's no
competition. And
don't kid yourself that it can be
passion can be very intense. But you'll
notice as you get into the 500s
yourself, as you get into especially the
high 500s, people are attracted to you
like flies. And uh very amorously they
come on very amorously.
Uh there's almost an onslaught.
People are they just fall in love with
you. Well, at that level you see you're
in love with everyone.
So what they're in love with is the
reflection they're getting back of the
recognition of their self because of
your lovingness. So in your presence
they feel this intense state which is
spiritual love but they misinterpret it
as phys as personal love. They think
it's personal.
No, it's not personal. But as you get in
the high 500s, you find you're very
attractive uh to people. And um
if you if you haven't transcended the
temptation, you can fall. And there's a
lot of well-known
uh spiritual teachers whose books
calibrate reasonably well. But at later
on uh later in their life, they their
personal calibrations fell down.
And it was probably that this doorway
was not guarded. So as the shepherd of
your sheep
um that's another doorway you got to
watch that
the energy of lovingness is very very
attractive to people and they will be
attracted to you and you will get very
surprising propositions
in the midnight in the zoo the ape looks
at
hi sweetheart.
Um
uh this is very curious question. I
never ran into it. It says at many
spiritual meetings and seminars there's
more women than men and yet
traditionally it has been men who have
been the great avatars
etc.
Huh? I never question answered that
before or questioned it before.
It I suppose it depends on the spiritual
depends on the community. Depends on the
community because there's many
communities where they're practically
all men especially uh the Middle East
etc.
Uh any congregation is almost 100% men.
I don't know if you even let women in a
mosque do they
100% men. So it depends somewhat on the
culture, depends on time, availability.
It could be well, we've never asked this
before, whether the the woman is more
interested in um the qualities, the
qualities of life, whereas the man is
more interested in the materiality of
life.
A good friend of mine right now is is
sawing wood and hammering things instead
of here. Why is that?
Just not into it.
I asked him, I said, "How come you're
not there?" Well, I wasn't into it. I
was making a box.
When uh consciousness chooses the
feminine dimension, it's seeking to
evolve that aspect of its wholeness.
Correct. Resistance. Yes. So, the it's
reaching out. Let's see if we have the
choice.
um there is a karmically um granted
choice of gender. Okay. So, we could
choose the woman to be the woman because
we realize that we're a hard-hearted
materialist and and we choose a feminine
lifetime to learn nurturance,
uh softness,
the great feminine virtues. So, we want
to own who's that feminine goddess.
Who's the goddess? Um you know
>> yes yes coion right so we could own
>> no that's different terminology um
anyway it could be that the feminine
lifetime is then to nurture those
aspects
which are not within the usual realm of
testosterone.
Testosterone is going down the highway
with tattoos on a motorbike and
in a Harley-Davidson.
And why would he want to be at an airy
fairy seminar? You know what I'm saying?
This is not the lifetime for that. He's
still proving his macho and learning how
to handle being a male and what to do
with all that testosterone
besides having it kill you.
Testosterone is the most fatal substance
on the planet.
Kills more people than anything else.
I mean, all the wars, that's all
testosterone.
Marshalling and marshalling all that
testosterone with all the flags and the
music waving and the bravado and being
the hero. And
that's all testosterone.
Testosterone kills more people than
anything else on the planet.
in its biologic expression. Read the
fact.
You look at Adolf Hitler up there.
Testosterone. Testosterone. Get that
testosterone up with a flag. Deciceand
Uber Alas. Everybody goes off.
They do it in Japan. They do it in
China. They do it in Nank King. They do
it all over the planet. Century after
century.
That's the rule of testosterone.
Uh when the consciousness level of
mankind reaches beyond 500, they'll call
ancient history the ages of
testosterone.
Aggression, greed, murder, war,
hostility, bombing.
Imagine bombs in your shoes. I mean, is
that demented or what?
All right. And yet, historically, the
great avatars, etc. have been men.
That's also correct.
I think the reason is because the the
nerve the strain on the nervous system
as you go up to really very advanced
high levels which are beyond this chart
as you go to the levels beyond 600 I
think the strain on the nervous system
becomes enormous as you get up around
the seven beyond the 700s it becomes
almost beyond the doable
the
strain of the energy the constant pain,
sort of agonizing feeling of hot wires
being ripped out of your nervous system
all the time. Any any kind of negativity
that you hold within your consciousness,
it's just you got put in the electric
chair and they they got they got it 10
volts below kill, you know, and you've
got to find out what that is. You've got
to clear that with very intense prayer.
Uh and only with the help of the Holy
Spirit does it even resolve. So, it's
arduous. I don't think it's um I think
that's what it is. We'll just see.
Um
the physical there is the physical
physicality of the man is needed to
handle that kind of energy resistance.
The physicality is really brutal. uh
seem to perfect
uh love and devotion.
And then to go beyond that into the like
800s and all
requires um
almost like a testosterone driven
onepointed ferocity. It's a ferocity
to grit and walk through the day
with this ex agonizing
almost paralyzing pain to act and behave
normally and at the same time searching
what it is in you that's out. Is it
coming from out there? Is it coming from
within you? Is it coming from your own
karma? Is it coming from the collective
to try and track down the origin of it?
you know.
Uh
so I I think that's what the answer is.
It has nothing to do with uh femininity
or masculinity. It has to do with I
think just the capacity of the physical
body to handle shoveling tons of coal.
There are women that can do it, but not
statistically. They're not the great sho
cold shovelers of mankind. And
uh why would anybody want to be?
I mean, when when you've got this kind
of a body, it means you're being really
called to perfect certain things. And I
think some people that deny gender are
are really denying the spiritual reality
that this gender is supposed to be
teaching them. And they're delaying
their own maturation.
Just like the man has to learn to
overcome fear in the face of death, you
got to be able to walk into bullets. If
you don't walk into bullets, you just
don't get over a certain level.
Forgotten country, there comes a day
when you just got to walk into bullets.
And that's sort of a testosterone kind
of a thing. You know,
the woman faces the same thing but
differently in the context of nurturance
and childbirth etc. She risks her life
over and over and traditionally the
women lost their lives frequently
uh childbirth fever and died in
childbirth. So in my grandparents day
our family bible you know out of five
children three die and the mother then
eventually then the birth of the eighth
child dies. So that was very very
common. So the great risk of
was the willingness to give one's life
for nurturance for continuence
uh out of compassion and love for one's
children and the continuation of the
race. So it just to me it's it has
nothing to do with political
correctness. It has to do with the
obviousness
of what the task would be in one form
rather than another form. You know what
I'm saying?
So
if individuals and high fives and sixes
are holding up the consciousness of the
rest of the world, what happens when
they die?
Does every level consciousness remain
within the world?
Um, yes, I believe so. I mean, that's
just my opinion. The answer to that is
yes. Yes, because it becomes part of the
collective consciousness of mankind. So
you see every time you forgive someone
or choose to forgive rather than hate to
um
every time you ch ch ch ch ch ch ch ch
ch ch ch ch ch ch choose mercy over
revenge.
This has not only a karmic consequence
to yourself but to the collective
consciousness of mankind.
You see we saw the consciousness evolves
the cal calibrated level consciousness
of life itself evolves over time and in
this new book I sort of track it from
its
appearance on earth in and you might say
the ooze
the ooze what it's what's calibrated
level consciousness of the ooze you know
what I'm saying the primordial ooze and
then out of that the most important
thing was that it doesn't happen as a
chemical accident the chemical um the
scientific viewpoint of evolution is
that life started you know and
accidentally all these chemicals got
together and in the right bright
sunshine and bang you had life but
that's a category error life is a
totally different category from
chemicalness um
so anyway the level of consciousness
of life on this planet has continuously
gone up or the the consciousness level
of mankind has constantly gone up. Let's
just redo the consciousness that the
level the consciousness of mankind at
the time of Jesus Christ we have
permission to do that resistance was
approximately 100 resistance the
conscious level of mankind as a whole
was 100 okay so the impact of Christ on
conscious level of mankind was to raise
it dramatically resist the impact of the
Buddha on conscious level of mankind was
to raise it dramatically resist the
Impact of Krishna resist the impact of
all the great sages and gurus and
saints. The impact of Mother Teresa on
the consciousness of mankind is to
uplift it. Resist.
All right. The the impact of turning
over the beetle helplessly lying on his
back is to raise the consciousness level
of mankind. Resist. So you don't have to
be a great recognized saint to
profoundly affect u the evolution of
consciousness. So we see it's gone up
tremendously,
tremendously.
Um,
all right. We've handled most of the
questions. Question is suicide. I've
never checked out suicide.
We asked permission if we have a
permission to check it out.
We have permission to check out suicide
in this audience right now resist. Okay.
Uh, I'll give you my intuitive
understanding of it. The um
karmic consequences of suicide are no
different
than
than that of
um the state of consciousness which led
them to it in the first place exist.
The physicality of it is rel is
irrelevant.
So if you commit suicide because you are
in a state of grief at 60, the only
thing that happens is you go out of body
and you find yourself at 60 resistant.
So it doesn't solve the problem.
Now you don't have a physical body.
You're in your spiritual body and you
still got the same dilemma
which may or may not be beneficial.
Okay. I don't know people. I don't want
to jump with the go with the world's
presumptions to not have a physical body
could be actually an advantage at that
point. Resist. No. H. It's better to
keep the physical body until its karma
runs out. Resist. Okay. So, if one
commits suicide then prior to
the karmic timing of the leaving of this
physical body, you hang out in the what
do you call it?
>> I don't know. No.
>> Uh,
>> I can smell when they come around this
>> discarnate. Okay. All right.
>> So, you've got three more years to to
live because we said the karmic
karmically the age of the body is
already set. The time and date of death
is already set. Let's reconfirm that
time and
time the time of b of death is already
karmically set for this lifetime or is
it okay? So if you don't see it out,
let's say you commit suicide 3 years
before you're let's say you're destined
to die at 72 and you knock yourself off
at 68, you're going to have to spend 3
years on the other side. Resist until
that karma is over. Resist. You're going
to be a discarnate resist. Okay.
All right. So now you've got the misery
that led you to do it and the
physicality, the karmic commitment. I
don't understand that because I've never
researched it. A lot of this we're
talking about is somewhat irrelevant,
but it is irrelevant, right? But
spiritual questions come up because you
have a microscope, all kinds of things
you wouldn't have bothered with. Now you
got to run and pull them out of the pond
and look at them.
So to some degree, we're doing that. But
it is a natural question. Um
I think uh yes. Okay. uh praying for the
individual who has committed suicide may
we have permission to ask this resist is
beneficial to them resist it is
beneficial in other words okay so
praying for the person uh who was
convinced I would be then beneficial and
help them to overcome their guilt about
it and all
so that's not an you know who was it
that did a book on death the first
famous one the German doctor, huh?
>> Right. And and others
um
have I think she wrote that um the Oh,
yes. the near-death experiences of
people who tried suicide
were not not any different than those
who had were dying of natural causes. In
other words, there didn't seem to be in
her observation or studies
any identifiable negative consequence at
the time
because what you're going to experience
is exactly what you're experiencing
while you're in the body. The
hopelessness or desperation
uh is going to continue whether you're
in the body or the out of out of the
body.
So there's no let's see
um
the karmic consequences are are due to
the state of mind that led to the
action resist. All right. So it's
spiritual intention that sets the karmic
cost or consequence. Resist. All right.
So it isn't the physicality that's
important.
So if one did it out of hate, out of
rage, out of despair, out of getting
even,
uh out of retaliation, out of uh
you know skewering somebody else with
guilt, he made me do it. He let me you
made me do it. Note that skewerism.
So the extreme hostility of that.
So you're stuck with the karma of the
extreme hostility which led you to try
and skewer somebody else with a lifetime
of guilt because you knocked yourself
off. Right? So we're still dealing then
with the price is the price and the
quality of it all is occurring within
the level of consciousness of which the
physicality is then the acting out of
it.
It would seem we'll ask this last then
we'll do it that the karma is really no
worse just because one acted on it was
the karma is actually no worse
it's already worse that's why you did it
in other words the worstness has already
happened already that's why so the
suicide is really the consequence of uh
the despair and the self-hatred or
whatever whatever it may be u that led
you to do it in the first place. So it's
again intention which seems to
um
uh determine the karmic consequences.
All right. Now we ask if there are any
more questions and then we'll go on with
the lecture. If there's any more
questions, we'll answer them first. Any
more questions about some of the things
that we've raised already?
>> The coming time frame for the body, can
that be extended?
Um
>> I got I never got that it was a yes. The
karmic con the karmic
u lifetime of the body the karma of the
body is already set at birth resist.
It's alterable resist. It's alterable.
Resist. Alterable for worse. Resist. You
can alter it for worse.
uh you can uh in let's see increase the
longevity through spiritual
uh alignment resist
the the lifetime would tend to be more
healthy and extended just due to the
energy of the spirituality resist oh I
see yes
>> um yeah okay because the energy
um
we have in the audience a doctor who did
a study on the relationship between
spirituality and survival from serious
illness such as HIV
and um
very statistically accurate and very
scientific from an academic viewpoint
and it demonstrated that spiritual
alignment with spiritual values. You can
speak if you wish to. Anybody you want
to speak up doc or not?
>> Huh?
>> Anyhow, the point of the study was that
uh the longevity was related to
um spiritual commitment that spiritual
commitment tended to increase survival
rate from any illness. And anybody who's
have been in a course of miracles group
knows that because in every course of
miracles group we've seen people with
hopeless advanced fatal diseases and
they're still walking around and some
are at these meetings in fact who had
uh very slim chance of recovering.
There's some here today. Uhhuh.
>> Altruistic behavior and
nonjudgmentalist.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Altruistic behavior and
non-judgmentalists.
So those are
general spiritual principles
uh non-judgmental
and altruism
uh the thinking of the welfare of others
the opposite of the egoentricity of
narcissism
which is the infatilism which is the
basis of criminality and all the things
that newspapers.
Uh so it's really maturation then to
stop thinking about me and my wants and
my desires
and blaming others and accept
responsibility.
So the altruistic person who turns over
the beetle then has a much higher chance
of surviving everything. And I think
that's been proven with heart disease,
heart attacks.
It was the famous heart surgeon that
wrote about it, did the first study on
it. And um
uh
that those people who had a spiritual
orientation to their life had a much
higher survival rate from
uh coronary artery disease and every
other disease. They had a long much
better longevity.
Um so the answer was yes you can
increase the longevity of the uh life of
the body then by the sheer what you've
changed is the energy field in which
it's uh being nurtured. Yeah.
Somebody had another question.
>> Yes.
>> You hear me?
material common everyday that comes up
even start.
>> What is she asking? How you escape the
attraction of the world? And it's Huh?
>> Oh, the dualism of the world. Yeah.
Well, you don't have to be attracted to
it.
we can be fine with doing whatever we're
doing regardless of problems that may
come up right but I think what happens
is that
is that we're so used to thinking
dualistically that that holds us so
strongly
>> yes there there's a certain amount of
spiritual work one does just on one's
relationship to the world in general
the ones in us who are glamorized by by
it.
You know, most people are glamorized by
it. The ones who are attracted to the
sensationalism of it, the excitement of
it, the drama,
the societ, the society you're talking
about is the ego projected out there for
us to observe and learn from. So the
value and I use social examples in my
writings and talks because the ego
projected out there is now dramatized on
channel 15 for you to witness. Uh and um
so without being personally in involved
in it in particular,
the more painless way is to witness it
and learn from the observation of what
is going on in society and then you can
see it within yourself and clear it.
It's much easier to see it out there. So
you can see the
the the difficulties of positionality in
the world and the price that is paid for
it. And this makes it somewhat easier to
accept in yourself that this is a
natural human proclivity.
We're talking about softening up the
super ego before you start examining
yourself with the microscope
and detailed uh very intense spiritual
work which people eventually get into
those that are really committed.
Eventually, you get into rather intense
meditations in which every single thing
is examined with great intensity.
By now, you're sophisticated enough to
know that that's not just a personal
defect of wonderful wonderful you. That
this is
the rubbing off of the nature of human
society. So, the society is merely a
projection of the collective ego.
And so what we learned by watching the
news and reading the newspaper people
say well shouldn't you know there was a
year period of time when the energy was
totally prevailing and there was no
interest in the world or anything went
on in the world never wrote a paper
magazine I didn't own a TV or radio
no idea what went on for 10 years or so
one can conversely develop an aversion
to the world.
So
to be perfectly balanced, there's
neither attraction nor aversion. One is
not repelled by the world and say, "Oh,
I can't watch TV. That's all disgusting
stuff." Uh
nor can you be attracted. So the perfect
spiritual balance is neither aversion or
attraction.
Because you have no aversion or
attraction, you don't have to avoid it.
to return to the world, you you can't
really have any deep aversion or
attraction.
It isn't a matter of being detached.
It's a matter of being nonattached.
If you're detached from the world, which
I did for a good 10 years, the world has
no significance, importance, etc. You're
detached. You are not involved in the
world. You have no involvement in the
world. Whatever it is that you become is
affecting the world just by the essence
of that which it is. But there is no
actions on your part in one way or the
other.
That's to be that's the perfect
renunciate
and the life of the aesthetic. So for
some years I was a an aesthetic
renunciate. Never went anywhere. There
was nothing to see. No social life was
uninteresting.
It was all irrelevant.
Then there's a difference between
non-attachment
and detachment.
So then there was a relinquishment
of detachment as a positionality,
as an aversion, an avoidance.
Um to see the world as a trap and
therefore avoid it, which is the
downside of being a renunciate.
There is a there is a time when your own
spiritual reality has be sufficiently
strong that you can walk outside the
closters and still remain that which you
are. You can speak to strangers and eat
food and touch people and either mate or
not mate depending on the suitability of
your lifestyle.
You so the detached person is a
renunciate avoids the world and this can
become itself a deterrent to
enlightenment.
If it's neither this nor that then you
can participate.
So the person who does return to the
world does so on the level of
nonattachment.
It would not be safe if you're still
attached because it'll suck you right
back in. And that's why Ramach Krishna
forbid his followers to touch sex sec
you know have nothing to do with sex or
money because the energy the attraction
was too strong especially at a young age
to be nonattached then means it's okay
if it goes this way and it's okay if it
goes that way and if I see the parade I
will enjoy it and if I don't see the
parade I won't I won't miss it. Neutral
is a very good space in which to work at
that neutral
uh you're you're released from your
attachments and your avoid your
avoidance and attachments. You're pretty
free.
You can either stay or leave. It's okay.
If we make it to the movie on time,
we'll watch it. If we don't get there,
we won't go. It's okay either way.
You're not attached. You don't have to
cry that you missed it. You don't have
to get furious that your partner was
fixing their hair and you couldn't get
out the door in time and therefore you
missed the movie or whatever. Yeah, you
know how life goes with people. A daily
bickering life, you know. Well, if you
had hurried up, we would have made it on
time. Now we now they've changed the
price and now it's a 450. If we got
there when it's 350. So life becomes
this little bickering trivia
in which you're attached to winning and
losing and winning and losing face,
winning and losing control.
All right. So then at a certain point uh
one becomes nonattached.
Therefore to win or to lose is really
irrelevant. If the other person wins the
argument great you won the argument.
Oh you let them win the argument. Why
not?
It's fun letting people win. Did you
ever do it? They teach you how a dollar
20 and think you didn't catch them. I
love to have a dollar 20. Why not? You
know what I mean?
What difference does it make? No.
>> You're not attached to winning. You're
not attached to losing. You're not
afraid of winning and afraid of losing.
You're afraid if you win that you'll get
attached to winningness and get
addicted. And that's what happens in the
casino. So, the casino lets you win
enough
to get you hooked. you know now you'll
keep coming back until you're cleaned
out.
So that's the attachment. So the
attachments then which we're trying to
re relinquish are really coming out of
the solar plexus.
So the solar everybody thinks sex is the
base chakra. No, it's the attachment.
It's the solar plexus attachment to that
activity and what it does for your ego
and your sense of satisfaction and your
sense of aloneeness, desiraability, your
self-esteem. So, it's all the things
that are piled into the meaning of that.
So, we're attached to the meaning of
things and that's why we're addicted to
certain activities.
So the perfect
practice then uh in a meditative uh
contemplative kind of a practice is
neither attachment nor aversion.
You neither hate it nor are you addicted
to it. You don't have to avoid it.
If you're attached to things then you
have to avoid them. You can't have one
piece of chocolate because you know
you'll eat the whole box.
I remember when I finally got off
chocolate and I'd released I'd let go of
chocolate for a long time and chocolate
kept coming up. Finally, I completely
lost any desire, thought or appreciation
for chocolate altogether. And I said,
"Wow, I'm off chocolate. I'm free of
chocolate. I got unhooked from Diet
Pepsi years past. Now I have one can all
day." So all these things you get hooked
on. I remember when I got free of
chocolate. It was hysterical because the
very next night, the course of miracles
group was coming out from New York and
they had about 40 or 50 of them in the
house and they brought this huge
chocolate cake.
So I didn't have to avoid it because I
wasn't going to get hooked by it again.
So I could either have the chocolate
cake or not have the chocolate cake. It
was a great sense of freedom. I didn't
have to avoid it for fear I get hooked
on it. And the same with Diet Pepsi. I
finally got it hooked from Diet Pepsi.
And now I can have a can or not have a
can. There was a time if I left the
house and there was no Diet Pepsi with
me, I had to turn it around and drive
five five miles back to the house to get
a Diet Pepsi. That's being hooked,
right?
All right. Now, if I leave without a
Diet Pepsi, I I don't need one. So the
freedom to enjoy things then means being
free from aversion or attraction. You do
that through the spiritual disciplines
the major ones that you don't have to go
to a guru who said 800 to get off these
these very important ones. You're
looking at 200 to two you're looking how
to get to 250. You're not looking how
you don't have to have a world famous
guru or something because this is
spiritual practice to let go of your
attachments and your aversions. And once
you're free then you're much quicker.
It's much you're much more free to move
up more rapidly. So I think these basic
spiritual thingseticism
uh versus addiction uh all these things
are very important. So the 200s are
extremely important because it's really
there that you go free. You see the
experience of God over here is freedom.
Huh? Experience of God once you're over
200 over here. Where is God over here?
He's um
well he should be around two around 200
right right here right here about
around in here I don't know what
happened to goddess freedom I god view
is one of
freedom is supposed to be in there must
be on a different chart but
uh about 210 you experience god is as is
freedom you suddenly own your own
freedom that you're free to choose
you're not hooked this way and you're
not hooked that
and u God has experiences freedom. So
it's sort of an exuberant uh state of
spiritual growth when you realize that
God is not vindictive.
Um
any other questions on the subject?
Here we go.
Then I we'll after after we finish the
questions I'll be glad to see people
personally or sign books or anything and
then
>> question about the karma like it's pre
predetermined your karma you come in
with a certain amount of karma to work
out
>> and so is it to your benefit
to know what that is?
I think we're we're going to have a
whole lecture where we're going to focus
on it. Um to understand karma is a great
spiritual benefit if you're a spiritual
seeker.
One of the difficulties with western
style religion etc is it doesn't really
comprehend karma nor does it realize its
importance. It comprehends it in in that
it knows that um negative
behaviors in this lifetime will result
in a negative consequence after you
leave the physical body. So although it
denies it believes in karma,
uh it doesn't. What it really means when
it denies karma is reincarnation. It
means it doesn't believe in physical
reincarnation.
All religions believe in karma. Let me
tell you differently. The whole point of
religion is the awareness and the
responsibility that the spirit body is
going to continue along after the this
physicality.
Uh so if people were more aware in the
western world that every action has
a consequence a very profound
consequence and may have a very
long-term
consequence then there would be greater
responsibility
responsibility.
So those
cultures which are more sophisticated as
far as their understanding of karma are
much more aware that every action has a
consequence
and it has a long-term consequence. So
we're going to do a whole session on
karma. I forget the specific question
she asked. Oh yes because consciousness
itself transcends many physicalities,
many lifetimes. Uh it goes on for eons
actually. Let's see how long
consciousness goes on. You have
permission to ask that the consciousness
uh had gone on for eons. Just
therefore,
we're talking about eons. This
consciousness,
the consciousness uh present in this
room has gone on for eons
to reach this degree of evolution and
complexity and consciousness and
awareness. And there are many dimensions
where no such thing goes on.
There's many dimensions in which we are
already would be considered masters and
there's other dimensions in which we
would be considered bumbling idiots.
Let's see if that's so
there are dimensions in which we uh this
group here would be considered spiritual
geniuses resist. We would be considered
saints resistance. We would be
considered saviors resistance.
So compared to other dimensions, this
group here, we're already extremely well
advanced. Compared to other more evolved
dimensions, we are bumbling idiots
resist
barely out of the cradle resist and in
kindergarten resist. All right.
All right. So if there's an infinite
number of universes and the infinite
number of universes are expanding at an
infinite rate. Just the mathematical
probability is that there are infinite
numbers of universes more advanced than
our own and infinite number of universes
less advanced.
That's okay, right?
That's okay. Some are ahead, some are
behind. Yeah.
>> Could you talk about how pesticides can
>> Oh, yes. effect of person.
>> Uh that came as a result of an
experiment which we've done a number of
times
in this country and others. Um we don't
have time to do it today but if you take
two apples one you don't know which is
which. And I say everybody look at this
apple the whole crowd goes weak. I say
look at this apple crowd goes strong. We
know experimentally that the
consciousness knows which one has the
pesticide in it.
It's been done blind on us uh as well.
When we were in Korea, whether we were
handed two packages of green stuff and
she said, "Let's have the crowd
calibrated on it." You know, I didn't
expect it wasn't programmed. She just
came up with it. And um uh so we did.
And the one bag of greens, I think it
was cabbage, made everybody in the crowd
go weak. And one bag made them all go
strong. And the one that made him logo
weak was a pesticide just like the apple
experiment. So that's what leads to her
question.
If merely looking at it, picking up on
its or aura can make you go weak, then
what in the world would be the effect of
ingesting that stuff for a lifetime? And
what would be the effect on a whole
civilization such as ours where
everybody's stuffed to the gole with
pesticides?
Scary, right?
We have permission to ask about this.
We've never asked about this before. Um,
oh, I get what it is. Um, the negative
energy of the pesticide compared to
one's spiritual power is extremely weak.
Is this Oh, yes. see positive energies
that because you're looking looking at
laws rhythmic progression
uh the fact that you're you're kind to
the person next door is so powerful
that a little bit bit of pesticide
doesn't really
kill you. In other words, the negative
is so weak.
If it weren't for the fact that the neg
ne negative energies are weak, mankind
would not exist. We said 85% of the
people on the planet calibrate below
200. If their power was equal to this,
the planet would have exploded millions
of years ago.
All right? So the negative effect of the
pesticide is so weak.
All right? So it's like one zillionth of
an ounce of the negative and just one
loving thought as you pass an old lady
on the street you just sort of your
heart goes to her has already negated
all that. So if you're very loving and
pure in heart you can need a lot of
pesticides.
That is a fact. Resist
like smoking doesn't affect some people
at all negatively. Resist. Yeah, it's
just because it the chemical effect is
so small compared. That's why 15%
counterbalance is 85% resist. All right.
All right. So, pesticides do affect um
affect us negatively because we can
demonstrate and we could do it again in
this audience that merely looking at it
makes you go weak. But that of course is
a kinesiologic response in which you're
trying to decide whether that's above or
below 200. That doesn't tell you how
much power it has. It may make you go
weak, but it may be very very weak. Huh?
So we don't have to be afraid of it.
What I mean? In other words, our
positive energy is so powerful that we
can handle a little negativity without
going down the drain.
uh be a good thing or none of us would
be here. We'd all be killed just by
breathing a couple of breaths of air
or drinking the water. So
perhaps some of the environmental fears
are they're correct but exaggerated.
They're given far more power than they
really have because man if he changes
his mind about something can totally
shift it. enormous amounts of energy and
power
>> and the weak the power of the weak the
negativity is too weak.
>> What?
>> Your chest.
>> Oh, the chest X-ray.
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, they're not interested in that.
>> Yes. Well, the we were saying yes that
uh positive um positive thinking is good
for you, right? Uh Oh, yes. Well,
anyway, my own chest X-ray has never
been too great. Uh it had I had aviary
tuberculosis, which is incurable. You
get it from birds. And the chemicals
that cure regular tuberculosis don't
cure aviary. But anyway, for 12 or
$15,000 worth of multiple medications,
all of which makes you nauseated. after
a year you got a 30% chance it may cure
you and save your life from aviary
tuberculosis
or they could surgically take it out and
do both to which I said no
and uh then there was all kinds of
scarring adaltois I've got multiple
x-rays over the years you know and I
thought so if you die of avary
tuberculosis I mean who who cares
beats being run over by a truck you know
what I mean you got to go somewhere
people people forget about, you know,
this this running after longevity is
when you block this hole, the water's
going to have to find another hole out.
You're going to have to get off this
planet some way, folks. And if you don't
go this way, you're going to be forcing
yourself to go this way. You know what
I'm saying? If it's not a truck, it's
going to be a harpoon or it's going to
be an earthquake or
see cancer or something. I mean, you're
going to force yourself out of here
someway because nobody stays here
permanently. So, it's only a matter of
your choices. So anyway, I told the guy,
"No, I'm not going to do that."
And so they did a biopsy without
anesthesia. We tried bonoscopy without
anesthesia, which doesn't work
because the physiologic response, you
can't control it. And uh so anyway,
after all this drama, I'm sorry I ever
saw a doctor in the first place. I
really am against seeing doctors, to
tell you the truth, because you have one
thing wrong with you. By the time you
leave there, you're a wreck. They you've
got anemia and your cholesterol is too
high. Oh, Jesus. Now you're Now you're
an invalid. You're a walking invalid.
You're scared of your diet. You can't
have a cheeseburger anymore. Every
cheeseburger is killing you. Ah, it's
horrible.
Your life is down the tubes. Well,
anyway, so if you want to spend all this
money on all these drugs and be
nauseated for a year, you got a 30%
chance it'll cure it. Or you can just
croak. I said, I'll croak. Why? So
anyway, I just did a little bit of
processing on it. I didn't do much
processing really actually come to think
of it. No, I quit resisting it. That was
it. Neither aversion nor attraction. I
thought, well, I'm not going to be
attracted to dying of it because it's
nice to get out of here. And neither am
I going to have an aversion. So, I did
non neither attraction nor aversion on
it. Well, then I had to have a check-in
for someone chest X-ray. Oh, yeah.
Because of migraine headaches or
something.
He said, "Well, it could be cancer of
the lung and it's gone up to your
brain." Oh, that's sure. You see what
you get?
tell you I mean there's there's places
where doctors are handy but as a general
rule
could be cancer from the lung you're a
smoker so you got cancer the lung has
gone up to your brain and this is giving
you so we'll get electron we'll get a
skull x-ray we'll get what else what was
I going to tell
>> yeah chest x-ray right so anyway the
chest x-ray came back um perfect
everything that was in the chest is
gone. No scarring,
no tumors, no tuberculosis, no
adalcttois, no fibrosis, nothing
clear. That was just two weeks ago.
Yeah.
You know, it doesn't make any difference
one way or the other.
And if God asked me, I'd say, "Look, I
mean, I thought I really want to finish
this book. That's really what I want to
do."
And uh so I felt a little guilty that I
wasn't taking a positive action. I said,
"If this knocks out before you've got
maybe you got some karmic obligation to
do this book and you're going to have to
come back all over again, do this book
now." So that's those are the mind games
that your mind plays with and then you
realize that that has nothing to do with
reality. but appropo of what we were
talking about healing this I'd forgotten
about the uh that whole thing you know
that was a whole drama in itself to live
out those things so I feel sympathy for
anybody who's going to doctors and
getting any kinds of diagnostic
treatments and and all that because I
know what's involved not only that but
it's very boring to sit in doctor's
offices forever not a one of them can be
on time they own a clock or what I mean
you know in my office they got
appointment at 10 4 after 10 is late as
I make weight. You know, you can sit in
the doctor's office and two and three,
three hours goes by. So, it's a heck of
a way to blow your time. I don't advise
sickness as a way of resolving
psychological problems.
And I tell everybody, no matter what's
wrong with you, do go do the course of
miracles and after you finish it, then
come back and see me about it. You know,
because there's no point wasting
physical time on that which merely cures
itself when you're willing to forgive
yourself and everybody else.
And so I think that's the end of the
questions. All right. And then we'll
just we'll meet with anybody who wishes
to meet and I'll talk to anybody
personally.
>> We have one more question and then
that's it.
>> Oh yes. Okay.
>> We did before already.
>> Okay. Let's just see. Let's do the
change. So I don't remember what the
number is. This group has gone up over
two points during this lecture. Over
three points over four points. Five
points. Six points. 7 points.
goes up seven points, eight points. Some
people have gone up over 20 points or
some people over 30 points. Yeah, the
group is as a whole used to go up around
5 8 9 10. Today was nine points as a
group. Uh but some within the group uh
made major jumps. So
>> 20
>> yeah 20 points. Uh that'd be five points
a lifetime, four lifetimes. uh
just certain information itself. The
reason I like to share it is just the
information itself already has a
benefit.
If you know that
um
if you know that
you cannot experience your own physical
death, it's not possible.
instantly leave the body just as the
animal does as the physical death occurs
and you are the witness of the
physicality of it. Nobody can experience
their own physical death. It's not
possible. You'd have to be there and
you're not there anymore. So, how could
you experience it? You know, doesn't
even make sense. To know that is a
relief. To know that the time of your
departure is already preset is a relief.
Why worry about it? You don't have to
worry about it. It's all preset. You
might as well have a good time. Enjoy
yourself.
If that's set, the calibrated level of
consciousness is already set at the time
of birth. You're already born at
whatever you start out at. So, you don't
have to feel guilty that, you know,
you're not a genius if you're born with
an IQ of 82. You're going to learn what
you can at 82 because that's what you're
supposed to be doing at 82 is learning
how to spell. Uh so, we accept that
which we are. We say we give thanks to
the Lord that these are many things that
are taken out of our hands that they
would be a great burden to us. And we
thank thee Lord for taking on the
responsibility of our life, our human
life, our parents, our departion and our
ultimate destiny.
Oh.
Um,
we did and we saw that it calibrated
much higher than pronouncing it
differently. Consequently, we'll go.
And I thank you all.
I love them all. They're so adorable.