Somebody asked about the severity of
menopause. Um
you see the the the mind is so powerful
that what you hold in mind tends to
manifest. Right? That's a pretty
well-known generality. The whole course
of miracles is based upon transcending
that illusion that you are at the effect
of anything out there.
So if a person is having severe symptoms
of anything menopause being one of them,
the prevailing belief systems about
menopausal systems are sufficiently
strong as to guarantee you you're
developing menopausal symptoms just out
of the fact that you automatically will
pick up that belief system from our
culture. There's no way to avoid it. You
turn on TV and there's, you know,
somebody somebody pitching something for
menopause. So even if you don't believe
in menopause, you sure will if you hang
out in our society. And uh so that
prevailing thought form then you you
give belief to it. The um truth as
reveal I I think the course of miracles
is very excellent in that. Once you get
below beyond lesson 76, you realize that
you are not at the effect of anything
out there. Nothing out there has any
power over you. Unless you believe in
menopause, you cannot get menopausal
symptoms.
You say, "Well, I don't believe in
that." Yes, you do. Uh unconsciously,
you're holding that or some aspect
within yourself is holding that as a
truth. Because of that, it's
manifesting. And I always tell people
who have illnesses of one kind or
another, do the course of miracles and
hope for the best
because you don't know what your karma
is. But if you advance to a high degree,
you can transcend that karma and you
won't even be subject to that.
question.
>> You see, because yeah, you because you
see karma is a whole area for
investigation. In kinesiology, one of
the neatest things about it is you can
ask questions about whether you got it
in this lifetime or or did it come from
elsewhere? You know, um, everybody's
mean to me. Well, why do you suppose
everybody's mean to you? Well, because
if you were once mean to lots of people,
they they've just been hanging on the
other side waiting for you. And now
they're getting even. So all all you can
do is u try to correct that karmic
propensity. Those are only propensities.
Karma is only propensities. Sometimes
it's so exact in its manifestation
that you wonder uh it seems like more
than a propensity.
In the middle of that surgery I had on
the groin. They did a hernia operation
with no anesthesia.
I knew I knew and in fact I saw the guy.
I know exactly what I did. I saw the
error was and I saw this was the undoing
of it in my strict superego conscience.
Only by experiencing what he experienced
could I
write the karmic wrong that I had done
out of what I took against myself is
spiritual cowardice. I didn't have the
courage to finish the job
>> there. I'm going to ask that question.
Does there was is there a physiological
response when an angel comes into your
aura? Yeah. Right. U in the in the early
early stages and I'm going to get to
your next question. In the earlier
stages the the experience I had was
uh a tingling like a tingling. No, it
was like a flow of energy going up the
spine going up your whole back. It was
exquisite. It was a sweet uh like a low
low energy orgasm almost. It was
exquisite and it just was continuous and
it went up the back and it seemed to go
up the spine into the brain
and in the brain it created a sweet
incredible sensation. And if you focused
over on this side, the sensation would
focus to this side of the brain and this
side of the brain. And then it came down
and the experience was that when you
went by something that needed some kind
of spiritual help, probably a group of
people praying or something, this energy
would was still exquisite. It would go
out the heart and go to that
uh automobile accident or people about
to have a fight or couple uh arguing in
a subway train or something and it would
go there and then sort of accomplish its
purpose and the people the argument
would stop and all of a sudden the
energy would stop, you know. So that was
that kind of energy.
Uh that kind of energy disappeared
eventually
and
so long as consciousness remained
stationary
uh there was no problem. But I think you
can get tingling and uh all kinds of
sensations and as I told you it got
further any kind of error within the
aura was exquisitly painful. What were
you going to ask? Um, what is your
experience with people who go into past
lives uh and might pick up an illness?
Because I've heard of people who have
been told they had cancer in a past life
and then it became apparent in this
lifetime.
>> Yes. So the question has to do with
karmic propensities.
One one value of kinesiologic research
is you can ask
um do I have permission to ask about
this? Yes. Is this a propensity uh
coming through from other lifetimes?
Yes. Uh what was the you can then decide
you know find out what was the decision
you made. Don't forget they all have to
do with intention. Something could be uh
you could run over somebody with a
motorcycle but the intention was not
murder. So
even the law recognizes the difference
but it could be you know karma is a
whole very difficult subject. It's not
popular in the west. It's karma is
confused with reincarnation. The two
things are not the same thing at all.
Karma is one thing, incarnation is
another. Uh karma does not determine uh
they're two different subjects actually.
Jesus Christ did not to our knowingness
say much about it. He didn't say
anything about reincarnation, but he
sure did say plenty about karma.
All religions teach karma. All religions
teach that what you do in this lifetime
is going to have heavy duty consequences
in your life next lifetime whether it's
physical or not. There's absolute
agreement between all religions. Uh
karma is why you avoid sin because you
don't want to descend into the lower
astral.
Um karmic propensities. Um I I think
with kinesiologic research you can find
out what you can about that. It it's
funny. Most people have an intuitive
knowingness of if past lives were
significance. It's almost as if they
know it.
If somebody suggests you, you know, you
you you look just like, you know, you
act just like a pirate sometimes or look
like a pirate and you all sort of a and
you're attracted to these motorcycle
guys who look like pirates. You know, I
recognize these guys from uh they were
the same guys that were on the ship. You
know what I mean? I used to hire them.
We didn't raid other vessels with nimi
pimpies. I'll tell you, you had to be
you got to kill all the guys on the
other ship and steal their gold. I mean,
you can't exactly be
a pussyfoot. You know, they are pretty
rough guys. So I see him back, you know,
same bandanna, same clothes, same
tattoos, same ring in the ear. Nothing's
changed. They just changed them with,
you know, a ship for a motorcycle.
Hang out in gangs. It's the same damn
crew. Same people, right?
>> What about grace, though? The power of
grace.
>> Yes.
Grace is.
almost like the letting go of the
sovereignty allows that which is
sovereign to intercede.
We call that intervention via the Holy
Spirit generally, right? Yeah. That
through contrition, through uh
undoingness, through surrender and
willingness
that um
we create the space for the miraculous
which occurs as
termed as grace. Huh.
Enlightenment itself is
by
God's grace
because all you can do is remove the
impediments. You can only remove the
impediments to higher consciousness. You
cannot cause higher consciousness to
happen.
You can remove the impediments to love
and then love takes over.
uh love having a higher energy tends to
transform the event itself.
So we can remove the impediments but the
final step is by God alone. You know God
only
that we call grace.
Grace means that to our degree of
knowingness, we could not possibly
justify it within any kind of reason.
The reprieve at the last instant even
though you know you committed the crime
and yet suddenly the reprieve come
through.
Some people say it's the earned karma,
good karma from other lifetimes. Huh?
>> What? What is the function of wanting
something better in life? If we if we
feel there's something which somehow
gives us the notion or the sense that
that would be better and it's not
necessarily a high spiritual thing but
just something we seem to naturally want
and then the sort of strength that
wanting focus on it often brings with it
I find also a sense of a higher
vibration even though it's something not
necessarily spiritual.
Isn't that following this higher
vibration, this goal, something which
pushes us along?
>> It isn't necessarily following a higher
vibration. Intention is very powerful if
you remove all the blocks to intention.
It's it's possible to manifest things
that would not otherwise be manifest.
That was a one of the basic teachings of
EST. You remember EST? very hard
seminars training. EST was very big as a
weekend workshop uh training back in the
70s I think it was.
Uh EST would never allow you to have an
excuse to be late if the class started
at 8:00 and you showed up at 8:02.
You had to stop stand there until you
admitted that you that you chose to be
late. So the person say, "Well, there
was traffic and there was this and
that." all these excuses
uh until you finally accepted that your
reason you're late is because you chose
to be late. They wouldn't let you in the
door.
Why? Because you rated something higher
than being on time. So you actually
chose
and you'd rather sleep late than get
leave early enough to make sure that no
delay would get in your way.
Responsibility. So intention if you
remove all the blocks the ifs and ends
and buts in the if you remove all the
excuses intention can be very very
powerful. It it's not that it's a
different energy or vibration doesn't
show necessarily a move up the scale of
consciousness but is much more likely to
to accomplish this objective.
That's what prevails when I catch
chickens.
Nothing stands between me and catching
the chicken. It's like a clear channel
opens between me and the chicken and
this energy shoots through the through
that opening. That's why I would never
engage in karate again or any of those
things because once you've got that
space, you would just kill the other
person in an instant. There's no way
they can stop it because
all considerations are removed.
Therefore, the power shoots through you
and it's the power itself that
accomplishes it. And death in one blow
would be a snap. Yeah. So intention then
is what accomplishes the seeming
impossible. Dedication. That intention,
that dedication is what I was talking
about. When you walk to the razor's
edge, when you let every thought go as
it begins to come up, the willingness to
surrender it, surrender it, surrender
it. Those of you that are in 12step
programs, it'd be like you take the
third step on every single impulse,
thought, feeling
uh as it arises. The willingness to
surrender everything to God. Um, and
that's coming out of the heart.
Somebody's been diagnosed as having an
illness. Uh well
in this case it has to do with attention
deficit disorder. I'll give you a
practical clinician's diagnosis of
definition of how to diagnose ADD and
ADHD. I've had 50 years clinical
experience and right now I probably got
three or 4 hundred patients with these
disorders.
Uh, as a pragmatist, ADD or ADHD is
whatever it gets better with rolin.
People have all kinds of fancy. They
want to do psychological testing. It's
usually a ch, you know, attempt to milk
the parents. There's therapist for ADHD.
Good luck. It's a neurologic condition.
It's genetic. It's due to the fact that
in the pre-entral gyus, we have
suppressor strips. When you cut a
chicken's head off, it goes crazy,
right?
So, the motor neurons automatically
respond via the spinal reflex, except
that there's descending tracks that
suppress it. These are coming from
suppressor strips in the free pre-entral
gyus in the brain, the preoter gyrus.
The suppressor strips, if it wasn't for
the suppressor strips, your your bodies
would all be going in every which way.
See, because you're just dealing with a
spinal reflex. A spinal reflex. If I
touch this, this is going to jerk. It's
only because of the suppressor strip
that this doesn't jerk. Every time I
touch it, every little breeze that goes
by would cause a spasm and a response.
So, the ADHD person is responding
constantly to stimuli that our
suppressor strips hold down. See,
they're always restless. They're always
jumping around. They can't keep their
mind at one thing because of their
distractability.
uh what rin or some medication like that
does is stimulate the prefrontal
pre-entral gyus. So it activates the
suppressor strip. So what would be a
stimulant to a normal person is a
seditive to them and uh it's also used
uh in old folks home. A lot of old folks
black coffee puts them to sleep because
the suppressor the sleep sleep center of
the brain is underactive. So you
stimulate the sleep center and wake them
to go to sleep. So anybody who has ADHD
uh you use what is a trial dose of rolin
if they get instantly they get better
within an hour they'll tell you right
away I can sit still I can focus. I can
think I can behave. I can I can mind
when you say don't slam the door. or I
can remember to not slam the door that
diagnoses it. U whether there's better
treatments or conditions, I don't know.
Uh the kinesiologic test, you know, is a
is a tentative test. I would test it and
say whether or not this person has it or
they don't have it. If they have all the
symptoms, though, I would certainly do a
trial of it. Why? Because an untreated
case of ADHD then compounds itself. The
child can't behave. So, they begin to
get a self-concept that they're bad.
Other people don't like them. They feel
the school's against them. They lose
their interest in learning. They drop
out, hang out in the street and do drugs
and start robbing many stores. So
untreated ADHD is worse than
misdiagnosing it. The worst thing that
can happen is if you don't have ADHD and
you take rin, you're going to be nervous
for an hour or two like you drink too
many coffees. It's better to diagnose it
and treat it. And then if there's
behavioral means of overcoming it, God
bless them. I've never seen it happen,
but it could.
Well, everything's possible to God,
right?
I've never seen anything about it. I
think they just It's a more of a
political position than a clinical
reality.
There's nothing wrong with having ADHD.
I mean, except that if it's untreated,
you get all kinds of negative feedback
from society, and that has the worst
effect.
Um,
and I don't know what this says.
What does that say?
Uh
this is various healing techniques. Yes,
there is a a great variety of healing
techniques as there are spiritual
techniques that calibrate within the
200s. That doesn't mean they're uh not
as good as something that calibrates
higher. It means that it's addressing a
different domain. Reiki, I think, and
all those many of those things calibrate
in the high 200s.
What's important is whether a thing is
integrous or non-integrous.
Reiki doesn't promise to take you to
enlightenment. They don't make that
promise. They just tell you that
we're going to put positive energies in
place of negative energies or whether
it's absent energies or whatever. Um I
would just say, you know, if I have a
disorder, I'd say, is this Raike
therapist over 200? Yeah. U this is
helpful to my Raiki is going to be
helpful or is helpful to my condition.
Yes or no?
>> Oh.
They're asking about
level.
>> Oh yes. Can a person well yes the hope
for progression is to go from a lower
level consciousness to a higher one. And
we presume that all that almost
everybody involved in spiritual work has
that design in their mind and that all
religion has. Well, we know historically
that's not as always the fact due to
errors. Can a person make a mistake and
go down? Yes. Just as just like the
miraculous can occur and you can go up.
Uh
when I got hit in 1965, it was like
that. It was just in one instant
total transformation. The uh mind was
dead. The ego was gone. The person was
no longer there. And there was only the
starting stling magnificent of all of
creation.
Yes. In one instant.
One can also say the make make a mistake
and go down. Um
what precipitated the sudden positive
energy? I'll tell you that and then I'll
tell you some stories about people go
down. Then we'll take another quick
break. Uh and then we'll finish up any
personal questions.
The
the touch from the archangel which was
the mo the motus
of the transformation of consciousness
came as a response from the pits of
hell.
Just as you move up towards the heavens
form becomes less and less dominant and
finally becomes formless.
The descent into hell was similar. that
the sudden into hell came after a long
period of hopeless illness despondency.
I'd been an atheist for years and I
looked to philosophy. I looked to all
kinds of things for the meaning and
significance the truth of the core of
life
and um was on overcome the illness or
find any kind of meaningful spiritual
truth.
uh I already gone through theology and I
saw its intellectual dimensions and
limitations
and um anyway there came a period of
slow descent into hell as I went into
hell forget I was an atheist at the time
a very convinced atheist and
in the upper levels of hell were sort of
like paintings by who is the painter the
famous painter of hell there's all these
tortured things with
Huh?
>> I can't hear.
>> Well, there's an artist that depicts him
graphically.
>> Anyway, it was like that. There's all
these tormented beings and uh I suppose
like the torture chambers of the Nazi
party or something and the screamings
and agony and dismemberments and it was
horrific.
And uh that's what everybody thinks hell
is. Whoa, man. That's just checks for
openers.
This is just this is just game playing.
Uh it gets far worse. It becomes
progressively formless.
The despair now comes from such powerful
depths
that they were never suspected. that the
depths were that deep, that profound,
and pitiles and hopelessness and
despair. And in leaving the world of
form, I remember just like in D, I think
it's in Donniey's inferno, I saw a sign,
or it wasn't like a painted visual sign,
but a knowingness. It said, "Give up all
who pass here or something because there
is no coming back."
And the descent became worse and worse
and the agony became the agony of no
hope throughout all of infinity. And
understand you understand in the
timelessness
it was
form non form it was nonlinear but like
the negative side of nonlinear
beyond form
and again purely subject. It was a
radical subjectivity
of
the other end of what the nonlinear
domain of enlightenment would be. In
that in this pitch blackness of hopeless
despair, the agony was indescribable
because it was of the spirit
and it was in the domain uh just like
the highest level is beyond all time. It
was beyond all time. Because it's beyond
all time, there is no time in which it
could come to an end. And therefore, it
was forever.
It was the the foreverness of hell. It
isn't hell. It's its foreverness. There
was no hope of ever.
And at the depth of all that, the
atheist said
something in the atheist said, "If there
is a god, I ask him to help me.
I didn't hold my breath.
Then everything went blank. And a day or
two, the day later when I came to there
was everything transformed.
So that call came out of the depths of
hell. And I think I did want to the
level was so deep that it took an
archangel at 50,000 to go there.
That's bad, ain't it? And anyway, it
took a 50,000 caliber angel uh to go to
that depths and survive it. Uh you would
have to have great enormous spiritual
power to
persist to walk in and walk out of that
and took me with it.
I forget what that was an answer to
something.
Yes. Can you go worse? Yes.
There's a curiosity that we noticed and
it's only in the last year I really been
looking at it that people will calibrate
higher earlier in their life than later
or vice versa. Uh people will make a
profound jump and jump hundreds of
points in a vertical direction.
I noticed some extremely well-known
gurus and when I would calibrate their
level they were like 200 and something
somewhere even below 200. I said, 'How
can a
well-known
guru worldwide fame calibrate at that?
It's not believable.
Sometimes the writings would be in the
high five 500s
and yet the being was only 190 or one
couldn't understand it. Then I saw and I
knew then from my own experience what
had happened
in in in a very advanced state there
came suddenly a knowingness
it's what I call the confrontation with
the opposite
it's like when you reach a certain level
the power of that on the planet is a
challenge too the satanic luciferic
energies and one almost summons forth
one's opposite.
Um, it once happened through a teacher
once happened through a teacher who had
once been in high space and now came
down. And in talking to him about
uh I wanted to teach you he wanted to
charge for a certain teaching. I said,
you know, teachings are gifts from God.
You can't charge for teaching. You can
charge for the hall. You can charge for
food.
Um I said I would I would like to teach
this to all the um pre all the think of
all the monasteries and seminaries where
people are battling sin and sin is
nothing but an attachment. If you let go
of the attachment sin disappears because
it's only an attachment to begin with. I
wanted to give it away. Well, all of a
sudden,
it's like the person was swept aside and
the doors of hell opened up and this
horrib energy came through and started
to talk in this crazy way that Jesus was
just an astral and Buddha was just an
astral and um it's no good unless people
pay for it. And u
it was bizarre and then and then talking
this got even dumber. that. So there's
suddenly a confrontation with the
opposite of wherever you're at. Uh and
one time the the energy came through not
through a person, not as a entity,
through a person. And um
uh oh yes, that was at a point where one
had transcended personal karma.
What was the energy of that field? Okay,
that was at maybe what 700. Yeah, around
700. Your consciousness had advanced to
a level that you cover around 700.
Suddenly there was like a confrontation
but not with an entity because in the
higher realms there are no entities.
There's no angels. There's no spiritual
guides. All that stuff doesn't exist
there. But there was a presence. This
presence was a knowingness saying
through the knowingness
now that you have transcended personal
karma karma you are no longer
answerable.
There's no consequence to anything that
you do. You have infinite power overall.
One could then choose that power or not.
It was like a rarified. It would be like
being up in a high pass in the Himalayas
sort of visually speaking. But it was
this tempt. It was a temptation. I saw
who'd been through there. I saw that
Christ had been there said no. I saw a
couple of people who you would call
fallen gurus. I saw they said yes. It's
like I saw everybody who'd ever been
through that pass and I saw their
choice. And so, um, I said, "Can that be
used for personal gain?" And and
refused.
Refused. You're going to refuse all that
power. You're going to refuse all that
power, all that dominion over.
Anyway,
uh,
so it would appear that a number of the
famous ones, it also happens to
non-spiritual people. It happened to
Napoleon. You calibrate the level of
Napoleon during his heyday when he was
the spir military genius and on the
rise. uh Napoleon calibrated about uh
450 right let's see what Napoleon
calibrated calibrated uh Napoleon when
he was the became emperor the the great
conqueror of Europe uh was over 450 455
he was 455
all right Napoleon
um by the time he was on elbow
calibrated over 200 is it
he calibrated over 170 175
He dropped from 450 which is enough to
be president of the United States
to 175.
Why? Because his success had brought a
megalomaniac
um
power over others.
And so
what happens to some of these gurus
which I don't want to mention their name
and some are world famous I'll tell you.
and
you calibrate their writings, their
writings may be 540, but that entity is
now 190. Many of the highest gurus now
calibrate in the low 200s. So what it
means is fame, fortune, power over
others, having many followers,
uh becoming famous,
uh having fancy titles,
dressing in fancy garb, being called
Baba this or that. Eventually, it
summons forth the ego again.
uh the temptation
uh to spiritual vanity. So it means in
the beginning they had let go enough
personal ego to reach a good high
personal state
spiritual state that then attracted many
people.
The person then still had unsuspected
spiritual ego within themsself. My guess
is they were unaware unconscious that it
was happening. It's be like you begin to
believe your own
uh
>> your own PR. Yeah. So because there are
some well-known gurus that still around
Sedona you mention the name it goes ooh
ah ooh get out of here.
So you calibrate that entity now and you
see there's nothing to about. So all
right so it happens is a temptation. So
success happens like that. If it can
happen to Napoleon, it happens to movie
stars. It happens to rock stars. Uh
people start start out naively. But
the wolf comes described in sheep's
clothing. Luciferic is the energy that
destroyed Enron. They're not satanic.
They don't want to cause anybody to
suffer, you know. But the unprincipled
greed for power.
So
the spiritually p person as they evolve
spiritually should be watchful the
spiritual ego. If one does it out of
one's love for God
you see because of your love of God your
consciousness grows. As your
consciousness grows it benefits all of
mankind. Every living entity on this
planet benefits from every single degree
that your consciousness advances. So
you sacrifice personal gain.
The Achilles heel of these fallen gurus
is the they they themselves were not
trained by somebody sufficiently
advanced to guard them against
the attack from their own spiritual ego.
A good spiritual teacher should warn the
student. As you advance, your spiritual
ego is naturally going to come in there
because that's the way it's designed.
It's not you doing that. Therefore, you
don't have to bother with guilt. You can
just assume you write a good book, it
becomes popular, your ego is going to
come right in there. It's automatic.
Just know it. Every time you win a game,
your ego is going to come in there and
say, "Boy, aren't you something?"
You see, because the idea of a personal
self still persists. A truly enlightened
guru is not sub not subject to that
because there is no personal self there
to claim any gain there anybody there
nobody there that claims to be the funny
man when the jokes come up you know what
I mean they come up of their own
so the spiritual knowingness arises of
its own essence there's no personal self
to take credit uh or for any gain
therefore a person is safe if they no
longer have any interest in gain,
followers, money, wealth, influence.
There was one guru that had what was it
90 Rolls-Royces or something. Anyway, he
went down in flames. But if you test him
out, that particular one, cuz he's so
famous in Oregon there, in the
beginning, his teachings were quite high
and then he crashed down to uh a level.
It was from having many followers. And
you see this the seduction of the
luciferic is very subtle. It's very
clever too. It's very clever. Um and it
deceives even the guru of that level.
For the good of your followers, you
should really have all these and display
the power of God manifesting as
abundance. You know what I mean? You've
heard that kind of crap every street
spiritual street corner, right? How many
workshops have you gone to that said
told you that? So the difficulty with
what I call the false guru is that the
error is one of context not content.
They sound very ariodite because the
content is correct. However, the context
in which this is presented is facious.
The student is not that advanced. The
student is not that advanced. The
student is impressed with the content
and the level of the spiritual error is
outside the level of this of the
student's awareness. Very often it's out
of the con level of the aware level of
awareness of the guru. Even the guru is
not aware that he's been taken in.
Just got suckered in and is now serving
luciferic energies from other domains
who are threatened by unconditional
love. unconditional love. See, they
wanted to give away a spiritual
technique which would unhook all these
all these um
monastic people who struggle with sin
and all that kind of stuff. I mean, this
would relieve them of all that suffering
and um that would be a great threat to
the luciferic domin domain in this uh
planet.
Okay. Anything else?
Um we do have
an optimistic view that since we've
passed this 200 level that things are
getting better on into the future. And
how how do we know this is more of a
wave? If you look back two years ago,
everybody thought the stock market
really went up.
>> That's u because you're talking about
two different domains. One is
consciousness which has nothing to do
with form. consciousness is beyond form.
The other that stock market is subject
to form. Um
the question is also hypothetical but
aside from this being hypothetical we
asked what is the nature of the essence
of consciousness itself and the essence
the nature of the essence is like an
acorn. It innate essence is to grow and
to prevail.
Um if we calibrate the energy field of
the consciousness level of mankind over
the centuries over the centuries it
prevailed at 19 190 century after
century after century.
You see one thing chiology in in
spiritual research does it lends itself
to research teams. If you have a
particular interest you can get
together. We used to do this every
Saturday morning. uh four or five people
we'd choose up teams and we'd each one
research a specific area
all I've done in power versus present
really a new science you might say you
know each one of these one a change of
even one point is very significant you
know but I had no time to do all that
all I've given is broad broad areas
you could go back century after century
and see if there were any variations and
if there were how much variation and so
associated with with what etc
and do very specific research on that. I
did not get the feeling in going back
over the centuries but it was limited
the ones I did that it was cyclic. I got
it that
it was progressive that it going it it
constantly progresses,
you see, but like um like a scale. One
one feather on this side tips you from
this side of zero and one feather over
here tips you on this side of zero. You
say, "Well, that's only one feather."
Yes,
but that's all the difference in the
world, right? A laser beam being shot
off a million miles off this pointer
would pass some universe is different
than this. And that's only one feather.
But that one feather is what our karma
rests on. Right? It's the one feather of
a let it go. Instantly the feather went
over on the other side. The sharp retort
you could have gotten even and hurt
their feelings back. You say, "Oh, the
heck with it." That's the feather that
makes the difference. Yeah. So
you might say
consciousness progresses
at the rate of feathers. Every feather
you let go affects all of mankind. Let's
see if that's true. And then we're going
to take a break again. And then
afterwards we're going to do
kinesiology. We'll do questions and
answers. And we'll do interviews with
people that travel distances to see
every iota of spiritual gain of
spiritual progress on the part of any
individual affects the totality of
mankind.
Resist. Yes. Every single minute little
feather that you put in benefits many
elsewhere.
Some child lying there suffering in
agony and suddenly a feeling of hope
comes in. That was your work that
impinges on that child who has now
karmically earned the right to it.
People ask you know the other thing that
we have to say before we'll take a break
and then we'll resume after a few
minutes break for those who wish.
Um without karma there would be no
explaining how it is you see the
children I'm not supposed to be in this
now am I? Okay.
Uh,
everybody has a a calibratable level of
consciousness at at birth at the moment
of birth. You're born at 300, you're
born at 200, you're born at 600. How
could that be? You see, without
understanding that consciousness
prevails over huge eons of time, there
would be no accounting for why it is
that some are born in Boffer with a
calibratable energy of 45 and will
probably not live more than 6 weeks and
they will expire
starvation
and another comes in
with the genius in Einstein
born that way.
Usually the consciousness does not
advance much in a lifetime. People come
become spiritually committed can go very
rapidly. The average lifetime is maybe
five points. You know the trial and
error. You learn the hard way. Uh not to
make enemies. Maybe a couple lifetimes.
All you learn is don't make enemies.
Nobody needs enemies in this world. Let
me tell you,
nobody needs enemies in this world. Uh
but it may take lifetimes just to learn
that little thing. You just jump five
points, right? But even when you do,
lots of people now feel pretty good that
it it's not smart to have energy in this
world. They thought it came from them.
No, it came because of you that you put
that out there that that really works.
So you you help all of mankind with
every spiritual movement you make. Yeah.
Uh can can a person use kinesiology all
by themsel? Yes. There's the so-called
method which is described uh in a book
called map
written by a nurse.
I think we have a a page out in front of
people who are interested in kinesiology
uh sources that they can tra uh contact
for much greater information. I'm not a
kinesiologist. You understand?
Kinesiologists are very often holistic
health practitioners. Um
chiropractors usually the best holistic
chiropractors and we have a friend who
does it constantly using this ring
method. You know you hold your you know
everybody know this method.
>> Yeah. You hold it as strong as you can.
Now you picture Jesus and try to pull
it.
Now you picture Ben Lden and try and
pull it. You'll notice there's a
difference in strength. So kinesiology
is really a difference in strength. That
which is pro-life tends to make you go
strong. that which is anti-life makes
you go weak. Um
again that sounds like a polarity. Um
in these these gradations of
consciousness we start out from the
infinite. If you calibrate what is the
energy I'm doing this for the book I'm
doing now. The various names for God. U
what does this name for God? What is the
energy that it reality behind it? and
it'll it'll say infinite. The the true
names for God all calibrate out their
infinite.
Um
there there is an a book that describes
this particular technique. Then there
are people who are professionally
kinesiologists
and they put out very excellent teaching
tapes. They're much better at
demonstrating it than I am. We have a
friend who's a a chiropractor,
holistic practitioner, and as you're
talking to him, he's he's checking out
the calibrations, the energies of
everything you're saying as you say it,
you know, and he's checking out your
past karma about that. And his fingers
are going like this. He's like tracking
everything you're saying and doing. And
uh well, I I think in one lifetime, you
probably pulled your grandmother's armor
almost out of the socket. And that has
could have something to do with the
guild about that. and and he's going on
and on and here's what you can do. Press
these acupuncture points and here's the
affirmation I'll give you. I forgive
myself for losing my temper and injuring
somebody I loved, you know, etc. So
that's one approach to kinesiology. Mine
is only to do research in spiritual
truth and spiritual reality and and try
to devise an understanding of the whole
evolution of consciousness
throughout all of time.
We ran across the fact that there are
multiple dimensions uh of this is only
one dimension.
Uh that there's an infinite number of
dimensions. Each one of them is has
their own reality.
Each one has its own hierarchy.
Uh the astral domains, you can go to any
spiritual bookstore and there's all
kinds of books channeled from all
different domains.
those within that astral domain. Uh
you'll see there's a whole hierarchy of
beings and and titles and they have
their own gods and um
these are are by choice. These are by
choice. Um
many people uh are repelled by love and
goodness and God and forgiveness. There
are countries where it's actually
illegal. You know that in Cambodia after
pot Paul or whatever his name was
executed anybody who was everybody um
any public uh exhibition of love or
lovingness or forgiveness uh or mercy
was uh illegal get you put in prison.
So
uh the Nazis trained their soldiers to
be uh totally immune to love and
tenderness and any consideration
You remember this famous incident with
the Japanese soldier bayonetted the baby
being held in the arms of his mother and
felt victorious that he had
perfected the satanic energy.
So the negative what we would consider
from a spiritual viewpoint
non-integrous realms have their own
integrity
where your status depends on your
capacity to be unfeillingly cruel. The
Japanese certainly exhibited that in
Nuria in the early 30s. They exhibited
in their treatment of the prisoners in
World War II.
Uh
there are domains in which which are the
opposite of ours. To have compassion
towards another is a weakness and you
are laughed laughed at as a fool. You
understand?
Mirror image of ours.
You see this in the mafia where you're
not a made guy until you murder somebody
with a witness.
You have to, in other words, choose
hell.
choose hell. Now you have rank in hell.
Mhm. So
Adolf Hitler and Stalin and all those
fellas probably have a high rank in the
domains where they are. You know what I
mean? Kill 70 million innocent people
without feeling a thing and then commit
suicide at the end.
All right. So that's how you get to the
head of the mafia in those rooms.
I don't know. It's probably a choice.
choice. Why is it that life uh can
express itself in such a way? That's
been there's a couple of questions
really refer to that there is no
opposite to God. That which is not God
is is merely the refusal of God but not
its opposite. Now we said that those
those levels have to do with love. So at
the very top you have that which is
infinite loving infinitely loving. And
as you come down,
life doesn't disappear. It takes a
different form. Beyond 32°, water turns
to ice. Below 200, life turns into a
different expression.
That mollisk, who stands for the most
venomous thing I know of on the planet,
makes a black mamba go scared.
Even a black mamba is scared of that
mollisk. Anyway,
uh it calibrates about five or
something.
Uh should we call that evil? I don't
know. Maybe that which chooses that
lifestyle thrives and feels good about
it.
Uh
it's choice. One can see then
don't forget you're trying to escape the
trap of duality. What you're seeing the
is the gradation of one.
Just like there's light and less and
less light. There's love and there's
less and less love. If you remove love,
then you have the selfservingness which
we would call from a psychological
viewpoint narcissism. The concern only
for
oneself and nothing else other than
one's own desire.
One way of understanding the ego in a
way that gets you out of duality and the
make wrong of the ego. The reason I
don't like the textbook of the course of
miracles is it lapses the workbook is uh
very good and I tell people do the
workbook and ignore the textbook. Why? I
used to be a spirit you know teacher. I
brought it to Sedona
and I knew Helen
and all the people involved and um
the textbook gets into a polarization
with the ego. See, like the ego is the
bad guy and you're the good guy and your
job is to conquer the ego.
That's getting polarized with the ego
and that's going to strengthen the ego.
Uh
There is that which is loving. All
right? Because one chooses a spiritual
pathway. Don't forget you've already
made a decision based on a
positionality. You've already come to a
conclusion, a positionality that
spiritual is better. Right?
Spiritual is better for you. That's your
choice. Spiritual is not better for a
black mamba.
black mamba decides not to bite not to
bite and kill you, he don't last long as
a black mamba. So, uh, life takes its
various forms. It also there's questions
here that I really can't answer.
We could say that that which creates
life gives life complete freedom.
Life is then free to flow however it
flows. Whoops.
Uh life is
comp is created completely and totally
free. We have permission to ask that
life is is created completely and
totally free. We have permission to ask
that. Resist.
Do not have permission to ask that.
What's the why you got to know?
Do I give myself permission to have the
freedom to live my life the way I
choose?
Give myself freedom. Give myself
permission to have the freedom to live
my life.
>> Let's stay within the realm of the
knowable because uh some of the
questions really deal with the
hypothetical.
Um,
why is it that things that seem
ungodly or
devoid of love
and seem to exist?
And the answer is I don't know.
It would seem that one has a choice
um within one's own experience. you see
that you you were presented with
possibilities
uh to choose one way or the other. So
that's all we can say is that by choice
one advances in this direction or one
chooses the other direction.
What the why of that? Let's just get a
definite answer on that one.
>> The why of it is because of the audience
resist. Oh, the why of it is because of
the question resist. The why of it is
because of the intention resist.
Yeah. Something's very odd about it. The
intention.
Oh, I know. Uh,
what I'm thinking is so resist. Okay.
Thank you. All right. So, it isn't
something we need to discuss. You don't
need to know it. You can become
enlightened without answering the
question.
It's a hypothetical question.
I'll get that into in the next book.
Uh
the answering the question of what seems
to be the polarities of good and evil is
quite a conundrum. I mean it has
bothered man since the beginning of
time, right? Because Eve didn't know
kinesiology. We've all had a tough time.
She calibrated the energy of that viper.
We you know life might be different
right?
But so there are unanswered questions.
There are unanswered question uh why
that should be. Huh? Why that should be
that way?
We'll leave that for another book. You
know, now can certain drugs cause people
to go suicide? I can't say that a drug
has the power to cause anybody to do
anything. There are certain drugs that
are alleged to have certain side effects
and the exact reasons are not exactly
known.
Sometimes the clinical reason for it
does uh occur later. There is a
dermatologic drug that is alleged to
drive people into depression
and into suicide. But you see every step
along the way you have a choice. If
you're depressed, you can go see a
doctor about it. You can go take an
anti-depressant about it. You can see a
psychiatrist. If you're that depression
thing is suicide. So you've got your
freedom of choice. Usually out of pride,
the person won't go see a psychiatrist
and they kill themselves. But it it's
not really due to the medicine. It's due
to the fact that they were too prideful
to go and consult another human being
about what their problem is who probably
could have cured him with Prozac.
There are drugs that do have effect on
the brain's neurotransmitter systems and
can create quite a depression.
This is also the peculiar thing.
remember when Prozac was accused of
driving people into maniac states and u
you see there's there's two kinds of
depression there's depression depression
which is just serotonin and maybe
adrenaline in the brain and then there's
bipolar depression chemically they're
two different items in the brain so if
the doctor thinks this is plain
depression and it's really a bipolar
depression you put them on Prozac you
take them out of the bipolar depression
and throw them into bipolar mania
The Prozac doesn't cause the mania. What
it does is it removed the depression and
now the mania. So
uh every patient I see with depression,
I suspect they're bipolar depressed,
they're possibly that. And that if you
just put them on a depress
antidepressant, they may go into a manic
state. See, so it wasn't that Prozac
drove people into mania.
Uh it's that it uncovered a undiagnosed
bipolar condition.
So anyway, it doesn't cause you to do
it, but it would uh present you with a
situation where you might choose that.
Well, when we talk about the unfolding
of the universe,
this understanding of it is
that intrinsic to
creation is the power of creativity. So
that that which is created has within it
the essence of
the essence of God, which may then
continue to manifest as further
creativity. In other words, it's innate
to the universe
by virtue of its creator.
Now, what seems to be an unfoldment of
the universe, you're talking about
perception.
From the viewpoint of radical reality,
nothing is unfolding. That probably
sounds like nonsense.
from that which is nothing is unfolding.
There's nothing to be explained.
An unfoldment would be
a change,
a moment.
These are all selections of perception
which then seem to beg for an answer
only if they're perceived as such.
In as much as
in the realm of the absolute, none of
that is happening, there is nothing to
be explained.
That probably doesn't make any sense.
The supreme being is unmanifest,
unmoving, unchanging.
There's nothing unfolding, nothing being
revealed.
It is as it is.
Out of that unmanifest,
arises the manifest
in which perception because it's
sequential
sees things as happening and then looks
for an explanation of the happening.
There is nothing happening. Everything
is just is as it is. Huh?
Even when I say unfolding, what I'm what
I'm really saying is from the viewpoint
of perception, it seems to be unfolding.
From the viewpoint of a more radical
reality, everything merely is what it is
because each instant is complete and
total within itself
and is outside of time. So many of these
questions only make sense
from the viewpoint of time.
I don't know. I don't think that's a
very good answer for the listener, but
um because it cannot be explained. So
many things cannot really be verbalized.
Um
it's just the reality as it is
and it's not explicable.
Those are attempts by verb verbiage to
address the question
but it doesn't answer the question
because
because there is no question. So there
is no answer that is um not
comprehensible but it is so is that so
let's see for my own sake
so yeah that is so
that which seems like a question is a
positionality
languaged from the viewpoint of the ego.
And because it makes semantic sense,
it presumes there is an answer.
From the viewpoint of radical reality,
no construct within form
is real and therefore is not actually
answerable.
Every question is
unreal.
There's a it seems to be answerable at a
certain level. But as you transcend that
level,
no question is possible and therefore no
answer is necessary nor is it possible
either.
The best way I can answer that question
is with a nonsense bit of nonsense dog
roll which probably originated in
1800s in England. Why is a whirling
mouse? Because the more it spins and
then some.
That to my ear is the sound of all
questions. But uh that gets translated
into what I understand the human is
saying by that and therefore it's
answerable. All questions are in the
form of why is a whirling mouse
when you examine them and take them to
their roots.
Why is a mur whirling mouse? Because the
more it spins and then some. Oh, thank
you teacher. We'll go on to the next
a person does when they're enlightened.
>> She wants to know
what does a enlightened person do when
somebody's about to kill them and shoot
them.
It's his problem, but I don't want to
hear it.
Yeah,
that's funny.
I didn't think that up. That's one of
those things that came to me one time
during a lecture and she likes it. So,
okay. Have we answered everybody's
question? Because now we'll go to any
specifics that people uh may have.
Some things are not answerable.
Um,
and if they're not answerable,
one is one is not to decide that one
doesn't know the answer.
One is to decide that the question is
not answerable.
Why is a whirling mouse? I got the
answer after 50 years of meditating on
that co.
Because it isn't.
Oh lord.
All right. Now we'll go to specifics.
We've got some time left for anybody
that has specific questions. A lot of
people ask about specific spiritual
organizations, techniques, workshops.
Um
the best thing to do with them is um
most of them are going to run in the
200s.
Uh most of them are quite useful. Most
of them lead to a greater understanding
of human psychology and motivation along
the way.
Most of them are part of the broad
educational training that a person needs
to become spiritually evolved requires
really in a way a certain degree of
sophistication
uh in our society at this time
at in this lifetime. So one is sort of
getting a general education about the
whole spiritual domain. What are its
dimensions? What are the various avenues
that people follow? Sort of an
understanding of humanity.
Um in its in its desire to know itself
and to know the highest truth.
You one comes out from looking at all of
it with a certain degree of compassion
for all of humanity.
um
the incredible lengths to which people
go uh to reach God. Uh prayer wheels
that they go tens of thousands of times.
People that sit in this decades reciting
the same mantra over and over.
The dedication, the profound uh
commitment is, you know, awesome in a
way. Uh,
in the book I'm working on now, what we
did was we calibrated a lot of these
techniques. The Jesus prayer, um,
namashaya, uh, what's the one we did the
other night? Um, man,
>> you're right.
U, and many of them are quite high.
They're in the 500s. And um there's no
doubt that if you recite a mantra that's
in the high 500s, then the motivation
behind doing such a thing is sufficient
to drive one the whole way. In other
words, there's no magic in the mantra.
No, there's no magic in the mantra. A
lot of these spiritual things get to be
held in a magical way. No, the intention
behind the prayer wheel, whether there's
a prayer in the can or not, as it
rotates around and around, probably has
nothing to do with it. But the fact that
anybody's willing to sit there and
rotate that thing 10,000 times for the
good of mankind, that's enough to get
you all the way into heaven. If I was
the doorkeeper,
a spiritual misamorph got all the muscle
to rotate that
rotate that prayer wheel. the things
that people do um you know brings great
compassion that man would be that
interested in the ultimate reality in
the desire to reach God uh to do all the
strange and what's sometimes seems
almost horrific things to reach the
truth uh is probably that which
contributes to the salvation of mankind
and brought Christ down to earth uh as a
savior to manifest the energy of the
savior. Mankind in a way, let's say,
earned it. You might say mankind earned
the right to have the Buddha here and
Jesus Christ and all the great teachers
that have been here by its own karmic
merit, earned the right to salvation.
Huh? Mankind and mass, the totality of
mankind. Yeah. Are we all for that?
Everybody vote for that.
>> I vote for it.
Any
other questions? Any specifics?
Anything?
>> Is there a difference in the calibration
in regards to relationships perhaps
between an individual being calibrated
above 310 and one that may calibrate
just about 200?
>> Those levels there denote the general
realms.
300 the 300s have to do with u really
willingness. Uh 310 is willingness. Huh?
310 is a different energy altogether
than the ones below it. The ones below
it are integrous.
Uh willingness is already the beginning
of joy.
Uh to be asked to help with a with a
project and to to feel the joy of
contributing to that project.
uh to know that you are um
part of humanity by doing so that you're
assisting the people you love. You're
it's almost like you acknowledge the
family love of mankind.
The willingness to be of service to
others is already a very good advance.
People in the 300s are great to be
around. uh uh they're helpful, they're
cheerful,
they take responsibility for their own
actions, they don't tend to blame things
on you.
Uh and therefore, they're very strong.
They're very strong. They really build
the nation, but they build it, you might
say, to degree on the willingness of the
200s to put forth the effort. The joy
isn't there yet. In the 200s, you don't
experience the joy.
There's satisfaction however and there's
a feeling of freedom.
Uh the the level of neutrality where is
neutral 250 uh neutral is a very
comfortable place to be. For one thing
you've escaped the fear and negativity
of the lower dimensions.
With neutral it's okay if you get the
raise and it's okay if you don't. It's
their worry. You know what I mean?
Down lower. If you don't get the raise,
you think of suicide or you go into a
rage and go postal.
Go Postal is down near the bottom there.
Uh neutral. If you don't get the raise,
you say screw it, you know. Uh I lost a
lot of money on Inron. What the hell?
I'll make it back some other way. Uh
whatever your financial karma is, you'll
get it back. Yeah. So neutral is a easy
are easy people to be around. They're
not vindictive.
Um they go with the flow. Neutral is you
go with the flow. In neutral, you're
pretty self-sufficient and you're
comfortable with yourself. Because
you're comfortable with yourself, you're
comfort other people are comfortable
with you.
People are as about as comfortable with
you as you are accepting of yourself.
The person who's totally self-honest and
self-accepting
never gets resentments and they don't
get their feelings hurt. There is
nothing you can't say about them that
they don't know already and it's okay
with them.
The way to disarm your opponent is to
agree with everything he negative he
says about you and tell him not only are
you the best a liar, but you're the best
liar in town. You're worth a fortune.
You want to hire me? I can sell more
Buicks in a day than you'll sell all
month. So anyway,
what do you think, Ralph? Anyway,
no matter what they say, you insist that
you are a high degree of that and
immediately your opponent becomes
disarmed. Huh? You understand that? It
has to do, it's like martial arts. You
see, as he comes with you this way, you
go with him that way. And now his attack
is is weakened because he only can
attack you if you resist him. So if they
tell you you're selfish, you tell
himself is good.
This world was built on selfishness. And
when it comes to being appropriately
selfish, I'm the king. Well, what can
they say? You've already agreed with all
you would disarm them. You know what I
mean?
Yeah.
So, neutral is a very comfortable space
to be in. You see, they're out of
denial. 200 is a level of integrity.
Integrity is a level of truth.
Um, you can't get sober in AAN unless
you cross the level 200 because 200 is
the first step in AA is I admit I am
powerless over or any of the
12step programs. I admit that I'm
powerless over so and so. Well, that's
the truth. Cuz if you had power over it,
you wouldn't have the problem, would
you? So to even So that's jacks for
openers. So 200 is jacks for openers
into the spiritual world where you're
you're willing to admit the truth about
yourself and you give up being defensive
and you give it up out and and you stop
being guilty. So people below the line
are hard to deal with because they're
very defensive.
They're very defensive and uh
Oh, everything's falling off my
electronic tree here.
You plug the end of all these wires in a
plug and I'm going to go up in flame
karmically it might be good you know
so 200 is the neutral is a very nice
comfortable place to be 175 you see
Peter people are prideful and they get
titied if they make any mistake you see
if you if you say you stack the the
cards backwards I did not and you told
me that and you know it's very defensive
so it's hard to deal
Neutral is easy going because each
neutral knows that you can't live a day
without making lots of mistakes. It's
impossible. Every person who didn't make
a mistake and the day stayed in bed all
day and it was a mistake to stay in bed
all day.
So the fallibility so forgiveness comes
in out of compassion. So compassion uh
is really the answer to most of the
lower negative energy fields. Compassion
for yourself and for others. is a
willingness to forgive the willing
willingness to to forgive and and
overlook human error and human error.
Error is built into the human mechanism.
Uh, and so error is inevitable. And I
just read a very good article out of
Fortune magazine
u that most companies are designed for
success and they have made no
preparation for error.
And they're discovering now that the
company that knows how to turn error
around in a very positive way is a far
more profitable, beneficial, and
friendly place to work. So in your
company, what you do is you you set up
your error strategy. First of all,
errors are going to occur here. How are
we going to handle them? What are we
going to say to the customer, etc. So,
you get out of defensiveness
and you turn it around into a positive.
I thought it was a very beautiful
article
for Fortune magazine. You see, a lot of
what is really considered spiritual is
quite acceptable in the in in the world
of commerce. As long as you don't label
it, as long as you don't call it
spiritual, uh it goes a long way and uh
of course it's very profitable uh on the
bottom line. Spiritual principles are
highly profitable to the companies that
institute them. Uh but they don't use
the ter spiritual terms or spiritual
terminology which turns a lot of people
off.
But the basic truth can be very
profitable to any company certainly to
be considerate of of the customer. And I
don't know how any of these companies
make it that you call up and you get
this string of answering machines and
they what what you call sort of a thing.
You punch six and then you punch eight
and 12. I mean how much does a human
being cost an hour nowadays? You can get
them for like $9 an hour, right? Meaning
this giant corporation can't afford $9
an hour to have a human being say, "Gee,
how may I help you?" in a really
friendly voice. Wow, they're saving $9
an hour and losing millions by the hour.
Disgusted
customers hang up saying, "I was on the
phone for 20 minutes and I never got a
human being to hell with them." You
know, what does it cost them? So, the
insensitivity
of corporate life at its interface with
the human domain is of interest to me.
Uh I recently got a call from a writer
for the Wall Street Journal writing an
article on that. Uh is are is the
institution of spiritual principles in
business actually does it actually show
up on the bottom line or not to even ask
the question seems to me so absurd. But
you know there is yourself you get
somebody helpful and friendly on the
line. So what you want is somebody who
answers your telephone who's at 3:10.
Hey, neutral. Uh, no, you ain't in now.
It's okay with them to disappoint you
because they they're not riding their
self-esteem doesn't ride on pleasing
you. Person down below may go get be
angry and another, etc. Uh, an apathetic
person, we get a lot of apathy on the
telephone. Those are about fourth grade
dropouts and the government has assured
them some kind of a a job, but they
really shouldn't be in the workplace.
actually they need training on how to be
in the workplace. So each one of these
fields represents a certain level of
consciousness which is impersonal.
Each one of these fields by our ascent
tends to dominate
tends to dominate the field. So our
thoughts without realizing it
tend to be uh in tune with a prevailing
energy field uh which we have brought in
out of our own agreement.
We call that entrainment. The energy
field prevails in society
and by your ascent you agree to that
energy field and now it tends to
dominate your consciousness.
We see that the success of the negative
energy fields
depend on that entrainment.
And in that book and the book I'm just
finishing in research I'm doing now.
The en it isn't the lyrics of certain
negative kinds of pop music. It's the
energy field which accompanies it which
is like a carrier wave. That carrier
wave contains the
um pattern of that negative energy
field.
So it's possible
to unconsciously invite in a negative
energy field to dominate your
consciousness. You went to the party to
have a good time, but when you walked
out, you're now under the domination of
a field which we could ter term satanic.
One has now agreed by propinquity and um
the energy field now dominates that
person's consciousness. So all they did
is listen to a lot of rock music and get
stoned. And as far as they're concerned,
that's just having a high time. And
nobody sees the connection between that,
walking into the school room and killing
eight people just and you ask them on
you see them on TV, why'd you do that? I
don't know. I just felt like I wanted to
see what it felt like. He just wanted to
see what it felt like.
And how did the person ever get to that
level of consciousness?
Uh because their consciousness is
dominated by uh a negative field. So
these fields which we tried to calibrate
uh
we can depict them with a generality.
Don't forget these these calibrations
are sort of general. In other words, I
can't say that it's 200 or 20 1.2.
Why? Because it's really a whole new
field for investigation.
Um, one could spend a lifetime in a PhD
uh, dissertation exploring
just a few points above and below 200
and how that manifests in society. What
does a jump in two points from 202 to
204? How does that manifest in
uh, one's annual earnings? How does it
manifest in job title? Uh even two
points from 202 will take you from the
back desk to the front desk. Right?
From 200 will take you from the desk
front desk to 202 will take you to the
manager's office and another two points
will take you up to be assistant
manager. Probably another two points
your manager. You know what I mean? So
we're dealing in broad numbers. But I'm
sure even slight variations have quite a
profound effect as they express themsel
in human life and society.
So each one of them is really um a field
for uh detailed research. What we've
really done is sketch out the broad
outlines, the broad outlines,
but we haven't mapped out every croo and
cranny in the in the coastline.
How far is up the scale is it possible
to go in one lifetime?
>> I never asked that.
From the depths of hell
to the presence of God
within a day
is a subjective experience.
So that would be practically the whole
scale.
It's possible
to jump enormously. See, because you
don't know what kind kind of karmic
loading is behind such a move.
You understand what I'm saying? You
don't know what the
what the possibilities are. You don't
know what the possibilities are. I think
by choice.
Uh yes, I think I see what the answer
is. You know, actually what I actually
myself did and what Ramana Maharshi
recommends. Okay.
Uh, taking the third step at great depth
will take you all the way from the
bottom to the top. Resist.
Okay. What I did was
what's called in aa the third step. The
willingness to completely surrender
one's life completely and totally to God
with no considerations, no withholdings,
no matter what.
Ramano Maharino recommends to look
within and ask who am I?
To me that's not exactly correct. It's
not who am I, what am I, who you're
looking for a personage again. It's look
like you're looking for a bigger better
ego. So I don't agree with that teaching
as it is verbalized. What am I? Because
the what is impersonal. The who you're
looking like for a higher person.
Um when Ramano Maharshi you know
suddenly dropped over at age 15 or 16
whatever it was he was just an ordinary
religious person Hindu and thought he
had died and obviously in that moment
completely surrendered
and
saw himself as dying and dead
and then came out of that experience at
700 and he never left the
I know what he experienced because
in walking through
what should we say
in completely surrendering everything
there was the experience of dying a
great profound anguish
of really dying. One knows that one is
really dying.
And you know you're dying. And
it's it was in this experience rather
dreadful. But it only lasted
well few seconds, half a minute,
something.
But it was very very definite. The
experience of dying.
It's not possible to experience one's
own physical death. You know, forget
about
experiencing your own death. Nobody
experiences their own death. It's not
possible to experience your own death
because you're out of body and when the
body goes you're not there. So you don't
experience any death because you haven't
died. How can you experience your death
when you haven't died? Uh but the death
of the ego yes that was the the death
that people dread is really they think
it's the body but it's the
ego is one one's identity. So the
willingness to surrender
even one's identity as as I as me
uh to God can bring about an enormous
change because it was through that great
space that
uh the splendor of that which is shown
forth.
You never experience your own death.
There's two questions that we could do
just as a aeratifist.
>> We have permission to resist.
One never experiences their own physical
death.
Resist. That's a fact. Don't have to
worry about experiencing your death cuz
it ain't going to happen.
Uh the other question that's sort of
need to know, we have permission to ask
this one. Resist. The time of your death
in this lifetime is karmically set.
resist. It's karmically set. So why
worry about time is certain and you're
not going to experience any death
anyway. So because the ego, one of the
greatest reasons for the propagation of
the ego is fear of death.
To really know that you're not going to
die, you're not going to experience any
death. And it's already said already
release a great deal of reason for the
ego to continue its dominion over you.
Um that brings to mind question about
karma. So what can you do in this
lifetime to negate any karmic
responsibilities that you may have
acquired? Any shortcuts?
>> Do good at all times to all people.
Cross your fingers.
I guess one follows one's spiritual
direction to the best of one's ability,
which is all that's required. You know
what I'm saying? That's all that's
required. Yeah. It's not that God is a
cruel taskmaster. You see, God is not
arbitrary. God is is is completely non
arbitrary.
And so, one earns one's way out by one's
own good intentions.
And you watch Dickens Christmas Carol
every year. It's worth watching every
year because I think it's a great
spiritual treatise. I think this
Christmas Carol is one of the greatest
spiritual treatises ever written
you know the ghosts of Christmas past
and we see where it would take us in the
future and now we have the chance to
choose differently that's all. So it's a
great he was a great spiritual teacher.
Anything else? My the question is do you
um are you free to move to their level
of calibration
>> or do you induct them to yours? What's
the bridge between the two?
>> All right. Uh you don't move your level
of consciousness to match theirs. Um
out of willingness to communicate
one accommodates accommodates
the personality the you know what young
call the persona does that all the time.
Certain type of languaging is
appropriate for one group and it is not
for another. So you do as the Romans do
for a sake of harmony. Huh? For the sake
of harmony. Uh
the persona in this particular
uh instance here automatically adjusts
to whatever environment it's with.
It tends to
uh not want to be around people who
calibrate less than 200.
Uh it doesn't enjoy it much anymore than
it enjoys loud noise.
Uh it doesn't enjoy it. But um
there's a natural willingness out of
compassion to
be what you feel you can be to others
when it is appropriate.
If it is non-integrous, there is
absolutely no reason to go along with
it. One could merely disregard it. You
know, Chris said, "Do not fight evil. Uh
just uh ignore it. walk away from it. Uh
to walk away from that which is not
compatible
at a certain level. One for instance may
leave the big city and move to the
country where it's very quiet.
Now the peace and quiet of the country
will drive some people nuts
and uh
and they come and visit you for a day or
two and uh they can't wait to get back
to the big city.
They're attuned to that energy and uh
one just does what one can to be
compatible with others uh for the sake
of harmony.
You don't have to start giving him a
lecture that
that uh bull fighting is wrong. Bull
fighting caliber is a 35 by the way. So
dog fighting
bull fighting on calib around 35. It's
about the same as the Roman coliseum.
blood for the sake of blood. But you
don't have to give him a give him a
lecture about that. You know
that the dog fighting is immoral or
something.
>> What about relationships?
I don't want to get into that subject at
all.
If a spiritual teacher is not supposed
to accept any money for the teaching
just for facilities and food and
whatever, how does a spiritual teacher
uh eat?
>> It isn't that they shouldn't, it's just
that that's not a primary goal. It's not
a goal. See, but naturally, one has uh
reality needs that have to be met. So
what's appropriate
uh
it's that you see all things that the
calibrated level is all based on motive.
What is the motive?
Um
the the the the motive is the integrous
teacher is not interested in whether one
has lots of followers, lots of fame.
uh you do it for the sake of the work
because of the joy of the work. I have
three radio programs coming up soon. The
question is why should you do a radio
program? I don't really do I do do I
really want to do radio programs?
Well,
to have this kind of knowledge and not
share it with others.
In other words, to have certain
knowledge that could be helpful to
others, one gets joy out of sharing it
for whatever. See, it would be like Sir
Alex Fleming, you know, discovered
penicellin. He excitedly ran all over
the place. Say, "Wow, this can stop
disease. This can cure disease." For 5
years, he ran over and knocked on all
doors and everybody laughed at him. Then
World War II came along and soldiers
were dying of infection. More people
died of infection in the war, you know,
than by gunshot.
Civil war, more people died from wound
infection, anything else. So here he's
got a cure for it. Penicellin completely
stopped the spread of bacteria. And so
he's saying, "Wow." So he runs all over
excitedly.
That's what a spiritual teacher does.
Runs all over excitedly and wants to
share it. So the pay that you get is the
joy of uh the sharing.
Uh
what you the the only difficulty is you
don't have the amount of time that you
would like. You'd like to like to do all
the programs, go to all the speaking
engagements, talk to everybody that you
could all day long, but you have rent to
pay. So I look at it if something pays
the rent and frees your time so that you
can spend that time teaching, then
you're giving it back to the world. You
understand what I'm saying? But to store
up uh ridges on earth I think is uh
foolish. You know storing up ridges on
earth is not appealing. So all the
material things no longer have any
appeal.
After January of 1965
there was the instant loss of all the
things that motivate average people.
success, uh fame, uh having lots of
patience, being uh you know, well
thought of, all those things were
meaningless. So what was the purpose of
going to work at all, you know,
returning to the office?
Uh and it was really compassion for the
suffering of patients. And now I had a
new dimension. And I could see within
the psyche of the patient, the real
source of of the illness and um and that
they were devoid of the recognition
uh the validation of their this the true
self within because their external was
so repulsive very often that there was
really nobody even their own mother
couldn't love them. See, so what they
needed was somebody that could that
discerned the self with a capital S
within and acknowledged its presence.
Instantly they felt healed. Instantly
they felt healed. Uh when you feel
acknowledged and gotten and understood,
you know that instant of connection only
takes a split second. It can happen
anywhere in the world at any time.
Instantly there's a mutual recognition
of the truth of who you are. Once that's
validated, after that things don't
really matter. Whether you get better in
terms of the world or not is sort of
irrelevant. But
so the capacity to do that is what
propelled the
uh propelled the continuation.
The joy of one's um the joy of one's um
perfection or expertise or whatever you
call it. You know, musicians uh very
musicians typically live to be very old
and sort of humorous
and artists. You know, it's not unusual
for symphony conductor to father father
a child at 92, you know, and uh 30 years
after other people have retired and died
already, still writing symphonies,
conducting artists tend to be longived
and humorous
live into their late 90s. So something
about humor and art and music is somehow
life sustaining. Yeah. It's interesting,
isn't it? When I was young, you worked
for the company till you were 65. You
got to go watch. They had a big
retirement party. You then got with your
wife in a in a recreational vehicle,
tour the United States, came home and
dropped dead in two years. So everybody
retired at 65, had a retirement party,
toured the world, and dropped dead in '
67. Because now you don't have a title.
You have no name. There's no reason to
continue to continue on. You see,
>> never
comment,
>> huh?
>> Uh following.
>> Susie always has a funny joke. She
always phrases it. You never see a
U-Haul following a hearse.
That's her way of expressing Jesus
sentiment. There's no point in piling up
on earth cuz you can't take them with
you. One continues out of the joy of
uh the expression of that which you are
which is the love of the self for all
and to be in of service to God is
infinitely joyful requires no external
payment whatsoever. Yeah.
Could you briefly comment on the
spiritual causes of depression?
>> Conscious spiritual consciousness is of
what?
>> Depression.
>> Yes. Depression.
>> Yes. Um,
one can unravel depression
from various viewpoints.
Of course, it's seen as hopelessness,
lack of selfworth.
It's sometimes expressed as anger turned
within oneself.
So what is the
there is a personal self evaluation
there.
We'll skip the karma in the whole story.
We'll go to the brain chemistry. You can
turn depression on and off by raising
and lowering one of the brain's
neurotransmitters.
Genetically about a third of mankind is
prone to depression. Women are more
prone than men. certain age groups are
more prone.
You can turn depression on and off by
raising and lowering one of the brain's
neurotransmitters. So that's the
physiology, the physicality,
the genetics of it. The karmic
propensity is something else. It comes
from self evaluation. The lack of joy in
the experience of it's it's really due
to the lack of joy in the experience of
one's own existence.
And the answer is truthfully aside from
the brain chemistry uh spiritual
and it resorts it resolves only one one
surrenders the depression to God and
says I will be of service even though I
am useless and
uh hateful
but even as that I can will continue to
serve and the depression will lift
itself.
It's to some degree a narcissistic self-
evvaluation which the degree of
narcissism
refuses
the um judgment of the world. The
judgment of the world is that you're a
good father and husband and all that
together. But the ego in its sort of
megalomania
disputes that and says on the contrary
you are wrong and I am right. So there's
a vanity of the ego at the core of it.
It's not really cured cured until that
narcissistic core of the ego is
resolved. Yeah. Surrendered to a higher
power.
No, nothing that you think about
yourself is true. It has no validity.
Whether you think you're great or you
think you're horrible, they're both
irrational
and somewhat lun lunatic. Lunatic.
If you think you're great, that is a
moment of lunacy. And if you think
you're awful, that's an equal moment of
lunacy.
There's no validity in anything the ego
says about itself. You know,
>> there's
changing
the The word god
the word god
>> goddess is it is there any harm in that
um and I'll tell you what
>> I never asked the question but I will
give you what I have done on the subject
that um certain um really political
they're really political positionalities
uh when you calibrate them you get no uh
if I ask what is the energy of Father,
mother, God, the arm goes weak. Huh?
It's you're projecting a political
judgmentalism
which is an abstraction of a social
onto that which is beyond all gender.
You're not saying God is a hearer or
trying to escape it. You think, well,
I'll escape the dilemma by using both
genders and call God
she he.
Yeah, let's ask about it.
Uh the energy of mother, father, god is
is positive. Is this mother, father, god
is your one gender is bad enough, but
double gendering is double bad, right?
No, the use of he and referring to God
is the traditional he that is generic.
The generic he of divinity.
Just like woman is, you know, the word
man, mankind
is generic. It's not gender. It's
generic for the species. Uh it's not
it's not a generic it's not a gender
designation.
Uh
if we ask is he is appropriate for God?
I'm I'm always tied up in these things.
You can see they're trying to get me.
He is an appropriate
uh he is appropriate in referring to
God. Is it? Yeah. It's the generic he.
Uh-huh. The generic he. It's not the
gender. He.
Well, I'm going to get in hot water if I
keep up with this discussion. So,
it's 5:00.
while we hit. I see you don't have a
position about it. You were just asking
about it, but some people when they
bring it up to have quite a position
about it.
No, it's it's it's first of all the
perception is incorrect to project the a
political uh politically correct
positionality about it. Project that. So
that that's the first error. Then they
try to correct an error where there is
none. But you see, because there's
nothing really to defend and nothing to
refute because it is not um whatever you
call it between the sexes, sexism. Yeah.
Right. All right. So, and we've done the
best we can today and uh we've tried to
answer all the questions we can.
What I really try to convey is a grasp
of the difference between the linear and
the nonlinear
because to know under which bush to look
is very helpful. Understand what I'm
saying? That's what I'm really trying to
say. And too many things say, "Well,
we're looking here. Why you're looking
there? Cuz that's where the light is,
right? That the keys were lost over
here." Right? So we're trying to
create an understanding of how to
approach that which is really
unapproachable from the world of the ego
without ending up in the dead end of
many religious uh rigidities and belief
systems as enlightenment is quite a bit
different than being a religionist.
Okay. And thank you for the privilege.