It's because of the macho of all that.
The way you get to be an Afghanistan
soldier is you take somebody who hasn't
got anything and you offer him a gun.
Now he's instantly an Afghan. He's he's
a soldier. He's on your side willing to
kill for you. All it takes is to give
the give the guy a gun. So that macho
then is an open openness and it comes
from the animal world.
All right. So we can transcend that. We
can forgive it and say that that's what
comes from the animal world.
Uh you know one of the things a man has
to learn how to hand is how to handle
his testosterone, right? One of the
challenges of adolescence.
And the girl's problem is how to handle
his testosterone too, right?
as well as her own because she also has
testosterone.
Okay. So,
we transcend a thing when we accept it.
We accept it when we forgive it and we
feel merciful towards our own ego and
that of others. People cannot help but
be the way they are. And all the
hypothetical objections that they could
be other than they were,
the hypothetical has no reality. There's
no reality in the hypothetical. You hear
it used all the time in bureaucratic
uh
what do you call political arguments.
The hypothetical is always posed and
then the defendant is supposed to defend
himself against the hypothetical.
His trap in the rally factor is one of
them is he gets trapped all the time.
Somebody poses the hypothetical and he
takes it as the real and then argues
against the hypothetical. He just you
just say that's the hypothetical and
doesn't require any argument. but he
gets caught in it
uh defending himself against the
hypothetical. Well, what if everybody
thought like you did? Then we would well
that's not a fact. There's six billion
people on the planet. Six billion people
are not going to think that way all at
the same instance. So, it's not going to
happen. So, it doesn't have to be
answered is the right way to look at it.
Right?
All right. So, forgiveness then is very
very important in spiritual work. This
is a level we all struggle for with our
egos to be merciful towards ourself,
harmonious with others, accepting of our
self and others without condemning them.
So here's where we get off condemnation
of others, right and wrong,
judgmentalism
and and and
righteousness, which is the worst of all
the ego prideful positions. No,
we transcend and we be as we do we come
into understanding and capacity to
comprehend and we reach this wonderful
level called reason. Re reason in which
we now God becomes wisdom. Life becomes
meaningful. My life is meaningful. So is
yours and so is all of society. You see
down here it's seen as hopeless or here
is seen as as awful or sinful or
terrible or frightening. But now we be
see as meaningful. We get curious. So in
the 400s you see great curiosity.
Everybody thinks well the intellect
that's truly human. No the intellect
as we see until we become enlightened
everything all the way up the scale is
still a refinement of the animal.
The base of the intellect is curiosity.
Wanting to know what's here? What is
this for? What's this do? What does that
mean on there? Pepsi.
Why is it red and blue? See curiosity.
Where do you see curiosity arise in the
evolution of consciousness in the
animal? The animal's survival depends on
curiosity. It's always nosing around,
sniffing that, sniffing that, looking
here, looking there. I look out my
window and watch our animals and they're
all going here, going here, sniff this,
sniff that. So,
so
the animal then is still with us and
it's dangerous
as Eve found out.
The desire to know curiosity.
Eat the apple of what? Apple of
something some tree. Not supposed to eat
that tree. She just had to know what the
hell I was like, right? So that was the
animal just couldn't stop sniffing,
poking its nose in.
The downside of the animal then is you
get trapped in curiosity and person
we're not talking about directly
enlightenment itself today but we will
later. The person struggling for
enlightenment you have to watch
curiosity is a trap.
Sedona is full of people trapped by
spiritual curiosity. They're into every
kind of new age uh circus and sideshow.
They get distracted for years following
all kinds of
um sort of um leftovers from ancient
Mesopotamia. You know what I'm saying?
in which there's a spiritual sideshow
going on all the time from psyching
reading here to the running the ruins on
you there to casting the stones to doing
your numbers to reading the sole of your
foot to reeling your hand and looking in
your eyes to pulling your ears
counting the vertebrae counting your
bumps phronology I mean the whole deal
you can spend lifetimes there's people
probably in the audience who spent years
following some crazy track you know
the esoteric fascination of the
esoteric. So, it's a sideshow, folks.
And you know, here there's the throwing
the balls and here's there's throwing.
It's just like a sideshow. It's like the
you walk down the side show the same
things. Here's acrobats blowing smoke
out of their ears with needles stuck in
them.
Weighs 82 lbs. He hasn't moved in 14
years. No.
The last time he ate was 1937. Oh. Oh.
He must be He must be Devoning.
He's an idiot, man. He's like trapped in
this.
You have to. All right. So, if we're
animals and the animal is curious
naturally, I checked them all out, too.
Didn't you? Anybody here failed to check
it out? Oh, well, God, you got a lot
more books to read.
You have to read every guru. Baba idiot.
Baba dum dum. blah blah blah blah blah
smoke goes out of his ears.
They have millions of followers folks.
So it's big. It's big business. Big
business. People come from all over the
world to meet Baba.
All right. So curiosity then. So for the
person who's dedicated to enlightenment,
however, that's a trap. You haven't got
time. The Buddha said waste no time. And
in the book, one of the books, first one
I think or the second one, forgot second
one. I think it says it opens with waste
no time. You don't have time to check
all that out. If you're devoted to
reaching some degree of enlightenment,
you don't have time to check out the
astral circus.
It's amusement. It's intriguing. What's
intriguing about it is that it comes
from elsewhere. Anything that's
invisible and comes from elsewhere must
be divine. So the difficulty is it
doesn't know the difference between
uh religion and spirituality. It doesn't
know the difference between the occult
and spirituality.
The downside of Sedona is it doesn't
know the difference between the occult
and spirituality.
The difficulty with
the traditional uh world of especially
of Europe is it doesn't know the
difference between spirituality and
religion.
The constitution in the United States
which calibrates to 700 clearly defines
the difference between religion and
spirituality. It says spirituality okay
uh but no establishment of religion. So,
uh, trust in God is spiritually
integrous with the constitution.
Making the government Catholic is not.
So, all right. So,
the the interesting thing about the 400s
is there's a great increase in power
because you don't have to lift barrels
in order to count them. In the lower
levels, you got to lift all those
barrels to count them.
One,
two.
When you get the intake is born, you go
four * 2 is eight. Thank you. You don't
have to lift any of them. You already
got how many is there. So your control
now of the world of form is enormous
because you can abstract. You can deal
with abstracts.
The computer is of course a very
advanced capacity to deal with symbols
and their abstract significance. Huh.
The downside of the intellect, however,
is quite sizable. Um, quite sizable
because it's also prone to error. It
thinks because a thing exists as a
concept, therefore it has a comparable
representation in reality, which is not
so at all.
So, the downside of intellectualism,
which we hear every night on television,
everybody's got some intellectual
scheme. Last night. Last night it was
right after the the World Trade Center.
We should have talked to those people.
Oh, yeah. Right. Okay.
Okay. We should have talked to those
people. Yeah. Yeah. Thanks. You go talk
to them. Okay.
And I'll wait here. You tell me what.
Okay. Yeah.
Before World War II, most people out
there haven't lived before World War II.
There was endless talking. Every
bureaucrat in the entire face of the
world was talking. Everybody talked
themselves blue in the face.
No, it takes more than talking, folks.
And all right. So anyway, the downside
of the inlet then is that it uh thinks
that the hypothetical is real. Deals
with the hypothetical as though it was a
reality,
and doesn't know its own limitations. So
the ego the down the downside of the
intellect the upside you might say is
science
the downside is the egotism of science.
It doesn't know its own limits. There's
nothing built within the intellect to
tell it
when it's out of its own field
because the intellect is perfect for
dealing with
um the concrete and it's and it's good
for dealing with abstractions of the
concrete.
A true scientist knows the limitation of
science. Huh? If you see people on
television, there's always some
pseudocientist
uh trying to disprove all spiritual
concepts, out of body experiences,
near-death experiences. There's
professionals there on all the time.
Their whole life is dedicated to
disproving any reality of the
non-physical domain. Their stake is
heavily into physicality.
The joke is it's the non-physicality of
their subjective consciousness that
allows them to think that objective
physicality is all there is to life. But
I mean that's just a little paradox that
I see
cuz that's an abstraction you know to
think that anyway. Uh so the 400s of
course is the world of the intellect.
It's the world of modern science,
civilization, the university,
great books, the great books of the
western world, which I was very
fortunate to have a set. I was uh doing
writing and I needed references. I went
to Sedona Library was having a sale and
for $500 I picked up a complete set of
University of Chicago great books of the
western world which I really prized
because it's the greatest thinking of
which man has been capable of you know
since the time of the ancient Greeks and
uh right down until the last book is
Freud
anyway I hope I can write some newer
ones since Freud anyway
I think it starts out But anyway, as a
kid, that's what I loved, reading the
encyclopedia. And I still, if I if I
could have a simultaneous other
lifetime, I would spend it reading the
great books of the rest of the world
because it it's it's just beautiful the
capacity of the human mind to address
certain very difficult issues. Of
course, it doesn't solve the
doesn't solve them because then there
wouldn't be any more volumes to it,
right?
Because the the ego cannot go beyond
itself. So a true scientist says to you
says to you when a spiritual argument
comes up I don't know that's beyond the
realm of science. There's an honest man
for you. It's beyond the realm of
science. He doesn't try to prove that
the near that you know that experience
of the presence of God is due to due to
a lesion in the parietal region of the
brain. Here
there's a guy who was all getting on
television. and he's always getting
near-death and and near-death
experiences and things like that of body
experiences and trying to prove that
it's due to some locust in the brain or
something very interesting.
Of course, the way you differentiate is
you calibrate the level of consciousness
before and after the experience. Before
and after a spurious experience, the
consciousness level remains the same.
Before and after a true experience, it
shows an enormous jump. Let me just ask
in this case here.
The jump after the experience in the
snowbank was over 50, 60, 80, 90, 100,
150, 160, 180, 200, 300.
The jump in the snowbank of this entity
here. It almost froze to death at age 11
and 12. before the experience and after
the experience that it jumped 300 points
after the experience.
The presence of God prevailed, you know,
and I wrote about in the book.
Anyway, I got out of the snowbank into
the snow and this profound,
unbelievable just you just melted in the
presence of
that which is infinite, wordless, beyond
all form,
not different than what you are
strangely. in age 12 that was what I was
experiencing was not different than the
reality of the inner sense of eye but it
was all nonverbal and I never explained
it to anybody or mentioned to anybody
but that jumped at 300 points you can't
do that by poking a you know if you poke
something in the parietal region of the
brain and you're 410 when you started
after the surgery you'll still be 410 so
that's how you can tell whether it's
genuine or not genuine
How about the out- of- body experience?
Let's see if that had an effect. The
out-of- body experience. Um, when I was
in sick and bed, I was 6 feet over the
bed. Uh, that resulted in elevation of
consciousness resist. No, it didn't.
See, out of body, as strange as it was,
it was highly educational
to be weightless in the middle of space.
It was great. I mean, I I I'm great. I'm
all for it. Uh but the the person came
back the same. It was just strange.
Uh indescribable. In those days, nobody
ever wrote about such things and I never
discussed it with anybody except my
analyst.
We both decided it was a a toxic
condition of the brain and and it caused
the projection of the body image into to
a seemingness out. Well, we let it go at
that. I don't know. We never heard about
it. Anyway, because TV confuses the two.
So, I just thought I'd demonstrate
before and after the out-of- body
experience, which was quite surprising.
It happened back in the 50s and nobody
was on TV about it in those days. And uh
it was the same, but the near-death
experience was profound. The residual of
the near-death experience, which which I
never spoke about until I wrote about
it, I think in '95 in that book, Power
Versus Force, the residual was a
complete elimination of fear, fear of
death. And during World War II, I had no
fear of death at all. Mines could be
going off and mine sweepers blowing up
and people drowning.
I mean, I was interested in, you know,
whether we had coffee this morning.
Generator is out cuz we had live an
electromagnetic tail and took all the
power. So there's no no coffee. Well,
that was the tragedy of the day. No
coffee. Now that you're going to get
blown up, but that you can't do that
intellectually. You know, if it happens,
it happens of its own. So you can't say,
"Gee, look at me. I'm fearless.
because it was a it's just an side
effect of that phenomena. People who
have had heart attacks and survived and
near-death experiences that that's very
common. The fear of death disappears. So
there's a transformation of
consciousness.
All right? So the the reason
accomplishes a great deal. We see God as
uh so this is the world of theology. The
world of theology.
um going to theological university you
study about God and reason and
comparative religion and it's all very
fascinating I find it very interesting
very interesting
all right so that's mean all right now
we're going to go from there and this is
this is a movement this is a movement of
sudden like reverence and lovingness in
which your view of yourself and others
is benign
and it's sort of a falling in love
It it happens to every almost everybody
spontaneously. You'd be walking along in
the woods and some little dog walks
along and all of a sudden you feel like
a sense of delight delight. Unplanned
moment out of nowhere you were worrying
about paying the rent and all of a
sudden here's a sense of joyfulness.
A dog a dog's wagging tail. Let's do we
did it last time but I always like to do
the dog's wagging tail. That little
white dog, his wagging tail is over 500
resistant. That little white dog just
charmed us. We in a small town and this
workman's dog, cute little white dog
jumps out of the back of his truck,
comes over. He just just he just loved
you up like crazy. And he wanted you
love him up and
it was a 500 experience. I said, "Can a
dog be 500?" Yes, by God a dog can be
500. Dog's waging tail is 500. And as I
also say every lecture, a kitty's purr
is also 500.
>> Kitty's purr is what I was going to ask.
But what I was going to ask Dr. is when
you talk about the animal brain below
200,
how does that fit? Is that just is that
just the purity of consciousness?
Wagging dog and kitty.
the um
the the the brain is I'm just speaking
of it as um anatomical structure which
arose through the animal world. However,
it can be used for divine purposes, you
know, by the time you reach the
evolution of the human. What was
originally designed just as a dagger or
something can be used. So intention and
purpose now begins to change the use of
this complex machine just like your
computer can be used to watch uh porn on
the on the internet or it can be used to
do research in the most advanced
subjects. So now this animal brain which
is the substrate of our the physicality
of what goes on in our skull
be by intention can be made to serve
higher purposes lead to spiritual
evolution along the way.
Let's see. I wish there were three or
four of myself because simultaneously
there's at least half a dozen things I'd
like to be researching every minute. See
I'd like to have one group here, one
group here, one group here. I'd like to
check out how is it that the kitty's
purr is 500 and the dog's tail is 500.
Huh? That's greater than most of the
people on the planet. We showed you 78%
of the people of the planet below 200.
Forget 500.
Of course, the kitty's not always at
200.
Kitty's not always at 200 anymore than
the dog is always at 500, but neither is
the human being.
So, but for some peculiar reason, I'm so
there's some karmic and probably very
interesting and entertaining reason
behind this which I say if we had more
years and time to check out why is it
that the animal in this particular
animal is capable of love and why is
this animal capable of love. Well, we
know the herbiviverous animals in
general tend to be uh lovable, but the
canine and the cat, you know, are also
carnivores. So, here we have two
carnivores that are have a capability of
lovingness, lovingness. We all know how
a cat goes for lovingness. And our cat
is very attracted to lovingness and
loves people when they come in the
house. And if they like kitties, they
instantly it's a it's a match. So here
we have this reflection of human love
coming up in animals that are more
capable of love than 78% of the human
population
that uh uh um gorilla coco calibrates
over I think Coco calibrates 240, right?
We said uh Coco we have permission
calibrates over 240 250 260 calibrates a
250 uh gorilla she you know Koko's
famous and frequently on
uh the public um education uh channels
and Koko's quite famous you know and has
learned a great deal about humans and um
has a lot of human motivations seemingly
human motivations including
and is able to think and reason and use
sign language and interestly can
construct put together concepts and
construct the sentence. Coco can
actually construct a sentences and
communicate with humans.
I don't know the reason for that. But
you're safer with Coco than 78% of the
people on the planet.
78% of the people on the planet will
steal your steal you blind. Coco knows
that's your hamburger. We'll sit back
and let you wait cuz that's your
hamburger.
>> Yes.
>> Um for each individual human, does the
calibration
is is there an average or do you go up
and down significantly during the day or
the week or the month depending on your
behaviors?
>> How stable is that level of
consciousness? The level of
consciousness is set by karmic
apparently by karmic merit merit which
is the the totality the composite of
spiritual decisions of the spiritual
will. It's spiritual will that is the
source of
um the center from which you evolve
spiritually. The center the center out
of which you come for your spiritual
work is the spiritual will. It's a
spiritual will which sets karma and not
necessarily actions.
That is correct. That is correct.
Spiritual will. So you see your feelings
and your emotions shift up and down the
scale here all the time. But that
doesn't change your intention. Your
intention is quite a deliberate thing.
Uh
so your intention is more or less the
stabilizer of the ship. See, and you
make little corrections, you know, when
you're driving, you make little constant
corrections in the wheel, but your
intention is to drive east, you will
continue to drive east. So these minor,
these are fluctuations. Uh we all
periodically get annoyed, uh angry,
fearful,
etc. But our intention remains the same.
So intention of a decision of the
spiritual will is apparently what sets
karma. It's when you've had a chance to
think about it, reflect on it, and
decide to make that make that move. Then
now that is permanent. So every action,
thought, feeling, every decision we make
is then reflected in the infinite field
of consciousness where it is retrievable
forever. The reason Canadiology works is
we can go back and get what was the
level of consciousness of Napoleon.
We find out that many world leaders
including spiritual great gurus etc
calibrate higher higher in the beginning
of their careers than later. Uh this is
true Napoleon who was about 450 in the
beginning and then after
uh a while they get they come they get
pulled down by the ego greed and power
over others and selfishness and
arrogance.
So Napoleon didn't stay at 450 before he
died. Napoleon was we have permission to
do Napoleon before he died. Napoleon was
over 200.
He was over 240.
Napoleon had dropped about 300 points
calibrated levels of consciousness.
We see this also on very famous gurus
who gained great millions of followers
and world fame and
etc. And the beginning of their careers
they usually calibrate in the 500s and
they write books that are famous etc.
And then you say, what is the level of
of this writing? It's 500. What is the
level of this writer now? Sometimes
under 200.
I was shocked people with great names
and everybody go oo and a when you
mention their name and know calibrated
in the low 200s and some even below 200.
So that means that you can choose to go
up or you can choose to go down. Oh, you
can choose to go up or choose to go
down. So as Napoleon
uh or Hitler won, Hitler I think was
higher than he ended up. Where was
Hitler when he wrote minecomf
Adolf Hitler we have permission resist
was over 200 when he wrote minecomf 250
he was over 245 250 so he was into
nationalism 250 when he wrote mine comp.
He was in prison at the time for a
failed push remember. All right. Hitler
before he died, we have permission
resist. Before he died, he was over 60.
>> Wow.
>> So, all right. The spiritual will he had
many many times to change his mind.
Uh but the reaffirmation of that
direction apparently is what sets the
karma. So, the karma then is like a
little traveling program, a little
computer chip in your spirit body.
And uh it pretty much determines where
you're going to go and how you're going
to behave and what's going to happen. Is
that predestination? Well,
predestination is just a term. You could
call it that. You could say what befalls
you in this lifetime is a combination of
karma plus your exercise of the freedom
of choice. On the other hand, karma has
limited your choices. You know, you
can't decide right now to become a
squirrel in the next instant. You know
what I mean? Your choices are limited.
You can decide to be poor in a hurry,
but rich in a hurry takes longer.
Revelation. All right. So 500 is the
beginning. I call it uh 500 is the
beginning of a revelation that there's
something more to life than just this
stuff down here.
Beginning of a revelation.
You see although the world is described
in terms of Newtonian paradigm of
reality and the lower levels of the ego
life is lived in the subjective
experience
which is indefinable
that which is experiencing that you're
here now talk listening to the words
you don't even have to pay attention to
the words what they're saying echo it
you're still aware that you are here
Right.
So, one is innately aware of one's
existence
uh and what is being registered in
consciousness
and that's where we live. That's where
we live. When you get a new car, the
thrill, the excitement is experienced
subjectively.
There's nothing objective out there. The
car is not happy.
There's some inner indefinable and it's
beyond uh form.
Form may trigger the experience
in the form of a car or winning the
winning the lottery. That may trigger
it. But all experience is subjective.
The only reality there is is
subjectivity.
That's the essence of eye of the eye.
And the book series I'm finishing now
called I
is that the presence of God is found
through absolute subjectivity. Radical
subjectivity.
Yes.
>> Can someone have a split consciousness?
>> Yes.
Um that brings up a whole different
subject.
>> Does some Can someone have a split
consciousness?
>> Yes. I'm going to repeat that. Uh, can
there somebody have a split
consciousness? That brings up a whole
different subject. We have time for it,
I think. Um, no, we don't. We only have
a few minutes. Brings up the question of
possession and, uh, more than one
personality, one body, uh, multiple
personality disorder.
Um it brings up the fact that uh
entities of different realms can uh
forcefully uh sometimes take over the
consciousness of the human being. A
human being can focus
and by karmic um propensity by some
karmic
um event
uh allow for let's say some lower astral
to take temporary possession of the body
and possession of your consciousness. So
you think that things are happening that
are really going on in a different
domain
crossing over from one domain to
another.
We had an entity coming up from another
country and why very insistent send all
kinds of faxes. We would answer the
faxes.
Uh some of the faxes would be sensible
and then faxes would come through that
were really stupid. I said we already
answered that you know this person
insisted on coming all the way from
Australia to see me. See and we refused.
We said no we can't do that. We don't uh
we didn't want to move. Anyway, this
entity
would was was on the one hand
well-meaning calibrating in the 300s
and then a week later a completely
ridiculous facts had come through and
what that entity calibrated at what
>> 50 or very low 70 right
>> I know
>> we have permission to ask that entity
resist that entity was over 50 60 yeah
that entity was around 60
both in the same body. So sometimes this
guy be a really nice doing everything
for the good of mankind. The next thing
he was he had really an evil intent
about his visit to me and I was very
happy that he
didn't get to meet me or I might not
even be here. So
yes, there is a possibility and it's a
karmic I think it's karmic inheritance,
right? Karmic inheritance. Uh one
opening for it is blasphemy. Resist. One
bl one opening for it is to curse others
to hell. Resist. All right. So there are
very negative spiritual decisions you
can make that will then open the later
karmic possibility for that which you
just called in to visit you folks. You
curse somebody to hell. Now you get to
see what hell's like. So some of the
patients we see in this in the hospitals
that are calibrating like 35 are doing
so because of past
serious spiritual errors
that may correct it agrees with religion
in some degree that there are some
things for which the Holy Spirit cannot
forgive you. You'll have to work out the
karma of that yourself.
>> Is there anything beyond choice?
>> Huh?
Um the question is really one of levels
of consciousness. At a certain level of
consciousness, choice is quite possible.
It's more hypothetical than real. But it
is also it is also real. There are
certain levels where choice is not
possible.
In the highest realms, no choice is
going on. Everything is happening of its
own is an expression of
what in Sanskrit is called the parushia.
the presence of God within as self which
is manifesting through the human
physicality as let's say this
speakingness the speakingness there's no
choice involved in this speakingness
it's it happens of its own and um
so there are varying levels so as we go
up the higher levels of consciousness
we'll get to that so forgiveness
acceptance reason you come up to
lovingness which is the realm of most
interest to spiritual people spiritual
People are worried about how to get over
the ego, how to get over the guilt of
the ego etc. and despair over it and how
to get to love. Love is 500 and it's a
whole different domain. The love is
really the dawning of the light of the
presence of God within human
consciousness in the nonlinear domain
at 500 year well beyond the Newtonian.
The Newtonian really reigns up through
reason. 500 now
re uh at 500
there's a different the nonlinear
begins to take precedence. It's
lovingness that makes the decisions that
is the background of your decision
lights up your decisions. And most
people in spiritual communities,
spiritual work groups such as this and
others are committed to reaching 540.
540 is unconditional love.
That's the um the saint. Uh the saint is
actually 575. But unconditional love
calibrates at 540.
That's what we all strive for. Most
people in the spiritual work strive
first for love and are delighted with
it. And then the energy of that love
leads them to drive on and they despair
over any limitation.
That's the spiritual dilemma of uh the
United States, our citizens and how to
handle bin Laden. And you saw the
endless discussions of ethics and
morality. And certainly the United
States has become reawakened to the
seriousness of morality and what is
ethical uh what is the ethical,
spiritual, what is the right way to
handle this. And um the president being
Christian and expresses Christian values
you know what what is the what is the
position what is the position of the
church been you know that I forget who
it was St. uh whatchamacall talked about
justified war. You know, when is war
justified? When? So, we have this in the
500s. Then you have the whole dilemma
down below. It's no problem. Blow the
sucker away. You know what I mean? It's
no problem
up there. There's the confusion of
Christ saying, "Turn the other cheek."
So you get the sort of liberal wing
which says well you know passivity.
No Jesus said when he said turn the
other cheek you know he also what he
also he says spiritually
and he also said uh render unto God that
which is God's and under Caesar that
which is Caesars's. So what he's saying
don't mix levels. Don't mix levels.
They'll mix levels. The Native American
Indian is quite aware of that. He he he
prays and prays and asks the animal for
forgiveness and that he he loves him and
he loves us and he appreciates his life
as he kills him.
So he understand the Native American
understands there's different levels.
There's the physical level where without
this I cannot live
and you are sacrificing your life for me
for which I give thanks to the great
great spirit
uh a sanctification of life. So
intention then is what sets the karma.
Intention is what sets the karma.
Unconditional love then is the capacity
to be in love. It's really in love with
life. You'd be driving along and all of
a sudden you just feel a surge of joy.
You're just sort of in love with life
itself.
And at 540 you pretty much do fall in
love with everybody. And people belong
to 12step organizations know what that's
like. Uh you leave your judgmentalism at
the door and everyone is unconditionally
loving to the best of their ability. It
leads to a saintliness saintliness and
it brings you into serenity, a
joyfulness, a feeling of completion. uh
God is uh infinite love and the joy of
life is that
that the source of that life is the love
of God and that takes you into a sort of
an exquisite state uh which is
transfiguring. 540 is transfiguring.
Your inner life is one of serenity.
Although your emotions may jump around,
they're not who you are because the the
persona, the personality which interacts
with the world is not who you are and
and you're not, you know, along the way
to spiritual work, you realize that it's
not what you are anyway. You know, why
are you wasting time with it? You know,
it doesn't mean anything. And you could
drop it at any time. You know, you say,
"Why don't you drop that?" Yeah. Okay.
So, it's not who you are. See, cuz if
it's who you are, you're not going to
drop it no matter what because that's
intention.
But emotionality can come and go and
meet anything. And even a saint can get
annoyed with something. And it doesn't
mean he's not saintly. But if you ask
him, does he believe that? He doesn't
believe that. No. And it's just the
animal talking. So the animal will talk.
If you step on his toes, he'll say like
that. But that's not who you really are.
All right. illumination and bliss at 600
uh there's a transformation uh which
occurs with the surrendering of all
sense of self as the ego
then that so 600 is the crossover from
I as limitation and form to I as the
field
as consciousness itself
as the subjective sense of eye. The
sense of eye is coming out of an
infinite non-personal eye which as it
comes through you, you personalize
and give it a discrete meanness. But
that's late in
the process of awareness.
The one thing everybody in this room is
unanimous on is we're going to quit now.
Is that you are
anybody disagree?
Well, the only thing you can say with
absolute certainty
is that you are.
And even at about 8:40, you're going to
have to let that one go and not even
know whether you are or are not because
that again becomes an abstraction. To be
or not be is already again an absurdity
to be let go of at 8:40.
So now we've pretty much described the
world, you know, a circus, a game game
board. The ego is an endless game board
and uh your TV is your latest tunein on
the game board of the ego as it plays
out there in what the what originated as
the animal world has now been infused
with spirit. And you see the ego playing
itself out. And so the the news is no
longer ex you know depressing
any more than your little animals
depressing. Are you dep he's a good
fellow. You see he's a good fellow. He's
done everything I asked him this
morning. What more could you ask?
He even purr at times. Let's hear a
purr.
Can you wag your tail?
So you make friends with your little
animal. Stop being angry at it. Forgive
it. adopt it. Uh take responsibility of
it. Um cheer it on. Cheer it on. Life as
a human being is extremely difficult.
Jesus Christ said the same thing.
You're between the physicality, the
instinctual world, the animal, and the
knowingness of the spiritual domain.
That is a very
purgatorial almost way. Is this a
purgatorial expression? This world this
we resist. Yes, it is.
options. We said there are multiple
heavens this morning. Did we say that
here to the crowd? Oh, multiple heavens.
Multiple.
So, it's a multi-dimensional
universe. It's not just heaven, hell,
and earth, but an enormous infinite
number of possibilities in on all levels
of existence.
Wow.
Thank you.
>> Thank you.
We're looking at somebody as choice
choices. You know,
a lot of choices are really decisions.
Decisions
choices come and go, but decisions are
more longlasting.
Like person said, I couldn't decide
whether to go to a movie or commit
suicide.
The the the option to see life as absurd
is always there. To see it as comical is
always there. To see it as sad and
tragic is always there.
The ego of course gets great benefit
from choosing the lower positions. You
know,
your ego can't hang out too long if it
starts picking up there all the time.
So, it likes to get into self-pity and
get on channel 15 and so
5:30 on channel 15 is Saab time.
Uh, no, 6:00. 6:00 on channel 15
is where
everybody gets to cry and blubber and
tell you how sad their life is.
And uh it's good for you can juice that
for a lifetime. You know what I mean?
Pick a tragedy and mull on it and play
off of it. So the ego gets great
satisfactions out of these lower things.
Seeing as this group here is interested
in spiritual evolution. How do you get
all out of this? There's more than just
choice. I mean
it's understanding the nature of the
ego. The ego gets enormous gain out of
the bottom of the chart.
There's nothing better than self-pity,
nurturing hatreds, nurturing anger,
nurturing for a lifetime injustices.
If you lack an injustice, you can look
back at your ancestors and find somebody
who persecuted them and you can get into
that one.
Everybody comes from somewhere back in
time. And somewhere back in time, the
Goths invaded you or the Anglo or the
Saxons or the Normans, you know, I mean,
you can always get revenge against
somebody
and adopt a political position and get
banners and raise money from the
government. You know what I mean?
You can always get it by. So, even if
you lack tragedies in your life, I'm
sure if we look into your
ethnic background, we'll find tragedies.
And so justification for positionality
is one of the jobs of the mind to
perpetuate its existence.
Uh the ego is self-perpetuating
and it gets its energy out of
the way it juices the lower positions.
You'd say, well, why do 78% of the
people want to stay in a non-integrous
uh position in life? First of all, they
don't know it's integrous. As far as
they're concerned, it's integrous.
Killing your enemies is heroic, right?
So, ignorance prevails over the whole
field, but the payoff that people get
out of these ego positions is what gives
them their energy.
So we pretty much covered the course of
the U map. Most people here are familiar
with it. It's in the book power versus
force. It's in uh eye of the eye. We'll
reprint it again in the in eye. Uh the
the interesting thing was that
consciousness first of all
humans cannot tell the difference
between truth or falsehood.
This certainly gives that which is
facious a tremendous edge
between the uh the the yearning of the
ego for something to juice and not
knowing that there's between truth and
falsehood. You wonder that mankind got
as far as it did.
And finally in ' 86 it crossed over
for karmic reasons. When we ask was that
why was that so? It said the collective
mankind karma of mankind had justified
it.
So that the spiritual work of people who
did that was being done at times of real
great darkness uh you know manifested as
an advancement in the level of
consciousness of all of mankind from
which we all benefit. So our spiritual
work constantly benefits others and uh
even if that's not a conscious intention
but that's the nature of consciousness.
Um, we had a fun a fun question here
during the interim which I I will have
to really put up on my wall at home. It
says, "Please define God."
All right, folks.
You asked for it.
Well, to begin with, you need four years
in a theologic seminary to start the
discussion.
You have to study all the theologians
throughout all of history.
Uh we've calibrated a lot of them and
actually theologians is a list of the
things that we're calibrating.
To to define then is uh the work of the
intellect. To define means to make
comprehensible to reason. So the
question is coming up in the 400s. The
question has to do with theology.
Theology is in the 400s.
The Buddha of course did not define God
for the very good reason that
the the definitions of God are not what
God is. And people would then seek their
own definitions rather than experiencing
the ultimate reality.
Um
in the left hand column we
put the go the view of God and
as you see God goes from the despicable
really the lower astral realms are
really talking about
those energies that prevail in the lower
astral domains.
Um and and going out all the way up to
God as infinite love.
And as you move up, you move to a God
that becomes progressively more
experiential.
The 400's God is a verbalization, an
abstraction, a definition.
Uh and it depends heavily on
uh concepts drawn from history,
primarily religion.
The religious history
is one thing. Enlightenment is another.
What happens in the beginning is a great
avatar appears
who for reasons which I can't go into in
today's lecture. The avatar appears. The
avatar calibrates at a th00and
until at least recent times. A thousand
was the highest spiritual energy the
human nervous system could handle.
Even on the way up to a th00and it is
often very painful, agonizing
and extremely difficult. The energy as
you go up to 600
becomes exquisite
in the high 500s. Uh the condolini
energy runs up your spine. It's
exquisite.
It's like u
an exquisite sensation and it runs up
your back and
up the spine and into the brain and if
you if you think of the left side of the
brain it runs you can look you can run
it into the one side of the brain or the
other and it's exquisite goes on for
I don't know remember how long it went
on a couple years I guess and then it
comes down and it would come out the
heart and heart region and then it also
So exquisite, exquisitly pleasurable
um
indefinably exquisite and then on
occasion it would go somewhere. This
energy would of its own
that's the time of the miraculous also.
That's the time
that was the time of um the miraculous
and uh and many of the so-called what
they're called cities si dd h i s
certain they call powers they come about
as a result of the energy field which is
not
which exists on its own. So that the
miraculous happens within the field as a
result of the field has nothing to do
with you or a person.
We're we're sitting in a restaurant in
Korea and somebody says
this is a lady we brought to see you.
The lady sits down.
She explains that one side of her brain
has gone dead and is paralyzed. What was
her remember? the one inside of her
brain had gone dead and all the doctors
and this and that. And as she's talking
on about this, you know,
I wonder why she's seeing me about this.
I have no idea. And uh she's not talking
to me as a psychiatrist, but she goes on
and on about this thing. And then what
happened? And then uh
well, oh, I know. And then then she
stopped talking and she went away and
everybody uh marveled at that. And we
got endless letters that this woman had
become cured
cured by the energy.
So that during there was a period of
years when that would happen all the
time and people would sit down and have
all kinds of things and walk away fine.
And I would just say whoa. You know I
mean it it's the energy doing that. The
energy has the capacity to do that.
There's no decision on anybody's part.
It's probably a karmic uh potentiality
arises and brings the person into the
field and the field happens of its own.
Uh the course of miracles I say says the
same thing. It's by the virtue of this
holy spirit that uh the transformation
comes about as a result of the self with
a capital s within within the other
within the aura of that presence. Huh?
I forgot where I was recalling that. Oh
yes. Um
so up to 600
the um subjective experience is one of
increasing joy, radiance,
effortlessness.
Everything happens by synchronicity.
If you think I forgot a pointer, a
pointer suddenly appears in the world.
And that's that's normal. That's what
life is like when it's normal.
It's because of the harmony. Everything
is in synchronicity and things are not
disconnected in time. There is the point
where there is not a this causing a
that. There is a unity that from
perception looks like a this and that,
but it's all a unity. So, as you think
salt, the waitress says, "Would you like
some salt?" And it all happens of its
own.
To see how this comes about,
you have to transcend causality. The
ordinary understanding causality which
we did in the first lecture.
There is no this causing a that.
Everything is coming about as a
fulfillment of its destiny as set by the
qualities inherent in its essence
because creation is continuous at all
times. So you don't see this causing
that. What you see is creation unfolding
thusly. Huh? And as the electron on this
side, the universe spins this way and
this one is in concert. It's not that
this electron is causing this one to
react, but that which is unfolding this
as a simultaneity of the two which was
expressed by Carl Young as
synchronicity.
So there is no this causing that. the
field brings about the potentiality
within the field.
The higher the field ha gets, the
greater it its capacity to do that. As
an electromagnetic field gets stronger
and stronger, it can lift heavier and
heavier particles of metal. Yeah. Mhm.
The ultimate source is the unmanifest.
Beyond all universes,
there's an infinite number of universes,
infinite number of planes, infinite
number of domains, infinite number of
dimensions,
all coming out of the unmanifest.
As the unmanifest becomes manifest,
inherent within the manifest is the
quality of creation.
There's not a this God causing a that
thing.
Creation then
the power of creation is that which
accounts for your existence.
So the evidence for the presence of God
is your own existence because nothing of
its own has the power within it to
create its own existence.
To account for that for not seeing that
the ego thinks there's a endless string
of co billiard balls
in a string caused called causality.
God started the first billiard ball
going and now evolution is gone and then
after you leave this physical domain,
God's waiting at the end. Ho ho.
God disappear in the meantime. Started
the ball rolling. Took off. Good luck,
folks. I'll see you at the end.
Judgment day. Woe unto you, brother.
That which is infinite m power then
manifests as
what we experience as existence
that godness is I mean that that's what
we call God. God is the infinite
potentiality
that can manifest as creation as the
universe is all the universes and all
the universes
to experience that that is the source of
one's experience of one's existence
that one is that which brings forth
then is called enlightened
on the way up to 600 then The journey is
increasingly exquisite.
Exquisite,
extremely exquisite.
In the high five 500s, life becomes
synchronous.
One sees only love everywhere.
One sees only beauty everywhere.
Nothing else seems to exist.
There's a period that you go through
where you can't stop crying. is a
uh spiritual traditions. Uh this is well
recognized in certain monasteries.
Anyway, as you get into the high- 500s,
there's a sensitivity to the presence of
love.
You're in an airport and a man looks at
his wife with a loving glance and
instantly you cry. It's just too much.
You can't handle it.
And that's one reason I don't talk about
the way to God through the heart until
later in the lectures.
Otherwise this would consist of one
lecture
because as that energy comes up it's
almost incapacitating
and prior to that there's periods of
high energy of exquisite joy
periods of the happening of uh what the
world calls miraculous.
Um,
there is a less and less awareness of
the physical body. You can forget that
it even exists and be surprised when you
see it passing a mirror.
I can remember wondering who was in the
house
and that was the mirror and
and one time try walking through a wall
and bang physical body was still in this
domain.
Yeah, the nose got a little flatter but
it's good
sort of transcending identification with
the body. So first we we transcend
identification with the body as I
uh eventually the feelings is I the
thoughts is I
and in the infinite state even beyond
consciousness that which I am is beyond
consciousness itself. It's that out of
which consciousness arises.
Out of which consciousness arises.
That which is nonform is present in all
form.
It is out of the formless that form
arises.
So the journey to the 600s is exquisite.
Um making friends with your ego is the
best thing to do.
Uh learn to pet it, like it, love it,
forgive it.
Because on the way you go through these
extraordinary states
the uh presence of the not paranormal
what would you call it I don't know what
it was
um that things would happen with even
within the physical domain merely by
imaging it electronic equipment
especially would fix itself just
like that to this day I can't hold
certain thoughts in mind without the
electric and the car going out.
So when you ask me to look at something
negative, it can blow out the
electricity electronic things in the
car. So there is some kind of a
connection between the physical and the
spiritual.
Then
out of the high energy of the coming out
of the heart
near the high 500s there is a state of
exquisite bliss. There is a state in
which
all is wiped out and the mind becomes
silent
and one becomes immobilized and that at
600 the mind stops is silent. There's
only the infinite presence of that which
you are
beyond all time, beyond all dimension,
and yet not different from that which is
all one in the same thing.
And the divinity of existence shines
forth through all that exists.
That's why it's hard to function because
all reflects divinity
no matter what its form.
So in that state incapacitation occurs.
Incapacitation occurs and um
no function is possible
and whether the body survives or not
depends on karma and that which is
around you. And if karm the karmic
propensity is for the physicality to
survive then the the requirements to
make that happen are there
to this day. The body doesn't eat unless
somebody reminds it half the time. And
uh
were it not for very good friends,
the body would be thinner than it is. So
somebody reminds you to eat.
But then beyond 600, usually everyone
stops there. Out of those who become
enlightened, 600
about half the people will not survive.
Half the people will leave the world
because you don't have to stay in the
world. So the option to leave is
available
from the high 500s from 600 up. There's
no necessity to hang on to the body.
This is strictly an option. You can
leave anytime you want. And to make it
happen, all you have to do is picture
yourself as leaving the body and it
happens. And
then some karmic propensity from some
higher level will
pre prevail. Yeah.
So we went up to 600. Oh yeah, that goes
from 700 to a,000. We've never talked
about uh you know really beyond 600.
Um but 600 is
600 is devastating. 600 is
um
I'm not sure how one survives it really.
It's um
profound.
The change is profound.
It's and everything becomes silent and
in the silent everything stands forth
in exquisite brilliance
shines forth as brilliance
consciousness usually stops there
doesn't go further first of all there's
no further to go
one has already
become the ultimate possibility
there is nothing and nowhere to go from
there. So it would not
come to anybody as an option. In that
state there is nothing beyond that state
because that state is what one has
always been prior to what the world
calls time.
That which occurred in the snowbank at
age 12 was already the infinite presence
as self beyond all time. and the
understanding that uh that which I am
existed before all this before this
universe or any universe was already a
knowingness. So it's all this is
nonverbalized. So the spiritual
information
in from the high 500s on up never comes
about as thinkingness.
It isn't you think this and therefore
you then reach that because it's a
nonlinear. It's more like a it's a
presentation and awareness that just
like when you get up in the morning you
realize it's light out you know nothing
you did caused the light it's just the
light comes up of its own and
illuminates all that is so the six we
never went beyond the 600s in our
calibrated scale
and so we did uh recently and we'll get
to that anyway this is the the de the
the world's population we did that
uh I think in the last lecture the one
before we did it on the board there and
then Lou set it up on his computer while
we were sitting there. But this
demonstrates uh the world population. We
were talking about calibrated levels of
consciousness and how they are
demonstrated within the world.
Um and this is the distri distribution
uh from a different uh
using a different sort of a different
way.
I've been trying to fool around with
just you know how to best demonstrate
it.
We also played around with the diagram
of a tri of a pyramid you know in which
let's say 15% of the world's population
is at the top of the pyramid and then
the pyramid is down. So the masses of
mankind
so this gives us some idea where we are
in the evolution of consciousness
ourself. You see where are we in the
evolution of consciousness? Well, over
here is the animal world and then it be
shows up in the human and then um it
here it snarls and here it gets angry
and and now it begins to own that it has
a responsibility
and it becomes aware of itself as an
existent reality and from 200 on now we
see the appearance of integrity. This is
a different animal from over here. I
mean this is a different this is a
different being answerable to yourself
answerable to yourself from now the
levels of spiritual awareness
that is completely a different paradigm
of reality. So as we cross over
200 and up we're in a different paradigm
of reality.
These are the states of intelligence
wisdom. This is Einstein and Freud and
uh
uh Sir Francis B. The greatest
scientific minds that have ever lived
are all at 499.
Uh as we've said before, Sir Isaac
Newton, Einstein,
that's the level of the intellect. So
500 is another dividing line. 200 was a
great dividing line.
We said that 310 was uh suddenly the be
becoming helpful, willing and cheerful
and contributing to society instead of
looking to drain it. This stops here.
People stop projecting blame out there.
They figure there must be something they
did. They take responsibility. 400 is
thinking this capacity for intellection
and realization.
The light of divinity really shines
forth now at what we say is the level in
the 500 where the opening of the heart
now differentiates
people from those that are loving and
those that are less than loving but
still positively oriented. 540 it
becomes unconditional.
The purification continues and then at
600 is this
enormous transformation which cannot
really be described. Generally it stops
at 600 and uh
statistically we found that 50% uh
leave the world there and 50%
uh stay. Now those that stay,
what happens to them? Well, let's see.
uh
it's not of any statistical significance
to the world because the number of
individuals is small. The it's of
importance only the impact it has on the
world.
Um
at 6001 is b out sat chananda.
Where is sat chittananda in there? Huh?
What happened to Sat Chittananda? H. Oh,
Sat Chittananda must be next door.
Here's I know Satan someplace. You can't
give a lecture on spiritual things
without using a few Sanskrit terms to
show that you're
right. Can't talk about joy and bliss
without mentioning Satan.
Why? Because spiritual people you know
we've all read so many texts in
different from different cultural
backgrounds. So the you know please
define God is first of all theological
coming out of the 400s
then it's evidentary our knowledge of
God coming from those who traditionally
have been called enlightened from the
avatar through the saint. So here's the
avatar
uh Christ, Buddha, Krishna, Brahman,
different names in different cultures
that consciousness at 985.
A person in 985 has the capacity to send
forth and radiate into the world an
energy field
which tends to recontextualize reality
of all of mankind for centuries.
What happened 2,000 years ago
defines right through the next 2,000
years and 2,000 years and 2,000 years
are definitions of right and wrong value
uh the 12 commandments the courts the
judiciary
um
its influence on architecture values
mores
human behavior is profound even without
being stated so it's the power of that
energy field which contextualizes
the consciousness of all of mankind. So
the value then is not specifically the
specifics of a teaching but the fact
that an energy field at 1,00 appeared
within the consciousness of mankind
thereby transforming it because power is
a reflection of context.
So a context at 1,00 has sufficient
power to influence all of mankind
throughout all of time that that power
in that consciousness is still present.
Although the entity that came and left
and reflected it to us has come and gone
the energy remains the energy remains.
Uh
so in high 500s we say we went from love
to unconditional love.
575 we say those people are saintly.
This is what people the naive spiritual
seeker begin at least in the beginning
thinks they're going to find. They're
going to find somebody who's saintly
walking around in sandals with long hair
and a staff and a robe
who smiles sweetly at you.
At that point the sound of gongs is
heard
is heard in the background.
Incense arises in the air in the great
WM.
Well, it doesn't happen that way
necessarily.
If you men up Zen masters, you will know
you're more likely to get bonk over the
head. Wake up. So, anyway, saintthood
may take the different forms. Um, but
when it first hits you, this is how it
hits you. So you you're not going to
really keep your job at XYZ Corporation
very long sitting there blissed out in
front of the computer and you've
accomplished nothing since this morning
at 8 nor have you moved or gone for
lunch and people begin to speak of you
that he is maybe a little you know
all right at that point most people
leave the world you leave the world
especially uh complex world like New
York City and you come to a small mall
smaller place very often where other
people are spiritually oriented and uh
your condition uh is permissible. It's
permissible to walk around blissed out
in Sedona.
It used to be. I don't know if it is
anymore. Probably get you a ticket now.
But when I first came here, you could
walk around blissed out and people would
say, "Man, he's just blissed out." Which
means you didn't need to change your
clothes, didn't have to eat. You could
get skinny. You never bothered getting a
haircut. Your beard got longer and
longer and you were just blissed out and
it was okay. It was fine. Hey, don't you
think you ought to eat something?
Your friends would say to you. See? So,
all right. So, that was a community, a
safe community. And so therefore you
often see a shift to community. People
will leave a complex demanding because
it's so much in form. And what happens
at 600 is that the world of form
is very uh I don't know very difficult.
It's very difficult to think of form. It
takes energy like understanding
comprehending in a in a languaging way
what people are talking about.
Um takes energy. You have to keep saying
what and the meaningfulness of it comes
to you in a different it comes from a
different domain.
So there's a translation of form into
nonform so that one is aware of
what the fish are talking about.
Anyway, Fish and I understand each
other, but the
the nonverbal
communication becomes progressively
important. That's why the communication
with animals becomes very easy.
You and the animal know exactly where
they're at with each other. Nothing need
to be said. Your intention is read in an
instant by that animal, and you can read
its intention and come back to it with
what it needs to comment.
And the snake will lay there. The snake
will coil up and start to strike. And
then this profound stillness and peace
prevails. And it dominates the snake.
The snake cannot strike out of that
field because it's a field of perfect
peace and safety. And it's more powerful
the snake. And the snake is just
entranced with you and sits there and
looks at you for minutes. He's never
seen a human being before. And he's just
wailed away from it, you know. And
finally
he goes away by himself and says goodbye
rattles his tail and all is safe and
peace because that is the domain
uh which is prevailing. So at 600
then very often there's it's not
possible to function. And those of you
that are into spiritual serious
spiritual work, it's probably advisable
to have somebody that knows you that
knows you're doing serial serious
spiritual work because you can be
thought of as catatonic and taken away
to a hospital.
Yeah, that happened one time on a rock
and uh
um then there was nothing that would get
the body off the rock at all. It was
just blissed out and uh no no threat, no
thought. Take it away, give them shock
treatment, put them give him thyazine,
put them in the mental hospital. Didn't
matter. Rest them. Nothing nothing got
it off the rock except love. The love or
something that was about to happen got
the body off the rock. So love alone had
the power to do that.
So I would say because you can make
sudden jumps and you can make sudden
leaps in consciousness and you will not
know they're coming. You uh will can be
sitting there chanting and doing some uh
releasing system or technique or
something and um you do this every day
for two hours a day. I I meditated for
that and uh nothing seems to be
happening and suddenly walk down the
street and find yourself totally in a
different universe.
So it's good that friends of yours knows
that you are not catatonic and if you
have a silly grin on your face and get
faint at the sight of love that maybe
they should just make sure you eat and
look after you. So 600 uh many people as
they get close to that they seek out
spiritual communities they join ashrams
they move to a place like Sedona or at
least the way Sedona used to be where
such states are understood and intuited
and people can tell when people are in
sort of a blissful state. Okay. So what
is the awareness then at 600 is uh
well I don't know that I was ever in
that state but uh amnness never came as
an awareness to me uh never experienced
amnness um at age three as we described
before I came out came out of oblivion
came out of the void the belief in the
void of previous hinana Buddhist uh
lifetimes that the ultimate reality was
void was void. The misunderstanding of
void is nothingness which is a very
serious spiritual error. It's made in
the Buddhist tradition. There's serious
errors in the Christian tradition. The
Buddhist tradition is not understanding
the Buddhist teaching about voidness.
That which is nothing, you know, no
thing is not the same as nothingness.
Nothingness cannot exist as a reality
because for it to be it would already
have to exist which voids it already as
a as a
you know what I'm saying and besides
there would be nobody to be there to to
talk about it. So there would be no
speaking of void. It would be like
the boat would tell you that the element
reality is void. It just disappeared.
Right? No, because
no thingness. So that was the
presentation at age three or four was
out of nothingness because previous
lifetimes due to that belief system and
I was a very arduous Buddhist monk.
Hinana Buddhist monk uh went out of body
void.
That's the belief system.
The ego's belief in void can manifest
voidness as a subjective experience.
However, it's not the ultimate reality
or you would stay there. You don't stay
there because it's not the ultimate
reality.
Oblivion is a belief system. Anyway,
voidness would happen. There were
lifetimes in which that did not happen
and there's a lineage between the vo
lifetimes. But anyway, this lifetime
came out avoidance again and wham, there
was this body in a little wooden wagon
and it was spring and the wand sunlight
going on and um of course this
three-year-old doesn't know how to talk
yet. Doesn't know words or anything and
is stunned with the shocking fact of
existence. Existence.
And with the shocking fact of existence
instantly arose the fear of
non-existence.
It's corlary. It's opposite came up.
That calibrates at 940. That I think
existence versus non-existence. Oh, no.
8:40. So, this was the 3-year-old was
already looking at the conflict
uh polarity in a very advanced spiritual
dilemma of existence versus
non-existence. Is the ultimate reality
existence or non-existence?
Is it one or the other or neither? No.
In a non-verbal state there was only the
fear of non-existence because if I exist
then it could have happened that I would
not have come into existence. So there
was the fear the polarity of existence
versus non-existence which set the
karmic
spiritual conundrum to be solved in this
lifetime. Yeah, it was already there. So
somebody has something about karma uh
you can't you can't come in at that
level without having
um done a lot of prior spiritual work.
So
this is a a a state of exquisite bliss.
It uh it's it's rare and have for those
who go into it never come out of it.
This the sense I am the only in God is I
am
says please define God. That's what
brought all this on folks.
She shouldn't have asked that. Anyway,
uh I amness I never understood. Um
there was existence as existence.
Then there was the correlary the
possibility of not existing. But there
was never the thought of I amness.
So the religious descriptions of God as
I am or I am that which I am never had
any reality for me. It still doesn't.
Amness is a state of beingness.
Beingness and the reality is beyond
beingness or or not beingness. It's
beyond existence versus non-existence.
It's certainly beyond beingness. So I am
is already redundant. Is already
redundant. Amnest like beingness is an
intransitive verb. That which is the
ultimate reality requires no verbs, no
adjectives, has no nouns and doesn't
need an entrance transitive verb of
beingness, isness, wasness,
or anythingness.
It's beyond anythingness. So I amness is
to me is not exactly a valid statement.
However, when we calibrated, it comes
out as 650.
That which I am is existence.
Anybody can reach through meditation.
They're letting go of identification
with the physicality of the body as
self.
Then letting go the content of mind.
Becoming the witness of the content of
mind.
Then becoming the awareness
behind the experiencer of the witness of
the content of the mind. You see layer
by layer you withdraw your
identification from the particular from
the finite from the definable from the
material.
>> That which I am is the witness of all
that is and the witness does not change
depending on content. Yes. How do you
how are you able to use language or the
context of this reality when when you
you feel your energy? You're not formed.
How are you able to speak to people?
>> It happens of its own. In the beginning,
it doesn't happen at all.
There was no mention of it for 30 years.
there's only a condition
which um prevented any participation in
the world for a prolonged period of
time. Then the bo body began to
participate in the world again.
Uh I don't have time to check it out but
it's probably some karmic commitment or
propensity to whether or not it
continues. There's no necessity to
continue. No necessity. But it goes
about its business. it was a physician.
So it can went eventually back into
practice. People would say for instance
I mean all human made motivation
disappeared. The mind is silent and what
the world calls human wasn't even there
anymore. Um even the idea of serv
serving others helping the world uh
making a living all those things that
were meaningful were void of they didn't
even exist.
That which you are goes about that which
it is as an expression of the essence of
that which is it has evolved into over
eons of time.
So this
had the
had the knowingness of the physician
psychiatrist psychoanalyst practitioner
and it went back into practice. But when
it did the whole thing was totally
different.
There was dealing with um it was the
biggest practice in New York City. Uh
and it specialized in severe illnesses,
schizophrenia primarily. So the most
hopeless of the hope hopeless came from
all around the world. And this energy uh
enabled the self to recognize the self
within the entity that was all wrapped
up there and full of drugs and in a
straight jacket on the floor and
instantly there's a recognition and a
inner healing within the entity
and it's healed.
Whether it recovers in the
in the eyes of the world was something
different. Sometimes it did, sometimes
it didn't.
But the whole practice was transformed
into a different
way of being in the world. It went on of
its own or forget it still goes on of
its own. It goes on of its own right
now. And
there was no discussion or mention of
the inner state. No mention of the
interstate.
No mention of it until
the writing of power versus force in 95.
The calibrated scale of consciousness
and kinesiology gave a bridge.
How can the nonlinear be meaningful to
the linear?
Well,
traditionally it really hasn't because
even religion doesn't understand the
mystic the enlightened per person. Once
you go up the scale, you become
what the world calls, I guess, a mystic.
One's inner
reality is what they're talking about.
But there's no recognition by by
religion. Religion usually gets quite in
conflict with a
with a sage, let's say. Yeah. Whatever
you call them.
uh although it's the source of the
reality of their own spiritual core,
their own religion,
the mystic is disavowed and very often
considered a heretic.
Way to get burned at the stake is to
become a mystic in the middle ages.
It's a bad time to get enlightened.
2000 is better.
uh
because the reality as it is experienced
is at variance with how it's described
by God. I mean by religion.
I told you this morning the the negative
views of God as a arbitrary punisher and
that's is you know that's insanity. You
know that's the god of insanity.
How insane can you be to not know the
top of the box from the bottom of the
box? Is God at the top? Is the source of
the light? Or is it religion says he's
at the bottom? The great punisher
waiting for you with whips and chains
and tortures. Oh, get away from it. I've
been in hell and no god would send
anybody there.
In fact, anybody who was evil wouldn't
even send anybody there. It's beyond
evil. It's beyond any possibility of
knowingness of what it could be.
Never curse somebody to go there, folks.
It's really bad deal because you see
that which you condemn others to becomes
your fate. You understand? You cannot
condemn somebody to hell without
uh automatically precipitating some
hellish conditions and experiences later
in life. I'll get to the raised hand in
a second. We just wanted to finish this
scale because somebody asked me what
about about God and that's really quite
a discussion.
So, uh I amness never made sense to me.
It still doesn't. And it seems
redundant. Uh the word I is sufficient.
I is complete and total because the
ultimate reality of God is the source
out of which consciousness and awareness
arises. That which is unmanifest and
manifests as consciousness
which radiates forth as the light within
which one knows the content of
consciousness as form and mind and
meaning and significance and all that.
that it becomes within the linear domain
as best expressed by
whose domain is it you know Newton
sir Isaac all right self is existence
sir Isaac Newton
uh these are terms from the world and
I'm trying to put them together just as
I did the original scale
this that which you are self is
existence
self is God manifest is we said by what
is that 700 something like that th those
are the somewhat
well-known gurus the the well-known
teachers I like of recent years nisarada
Maharaj
Raman Maharshi various ones like that
they calibrate at 700 740 around in
there the sage is 700
the sage seldom goes anywhere the sage
usually stays home And people come and
visit the sage.
And the sage rarely moves beyond
whatever level. When Ramana Maharishi
hit 700, he fell down at age 15. Felt he
was dying, which is correct. When the
ego goes, it's death. The only death
that you can experience is the death of
the ego. You can't experience death of
the body. Uh cuz you're out of body. The
ego's body's laying there. I mean, it's
not even interesting.
But death of the ego, the the self, that
is a whopper. And uh it takes all you
got to go through it. Uh anyway, so
Romano,
who I checked him out by previous karmic
inheritance. He had, you know, he was 15
or 16, not particularly religious. She
was going about daily life. One day he
falls to the ground, feels he has died.
He's felt he's he felt himself dying.
When somebody feels himself dying, you
know that they have hit the end of the
ego and that they're on the threshold of
enlightenment, which is what he did. So
when he felt himself die, when I read he
felt himself die, I know this was the
real thing because that's exactly what
happens.
And then he went into a bliss state and
sat there for weeks, didn't eat and
didn't drink water and was dehydrated
and eaten up by bugs and stuff.
It's comical because it's it's just the
way it is. So anyway, these bugs are
eating him and he hadn't eaten anything
and had drunk anything and he couldn't
care less. He's just in this incredible
state, you know. And then there were
actually he was in India where there
were some spiritually sophisticated
people that realized what had happened
to him. They began to chase the bugs
away, feed them and give them to drink
water and all. And he didn't speak for
two years.
It's very funny because in the meantime
a fake guru of which the world abounds
started taking credit for his blissed
out state. India being more spiritually
sophisticated than America. Here we
would have taken him to the hospital
give him shock treatment and shot him
full of thorazine but anyway it was
spiritually sophisticated community. So
this uh spiritual faker and I'm telling
you there's a lot of around and you
don't have to travel to find the farm.
So starts taking credit. He says, "This
is my student. Look at this bliss state,
you know." So he started signing up
students right and left.
Ramona being in a in a in a mute state
for two years, unable to speak or say
anything, had nothing to do with it. Of
course, he couldn't have cared less. I
mean, it's guys making a living off it.
So what's the difference? Yeah. If
you're a statue, let the birds use you
how they will, you know, it doesn't
affect the fact that you're a statue.
Yeah. So with uh with coaxing and all
after about two years Ramano began to
learn how to speak. Uh but the speaking
again I don't know if he spoke of his
condition or not. I don't know what he
spoke of but
uh the condition cannot be spoken of. So
finding the the levels of consciousness
gave a bridge to try to make the
nonlinear comprehensible to the
linear.
As you go up the scale of consciousness,
you see you're going from that which is
definable, measurable,
scientifically verifiable to that which
is becoming more ineffable. As you cross
over at 500, you left the world of
science. Science can't measure that.
Can't put it in a box. Can't take its
temperature. Can't get its atomic
weight. Can't get its vibration on a
spectrometer.
It's left the world of science, the
Newtonian paradigm of reality. And so
500 love is the real emergence of the
nonlinear, the spiritual reality of the
nonlinear, which is the presence of God
is love.
People say, you know, where do you find
God? God is love. God is everything.
Loving within yourself is already the
presence of God. How can you tell?
Anybody who's interested in spiritual
work and spiritual development
has already within them the presence of
God that is pulling you like a magnet.
So it's not that you are pursuing God,
but it's like the magnetism of the self.
That which you are, the truth of that
which you are is drawing you inevitably
inevitably to like a moth to the flame.
Can't be resisted.
So here's Raman Maharshi. Niser Gada
Maharaj the same thing. That's why I'm
telling you you should have a friend
that knows what you're up to.
Niser Gada of course ran a beady shop.
It's a cigarette smoke shop. Politically
incorrect in today's world that's for
sure. But anyway, he ran a smoke shop
and he smoked endless cigars himself.
And he would excited get excited and
pound on the table and talk to his
followers, you know. And he had a little
shop little attic up over his beady shop
in Bombay.
And he was merely practicing I forget
the not mantra the statement that his
teacher had given him. I am all or
something I don't know something simple
sounding thing but he really focused on
it. And of course the real critical
thing that works in spiritual work which
we'll get to in later lectures is the
fixity of focus. When you decide to
really go for it, it means you cannot
deviate from the edge of the knife for
even one split second. If you're going
to surrender every sensation, impulse,
thought to God as it arises into the
focus of consciousness,
that has to be done with a fixity of
purpose, which is like a razor beam.
Enormous intention and you're not going
to get off the edge of the knife for
anything. Hoops and hollers on this
side, sad crying people on this side,
wealth, happiness, radiation, seduction.
Nothing gets you off the edge of the
knife when you start that. You better
warn your friends because the end is
near. So this is devotion and
dedication. The and the way of the
heart. You see, to to to live on the
edge of the knife requires an enormous
devotion.
So the way of mind which I tend to talk
about in public because I can talk about
that when you talk about the way of the
heart you very often have you can't
study because the bliss day comes back
and you're walked out of it and that's
in the lecture if you can come up and
you can bless them maybe you know so
all right so you don't really have any
say over it there isn't any you to have
a say
uh there isn't any this causing of that.
There isn't any uh center center point
of the ego mind that is making decisions
about what will be said. You see in
ordinary consciousness you think there's
a me that is making a decision to say of
that
on top of that you get purpose and
intention and becomes very elaborate. I
don't know how anybody manages it.
No, what happens is because of the
nature the quality of the self within
with a capital S the perushia that core
of the self out of which the expression
comes forth happens of its own.
The question arises from the audience
that affects the self which then speaks
back through this
person here this animal here.
All right. So
this we usually call a sage. This is
Ramana Maharshi Nisagod Maharaj.
Uh
this experience here
now we're getting into the sense of I
see
um because as that state opened up that
which I am
that which I am it sounds so stupid.
That's not right either. That which is
um is all that is
and it
the the common nature through all of it
is divinity.
That which you are that which is and
it's the experience of reality as
allness.
We mentioned the error of void. That is
the ultimate reality allness or
voidness.
That's what happened at age four. Poor
guy laying there in his little wagon.
Boy. Anyway,
what what a conundrum for a
four-year-old. Well, so anyway,
the ultimate reality is allness. see
allness. So out of the conundrum of the
ultimate reality as allness or
nothingness arose the confirmation some
50 years later or whatever it was of
self as allness.
So realize that that which you call I,
that which is the self, that which is
divinity, and that which is all that is,
uh, calibrates at what does that say?
750. Yeah. All right. Then from 750 to
800, what happens is 30 years of
silence.
uh because the it's the transformation
is so stunning that you're struck dumb
for 30 years. The mind doesn't think to
think in the to think in the presence of
the infinite presence would be the
ultimate absurdity. Not even
it's not even a possibility. Um
so out of that silence then arose some
kind of an awareness of this bridge and
how it could be explained.
Um
how it could be explained. Yes. How it
could be explained.
This this this came about of its own
this understanding of the calibrated
levels of consciousness as a way of
making the nonlinear comprehensible to
the linear.
The human mind is used to scales,
calibrations, temperatures, and
therefore the calibrated levels of
consciousness seem to make sense. And
you know, we stumbled on kinesiology as
the ultimate tool.
and um that the field of consciousness
is um
infallible
because it's based on that which is that
which has reality
and therefore it cannot be fooled.
Therefore the kinesiologic test is only
a tr test of yes
it has no test of no. When the arm goes
weak it doesn't mean no. It merely means
the absence of yes
because the infinite reality is
allness
and existence and truth. Its opposite
has no existence.
And we used an example in a previous
lecture.
There's only electricity going down a
wire or not electricity. There is no
such thing as non electricity going down
the wire.
Electricity is either present or not
present. You understand?
Things are either present or not
present.
Absence is not a reality. You can't take
an armload of absence and bring me an
arm load of absence
any more than you can bring me an
armload of non-existence.
You know what I'm saying? There is no
opposite to God. There is no opposite to
God. I think the beginning of the course
of miracles in one of the early pages, I
forget the textbook or the workbook says
that
something about there is no opposite to
truth.
Understanding in that eliminates all
fear that there is no opposite to truth.
And so we'd say the capacity to now
communicate this would be 800. That's
the teacher of enlightenment. And he has
a title. Where is his title down here?
You had a title somewhere.
You had a title so the world knows where
you're at in Korean. U so 800 would then
be the capacity to teach this. These are
not great teachers. You see and the
reason for that is you can be the
greatest piano virtuoso in the world but
that doesn't make you a good teacher of
the piano.
You can be hyids but be a very bad
violin teacher. So to be the virtuoso is
one thing to be able to convey it to
others and share it teach it to others
is something else. So it's like a
separate karmic kind of a commitment I
would say probably most likely a
commitment is that a commitment I never
asked. We have permission to ask resist.
That was a prior karmic commitment
resist uh an agree no agreement. That
was a prior agreement resist. Okay. All
right. Maybe for getting me out of hell.
Huh?
All right. So that was 800.
Now 840 that oh yes that's that's what
this what occurred in this lifetime at
age three or four was the confrontation
the confrontation with the ultimate
reality as existence or non-existence.
were not existence a possibility, whence
would it arise?
Existence, you see, because the
unmanifest becomes manifest. As it
becomes manifest,
the god as the godhead. So you might say
the Godhead is the unmanifest out of
which divinity arises and the nature of
divinity is creation and henceforth
everything that evolves out of creation
itself has the capacity for creation.
So all is in the process of being
created as well as being creator you
might say. So things are not arising in
the world out of causality. They're
arising out of creation.
Everything, every
what we call thing, every what the world
mind calls event is not sequential.
It's only sequential from the from the
viewpoint of the observer because you
perceive things sequentially. You think
that one thing is causing another.
So if we have these balls A, I'll do it
from your viewpoint. A B CD,
the world uh assumes that you hit A with
a Q stick and that hits B and that
causes C that causes D. And that's the
Newtonian paradigm of causality.
Actually the way it comes about is that
that which causes A is simultaneously
the cause of B is exactly and
simultaneously the same as the cause of
C and is simultaneously the cause of D.
It takes the totality of God to account
for the existence of everything at any
moment anywhere in time.
Otherwise God would have merely set the
billyard ball rolling, disappeared off
into heaven which is up there. Don't
forget folks, you're down here and God's
up there.
That's the truth of religion. God is
transcendent.
That's where the mystic gets himself uh
burned at the stake. He says, "No, God
is imminent.
That which is the source of life itself
within oneself. The source of existence
and reality, the source of the awareness
of your existence
is the presence of God as within as self
as the ultimate reality.
And that is the truth of the enlightened
sage
who says that God is not only
transcendent but eminent. He doesn't say
that. The sage says knows that that
which is imminent is also transcendent.
They are not opposites. They're only two
different ways of looking at it. That
which is transcendent is obviously would
have to be imminent. And that which is
imminent would obviously by definition
also have to be transcendent. To say
that God is either transcendent or
imminent. God is realized the presence
of God is realized as imminent then we
say the person is enlightened or a sage
or whatever you want to call it. All
right. And in some religions like Islam
um to be enlightened is u heretical by
definition. Heretical by definition.
Islam.
Islam comes out of Muhammad who
calibrated at 700. So
at his highest peak, Muhammad was at
700. And Islam has never done as well.
It does it does better in in
forcing
adherence. Islam is superior to
Christianity enforcing adherence
and
to about a mecca five times a day is
quite an adherence. So it has a profound
adherence but its ultimate truth is not
what
some others have achieved. So the avatar
then beyond self and existence. The
avatar at 985
um
is that power is sufficient to influence
mankind throughout all of time.
What's the difference between 985 and a
thousand and only came upon it recently?
I was explaining in a lecture or two,
writing or something the obvious nature
of reality as it appears and then
realized that the Buddha differed. Oh,
so he calibrated um you know the
Buddha's law of
of um it was stated by the Buddha the
law of endless causation. So what I just
said already differed from what the
Buddha thought the endless causation
that the cause of one thing is an
endless series of causes.
But to see a cause you would have to
have something that is caused and to see
something that is caused is already
within the world of form.
To see as
to see that everything is coming out of
the spontaneity of creation out of the
essence of that which it is calibrates
at a thousand the and the law of
infinite causation dependent causation
calibrates at 985
that was we just discovered that this
week or something. So
these are the great the great
enlightened beings of all time who had
not only the capacity of the knowingness
but the capacity to express it in
society in a way that was sufficiently
meaningful that it recontextualized
all of society for a thousand years.
Um so that's I as the ultimate reality
is the subject of the book I'm finishing
that that which you experience as self
that which you say when I say I how can
you experience your own existence
we experience that which I am as I the
pronoun I it's very interesting that the
pronoun I is capitalized just as the G
is in God the only pronoun that's
capitalized his eye.
You would think out of humility, mankind
would have made himself a small eye
and God the big eye, but he didn't.
Why is I the same as God? I is
capitalized and so is God. Is that
grandiosity, megalamania, insanity?
What?
No. It's because the truth is that the
personal eye can only be known by virtue
of the infinite eye which underlies it.
It's because of the universality
in the infinite knowingness of the eye
of the self, the presence of God within
conveys to you the capacity to to be a
aware of your own existence as the small
eye. So the small eye knows that it is
by virtue of the infinite eye
which is the source of its consciousness
awareness and existence
to know self is I. So the ultimate
statement please define God then is
God is the infinite eye within
and without. the infinite eye of all
that exists
beyond all dimensions, beyond all
planes, beyond all universes, beyond all
divisions.
Therefore, you don't want to bring down
the level of I by saying amnness
because I as the infinite reality is is
a thousand
and I as amness is already a
considerable condensation
because now you put the condition of
beingness and isness upon it.
Beingness and isness means to come into
manifestation. But the infinite I that
which you really are is the unmanifest.
The infinite eye is the unmanifest.
To say I am
means that you are now manifest. It
limits the realization of that which you
are at this moment. One experiences
oneself at man as manifest.
But that doesn't mean it's the ultimate
reality any more than you are your body
or you are your mind.
Have we done with God yet?