Welcome to Dr. David Hawkins Sedona 2002
series, The Way to God. Lecture 3, the
levels of consciousness, subjective and
social consequences.
Originally presented March 9th, 2002 at
the Sedona Creative Life Center.
Today um the lecture was about uh the
topic announced topic was about um
I forget what it was
anyway we'll talk about it because
what I want to do we're we're giving a
series of 12 lectures
uh so that I will then have said
everything I have to say
that I can rest peacefully in the great
beyond. You see, I don't want at the
last moment to say, "Oh gosh, I forgot
to tell them all about it."
Uh, that's a good rule of thumb, you
know, for spiritual decisions
is um what do you what do you want to be
responsible for on your deathbed? And I
remember making a number of decisions in
my life
u because uh the last moment is really
quite a confrontation.
Anyway, today uh the topics uh are
really the emphasis of in other words in
that talk we will try and cover that
subject. However, we always call cover
all of it. So
every lecture I want you know complete
is is really complete in a way but the
emphasis is different.
So, we'll talk for a while and then uh
I'll talk for a while and then we'll
have a break and then after that we'll
have questions and answers.
In the past, we've had people write them
and send them up. But, uh you can also
just because we have a very good um
sound system now, you can just ask them
from the audience, you raise your hand
and and uh I'll repeat the question. Uh
that'll make it easier for everyone.
And I don't see all that well to read
those cards anyway. I don't know what
they say. I just
make a wild guess.
Yeah.
All right.
So, today we're emphasizing the um
the map of consciousness as it applies.
uh what it is uh what is the world and
um and then how that relates in general
to
the whole field of consciousness.
You're aware that
consciousness as defined in the writings
that I've been doing can roughly be
defined as the linear and the nonlinear.
The linear being the ego, the world of
form, definition, that which is
temporal, that which the world believes
is reality.
As compared, and this is just a point of
perception, it's not a different level,
but compared to the nonlinear, which is
not definable as form,
is considered by a large percentage of
the world to be unreal.
uh and it's classically defined as
spiritual.
The map of consciousness crosses over
between the two. The importance of the
book power versus force was after 30
years of not seeing anything about the
subject at all. I suddenly became an
expert how to define how to make
make it possible to go from the known to
the unknown.
The subjective
the radical subjectivity of
a spiritual state is difficult to
describe and as I say for 30 years I
never mentioned it.
Uh and then saw this
medical test called kinesiology. It was
considered a medical test. And when I
saw John Diamond do that kinesiology,
instantly I saw what what it was because
I was myself already. My reality was
nonlinear and therefore I saw it from a
different dimension than the rest of the
audience.
It was always presumed to be a local
phenomena where a local condition causes
a local reaction.
And I saw that it was a nonlinear
phenomena
and that the reaction was due to the
presence of a nonlinear state of
consciousness.
So it opened then
that kinesiology could be used beyond
the linear
and beyond the local. And in
experimenting with it over many years
now, we found that we had a means of
directly accessing a field called
consciousness,
which is again um very iffy to people
who live in the
uh Newtonian paradigm of reality.
Consciousness in that definition is
whether you're awake or asleep.
Consciousness in the spiritual
definition of course is the field in the
field from which one is aware of one's
existence
and the content of mind.
It is the field and it's not the
content. So the world the ordinary world
lives in the world of content
takes the subjective uh for granted
without appreciating what it actually
is.
The subjective is where
we exist. We exist. Our knowingness, our
awareness that we are or that anything
else is is only because of a radical
state of subjectivity.
It's roughly called awareness,
consciousness.
And the thing that differentiates it
from the Newtonian paradigm is that the
subjective has no content.
So we might say that the world is let's
say if computers had arms and legs and
we're walking around the computers in
the ordinary world would all think that
they're their software. They say I'm Mr.
QuickBooks. Glad to meet you. And you're
Miss
Miss IRS computer form number 616. Glad
to meet you. And then there would be a
maverick in the midst of all of them who
walks around and says, "Well, I'm my
hardware. I'm none of those things." And
they would consider him slightly insane
and put him off in a corner. So if he's
wise, he doesn't mention that and I
never did for 30 years.
that I'm my hardware and the software
comes and goes. Uh and uh but the the
one reality behind all computers is
without hardware there's no software
programs possible.
So the world thinks it's its programs.
All right. So today we're going to talk
about those programs and
of course illuminate the whole
understanding of consciousness itself as
a consequence.
Most everybody here has read power
versus force or maybe eye of the eye.
Either way, uh you know the map of
consciousness has become extremely
wellnown. and it's widely quoted and I
get requests every day to reprint it in
some publication or article.
So it's become um a useful tool. So we
should really then understand what it
really uh reflects. What does it really
reflect?
And as we will see
it's a way of it's a it's a way of
describing
the ego is really what it is.
If we look at society we we were talking
about the map of consciousness as it
expressed in today's society. If we look
at the world and society
uh what we see is the ego projected out
there.
The world itself is uh a playground,
uh a graveyard, an amusement center,
depending on your point of perception.
Yeah. So, uh I consider it
entertainment. It's sort of like turning
on the TV. And, uh yesterday morning's
newspaper was was dramatic. It it had
two of the most horrible stories you
could possibly read. And it just broke
me up because, you know, it's like the
world pushes the extreme just like TV
programs do. Push the extreme.
When was a baby that got left
three-year-old left home by its parents
with the uh their pet python.
When they came home, the baby was dead.
The python had strangled it to death.
What do they think the python was going
to do? Play dominoes with the kid? I
don't know. So anyway, you say, "Yeah,
right." Uhhuh. Well,
when I was a kid, my grandmother would
always read the newspaper and then she
would cry. She would always find a sad
story and cry. And my grandfather would
get very irritated with her.
Molly, when you cut that out, there's
this little three-year-old Tikeke. He
was strangled to death by a python. And
she would weep and weep.
So to her, it was sad. Uh to me the
story was like ridiculous. Like life is
a theater of the absurd. Yeah, theater
of the absurd. So we'll talk about these
levels of consciousness to get them
clarified for once and for all what they
mean and clear up any confusions that
there could be about it. To begin with,
they are neither better or worse. It is
not a hierarchy of worthiness
or accomplishment.
It is a way of looking like a prism. A
prism breaks up the light and to its
different colors. It doesn't mean that
ultraviolet is better than blue or
better than green.
So what we've done here is break up you
know the level of levels of
consciousness with a prism and these
would be the colors that come out. So
these colors
these are what they are is progressive
levels of power within the field of
consciousness. First of all
um the higher you go the greater the
power.
It's to some degree it's like a
thermometer
and this thermometer
then these are various degrees of power.
They are also various degrees of love.
They also are various
degrees to which you might say the
presence of God is consciously reflected
into life.
To transcend the opposite, it's
necessary to give up a positionality.
And we use a thermometer as an example.
You can't just say put your finger here
and say, "Well, above it it's hot and
below it's cold." And now hot and cold
are opposite. That's what the mind does.
We took that up in the lecture on or we
will be on transcending the opposites to
reach the state of so-called state of
enlightenment is necessary to drop all
positionalities
in which duality disappears
and that is the pathway of adv advida
which we'll have a lecture on
any dropping of positionality. So
neither um the presence of God as it is
manifested as it manifests and radiates
through a specific consciousness then
um we would say at the top is
that the light is clearer that there's
less uh darkness in the field and that's
why they're called enlightened states.
The light actually is almost an
experiential. It's almost like
a great clarity and light does suffuse
everything.
As the ego imposes its uh
itself between truth and its own
egoentricity, we might say that the
bottom is uh egoentricity.
Let's say that the bottom of the if the
top is God, what is the bottom? The
bottom is
profound state states of egoentricity
um
out of which um considerable damage to
world the world can come in our view of
it uh let's say Mr. been loud and
calibrates at 70 which is down in here
and uh
so that which is below brings tends to
bring what the we consider somewhat
destructive but that of course is a
point of view.
It was constructive from his viewpoint.
So again constructive and destructive
are only positionalities.
The levels of consciousness however we
were able to calibrate using kinesiology
and I forget how we even started with it
but um the levels are really
traditional. It's really the perennial
philosophy only documented and I've been
having I was going to say brought up as
a psychiatrist
brought up as a psychiatrist.
I was brought up as a psychiatrist and
psychoanalyst and psych psychoanalyst
and uh so
I naturally apply these things as I
understood life and the human mind. So
these are states that are both emotional
you see emotional
and uh intellectual and spiritual
and um these are the names by which we
commonly know these phenomena in daily
life. anger, fear, grief, pride, hope,
all those things. Then to give it uh
an additional usefulness,
it's been calibrated and the
calibrations turned out to be
logarithms.
So that a move of a few points on the
scale
uh as you're aware in a log is to tend
to that that number. So it's a very
sizable move. Very sizable move.
The move from let's say 200 to 202
does not sound much in numerically but
because you're talking about the
logarithm
it's 10 to the 2022nd power rather than
200th power. So numerically that's quite
a difference.
Where is that in society? Well, we found
we found that um most u government
agencies calibrate about 202
that 200 is the level of integrity. So
we said 200 and over we made the
interesting discovery that 200 and over
uh that some things made you go strong
and some things made you go weak. So we
discovered that kinesiologically then
consciousness is aware of the difference
between truth and falsehood between that
which is pro-life that which is
detrimental to life
and on a scale of 1 to a th00and so we
said well on one to a th00and what is
this dividing line it came out 200 we
said is it over 150
so these numbers were arrived out
pragmatically by discovery. Their value
is relative. Their value is relative.
Anybody can make up their own scale. You
can make up a scale 1 to 10. You can
make up a scale 1 to 100. You can make
up your own scale. If you're going to do
calibrations and and try to arrive at
numbers to compare to this SC map, you
you have to sort of prefix it with uh as
compared to this map, so and so or
something calibrates over 200. And some
people don't do that and they come up
with um strange numbers that their baby
calibrates over 2,000 and things.
They send me excited telegrams.
They do literally. We get faxes, phone
calls, stuff around the clock. Well,
they're just newborn babies, 1200,
wasn't it? Whoa. I thought the baby
Jesus just reemerged.
So if you're not getting the same
number, all right. So it's a relative
scale. It's not an absolute scale. Uh
it's useful.
It is profoundly useful.
On the one hand, you could ignore it
completely
and just trust and and love God and
that's sufficient. That's that's so you
don't have to do any of this. But being
a human being with a mind is probably
not going to satisfy you to do that. And
as somebody said to me, it's also quite
boring.
This does add some entertainment on the
way is better than saying the rosary
thousands of times, which can be very
boring if you ever tried it. And you get
up to about a thousand, man. It's like a
drop over deal. And Jesus still is not a
rosary. He's showing himself in the
room. So
anyway,
>> all right.
The world then is interesting. In the
books that I'm writing, I sometimes cite
events in the world. And people will
say, "Well, why are you saying something
about the world?"
It's not because I'm concerned about the
world. It's because it reflects the ego.
When you read the daily newspaper,
you're seeing your own ego projected out
there. It's really a neat teaching tool.
I love the evening news because it's
hysterically entertaining because you
see the games the ego is playing and the
ego speaks through this person's mouth
and then this person's mouth you know
you know what I mean it's a violation of
our civil rights to you
or say in God we trust okay you could
say in God we don't trust or we could
say we don't trust in anybody how's that
forget trust I mean you can't bring up
the thing without a political, you know
what I'm saying? All right. So, anyway,
we found that there was a critical
level. This is known in foreign
cultures. When we were in Korea, they
said, "Well, that's the way they buy a
tangerine in the store. If the tangerine
makes you go strong, you buy it. If it
makes you go weak, they don't buy it."
Commonly known based on the strict
obvious physiologic
um basis that all that is has certain
characteristics. Protoplasm if you uh
withdraws from that which is noxious
um
it bleeds if you stick a needle in it
that's impersonal. So these fields of
unconscious of these calibrated fuels
are impersonal.
Kinesiologic test is impersonal.
I didn't introduce you to my right arm.
Susan say hello. This is my right arm.
And many of the numbers right now we're
working on a book that's going to have a
thousand calibrations. Everything and
anything that ever was on the planet
that ever meant anything from Cicero and
Nero to the PA to uh Westminister Abby
to all the great beings throughout uh
the great books of the western world
etc. So we do lots and lots and she is
literally my right arm as you can see.
All right. So these these are very
pragmatic. They are very useful. They're
radically useful because it tells the
difference between truth and falsehood.
Um
it was devastating
and um a few people who first reviewed
the book uh were totally devastated. One
man took off went to Europe and spent
two weeks to recover from the shop. The
realization that you can tell truth from
falsehood is so profound that hardly
anybody gets the implication.
No. At no time in human history has it
been able to has there been any way to
tell truth from falsehood whatsoever.
And we see all kinds of approximations
of scientific method and all these
desperate attempts to tell what um Susan
and I can tell in a second.
you look at the the IRS form, you know,
and I said, well, we could either spend
about I think it takes an average of 16
hours to fill it out or something like
that. Or we could say, let's see, we
over 3 2,000 3,000 4,400. There we go.
You send him a check. We check the
kinesiology. This is what we owe you.
Sonia is sitting in the back there does
all my manuscripts. She spends endless
thousands of hours writing all these
books and editing them. And we all
that's how we say how much do they owe
you 800 900,000,000
okay that's how we figured other people
would have a long tabulation with a time
clock time in time out time to go to the
bathroom or should that be on the clock
or not you know what I mean
all right
to be able to tell the difference
between truth and falsehood is is
enormous is enormous profound
um its implications its applications in
just about everything in societ society
is is is profound.
Um
in in the daily news there's always a
war someplace and in every war
the United States for some reason never
knows what's happening. The US is always
surprised
surprised by Pearl Harbor. Yesterday it
was surprised last week was surprised
that they attacked some place in Afghan
and they were surprised to find it was
loaded with zillions of soldiers. They
only thought there was a few people
there. They're always surprised and uh
never need seem to know what's
happening. They were surprised by the
attack.
Uh so its implication is um to not know
is to be vulnerable
and to know is a much better position to
be in. It would be better to know how
many
uh soldiers are hiding in the caves
there than to walk in with half a dozen
people and find you're surrounded by a
thousand or something. All right. So the
usefulness is very very pragmatic in
daily life. Uh lots of times a question
will come up and we just ask
kinesiology. We get a yes or no and
that's it solves it. you know, uh
you you notice that a lot of people are
very familiar with this thing and we've
talked about it before and so I don't
want to u
spend undue time on it.
However,
the critical point is whether a thing is
over 200 or below 200. You don't need to
know the number. Either a thing makes
you go strong with kinesiology or it
makes you go weak. Now, how accurate is
the test itself?
I'm not a kinesiologist. Kinesiologists
are there many people who are expert.
They do it all day every day. Uh and
they're very very adept at it. They use
know various techniques. There's the
ring technique where you can pull and
see if you're if you compare how strong
you are holding Jesus in line and how
strong you are holding bin Laden in
line. Uh get a yes or no. Uh we say
generally if it's an important question,
we like kinesiology with two people. Uh
one reason is if you can find somebody
you can work with and that can be a
problem. Uh a lot of married couples
cannot work with each other. They have
to find some other person for reasons
I'm not sure.
Uh but if you find somebody you can work
with and you work with them
consistently. So if you're involved in
it in sort of a very serious way, what
happens is that the person you work with
becomes strangely attuned to almost your
question. If almost as I walk over to
ask
a knowingness comes on on and the answer
is there. In fact, I can feel it run
down my arm as I ask it. You become
quite adept at it after a while.
The person that works with you gets to
almost intuitively tune in to uh I'm
searching for something uh and I have no
clue to it. and and suddenly she'll say
what about the so and so and we ask and
yes that's what we're looking for. So
the value of having a partner is their
their intuition is added to yours and
you can accomplish rather formidable
tasks in very short order. There are
train people who are trained in it.
There are um techniques that are well
demonstrated in videos, books and audio
tapes. Um I can't think of his name
right now but we do have a sheet of
references to uh kinesiology uh
teachings on the internet various
resources
uh switched on living is done by what's
his name
>> Jerry
>> huh
>> templates yeah does a very neat
demonstration
so as I say I'm not a kinesiologist my
only interest Galileo's interest in
telescopes was you can see out there he
but he wasn't really you know a
telescope maker. It wasn't really his
thing. So uh we refer questions on the
techniques out to people who are good at
it and in many communities the
chiropractors are the best at it. They
have they use it more extensively or
holistic doctors.
Um so anyway it's extremely useful
technique. Um yes or no. People say well
can I get the same answers with dowsing?
And the answer is generally generally
yes. Generally yes. Um as far as yes or
no as far as a yes or no answer.
All right. So the calibrated levels then
have enormous significance
uh in in doing the most important
events, people and places in all of
human history. Um you get almost a
topographical map. you get begin to get
an understanding of human history that
is not capable that you're not capable
of getting from just uh dry linear facts
uh or even from travel logs. You begin
to see how consciousness evolves. And so
in the book I'm just finishing, I try to
track the conscious the evolution of
consciousness throughout time and
throughout all of evolution up to its
present point and the emergence of a new
level of consciousness, a new kind of
humanity.
You know, out of homo sapiens, we see
what Homo sapiens is been up to the last
several thousand years. Before that, we
had Cro-Magn and we had Neanderthal man.
And um as you see, I'm not politically
correct. I don't call him Neander. I
call him Neanderthal. I grew up with
Neanderthal. That's going to have to be
good enough.
Anyway,
we the most important thing we
discovered for mankind in general was
that the level of consciousness of
mankind went from 190 where it had been
for many many centuries and went to 207
about 1986.
That began then the emergence of a whole
new paradigm of what's possible for
mankind despite today's headline news.
Um, and it signaled to to me anyway the
emergence of a new paradigm of reality.
And it signaled the emergence of a new
branch off the evolutionary tree tree
which I call homospiritus.
Homo sapiens did not have spiritual
awareness. Homian homo sapiens have been
busy killing each other and murdering
each other and drowning each other for
centuries and centuries and centuries.
killing each other off at the rate of
$70 million, 70 million lives in one big
sweep, World War II.
Um, now a new emergence is the dominance
then of a positive spiritual energy
dominating the consciousness field of
mankind. So what you could get away
with, what was acceptable in past uh
times, in past times it was assumed if
you captured an enemy naturally you
enslaved them, raped them, pillaged them
and killed them often and mutilated them
in horrible ways. And that was
considered okay. It's the way the world
is and nobody questioned it. At a
consciousness level 207, there would be
a cry of outrage, an outrage. Uh so
the fact that our consciousness has now
emerged so a new emergence of awareness
is dominating the whole field of human
consciousness
with profound implications for everyone.
All right. So 200 then denotes a
difference between
and again it is not a level of
opposites. It's not that 200 above is
one reality and below 200 is another
reality. It's not good versus bad. This
is a thermometer.
And this is the thermometer.
And the presence of God, the presence of
love is what
accounts for the calibration.
Above this level, you go strong and
below it goes weak. And it looks like
you're looking at true and false. It
looks like you're looking at good and
evil. But that is not the case.
The case is that you see water. Water is
still water whether it's ice, liquid or
steam.
The only thing that changes there is
temperature. Above this temperature you
got over 212 it changes its quality.
Then below 212 it turns back into
liquid. it changes its quality, but it's
still just water. Then at 32 degrees
Fahrenheit, it changes its quality and
turns into a solid.
So you can't say steam is the opposite
of ice or that water is the opposite of
steam. You understand what I'm saying?
I'm trying to get out of any trying to
use this in any kind of positionality.
As the temperature increases or
decreases
then quality changes. The same with
light in a room. There is not two
different things light and dark.
There is intense light. As the light
gets lower and lower and lower, it gets
dimmer and dimmer and dimmer. Then it's
harder and harder to see. And we say
it's dusk or dark. You know, there's
only one variable and that's light. The
presence of light. That's the only
variable. There's not two things, light
and dark. You can't get a take take a
box of darkness and put it someplace or
say shine me some darkness in this
closet. It doesn't have any existence.
The only reality then is light and light
is either present or not present and
it's present to varying degrees. So the
analogy is that the love of God is like
the light and
up here the love of God is quite intense
and down here it diminishes and uh
becomes progressively darker.
When this happens, the human emotion
that goes with it
goes through the whole panorama
from an ecstatic state, a state of
state, there's a state beyond ecstasy, a
blissful state of absolute serenity and
stillness.
As the as the calibrated levels come
down, you see the shift of emotions. And
below 200 we notice that these emotions
are
classically negative and painful.
And here down at the bottom they become
quite severe
and suicide they even lead to suicide.
The interesting thing about calibrated
levels of consciousness
is that everybody has a calibrated level
of consciousness the instant they're
born. The instant they're born, there's
already a calibratable level of
consciousness
which has a certain implication. And
we'll have another lecture with which we
talk just about karma itself.
Uh either life is extremely unfair
or there is a coherence and a spiritual
uh coherence to the universe in which
case there is no such thing as
accidental.
In a coherent universe in which the
presence of God is the infinite context
out of which all reality arises. Uh
there is no such thing as an accident.
Accident like the word chaos means a
limitation of perception. It means from
the Newtonian point of view it looks
like an accident. But from the overall
point of view there are no accidents
possible. Then
the infinite reality of God then is like
an infinite electromagnetic field.
Its power is absolute. Its power is
unlimited. Its power is infinite.
All that is is held within the infinite
power of the infinite context of God.
Nothing can happen outside of it.
Consequently, an accident is not
possible. For an accident to be so, it
would have to be outside the infinite
context of
um the universe. And if it was there,
you wouldn't know it. So, no accident is
possible.
Everything falls within a coherence.
Each thing is
where it is because of what it is.
Each thing becomes the fulfillment of
its own essence and in so doing its
characteristics define where it will
position itself within the overall
infinite field of power. So that you see
nothing is causing anything.
Everything is just being what it is. As
a consequence of it being what it is, it
automatically moves in an infinite field
of power.
Is that clear? Yeah.
So that takes care of causality. Causal
and causality. It's important to
understand that because we want to get
it past the barriers of um picturing God
as some kind of a judgmental
arbitrary
uh being. And people fear death because
now you're going to meet the great
judgmentalism. Huh.
All right. So each thing is where it is
and it's being what it is because out of
out of creation its essence then defines
that if it has wings it flies. You see?
Yeah. But that's coming out of its own
essence. So those who seek God do so and
out of the evolution of their own
consciousness
because the quality of consciousness is
to seek progressively seek to know its
its own nature.
All right.
>> Yes.
>> Are questions permitted now or rather
>> anytime. Anytime.
>> In essence then are we saying if it's um
>> if you you got to stand up and speak so
I can hear.
>> In essence you hear what he says. In
essence, are you saying that um if it's
not there's no accidents then does that
make it predestined in a sense?
>> That question always arises.
The entire universe is one karmic unity.
People say you believe in karma. It's
not a matter of believing in karma.
The entire universe is one infinite
coherence.
the context of which has infinite power
because a power arises out of context.
Therefore,
out of the infinite potentiality that we
tend to call God arises the entire
universe as an obvious coherence.
What was the question?
>> There is an accident.
>> Oh, accident. Yes. Right. So each thing
then what occurs is a result of the
essence of its own
uh reality.
Each thing then you might say has its
own karma within the infinite coherence
of the universe. Nothing can fall
outside the universe. So consequently
everything within the universe is
subject to the laws of the universe.
Each thing then
is the result of what it is spiritually.
What it is is the accumulated result of
its own decisions by its own spiritual
will.
By one's own spiritual will, one rises
or falls like a cork in the water. Huh?
Each moment we choose instant by instant
to constantly choose in one direction to
constantly choose the direction of the
light light
uh eventuates and constantly going in
this direction to refuse the light which
is your privilege.
Yeah. Everyone is created free. One can
refuse God, refuse the love of God. One
can condemn God. one can go
um and thereby choose the dark. The dark
is by one's own choice.
And those who ridicule God will then go
to realms occupied by those who ridicule
God.
If we calibrate them, they're not where
you want to go. And that's what Jesus
said. You don't want to go there.
He said it's not wrong. It's just that
you really don't want to go where the
sinful go when they die. Uh and the
Buddha said the same at every great
religion and spiritual teacher tells you
the same thing. You know that you really
don't want to go there. Uh anybody who's
ever been in profound guilt, shame,
agony of depression and loss or terror
or hopeless rage. Uh those are just uh
those are the um approach approaches to
hell. And when you get to where really
gets bad. So the great teachers have
advised us that it's not where you want
to go. And that is that is a correct
statement.
Um so it's not that we're pre
predestined
because predestination sounds arbitrary.
Uh
you can only be that which you are. Let
me answer it that way. By the nature of
existence and beingness, one can only be
what one is.
What one is, one has sculpted by one's
own hand. So then there in lies the
infinite justice of God.
All right? So the these emotions then as
they go up the scale become increasingly
agreeable.
These are everybody comes to see the
doctor in these states. This is my
office down here. Despair and anxiety
and depression and uh angriness and um
people don't see me out of uh arrogance
but yeah they do. Uh
uh anyway as we go up uh as we go up we
see the levels are far more uh and
that's because the process is different
here. Here you at the level of integrity
you have the be real true beginning of
empowerment at 200
below that you get inflation the reason
I don't like politically correct is
because it calibrates at 190 and and
there's a grading holier than thou
superiority about it and it it's not
held up
it its results don't verify it. So
there's an ego inflation egotism here.
The over here at the lower levels the
ego like uh shrinks you see but here
it's inflamed and pridefulness.
Um
here we have the anger that anger gives
people a temporary sense of power. It's
a false sense of power. It's the most
difficult problem I have. I I'm chief of
staff at a resident big residential
place
uh where we have 50 teenage girls and
their main problem is angryness other
than impulsivity and poor judgment and
getting into all kinds of horrible
trouble. Uh but
uh on a day-to-day level they're getting
along with each other is constantly
impaired with angriness. They're always
angry. They're like Johnny One note. No
matter what happens, their only response
is anger. You know what I mean? If it's
too cool in the room, they're angry
about that. If it's too warm, they're
angry about that. If I mention a certain
subject, they're angry about that. And
if I don't, they're angry because I
didn't mention it. So, I mean, it's just
a proness to angriness.
If you don't have any power, the next
best if you if you fail power, see,
these are all levels of weakness. If you
don't have any real power, then the next
thing to do is to inflate yourself. So
you see the puffed up arrogance of
Malachevich. You know, he when they take
his picture, he's always got his head up
like this. And
the UN and all the world, all the
countries of the world have no right to
question what I do. I mean,
that's Wow. And
all right. So
from 200 down are really levels of
weakness and 200 and over are levels of
power. If you have real power, you don't
need all that.
It's like
it's like self-esteem.
If you lack self-esteem, then you feel
you need self-esteem.
If you have self-esteem, you don't need
self-esteem and you're not even
interested in it. You know, people think
you're fine, you're glad they're happy.
If they don't think you're fine, it's
their problem. You know, what people
think about you is sort of irrelevant
because you're autonomous. So, these
people are not autonomous. what people
think about them makes a big very big
difference because they're levels of
weakness. Then uh these are
levels of force. Up here you have power.
Power just stands there by itself. Power
influences everything within its domain
as a consequence of that which it is.
That which you are has a more profound
effect on everything than that which you
do. That's sort of the meaning of
the spiritual teacher. It says don't
worry about saving the world. Save
yourself because through your the
evolution of your own consciousness,
you're already doing more for mankind
than you can do out there with blackards
and u
take God out of business or whatever it
is. Whatever it is,
the world you see is just u a story, a
perceptual story as witnessed by the
ego. And therefore, there's nothing out
there that needs saving.
Don't waste your time saving the world.
Save yourself because thereby you
radiate forth that which has a profound
influence. You see, force always results
in counter force. So force goes from
here to there and
requires counterforce. It exhausts
itself. Sooner or later the troops on
this side and the troops on this side
are going to deplete the resources.
At least the numbers of the population
are going to decrease. You could say
that
uh in due time they die by the millions.
Um
so therefore force is relatively weak
and it's what the world relies on. The
world relies on force. Those who have
enormous power don't need to bother with
force. So these people resort to force
because they lack power. Inflation makes
you feel important. Being aggressive and
angry makes you feel. The animal swells
up with anger and the he he puffs up
there and he goes boom boom boom and he
tries to intimidate. You know,
power is is you get in a flick of an
eyebrow.
I would look at my I would do something.
I'd look at my father, flick of his
eyebrow, and instantly I behave
differently.
He didn't have to beat me, threaten me,
anything, you know.
It's because of where we were, you know,
probably a mutuality on a certain level.
The slightest flick of the eyebrow was
sufficient. And it still is for me. All
a person has to do is say, and I get I
got it right away. I got it.
All right. Here the people become
becomes enslaved. They become addicted.
This is the level of cravingness. This
is wantingness. So up here you were
arrogant. Here you hate everybody.
You're angry at everybody. And 125 is
the level of wantingness.
This comes out of the solar plexus just
as the higher levels come out of the
crown chakra, the third eye, and and we
get to love the heart. Now we're down to
the solar plexus. The solar plexus is
also a level of courage. Courage. You
have to have a lot of guts to get out
there in the world.
But if you get caught in it, too much
energy in the solar plexus, you get into
craving this and wanting this. And the
difficulty with this is you can never
satisfy it. You buy this, it's satisfied
for the moment, but tomorrow you'll want
that. The next day you want that. And
there it's endless. It can lead of
course to the addictions uh drugs and
alcohol, sexual addictions, the
cravingness for power and wealth and u
and worldly goods and things like that.
Or it can be a craving for experience
and novelty
uh chasing sexual partners and
uh wrecking up a score and various
things craving agilation of the public.
Um so the cravingness is difficult
because it's not satisfiable. There's no
end point.
That which is real has an end point.
Uh
you strive for this, you get it. Now
you're satisfied. But here there's no
satisfaction. This is uh you say you
read about these people that have $200
million and then they rip off their
country for another 200. Then they rip
off their business for 300 million and
make everybody all the stock owners
power. You say, "Well, he's got $300
million. Why does he need more?" I don't
know what you do with $300 million. It
would be an enormous nuisance if you ask
me. I mean, baggage, but you say, "Well,
what do they want more and more?" Or you
read a robber. He robs a John Dillinger
used to I think now he just robbed that
bank there last weekend and got 28,000.
Now, Thursday, he's robbing another bank
in another town. So, even as a kid, I'd
think, well, why does Dinger need more
money? He's got He couldn't have spent
it since last Thursday.
But the next Thursday, he's robbing
another bank. And then a week later,
he'd be in another town. I lived in the
Midwest, and we all my mother was always
afraid of John Dillinger. We locked the
doors at night cuz John Dillinger is
loose.
And he was always robbing another bank
and then another store, you know. I
said, "What did he need all that money
for? He's already got this old this old
car and he's got gas in it. I mean, what
does he want with all this? But there's
no end to that. Below that, you start to
handle fear itself. See, we said desire
is craving this. Under that is a fear
and fear runs most of the world most of
the time. Fear everything. The number of
fears to say to conquer fear a fear
um doesn't really solve it because
fearfulness is a state of consciousness
and it will just invent new things to be
afraid of. Afraid of tomorrow, afraid of
yesterday catching up with them.
Uh so fearfulness then is a lack of
faith in God and uh one lives in
constant.
one may uh withdraw and become
despondent. So as we go down we see the
eventuality of depression, despair, the
giving upness of homeless uh
hopelessness.
Out of the pridefulness then underneath
there is anger, the wantingness.
Now the direction that you move is
what's important. It's not where you're
at. It isn't bad that you're here and
good that you're here. maybe
subjectively, experientially is
what's important is what direction
you're moving. The direction that you're
moving.
Um
the great value of television is that
the third world countries that lived in
apathy when television came on in the
poor neighborhoods uh all over the world
uh people that were in apathy saw all
the beautiful things on TV. Gee, how
Americans live and all that. Wow.
Uh,
out of that came desire,
out of apathy. They began to want. Well,
right. To come out of hopeless apathy.
What's hopeless apathy? You don't pick
up the garbage on the streets. You don't
give a damn about anything. You don't
bother getting auto insurance. You get a
ticket. You don't bother going to court.
Apathy is like uh uselessness.
uh it's very hard to handle. Uselessness
leads to more uselessness and it becomes
in a whole subcultures are based in
uselessness. All right? So if you get
that person then out of apathy
uh and up to desire now you can get them
up to anger. Hey now they're angry. all
the have nots ha have it and I don't
have it and uh we'll bomb America and
get even with them because they have it
and we don't have it whatever.
Anyway, uh out of this anger then out of
the anger you get more energy and then
out of the beginning of pridefulness you
have the courage to face the reality of
what it takes. You see what it takes to
get out of apathy and poverty and not
having this to having this. Well, when
people find out what it takes, they
change their story a little bit cuz I
console a lot of those people.
Uh they want to stay in bed in the
morning. I said, "No, you can't in this
world. You have to get up at 6:00 any
morning. Even if it's cold and dark out,
you have to get dressed and you have to
travel to school or to work." Oh, I
ain't going to bother with that.
But you can't have it both ways, folks.
You know, so if you courage is facing
biting the bullet that yes, you do have
to force yourself to get up. That's why
we have alarm clocks. Of course, you'd
rather stay in bed and listen to the
radio, etc. All right. So, this is
biting the bullets. So 200 is a very
critical level and what you get in
return is now
instead of coming out of weakness and
and and
the utilization of force you come into
real power.
Real power now begins to totally change
your life. People react to you
differently, respond to you differently.
Your intentions tend to manifest within
the world.
A friend of mine who's moving upward
rather rapidly spiritually said to me
just the other day. He said, "Gee, I was
holding exactly what I wanted from this
guy in my mind reviewing, I wanted this,
this, this, and the other thing." He
says, "Then I ran into the guy and
instantly he said to me, you know what I
think I want to do for you? I want to do
this, this, this, and this." And he
says, "That's exactly what I was
thinking about fell over."
That's a subjective experience. So what
you hold in mind now tends to manifest.
And there therefore comes the the saying
be careful of what you hold in mind
because it tends to materialize.
Um
because as you move up and become more
powerful, it does it does tend to
materialize.
Down here we near the bottom we have a
starvation at 20 or so. There's barely
enough life energy to pull
to you that which you need to survive.
To be born into this world with a
calibrated level of 25 means you'll
probably be born in Ethiopia Bafra
someplace your parents will probably
have AIDS. You'll probably be dead by
age 6 months of starvation.
20 hasn't got the what it takes to pull
nurturance to it. totally lacks power.
It's why you can't cure poverty with
money because poverty is a reflection of
a level of consciousness. It will always
pull poverty to it. People seek the
bottom of the barrel because most people
who attend these lectures are,
you know, conditioned by a meritocracy
in which we assume moving upward uh and
forward is is what life is all about.
Huh.
So there are people who are born, don't
ask me why, at a consciousness level of
25. There's one place where I go and see
patients. The consciousness level of the
patient population there is 35.
35. Here's the consciousness level of
the population there.
All right. So some people are born to a
low level of consciousness. They they
arrive because of what we will probably
find with discover later on.
Uh
we we have permission to ask this in
front of this audience. Read this.
Because of prior karma. Read this. The
answer we get is prior karma. You can
argue with it. I don't care if you
believe it. Because of prior karma, they
have are arriving at a level of 25 or
30. Huh?
Maybe then in the lifetime as a warrior
where you slaughtered the captives
instead of allowing them and giving them
some kind of freedom.
If you if it was your choice, you could
either let them live or not live
and you let them all die. The
consequence could be that you have
blocked off the light further and
further and further until now you
yourself are
an entity that vibrates
either with or without a physical body
at 35.
That entity that entity vibrates at 35
whether it's in or out of a body is
relatively immaterial.
If it's out of a body, it will
experience the hells
in
other domains. If it man, if it
materializes in this world time, in this
world, it's going to be here.
So spiritual work then is
making choices that move us up towards
the light. So that's all we do in
spiritual work. And the whole use of
this scale, the whole use of what we
learn from it is merely to support the
intention on the part of everyone here
to move forward
uh in consciousness and to fulfill the
human potential.
Being a human being is extremely
difficult. And if you look at the whole
evolution of life on this planet, uh you
see it coming up from
germ plasm on up through uh primitive
life forms. You see the
the energy field is 70 is the energy
field of the era of the dinosaur. The
dinosaur is the rapacious
energy that lives only by the
destruction of others.
The dinosaur only is alive because it
kills you. And if it doesn't catch you,
it'll catch you. So, it lives by the
death of others. Huh?
Later on in evolution, we see that the
dinosaur finally disappeared itself.
Disappeared itself. It brought a meteor
to kill it off or something. I don't
know how it did it, but the dinosaur to
kill itself off. And we saw the
emergence of the herbivore. We saw the
emergence of a whole different line of
evolution. The herbivore does not live
by the killing of anybody or any other
thing or any other entity. In fact, the
herbivores that eat the grass, you know,
it takes the oxygen and it takes the
sunshine, the chlorophyll that the
plants have put together, turns it into
fertilizer, makes more grass,
doesn't kill anybody. It needs to top
off the grass, but the roots still
survives. So, we see the emergence of
that which is benign. That which is
benign does not have to kill for
survival.
As we get above the line, then we see
that
we might say the collective human karma
then began to manifest in the evolution
of higher levels of life.
Now, Chromagn, the Enderthal man, Homo
erectus, finally Homo sapiens.
Homo sapiion wasn't really aware of much
of anything yet. Homo sapien
uh knew more than homo erectus but still
was not a walking genius by any means.
Right? Took hundreds of thousands of
years.
Slow painful evolution.
And then came the emergence of spiritual
awareness. first spiritual awareness was
the was intuitive and began to ascribe
you know events to the stars and the
weather and um then mysterious entities
called gods etc.
And human consciousness then evolved to
the point of greater spiritual
awareness. And in so doing through it
went through primitive forms,
anthropomorphic gods and primitive gods
etc.
It finally reached the state however of
in which God became the the ultimate
symbol of morality, ethics, right and
wrong. became the yard stick for
behavior and guilt emerged. Guilt,
profound guilt.
Um so that being a human being is
extremely difficult
because the evolutionary tree of a human
is via the animal.
We all this same thing here is made of
bone and blood and uh meat.
This thing here is meat on a stick.
Never thought of it that way. People
say, "Do you eat meat or don't meat?" I
said, "Man, you are meat." Every lion
knows that.
Ask a lion what you are. He tell you me,
your dinner, your lunch. As far as he's
concerned,
you're a lion's lunch. So
the human brain then is structured uh
based on the emergence of the animal. So
we see awareness coming up through the
animal kingdom
and becoming more and more complex. That
complexity being the neuronal structures
of the human brain
and the beginning of spiritual awareness
now puts man in the most difficult if
you ask me a position possible. You have
on the one hand animal instincts which
run you whether you like it or not by
the very structure of the brain that you
inherit.
And now you have spiritual awareness. So
the human being is balanced between the
animal and the spiritual.
So you can't just chop up your enemies
with glee anymore. That throws you into
a terrible guilt complex. It's against
the law. It's illegal, etc. So now the
human being lives in a world, however,
of possibility. The animal does not live
in a world of possibility.
The lion sees a rabbit running. There's
no possibility except to eat the eat the
rabbit. What else can he do? He doesn't
he's not going to read the rabbit a
book. You know what I mean?
So the animal side is instinctual. The
animal side is built in. We're wired.
It's wired into the human brain. So
genetically you come onto this planet
without remembering to ask to even do
that.
Nobody asked me did you remember being
asked? Do you want to get born this
time? I don't know. Without being
consulted.
Speaking of politically correct. You
really think we should allow that to
continue.
What are my rights? I wasn't even
consulted about whether I The most
important fact is I exist. And nobody
even asked me about that, much less as a
male or a female or what. Well, color
nothing was asked. So there you are. you
all of a sudden you're here and you've
got this human brain that's uh based on
the animal brain.
The ego is from
a global understanding the evolution of
the animal. The ego from here down is
nothing but the animal. This is all
animal right? Today's Today's headlines
are news reel. You can see on any monkey
island in any zoo. The world is monkey
island.
Gimme gimme kill.
Rape rape rape. Hold her down and have
sex with her. Kill them. That's what you
see on Monkey Island. You know the alpha
male, the alpha female.
jealousy, competition, territoriality,
possessiveness,
greed,
all that runs the human domain um is
not different than the animal world.
So, one way of looking at the ego then
is to have compassion for it as your
little animal.
This is your little ammo. And he gets
mad. He wants and somebody gets ahead of
you in traffic. Oh, that son of a
You know what I mean? Beat on the
window. Pass me. Bye.
Anyway, you got to win fight.
Okay. The human brain is wired that way.
So, what's the point of feeling guilty
about it?
There's no point of feeling guilty about
it. There's no point of grieving about
it. That's just the animal. So the e ego
then is nothing but the animal. It gets
labeled evil, bad, all that. But if you
forget all the labels, it's really just
the animal. If you give up
judgmentalism, you can just accept it
for what it is and say, "Of course it
wants to do that. Of course it wants to
do that."
Anything good happens in my life, I say,
"Okay, let's hear it from the ego."
something good happens, spiritual ego
comes right up and says, "Aren't you
marvelous? Isn't that wonderful?" You
know, you know, it's going to come right
up there. That's what it does.
Otherwise, we wouldn't call it spiritual
ego. Okay, it's doing what it's supposed
to do. Ah, there you go.
How to get out of guilt and fear and
everything about your own ego. It's
nothing but the animal and it's doing
what it's supposed to do. Millions and
millions of years, it learned how to
survive.
It's supposed to do that. Supposed to go
give you the whim whims.
It's supposed to be It's supposed to go.
I want to kill that so huh.
You say, "Okay, I heard it." So that's
what the animal in you is trained and is
supposed to do. If it wasn't successful,
you wouldn't be here today. It's because
you owe your life to the success of your
animal predecessors.
your success as a human being, not your
success with the capitalist
or your fate, depending on how you look
at it. Anyway,
so here you are, a spiritually aware
being stuck with animal instincts.
They're wired. They're in your hardware.
The phamic nuclei, the nuclei at the
base of the brain where the big
emotional lyic system comes out, it's
automatic. It's triggers. I could show
somebody a flash card. Your lyic system
is going to go right off. Electro and
sephilogram shows that flash. You
haven't even had a chance to say hello
about it. Yes or no? Built in.
Not only is the animal bill brain built
in with all these negative emotions
here,
but at the very back of the brain, you
have the rh the the old the old dinosaur
brain. The reptilian brain is still at
the back of the brain. Right? Anybody
knows anything about anatomy, you know
at the back of the brain is what is it?
The rhin and sephylon or some horrible
name.
Something you don't want to meet in the
dark at night. I think it's a rhy and
sephflon. Sounds scary. Whatever.
Anyway, the old primitive reptilian
brain is still at the back of your head.
Every evolution of the animal chain as
it evolved is represented in some
nucleus in your hypothalammus or your
figalatorus. Take that.
This is in your figalatorus right here.
And when it wiggles I just get that
feeling. I don't know. Every time I look
at a doctor, I just shake all over.
It sets off her figtor into a scare
thing. Huh? Because her head says enemy.
Uh-oh. Enemy prey predator response.
Prey predator response.
So these levels of consciousness then
now what happens is consciousness begins
to evolve. Consciousness begins to
evolve. We see the beginning of
intelligence.
I want I love that wonderful gray
parrot. It's University of South Arizona
of Arizona there. What's that parrot's
name? I forget. Anyway, this parrot
talks and um thinks and can pick out
colors, choices, numbers. She'll say to
him, "Get green cube." Oh, he goes over
and gets the green cube. Put down green
cube. Oh, get four red round. Oh, four
red round. Your parrot knows how to
think already. And of course, you all
know Koko, the gorilla who has quite a
big vocabulary of 800 words or something
like that and knows sign language. So we
see the emergence then of thinkingness
the capa capacity so we're talking about
now is the emergence of the forebrain
the forebrain
the capacity to think present even in
birds present and becomes more and more
complex
that gives you more ways to suffer now
than you'd ever thought of before
with a poor brain man you can feel
guilty about everything from instant to
instant why' I say that why I do this
why did I wear this Oh golly, why didn't
I bring my hat? How come I forgot to
guess? Gez, did I Oh. All right. So now
the capacity for suffering increases
enormously. On the other hand, the
capacity for satisfaction does. So we
come out of the animal world. Then what
what I'm trying to do is recontextualize
the ego. The ego is not a bad it's not a
awful. It'll it'll take you to to
terrible places if you let it if you let
it run you. It'll take you to terrible
places.
But it gets scary labels put on it in
the spiritual and religious worlds. It
gets scary words. Sin and evil and oh my
god. Uh now you lay awake at night, you
know, worrying about all that stuff.
The animal naturally wants to be right.
The animal naturally wants to win. The
animal doesn't care about other animals.
It would just assume kill it and uh take
over its prey, take over its mate, take
over its territory. So you know what
Fred called the id, what is in the id is
the animal. So
based on a profound spiritual premise,
let go resisting things. You let go
resisting it. Instead of suppressing it
and repressing it or denying it, what
mankind does is repress all this, deny
it because of guilt and project it into
the world, he doesn't eliminate it. He
just moved it out there. Well, it's much
nicer to feel that they're the bad guy
and that you're not the bad guy. They're
the ones. So, naturally, the Americans
because they're successful made Ben
allowed do what he did. And there's all
kinds of
leftist calmness. No sooner that it
happened then again instantly got on TV
and started blaming America for having
being responsible for bin Laden doing
what he did. You know by virtue of the
fact you save your money, work hard and
get out of the bed in the morning
instead of laying in bed and have
learned how to use the wheel and count.
Now you should get killed. See? So
I've been in parts of the world where
the wheel hasn't really been used. I was
up in the top of the Andes and they're
still dragging things around with
sticks. So help me God. That was in the
70s. Like they hadn't heard of the wheel
yet. Everybody's going alongside the
road pulling two sticks. Not even the
wheel. Not even the wheel. The 1970s.
Okay. So
we have this spiritual dilemma then of
the animal instincts coming out of
evolution can't be avoided.
So that's our karma. We have the karma
of the animal kingdom. Right? If you
didn't have the karma of an animal
kingdom, we'd all be in spirit. We
wouldn't be sitting on our butts and
chairs.
We'd be floating around the room, which
I really like myself.
I
I've never been an enthusiast of the
human body. As a kid, other kids seem to
be very enthused about it. They like to
rustle and do all kinds of disgusting
things.
get their dirty, grimy fingers they've
been picking their nose with and stick
it in your eye in a wrestling match. No,
thank you. Disgusting. No thanks.
>> What?
>> I never liked locker rooms. And u
anyway, the physicality of being an
animal was never my greatest thing. And
u while the other kids were playing hoop
ball, I was reading the great books of
the western world. Plato, arguing with
Plato and Venzic.
So
that's how people enter the world. They
enter at a certain thing. It comes out
of their past experience, their past
life, their past decisions.
And apparently there's a decision now to
transcend
uh the physicality and the the
compulsion of the animal. So what we in
spiritual work try to do is overcome the
compulsiveness of the ego of the animal
reflex to not automatically respond with
guilt, automatically respond with fear.
Uh and we be as so as we go up we become
more and more free. Somewhere up here is
the word freedom and u I've lost it.
Well, as you beginning letting go of
things, you come out of this level and
you begin to reach a level called
neutrality. I'm starting out this
morning on the lower levels and we'll
move up. The day will get better as we
go along.
I wanted to handle today's headlines.
Oh, some of the headlines this week were
just I say, "Oh, wow." But I I really
can't even repeat them to somebody else.
Um, so that's the animal mess. So we can
stop feeling guilty about animal
impulses. We can forgive them. I think
everybody should give their body a
nickname and and adopt it as a pet. I
have adopted this as a pet.
And you see how friendly it is. It does
what I want it to do.
It expresses I mean it's just a
marvelous thing. Uh it does all kinds of
wondrous things. Uh so the best thing to
do is to make a friend with it and get
to know it for what it is. It wants to
win. It wants to survive.
It uh has all these animal needs and we
can stop feeling guilty about it. If you
don't feel guilty about it, you don't
have to deny it. If you don't deny it, I
mean, what kind of an animal are you
anyway? Don't you want to win? What are
you stupid? What? Of course you want to
win. And
if somebody passes you on the highway,
don't you want to drive them off the
highway and watch them turn over? Of
course you do. It's fun. There take that
you. Uh, okay. So, you cheer your animal
on. You become its champion. You see
what's happened now? You've adopted it.
It doesn't have power over you. You see,
by owning it, you don't have to deny it.
When you don't deny it, you don't have
to guilt. When you accept it for what it
is, you don't have to project it into
the world. So you don't see all that
evil in the world anymore because you
stop projecting it. It's because you
felt guilty about various things. You
project it into the world. You think
they're after you. They're out to get.
No, that's your projection onto the
world. See, the world then becomes a
movie in which you see that which you
project.
The more you own the downside, the less
you project. And now instead of seeing
the world as tragic like my grandmother
and crying all morning every time she
read the paper, you see it as an
absurdity. Huh?
It's an absurdity. So now when you as
you move up, it becomes
tragic but also absurd. Not to really be
taken seriously. Why? Because each
player on the field is where they are as
a result of their own decision to be
there. It's by one's own choices.
We heard the fellow who blew up the
world, it wasn't the World Trade Center,
who was the fellow that blew up the
Oklahoma building.
>> All right. So any what whatever his name
was, he made that choice consciously. He
deliberated, made careful plans, and as
he went to the gas chamber, he said he
presumed he was going to hell.
And then he hopefully said, "But you'll
meet a lot of nice pe, you know, meet
all your friends there." So that
and nobody forced him to do it, did
they? So every everyone here is here
because we've all made choices.
And I want everybody to become friendly
with their ego to um accept their id,
give it a a name, become its owner, put
it on a leash, and
that's the uh wisdom of the famous Zen
ox hurting pictures, is it not? In the
beginning, the ox is wild and
untameable.
And then with spiritual evolution, you
see the person riding the ox. And then
we'll get to the next pictures after a
break, shall we? So, we should take a
break.
>> Do you know what she's saying? You got
to tell.
>> Yeah. When you test kinesi,
>> do do you do you ask for some sort of
permission?
>> Yes.
>> Could you
>> We haven't mentioned the technique this
morning. The technique is very very
simple. Um it takes um about 20 seconds
to learn this technique.
Uh we have permission to ask this
question in front of the audience.
Resist.
There are multiple there are multiple
heavens. Resist.
Isn't that interesting?
Let's ask another fun question. Uh the
time of your death is already set at the
time of your birth. Resist there. That's
you don't have to worry about death
anymore
and you don't have to worry about
heaven. Aren't you glad you came to
today's lecture?
All right. The moment you're gonna leave
is already preset. So, there's no point
in worrying about death and, you know,
worrying whether every bite of a lasagna
is going to kill you or not. Because if
you're destined to go at 82, whatever
you eat is whatever you eat. You know
what I mean?
On the other hand, you might be in lousy
health when you die instead of good
health.
Croak over in the pink. You know, I like
to croak over in the pink. You know what
I mean?
>> Also,
if your death is already planned, does
that mean
I had a neighbor and fail?
>> Well, there there's a matter of choice
there. There's a matter of choice.
No, I don't think suicides doesn't know
because that would be violate the
freedom of the will of God. Uh no, you
would have the the choice of life versus
death. Um
at that point you have the choice of
life or death or surrendering to God.
So the point of suicide
is a critical spiritual opportunity.
At that point one can completely
surrender the totality of all you think
you are and what is going
You have the you can surrender all of it
to God. You can either commit suicide or
suddenly go into a really high state.
You can transcend right from the doors
of hell. And heaven and hell are a tenth
of an inch apart. And having been there,
I can attest to the truth of that
statement. From the very depths of hell,
which are worse than anyone can imagine.
really
>> um there was the total surrendering
and then
emergence into a totally different
paradigm.
Yes.
>> Have you asked me to remind me about
calibrating the conscious of the
>> Oh yes, the audience. We've got the
audience.
>> I always forget the audience is here. I
don't know why
we have permission to ask this. We
always ask permission. Do we have
permission? The permission also depends
on context. Sometimes you'll get a yes
because of the of in other words I may
get a yes. I may get a no in front of
the audience but I may can I ask this at
home it'll say yes. Why? Because there
may be people in the audience it would
be too upsetting to and it's not
advisable to create scandal. Huh?
Um this audience is over let me guess.
It's just over 4:30. 432 433 434 435 Oh,
before we started, this audience was
over 433 434 435 436.
Before we started to speak this morning,
this audience is over 435. 436.
This audience is now over 436. 437. 430.
Oh my god.
we'll do at the beginning and the end.
All right. Um I'm glad I was reminded of
that. To merely hear certain information
already has a transformative effect that
just the hearingness of the information.
Just to know you don't have to fight
your ego, blame it, feel guilt about it,
go to hell because of it. You can adopt
it as a pet and train it. You know, it's
fun. And of course it gets and we said
you should champion all its animal
instincts and say, "Hey, good for you.
You did just what you're supposed to
do." And instantly you're off the guilt.
You understand what I'm saying? Uh
you're on top of it instead of
underneath it.
I wanted to finish up the levels of
consciousness this morning. We've got
some fun graphs I want to show you this
afternoon. And uh anyway
these levels of consciousness then are
really the evolution of consciousness
towards the light. It would be like that
is an innate quality of consciousness
itself. On the other hand consciousness
is in no hurry. It can take eons
eons.
This consciousness
we have permission to ask about it uh
has existed for eons
before all time even started I am was
have been
so that which you are has already been
around for eons you understand and out
of all those eons this is where it's it
has arrived at at this moment and we can
then calibrate that and even reflect
that on this scale of consciousness we
have a pointer now
as I was saying if you hold it in mind
it'll appear
I just realized that that is funny isn't
it okay
we we were going to show you know so
that you understand the human condition
We said that society reflects this map
of consciousness.
Where is society? I was going to do this
this afternoon, but we'll do it this
morning so you won't
be frustrated while I eat lunch here.
If we calibrate the level of
consciousness of all of humanity,
here's where it is. Um 78% is below 200.
Huh. So,
here's another scale. Maybe easier to
see. Huh. That one's a little too dark.
This one's lighter. Yeah. There we go.
Uh,
a friend of mine did this. Lou Fornier
who's been who attends the lectures and
today can't be here. Anyway, he does
these on his uh while we were giving the
lecture last time or the time before he
was sitting there with a computer and by
the time we finished the lecture, he had
this set up to go.
And uh so that's the distribution.
Consequently,
what do you think today's newspaper is
going to be about? Huh? So it's going to
be because the newspapers are generally
around 385.
Uh this is CBS News, NBC, and the news
broadcasts are around in the upper 300s.
Uh
what's his name? Rally the factor. He's
around the Fox News is about is up
around here.
uh CNN is is up around here anyway. So
the way this world looks to this level
of consciousness is going to be the
today's news.
However, the news also focuses a great
deal on the 400s and we'll be talking
about the 400s later this morning.
That's the percentage. That's how the
world distri world population is
distributed.
And
here's my latest masterpiece.
I did the crude originals and L did the
refinement. And this is sort of how the
world is distributed. Um
84% of the population transcends 10
that you know that leaves 16% to die,
right? 16% is in the process of death
itself or very close to death.
Uh
the United States of America calibrates
around 400 and in the 400s. The modern
European western civilized world
calibrates in the 400s. This is the
world of civilization
as we know it. Civilization as we know
it, how it has evolved until this point
in time. All right. So that was just to
give you an idea of the distribution.
The majority of mankind when you see
how how that's distributed then you see
that the majority of mankind has not
reached the level of integrity has not
reached this level here. The majority of
mankind is in the lower part of the box
which gives you a certain degree of
compassion for it. In other words,
people can't help being other than how
they are. You understand that?
Whether someone is a perpetrator or a
victim is all a point of view.
Is bin Laden a perpetrator?
No. He's the victim of ignorance.
Is he someone to hate or someone to feel
sorry for?
To be so ignorant about the nature of
God and reality,
to be so un unevolved,
to be less than an animal,
you know, even the wolfpack cares for
its mates.
So
is he someone to be hated or
so he might say that people in the lower
part of the box are the victims of their
own ignorance. That's what Jesus said
when he said forgive them for they know
not what they do. Their level of
consciousness isn't high enough for them
to even see that they got a choice to be
other than they are.
So one of the consequences
of karma is the range of choice. People
at the bottom of the box don't have the
choice to be other than what they are.
Spiritual evolution has been one earned.
to have a choice that you have a
spiritual option is a choice
for
you see how few are the options of a
person at the bottom of the box
uh if you're born
on certain streets in certain big cities
you either become a member of the gang
or you die right
I always get a kick out of treatment
centers we take them out of the gangs we
treat them this we treat from all this
and you send it back. How are they going
to survive?
You want to behave like middle class
Protestant America ideal
on the streets of the inner city?
>> Yeah, good luck.
If you want to survive, you have to
transcend it. Why? Because then you have
choices. You don't have any choices when
you live on a certain block. either join
the gang that runs that block
or you get eliminated.
They don't have the choices
to see that. Then you see that each
person is
to some degree the victim of where they
are in the evolution of consciousness.
To some degree, if you like victimology,
victimology is a very big subject in
today's society. Everybody, there's a
great deal of competition to be victim.
Everybody's trying to get into the
camera.
So So
>> all right. So we said that over here
these this the lower levels are power.
Power is a substitute for I mean level
lower levels are force and that for
force is a substitute for power.
Those who have power don't need force
because they influence everything within
their domain by virtue of what they are
by virtue of what one has become. So the
greatest service we can give to all of
humanity is to become all all that we
can become to the best of our ability.
And that energy radiates out and lifts
the level of consciousness of all of
mankind.
We should have a little line in here.
Mankind was at 190. 190. That's
pridefulness, arrogance, and of course
denial.
Uh
that's the uh rule of uh righteousness.
Righteousness scares me
because righteousness is the
justification for every major
devastation we've ever seen in society.
When people talk about the righteous,
give me a break.
It is out of righteousness that all the
horrors of mankind arise.
So mankind's history, if you watch the
History Channel, the International
History Channel, is a fascinating
channel to watch because you see the
evolution of consciousness as it
expresses itself in the interactions of
society and different cultures
throughout all of time. It's really when
I was a kid, I hated history because it
seemed like a dead subject. But now it's
my favorite subject because you see the
dance of the ego as it expresses itself
in human interaction.
And you can calibrate the levels of the
playing fields involved in the Napoleon
and all the great Henry VII. When you
calibrate all the levels of the monarchs
throughout history and great great many
other world leaders, you see why the
world is the way it was. Huh?
It's only become by becoming conscious
that a person can avoid being swayed by
the demagogues who temp who routinely
sway society. Huh?
So down here we have force and force is
a substitute for power.
As one's integrity begins to you see
one's over here we have the view of our
of our self over here everybody's
miserable they're not deserving to live
they should kill themselves because
they're evil
the lady who's on TV right now killing
five children is probably down here in
the very bottom sees herself as evil etc
etc and sea herself is hopeless and
tragic and all these things all right so
this The view of the self miserable,
undeserving of life, evil,
tragic,
frightening, disappointing, weak. Now,
as we get up towards anger, one get
one's self view becomes belligerent.
Belligerent. So, the kids we get off the
street at the treatment center are
belligerent. They're all into what is
that called? Dissing each other.
You don't flag their colors or something
as you go by. You've been dissed and now
that justifies stabbing them or
something, burning down their clubhouse.
They live in a strange world. See, with
its own rules. All right. So, the
viewpoint of of God then is a reflection
of one's level of consciousness. And
this culturally as it expressed over the
centuries has had a profound impact on
society. profound impact.
These are all levels of ego mania in a
way. These are all levels of
egoentricity.
Egoentricity
at the bottom at the bottom of the box.
God despises you. God hates you. He
throws you into hell because you are
worthless, sinful worm.
Because you're evil. You see, God is
vindictive. This is the God of the Old
Testament. The God This is the God of
the Old Testament. So these are the
negative depictions of God. They come
out of, as Freud said, out of the
unconscious, out of the id. All that you
hate and despise about yourself, you
project onto a deity. And the God of the
Old Testament, many other cultures are
are really demonic. So these are the
demonic depictions of God. God despises
you. He's vindictive. He wants to tor
He's also sadistic. He likes to be cruel
and throw you into hell for endless
torture.
He disdains you. He has nothing to do
with you. He condemns you. He's
punitive. God gets even with you. God
the Old Testament was prone to jealousy
and vanity and he would get pissed and
and blow you away.
Punitive God. So this is the God of
judgment day that everybody's scared of.
Let's settle judgment day. We took care
of death and and heaven and all. Let's
do judgment day. We have permission to
ask about judgment day. Resist. Judgment
day is today. Resist. Thank you.
Judgment day is today. Judgment day for
the this this person here is now. Today
for the persons in the audience is
today. Resist. Every day is judgment day
because every day you make a decision
that moves you as an iron filing in the
electromagnetic field of God.
To be here today has already changed
your karma instantly. Right? You're a
different iron failing than you were
yesterday.
Every day is judgment day. If you die
right now, you're going to go wherever
you are right this instant. Right? Next
week, God's not going to change.
All right? So, this God is punitive. The
angry god. This god denies you. The
person is always wanting something.
These are the prayer. Dear God, please
give me a new Cadillac. Right.
A new Mercedes Benz. What's that song
by?
>> Mercedes-Benz.
Okay. So, this is where kids get
disillusioned with religion and God. You
know, I remember running to catch the
bus and I would live down the country
and it was a mile to the nearest bus and
I had a violin lesson in town and I'm
running down this I got out of school 5
minutes late and the freaking bus leaves
in 20 minutes and I got exactly one mile
to go and I'm running with my violin and
I'm praying up a storm. I mean, I was
really cuz I mean if you missed your
violin lesson and missed the bus, God
help you.
And uh and just as I got close to the
bus, it drove away. Well, h that's what
we all have to face sooner or later in
childhood, isn't it?
I got I pray that I passed the test and
you got a D minus. Oh,
okay.
So, here God's angry. He's he's mad at
people. God seems to hate people. I
mean, if God's the creator of man and
woman, you know, why would he hate you?
Or anyway, he created us as not having
the ability to tell truth from
falsehood.
Life would have been different if Eve
had known kinesiology.
She had never attended one of these
lectures. So
she gave into curiosity. Curiosity.
Curiosity.
Okay. Out of that curiosity then she
went from the oneness. The garden of
Eden is the peace and stillness of
oneness. And she bought into duality.
She bought into perception and out of
duality you get conflict, good and evil,
heaven and hell and all the rest. So she
bit into
what the 400s does best and
this from that. So from
an enlightened state of innocent
simplicity
in which there is no conflict
there was the buying into the world of
perception and there was born duality
and thus the fate of man is
allegorically at least described.
All right. So these gods are then very
angry gods and of course not only
vengeful but
uh here's a god that's indifferent. Here
I am running for my violin lesson and
what the hell am I? Nobody in the world.
So this is your view of yourself as a
worm. You
pray of a storm and nothing happens.
This is the disillusionment of childhood
with religion. They prayed and prayed
for something and it never happened. and
so and so died anyway. Yeah.
>> All right. Now, we get to to courage or
our view of God begins to change, huh?
It uh God is perhaps a possibility and
of a different nature now because now
200 is a level of empowerment.
200 is
you remember estart
airhard seminars training the purpose of
est was to get you off
projecting blame and to own to become
empowered by owning
that it wasn't the traffic that made you
late
and you if you were late to an S meeting
you had to sit outside the door and the
trainer would ask you why you were late.
You'd say, "Well, the I missed the bus."
You have to stand there and wait. Wait
some more.
And the elevator was slow. Uh-huh. And
the alarm didn't go off. Uh-huh.
And finally, you say, "Well, I chose to
be late. You may come in now." You had
to own your yourself that some aspect
you decided that. See,
some aspect. You didn't set two alarms.
You didn't set a backup to make sure,
etc. Okay. So the reason Warner did that
is because he tried to get you over the
level of 200. So the a su if you did s
you were successful if you now had the
courage to own your own decisions and
take responsibility
down here. The blame is put out there.
These kids that I treat the girls ranch
they never did anything wrong. The other
one always made them do it.
Many famous murders.
Famous murders. Ones that preoccupied
the public for a long time. The reason
that perpetrator never appears to be
guilty is because she deserved it. She
made me do it.
She made me do it. What's there to feel
guilty about? Huh? To not own. So that
person calibrates them below 200.
The difficulty with getting the kids in
the girls ranch to to improve is you
can't get them to own that they're the
author of their own decisions.
So here the blame is put out there. It's
the other guy's fault.
All right? So you affirm then at 200 k
of courage.
When you get up to 250 is is neutrality.
250 is you've become re released from
attachments. There's a method known as
releasing which I think is a very
excellent method. Uh letting go, wanting
to change things, control things, become
detached from things. So you you stop
controlling everything and stop worrying
with people.
If you are a good releaser, you
certainly end up at least at 250, which
is neutral. And neutral is very
comfortable.
people uh at neutral here. If you don't
get the job, you kill yourself or you
kill the other guy or you blame
yourself. You go into depression and
stop eating and take an overdose.
Up here
in neutral, it's okay if it goes that
way and it's okay if it doesn't. You
don't have you're not riding on what
happens out there. You're not living on
the projections of the ego.
You're neutral. If you get the job, it's
okay. And if you don't, there's a lot of
other ones. Anybody tells me there's
unemployment doesn't know what they're
talking about. I can open the
unemployment page, the employment pages,
jobs wanted, you know, help wanted pages
of any newspaper in the United States
and find three or four pages of jobs. I
can walk down any street in America. It
says help wanted anywhere. Do it in
Sedona. Says help wanted on every single
block.
It's not out there. Unemployment is not
out there. Unemployment is in your head.
Right after World War II, all the vets
came back. We all got 5220. I only got
5220, but I also had three jobs at the
same time,
right? Survival.
All right. So, the willingness then
neutral is okay. As we get up to
willingness, we have a whole different
inspiration. We become God is inspiring.
Things look hopeful. People in
willingness are fun to be with. People
in willingness are cheerful, optimistic,
they help.
If one or two people are trying to lift
a sofa, a person in willingness comes
over and says, "Can I help?" They just
automatically do that. They do that
because of that's who they are. Cuz when
you moving moving up to
lovingness, then you're becoming an
asset on the planet. These people are a
detriment on the planet. You know, they
make cannon fodder. They use they're
useful that way. Cannon fodder.
But they're not really an asset. In
fact, the 78 below percent below
uh that level there are really supported
by these at the top. These are the
people at the top that allow to keep
these people alive. If it wasn't for the
people at the top, they wouldn't have
sidewalks to walk on. You know what I
mean? You wouldn't have a car to get
into.
You wouldn't have the steel to make the
car. It's the people up here that
provide the jobs, that provide the
income, that provide the taxes, that
provide the services of which these
people live because they don't pay any
these people don't pay any taxes.
So these people are powerfully
productive. Powerfully productive. So
the sales manager just gets the team
together. He gives them a pep talk. They
all feel fantastic when they walk out.
It's because he's probably at least
around 350 or so. He's up there in the
positive. These are the go-getters of
the world. Go-Getters of the world. Then
what gives them their power is
intention. Intention. So what Wernernner
taught in s if it's your intention
absolutely to get to that lecture at
1:00 you will be there. And failure to
be there 1:00 is a defect of intention.
So we're not always made you responsible
for your intention. It means your
intention is out. Your integrity is out.
If your intention is there, intention
overcomes all kinds of obstacles. And a
fierce determined intention can overcome
almost anything in this world.
Fierce intention
is what you discover in sports when you
reach or in exercise or in labor. When
you reach the point beyond which you
cannot go,
you white knuckle it, clench your teeth,
and by your intention, you drive through
the barrier.
It's an incredible experience to do it.
Many people have had it in sports,
running, and various various ways. I
discovered it in a warehouse when I
could not lift one more box of canned
goods in Theville, Wisconsin.
110° in a pee canery and 110° in this
warehouse with no windows and I could
not lift one more box. Not one more.
And uh I was never a heavyweight to
begin with. And anyway uh after maybe 12
or 14 hours in this heat, no water and
no well I said I can't do it. And then
something came up and there was this
incredible decision to go through the
barrier and I crashed through the
barrier and all of a sudden the boxes
became weightless. I lifted them like
feathers. I could keep I could have kept
going for days and I've done that many
times on lifting stone and all. Once you
discover what's beyond that barrier, the
the runner discovers that pushes itself
to the limit and will not accept the
limit and by intention drives through
it. And suddenly the runningness half
happens of its own. The runningness
happens of its own
to some degree. This is also exactly the
same as it is with spiritual work. When
you get to a certain point, you cannot
go any further
and suddenly you're out in the free and
everything happens spontaneously.
All right. So willingness then
willingness is also the open door to
success. Willingness is powerful because
the person here owns that it's their
intention. Owns takes responsibility.
They're optimistic. They're willing.
World is hopeful. And God now becomes an
inspiration. Inspiration.
acceptance is even higher than that
because acceptance now
uh there's a willingness to forgive
uh on a spiritual level uh acceptance is
a harmonious and more merciful way when
we were talking this morning instead of
condemning your ego as as being the evil
in you and all the rest the devil and
Satan and giving it all kinds of hor
horrific names
if we're accepting then we accept it we
forgive the ego for being what it is I
mean it grew up as an animal. What do
you think it's going to do?
Algebra. You know the animal you got to
do algebra.
All right. So we transcend positionality
through forgiveness and acceptance. We
come into a merciful
merciful state of mind. If you're
merciful towards your animal then then
you're merciful towards other people's
animal. Huh? So when somebody passes you
on the highway, you say, "Good luck. I
don't care if he gets in front of me."
You know what I mean? We're all going to
arrive at the same place, same time
anyway, which is the next stop and go
live. We're all going to be sitting
there at the red. So let him get a car.
It makes a difference.