So what we haven't mentioned so far, we said,
truth only comes, meaning only comes out of context.
And one context that we haven't spoken about this morning, of course, is karma.
That you have both discernible context, undiscernible context,
and non-identifiable context called karma.
That's why much scientific experimentation doesn't make sense.
And so they come up with contradictory results because they don't define the context.
The reason computers can never create an artificial intelligence,
it can only do logic trees, logic trees in human intelligence.
Human intelligence is a subjective evaluation
of an infinite number of millions of data of information
which it intuitively wins its way through without actually processing.
The reason you can't...
You can't do a computer replica of human consciousness
is for one thing, the major portion of the context is missing.
It can only program content.
One piece of context that is not available to put on the computer
because it's unknown, is karma.
No matter what you say.
And that which is in the unconscious.
So all you could put on the computer would be that which is reasonably logically recallable.
It totally, you cannot put what's in the unconscious
because by definition it's unconscious.
If it's unconscious, it is not available data.
You can't put that in the computer.
Context is non-linear.
Computers only deal with the linear.
Therefore, meaning, significance, value,
you can't put Mother's Day on a computer
because the reverence,
how do you put reverence into a computer?
Logic series, you can't.
Why?
Because it's a feeling state, it's a way of being with,
it's a way of being with the totality of that which you are
and the totality of the feminine.
The way this consciousness is with the feminine
evolved over eons.
Evolved over eons.
It's reverence for the feminine is eons old.
All right.
That cannot be put into a computer.
So it's context that gives the thing meaning and value,
significance.
Our spiritual work then derives its power,
derives its power.
We said you can go to metaphysical lectures
for 35 years and never change one iota.
It's because the person has denied the power within them.
There's the power to transform the world,
the world of the word,
into the world of the word.
Into the subjective experiential world of spiritual truth.
The power is within you.
Where does the power come from?
The power comes from willingness.
Willingness about what?
There was the willingness to accept that women were to be revered.
My grandparents said that, my father said it.
There was no resistance to that, no resistance.
The truth instantly at home.
Hmm.
There was no trust.
There was trust in the words.
There was trust in the sincerity with which they were said.
There was trust in the integrity of the speaker.
All right.
So out of love for the source of the information,
all resistance was relinquished.
And that was accepted as truth and incorporated within for a lifetime.
Same thing should then ideally happen with spiritual work.
The power of truth.
The power of self.
The consciousness of the teacher.
The educator should be sufficient that one's trust in it is profound like it was in my
grandfather.
Then the resistance dissolves itself.
If I tell you that the feminine is infinitely divine, worshipful as the expression of God
in that expression, you know that's the truth, is it not?
Is that the truth?
Hmm.
You reverence that within yourself.
The feminine within yourself you reverence as the expression of God, as it expresses
itself in the feminine.
As it comes out of form, the divine begins to take on attributes which we eventually
recognize as form.
The difference between male and female, divinity has already come into form as male and female,
because tomorrow is Mother's Day.
I'm concentrating on the feminine, the magnificence and the beauty of divinity as expressed as
the feminine.
So our acceptance of that doesn't depend on its being accepted by other people.
It makes no difference to me how other people hold women within their psyche.
It's their problem.
You see?
There's no problem.
There's no conflict and no problem with the way it is within.
Huh?
As close to its being, as close to its divine nature as possible.
So what did the grandparents do?
My uncle, my, all the men in the family held women who reverenced it.
Why was it so powerful?
It was because they were holding it as close to its divine origination as possible.
They were holding it as a condition.
Not as your uncle, I mean, not as your aunt or your grandmother or your mother, as personages,
but they were holding it as a powerful field of realization.
And I got it.
I got it.
I got what it was.
The divinity innate within the feminine, that's what I got.
That's why it is worthy of reverence.
Hmm?
So our resistance to incorporating truth and resistance,
to incorporating truth and instantly recognizing it then,
the resistance to it can be bypassed by faith, love, the trust and openness,
and the divinity that we intuit as the field out of which the information is coming.
It is out of infinite love that that is forthcoming from consciousness,
consciousness into the awareness of the listener.
It doesn't take 35 years of attending lectures.
It takes one instant of trust.
One instant of trust.
One reason we use kinesiology is to clear the obstacles to trust.
Huh?
If I tell you that the expression of motherhood,
and this calibrates at 540,
and the way women are held by political positions,
and the way women are held within the urbic world,
if we calibrate those levels,
that sort of removes the doubtfulness,
the doubtingness of the intellect.
The intellect is the great doubter,
and the great blocker to truth.
So we try to also handle the ego at the same time.
So all that I've ever spoken of became an absolute reality in one instant,
35 years ago or whatever it was.
Somewhere in the long distant past.
All that I'm saying today became an instant reality, wordlessly.
That's what speaks right now.
What speaks right now searches for how to express that
so as to bypass the resistance of the intellect, the mind, and the ego.
And you see, as I saw as a boy,
the incredible,
magnificent sense of the divinity of woman.
One instant, my grandfather said,
you'll never speak to your grandmother that way.
I got how she was held.
So it takes one instant to get what you're looking for.
Not 35 years.
It only takes one instant.
In one instant, the ego lets go its resistance
out of faith, confidence, and trust.
That's what it does.
When my father said that to me,
I knew it was not a lie.
I knew it was truth.
So all resistance stopped.
And that became incorporated into the truth of my own reality.
The truth of my own reality.
So I'm going to use personal experience to demonstrate a certain principle.
The last thing I want to happen is people come to these lectures
and then tell me nothing has changed and nothing's happened.
I'll kill myself.
In a dead body, I killed them.
I said, I went to all these lectures and nothing changed.
I will.
I'm going to die and it's going to be on your head.
You made me do it.
That's the you made me do it game, right?
Ah, yes.
Uh-huh.
So you might say,
in a certain context then,
that I belong to you.
Everything I'm saying today belongs to you.
Is that so?
Yeah.
Everybody here totally owns what's being said.
Everybody here totally owns the speaker.
So what is the speaker then?
The speaker is what?
Spiritual educator.
There you go.
How's that for a term?
Is that a good term?
You like that?
Okay.
Spiritual educator.
In other words,
we share with you the truth that
it was subjectively experienced
and as it is present within.
Huh?
But that's not comprehensible.
So we go back to what it is that
keeps it from being comprehensible.
We try to explain it in terms that are
understandable to the scientifically trained mind.
We have to pay attention.
Jesus wasn't dealing with scientifically trained people.
You know what I'm saying?
They couldn't read or write for God's sake.
He had a snap of a job.
They hadn't read all the books.
There weren't any books on the whole thing.
You know what I'm saying?
No.
Things have evolved in the last couple thousand years.
And the listener, the student of today,
is somewhat different.
Considerably different.
Far more sophisticated.
In the 400s.
Those people there that Jesus dealt with
were probably in the 200s.
Right?
Huh?
Yeah.
Can we ask that?
We have permission to ask that.
That became followers were below 200
to start with.
Yeah.
So it was the power of the truth coming through
that transformed the people
and the people instantly saw
the truth that he revealed.
That was his authority
out of which they became enlightened.
The saints were all became enlightened.
As a result of the capacity
to drop all resistance
and just respond to that truth.
Just as I did with my grandparents
and my father
about who women really were.
And I got in an instant
who they really were.
Didn't need to read any books on the subject.
Just got it right off the bat.
One instant I got who women were.
And in the lectures all we want
is in one instant
we get who we really are.
All of us here are a gift to the world.
Let's see if we're a gift to the world.
Is a gift to the world.
Wow.
Okay.
So our being here at this moment,
all of us who are here at this moment
are collectively a gift to the world.
The world calibrates at 207.
This group calibrates at 430
as they walked in the door.
That's already a gift to the world
of just who we are.
Who you are is a gift to the world.
Different way to hold yourself.
When you walk through Walmarts
and you smile at somebody,
they get it as a gift to them.
You notice how they light up?
You ever walk through Walmarts and smile at people?
Everybody lights up all the way down the aisle.
Just try it.
I mean you probably never noticed it.
She's pushing this and you're pushing that.
You look over and smile at her.
It knocks them out.
She's so happy that somebody smiles at her
and recognizes her
that she just beams right back to you.
It's like instant love all the time.
I used to do that in the streets of New York City.
The streets of New York City are like Walmarts.
I lived in New York City.
I would just walk down the street
and just love everybody as they came along.
People just beamed.
You can stop anybody on the street of New York
and start talking about anything.
What the hell do you think about me or so and so?
They'll instantly give you a talk.
It's like you've known each other for 30 years.
There's no barrier there.
I love the streets of the city of New York.
You can stop anybody.
Everybody's a character.
It's terrific.
The dialect, the whole style,
what it means to be a New Yorker,
the certain implicit understanding
of the rights and wrongs.
Under certain circumstances, stealing is not really stealing.
He left it out.
Oh, well, if he left it out, that's different.
Totally different.
Change of context.
He left it laying there.
Well, okay, he left it laying there.
Even a judge wouldn't convict you, probably.
He left it laying there.
A whole different context of ethics and morality.
So what is acceptable there
is not acceptable here.
The context of New York City
is different than the context of elsewhere.
You understand that?
The context makes it different.
The context makes its meaning
and its significance become different.
So context defines meaning and significance.
To do the same thing here
that would be nothing at all in New York
would be ethically a different animal.
A different animal altogether.
He just can't take his change
and not feel guilty about it.
Well, he left all his change on the bar.
You know what I'm saying?
He went to the bathroom.
What do you expect?
It's going to be there when you get back.
What is the great block?
What is the great block to keep it from sinking in?
I don't know.
Have you got any idea?
We tried to approach it from the viewpoint
that the ego as a totality
will not tolerate
any infringement of its boundaries
because it realizes that it's a threat to its totality.
It's an interlocking system
and to let in love
means that the end is inevitable.
Let's see if that's so.
To allow in love
means to the ego ultimate dissolution.
Aha!
Above all else then,
ego fears love.
The ego is scared to death of Mother's Day.
The ego is scared to death
of what Mother's Day really is.
It's scared to death
of what Mother's Day really is,
really is, really is.
The recognition of the divinity of love
in its expression,
of course on Mother's Day as the feminine,
would mean that love
as a prevailing dominant value
would infiltrate all of society.
And that would be the end
of many corporations
and political positions and all.
Therefore, yes,
the ego is scared to death of Mother's Day.
I don't know if it's scared of Father's Day.
We'll wait till June.
All right.
So love then becomes the greatest threat
to the ego.
The way to not go to 35 years of lectures
is nothing happening then.
The secret of it is love.
The secret is love for the truth.
The secret of it is
faith and confidence
and the integrity of the source of the truth.
And one means of accomplishing that
is by kinesiologic testing.
To what degree you can trust
the validity of what is being said.
It comes through the energy field,
calibrated energy field of the speaker.
The level of the truth then.
Truth because truth is only meaningful
within a certain context.
And what is the context of the words
that have been said?
We could test the truth
of Deutschland über alles.
And then we could test the context
out of which it came,
the consciousness of Adolf Hitler.
Actually, Adolf Hitler played upon
the evolution of fascism in Germany
arose out of a philosophic position.
A professor...
It's in my book, I forget his name.
Pfaffenhofer or something.
They justified the German invasion by...
It was a doctrine of
Räumsleben or something.
Living room.
Lebensraum.
That Germany had the right to invade
neighboring countries
because it needed room to live.
Boy, that was a weak one, huh?
But it built the whole country.
The whole structure came out of that.
Room to live.
Golly.
That's what I transmit
to the fellow drivers on the highway.
I need room to drive, folks.
Therefore, I have the right
to crash my car into his
and knock him off the road
because I need driving room.
That's a rather weak intellectual position,
isn't it?
Did we ever calibrate that?
No, let's see.
Deutschland über alles
calibrates over 100, 110,
120, 130, 140, 140.
Okay.
Adolf Hitler at the time.
We have permission to resist.
Calibrate over 120, 130, 140, 150.
It corresponded, huh?
Okay.
All right.
So then the demagogue finds
the downside in human nature
and knows how to directly appeal to that.
The smart politician knows
what the consciousness level of mankind is
and that he can easily summon up that hatred.
He knows that hatred is there
only waiting to be summoned up.
At the opposite end,
we know in spiritual work,
because of the reality of existence itself,
that the capacity for love
and for enlightenment is also available
within human mankind.
So we'll leave hatred to other people
in order to summon that forth.
And all we want to recognize here
is that divinity is the source of your own existence.
It is out of divinity
that consciousness arises.
It is consciousness.
Consciousness is the field
holding us all together,
out of which everybody is able to hear
and experience that which is being said.
The presence within all of us
is what allows us
to experience
the subjective experience
of that which we are
and which we're trying to verbalize here.
So reality then is a radical subjectivity.
We'll get to a lecture
on meditative techniques at all.
But at all times,
the shortcut to God is
to merely realize
the infinite presence
of your own capacity
to experience
and the source
of your own existence.
Nothing has within it
the capacity
to create its own existence
out of what comes existence itself.
We bypass causality
as a plausible explanation.
And I think in the first lecture
we knocked causality on its butt.
And the world hasn't heard of that yet,
but the days of causality
are over, folks.
So let's get to it.
Because the ego will say,
well, what about causality
as an explanation?
Everything is created
in such a way
that its essence
unfolds
due to the divinity
of its source.
It is because of the divinity
of the source of creation
that all things are perfectly
what they are at any moment.
That which appears catastrophically awful
appears that way
because it's out of context.
Because of who you are
in the present,
that looks terrible
in the past.
That's already a judgment.
The awful
manifesting its awfulness
is supposed to be awful
in the awfulness
of its awfulness.
And it's perfectly awful
in the dreadfulness
of its horrific
and horror.
Despicable.
It's supposed
to be that way, folks.
So you know what it is.
Now you know what it is.
And then, we choose differently this time.
We look at the dead bodies
on the battlefield,
we look at the run over children,
and something within us begins to change.
But it changes so slowly, doesn't it?
If you calibrate yourself,
consciousness level of mankind
century by century by century,
190, 190 you see.
Wow, didn't mankind learn anything?
War of 1812?
One war right after another.
Hitler was really so stupid.
I mean, he was really stupid.
Napoleon had just pulled that trick
and blown it.
And he went around and did the same thing.
Invade Russia.
East and west are from the same time.
How can anybody be so stupid?
Stupid, stupid.
So that ignorance and that stupidity
we're trying to find a way through today.
The Buddha and Jesus both said,
the only sin is that of ignorance.
Sin as a moralistic put down
is really useless.
It's using guilt as a hammer
to beat people to death with
or beat yourself to death with.
It says there is ignorance.
Ignorance seems to be innate then
in the structure of the ego itself.
How can you go to 35 years of lectures
and not get anything?
Still be the same person.
There's something within
the ego itself
that accounts for this.
Century after century.
Millions slaughtered.
You go to the next century.
Would it be better? You'd think so.
No, still 190. Millions more slaughtered.
Still 190. Millions more slaughtered.
You say, whoa, there's something
that's really thick-headed about the ego.
There's some innate stupidity.
Innate stupidity.
There we got it today.
The ego is just stupid.
It really is dumb.
So we should treat it like an imbecile.
Stupid.
Dumb. Pitiful.
We should feel sorry for the ego.
It is so dumb.
It can sit there for 35 years
and not get it.
I think maybe what happened was...
Yeah, I see what happened.
Ah.
Alright. The source
from which you are learning
or hearing or something
has to be of a certain dimension.
To break through the resistance.
I held my grandfathers
with reverence and respect
and my father and my uncle.
Because of that,
I didn't argue.
And it was appropriate.
The way women were treated
was appropriate to the way
that they were held.
And they showed me how they were held.
And the reason it rang true
is because it was based on spiritual reality.
Yes, the feminine is the expression
of divinity.
In that genre
of human expression.
And I got it in an instant.
The same thing should happen
in any spiritual literature,
spiritual teaching, whatever.
The respect, the letting go of resistance
to the truth
of its source.
What is the source of its truth?
The source of its truth
is the presence
within
that speaks.
Classically with speaking now
it would be called
in Sanskrit
Purusha.
Purusha would be the essence
of the self
of the teacher
which is expressing itself.
That's what
is expressing itself.
It has nothing to do
with the body
that it is using at the moment.
It will use anybody.
You can't trust Purusha.
It will grab anybody, speak to anybody.
Get there.
The source of
the realization
of the truth of all spiritual teachings
is the
self within you.
You have within yourself
the power
of recognition.
It's only the recognition
if what my grandparents
had told me, my grandfathers
my uncle
had told me
was not innately true.
It would not have resonated within.
It's because
of the presence of truth within me
I was capable
of hearing the truth.
It is only because of
the presence of truth within
everyone here
that there is any capacity
to extract any truth
out of the research that we've
done and we are sharing with you.
Oh my goodness.
Is consciousness
a byproduct
of the spirit
entering a dense matter?
Oh boy, oh boy.
I don't know.
We've got enough questions
to keep us busy for a while.
Each question reflects
what we intend to talk about anyway
and it just reminds me
of what we were going to talk about.
The disassembly of the ego
takes eons of time.
Most people in this audience
have been here 50, 60 times
before to try to accomplish
that which
happens within an instant.
I use the word happens
linguistically to make sense.
To sense
one's reality is simple.
It's only a matter of
knowing where to look.
If you look over here, you're looking
at the written word.
35 years of the written word.
Where is
what you're looking for?
You can all sense
right in this instant.
Right in this instant.
These people are already distant.
I see it.
What you do is
you catch
the experiencing
of the world
just prior to the mind's
commentary about it.
If you back off from the mind
you'll find an inner stillness
which hasn't said anything yet.
You live in the space
before the world has said anything yet.
When you walk outside
you're struck by the beauty
of the surroundings.
You haven't said anything about it yet.
You live in that space.
The space is pre-verbal.
Prior to mentalization.
The difficulty with
verbalization
is
one has to come out of that space
and come forward into that
verbalization because that's what
the world expects.
You
world speak
or the world doesn't understand
because nothing is being spoken.
Right at this moment
just sense within yourself
that which hasn't had a second yet
to make any comment about
what the speaker is saying yet.
The mind's commentary
is a delay.
There's a split second delay
and you live in that experience
before any comment.
When you dive off a diving board
there's no thinkingness about it
as you hit the water.
The thinkingness comes later.
A split second later
that dive wasn't made correctly.
Ow.
That dive wasn't made correctly.
But that's a split second
after you go splat on the water
and realize
that full gainer
was only a three-quarter gainer.
The Red Valley Express
even as you think
you're not getting it
you're there right now.
Right now within everybody's consciousness
is
the presence of consciousness itself
prior to any kind of content.
So
you draw back and you live
in the space
right before the mind starts to make commentary.
And you hold back
in this space
beyond the mind's thinkingness.
Thinkingness should be
voluntary.
I think when I'm forced to think
the world is forever asking you to think
and comment.
No end to it.
You're always exhausted
by coming out of the infinite peace
and beauty of silence
because the world has some
dumbbell question.
Hello?
What is it now?
It takes energy.
I have a new
wonderful telephone
at home.
It's a space phone
or whatever they call it.
I don't understand electronics and all that stuff.
Why?
Because you've got to read all this fine writing.
No matter what you buy
it's got a 16-page manual.
Get away from it.
My favorite radio
is in the waiting room of my office.
It's like the radio I grew up with.
It's got a dial.
It goes on, volume, off
and on.
The world hates
that kind of a radio, I guess.
You know what I'm saying?
Nowadays, somebody gave me an electronic
radio, a new radio.
It's got a 14-page
I can't even
get it to tell time.
I've got one. I don't know what
you do to make it even tell time.
You see what I'm saying?
You get dragged into this complexity.
It pulls all your energy and your interest
and your survival gets pulled
out there.
Yeah, Ramana Maharshi said it correctly
when I read Ramana Maharshi.
I said, that's it?
The mind gets pulled into the world
away from the self.
And one's reality
is prior to the self.
One's reality is
prior to the self
as what?
As a condition.
As a field.
So your reality is a field.
It's the innate field
out of which,
just prior to thinking this,
when you wake up first thing in the morning,
the field is there.
You don't even know who you are yet.
You don't know what your name is.
You don't know where you are.
There's just the awareness of awareness itself.
And at that point,
all you know is that you're awake.
Period.
You know that phase when you wake up?
You know you're awake and that's it.
So that's what the condition is
It's always present.
When thinking that I am that which is talking
and thinking is what's real.
The identification of self,
of reality as the ego,
when that goes away,
in an instant,
there's deadening silence.
Then the question is
how to be in the world
of dead silence
when the world is talking all the time.
It's hard.
It took many years to adjust.
How to do that.
Most people when they go into that space
don't readjust.
They do not reenter the world.
Some kind of karmic momentum.
Some people do return to the world.
Alright, so
at all times you're really making an effort
to come out of the state of inner peace.
It's sort of like
having to wake up
and deal with the world.
Look within yourself and see
there's really a reluctance
to deal with all this thinkingness
and judgmentalism
and emotionality.
It's exhausting.
Within yourself you'll find
man, I'm really tired.
Is everybody here tired?
Man, I'm exhausted
with dealing with the world.
That's why people look forward
to dying.
I can't wait until it's over.
It drags on
and on and on.
You know what the end is anyway.
So what's the big deal?
An hour later it's all the same, isn't it?
Which brings up the question
on Alzheimer's.
Somebody asked me about Alzheimer's
and I've dealt with Alzheimer's
a lot the last five or ten years.
In Alzheimer's
the spirit leaves,
starts leaving.
That's all it is.
You're not really there anymore.
You're like an enlightened person.
You ask an enlightened person
what is today's date?
What the hell does he care what today's date is?
He doesn't live in today's date.
There's no date in reality.
There's only the experience
of nature being what it is.
If I go and ask a tree, I say, what's the date?
It doesn't live in the world of dates.
The tree doesn't live there.
The tragedy of Alzheimer's
is in the witness of Alzheimer's.
The suffering is in the witness.
When you don't know what the hell
the date is anymore, are you suffering?
No. I've asked a thousand Alzheimer's patients,
how are you?
I'm fine.
They say that you can't eat,
and you're this and that.
Oh, I'm fine.
You know what day it is today?
Oh, I don't pay attention to those things anymore.
What year were you born?
Oh!
That's what they say to me.
What year were you born?
Oh!
Like asking a woman her age,
you know, 40 years ago.
You never asked a woman her age.
Oh!
Then they make up stories
to make you happy.
I mean, you obviously want an answer from them,
so they'll make up a story on the spot,
and five minutes later,
they've forgotten the story.
Do you fear Alzheimer's?
No. Why?
Because people identify
with the content of ego as self,
and there are people
that are frightened to death
of losing their memory.
What the hell if you don't remember
1932 to 1934?
What's so precious
that you want to be able to recall it instantly?
Right? Anything?
A person says,
I'm afraid I might lose my memory.
I hope. I mean,
nothing better could happen to you.
Memory is the recall
of perceptual illusion
as it compounded over the years.
I mean, it's like the poison well, folks,
though it's killing you.
So, do I feel sorry
for the Alzheimer's patient? No.
It's the witness, the family.
Two-year-old granny's losing it.
They're weeping and sobbing.
Is granny weeping and sobbing? No, she's not.
How is it here
in this nursing home?
I went to all the nursing homes
in the Ababai County
for close to ten years, right?
Every day I knocked my brains out.
There wasn't any other doctor
that would go see them, so.
The county was happy somebody
would make a house call
and go to the nursing home
because it was horrible.
I loved them all.
The men and the women
were all cute as could be.
And it's because you can see
what's lovable has been
completely preserved.
What's lovable is totally there.
What's irrelevant has disappeared.
All they've lost is what's irrelevant.
As you get closer to the end,
some people have,
let's not even title it anything,
the spirit begins to leave
before the physical body.
Some people, by the time
they physically die,
the spirit's left years ago.
I knew Bill Wilson.
He was the founder of AA.
Bill would say,
and I actually treated him
the last year of his life,
vitamin E and various stuff,
antioxidants we were fooling around with.
And he would drift off.
And then
his watchers would be concerned
that Bill had drifted off.
How is it, Bill?
I'd say, you know,
there are many places you can go in heaven.
He'd been visiting heaven back and forth
like he was shopping for a future resident.
You know what I mean?
But you see in old people then,
do I fear Alzheimer's in myself?
No.
No, I don't fear Alzheimer's in myself.
I'm 75.
I have senior moments, however.
I call a lot of people,
what's his name?
What's his name and what's her name?
I know who they are.
So what happens then
is that which is important
and significant
is no longer located
within the ego's functions.
It's not important to be able to figure out,
to read this manual
and figure out how to push all these buttons
so that I can set the watering system
for every third day
and half time on rain days
and three days on...
I looked at one in the store the other day,
a new watering system thing.
It was mind-boggling.
It has so many bells and whistles
you couldn't figure out how the hell
to make it water the lawn, you know what I mean?
It would serve 12 stations.
Why would you... 12 stations?
I just want one that turns it on and off,
you know what I'm saying?
On at three, off at four.
Don't you have one like that?
No, we don't have one like that.
I'll tell you folks,
the easiest way is in the morning
on the way to work you turn the watering system on
and on the way you turn the hose on,
the sprinklers, and when you come home
you turn it off.
Is that simple or what?
Just saved you $72.
Oh, you can turn it on and off yourself.
Never thought of that.
After breakfast you turn it on.
Before dinner you turn it off.
That's all it takes.
Alright, so reality then
is the world of simplicity.
The person with advanced Alzheimer's
is ultra simple.
They have no needs, no wants,
you say to them,
how are things here?
Fine.
How are they treating you?
Would you rather be someplace else?
No.
While you're still hanging onto the mind
in the past, you grieve.
But as happily Alzheimer's progresses,
you lose that attachment to the past
and now you're not grieving
that you're not living on the farm in Michigan anymore.
Except to the witness,
he is probably closest to enlightenment
than most human consciousness.
That's a statement of fact.
I used to look at the Alzheimer's patients
and I thought,
Christ, he's a Buddha.
What's his problem?
No problem.
How are you?
I'm fine.
How are things here yesterday?
I don't know.
Where are you going tomorrow?
They're living in the instant of now
in which the self is still present
but it's only present in the self
with a capital S.
It's not present as a small s.
Alzheimer's is the dissolution
of the self with a small s
and those who are more spiritually advanced
see that the self with a capital S
is still vitally there.
They're just as loving, warm, friendly,
responsive in the instant.
That's what we summon forth in Walmart.
When you lose your
identification with your persona,
you're just walking with a basket,
you're a nobody.
These two nobodies can instantly be
very friendly and quite loving with each other.
Isn't that true?
If you're walking in Walmart
and somebody bumped into your basket
and suddenly she started to cry,
you'd say to her,
huh, you know what I mean?
Because that veneer that prevents us
from realizing who we are
has been removed.
Alzheimer's from a certain viewpoint
then is a blessing.
You forget that you're dying
so you don't have to even grieve that.
If you don't have Alzheimer's
then you've got to worry that you're dying.
If you've got Alzheimer's,
it doesn't even enter your mind to worry about it.
The whole thing is effortless, painless,
and I think on the other side
you'd hardly notice the difference.
Do you? Could you go on the other side?
Do you notice the difference?
Oh yeah, you notice the body's laying there.
Anybody who's gone out of body
realizes that.
You realize, oh, where's the body?
It's laying there in the bed.
I forgot.
I thought I was still that body.
So helpers come to remind you
that that isn't yours anymore.
You don't need it anymore.
You don't want it anymore anyway.
It's a mess.
You leave it at 93,
blind, deaf, dumb, crippled,
with arthritis and one leg missing.
I mean, who's going to hang on to it?
So that's my view of old age suffering.
The suffering is due to
hanging on to what?
What it was.
And the absolute refusal to surrender.
Death and dying Alzheimer's
are moments of great opportunity
to reach spiritual enlightenment.
They're great moments because
the investment in the world,
the investment in the mind,
the functions of the body and the mind
have diminished to the point
that it's easy to let it go.
Easy to let it go.
To be in the space just prior to thought.
So your reality
is the sense
of presence.
Your sense of being here.
You hear what he's talking about.
It isn't necessary to really understand it.
You sense that
you are present.
You sense that you're in the presence
of the presence of the allness
of us here.
Just like when you walk out in nature.
Just before your stupid mind
says, isn't that a beautiful tree?
You catch the space in which you saw
a tree's beauty without comment.
That's the space you live in.
Just prior to thought.
It's easy to just
fall back into it.
It's not like something you have to accomplish
through years of study and meditation.
The willingness to trust it
and just drop into that,
back into that.
That is your reality.
Your reality is a priority
to any programming.
Your reality is
what is in the computer world
the software and hardware.
Your beauty is the hardware
which is always present.
Prior to hitting the button
and getting the software.
Oh, isn't that a beautiful tree?
It's too late already.
However, even while you're saying that
you can back off from the ego
and not identify with that statement.
The two things exist.
Reality is both context and content.
One can realize the foolishness
of the statement
and simultaneously
be aware of the beauty of the woods
prior to any comment.
We'll do one or two more questions
and then we'll break for lunch.
Trying to read these is something else.
They really have
very good handwriting.
It's like reading the stuff
on the back of the clock
on how to make it work.
How should we hold the situation
in the Middle East
coming back to the present world?
The presidency
calibrates around 450
and it has throughout the centuries.
I think a few of them
in olden times
but in modern times
the average consciousness level
is about 450.
I think Roosevelt was like 499 or something.
Churchill was 510.
The consciousness then
of the leaders of the modern world
are usually in the mid-400s.
They're going to do
what appeals to reason
the intellect,
intelligence,
research,
their advisors.
They're going to do what
they're going to pull together
the best advice team
and then they will give it
a slight preference
due to political position.
Current president
has no problem
with right versus wrong.
Right is right and wrong is wrong.
What's the problem?
Within that context,
it's true.
Now your question is
should that context apply?
When a tiger is about to rip
your jugular vein out,
the context is a little different
than looking at a
tiger in the zoo.
The context is a little different.
What's permissible?
The alternatives
are somewhat different
depending on context.
So it's the context of the zoo
that makes it a little different
than the jungle.
This has to do...
My goodness,
these are tough ones.
Oh my golly.
We got some really brilliant minds
here today.
We will answer all these things
in one way or the other.
I'll just answer one more question
and then we will break for lunch
because these are a lot to sort of
look at and pull out the essence of it.
I forgot what I was
going to talk about.
There's a lot of questions about
calibrations of the level of consciousness.
Calibrating levels of consciousness
is only a tool.
It's a way of getting information.
It doesn't get you enlightened.
But it does tell you
what's a dead end.
What's a dead end?
And also what's a pitfall?
What to avoid?
Which way to go?
So it's helpful
in the first direction.
Of course, the capacity
to tell the truth about anything
instantly brings up a zillion questions
about everything.
So you have to look at the intention
behind the curiosity,
behind the question.
Very often you find out more
about what you wanted to know
by examining the reason
why the question is coming up.
It's been a unique opportunity
because we've found out
that there is access
that accounts for
the spin of this photon
in this direction.
Instantly the spin of the photon
And the only thing that changed
was human consciousness observed it.
Human consciousness
did nothing but look at this photon.
Instantly the photon rotates this way.
This photon rotates this way.
Instantly.
No connection between the two whatsoever.
The only connection that's possible
would be that there's
a field, a field,
common, a matrix,
a matrix, a latticework.
I think it's called in quantum mechanics
hypothesized
a matrix,
a matrix, a latticework.
Something that under which
the whole universe,
the reality of matter,
the reality of all that exists
then arises out of that
which is invisible,
indefinable, undefinable,
unlimited.
It's that sense of that
within yourself.
It's just a matter of sensing it.
It's a matter of intuition.
You go back within yourself
to that which is
there prior to hearing this word.
There is something there
right before this word
is heard and right before
the mind thinks of a
reaction to the word.
It's in that space,
the most likely place
and situation
to find that space
that we call enlightenment
is while you're eating cookies.
Diana's cookies.
If that don't take you there,
nothing will.
So we'll resume then
in exactly one hour, okay?
And we'll do more questions.
I'll have a chance to look at the questions
during the break.
Well we were asked to test
a number of various things.
Many of them I already know the answer
but just for fun, a near death experience
to ask that question.
I don't think it's
correctly phrased right.
Near death experience
helps one transcend
the identification with the ego.
It can bring about major
transformations in consciousness.
It can bring about
a major positive leap in consciousness.
The way you tell out of body
from a near death experience
and there's a lot of lack of sophistication
not only in the general public
but even some spiritual teachings.
Out of body is one thing
near death experience is another.
Out of body doesn't necessarily
change your calibratable
level of consciousness at all.
That's a fact.
You can go out of body, come back in body
and boy that was really interesting.
But that's really not
a major shift to consciousness.
Near death experience
is of a
totally different dimension.
One is just
awestruck by the
immensity of the realization
of the nature of divinity
and
that that which you're experiencing
is not different than that which
who you are.
So it's a major transformation
near death experiences.
So to tell the truth
you can calibrate before and after
the experience.
Out of body usually you'll be about the same.
However out of body
you do become more sophisticated.
You also have an etheric body.
One thing that you're quite certain of
as you're floating in space
is that you have an etheric body
because now you're it.
Out of body is
of course quite exhilarating.
It happened to me many years ago
in those days
and nothing was heard of it.
I think I've recounted it before.
In a serious illness
suddenly there I was
looking down at the body
in the bed
and the interesting thing was
the sense of self
went with the etheric body.
The capacity to know
feel, think, hear
reason, everything.
The sense of I was up here
and it was down there.
So it is an opportunity
to realize
that the sense of self
the spiritual self
is an energy body and not a physical body.
At the time
I don't think it had any
particularly transformative experience.
When I told my psychoanalyst
about it
I was in psychoanalysis at the time
I bless him, dear Dr. Oversee
I said
God almighty there was this experience
what you had a toxic psychosis there
with a duplication of the body image
and a rejection of one aspect of it
and I said
you're right, you're right
we were both atheists
he didn't think much of
God and religion and at the time
I didn't either so
we didn't have any problem with it
it was a toxic
couple of irritated brain cells
that's all we knew about in those days.
Alright we've got some interesting
leading questions into the subject
which we're going to go into anyway.
In my talking about women of course
just using Mother's Day
as a point of reference
I'm not differentiating
men from women because
divinity of course is equally
present
the form that it takes within the
perceptual world is different
I mean a man is different from a woman
within the physical world
and symbolically
they represent
symbolically in the unconscious
those of you who are
familiar with the work
of Jung and all
realize that the archetype of
the feminine and the archetype of the male
are two different things and historically
they've always been
even the planets are named with various
genders and the gods and all
that's really a different subject
it's a subject
of study in itself
the origin of how this arises
how it expresses itself
the divinity
of all is the same of course
I was just talking about
its expression
as a woman
and then using that
to denote the importance of
context, how woman was conceived of
in the 1800s
early 1900s now
is a shift of context
but the reality of course
has not been changed at all
some of these
are a little too complicated
I can't answer them
they're beyond me
all right
I'll take my notes about them
here we have
we forgot to put this up before
it's just a point of reference
it's a very useful point of reference
because I get many requests
from all kinds of groups
publishers, writers and all
to reproduce it
and I always tell them yes
because it's useful
as a teaching
teaching device
and
people say well
see people can't seem to get out of
the ego's
view of things being better
than others or ranking them
is there
is 500 better than 400
no, 500 is a different
different problem than 400
to have any calibrated
number at all indicates a problem
if you're at 500 your problem is
things aren't better than others
they're just different than others
people that are just entering the 400s
are trying to
own the capacity of reason
and logic and all
and what is what we call
sophomoric is usually something
somebody that's just entered the 400s
and they're dazzled by their capacity
to use logic and thinking
and
because they don't realize its downside
they take it to the ridiculous extreme
you know what I'm saying
and then they write
legislation
I mean it's okay
the abstract but you should try to live
with it
I read somewhere that the
the IRS regs run
58,000 pages and of course
you know as a taxpayer
you are legally liable
for knowing all of its contents
you realize that
because
it's unknowable the government can't
understand it so it makes you responsible
for knowing it
so I mean that's the intellect gone wild
without any limitation
so ranking would be then
the mind's
proclivity for status
and things like this and then projecting it onto
these fields
nothing is better than anything else
it's different than
something else because it's addressing
a whole different problem
it's addressing a whole different problem
is loss
the occasion for grief
or is it
the gateway to freedom and elation
depends on who you lost eh
yeah
so you see you don't have
to mourn loss at all
you can see that
loss is the occasion
you know let's say you own a whole head of
cattle and they're all dead by morning
terrible disease
well you don't have to get up and milk them
I'll tell you that
four o'clock in the morning in the midwest
through the snow and the ice and pitch blackness
with snow up to here
and walk through all that cattle poo
to milk this thing
alright
so every loss then
can be recontextualized
as an opportunity for freedom
as valuable as that
position may have been
it still is the opportunity now
to discover a new life
the company collapses
you lose your position
is that a loss
it is only if you hang on to the past
what is really going on
is you're afraid of the freedom
that the dissolution of that commitment
now opens up
you're now free to become anything you want
go anywhere you want
are you going to stay in the same part of the world
same part of the country
in other words it's sort of scary
the freedom that you had
alright so
ranking then would be just a projection
that we project onto this
and the question often arises
how do you see perfection
in any and all conditions
because perception is a projection
and
you will find what you're looking for
that's the whole basis of
quantum mechanics
the reason they stop calling things measurements
is because
what is found is
the consequence of what you're looking for
the observed is
then seen as a function
of the observer
the observer
the observer is what determines
what's observed
now what's observed
depends on intention
we said that calibrated level
of consciousness
as well as karma has to do with
spiritual intention
now spiritual intention doesn't
fluctuate
it tends to move quite slowly
although you can have a major event
such as a near death experience
or a spiritual intention
suddenly takes a giant leap
the moment to moment
little angriness, irritation, regrets
all these things
those are not fluctuations on the level of consciousness
level of consciousness is pretty steady
it's set up by the
karmic
karmic development
of
your spiritual commitment
so the spiritual commitment then
tends to prevail
fluctuations may occur
only in a fleeting thought
so if you calibrated a thought
the thoughts may jump all over
but that which you are
doesn't change that easily
and people involved in spiritual work
know
how difficult that is
to get it to change
so
it's pretty much set
and determined
how you see the world
that calibrated level of energy
is influenced
then through your own decision
is it influenced by the group
yes
I think so
you calibrated a level of consciousness
is influenced by the group
with which you identify
yeah
it is influenced
because you are saying
I see that as my reality
so it isn't so much the group
is that you
are verifying that the group
represents your own
spiritual goal
not killing innocent children
may be a very important
spiritual learning down here
there are certain very large
religious groups in the world right now
where getting up this far
is a great advance
getting over 70
is a major improvement
that God is not pleased by your
killing thousands of innocent women and children
would seem so
ludicrous to us
but it might be a tremendous
aha to somebody
so as you move up
your own spiritual awareness moves up
the group that you find useful at one time
you are going to outgrow the group
eventually you outgrow all groups
so the group is useful
as mutual support
and
continuous feedback
helps to clarify one's understanding
of that particular religious position
or spiritual position
and then one moves on
I think we spoke
there were a number of different groups
people asked me about individually
I don't like to do them publicly
you see by their fruits you shall know them
we don't have to ask what
is
the calibrated level of certain
groups and their actions
because
by their fruits you shall know them
so we did write something about
the difference between a true spiritual
group and a cult
cults calibrate below 200
that's the quickest way
a cult is non-integrist
so a cult may take the name
of a great leader or avatar
or spiritual guru or whatever
and call itself that
and then underneath the guise of that
really become a political action
group
the one in China that's having trouble
with the government you see
its problem is
that it didn't stick to just
strictly spiritual it got political
when it got political
it began to challenge the Chinese authority
all governments
by nature protect themselves
that's why they're your government
so China
outlawed them right
Falun Gong I think is the name of it
so if you stay home and meditate
and do good works the government will not take
a position about you
but if you start getting out there with the parade
and you're going to overthrow the
regime and put in your
philosophical concepts
prepare to die
you know prepare to die
you can make a grandstand statement
but that isn't what makes the world
turn you know what I'm saying
so a cult can take on the name of a great
leader call itself
you know the holy church
of God and
the holy church of God
and then the name of the holy church of God
burned down the homes
of whatever
you know what I'm saying
just because they call themselves that doesn't mean anything
alright so we define
the difference between a cult and a truly
integrative spiritual group
of course we as a group know all you have to do
is calibrate them
but to the world
that which is of God
gives forth love and peace
it's as simple as that
love and peace is what radiates from it
sometimes that
sometimes the original of the spirit
the originator or the original speaker
of that spiritual truth
it is loving and pure
but then that's grabbed by other groups
who then run with it
and use it as justification
to
convert people by the sword
Jesus meant the sword of truth right
didn't mean
the sword of steel
so it's misused
then for other ends
we notice
that people are born
at different levels of consciousness
the very instant of birth
and there's another question having to do
with geography I meant today
to have a transparency
to project with the world map
showing calibrating the various
levels of consciousness
and prevailing civilizations
over the world
it's very interesting
because
you see that like
light
tends to attract light
that's sort of true
so if you're born with a
level of consciousness of
50 let's say
you're very likely to get
born into a body
that happens to be part of a civilization
civilization
that in general
calibrates around 50
in other words
it's like nothing happens by accident
that if light
light tends to go to light
at the very moment of birth
at the very moment
before birth even
the calibrated level of consciousness
of the entity is already
identifiable
we can actually calibrate it
what we just said is true
that's a fact
we've done it over and over
so what we think is
unspiritual
let's say we look at the lifestyle
of somebody here
and we go cluck cluck cluck
yeah but that person came in
here for them to be
at 100 or 150 is a major
advance
you can look
back at previous lifetimes
and these
areas that you transcend
become very
important
you stand out of that
lifetime
the lifetime of surmounting
physical death
it's thrilling
you commit harry carry
and ecstasy
the second you're out of body
ecstasy
surmounted that for all time
never again
to be inhibited by the fear of physical death
that makes a very ferocious warrior
who's not afraid of death
the fearless warrior
you can walk into a hail of bullets
and you don't give a rap about it
you're no longer susceptible to that
well now you've transcended that level
there's no point to
i don't have to get myself killed over and over
to get the point
you got a physical body
you see the thing laying there
the other spirit and you laugh at each other
great job joe great job
we both did it
so there's really no point to do that again
you don't have to commit harry carry 10 or 12 times
you get the point of it
it's not pleasant
so i'd only do it once
if i were you
it isn't that one thing is better than another
you see
as you grasp the totality
of consciousness
as it has evolved throughout time
and the way it manifests
on this planet
as the evolution of life on this planet
evolving into mankind
evolving into modern man
you begin to realize
what you're dealing with
you're dealing with
like a profound morass
out of which consciousness is only
just barely popping it's little head
it didn't cross 200
until the late 1980s
in other words
it's like
modern consciousness
is just being born now
we're probably part of the birth process
of
homo spiritus
and so
homo spiritus is
a declaration made by
this great wonderful being here
homo spiritus is correct
it is the emergence of homo spiritus
okay
in the book i
then i say
there is now
emerging out of this morass
of negativity
ignorance
and finally the 400s
the ego
the appearance of love which is relatively recent in the human condition
as a prevailing
energy
we have now the emergence
of the spiritually aware being
aware of himself
as a spiritual reality
the emergence of homo
spiritus
all the branches off the evolutionary tree
see
it's not a linear thing
where this gets better and better and better and better
in the evolutionary tree
evolution by the way happens on the level of
consciousness then it manifests within
the physical domain
but you see it's branches off the tree
this tree this branch goes off here
this branch doesn't just get longer
and bigger and better
no it stops there
it's potentiality has been realized
when it hits the perfection of that which it is
and then you see
later another branch off the tree
and then another branch higher
off the tree
you see the one branch doesn't
so the evolution of consciousness
as it's expressed in
mankind is not
the continuous evolution of one
trend at all
it's the emergence of a new trend
a new trend
those of us here today represent really
a new branch off the evolutionary tree
we are not an improvement
on Cro-Magnon man
we're not an improvement
we're not an improvement on homo erectus
homo erectus went here
and he got as far as homo erectus could go
end of homo erectus
each of us then represents
we have
a branch off the tree
and there's a new branch off the tree
called homo spiritus
that's a fact
that's so
and the group here
certainly represents
that which is homo spiritus
the awareness that we're more than
a physicality
the awareness that we're more than a mind
the recognition of
the spiritual potential within
to be discovered and nurtured
for it to flourish and blossom
did the enderthal man
worry about these things?
no
not suitable
I think Cro-Magnon man
was about 70
that has to do with physical survival as an animal
good enough to eat, to mate
to stay alive
so that's the animal
so he had to first perfect
the ability to maintain life
within animal form
within biped form
and then consciousness went on
consciousness got bored with that one
got bored with him
said he's boring
and went on and developed this Cro-Magnon
and then on through the ages
what we see now
is where the evolution of consciousness
is at its present moment
this moment here
the evolution of human consciousness
throughout all of time
throughout eons and eons
of time
has resulted
in us
we're it
we are it
amen
the advancing edge of consciousness
is really what is here today
is it not?
what is the ultimate truth
how does one reach it
what are the tools that are useful for the task
or the advancing edge of spiritual consciousness is
is it
is it possible
in the old religions
well religion is one thing
spiritual truth is another
hypothetically at least in the beginning
they are one and the same
but we see throughout history
how spiritual truth then gets destroyed
for secular means
and the original truth is lost within
the more spiritually
advanced person utilizes
what they realize
spiritual truth from that religion
and lets the shaft go
lets the shaft go
whether you eat meat on Friday or not
is really irrelevant to God
let's see if that's a fact
that's a fact
ok
when I grew up you didn't eat meat on Friday
because it was respectful
well no it was a sin
it was worse than respectful
high episcopal it was like catholic
anyway you didn't eat meat on Friday
it was really out of respect
for the religion
and respect for the teaching
whether it got you in or out of heaven
I don't know
but as a kid I suppose I would worry
if you ate meat on a Friday and died
you'd think you were going to the other place
we have permission to do some
public leaders resist
that are in the middle east resist
I myself have wondered about
this particular individual
we have permission to calibrate him in public
he resists
he's on TV every night so I guess he's not too timid
this gentleman
calibrates over 200 resist
wow over 220
240 wow 260
Arafat 250
let's see Arafat was
at 250
10 years ago resisted
no now Arafat is
interesting because we see a lot of
well known in fact currently popular
gurus that wrote
books years ago when they were in a high space
usually in the mid 500s
and their books calibrate in high 500s
but if you calibrate what is the energy of this
entity today you'll often find
they're like 130 common
very big name gurus in the world
everybody goes oh when you mention their name
you calibrate them to like 140
or something you know
it's because they went up
and then were hit by
you might say their opposite
and succumbed to the opposite
that's how the cult is born
and you have a certain charisma
when people start to follow you
you start to believe your own publicity
you start getting power over others
you start telling them what to do
you develop a cult
you have to swear an oath
you gotta pay money
get a thing on your whatchamacallit
and
every time the name of the leader
you bow
even Est
God bless Est
it was Werner right
it was Werner everything
bigger than a movie theater
on the screen
it was all Werner
on the other hand Est taught some
terrific things
with Est you can take off weight very easy
you know
lots of good things in it
alright
so then the cult we see
somebody asked me about various things
I said I don't want to calibrate them in public
the leader becomes charismatic in a cult
it becomes all Baba so and so
master so and so
master Baba
so it all becomes all master Baba
with many oohs and ahhs
so it's like a personality cult
then there's a
a specialness to belonging
to the group
there's a group form that gets a name
maybe an initiation ceremony
and
now the group becomes
you're either with them or not with them
you know
you're one of us or not one of us
so it becomes very
instead of seeing yourself
as part of the all
the allness of life
you now become partitioned as special
special
so you're a member that makes you special
then there's group lingo
which is only known to the members of the group
there's the specialness of the cult leader
there is a negative
reaction if you leave
if you decide you're going to leave
the holy
rosary of the round table
or whatever
horrible things happen to you
snakes in your mailbox
hate mail
so there's a negative reaction
if you try to leave
so you like become a prisoner
so the brainwashing
what is really brainwashing
is then proceeded about this organization
about its specialness
often it considers itself exclusive
some go so far as to say
that they're the only ones
that are going to get into heaven
you know it's a little hard to imagine
how many people are going to believe that
so there's a specialness
a uniqueness
a cult-like atmosphere
a specialness to belonging
or not belonging
various titles go with it
and after a while
there's probably a lot to be learned
there's a lot to be learned
at that level
but then at a certain level
you begin to realize
this is not freeing and liberating
this is confining
this is totalitarian
at its greatest expression
it becomes totalitarian
at that point your intuition will tell you
it's time to move on
it's very often hard to see
because
the adulation
with which certain people
are held by large groups
so mass hysteria
the suggestion of madness of crowds
takes over
so if you're in a group
and everybody's going
the charisma of the leader then
becomes magnetic
and the adulation of the group
tends to be infectious
so you've got to watch
that you don't get brainwashed
the only thing a teacher can do
is reflect truth
doesn't make them special, unique
anything at all
don't forget to a realized person
their condition is just nothing
it's just the way it is
is a cat's condition to a cat special?
no, it's just being a cat
so
a true teacher is just like a cat
I mean it just is what it is
but there's nothing to say about that
it's just being what one is
you know what I mean?
so there would hardly be any
adulation expected from being what you are
the cat doesn't expect me to say
oh great cat
because you are a cat
the presence within is so powerful
it is of itself
it bypasses all personhood
so there is no one to
go ooh and ahh over