Is the eye the self the god of all
universes of which there are an infinite
number is 1250.
To go from
around 700 or so which doesn't happen
very often on upwards is not a pleasant
experience. It is not like the early
it's not like the high 500s.
Uh it is not exquisite condundolini
energy coming up through you and pouring
out through yourself in in exquisite.
What happens now or what happened here
and happened with the Buddha was is the
the nervous system is overly taxed and
goes into exquisite pain. It's like a
burning sensation of red hot. It's like
the nerves have become
barbed wire, hot barbed wire. It's a
horrible sensation. It's throughout your
whole aura. So, you can't escape it no
matter what. And this means that there's
some awareness out. This signifies that
there's something holding up the
progression. Maybe that only happens if
you're karmically destined to progress.
Let's see. Yeah, I bet. Um that only
happens if you're karmically destined to
progress. Is this Oh, okay. Oh, wow. So,
if you have the misfortune of this being
karmically destined to progress,
this uh consciousness keeps going and
it's not satisfied with 700. It should
be its absolute totality, infinite
bliss, the knowingness of the oneness of
the divine presence.
But something out of some place can
force it to grow and it goes beyond
that. Hm. Then goes these there's these
horrible experiences which go on for
years and of you could be driving along
perfectly fine and suddenly a thought
goes through the
air somewhere and this extreme
discomfort starts and you find that
um you find out what the error is and
you correct the error
uh usually in the form of a prayer
and then it disappears.
So this goes on for quite a painful
period of time
at the moment
let's say I don't know if it was a
moment it seemed like a moment at at the
time of which of which the mind
disappeared
it was like obliterated by an infinite
presence of crystal clarity exquisite
beauty
exquisite gentleness and profound power
beyond All imagination,
all conceptions of power compared to the
power of the presence is infinite. It's
infinite, infantessimal. So
the mind is like whatever is left of the
mind is like obliterated.
And for fun
some 30 years later when I learned
kinesiology I asked let's ask about
that was the thought of an archangel
resist
I want to give you some idea of power
in the pits of hell the atheist says
beyond any hope the atheist says if
there is a god I ask him to help
Then infinite silence. Then suddenly
this infinite presence, absolute
silence.
And it was like it grabbed on to a
50,000 volt. The power was so infinite.
So the response to the prayer was a
thought was a thought by that archangel.
Correct. Karmically thought.
It's like a karmic, you know, I say it
funny. It's like an archangel was
cruising by and he hears this screech
from the pits of hell and he gives it a
thought
instantly
that which you were is totally
obliterated for all time and the
radiance shines forth and there you are
barely able to see in the light you know
it just gave you a passing thought I
guess I mean this is as good a way to
describe it as any anything how it comes
about
all is an evolution of consciousness and
we Call that evolution karmic.
The word karma here does not mean
reincarnation. Karma means that
consciousness evolves and each thing
becomes an expression of its essence.
And we call that karma.
You can't be a human being here sitting
in a bar body without already the karmic
inheritance that allows you to do so. So
there's no point to worry about karma
because
that which you are is your karma.
The ego is your karma.
There's no necessity to look for where
it arose from
any more than it's not too interesting
how you broke an ankle. The problem is
how to fix it. You know what I mean? As
a physician, I'm I don't care how you
broke it. Fell down the kitchen stairs.
You're having a battle with your wife.
That's all immaterial.
You want to fix what the condition is
now because the condition now is the
inheritance of the past. It was the
walking down the steps, the slipping on
the banana peel, the argument with the
spouse, the not paying attention. So
however it arose karmically
as spiritual students our presentation
is the
how we experience oursel in the present
moment as compared to how we would like
to become in due time.
Um so we said the archangel is 50,000
and up.
50,000 up. 50,000 for jacks for openers.
And the supreme and ultimate realization
of course is God as unmanifest as well
as manifest because that which is
manifest is both is both manifest and
beyond both. The ultimate reality is
beyond either manifest or unmanifest.
All of which are definitions of mind and
when mind stops they're meaningless.
Uh so that was the first question for
today.
So, okay, here's some interesting
questions.
And what's the value of a mantra? Well,
a mantra depends uh
you know, calibrating levels of energy
is useful. Uh let's take one out of uh
there's a translation by Sacha Danda of
a famous spiritual classic.
Uh oh god, I forgot the name of it.
Um
let let's do the mantra alm. Okay.
What's the value of a mantra? Well, it
depends on a lot of things.
Uh oh is over 540
ohm. The mantra ohm calibrates over 600
700 720 740 750
mantra ohm is in the 700s resist. Okay.
Okay. Now let's go.
The mantra au m is over 600.
Two it's over 300.
300 to over through 10.
Wow. Well well you go m or m makes quite
a bit of difference right? You go alm
you're going to take a long time to get
enlightened. Right.
All right. So, one reason for the
lectures is that this comprehend the
comprehension speaking to you now uh is
capable of explaining things that have
been mis misunderstood. The reason for
writing the books is to clarify things
that are obvious
um obvious
um with a capital O but not obvious with
a small O. So the the purpose of uh the
12 lectures, the books and all is to
fortify that which is
known uh in such a way that it is not
misinterpreted later
to fortify it with such a bull work of
explanation, demonstration
uh and clarification that it can't be
misunderstood.
The ultimate mantra is either om or
right.
All right. So an authority such as such
translate what is the book that somebody
gives the it's a great spiritual
classic.
Great spiritual classic. Well I'm sure
all kinds of people
study it and yet it contains very
serious errors. You know very serious
errors. So the purpose is first of all
to provide sufficient information that
it would be sufficient to take one the
whole way to share the subjective
reality of it
and also to provide a tool by which the
person like a compass can find their own
way through the woods. Huh?
and to also
warn of the pitfalls to warn of the
pitfalls where many fall off.
Seduction by that which sounds exotic,
especially if it comes from some other
realm.
Everything from some other realm is
called spiritual.
There are many realms and many of them
are not where you want to go. Nor do you
want to follow their advice. And yet
it's commonly done because it comes from
master gunk on the other side. Prison
goes to the swoon and says m babuchi is
talking to me. He says you should sell
your livestock and move to Cincinnati
and go out in the field and wait for the
UFOs to get come and reach you. Thank
you Baba. Yeah.
So
no, if you're going to do any uh
channeling transes um messages from the
other side, you better calibrate them.
Always calibrate the entity on the other
side because there are good people
because there are different realms.
H there's higher astral and lower astral
the highest higher astrals are called
celestial. There are multiple heavens.
There are multiple purgatories. There
are multiple hells
and there are entities in various
regions that would like to have
influence in the human domain
that um hate the human domain because
the human domain contains the capacity
to realize God. in the lower astral
domain is those who have refused God,
cursed God or blasphemed God as we
demonstrated before with kinesiology
and which as Jesus Christ said cannot be
forgiven.
In other words,
the belief in an avatar as one's savior
is necessary up to level 600.
Um,
and the savior can act in your behalf.
Lotus Land Buddhism teaches that.
Christianity teaches that
the Buddha of infinite compassion
can speak for you and you go to lotus
land. The what is it? Lotus
land which is what you know it's heaven
and the Buddha becomes your intercessor.
So you earn by devotion the right of an
intercessor to speak in your behalf
because you of your own level of
consciousness are not able to transcend
all the domains.
So the Christ speaks for you, the Buddha
speaks for you, other saviors speak for
you. Um
and
in that energy field all can be
forgiven. But it says some things cannot
be forgiven. And it's well to pay
attention because that is a fact. It
cannot be wiped off your slate by a
great spiritual master.
If it cannot be wiped off your slate by
a great spiritual master, then it is
undone by your living it out,
experiencing it out.
And
the time in hell is beyond time. Don't
forget that the lower levels of hell are
just like the higher levels. They're
beyond the form of time. And the lower
levels of hell are beyond
description. The agony is infinite and
it's forever.
It's forever because it's forever. The
horror of what has happened to you dawns
on you.
Therefore the to undo it
karmically one experiences that to which
they have cursed somebody else
and now you experience the hell that you
cursed them to etc. All right. So
there's various realms heavenly realms
the higher astral or commonly called
celestial.
In the experiences I described to you
today, there was never any other entity
there.
On the way to hell, I passed no devils.
Donnie was correct. Donniey's
description of hell is was literally
correct. Exactly the way it is. The
upper levels are torture and torment and
agony and suffering and dismemberment,
etc. But that's those are just jacks for
openers. Then you get to the real hell.
All that stops and a nameless dread
which goes on for eons.
Eons prevail.
In the higher realms there are celestial
beings and many of them have been
described in the spiritual literature.
The white brotherhood uh the visions of
the saints
and these are to me the higher celestial
realms in which form still persists.
Um the idea of
an other is not conceivable.
When form disappears as a reality,
there is no
this and an other that. So
it's not within this experience of
higher beings
guides and spiritual
um
divine figures that come to you.
They must be in higher celestial.
What this is asking about is the higher
celestial.
All right? So there are celestial realms
still within form. You might say what
lower heavens where form persists and
divine figures and you know frankly
that's good enough.
I'll take the lower heavens anytime. You
know it's a wonderful place.
So form then can persist as devils. We
can people experience the presence of
demonic figures, hellish figures
in the lower astral domains and saintly
figures and spiritual guides and angels
and the and the others.
I I pretty much restrict myself to what
that which
has been experienced as a reality. Other
things I've only heard about. So I
differentiate that which I've heard
about and that which I know and I've
never had to meet celestial beings.
Um
Native American spirituality
uh in calibrating there's a current book
I'm working on called All Stands
Revealed.
Um a number of uh Indian Chief Detroit
calibrates at 700.
Chief Detroit, you know, Chief Detroit,
the there's a very famous quotation from
Chief Detroit which persists to this
day. And he had quite a he and the
the Indians in the east who had a
Congress, you know, were pretty much the
basis of the Constitution, United
States, the structure of the United
States government is very much just
nothing but uh the way it was an inquiry
nation. Anyway, Chief Detroit calibrates
as 700 and the Native American great
white spirit calibrates as a very high
uh understanding of the of God. See,
because it's God as present both
transcendent and imminent imminent in
other words the the divinity of all
living things. So the Native American
sees the divinity of all that exists
which is put down in theology as
pantheism. See once you label a thing
you lose what it is.
To see that the the deer is divine
is to be
aware of the ultimate reality that the
great white spirit expresses itself as
all of life as all of life.
The Native American was quite quite uh
enlightened spiritually.
Um various teachers you see we some of
the question came up about comparing
teachers. You can't really compare
teachers. Each teacher is what it is. If
you calibrate the teaching of a teacher
or the book by the teacher, you'll end
up with a calibration level somewhere
around this. Uh usually the usually the
great teachers are in the 500s. Once in
a while you'll hit one as high as 700.
The Bhagavad Gita calibrates about
thousand.
The teachings of Krishna.
Um so each teacher then is is is
teaching from a different level. The
reason I talk about levels of
consciousness to know what level is
being spoken of.
If you read Raman Maharshi and he tells
you don't bother to say save the world
because the world you see doesn't even
exist.
That's about 740.
But that's not the reality of the reader
who says what about the starving
children? What about the cat that just
got run over and has a broken leg? I
mean, I'm supposed to just say that's in
my imagination. You know what I'm
saying? Is that meaningful or what?
So, a teacher may be useful to you
within a certain range.
Teachers come up at various parts of
your lifetime because of your karmic
momentum, the the the place that you're
at. So, what's meaningful to you one
level may not be meaningful to you at
another.
M
it's like comparing apples and oranges.
This teacher somebody mentioned during
the break a teacher of great area
edition very well known. He's a teacher
of great area edition. He is extremely
well read in the spiritual literature
and knows what is valuable to quote from
each teacher. And when he gives a
lecture and he does a lot of lecturing
he quotes from one teacher after another
because he sees the spiritual validity
and value of it. So he himself is
sufficiently high to recognize truth.
You have to be at a certain level before
you can even recognize it and begin to
quote it. So a teacher like that is of
value to tell you what you know the
variety the variety of things that are
available. Certain approaches will
appeal to you and others will not. Some
approaches will appeal to you at certain
times in your life and not at other
times.
The transmission of no mind.
Even the title people say, "Huh?"
Wang Poe, the transmission of no mind.
That's about what? 740.
Wang Po transmission of no mind is over
700, 720, 730, 740, 750, 760, about 750.
You see, because what we're talking
about and we're leading to in these
lectures is the there's a lecture on Ada
the way to God. It said through mind,
but its reality is the way to God
through no mind.
But the only way to get to no mind is
through mind. And so therefore, we'll
get to uh no mind through mind by
approaching it from no mind. Okay. So
now that's meaningful to me. You folks
know what I'm talking about.
Uh this has the specific calibrations of
a number of people and government
institutions. Now that is a really
interesting subject and it's the one I'm
working on currently called all stands
revealed in which we're doing about a
thousand calibrations.
Um, and some of these we did on a
demonstration tape called video number
one, I think, power versus force. At the
time we did that, we calibrated the FBI
and the CIA
and the um,
alcohol, tobacco, and firearms, ATF. At
the time, ATF, CIA, and FBI all made you
go weak.
Um, and I think it's on that tape we did
in '95 that the third level from the top
in the CIA had a mole
and that there was a serious mole at a
high level in the FBI.
They've since hit the news, but u
generally government agencies calibrate
at 20 about 202.
They're It seems to me like they're
integrous because the law insisted they
that they be that way,
but they're not happy about it.
Nor nor do you get much helpfulness or
cheerfulness about it.
It's like you're at the Motor Vehicle
Bureau. You forgot to sign on line six.
You got got to go back at the end of the
line.
Not just, you know, why not sign here
and hand it to me. No, you got to go
back to the end of the line because you
can I mean, where's the heart? You know
what I'm saying? That's 200. Listen,
that's my job. I have my I know my job.
I have my job and I do my job. That's
200. I know my job and I do my job.
and uh you can't fire them cuz they're
doing their job,
but you're not happy to be with them and
they don't seem to be happy with who
they are or what their job is. But
anyway, so it's preuncter. 200 is
preuncter. It's integris. If it says you
got to be there from 8 to 5, by god
they're there from 8 to 5. And it says
if your job is to run this computer and
run these lists through you, that's what
they do. So, it's dependable in that,
you know, it complies with the
requirements of the job description,
but it doesn't offer much beyond that.
Cheerfulness is is something else. You
know, when you when you when you phone
around these various companies, you get
some of you get an 800 number and then
you get bounced around on this endless
thing and then sometimes you get into a
a circle. Do you ever get one of those?
punch six and that takes you to the menu
and then menu gives you six is your only
way out of the menu.
This takes you back to the menu. Uh I
don't think that's even 200. Do you?
I always say you know the application of
the levels of consciousness to business
are quite profound. Um, a few people who
have been here, a few few people few
people few people few people few people
few people few we we work with uh are
endeavoring to take spiritual teaching
into the commerce and industry business
as long as you don't label it spiritual
religious or god you get away with it
you can take it in the back door by
calling it integrity that builds
customer confidence which shows up in
the bottom line and by and and it does
mali Rodriguez who's a friend of ours
had written a chapter in the book on she
had been a nun and uh left the the
cloistered life and teaches spiritual
principles to big corporations.
Her own corporation got wiped out in
9/11 disaster. Her own corporation was
heavily involved in the World Trade
Center there and got wiped out. But
uh spiritual premises if you take them
into business are very rewarding.
Ours is a non is a secular society in in
you know on one level it's secular
operationally it's secular so you can't
talk about things in spiritual terms and
religious terms
but you can take the basic principles
into business and as Mgalli demonstrated
and the she has the facts and figures in
the chapter she did in the book that I'm
quoting uh it actually shows up in the
bottom line in power versus force I used
Walmart as an example
uh because I had corresponded with Sam
and I recognized the integrity Sam's
ideal was integrity uh integrous uh
products by integrous people and
integrous surroundings
and um
and his idea of treating employees was
considerate and etc. So he seemed to
have heart. So let's see where Walmart
is today. Can we do Walmart today? We
have permission to do Walmarts today. Is
this I do Walmart at the time of Sam
Walton? Walmart at the time of Sam
Walton is over 350 380 390.
Walmart at the time of Sam Walton was
385 390 385. Remember where 385 is on
our list. It's up there.
It beats 200.
It beats 200. I'd rather walk into Sam
Sam Walton's business than uh the
nearest motor vehicle bureau.
So, all right. Here was uh here's where
Sam took it. He took it up here to uh
harmonious, hopeful, satisfactory.
Uh you can trust in them, made in
America, optimistic, the future's going
to be better.
Forgiveness, we don't ask any questions.
Bring it back. We give you a refund or a
replacement. That's a pretty darn uh
high level of consciousness, isn't it?
What do we say Walmart was at the time
of Sam? What was the number? What was
the number we got? 385.
>> Okay.
>> 385.
>> 385. All right. Um we have permission to
do this in this audience. Is this
Walmart's at this time is um below 385.
Resist.
It's about 325 330.
All right.
Uh this last week's issue of Fortune
magazine had a big article on Walmart
and it said uh that Walmart isn't
exactly as as great as it was at the
time of Sam.
I thought they were nitpicking a little
bit,
but you know, Walmarts has become a
giant colossus. It's hard to keep that
folksy rural atmosphere
when you're the biggest retailer in the
world.
How to keep it folksy when you've got
Walmart now has 1 million employees. Can
you believe a company that has 1 million
employees and a major outlet in every
major city in America and now crossing
the world in Asia and all I guess you go
to Walmarts in Hong Kong. So,
but anyway, he built what has become the
largest, most successful retailing
experience in human history. And he did
it from the integrity of 385.
So, anybody who questions whether or not
spiritual values have any serious
application to business, I only have to
look at Walmart. It's funny, a writer
for the Wall Street Journal called us
up,
I don't know, it was a month or two ago,
right? Yeah. Writing an article on this
subject wanting my views on it, the
value of spiritual principles in
the corporate world. And I referred them
to Mgalli's article. And uh
so to answer the question, do spiritual
values have any uh practical application
in the everyday world? Well, we just
tell them, "Look at Walmart and see for
yourself."
Would you rather go to Walmart or would
you rather go and renew your license to
the nearest motor vehicle?
I like Wally World or whatever you call
it, you know. You know, cuz in the front
they always have coffee and sandwiches
you can sit on and put your feet up and
they always have the great bargains and
they try to express everything in
Spanish and be uh you know as as there
for the American public as they can be.
Uh anyway
uh
and government bureaus is um as I said
the United States is always being
surprised and u it's always being
surprised because it doesn't know
anything and it doesn't know anything
because it it comes out of the
intellectualism of a political position.
What is it that amendment that forbid
the CIA from employing people with a
criminal background? Toretelli
principle. Was that a name? The governor
from or congressman from some state.
It was sort of um deadly dooright kind
of dogooderism kind of a boy scouty idea
that people with known criminal past
should not be getting paid by the CIA to
go out there and far out of information.
Anybody who's worked ever worked for the
police department knows that's your only
source of information. Who the hell do
you think's going to tell you? Who do
you think's going to tell you they're
planning to rob the bank next door? Mrs.
Simpson or behind you? I
She works at Walmart. She's not
How's she going to know they're planning
a robbery?
Oh god. To find out about criminals, you
have to deal with the criminal element.
Anybody knows that. So that that
principle which came out of the downside
of intellectualism
and idealism,
utopianism,
uh is why the United States is always
being surprised. We always walk into the
booby trap and the excuse is always we
didn't know it was there.
Pearl Harbor was the f, you know,
glaring example. every single battle
since then. We didn't know that there
was 50,000 Nazi troops behind the
mountain. Well, what do you mean you
didn't know?
How can you not know? You know, if
you're at war, how can you not know?
You'd better know. I wanted all those
people to give back their salary to the
American taxpayer, frankly, to not know
what was there at the Bay of Pigs.
So the the the not knowingness is coming
out of the downside of the 400s.
It's mixing up utopia a hope for. So the
far-left
intellectual position in my view of it
is is the child that's the wishful child
who's um believes in fairyland.
We should talk to bin Laden.
And problem is you get blown up by mines
trying to get to Von Laden to talk to
him. And if he captures you, you
probably torture you to death because
they like chopping up people and hearing
them scream.
Why do they enjoy torturing people to
death? Why not just execute them?
Because you don't get up in the
hierarchy in the lower astral unless you
can just demonstrate
your capacity for heartless cruelty.
That's how you get to be a kingpin
in the mafia. You're not a made guy
until you kill somebody in front of
witnesses.
Now they know you're a fellow denison of
hell. You've proven it.
And now you can be trusted to a certain
level.
All right. So the government agencies if
you calibrate them all it's pretty
disappointing. U the FBA FAA for
instance extremely low. If you calibrate
what is the level of integrity of the
agency as an agency you will get usually
get around 200.
If you then then we discovered but what
is the calibrated level of their
everyday functioning in the world and
then you get a disappointment. Although
the FAA may calibrate as an agency in
its structure, formal structure
bureaucracy at 200. What does it operate
at?
There's the disparity. Resist. The
disparity is over 50 points. Resist. Oh
my god. Uh, we have permission to ask
the FAA resist. The FAA as a
bureaucratic agency calibrates over 200.
Resist. Oh, it doesn't. Oh, calibrates
over 198. Oh my god, it's gotten worse.
Last time we did this, I think it was
200. It's over 198 199. It's not quite
integrous even at the bureaucratic
level.
>> Now, let's get what it is at the
operational level. It's the F FAA that
sets the standards for who should be
hired to run their hands all over you as
you walk in. Right. They just got the
bright idea lately that women should do
women and then men. I mean, that's duh.
I mean, that's really bright, huh?
The FAA operationally is over 140.
>> So all right, let's say the structure is
integrous, but the way it is instituted
is totally non-integrous
and you can tell by the everyday news
the way the FAA functions. What's the
name of that company that um hired all
the um
>> criminals? No, the the people who check
you over before you go on the plane, it
was called something bright. Argan
bright. Okay.
>> Well, the people that check you out when
you go through the X-ray and all
were all hired by Arganbrite resist.
Arganite Corporation. Yeah. Arganbrite
calibrates. We have permission to do
Argan Bright Resist. Calibrates over
160.
Argan bright doesn't even calibrate over
So, here's the people you're trusting
your life to. Thank you.
>> Here's the people you're trusting your
life to. Calibrates over 160. Not
integrity. You know what I mean? The way
down the scale here, you know, the way
down the way down in here and you're
getting on the plane saying, "I trust my
life to this guy.
Oh, golly.
I can't imagine that they only just got
the smart idea that women should check
out women and men." I mean, you know, it
was on the thing for weeks and I thought
sitting there I think that'd be simple,
wouldn't it? It
>> you better quit talking about this. No
one's going to come hear you again.
>> What?
>> You better quit talking about it or no
one's going to come hear you.
>> Why is that?
>> They won't get on a plane.
>> Oh, they won't get on a plane.
All right. Then they ask other famous
people. Uh yeah. So there a lot a lot
can be learned. Um, and and once you
once you see the panorama, it's like
you've got the map of of human
civilization. And when you calibrate,
you know, Henry VIII, U,
Julius Caesar,
um,
Franklin Delano Roosevelt,
uh, Churchill, you begin to see the
enormous
Churchill calibrated at 510. Churchill
FDR calibrated at 499. Most of the
presidents of the United States
calibrate in the 450s.
To be an effective cal, you can ask what
is the requirement of this office. The
requirement to be an effective president
of the United States is what 450.
Happily, almost all of our presidents
have been 450 or over or 460. Anyway, it
takes 450. If you ask what does it take
to run a giant world church, the pope
for instance, the ideal for a religious
leader to run a world organization such
as the Catholic Church is around 570.
If you go to 600, you're going to bliss
out the heck with the church. You're not
going to pay attention.
You have to have a lot of organizational
ability, a lot of political moxy, a lot
of knowingness. You got to be able to
deal with all the head the heads of
state. You have to do this in the in the
context of a religious history that goes
back thousands of years and is under
fire etc. in a complex political state.
So you need around 570.
570 is almost saintly. If you watch this
present pope as he tries to make peace
with the various factions around the
world, you get the sense of pres. You
get a sense of presence and the current
pope calibrates around 570 resist. Okay.
The Dalai Lama serves the same function,
a world function as the leader of a
world church and all that it represents.
The Dalai Lama is also around 570.
So when you get what are presidents um
Mother Teresa is about 700.
Uh
>> what about Bush?
>> Bush is around 460 or so. He's a bra,
you know, he's a Yale graduate and a
very smart man. 455 460 465. Yeah, he's
around 460.
That that's a bright president. In other
words, uh it's you got to be smart.
You have to deal in the world of form,
politics, power,
uh, bureaucracy, fundraising,
um, charm,
um, and the verbal capacity. You have to
have verbal fluency. You can't get up in
front of a TV audience and bumble,
uh, and get elected unless you're Bush.
See, because Bush comes Bush does it out
of a certain context. You know, the man
is integrous on the level that he
represents. You may or may not agree
with his level, but he does come out of
an old-fashioned uh right or wrong
Christian oriented
uh good old Texas boy. Uh the good guys
go there and the bad guys goes there.
What's the confusion? You know what I
mean?
So he gets away with it because of his
integrity on the moral level. See, if he
was running for president of Harvard, he
wouldn't get away with it because there
moral integrity is not a
is not a requirement. Did I was that
said by this entity here?
No. The president of a university has a
diff a different requirement. See? So,
you can't say that one level is better
than another. You'd have to say better
for what? Otherwise, we're comparing
apples and oranges.
Um,
the highest calibrated um unit in that
we got in World War II was the Tuskegee
Air Force. The Tuskegee Air Force had
the most perfect record, greatest number
of kills, smallest number of losses. It
was an all black. They were all black
airmen
and they calibrate extremely high. Well,
you had to be extremely high if you were
black in order to get into the Air
Force. So, these were all highlevel
people in which intention was extremely
powerful and they set up one of the
greatest records in World War II.
So, you learn a great deal by studying
history, calibrating the levels of the
various events. You can calibrate the
level of the events. You can with
kinesiology find out exactly what
happened.
Was the US informed before Pearl Harbor
or not? Who was informed? What did they
do with it and why? So I don't like to
do a lot of these things in public.
But um what goes on behind the scenes is
accessible because anything
is registered in the field of
consciousness is available to
kinesiology.
When you ask a question of kinesiology,
you you know, we ask permission and uh
sometimes you'll get a no. Sometimes
you'll get a flat no. Uh sometimes
you'll get uh if you try to find out the
why of the no, you may or may not find
out the why of no. Usually you'll find
out the why of the no. Sometimes you
won't even get the why of the no.
Yeah. We said that the time of death is
karmically set.
Can you find out the time of your own
death? You you you'll get always got the
answer no.
It's a general fact, but in your
particular to know yourself is not
allowed. It just says it's not allowed.
Am I allowed to know the exact time and
date of my own death? It says no.
It would probably have a dilitterious
effect, wouldn't it? Probably have a
delotterious effect.
and churches would be loaded though if
everybody knew.
>> So anyway, we can check out the great
gurus of history. As I said, a lot of
the great gurus uh uh are not as living
beings what they were at their highest
of their writings because
um
you might say that that which is in
contrast to that which you become which
as a spiritual teacher I guess I have to
cover. You see as you go up in levels of
consciousness you begin to pull to
yourself that which challenges it that
which challenges it.
Um
there are certain levels
I don't know if I should maybe we should
do that in the book I'm doing now
another chapter there there are certain
levels at which rather specific things
come at you and I think a spiritual
teacher should prepare it's a
responsibility of a spiritual spiritual
teacher to inform you of the downside
unconditional love seems to trigger you
go into a state of joy
seems to seems to bring up
its opposite choice.
In this particular
experience,
that which brought it up was quite
surprising. It comes up suddenly
out of nowhere.
It can come up through a person. This
person I was speaking to was a spiritual
teacher well known and well known
locally in fact who who had uh described
an excellent spiritual technique.
Um,
and this teacher then said, well, we
won't go that's later in the story.
Anyway, at that in that all of a sudden
this spiritual teacher, oh, I know what
it was. uh wanted me to be director of
the this organization nationwide, you
know, and uh I said, "Wow, we can give
it to all the monks and all the
monasteries and just think of all the
people struggling with sin and sin is
just an attachment." If you know how to
release the attachment, sin disappears.
You know, sin is just a
porative
epithet with which we describe certain
behaviors. But these these the behaviors
are just attachments.
So I wanted to give it to the world. I
thought, "Oh, wow." You know, give the
world a way to free yourself from guilt
and sin and all this crap. At this
point, the teacher suddenly went into a
rage.
The teacher's personality disappeared
and it was like an entity from hell. It
was a horrible energy and suddenly began
to speak in another voice and said and
said
Jesus and Buddha are just astrals.
You should never give away spiritual
truth.
I think is only as good as what you pay
for it. The higher the truth, the more
the charge.
He began to describe certain
industrialists as having done more for
mankind than Jesus Christ and Buddha
because they were just astrals anyway.
Uh and then the conversation got even
dumber got even dumber.
The temptation is in that case was
uh the temptation as you go up seems to
be
um best described as luciferic. Satanic
has to do with pain, suffering, war. The
satanic energies,
rape, pillillage, drugs, uh devastation,
inner city, street gangs, the satanic
rules there. Exxon, the luciferic,
that's power for its own sake. And the
manifestation of power is financial
gain. And what happens uh on that level
of consciousness was
the a knowingness came to me. A
knowingness this was beyond
this was um oh I know this was uh the
experimentation with going into the void
that which is the void uh in this
lifetime was triggered again. And the
way you get to the void of nothingness
is by releasing on the attributes of
God. Seeing love as an attachment,
beauty,
the grace of God is as attachments that
are holding you back from the ultimate
truth. The luciferic persuasion can
sound quite convincing. I'm just
abbreviating it now. But the way it went
was the way it came. It came as a
knowingness.
There was nobody there. But the
knowingness came
as an expression now that you know
you're beyond personal karma because at
that point one it's beyond form was
quite an enlightened state. Let's see
what the level that temptation came at.
That temptation came at over 600 650 700
720 about 720. All right. The
knowingness was now that you know you're
beyond personal karma
because
you're not answerable to any arbitrary
god because no such god exists and
you've already transcended
identification with all of form in the
human ego.
Therefore own infinite power as your
own.
Well,
it came across at a very as a very
convincing understanding
obviously had been
uh presented to many others in the past
and uh this was a rather erid it was
almost like compared to a high mountain
pass. No one there
no one hardly ever been there and I
could see who had been there and what
answer they had given.
The the appeal was infinite power. Power
over others. Power for its own sake.
Power for its own sake. The only of
course what's wrong with it was it was
completely devoid of love. No love. Just
power to own power for its own sake is
apparently a temptation. So the
spiritual student who is not prepared
for it goes into a very high state
begins to pull up its
uh I'm going to call it contrary not its
opposite but it's contrary it's contrary
choice. So to choose power for its own
sake then is the temptation of the
luciferic when you get to a very high
level.
The luciferic is the temptation of power
for its own sake. usually expressed in
our domain as wealth wealth.
So Enron is the expression of the
luciferic.
The satanic would be Adolf Hitler. The
luciferic is money and wealth and power
and position for its own sake. For its
own sake. The satanic would use that to
cause suffering to others. So Nazi
Germany,
the Japanese and Nan King uh
exhibit the satanic energy.
So the temptation then can be can come
up and you're unprepared for it and the
ingenuity with which it can be
presented. I am underplaying it can be
extremely in ingenuous ingenuous.
It's been probably been developed for
thousands of years by various entities
who rule over other domains. And what
they're really inviting you to is to
join their domain and become one of
them. Just as the mafia invites you to
become a made guy by executing this guy
in front of witnesses.
They invite you to enjoy and become part
of the satanic lower astral realm.
So those things apparently happen to
various people at various times. It can
happen to to people within the secular
domain as well as within the spiritual
domain. In calibrating the levels of
consciousness of people throughout time
as we said um Napoleon started out quite
high then fell to the megalomania.
So the other temptation is that of
vanity
the vanity of megalomania.
If we said that the top of the levels of
consciousness is God, then the bottom is
the ego.
The bottom is the ego and the
glorification of the ego as God.
This the I the small A to glorify the
small A
to worship the small I is to become the
egoomaniac.
So when Mallosovich
feels not the slightest contrition
feels it's his perfect right to destroy
millions of people merely because they
disagree with him or represent he's
something he doesn't like. Uh this is
the expression of megalamania. So the
ego
the unbridled ego then when it is
glorified
becomes the opposite of God.
which entitles the person to go to the
lower astral domains.
So their person then is there by choice
by denying the reality of God and
declaring that the ego is God that makes
the eye the small eye the center of the
ego God instead of divinity is God. So
that's how one gets to the bottom
instead of the top.
Um the difficulty with religions has has
been their confusion of the top with the
bottom. And as I've said before, the Old
Testament is the source of that. The old
if you check out the Old Testament with
kinesiology,
all all the books of the Old Testament
make you go weak with the exception of
three, Proverbs, Psalms, and Genesis.
All the rest make you go extremely weak.
And in the New Testament, of course,
Revelations calibrates at 70.
Its author is John.
Let's let's see what the source of
revelations is. We have permission in
this audience. Resist. The source of
revelations is a fellow named John.
Resist. He calibrates his 70. Resist.
And what he had was a hallucination and
vision of the lower astral domain.
Resist. Okay. So all these predictors,
these uh revelations of horrors, the
California falling off in the ocean, the
end times
is all true, but it's only true within
the astral domain. So
one thing a spiritual student has to be
clear is that the what applies to the
astral domain applies to the astral
domain in which there's a replica of
this world as we know it, but it has a
different karma. It's ruled by different
energies and entities. So what is
predicted for the astral domain is not
what is predicted for this earth. And
there's a number of teachers around
Sedona who've had the same vision,
shared the same vision.
Everybody got ready for the end times,
dug underground homes, etc., etc.
Waiting for the end times. California
did not fall off the ocean. The end
times did not occur. So to not realize
which domain you're speaking of to be
clear if confused you can check with
kinesiology.
The end times is describing a different
domain. Is it just it's a different
domain.
The if you experience that domain you
experience it as reality.
It's not like imagination.
It's when you're in that domain, then
you experience the experience of that
domain as a reality.
A person who slips because of brain
chemistry over into that reality
experiences that as though it is
actually happening.
And the reason you can't get them out of
saying that they experienced it as
really happening is because they did
experience it as really happening.
A dream is real when you're in the
dream. A nightmare is a nightmare is an
experiential reality. In the middle of
the nightmare, you are experiencing that
nightmare as a reality.
But that nightmare is not the same as
the waking domain of reality is of
course the differentiation between the
two.
So a lot of the spiritual errors that
have arisen uh religious errors
have arisen because of lack of capacity
to know one domain from another.
So the lower astral domains just like
the higher are ruled by entities. Each
of them have names.
So
the gods of the celestial regions have
names and so do the gods of the lower
astral regions.
Strict and narrow is the pathway. The
Buddha was correct. Strict strict and
and narrow is the pathway.
The Buddha also describes similar
temptations. Jesus Christ describes
similar temptations. The Lucifer came to
him directly the same. It was exactly
the same. Undoubtedly the same entity,
same energy. Is that the same energy?
It's not an entity. It's an energy
resist. It's an energy resist. It's a
Let's see. We have permission to ask if
it's an entity resist.
Uh it's an entity resist. It's not an
entity. No, it's a knowingness of a
certain energy field and it comes into
your consciousness that way. Remember
Jesus was tempted by
Lucifer? Was it
the devil? somebody
yeah uh offered him power over uh this
domain and the Buddha describes similar
temptations.
So
what I'm trying to convey
from experience
as well as available literature,
the spiritual student is often naive.
You know, wanders off in the desert with
a pint of water and a pair of sandals.
It takes more than a pint of water and a
pair of sandals to reach enlightenment.
It's a strict and narrow pathway. It's
rigorous. It's demanding. It's beset
with pitfalls. That which is in the
lower astral, its greatest pleasure is
to pull people off the straight and
narrow. The fact that you're on the
straight and narrow is what makes you a
nice prize, a nice plump one to pull off
with one temptation or another. That's
the source of glee of the demonic is
that they've seduced an innocent one. To
kill the innocent is the way you rise in
lower astral. It's by killing innocent
babies, you really get to be somebody.
Take a bayonet and bayonet the child and
the infant in the mother's arms gets you
really up in the hierarchy. Gets you
higher than the mafia.
Mafia only kills bad guys. Try killing
an innocent baby. That'll really get you
there, baby. You got to be cold,
heartless, cruel,
the ultimate of the opposite of
goodness.
So all these various realms have their
own hierarchies.
They're complex. They have their own
literature.
There are a lot there's a lot of
well-known books in the spiritual
bookstore which all of you know. You've
all run into them.
Let's ask about uh what's that one? I
have permission to ask about that book
in the science resist. Uh the uranche
book calibrates over 200.
Uranchia is a well-known book. It's a
channeling from some other domain
in the Uranchia hierarchy of beings and
teachers is even Jesus Christ.
All right. So before you get enamored of
any spiritual teaching, calibrate the
energy field of the teaching. And the
other thing you can ask is whether it's
suitable for me. It may be a very high
teaching and I say is that suitable for
me? He says no.
Why? Because at this level I would
misinterpret it. It would be injurious.
So the willingness to surrender to God
means to
let's say operationally if you get a no
from a kinesiologic question to question
why come up with an answer and then the
willingness to comply with it.
All pathways are pathways through the
heart because all pathways are the
willingness to surrender.
Um the ego's
um
the ego's delusion that it is capable of
knowing reality.
The ego is not capable of knowing
reality. By definition,
the ego can't know reality. By reality
with a capital R.
By definition,
it's a telescope that doesn't go that
far. You know what I mean? It's a 12x
telescope
and you're trying to see into the next
galaxy. You can't see the next galaxy
with a 12x. You know what I mean?
Okay. Anybody got any questions? We
covered a lot of stuff and enough to
offend at least half a dozen people,
right?
If we hit your favorite spiritual
teacher and found out that he's only 42,
well,
somebody's got to tell you,
you see, spiritual disillusionment is
very, very painful. To become enamored
of a certain teacher and then later
discover that teacher is not integrous
is horrible. It's really horrible. These
people, I've seen some in the office,
some I've known in the spiritual
community. These people almost to the
brink of suicide. It's worse than a
marital infidelity. It's worse than the
boss telling lies behind your back. It's
like the the ultimate
um
double crossing. It's like the double
and you discover that the person you
thought you know there's all kinds of
gurus that calibrate below 200 and I've
traveled a little bit around the
spiritual circuit myself and you see
pictures of this guru there and there
and incense is going and hearts and
flowers and fruit and the guy calibrates
120. You know what I'm saying?
Takes more than sandals, incense, and
robes and shaved head and sitting on
tiger skin to make a guru.
We're running out of tiger skin. So that
used to be you always had to sit on a
tiger skin and be half naked.
>> Could you speak a little bit about right
livelihood?
>> You're talking about integrity.
You know, the Buddha was a teacher about
right livelihood. one of the eight-fold
pathway.
It means that the to be integrous in
one's endeavors within the world by
which you make a living.
He recommended that you not be a butcher
and things like that that the
accumulated negative karma of constantly
killing life in return for money was
would undo a great deal of spiritual
merit.
Buddhism and fire language tend to talk
of merit, you know, spiritual merit.
So integrity has to do with intention.
We said a spiritual spiritual level of a
uh has to do with intention. The
spiritual will. When you do spiritual
work, you're really doing it from the
center of your spiritual will.
So you want to get away from thinking
there's a personal eye doing that.
There's no personal eye there.
Consciousness is impersonal. You make a
decision
from your spiritual will. It's your
spiritual will because your spiritual
will has infinite power. Your spiritual
will is is unstoppable.
Spiritual will will allow you get burned
at the stake and you won't flinch an
inch from what you believe in. That
takes spiritual will. The ego doesn't
have that kind of strength. The mind
doesn't have that kind of strength.
Spiritual will though is extremely
powerful. That's why the Buddhist said
once you have heard of enlightenment the
end is certain. Once you've even heard
of enlightenment the end is certain
because once the spiritual will he hear
hears that enlightenment is possible. It
clicks onto it and now it begins to
reorganize the intention of all the
intricacies of the ego and somehow you
just find yourself in the right place
and moving in a certain direction.
That's the result of spiritual will. So
integrity then is a decision.
The reason I I used Sam Walner's example
was because he seemed to represent in a
widely experiential experiential
way the value of integrity in business
because of that integrity which radiates
out the consumer has confidence that if
it's broken and you take it back they'll
give you another one. And of course
experientially I have done that and by
God they do give you another one.
If they can't give you another one they
fix it. So at least there is the
intention of integrity. So integrity is
extremely important and I think in the
spiritual community in government in
government it would be profoundly
unworkable.
I don't know how you going to get
reelected if you're going to be
integrous. You know what I mean? If you
I mean it's that um pork barrel law that
gets you the uh votes and if you're
going to be integrous and no we don't
need a road that goes 300 miles into the
desert and then stops in a pile of sand
then you would have to be honest and how
would you get elected? So
some some variance with uh integrity is
necessary on certain levels.
>> So what is the difference between the
illumination and enlightenment?
between what illumination
>> and enlightenment
>> generally illuminated refers to it I
think 600 and over it's denoted in art
usually as a halo if you calibrate the
energy level with a halo that which it
signifies is 1,000
saintthood uh or above
uh
the general public would say that
anybody into the high 500s is is
already illuminated. The saintly person,
we think of the saintly person
uh as reflecting the light of divinity
by their patience and all the classic
virtues patience and tolerance and
truthfulness and integrity
illumination. Let's go for I I I think
we had illumination on here on that
little chart.
>> Yeah, it's
>> Did we
600?
>> 600.
>> Oh, it is. Yeah. Okay. Okay. Let's just
ask. We have permission to ask.
Illumination is over 550, 580, 590, 599,
600, 601. Yeah. 600 is a level of
illumination.
It's because the presence of the self is
felt like a light. It's seen as the
light of consciousness. It's
You're conscious of that which in
ordinary life you take for granted and
never realize what it is. You never look
at it. Just like in this room, you're
aware of the contents of the room, but
you're not aware of the space in the
room. I mean, your focus is not on the
space here. Your sp your focus is on the
content.
Um, enlightenment becomes that you're
aware of the field. You're aware of the
field itself out of which the content
becomes meaningful. It's because of the
nonform of the field that the full world
of form makes any sense. It is by virtue
of that which is nonlinear that anything
linear can be discerned.
If space wasn't full of nothingness, you
couldn't see somethingness in it.
That sounds all right, folks.
Yeah.
>> What's the relationship between
beingness and consciousness?
>> Between beingness and what?
>> Consciousness.
>> Well,
consciousness is um the quality
that would allow the awareness of
beingness. The fact that you realize
know that you are.
Let's ask about the cat.
Kitty knows that he is resist
the cat knows that it is.
So you might say that's primordial,
right? Primordial.
It is by virtue of consciousness that
Kitty is aware that he is
Kitty has consciousness which comes out
of
existence.
Uh kitty has knowingness of existence.
Kitty has capacity to identify it.
Resist. No. Can't identify it but knows
that it is. When you look in into any
animal's eyes, it's instantly obvious
that it knows that it is. It knows that
it is.
It's aware of existence.
Did I answer the question?
I was thinking about it a different kind
of way, I guess.
>> What' you say?
>> She was thinking about it in a different
way.
>> Oh,
>> you see existence is a statement.
Beingness being is a transitive verb.
Intransitive verb. Sorry. Intransitive
verb.
isness, beingness, havingness, isness,
uh, are all verbs. In a verb, there has
to be a this and a that.
When you add beingness or amness,
you're saying that there is something
that has that quality.
That's why amnness has not been one has
not described to me what the ultimate
reality is.
Amnness
implies that there is something that has
that quality of beingness. That's what
an entritive verb means.
That implies a duality which is not my
own experience of reality which is
non-duality.
The radical truth is there is no this
experiencing that such as a quality of
beingness or isness.
That awareness is illuminated by virtue
of consciousness itself.
So that statement came out of
consciousness about beingness. Come on
up here and we'll discuss it and put up
your dukes.
Okay, let's have it again.
>> Okay. Um,
you indicated that at 600 and above, the
higher levels of consciousness, that the
the body would become incapacitated
basically.
>> Well, not that the body's incapacitated
>> to the point where it would need help to
exist.
>> It's more that um one's indifferent to
it.
The state is so complete and perfect.
Then there is no wantingness.
You see to move something you have to
have a wantingness.
All wantingness disappears.
Nothing you want.
>> The physical functions still are still
there. As far as
>> they seem to operate in a in a delayed
way. I think uh
many of the basic um physiologic
functions do stop.
Um breathing will even stop and only if
somebody intreats you do you breathe
again.
Yeah. Uh
>> well well in Jesus and and
>> so 50% of the people don't forget leave
the leave the body at that point. They
don't bother breathing again.
>> So
>> and I had no interest in breathing
again.
>> But somebody love me a great deal. I
could see that he believed that I would
be dead if I didn't breathe.
Because of his belief that I would be
dead, I breathed.
>> Okay.
>> Otherwise, you would be in grief.
>> So did did Jesus and Krishna and Buddha
have physical functions then when they
were at a thousand say level of
consciousness? Well, the Buddha had a
great deal of difficulty and uh
uh it's I only u
felt relieved about it when in Korea uh
there was a Buddhist u Bible in the
hotel room
and Susan's reading and she says the
Buddhist said he was racked with pain
and all his bones were cracked and all.
I said, "Oh, wow. That explains the
whole thing. No problem."
Um
let's see what happened with Jesus.
Well, don't forget they're different.
There are different karmic patterns.
Um the Jesus never spoke of uh he only
spoke of enlightenment in one place in
Matthew. He says Isaiah has returned to
us as John the Baptist.
Now I don't know whether he meant that
literally as a reincarnation of John the
Baptist or he meant the spirit that
spirit which prevailed in
>> Elias is the same spirit that prevailed.
I didn't know whether he meant physical
reincarnation or not but certainly
neither karma or reincarnation karma as
such is a topic as understood in the
eastern world is a subject in
Christianity.
Jesus Christ had no previous physical
lifetimes.
He he never had any personal physical
human karma.
As it says in scripture, he literally
did descend from heaven. Huh. The
Buddha, on the other hand, had had many
previous lifetimes and recall them great
clarity. And then anybody who was over
600, it's just a memory. It's not like
another lifetime. It's all one
continuity in which you remember being
in Cleveland, you remember being in
Honolulu and
>> Okay,
>> it's just a memory. See,
>> what was the rest of the question?
>> That was pretty much the question.
>> I I think you did a good elaboration.
>> Yes. Whether a person can function. Yes.
Right.
>> Well, as I say, half the people at 600
don't function. And uh
it's karmic
propensity.
It happened several times that if there
had not been some both of them had to do
with love. The uh experience in the
snowbank there was no desire to breathe
or re uh
reenter the body or become one with the
body again. There was no interest in the
body and uh I mean the state is complete
and total. There's no need for a body,
desire for a body. There's no no
physicality that has any appeal.
And the f my father had discovered uh
discovered where I was get traced the
paper wrote and uh we had a 29 model
Ford. It's hysterical 29 model for which
we' paid $15 by the way and dad found
me. So here is just shaking my knee and
uh I'm asked to do that which I did not
want to do more than anything. But if I
had not resumed breathing and come back
to it, come back to the body, he would
have thought I was dead. He believed in
the body, you know, if the body's dead,
you're dead. So I could see he believes
that I would be dead, which would cause
great grieving. And I love my father a
great deal. Don't breathe.
And it happened another time similarly.
Somebody who loved me a great deal. See,
the people around you all believe in
death.
So, it makes it very hard to leave your
body if you have any close friends,
associates, wife or something because
they're going to grieve and miss you
because they think you're dead.
And therefore,
600 and over, it's probably best to be a
monk living off by yourself.
And and if you don't breathe again, they
will figure that you probably had a
heart attack or something and everybody
be fine.
>> Yes.
>> Is it important for you to know what
level you are and um what what would be
the most important thing one could do
each day to to uh either maintain or
increase their conc?
>> You see in describing these uh these
levels you can pretty much guess where
you are without you know using
kinesiology. You can tell what are the
devils that besiege you. You see uh what
is the primary emotionality?
What is your view of yourself and what
is your view of God? Pretty much tells
you where you are. You know what I mean?
God hates me. I'm depressed all the
time. I hate myself. I can hardly get
out of bed in the morning. Well, you're
about 50, aren't you? Right.
On the other hand, I'm in love with
life. I hate to waste time just being
asleep in bed. I can't wait to jump out
till 4:30 in the morning. And I'm in
love with nature and animals and every
animal I see. I just love it. You have
to control yourself because that does
happen.
Luckily, you don't run into any tigers
cuz you would probably hug the tiger.
You know, you just love that tiger. I
love that tiger. Love that tiger.
Yeah,
you can pretty much know where you are.
Um it's sort of academic interest you
know like this audience is obvious
without even calibrating it you know in
the mid 400s in the people you know
people who tend to think like this you
know are are usually quite ariodite and
already are pretty well know pretty
knowledgeable and pretty well intended
you know to take out a whole day of your
time and devoted you know people who are
not interested in enlightenment really
aren't going to blow a whole day
and they could be watching baseball on
TV or something.
Yes.
>> Um, could you speak to Saba? I have a
friend that really
crushed by the current status of
the current status.
>> How do I do them?
>> Uh, you speak.
>> I I don't think I want to do living
babas that are You can do it on your own
and be prepared for whatever you find
out.
Can you tell me what is happening with
those who claim to hear
um guides and teachers and so forth?
>> Uh I have not known many people like
that. Um
um
you know when you speak of visions,
divine entities, hearing God's voice,
it's not within my experience.
You see, because
divinity, that which is God, is not
different than the self. So who would
there be to speak to whom? You see
that's in other words in
in duality there's a this and a that.
There would be a this being spoken to by
a that
not that is not the experience that has
been here. There is no this and a that.
There is no other to speak to this.
Um the advancing awareness because the
the awareness does advance from 600 on
up. you know, astonishing things just
come out of the blue
is coming from within. It's
annoyingness. It's like a cauliflower
that's grown a new thing. It's coming
from itself. It's not of a different
essence. That which grows out of the
cauliflower is just the essence of
cauliflowerness, you know. It's not an
otherness.
It's not like a beantock creates a
cauliflower. You see, so
with nurturance and for some karmic
reason that un that that awareness, that
knowledgeness, that knowingness,
the realization is one really of
comprehension,
the capacity to how to contextualize it
so that you can say it.
It doesn't change the reality of that
which you are or that which you're
experiencing itself because that's total
and complete. It doesn't need any
understandings
to be. However, if you're committed to
teaching then the capacity to be able to
fluently language that and explain it.
So comes the mo the awareness. Wow. The
Buddha never spoke previous lifetimes
because he never had me.
This is how we did it. Oh,
>> the Buddha. Wait a minute. I'm sorry.
Jesus Christ never had any previous
physical lifetimes. Resist. That was
just a knowingness.
You know, I don't need that. No. Doesn't
change who or what I am or what what the
reality is. Um the Buddha, however, did
resist.
Isn't that fascinating? I mean, it's
interesting the fact that there's multi-
dimensions. The fact that there's multi-
heavens, multiple heavens. So all the
people that you think are on mistaken
pathways, you couldn't worry about them.
They're all going to heaven. Yeah,
there's Valhalla. There's all these
heavens. If a kamicazi pilot does it for
the sake of the emperor, for the sake of
um truth, for the sake of the sun god,
Shintoism is the son god of whom the
emperor is the divine representative. If
he's doing it for the divinity of God as
represented in Shintoism by his emperor,
then why shouldn't he go to an integrous
place? He did it out of integrity.
Right? We might say he's mistaken. We
might say that uh that the um Islamic
terrorists are mistaken. I don't know.
I've never checked whether where they're
going to go, but
they didn't tell them the 72 versions
are all 900 years old. I told him that
joke last time
and that joke came out of the blue also.
I didn't make that joke up. People say,
"Did you make that joke up?" No, I'm
riding along the highway and all of a
sudden it breaks me up. So these funnies
that come happen of their own. I have
nothing to do with them and it just
breaks me up. I said, "That's
hysterical." I don't open
I would think too if you actually
believe that killing infidels is a way
of praising Allah I imagine that's
integris
the intention is tegorous resist
the belief system is correct resist
that
what their experience erience of heaven.
In other words, their destination is
preset by their spiritual intention
resist. So their spiritual intention
and you know we could look at it from a
different viewpoint and say it's really
stupid. But um
I mean if Bill Bin Laden killed off
3,000 Americans, he's only got 300
million to go. He better get busy.
You're going to have to kill 3,000 every
second to make any inroads because we
propagate faster than that. Right. Would
other men make them the same as what
tested for?
>> What did she say?
>> Does that
>> he may well yes except that we have
tested him and he's 70 70. So his his
intention his belief system is
different. You see there's those who are
naively
naively zealous and then there's those
who for political reasons use the
naively zealous for their own ends. So
the patriotism
of the soldier is been traditionally
misused throughout history by the
emperor who does it for his own personal
gain and couldn't care less whether
10,000 gets slaughtered. That doesn't
mean the soldier is not integrous. He's
doing it for what he considers the
motherland and his duty as a man and to
his wife and family. And
>> innocence the
>> innocence, right? You got it. So,
innocence is
uh innocence is the big hole in the wall
where the wolf gets in via the sheep's
clothing.
It is the one that the luciferic uses
and the satanic both use.
Um
it's because a man's not knowing truth
from falsehood that he's vulnerable.
See, mankind thinks he's the software.
Actually, he's the hardware,
but he has no protective circuit that
can differentiate. Puts in the software.
There's nothing that goes
falsehood. No, whatever the software,
this sounds as good as this software.
All software sounds good. Otherwise, it
wouldn't sell.
So one reason
uh that enlightenment is statistically
rare statistically rare is because you
first of all have it have to have an
intense commitment. There has to be a
certain karmic setup for it.
You have to have had the good fortune of
running to good teachers. You have to
have fallen into the soup and found a
way out.
You know, this energy fell into the
soup, painful soup. Uh get to the pits
of hell, you got to make some big
errors, right?
Karmically throughout time, some bad
decisions. And then came along the way
out. See? All right. So, integrity is
what carries us through. In business and
spiritual work, our intention is what
carries us through. doesn't mean we
won't make mistakes, but it's very
difficult to make the whole trip. And uh
even the best teachers don't forewarn
some of their students about what
happened. They just notice there aren't
as many there next week.
They don't tell you what happened to
them. We had 18 last week, 14 this week.
What happened to the other four guys
on the road to Damascus? Yeah. Would
that map of consciousness work for after
this life into an astral life?
>> Uh, well, that's another lecture. Death
in the afterlife.
We said that the infinite.
>> Okay, we're going to stop this.
We said that that which is infinite
and manifests itself as all the
universes
is like a giant electromagnetic field in
which through spiritual intention
it's as though you set the polarity and
charge on the little iron filing we call
yourself or your spirit
and Its afterlife is automatically the
consequence
of what it has become by virtue of the
power of the field. That's why the
judgment is God of God is perfect.
Nothing is where it should not be
because it can only be where it is by
virtue of what it is. Therefore, a court
in the water is exactly where it is
based on its buoyancy. What?
>> We have to see where the audience has
moved to now.
>> Oh yes. The level of consciousness of
the group.
>> We have permission to do this in front
of the group. Resist. They're over 435
436 437 438 439 440 441 442.
Went up seven points. Mhm.
You do that every day in a year, you're
going to be
you can open your own church.
Our our our research shows that the uh
the average person we'll just repeat it
because we do this you know the average
person uh consciousness advances five
points in a lifetime or is it five
points in one lifetime? One lifetime.
You know what it takes to go through one
lifetime. all the agony, pitfalls,
pains,
contrition,
penance, god knows what all it takes to
go five points.
At the same time, within a certain field
of consciousness, certain information
becomes like uh catalytic.
I like I like catalytic because
it isn't just what a thing calibrates
at, but its quality, you know, its
quality.
Um, and some information is catalytic.
To just hear it changes it.
If you know that the time of your death
is set, you can say, "Oh, I'm going to
quit worrying about, right?" I mean,
it's a relief just to know that. To know
that there's multiple heavens. You don't
have to be afraid. Gee, maybe I'm
studying the wrong teaching. I'll end up
the wrong place. No, there's heavens for
everybody. See? Um, because intention is
what sends it. Krishna says that in the
Bhagavagita, does he not? Krishna says
from the viewpoint of the supreme he was
at at a thousand he said those that
worship me even though they are mistaken
and call me by other names by virtue of
their devotion will be one with me.
So
that made me feel better when I read
that that the infidel even though I mean
what you know some this one calls this
one infidel by the purity of their
devotion to that which they consider
divine. So the devotion to that which
one considers divinity itself is
sufficient guarantee
to become one with the supreme.
So that's a comforting notion. I believe
in sharing that's which is comforting
and also sharing information
where the edge of the cliff is
where the edge of the cliff is. Uh okay
and then we'll quit and then I'll talk
to you all individually.
Anybody has any further questions I'll
be glad to answer them. A lot of times
people ask us specific books and
specific teachers and they're a little
timeconuming to do them but we can do
them if we get a chance.
Certain teachers get asked over and over
again and I know what they are.
That which is integras speaks of its own
and with sufficient spiritual
experience
you get to almost intuitively pick up
where it is. That which is
non-integorous begins to have certain
signs that you begin to recognize. The
guru has 97 Mercedes-Benzes. You say,
"What?" You know what I mean?
Just like the opposite. You know, the
other day, one last story from the world
and then we'll quit. The other day this
story in Arizona Republic, I get all my
information from the Arizona Republic.
Some young man is clean, some guy is
cleaning his gun.
uh and accidentally while cleaning his
gun shot his three-year-old. Hm. I
thought, well, now when you look at
that, that's interesting. First of all,
he had to violate the basic principle.
You don't clean a gun with a family
member in the same room. Then he had to
forget that he had the safety off. Then
he had to forget that there was a bullet
in the chamber. Then he had to forget
and pull the trigger.
Then with meticulous accuracy
in a 360 degree sphere, he had to pick
out exactly where the child was. And
they're always shot dead. Whenever
somebody's shot dead accidentally while
cleaning a gun, it's almost fatal. They
don't just shoot off their left ear.
You never read this a guy shot off the
toes of his brother-in-law. You never
read that somebody shot up their their
uh motorcycle by mistake. What's the
name of the favorite motorcycle?
>> Harley-Davidson.
>> Nobody ever shot their Harley-Davidson
by mistake in a cleaning their gun
accident. Isn't that strange?
Think about it. Okay.
>> Thank you everybody.
>> I want to thank you all because I do
enjoy and love everyone here.
The true love that I experienced.
YEAH.