So the other doorway past the intellect
is the aesthetics, the appreciation, the
reverence for beauty, the reverence for
purity and beautiness
and to see
the um
sacredness of all that exists.
Because all that exists
is coming out of
its source. Then divinity is intrinsic
and all that exists.
the capacity to experience this divinity
directly then becomes
uh relatively
innate to one's experience of
life itself. So how to transcend the
intellect? Um you can't get there via
advanced theoretical physics. You can't
get there.
You can certainly
demonstrate its reality because
using a calibration technique which we
talk about you can calibrate what is the
level of that beauty and we just did it.
We just did it. It's quality is
ineffable. Um we use the term beauty. We
use the term but that isn't the quality.
What makes you you the hair stand up on
the back of your head when the violin
hits a certain note is a different
quality of consciousness
and it transcends the intellect.
So the traditional ways to God the the
upside the positive side of religion
has been its recognition of beauty as a
great transporter of human spirit.
That's what I mean. The great cathedrals
of the world, great cathedrals of Europe
especially
uh
depict probably the greatest possible
achievement
of mankind within the physical domain.
The uh endless lifetimes. Some of those
cathedrals took a thousand years to
build.
Century after century, people devoting
their entire life to just carving
one pulpit in 3D. And I've looked at
pulpit that the man spend his entire
life. There's three levels of figures
within this pulpit.
One entire lifetime just to do that one
carving.
So um we won't talk anymore about beauty
in a moment.
Uh so that is one of the great and
traditional ways
to experience what you might say are
various aspects
of the presence.
That which is love, that which is peace,
that which is beauty.
Not beauty of perception, not beauty of
artistic um
appreciation
but an awareness that one is
experiencing the essence out of which
that beauty is being perceived.
So devotion and it's um so traditional
religion has u has understood that. So
on the one side there's the depiction of
God as sort of a frightening monster.
Uh on the other hand there's all that
really sustains the core and and keeps
it going because if there weren't any
truth there would collapse out of its
own negativity
as you walk into a great cathedral.
One time I was in Cusco and uh I wasn't
used to the altitude
and as I got off the plane I got sort of
a stoned feeling you know what I mean
like everything was incredibly beautiful
and I walked down the street and I could
smell this incense. Wow, it's
incredible.
And so I followed the incense.
The stone chilling was due to the
spiritual condition that I arrived at.
arrived in Cusco in and
anyway this the odor of the incense is
coming down the street
and so I automatically followed this
incense where it was coming from and it
was coming from
uh an ancient church and the church had
all these altars and these altars were
all made of heavy silver and you could
see the the prior influence on it. Um
anyway, um it was right before Christmas
and um as you got into the church, the
incense got heavier and heavier
and the organ was playing um flute music
and Peruvian flute music
uh type of religious music that played
on. So it's coming with the sound of
Indian flutes. So, here's this
incredible flute music and the incense
wafting through the air and it's coming
out of a great big kiln up near the
front of the So, near the front of the
altar is this big black thing and this
incense is pouring out. There's stained
glass windows and the sunshine is coming
through the stained glass windows. So,
the blues and the oranges and all are
intersecting the clouds of incense. In
the meantime, in the back of the room
are these old I can only call them
script descriptively crrons, old old
bent over with long black and the black
thing over them and they're rocking back
and forth to the music and clicking
these coins. So as the flutes are going
like this, they're clicking the coins to
the sound of the flute music and the
incense is surrounding everybody and the
colored light is coming through.
And because it was near Christmas, near
the in the front of the altar, there was
a cray. And in the cray were the divine
figures.
And these were lighting up and
unlighting up periodically with the
sound of the of the music and the
incense. And you wondered, whoa,
that's how you get beyond 500.
Enchantment. One becomes enchanted.
Okay.
The same states arise through
meditation.
The same states arise through mantra.
The idea is to
pull back from identification with
thinkingness and words and the intellect
and begin to un to begin to sense. So
one senses that underneath the intellect
and thought
is some field of awareness. Otherwise,
how would you know what you're thinking
or what is going on in the mind? So,
this thinkingness comes to a a stop and
one realizes
that the stunning impact of this beauty
represents the totality of the
experience. I'm only breaking it down
into words now. But at that time it was
the incense, the beauty of the music,
the chanting, the the rocking of the
people to the music, the cre with the
lights flickering and the sheer divinity
and reverence of the whole situation.
So reverence, the reverence for that
which is sacred,
reverence
for that which is sacred is one of the
doors that opens the way to the 500s.
One now does things not out of duty, not
out of fear of consequences,
not of not out of fear of punishment by
a negative arbitrary God. One does it
out of one's love for truth, out of
one's devotion to lovingness
as a quality and a way of life.
Lovingness, as we've said, is what makes
you stop and turn the beetle over on his
legs
in the alley. He lays there on his back.
He cannot get on his own little feet.
He's got a big black
and something in you. Then compassion.
So compassion takes us beyond the 500s.
The compassion for all that lives.
The compassion comes up in one of the
questions today to try to complete the
understanding of vegetarianism
as a spiritual quality. That's this
week's Time magazine. The cover of Time
seems to anticipate what we're going to
lecture here all the time, but
somebody's leaking info to them. Anyway,
vegetarianism we had brought up before
that um there are many ways of
contextualizing it.
It can be merely a way of sacrificing.
It can be what's called tapas
spiritual discipline not eating fish on
Friday you see was a way it can be
looked at various ways as a silly
superstition or as an ar anacross
an outofdate um it can be looked at many
ways it can also be seen as reverence uh
and respect for one's religious
religious teachers whether it's true or
not then becomes irrelevant.
It's irrelevant whether eating fish on
Friday is a sinner or not sinner. So
because
the calibrated level of consciousness,
the karmic consequences have to do with
intention.
So we'd say not eating meat out of
Friday on a Friday is out of fear of
thinking of it as sin because in those
days we all thought of it as a sin.
You'd have to confess it.
uh is different than reverence. If you
do that out of reverence, then it's a
totally different motivation. Uh
so reverence then for truth uh and the
pursuit of truth and reverence for those
who are equally committed to
approaching the seeking the truth. So
another way to go into the 500s is
reverence.
Reverence the appreciation of that which
is sacred. So even if you don't hold it
as sacred, I hold sacred that that
person holds it as sacred. So what is
sacred to them I respect because I
realize it is sacred to them
even though I may not be in agreement.
That allows us to appreciate difference
and still respect people who think
differently than we do.
So the vegetarian may do so for multiple
reasons and it would be the motivation
out of respect for life. It is certainly
part of almost every spiritual seeker's
um pathway at one time or another. The
question comes up a lot of these
questions come up. Can you have sex? Can
you have a job? You know I mean the old
thing was renunciation right? To
renounce the world renounce all these
things.
The way of non-duality is more that one
stays in the law in the world and merely
advances in one's understanding of them.
Moves from perception, moves out of
judgmentalism,
uh moves out of duality and perceives
them as they are. As you perceive them
as they are, their beauty shines forth.
So one can do it out of respect. Uh one
can do it out of reverence. One can do
it out of love for the animal.
Uh reverence for its life. The Native
American uh solve that one very well.
The great white spirit of the Native
American calibrates well over 700 and is
quite a very advanced understanding of
divinity.
So the recognition of the sacredness of
all life uh which leads to the prayer of
thanking the animal and uh for and for
surrendering its life.
So if you at the level where you think
that when an animal leaves its body it
dies there would be the obstruction of
thinking that you're killing killing it.
Huh? You think I can't eat it because it
means killing it.
We I think in the last lecture we went
through that killing us, didn't we?
We'll just do it for those who are not
there. U we have permission to ask this
in this audience resist. The animal
doesn't really realize that it just
died. It just goes right on in its
etheric body and doesn't even pay any
attention. Resist and comes back in
another physical body and hardly notice
that either. It just thinks it's one
dream or another dream. Okay.
>> All right. And so when you realize that
that nothing dies it uh and that nothing
dies nothing can experience death
because death is not a possibility then
it doesn't make any difference
there is a certain level also of
awareness I never calibrated what it is
uh we can do it this morning which uh in
which you see each animal willingly
surrenders its life physic its
physicality to god
V via you. Let me see that is correct.
Yes, because I saw that there is a point
at which at which the animal ensures its
own
evolution into the oneness with
divinity. It sacrifices its physicality.
For thee, oh Lord, do I sacrifice my
life.
uh as an act of worship I surrender my
life to thee.
That is so I understand the animal soul
in my animal soul because I'm that which
I am is all that is in my animal soul
out of my love for God
over and over and over again. I
willingly
surrender this physicality.
That's my act of worship.
So as an animal, you would be depriving
me then of one of my forms of act of
worship.
That's how I express my love for God.
In the presence of God, one would if
asked to surrender one's physicality,
anybody was beyond 500
would become choice of the opportunity.
If it pleases thee, oh Lord God, this
physicality,
I now surrender to thee.
You understand?
The sacredness of the animal soul
is not a human soul, but it all is
created by God is equally sacred.
Um, so the animal then
can only come into physicality
artificially in the numbers they do by
the fact that the man breeds them. If
nobody ate way, I think we said that
before. If nobody ate steak, there
wouldn't be any cattle out there. I
mean, who's going to raise cattle if no
one can eat them? All right.
>> By their sort of being recycled through
the energy fuels of life.
This is how they
reach the completion of the
potentiality of the realization of their
own divinity.
The animal experiences its own divinity.
It experiences its own divinity without
knowing its divinity. We just Yes, we
covered that last time too. And that's
what's called animal grace. You see the
intrinsic innocence, the incredible
perfection and beauty of the animals
that stands there. This happened to us.
Yeah. Just a few weeks ago. And the
three or four deer stood there. And we
looked at the deer and the love just
sort of like poured out, you know, by
itself. Their incredible stillness, you
know, the deer are just so fragile.
They're just so slim. And these little
guys are like this. And then looking,
they know that there's something in that
house there. We're looking out the
window at them. And they were
transfixed.
You know, the deer could not move. The
deer could not move. They stood there
like statues
realiz finally I realized that they it
was because of the energy we were
pouring out they were like blissed out
and staying there they weren't about to
move.
That's a fact that you know and this one
deer in particular was very sensitive to
it and I had to stop loving her
appreciating her beauty because she
couldn't move.
She was transfixed. Resist. She was
transfixed by the energy of adoration
because
the magnificence of the beauty of the
divinity within her shining forth in her
uh gray grace.
We're having bad mornings.
Well, you see what what beauty does to
you then. appreciation of beauty. It
takes takes you right out of the
intellect. I have to stop talking
because the physiologic reaction of such
beauty is you start to cry, you choke
up, you can't talk anymore. So that
shuts you up.
I don't know how we're going to get
through that lecture, folks. I'm going
to have to uh all right. So
we can adore and worship worship the
beauty of the presence of the creator
within all living things you know and
within all form
and um
can I eat that deer? No I couldn't even
my present level of consciousness that
particular deer I couldn't.
All right. So that fluctuates then
depending on where you are in your
spiritual evolution. Your understanding
of reality
is constantly transforming. So long as
you think is there's life and death, the
opposite dualities of life versus versus
death,
then
it would be you might say, spiritually
incorrect to kill.
Once one transcends that, and I've
already spoken of that too. One time in
a restaurant, I suddenly realized that I
am meat.
That's what you are, man. Like, forget
it. So, I ordered a steak in the heck
there since then. Uh, do advanced
teachers still have problems, bad
habits, and neurosis. That's hysterical.
Uh, well, let's finish animals first.
Can an animal ever take a human form?
Can an animal ever take an animal can
sometimes take a human form? We have
permission to ask this resist. No, we
don't have permission to ask this
resist.
Let me see. So, we didn't ask it
correctly. Um,
this question is suitable to be asked at
this right now. Is it? No, it's not. Not
suitable. I know that. Can a human ever
take an animal form? We have permission
to ask that one or this. No. For some
reason,
once in a while we get things that we
don't know the answer. Why? We got to
know.
Well, we'll go back to um teachers do
spiritual teachers have problems etc.
Bad habits.
The evolution of consciousness is
continuous. It's continuous. Can anybody
hear me? All right.
is continuous. Um it's more complex
actually uh more complex than can really
be described
because there is first of all the karma
being human intrinsic to being human
itself.
The karma intrinsic to the
physicality of humanness.
uh limitations of having a human brain
in which the old animal brain is still
functional and quite active. The whole
structure of the brain down to the
amygdala, the basic nuclei
are reacting emotionally to massive
things
prior to anyization.
You have the collective karma. You have
the collective unconscious.
The thing that we cleared this morning
had to do with something coming out of
the collective unconscious.
You have the karma of mankind itself.
You have your own individual karma.
Um
what appears to be a problem or a bad
habit or or a negative at one point
later on is not seen to be that way.
It was only the way you were holding it.
So in other words, it isn't a reality of
a thing, but your perception and your
belief systems and the positionality
that you have about it.
If you think you can you cannot
experience God by eating meat, then that
that's going to be a reality for you. As
long as you keep eating meat, then
you're not going to get that experience
because you have you're holding in your
powerful mind that this is going to
block you.
If you think you can't experience God
without going to communion every Sunday
morning, then that's going to be a
limitation. So each of these things to
say it's a problem to say it's a
limitation depends on where you are
along the pathway.
what's okay in a sen monastery in Japan
is not going to be okay
um in some other local four square
church let's say so it depends on
location which definitions and the
definitions you come from
automatically out of perception so
the first word in this question is
problems
everything's a problem.
Name something that isn't a problem.
Everything is a problem. Is that right?
Can you think of something that's not a
problem?
Air, there's not enough of it. It's
contaminated. Space, we're running out
of it. The seas are contaminated. You
can't trust breathing anymore. Food's
all full of poisons. All the
corporations are corrupt. The church is
falling down with pedophilia and god
knows what.
Everything is a problem.
Having a body is a problem. Breathing in
and out is a problem. Money is a
problem. Future's a problem. And of
course, the past is too.
The past and the future are both
problems. And the present is a really
big problem.
So this is all how you conceptualize it.
If you go back 10 years ago, go back 10
years ago. Now think ahead to this
moment from 10 years ago.
This moment is not even imaginable. From
10 years ago, someone says to you,
"Where will you be 10 years from now on
July 12th?" You can say, "How the hell
do I know?" I could be in Afghanistan.
Why did I say that?
All right. Look ahead now. 10 10 years
or 20 years. Look ahead and you're
remembering back. I remembering back way
back in what was it 2000 something man
beginning of the century
did we go to we were in Arizona there
one time were we you know what I mean
from the future the present is
irrelevant
from the past the f the present is
the present irrelevant for both the past
and the future then one what relevance
does it have
any
is it a problem how can it be a problem
if It has no relevance to anything.
That takes care of the whole problem of
problems.
A problem is whatever you think a
problem is. You know what I'm saying? Uh
if surrendering your life to God is
something that you understand the
essence of the divinity of it, then it's
a sacrament.
The sacrifice of the animal is its
sacrament to God.
It's its form of
expressing its value to all of life. The
same with bad habits or neurosis.
Anyway, these are all perceptions.
So what is
what a person does traditionally in
spiritual evolution is they give up a
thing in order to let go of their
attachment in in order to stop being run
by it. Um
when they become detached from it then
it doesn't make any difference whether
they do it or not because now its
meaning is different. Before that they
had to let go that this is going to
bring them security. this is going to
bring them happiness.
When you first let go of money, it's
very exhilarating. You just walk around
with no money on you and everything
happens fine. No problem.
The fact
the idea that I have to have money in
order to survive is illusion. So when
you face that one, you may give up
everything in the world, get an old beat
up truck and deliver manure. You know
what I mean? You still eat. And when
it's lunch time, somebody says, "You
want a sandwich?" When it's breakfast
time, somebody says, "Hey, you want a
donut?"
You go home at night, there's nothing to
eat and suddenly you find a bag of
apples sitting there. Where'd they come
from? I don't know. Everything just
mysteriously appears of its own.
Anybody's done the course of miracles
and has really tested that knows that's
true. You can walk out of the house
without a thing. Everything will be
provided.
Everything will be provided.
So, a bad habit then would depend on how
you define it, where you are in your
level of consciousness.
Um
and neurosis are really psychological
problems and all all of these things
come up all of these things come up and
the evolution of consciousness
almost everyone in its audience has
faced all of these things faced all of
them with u
more greater greater or lesser success
depending on the particular thing and
how you're looking at it.
The impediment is almost always your
belief system about it and how you're
contextualizing it. How you're
contextualizing it.
It's your belief system about whether
you eat a thing or not that is going to
affect how the outcome. The karmic
consequence is quite different. If you
see that it's irrelevant and it doesn't
really matter. Then you're either free
to do it or not do it.
As far as very advanced teachers, it
says, um, that's a hard one to explain
because
the core of that which you are is
stunningly transformative and blows out
everything. There is no person left.
There is no person who has defects.
There is no person who has neurosis.
There's no person who has bad habits. So
there's no reason to collect correct
anything because there is any person
that you would be correcting about. No
such thing exists.
The physicality continues on its own and
some degree of persona resumes.
Oh, the jocular repartee which this uh
persona is prone to you know it does it
of its own. It's that's what persists
within the world and allows for a
participation.
Otherwise,
one withdraws.
So, for some years, there's nothing
going on in the world of any sufficient
interest to get you reinvolved in it.
You don't read the newspaper for 10
years, 20 years. Uh you don't bother
watching television. You don't go
anywhere. You don't hear anything.
There's nothing to read or there's
nothing to know. So, there's no pursuit
of knowledge. You see, and because of
the passing illusion of perception,
there's a loss of interest in the world
and its events.
And if President Rean got shot or
something, you don't find it out till a
couple months later.
Somebody mentions it and you say, you
know, you're kidding.
You're kidding. He missed it all
together because it wasn't of that
sufficient. You weren't focused on the
world.
Most of the time when the person reaches
a very advanced level of consciousness,
they cease and desist from human
life and affairs. The majority of people
who reach very advanced levels of
consciousness are never heard from
again.
Only with great rarity and after
considerable effort is there the return
of the capacity to function in the world
much less to master both
uh simultaneously.
So
what would you would say would be a
problem would be a way in which
something is being looked at.
Other people see problems in situations
where I don't see any problem. As far as
I'm concerned, that's just the way it
is. And u
say people kill each other and millions
die. You say, "Yeah, that's right.
That's right. Shouldn't you be out there
parading for peace?" Well, I think
somebody should, but not me.
10 million come 10 million go. They're
going to keep recycling back and forth.
10 million more in this, you know,
century after century. It just goes on
and so you see the flow of the nature of
life and there is no desire to try to
enter the river and change its course
because the wisdom of God prevails.
Nothing escapes
what do we say the karmic unity of
the unmanifest to manifest. And what it
manifests is one karmic totality and
absolutely perfectly balanced unity. And
there is really no necessity to do
anything about it whatsoever because it
evolves of its own nature because the
progression of consciousness is innate
within the nature of consciousness
itself and it doesn't need your help.
Doesn't need my help.
That's the thing as a teacher you have
to go that's another whole block about
teaching or not teaching and the meaning
and the significance and the value and
and then of course no there's nobody
left to teach so it either happens or it
doesn't happen and it has to do with the
karmic coherence of
at a certain point one transcends
personal karma personal karma but one
does not transcend the the karmic
intention of divinity does not escape
the karmic consequence.
That's why the luciferic mistake of
selling out integrity for power over
others. When you see that there is no
negative god that you're going to have
to be answerable to is an error. At the
level at which that temptation comes in
is very strong. It's very cleverly and
convincingly phrased and many as the
guru has fallen for it.
fame and fortune and power over others.
You see, because the lie which is
luciferically expressed is correct
within content,
but it ignores the context that you've
not escaped the karmic destiny
of God.
You may have escaped your own personal
karmic destiny
at a certain level beyond 600. You're
not really answerable for it in a
personal way. But one is still within
the karmic coherence of the talitality
of of the context of God. So you're not
beyond karma. You're only beyond
personal karma. But boy, you sure are
within the powerful karmic field of the
infinite presence of almighty God.
And that is the sad discovery. Once the
mistake is made,
it is sacrificed to all for illusion.
God being the infinite context then is
the ultimate infinite possibility of all
that exists. All of which is kept within
a karmic perfect
balance. That's why you don't have to
fear judgment because everything comes
about as a result of the essence of its
own expressing itself within the context
of God. It's inescapable.
There's no such thing as a murderer
getting away with it. People say, "Oh,
he got away with it." Yeah, right. He
got away with it. Big joke of the
century. Nobody gets away with anything
because all is noticed
and that's what kinesiology is based on.
Kinesiology is based on the inherent
coherence
which is guaranteed by its essence as
divinity
that nothing escapes
the infinite allness of God and is
registered forever with an accessible
field that we call consciousness.
So that is the whole basis of the test
of kinesiology
that that which is registers within
consciousness
forever.
All that ever is or has been
and therefore all truth stands revealed.
All truth is accessible.
anything that has ever happened in is
accessible.
Our own search for spiritual truth then
tends to influence our family
uh for better or worse.
They either may think you're crazy and
decide they're going to go in the
opposite direction. Uh
I I would say people either are not to
evolve look directly at an incredible
miracle witnessed by all kinds of people
not even see it much less do they
understand the miraculous nature of what
they just witnessed. In fact they go
into denial of what they just saw. It's
very interesting
incapacity to see the obvious. So
people live in different realities. So
what because of one's level of
consciousness then what would be a
problem a bad habit or a neurosis would
depend on what level you're at
any more questions about that because
people do worry about uh such things
when you re-energize the persona in
order to re uh react act act be active
with in the world the persona is
habitual set set of knowing social
behaviors
u and the remnant of one's former
identity which is retained sort of in
the memory of the persona.
It isn't what you are what but it was
the accumulation of the collected images
of the world and yourself about that
which you are and it's sort of like an
astral shell goes on its own tra pro
trajectory.
Um
one gives it uh you might say sufficient
energy to
enable the continuence of a human
lifetime especially to reenter the world
to continue. But that's arbitrary. One
can disconnect at any time. Uh, one can
get involved with the movie to the
degree that everybody else that's in the
movie thinks you're in the movie with
them and everybody's happy.
The only difference is you can walk out
of it in an instant. It's just as a
matter of will. But when you walk out of
it, it's not always that easy to come
back. It takes um
effort to re-energize
um to re-energize
that which the world would call a
relatively normal lifetime. The nor the
lifetime is never really normal again
anyway. It's not really normal but it
does um conform to human society
sufficiently
to return to a functioning.
This has also its karmic u commitments
uh that may bring it about. We see some
what happened to some people. We see
that Romanoi for instance suddenly fell
down as a teenager and thought he was
dying and u
u was pretty much left for dead. I think
the bugs were eating him up and he was
uh dehydrated and stopped eating and
um
so it takes time. He was silent, didn't
speak for two years. So it takes time to
like re-energize
and it's usually because of the it's
because of well not usually it's always
because of the input of people around
you to eat and um breathe and sleep and
do all those things and the love of such
people uh then begins to get the bug to
stir again like it's coming out of
its winter hibernation. So the
hibernated uh remains of what the
potentiality is for humanness then can
be revived through the energy input.
Um
the effect on uh our family of our own
spiritual
um
effort then is um both good and bad. On
the one hand it may energize them.
We certainly can set examples at certain
levels that we can actually that we can
implement. I think crossing over 200 is
something where the the spiritual seeker
in the family does have an impact.
Um to insist on integrity, to insist on
the demonstration of integrity
uh is one where external pressure does
have an effect and that is at a place
where I'm
chief of staff. Uh
the rehabilitation of of these children
has to do with trying to get them to the
level of integrity to admit that I am
responsible for my own action.
Because you can't get above integrity
until you say yes, I'm the one that did
that. So long as you're blaming gimbals
for falling on the ice on the sidewalk,
you're still below 200 because gimbals
didn't push you over on the ice, friend.
was your how you put your feet.
You saw it was icy. You're 52 years old
and if you know how to put your feet on
ice, you shouldn't be walking on the ice
in front of gimbals and much less suing
gimbble. So, I mean, I've never had much
sympathy for putting the blame out there
because of the loss of spiritual
integrity.
I'm the one that was careless about
where I put my feet. And if you see what
I mean, every every ding in the car, I
take responsibility for. I mean it was
my thoughtlessness that allowed for it.
So that kind of training we can teach
our children. We can I think we can
inspire them to
uh become integrous and to feel the
increase of power and energy that goes
with integrity.
And if you teach them uh by example and
and and keep bringing to their awareness
that there is a certain payoff in
self-esteem which nobody sees.
Yes, you don't have to pick it up. You
don't have to pick it up. You don't have
to pick it up. But when you do over and
over again, suddenly you notice a
difference in how you feel about
yourself and that's called self-esteem.
So I think the building of self-esteem
through integrity is something we can
certainly do. You remember EST from back
in the 60s or 70s? I forget when was the
'7s.
>> Yeah. Well, what Wernner was trying to
teach, I mean, he had his own problems,
but aside from that, what he was trying
to do is get everybody over 200. He
wanted everybody to be over integrity,
take responsibility,
that you're creating your own
experience. And of course, everybody
went through shock. They took away your
watch and your lip ice. And
you couldn't go to the bathroom. You
couldn't eat. You couldn't drink water,
no tea, no coffee. It was a real big
shock. And people went through all kinds
of agonies. And it's really, you know,
it brought up a lot of compassion. You
see people lying on the lying there
crying and desperate because they she
couldn't have her lipstick or she could,
you know, didn't have her watch or they
had to go to the bathroom. I mean, all
these little trivial childhood things.
and they were going through these
horrible agonies almost, you know, going
through major crisis, major crisis,
major nervous breakdowns over some
little habit. It's lunchtime and they're
not having their lunch crisis. So it was
a very interesting experience and I
thought
that anybody who loved their kids would
send them to EST, you know,
because ES could do what you couldn't do
as a parent, you know,
uh it was very intense training, but you
also learned very rapidly.
And after that, you never worry about
making it to the bathroom ever again.
If you just resist it and resist it, it
disappears. Now you don't have to go to
the bathroom at all. Wow, that's quite a
discovery to go through the the crisis
of the bladder and come out victorious.
You had to go. You had to go and if you
don't go, you're going to go and you
don't go and then suddenly all of a
sudden it disappears. You ever have that
happen? It disappears. If you withstand
it and transcend it, a couple minutes
beyond that, you don't have to go
anymore.
Well, we can stop now. I don't have to
go anymore. So you just crossed another
barrier.
So I think those are things that we can
really encourage our children is
integrity.
U these other ones we weren't allowed to
to ask. Well maybe on private we'll see
we can find out why. So the main
emphasis today was how to transcend
the 400s. How to get to the 500s. As we
know only 0.4% of the population 4% of
the population ever gets to 500. 4% of
the population transcends 500 and 0.4
gets to 540. 440 is unconditional love.
So those those are the those are the
ways out of the box through love, joy,
peace, beauty, uh consideration,
devotion, respect for others,
the love we have for our animals whether
we eat them or not.
to see the divinity of the presence of
their love. And we as we said a dog's
wagging tail calibrates at 500 and a
kitty's purr calibrates at 500. So that
which we respect in the animal then is
not its animalness but it's love. We all
it's the lovingness of the animal that
we respect. And it's why people go to
such extremes for the animal. We say
well they're really a nut about an
animal. No, it's about the love. That's
the love that to this present.
The other day I was at staff meeting and
and this this girl who was very very
nasty and very very mean and had a long
mean mastery. I'll stab you to death and
use all kinds of four-letter words and
she's sitting there at the staffing
justly hostile and um just kill you,
look at you. And then her parents came
in from the reservation. Her parents
came in and walked in the door. They
traveled 5 hours to reach her instantly.
You could feel the love light up the
room. All that stuff disappeared. All
the irrelevance of all what had been.
And the reality was the love. You could
see the love of the girl, her joy, and
their joy eclipsed everything else. And
you're over 500.
Cuz in the region of the re level of
400, they should put her away already
and keep her there. She's not safe on
the street. But when you saw the
capacity for love, the capacity to
respond to love and the value that both
sides held for the love, then you knew
that uh it was all going to end up all
right.
So that is the main way out then. Love,
joy, peace, enlightenment, the
appreciation for beauty, the respect for
beauty,
and I think that's the way to the 500s.
So, we'll stop there for lunch and we'll
reconvene. What time? You
>> have to put my earring in.
>> Get a hook on. Need a hook on. There we
go.
>> I think
All right.
And don't you bloody blasters think I'm
going to give you food and water all the
way back to port and cost me good money?
Put them over the side.
Well, I paid for that one later, I'll
tell you.
Put them over the side. I'm not spending
the money to feed them and water all
them all the way back to port.
I'll have to tell you the truth about
slavery. It's a great advance in human
consciousness.
Slavery is a great advance in human
Does that make sense?
>> No.
>> Well, I just want you to understand how
positionality
positionality creates right and wrong,
truth, untruth, etc.
You see, in the olden days when the u
the great horde swept across Europe, the
uh the Vandals and the Visigoths and the
Mongols and the Huns and all these
peoples
and the Roman Empire had a heck of a
time surviving because it was one wave
after another of uh
>> I can't take you seriously.
You can't take me ser I can't take
myself seriously. I think
I feel like Captain Blie or something.
So
in the in the good old days when when
the hordes would sweep into civilization
Roman Empire was a very tempting plum.
Uh I forget the names. Those of you who
are good at history will know the names
of all of them. Vizigos the gods. I've
forgotten the names of all of them. But
one horde after another would sweep down
and not try to knock out the Roman
Empire. And of course they just killed
all the they just killed the people and
uh they always did the same thing. They
just killed people. And when you
conquered somebody you took their gold,
you had sex with the women and you
killed everybody. Then one day a smart
guy says, "Hey, these people are worth
something."
Said, "We won't kill them. Hey, let's
save them." And they began to sell them.
Wow, they're valuable. Human beings
became valuable. We won't just massacre
and kill them. The Japanese
Nan King massacred what 30,000 or
300,000 some phenomenal number. They had
any brains. They would have captured
them as slaves and sold them, right?
They weren't even that far in advance.
So all of a sudden, the value of the
life of a human being dawned on people.
They're worth money. Well, that's
somewhere up the line, isn't it?
I mean, you're moving in the right
direction, folks. That uh I don't know
how you turn these magical lanterns on,
but anyway, he he moved up to uh at
least we got up to greed. Anyway, he was
worth something on the market. So much a
pound. You know, they used to put the
slave up there and feel him and he had
mostly like me,
they put him in the bargain basement.
But
people now had a value. So slavery was
an advance in human consciousness from
just slaughtering everybody out of
hatred and seeing and seeing them as
worthless and potential garbage. So
slavery then from that point you see was
an advance. it'd be better to be
captured. And even in a few hundred
years ago, your lifpan was twice twice
as long if you got captured as a slave,
sold by the slavers in Africa to a slave
trader and bought by a aristocratic
southerner. You were now worth quite a
bit of money as a worker and you got
medical care, food, housing, clothing.
And the people who stayed back in Africa
got slaughtered by the next war with the
next tribe. So your chances of survival
were twice as long. You live twice as
long. So you see it depends on how you
look at slavery from that that
viewpoint. It was the beginning of the
realization of the worth of human life
and and the value of preserving it.
And if I if I spent a couple thousand
dollars for a slave, I'd take very good
care of him. I'll tell you, I take good
care of my car. And I took care take as
good care of my slave as I would my car,
wouldn't I? He'd be an investment. got a
couple. I mean, in those days, a good
sleeve was like $1,000. That would get
you to the top of the thing. So,
anything in history is depends on how
you contextualize it and that how you
perceive it, the positionality that you
take about it. And um if you're
perfecting
moving up from
apathy to greed, huh? Where is greed
here? Someplace around here. Where is
greed? desire words there, you know.
You see, to become greedy is a big move
out of sloth. Huh?
Yeah. That's the effect television had
on on the the great unwashed is he began
to see, whoa, what's possible. Up comes
I want that. Up comes anger. Anger's got
a lot of energy. 150 can get you off
your butt. Down here, they just lay
around in the gutter drinking gin and
letting their babies die of starvation.
Hoggarth London. You know,
we never did put hate on here. And um
and that we're going to put that on the
new map,
>> did we?
>> Well, no.
>> Yeah. Okay. All right. We do have
another Okay. Anyway, what the the the
pirate was into greed. Into greed. You
see, into greed. And making money was
more valuable than human life.
So, um, he had a lot to learn
painfully as it was. There's a couple
things I just want to be sure to mention
before, uh, I get taken away by these
questions. Uh, let's see. We wanted to
mention that slavery was an advance in
in civilization, which most people
wouldn't think about. There there was a
lady who u
became famous. There was a movie made
about her and a bestseller and all about
her lion and her life with her lion and
born free or something remember it was
great movie
and we asked people if they knew what
happened to her in the end what was the
end of the story years after the movie
in the book
anybody know
>> the lion killed her yeah the lion ate
her up
so people said isn't that awful after
all that love and devotion books
movies and everything about this her
love for this lion. He turned on her and
killed her.
And the minute I heard the story, I know
what the lion did. The lion adored her.
He loved her so much. He just ate her
up.
He just ate her up cuz he loved her so
much. He just And you know, in language,
we still say, you know, I could You're
so pretty. I could just eat you up. You
know, you want to eat up that which you
love. So the lion did not kill her out
of hatred or any kind of evil. He killed
her out of love.
The lion ate her up cuz he adored her.
Is that correct? He ate her out of love.
So you see when you're already in a very
high space of love yourself, you see it
where other people don't see it. You see
the love of the animal who sacrifices
itself
the glory of God by serving man. And you
see that the lion kills the lady because
he adored her. But so you so what you
see then is really representing your
capacity at a certain p level. You see
love in all all things.
Uh
we wanted to talk about the lady that
got eaten out of love. How slavery is in
advance. Oh yes. Um
um I was looking at the naivee of
mankind. you know the naivee
and uh realizing
that uh there's another level of
integrity which you never hear mentioned
and that is to take responsibility for
your own naivete
and to become the shepherd of your own
sheep
all right so Jesus said
you can't tell you know watch out for
the wolf and sheep's clothing.
But the wolf and chief's clothing eats
people all the time.
Having been warned of that, then
how does one protect oneself? Well,
until we discovered the kinesiology
discern truth from falsehood, there was
no objective means of doing it. And
therefore, it was said by their fruits,
you shall know them.
And that which radiates beauty, grace,
and love uh and peace, you can tell is
of God.
And that which radiates its opposite is
not of God.
Because consciousness is like the
hardware of a computer. It doesn't know
right from wrong. Doesn't know truth
from falsehood.
Every great sage who's ever lived has
said that man is
innocent on a certain level due to
ignorance. Because because the hardware
software software could tell the
difference, but you're born only with
the hardware. You're born with hardware.
Consciousness is like the hardware
and the programs are what society
programs you with because your own
hardware can't tell truth from
falsehood. It cannot discern
and has no control over what's being
programmed by. People get programmed as
they walk by an advertisement coming off
the television. They don't know that
they just got programmed, but I can pick
it up later with hypnosis or
kinesiology. You just got programmed.
You got the message is already
imprinted.
You didn't have any say over it. You
didn't say, "Gee, do I want to believe
this? Do I want to do I want this
imprinted on my consciousness?" You
don't have any much selection over what
goes into your software. The older you
get, the more sophisticated you get. You
get some selection of what you you can
pick which movies you want to see. and
the movies that glamorize uh that which
is non- integrous uh you learn to avoid
it because you realize your own
susceptibility
and vulnerability to the glamorization
of it. There's a new movie out now. I
haven't calibrated it, but it glamorizes
what? Chicago Gangsters in the 30s or
something
which has its glamour which has its
glamour.
Uh
to become the shepherd of your own sheep
then means to acknowledge that all the
subpersonalities with you in you the
child in you the adolescent all those
things that still are there
uh are now your responsibility
and because you're awake now because
you're awake more awake than the rest of
them within you you have to become the
shepherd that guards is the innocence of
the sheep within you.
Yeah. You take responsibility.
You take responsibility now
and say I recognize that my mind can't
tell truth from falsehood.
as a consequence. As a consequence,
uh I will not put myself in a position
where that naive
uh can lead to dilitterious results. You
know what I'm saying? It's like not
throwing your pearls before a swine.
It's I never cared for the language of
that. But it was uh the idea is that
what you pro what you you have to take
responsibility now for what you allow
yourself to be programmed by
which you have to be and the the glamour
the glamorization of every kind of
negativity by the current media is
probably the biggest source of
negativity the biggest input into the
consciousness of mankind right now. I
would say if it were not for the media
right now, the consciousness of mankind
probably be 10 points higher than it is.
Uh and the blatant uh the blatant non
integrity of video games and things like
that which are shocking. They're so
shocking that even the media that put
out negativity round the clock were
shocked by it. Just two weeks ago, there
was a new one out in which the graphics
of it uh even shocked people that can't
be shocked anymore. Training children
how to kill women, you know, how to
attack them, kill them, etc. And uh and
here's his mother. This came to my mind
as I watched this mother on on TV. She
says, "Well, I don't see anything wrong
with that. He knows it's just a game."
No, the unconscious doesn't know it's a
game. That's the whole point. It does
not know that it's just a game. This is
becoming a programmed trained killer
when it shoots its classmates. Just did
it to see what it felt like
for kicks. Did you hate those people?
No.
Whoa. I mean, that is really serious. If
you kill the people you hate, at least
make sense. Now you're beyond any kind
of logic, reason, sensibility, any
restraint, any restraint at all. So now
people are being programmed into
non-integrity
via nonlinear programming.
That is probably the worst downside I'll
ever see in human history. Why? Because
you don't have a choice.
So we have to own that the innocence is
is our vulnerability.
It's our vulnerability.
And um I think it's the answer of
certain energies to the advancing
spiritual awareness of the populace.
The answer of that which would rather
maintain its control because it did at a
level 190 until the late 80s had control
of this planet. It feels control
slipping. And now it has found a way to
program the minds of young children as
they're sitting there until they're
hopelessly in their camp and don't even
know they're in their camp. You just got
brainwashed and don't even know you've
been brainwashed.
That's a hard one to break out of. Huh.
And it's the most serious
uh condition I think on the planet right
now. Bin Laden is chicken next to that.
I mean, he's just obvious. He's nothing
dangerous about Bin Laden. You know, you
either go for grotesque insanity or
don't. But I mean, it's pretty blatant,
you know. But when you're buying your
kid a nice game for his birthday party
and training his little mind,
you become an expert at evil.
And then the mother sits there on TV.
Well, I he knows it's just a game. I
thought, "Oh, god, mother. This must be
the worst mother on the planet. I hate
her this instant." You know what I mean?
She's just sold her son down the drain.
You know, she thinks it's just a
harmless amusement. It's just a game.
Well,
all right. So, we said to take
responsibility to be the shepherd of
your own sheep.
And that is the awareness that within
yourself, within the various archetypes,
the subpersonalities
is still the programmable.
The programmable
and to watch what you're being just to
be aware to be aware.
All right.
Okay. So, now we were going to talk
about that and we were going to talk Oh,
yes. We talked about that from the past.
Um if we look go back 20 years from now
this moment would be irrelevant you know
not even conceivable and certainly
unimportant not worth a nickel 20 years
from now won't he remember it you know I
remember I went to a lecture by somebody
time and it was you know it's exciting
and fun and I don't remember really you
know you know so 20 years from now it
will only be part of a part of the
mosaic of your own lifetime you see and
uh
So we said that in reality this in in
the space of the present there's either
then uh now or in the future
that the focus on now that now itself is
equally an illusion as the past and the
future. This is more advanced and
sophisticated. But
if there's no then
neither is there any sense of not any
reality called now.
Outside of time, there's either neither
then
nor the future, nor is there a now.
Well, if there's no past and there's no
future and there's no now, then where
are you?
Where are we?
I don't know. Outside of time, some
I just asked the question. I do.
Yeah.
All right. So, there's questions here
having to do with the karma of various
ethnic groups and all. And you see, we
we've only sort of uh investigated a new
way of understanding and and
gaining knowledge about spirituality. It
hasn't been around that long. And
any one of these aspects in itself could
take a take a lifetime. You can take
take any one little aspect of this
chart. See, because these calibrated
levels are very gross. These are very
gross, you know, because there there's
there's great many variations of all
these things. There's anxiety, there's
terror, there's nervousness. I mean,
there's all kinds of fear, right?
There's desire, craving this, wanting
this, having to have this, just wanting
this. So there's subtleties and
gradations of all these. There's quite a
bit of difference between 100 and 101
because that's a logarithm. That's quite
a bit of difference. So I could do, you
know, spend a lifetime as a young man
now researching just this field here.
Just this field here. How it grows, how
it expresses itself, all the subtle
variations. Calibrate everything from
100 to 105 could take you a lifetime.
every variation 100.1 100.12 100 point
and because already because it's
logarithmic there's quite a difference
there's quite a difference so even a
tenth of 1%
so in a way we're saying well now that
we got this telescope we look up in the
heavens and we got and we see these
galaxies and we see the moons are on
Mars or whatever it is Galileo
but that was only the beginning of many
many lifetimes how How many astronomers
over how many decades are still just you
know barely breaking through the surface
of the subject. So we're at a
rudimentary state you know but just to
contextualize the evolution of human
consciousness in this way in itself
already has a transformative effect.
Thank you Lord.
What did I say backwards?
Oh.
Uh.
All right. Now, let's see. All right.
We're going to go through these. Uh, I'm
going to repeat the questions so we can
hear them. That's the value of having
them written. Uh, is that we can repeat
them.
Uh, there's a lot a lot said about
meditation and reason as pathways to the
presence of God. What of athletic
endeavor? All right. So we said that
what sets the karmic uh consequence,
what sets the calibrated level is
intention. Intention.
And I think I did mention that. Yes.
Power versus force. Because the
intention of the athlete not only has
quite an effect on his performance, but
certainly has a profound karmic
consequence.
One can do anything in the name of the
love of God and to be of service to God.
And peeling potatoes for your family is
to me as holy as praying up a storm in
church. Everybody runs to church and
prays up a storm. But the test of the
the test of the oatmeal is at the
kitchen sink. That's that's where the
test is. Anybody can feel holy at church
with the humans going. And I mean,
everybody feels holy.
Everybody feels holy at church. That
doesn't do much. It's good. If if you
can see the devotion, the the
sacrificing of oneself
for the love of others, then peeling
every potato is as holy as any other
act. And therefore, athletics
because athletics can demonstrate your
joy at your existence, your thankfulness
to God for this body and the joy of it
at the present time.
and be a way it's a way of demonstrating
one's love and devotion to God.
At a certain point of endeavor, physical
endeavor, athletics being probably the
most commonly one, you of course run
against the ultimate barrier.
It's one of those books I wrote about. I
don't know which one. Anyway, there is a
barrier beyond which you cannot go.
You cannot run. one iota of faster. You
cannot lift one more ounce. You cannot
lift one more box in the warehouse. You
cannot lift one more rock. You cannot
put one more arm over your head. You
cannot take another stroke in the water.
You've reached it, the limit, the
barrier, the blockade.
At that point, with grim absolute
determination, one can by intention
and will. You then discover how powerful
the will is.
The will is the crux of finding God.
You will yourself through that barrier
absolutely
at any price and crash. You go through
the barrier. The next rock doesn't weigh
anything. You lift it effortlessly. And
I've lifted rocks for 12, 15, 18 hours.
150lb rocks non-stop. Didn't even feel
tired. had to turn the headlights of the
car on because the whole work crew had
long left and it all fallen over.
Um, so this is a the most common place
that this is experienced I think is in
sports where everybody knows that the
4-minute mile barrier of Roger Banister
and once he broke it then many others
broke it. So athletics is another way of
breaking that barrier of the sense of I
can't and the real realization that
there is no limit really and um one can
break through it and u yes I did
describe I discovered that in a work
situation
uh where you couldn't lift one more box
and u in willing oneself through that
barrier suddenly all the boxes became
lightweight I was just amazed I could
hardly lift those crazy boxes of canned
peas
in a peanuty 110° and no windows in this
warehouse and you couldn't lift one more
box and um and that was when that there
was that discovery and um people who jog
discover that certain barrier and all of
a sudden your jogging is effortless and
you're in a state of high joy and the
jogging is doing itself.
You're not doing the jogging. that
jogging is jogging itself because it's
effortless
and I think that's where the Sufi
dancers discover it too where they and I
also discovered it dancing that there's
a certain point in which you stop
dancing and you are being danced just
like the boxes were being lifted and the
rocks were being lifted and the runner
finds that it's effortless
in spiritual serious spiritual work if a
person is really committed to
enlightenment you're going to run up
against that barrier there's more than
once There's that barrier beyond which
you cannot go.
And yet you have to go beyond it. And
you summon up all the spiritual power
and intention you have.
And by the intention of will and the
fixity of will, you break through the
barrier and the impossible becomes
possible.
That all also happens at around 600
uh calibrated level 600. Somebody asked
me about that.
There is that which beyond which you
cannot go and you go beyond it and
you're in a new universe. You're in a
new dimension of reality.
Uh new dimension of reality.
The thinkingness there's a point beyond
which thinkingness will not get you any
further. And there's an absolute
surrender. Absolute surrender of the
thinkingness. And then suddenly the
knowingness stands there where the
thinkingness was blocking it before. the
knowing the stance there.
Uh let's see. I want to keep these in
sequence so they answer them correctly.
Yeah, that's overcoming that that block.
And in spiritual work, everybody knows
there is that block where you cannot go
further. I think sewing saying the
rosary or spinning the prayer wheel are
all efforts to transcend that limit. I
cannot say the rosary one more time. I
cannot say the Jesus prayer one more
time. Who was that famous?
I don't think he was a Jesuit. I think
it was a monk.
Uh who just repeated the Jesus prayer
period. That's all he did. And it's a
very famous little book about him. And
when you couldn't do it one more time,
he did it one more time and broke
through.
Uh
what do you do when in spite of all the
spiritual work and surrender, you still
feel trapped?
No. Trapped and seems at a dead end.
Well, I already answered that, didn't I?
It's only when you feel you're at a dead
end that you make a major breakthrough.
As long as you think things are going
swimmingly.
They may or may not be.
What about the American Indian? Because
of their level of consciousness, how is
it they were suffered such fate at the
hands of the Europeans? I don't know.
You'd have to check out the karma of the
American Indian and see who they were.
and what they brought about upon
themsself.
Um,
we didn't say that all the
besides uh what happened to them
culturally again is from the viewpoint
of illusion. We'd say well it was a
disaster. It was sociologically it was
from a prosaic level of reason.
uh each of these things to get the real
answer, you have to go beyond the
apparent and go beyond what common logic
or reason would make you think or see
and find out whether or not it was
liberation.
How do you know when a thing is
catastrophe or liberation?
Because it was out of catastrophe that
liberation arose
in this one here. It was at the depths
of hell. You'd say, "Well, the dips of
hell after all that spiritual seeking.
How can that be fair?"
Yeah. Well, it smashed the last finger
to let go. What's that old joke? You
know, guy hanging over the edge of the
cliff with one finger and he says, "Let
go."
And the guy says, "Is there anybody else
up there?"
God, what now?
uh
after the experience of God is one's
level of consciousness raised over 400.
Well, everyone's experience of God does
have of course a profound effect and the
near-death experience
is transformative. The near-death
experience calibrates um people
calibrate considerably higher after it.
Out of body experience
is generally no major shift to
consciousness. However, there is a shift
of awareness. There is a there's the
awareness that you're not a physical
body. When you're out of out of when
you're out there in the middle of space,
just a sort of space in the middle of
space and the body is laying there in
the bed. It's rather clear that you're
not that because you're out here and
it's there.
And so, it is it always amazed me that
the the consciousness didn't whoop out
of body experience. consciousness um
advances due to out of body experience.
Is this?
>> No. Isn't that funny?
>> In this lifetime uh out of that bed, if
conscious consciousness advanced itself
or resist didn't No, cuz I was miserable
when I came back in the body. Anyway,
it was certainly was startling, I'll
tell you. It's just like flying without
wings. It's whoa. I mean,
all right. It always made me though that
out of body experience because you you
you are aware that you're the athetheric
body. You're not the physical body. It
seems to me like that would raise your
consciousness level. So, I don't know
the reason for that. I don't know. Maybe
it's because that's um Oh, that's the
expression and not the cause. Oh, I see.
I'm seeing it as cause. Okay. So, the
going out of body is already the
realization of the truth that you're not
a physical body resistant. Oh, okay. It
now makes sense. The reason you go out
of body is you're already aware on a
certain level that you're not a physical
body. And that's what allows for the
experience in the first place. I was
looking at it the other way around.
Uh-huh.
The consciousness level of mankind
raised after the level of 911.
I think we asked that before and said
no. The consciousness of mankind uh just
in recent days has gone up to two. What
did we get this morning? 208 209. Huh?
>> 209.
>> 209. Yeah.
So, it is um adv it is advancing.
I expect it to accelerate. Why? Because
the power of even one person over, you
know, 500 is so enormous that you get a
few individuals on the planet that are
in the high 500s, they're going to
already raise. and a few in the 600s or
700s. Mankind's going to just keep going
like that. And the more that go up, the
more that's going to cross the line. The
more they cross the line, I expect to
see
uh mankind get pulled right up into
higher and higher levels of
consciousness.
Um so we said, what is it today? What do
we say this morning? 209.
Yeah. Well, that's an amazing rate of
progression because it was at 190 for
many, many centuries. At the time of
Jesus Christ, the consciousness level of
mankind was 100.
100. It took it 2,000 years to go from
100 to 190. And then late 80s.
Then in the late 80s, it went to 207.
Now it's up to 208. Now it's up to 209.
So now
it's moving very rapidly, very rapidly.
Uh you see and I I think the decimation
of the corporate world and uh 9/11 and
all those things the net effect is that
integrity becomes more important. You
can be sure Mr. and Mrs. Stockholder are
going to be quite interested in the
integrity of any future stock
investments.
Yeah. Hey, let's do kinesiology and in
run before we buy more of that stock,
sweetheart. You know, this is an
integrous company. Yes. No. Boring.
Whoop. An integrous corporation is the
biggest, most successful corporation.
The fact that integrity shows up on the
bottom line is what some of the people
in this audience are. That's what
they're about to take spiritual
principles into the workplace, into
corporate America, into the bureaucracy.
I'd like to see it in the government.
You know what I mean?
I'd like to see I'd like to see him stop
quit stopping all the black people
coming up for Chicago and asking them if
they're babyfaced Nelson.
If we used the same political correct
style that we're using now invoiding
racial profiling, you know, in the 30s
we'd be stopping all the black guys
coming up from Chicago saying, "Are you
John Dillinger?" You know what I mean?
To total irrationality and absurdity of
a good part of human life and
consciousness, you know, is
how can the consciousness of the world
world mind be raised to 500 and can it
ever be done? It isn't like it's done.
It's like it evolves.
And my feeling about the advancement of
human consciousness over the millennia
is that consciousness
when we go back to the age of the
reptiles, we go back to the age of the
dinosaurs,
we see that the energy field of life on
earth was 70.
If we go 500 millions before that, we
keep going to lower numbers. So we see
that life emerges that consciousness be
it's
within the essence of consciousness to
constantly evolve constantly evolve.
So we would expect then that
there would be a time in the future when
the consciousness level of mankind would
be up to 500. Huh?
Shall we all vote for that? I'm in
favor. Okay. You had a question.
>> Uh, yes. Um, I've been looking at some
children lately that are children of
friends and testing like a
level of consciousness at birth and it's
been
very high and I don't know whether it's
because
children
>> I don't know.
I don't know because a lot of that is
sort of folk belief and and I'm always
suspicious of it, you know. Um I I'm
interested in the overall level of
consciousness of mankind itself, how it
expresses itself in individuals is
relatively immaterial.
It's the totality of it that u spells
the quality of life on this planet.
Um there are of course whole continents
where the level of consciousness is very
near the bottom and um it seems to be
the karmic u pattern. it it's as though
one comes in from a very low level of
consciousness and is born into a very
low level of consciousness which is just
a little higher than where they were
maybe and then there's a recycling and
coming back into higher and higher
levels of consciousness. consciousness
seems to evolve evolve over great
expanses of time. And my suspicion is
that that's because that's its essence.
Just as an oak tree grows within the
acorn is already the that karmic uh
propensity.
Uh
any experience of I think any spiritual
experience tends to reason with level of
consciousness. Certainly the near-death
experience we can calibrate that
any sense of closeness and oneness with
God. Um increase in sensitivity to
beauty, appreciation for the value of
all of life uh increases the
consciousness level of all of mankind.
Um
the effect of people the effect of more
advanced levels of consciousness on the
totality of human consciousness is to
raise it. And we did the mathematics on
that one time
and I forget the numbers but uh each
person at 500 is offsetting the negative
effect of probably tens of thousands of
people at the lower level. Were it not
so, mankind would drown in its own
negativity and self-destruct.
So each each forgiveness, each um
decision to love instead of hate, every
move we make in a spiritual direction,
helps bring all of mankind up to the
ultimate level, which we certainly hope
would be 500.
How does the body respond to oh negative
or positive statement independent of the
mind? Yes. Well, that's asking about the
kinesiologic test itself. Um, the
kinesiologic test is impersonal.
It's a response
of life at in its expression as
protoplasm
to the presence of truth or falsehood.
You know, the presence of truth or the
absence of truth. They're very strict.
So, it's almost like an analogous to
protoplasm. Consciousness recognizes
truth and like an electrostatic
condenser it recognizes electrons but it
does not recognize protons or posetrons.
So consciousness then is beyond personal
belief. So it's beyond mind and that
it's not within your capacity to change
it. Any of the questions that we ask
everybody will get the same answer to
irrespective of what your belief system
is about it.
That's a quality of consciousness itself
that it recognizes the reality of truth.
Anybody who's done the course of
miracles recognizes that statement that
only the real is real.
And therefore the the reason there's
nothing to fear is because only the real
is real and the unreal simply does not
exist.
That's what the kinesiologic test
confirms is that which is integrous
makes you go strong. That which is not
integrous because it has no reality. You
go weak because there the electric the
electric is off. You might say in the
presence of truth the electric goes on.
You go strong. In the absence of truth
you don't have a negative. You just have
the absence of truth. And because
there's an absence of truth there's no
electricity running down the wire and
you have no strength. So you drop you're
dropping because of the absence of the
truth and not because of the presence of
negativity.
Yeah.
Yeah, a lot of the things that we were
going to talk about came up in
questions. Um, is there evolution in
going to be is there evolution in
society amongst his leaders the material
practical world of business, education,
politics? And I do believe that these
are going to become demanded. I do
believe that
if nothing else, we can count on good
old greed to make sure we become
integrous.
You don't stock in the company. You want
to make sure the guy you put in his
president is calibrates over 200. You
know what I mean? Integrity pays. You're
going to see that non integrity takes
you down the tubes. It takes you to
bankruptcy. Yeah. It takes you to
bankruptcy.
U also of course the higher the level of
spiritual awareness, consciousness, the
people are healthier. We we know that
raising people's level of consciousness
of course of miracles of course is
everybody's uh common experience of that
is that the higher the level of
consciousness the greater the degree of
health the greater the resistance to
disease.
Um
I've come to believe um or
come to observe let's say that all
illnesses are cyclic. So every patient I
see in the office I hardly see any
patients at all anymore.
uh I've given up practically all the
practice but occasionally I stop it
still have some patients and uh when I
see a patient that the one thing I tell
them is that all illnesses are cyclic
uh every single illness that exists is
cyclic what does that mean it means it
comes and it goes tends to come and go
by its nature that which wasn't there
and now has come
must have but it must in its essence be
temporary temporary because therefore
if it was a reality it wouldn't have
come it would have always been. So if
it's if it's a temporariness that had an
onset then it has to have an also an
exit ramp.
That which came in on ramp has to have
an exit exit ramp as well.
Consequently all in illnesses cycle in
and out. What helps them to cycle out is
the advance first of all wearing out the
karmic propensity in the first place.
Secondly, the negative belief systems
that are supporting it. And I I think
they I think they karmically cycle out.
So I tell everybody, every illness I've
ever seen comes and goes. Everyone has a
capacity to go. If it hasn't gone yet
with you, then there's more you got to
be doing about it. or you just simply uh
have to be willing to to to wear out the
karmic timing of it.
Let's see. I lived a pretty bad life as
a pirate there for a number of years,
you know, and put a lot of people over
the side and killed a lot of infidels
and stuff. So, I don't know how much
suffering and how many veteran calls do
you have to put in for that? I don't
know.
went through the surgery there without
anesthesia and it was excruciating in
the middle of it. I remember exactly
what I did to that guy with a spear on
and I remember exactly
uh so how much pain and physical
suffering would satisfy my unconscious
that I have now paid that off. Do you
have to satisfy God with your suffering?
No. Oh God with your suffering. I mean
suffering is a penny game. Why would the
infinite God of all creation be
interested in whether you suffer or not?
Be bored to tears, wouldn't it? More
suffering. Oh, give me a break. Huh?
That's the old suffering ploy. Oh god,
look how I suffer.
Oh wow. So we have to get off that
suffering is holy. Stop genulecting
and dropping to our knees and worshiping
suffering and pain.
Um the God that we uh are speaking of is
not pleased with suffering and pain.
He's not pleased.
We ask permission to ask. That's fact.
Is it? No. God doesn't uh get off on
your pain and suffering. So who's
getting off on your pain and suffering?
The judge.
the savage, cruel, sadistic,
unrelenting, unmerciful inner judge. And
it's in each one of us and never
underrate the judge.
There's no degree of cruelty this judge
won't go to.
No amount of suffering. 20 years of
agony. Hey, those are just jacks for
openers.
Talk to me in another 20.