Well, I guess we're here.
Suddenly find yourself where you are.
It's amazing.
Well, this is the
12th of a series of lectures in which we
um intend to include everything you ever
need to know throughout all of time.
And what did I do with it? Now, let's
see. Here we have it right here.
This is all we need to know forever.
Well,
what's unique about the um the lectures
and the lecture is the combination of
the subjective and
which is nonlinear and um
and the linear which is the um Newtonian
paradigm of reality.
And what's been unique is that we had
the advantage for the first time
of having a technique of doing spiritual
research which has never been done
before.
What people talk when they talk about
spiritual research, they really are
talking about paleontology and
archaeology
where the great saints walked many
centuries ago. that had nothing to do
with spiritual truth which is a reality
a self-existent reality in the present.
So we had a means of exploring
unexplored realms
which in itself was mindboggling
and whatever left was left of the mind
was blown away for some time
and I had to retire from the world
completely because
so we've shared things that are rather
astonishing and one reason we use
kinesiologic
test during the lecture is just to
confirm things that seem outrageously
mind-boggling.
When it's all put together, they seem,
"Oh, yeah." But when you first hear it,
it may sound outrageous.
So, every month we discover something
new and dazzling,
and I thought we'd just start with
something new and dazzling today.
Uh,
everybody over 200, we'll ask this.
Everybody who calibrates over 200 goes
to a variety of heavens. Resist. Wow,
folks.
We told you you're karmically all set.
That's your level of conscious when
you're born
and that the moment of death is
predestined from the moment you're born.
You don't have to worry about death.
And now we're giving you the good news.
We discovered that and I it just came to
me and I said, "Whoa,
all over 200 go to a heaven because
there's multiple heavens." Resist. And
the heaven that you go to is aligned
with your calibrated level of
consciousness. Resist.
So
that does seem to solve a lot of spirit
religious conflict in which various
religious groups throughout time have
claimed
that they have an exclusive uh claim on
heaven. And only if you follow their
rituals and pay their dues do you get
into their heaven.
Sometimes the requirements are quite
outrageous. I don't know that I'd even
want to go to one of the heavens.
I don't want to insult any religion, but
some of them
have requirements to get into their
heaven that I think are somewhat
outrageous
uh and undemocratic.
So they ex they claim correctly it turns
out correctly that to be admitted to
their heaven these requirements need to
be followed.
Simple enough.
Those who wish to be with others that
are similar to themsel in belief
then
do have a certain realm where they
congregate. So that all makes sense,
doesn't it? that like goes to like
and that which uh
is committed to certain principles.
Then so there's a certain karmic
calibration certain not calibration
vibration a certain frequency then and
we said as you leave the body you
automatically find yourself in the realm
of your own vibration that's because
that's what you identify with and are
attracted to.
So that should handle the afterlife I
thought which would be good for openers.
The uh
the fate of people who are less than 200
is less fortunate.
The people less than 200 automatically
go to heavens resist. No that is not so.
H they go to other places but we would
not call them heavens. Uhhuh.
However,
they go to a place with which they're
familiar.
So
even that is not so bad, is it?
If you're used to killing killing others
and torturing prisoners and things like
that and you go on the other side, you
find yourself right in that realm where
all that goes on. So doesn't seem to you
like hell. It seems to you like home.
These people less than 200. We've never
asked this before. We have permission to
ask this. Resist. Just find themselves
what they consider to be home. Resist.
So much for the fears of heaven and
hell. And
it makes sense that one would find
oneself
in the realm uh to which one is
committed.
Uh
people sometimes say, "Well, it's too
bad you have these calibrated levels
because people can use it to say one
thing is better than another." Well, if
you do, that's your problem. It's not my
problem.
You can say having a Cadillac is better
than a Buick. I mean this is all in your
mind.
Uh it isn't that one thing is better
than another. Each thing is a
stratification of that which it is.
Spiritually evolved people tend to look
down on the lower levels and say isn't
that awful?
These levels below 200 they'll serve
serve
in their own way because
you see each thing is relative.
So angriness we said that the human life
on this planet is
of such a range there's an infinite
number of possibilities
and therefore
for the people down here this is high.
Huh? So instead of disparaging that
people live
in less than what we consider
spiritually idealistic levels of
consciousness
because this world is and I've forgotten
the world word
it'll come to me um
you know where you go to work off bad
karma and earn good karma. What's the
name of that?
>> Huh?
>> Purgatorial.
>> Oh purgatorial. Yeah,
because this is sort of a purgatorial.
I'm not going to call it purgatory. You
don't say he said it was purgatory. It's
purgatorial.
And that we have the whole range from
the ultimate
both ends of the scale.
So those people who live in rage,
hatred, and anger,
here's rage, hatred, and anger. Can you
imagine what a great high that is?
Look, I I I treat lots of girls like
that. And angryness, everything makes
them angry. They come in for the
staffing and I say, "What's the matter?
I'm angry."
Everything makes her angry.
Having to wait to come in makes her
angry. Being at staff meeting makes her
angry. Having to leave the staff meeting
makes her angry. You know what I mean?
What they have for breakfast makes her
angry. They live in the angry box.
And they're always hitting each other
and being angry.
And you say, why would they want to live
in angryness? To us, angryness is sort
of an unpleasant sensation. And you say,
"Dear Lord, please help me see this
differently.
Get me out of this anger." And
spiritually we sort of feel ashamed that
we sunk down to the lover of anger. This
is a high to people in apathy.
You see, we don't understand a lot of uh
music, gangster rock and hate rock or
what do you call it? Kill your sister
and rape your mother and stab your aunt.
Rape your neighbors. I mean, you know,
great stuff like that. And we say, man,
that is really degenerate. You know what
I mean?
uh these whole groups that make and
they'll tell you the reason they do is
they make huge amounts of money.
Well, making huge amounts of money,
folks,
is a heck of a lot better than being at
the bottom,
apathetic, penniles, povertystricken,
laying there, dying of starvation with
AIDS, Bafraa.
So if you come in at this level then
getting up to greed
anything is better than huh
you so now you understand the attraction
of this
self-righteous anger
this kind of music they play what do
they call it
there sort of an angriness rap yeah you
did this to me. You guys did that to me.
Now I'm going to get eat with you.
And they they feed off that crap. You
say, "What's with these people? Are they
smoking something or what?"
Well,
you people are going to get it and you
did it to me and now you Yeah, you're
getting yours and we're all getting even
and I'm angry.
And that's prideful, too. That's really
cocky. And the names of the groups are
usually the super supers.
The king of the supers.
The super super king of the supers.
Supers best.
All right. Now we can have compassion
for that because you see coming out of
apathy. Look at all these people down
here. The one thing we didn't get done
for the lectures that I wanted to do is
the map of the world in which we
calibrate the different continents.
and the different countries within the
continents.
That's a map that's really critical to
our State Department.
When you see who the heck you're dealing
with, folks, you know,
democracy, what does democracy mean to
somebody who calibrates at 45,
who's starving to death in the streets?
Democracy is an idealistic
pomposity.
It's a pomposity to people who live on
that level.
Unreal.
And it doesn't work.
It never dawns on Americans that many
countries, in fact, even continents are
not even ready for democracy. Wouldn't
know what to do with it. Has no value to
them. If you give it to them, they'll
quickly destroy it
because it has no value. Uh democracy
doesn't mean much of anything till you
get for around the 400s or high 300s. It
doesn't mean anything. It's stupid.
Many countries think to let people run
around doing and saying what they want.
It was really ultra stupid and America
deser gets what it deserves, you know.
All right. So begin then to be able to
accept the whole range of consciousness
without a better than a greater than a
right wrong moralistic
uh positionality about it
if you are in apathy. So the great
goonas you know piti comes out in three
gonas you know tamas rajas and satta
classically in Sanskrit tamas
is that of lethargy and resistance and
these people starve to death and they
don't have the energy when you walk
through their neighborhoods it's
littered with trash
you know you can tell by the energy of
the neighborhood and and it pulls it
pulls that to apathetic.
I remember seeing one of the most
beautiful waterfalls
uh I guess it's in this hemisphere
in this hemisphere and uh after a long
trail ride to get there and all and
here's this gorgeous waterfall with a
pool at the bottom and there's you know
there's broken down plastic tricycles
and paper bags and crap all over the
place.
So the people indig the people
indigenous to the area in apathy you
don't have the energy or the interest to
pick up trash around you. You just kick
it around and walk by it.
You don't have any pride there in the
pride. You don't clean up the trash
until you get out of here starting to
want something better. Get angry about
the miserableness of your life and have
enough pride to pick up the trash.
So the first sign of apathy then is the
so-called broken window
theory of sociology.
The first factory window that you don't
fix attracts the next broken window.
Attracts the graffiti, attracts the
mice, attracts the drug addicts,
attracts murder, apathy, suicide,
poverty.
All right. So out of the bottom here,
the person in apathy, in grief, this
person is paralyzed by fear. You can
imagine how good it feels.
Now you begin to understand the suicide
bomber.
The suicide bomber,
a nobody at all, suddenly becomes
a somebody
now commits himself to an integrous act
believing that it is for God.
Bang. He willfully sacrifices his life
for God and probably goes up into a
state of ecstasy.
Ecstasy. The kamicazi father was in a
That's correct. Resist
from being nobody and nothing and living
in fear.
You sacrifice your life for God as you
understand them or your country and you
shoot above this level.
And I'm sure they're in a state of
ecstasy because I can psychically
connect with them.
Now we begin to understand the purpose
of the world that provides the infinite
panorama,
an infinite panorama in which all of
this can take place. And by playing our
part in this panorama, we serve others.
Each one of us serves others merely by
being there.
So we can end up respecting them all.
As mistaken as we think they might be,
one must say
there's something to respect about
someone who's willing to sacrifice his
life
for his country, his cause, for God,
whatever. Huh? So to us we see it as
madness, mistakenness.
But now if we recontextualize it, we can
get a sense of what it must be. Huh?
Because if we moralize about it, we
can't handle it because that blinds us
to the reality of what it is. Huh?
And so there are the warrior heavens.
to go above this level, to die for
honor.
And you see the movies of World War II
in which they died for honor or they
were willing to die for honor. And when
the war is over, the warriors on both
sides become great buddies,
great buddies. And they meet every
victory day and celebrate each other's
valor.
So that takes us to the Valhalla.
There is an a place that the word
Valhalla would be correct.
The warrior heavens
to sacrifice one's life out of bravery
and courage takes you over 200.
So now you see the purpose of war
there on that stage.
You can walk into the bullets
and shoot over 200.
If you haven't done it before, try it.
It's exhilarating.
It is fantastic to walk into the
bullets. There is a high. There is a
charge. There is a knowingness.
There is a knowingness of being
connected with an infinite power and
integrity.
And you can't experience it unless you
walk into the bullets.
All right. That isn't what I was going
to talk about today.
Today we were going to talk about Oh,
yes. Today's lecture had a name. People
always want names for lectures.
We can't just say we're going to talk
about whatever, you know.
All the things we talk about are of
equal value.
Now today we're talking about um
the subject is the final moments.
that the name of the title final moment
in a way I wanted the 12 lectures to be
a totality a whole to take on from the
beginning all the way to the end to
connect the linear and the nonlinear
to include what we've been able to find
through spiritual research which has not
been known before and put it to
uh the service of everyone time.
And so the lectures have been
preparatory. We started out by
describing the structure of the ego and
by understanding how it's put together
and how it evolved out of the animal
kingdom. We get out of judgmentalism
about it. We see it's the
animal within us still exists as part of
our brain. The animal brain is still
there.
That gets us off the right and wrong
moralistic duality
positionality about it and we accept it
for what it is.
So we undo
the structure of the ego which stands in
the way of enlightenment.
We do it by seeing that it adopts
positionalities and these
positionalities then create duality.
The dualistic view of the world then
results in perception which obscures the
vision
of radical spiritual truth.
Somebody asked what is the name of the
whole all your lectures and books and
videotapes and all the teaching.
It comes from no
specific lineage
and we'll give it a name because people
like names
and we'll call it devotional
non-duality.
Now we have a name
devotional duality.
People say what do you study? I study
devotional non-duality.
Everyone here is at this great moment in
history and time,
the birth of devotional non-duality.
Wow.
Well, we need special hats or something,
don't we?
If you persist in the practices we've
described is
contemplation and meditation
and understand um
the ego begins to dissolve get dissolve
when when you understand it as you
understand it sort of
begins to limply fall away.
So there's less standing in your way.
Then you get to serious spiritual
practice
either in a formal meditative uh form
or in the kind of meditation which
I tend to favor which is more a
contemplative meditation which is
continuous at all times throughout the
day no matter what you're doing
in which one focuses on context instead
of content.
The focus is on the totality of the
experience
and not on the specifics,
the value of that
which I've never really, you know,
specifically defined
for the group.
I'll I'll write it out and if you miss
this, you miss everything of great
value.
You've been waiting for this moment,
folks. Oh, I know you can't see this,
but
what it all amounts to, we're going to
put in one simple design that unravels
all the secrets of the universe
throughout all of time.
I wish I wish they could see it. Honey,
we have to pull this critter out here.
I don't know how we do that, folks. It
doesn't have wheels.
Okay. Whoa.
>> All right. Now, we're going to specify
something in a in a way that I think
will really resolve it uh completely and
totally.
What was it?
We said the ego is linear.
And this this particular if we call it a
pathway pathway
emphasizes the importance of realizing
the difference between content and
context.
See because content is
content is uh specifics. See
and it's got a shape. It's got a design.
It therefore is in the linear domain.
This is in the linear domain. We we call
this content
because this is what your mind is
focusing on
specifics. So we call this content. Mr.
Content. Hi.
This is Mr. Content. So
this is the linear world. The Newtonian
paradigm of reality,
the linear paradigm of reality, radical
mechanistic reductionism, scientific
reductionism, materialistic reductionism
of science says it's not real unless you
can measure it, weigh it,
locate it in time and place.
Science to this day says that's all
that's real.
The madman at the edge of science are
into quantum mechanics. But the 99.9% of
science
wants this. In fact, they even put that
in the name of the journals now. It's
called evidence-based something or
other. They just discovered evidence.
Wow. Since the time of hypocrates, the
patient either gets better or it doesn't
get better. We call that evidence,
right? They just discovered it is in the
year 2001.
Called evidence. This is your evidence.
It's measurable.
It's subject to the differential
calculus.
Sir Isaac Newton then gave us the
mathematics.
The linear domain is solvable solvable
through differential the differential
calculus. Sir Isaac Newton who
calibrates at 499. A great genius. The
great geniuses all calibrate at 499.
is the master of the mathematics of this
realm.
This is what the world considers real.
This is
content.
If we were dissatisfied with content, we
wouldn't be here.
Now we sense that there's something
other than content.
There's something other than the
material measurable
and that is
the indefinable
context.
The ego
identifies with content.
Spirit is context.
And here is the great difficulty that
people don't understand
that content depends on context.
Therefore, the facious means to obtain
truth which ignore context.
This is true. They say true always
forever and it's sacred. It's true. We
worship at the world of science the
measurable, the definable
because to them this is real.
The upsetting news however
is this is comprehensible only because
of context.
is because of context.
The relationship between content and
context is then what spiritual work is
all about.
In the style of contemplation
or meditation which I describe in the
book and in the lectures and all one
learns to focus on the context
the person who is not spiritually
oriented is focused and identifies with
this as reality
is fixed constantly on content
is focused on specifics
and loses the whole awareness of
context.
The experience of the presence of God is
when context totally sweeps away
all except
the infinite allness which includes
includes content but only as part of
context. Now this dissolves into part of
the context.
All right.
If we take another content over here,
another smiley content.
If we focus here, this little smiley
face is part of the context.
If we focus here, this is part of the
context.
So context then includes whatever you're
not looking at.
The minute you shift vision, now that's
part of the context because what you're
looking at now is the content.
And that that little practice takes us
right to the door of understanding
quantum mechanics
that the observed
shifts based on the observer. Of course,
the minute I focus on this
and this is my focus of interest. Now,
this is just another piece of furniture
in the room. Doesn't have any value. you
know, it's just out there
and I focus on this. This is what's real
and this is just out there.
All right?
So that relationship between content and
context then is very
um a way in which we can bring the
totality of spiritual
versus personal into some kind of a
comprehensible form. We'll move this
away.
Um, I don't usually write notes because
they confuse me. Oh, yes. Content is
form and content. Yeah. Oh, yeah. I
remember now why I did this in the first
place.
How did I screw it all up like that?
Wow.
>> And there we resolve the entire
relationship between the Newtonian and
the non-newtonian, between the linear
and the nonlinear
and we take you right through the door
into the infinite quantum potentiality
without having to bother with the
shortinger equations.
You'll be relieved by that.
How in the back of the the new book I
put the quantum mechanic history etc for
those of you who are obsessive
compulsive and need proof
and when you see what you got to do to
agree with the proof you say old doc's
probably right I'll just take his word
for it
the purpose of all this is because
the book power versus force never really
specifically came down to this concrete
depiction.
So the linear is the world of force
specifics.
However, power
is a quality.
We call it a quality. We project that
thought onto it. Is a quality of
context.
The ego then identifies with content
whereas its reality is coming as is is a
consequence of context
in the meditative or contemplative state
of which in which we constantly
surrender content as it arises.
Those of you in the 12th step have been
the 12th step, you know the third step,
the willingness to totally and surrender
all to God at every instant.
As this comes up, we totally surrender
it to God. We do so in the interest of
the context.
The ego would have you think that
the mind, let's say, the mind and ego
are one of the same thing.
And karma, karma, mind, and ego are all
the same thing.
They're all the same thing. You don't
have to worry about that anymore.
You are your karma.
And how are you your karma? The form
that your mind takes in the ego
structure. So
alo that's one reason Jesus didn't talk
about it much because if you just solve
your problems in the present you're
solving your karma because because you
are your karmic problem that's why
you're here you know just worry about
what you are now that solves all the
karma because the way you are now is due
to all the karma. So if you do it now,
you undone your karma. So you don't have
to worry about karma unless you're
really hung up on it.
Occasionally we get people that are hung
up on their karma and I tell them, look,
get a one of these regressionists. They
take you back to previous lifetime and
you get to reexperience it. Sometimes
it's really quite relieving and quite
amazing. And some of those techniques
are quite effective,
very good. Sometimes they resolve your
doubt about something. Oh, now I see why
I don't like something rather. So, yeah.
Well, I wouldn't either under the
circumstances that he recalls, you know.
All right. At least at least you can
feel better about it.
If you assiduously,
assiduously,
committedly,
fervently,
constantly surrender everything as it
comes up to God
and stay related to
the generality of that which is around
you rather than the specifics.
If you do this devotedly,
one eventually transcends the
identification with with the content of
the ego.
We know you you'll be able to tell when
it's happening.
Your friends will say you're strange for
one thing.
Your friends say you're strange. you
know, you're making very good progress.
You really need to see a doctor. That's
a real good.
I mean, he's really flipped out. He's
losing it, you know? He's into this
whole God business. And
left home wife and kids and all.
Yeah. So
we can see just from the emotions you
see here's the process going on in
consciousness.
Uh
we see why these states are high. These
people are into destruction. They're
close to death dispondency. They're
withdrawn. They become slaves. They are
the slaves of the world.
And we see then the ego inflation of
pride uh gives you a feeling that you're
somebody and that's why they walk around
so cocky. Now you feel like somebody.
They're trying to steal this feeling
here without actually being this and it
doesn't work.
So pride is easily knocked off of its
pride leadth to downfall because it's
vulnerable. It's not based on reality.
It's an inflation. It's an inflation.
Boom. Boom. Boom. Boom. They pop up with
inflation. So, it's fake. So, on the
other hand, it feels good. It feels
good. Pride feels quite good.
Uh, but then pride meets the test of
whether it's actually courage.
And that's why the United States Marines
enlist you on the level of pride, but
then they move you to the level of
courage cuz pride won't hold up on the
battlefield.
Pride chickens out and runs. So
the Marines want you to move from pride,
being proud of being a Marine, coming
out of a lesser socioeconomic status.
And for once you're a gentleman.
So you salute them out of pride.
But then they train you. So the training
of the service is to take you out of
pridefulness, out of apathy, out of
self-centeredness
and into courage.
And so
traditionally throughout the centuries
the army the enlistment in the service
of the country has been one of the
pathways to integrity.
One of the pathways to integrity.
Of course it's possible to fail it and
crash.
Oh. So
I wanted to answer however by this
explanation the objection that one level
is better than another. It's not better
than another. It's different than
another and it's serving a different
purpose. Serving a different purpose.
You see
a pres you can't have a president of the
United States down here, you know, and
you can't have a president up there
either.
What kind of a president would a guy be
in 600?
Boys, boys, let's not fight.
I say peace
to North Korea. Peace to Afghanistan.
>> There's a lot around like that.
I don't understand what she's saying.
>> Gandhi Gandhi Gandhi
>> Gandhi calibrated you know at 700
Gandhi stood against the British Empire.
The British Empire at the time that
Gandhi stood up to it calibrated about
190. If I remember it was up
British Empire was around in 190 that
the position the position of the British
Empire at the time was about 190
resistance. Yeah.
Pride of the empire
hottiness. Hottiness.
The British aristocracy was notably
hotty
as are all most aristocracies.
which cost them their heads of course
famous Zars and their families etc.
Let them meet cake. So
Mahatma Gandhi however calibrated at 700
and you see Gandhi didn't attack the
British Empire nor did he run from it.
So he he took a a position of
uh standing for truth.
The question is always when you're
attacked what should your position be?
And the position should be to stand up
for truth to be answerable and to stand
for truth
whatever the consequences.
That's what Mahatma did. Mandi did he
merely confronted the British Empire
from a position of 700 the British
Empire calibrated at 190.
So that confrontation between 700 which
is enormously powerful
you see these rings of power out there
as you get up to 6700 and all
the context become is the power.
So you just stand there. We said that
power just stands there. It doesn't do
anything like gravity.
Can you imagine if you tried to measure
the influence on of gravity
and all its multitudinous expressions?
The figure would be incalculable, so
immense.
We'd have to weigh every object on the
planet and put them all together and we
would come up with a fantastic number.
It does all that just by standing there,
just by being what it is. Gravity
doesn't do anything.
700 is a very powerful field.
So 700 just stood there and stood for
integrity.
And then the British Empire at 190 ran
up against the brick wall of power at
700.
And therefore, Gandhi defeated the
British Empire without a shot.
Gorbachev defeated
comm the communist
monolithic
regime
also without firing a shot. There was no
giant Russian revolution that put down
the communist
empire. It fell. It fell apart.
Now it's in great disarray because it's
nowhere near capable of handling
democracy.
We'll have to find some means probably
few maybe go back to feudal times.
That's pretty good as a starting point.
Feudal times is where all of modern
civilization did start from at one time,
didn't it?
So
the difference between power and force
then is that power accomplishes
by virtue of the quality of that which
it is.
It doesn't have to do anything.
What does the spiritual aspirant
do for the world?
What they do for the world is a
consequence of that which they become.
Requires no effort whatsoever.
Wasn't doesn't have to do anything
except to be
your own potential.
So as spirituality evolves then what
happens is the power of the context the
field begins to shift.
We see whole continents, whole
neighborhoods, whole countries,
counties, towns,
neighborhoods within the town dominated
by certain energy fields. That energy
field now becomes more important
than the content.
You know it. The minute you walk into
it, the hair goes up on the back of your
head. you know you're in trouble even
though there's nobody threatening you on
the street. This is not a safe space.
You get that?
Certain neighborhoods that demented
you're in them. You get that
there are other places on the planet
where nobody would even think of
graffiti. I've been in great and
beautiful places
had they been located elsewhere
in which there is no graffiti
unlike the subway in New York.
Anybody ever ride the subway system in
New York?
Covered with graffiti vulgarity.
Yeah.
All right. What I really wanted to
emphasize today was the value that each
of these things serves its own purpose.
You see, each of these things serves its
own purpose. Each one of these things
has a conccomant emotion. Huh?
We disparage that which is below the
level below these levels.
In more advanced spiritual work, of
course, the the greatest significance
the greatest significance is not over on
the right hand side. The greatest
significance is
over on the left hand side
because
we begin to experience how
this evolves
through spiritual understanding. And so
the real focus of the spiritual aspirant
is how to overcome the residuals of the
old animal within your brain. How to
stop identifying with that. How to stop
condemning yourself, feeling guilty
about it. How to accept and love the
little animal.
If you're spiritually oriented,
everything with everything in the world
serves you. Everything in the world
serves you.
The other night, we were watching a
video of the greatest uh tiger
trainer in the world. I think he's
Russian or Yugoslavian. Slavic, I think.
Anyway,
he handles 10 or 11 wild Bengal tigers
all at once.
He adores them.
You feel the profound intense
love that he has for him. So his power,
I told you I'd put this where you can't
see it.
His power over the animals
is his intense love. He's aware of who
he is. He's aware of who they are and
they know it.
So when you watch him work 10 or 12
tigers at once, they all move in unison.
He has them almost spellbound
by the power of his love for them.
However,
at no time does he forget that they are
basically a wild animal and if you push
him, he'll kill you.
A very interesting lesson.
At no time does he turn his back
or is he neglectful
or does he go into denial that they will
kill you?
That's true. The most domesticated tamed
wild animal if provoked at the right
moment will eat you up.
We mentioned that case history in one of
the earlier lectures.
In that case, the lion ate her out of
love.
But
his concern was not that tigers would
eat them out of love, but that he would
provoke them.
So he, you see, you can love everything
and yet not be naive.
That's the downside of the 500s.
The downside of the 500s
is
you walk in a world of love. Only love
is real. The only lovingness is what you
see. Lovingness is what you experience.
In the beginning, there's a great naive
to it.
Spiritual awareness like other things
goes through various degrees of
maturity.
And the early adolescent is enthused
about spirituality and goes around hoo
la and praying for peace and sort of
fairy land of happiness.
The downside of that is an extreme
vulnerability. The naivee.
You see the tiger trainer is not naive.
And yet his love is intense. His love is
so intense. These tigers all behave
out of respect for him.
Therefore,
as a teacher, the purpose of today's
lecture is to prepare you for the
downside of what will come up if you're
spiritually seriously committed.
If you run around to lectures, read
books here and there, and play around
with the astral realm, get channelings
and all that, you won't have to deal
with this.
But if you're serious, the downside will
come up. All right. There is that which
is opposed to spiritual truth
and it has dominated mankind
until the late 1980s. You remember the
level of consciousness of mankind until
the late 1980s was 190. That means those
energies which oppose God, deny God and
would rather
have control of you and uh your beloveds
did dominate this
planet until the late 1980s.
Then for reasons
not completely or totally known, the
consciousness level jumped to 207.
As you evolve spiritually,
you see your power, the not your power,
but the power of your your energy field,
your aura, whatever you call call it um
becomes more and more powerful begins to
dominate
and that which was used to dominating
and controlling
until very recent times is therefore or
threatened by every spiritual aspirant.
Everyone who reaches unconditional love
then
diminishes the domain of that which is
non- integrous diminishes its control.
Consequently, one becomes the target for
that which is that is non-integrous and
would like to entrap you in its control.
So the downside of the 500s is that
naivity
in which you love everything and see
everybody as lovable
and as a consequence become blind.
Many are the gurus of great renown both
dead and alive today who reached the
high of the mid mid usually the mid 500s
and were taken down one after another
their numbers are rather shocking
at one time calibrate 520 540
now 180 huh
What happens?
You see, the tiger trainer does not
pretend
pretend that the tiger won't kill you
under if you ignore his in inner nature.
He demonstrates to me that you can love
and still be aware of the downside of
what you're dealing with.
If you think you can turn over your
trust fund to anybody who wanders down
the street and says he'd like to do it
for you, you will soon be a poor person.
Well, I trust everybody.
I only believe in holiness and love.
Well, folks,
how many people's retirement funds got
sucked in by that one
not long ago? Huh?
All right. So, the downside of the 500s,
unconditional love doesn't mean to be
blind.
Doesn't mean to be blind.
Be aware that all this is out here.
And frankly, it wants to get you.
I hate to tell you that
I want you cuz
I want to control you. I want your money
and I want power of you and you want you
to sign up. You can stand for what you
are without necessarily provoking them.
The reason I say this is because
in this
experience quote which the world calls
personal.
Such a thing did happen more than once.
It can happen in the non-material world
and of for those who are spiritually
committed the danger is one of spiritual
seduction.
We're going to talk about the traps
along the way and then we're going to
lead up to the final doorway. But you
don't get to the final doorway without
going through the 500s in various
places. So I'll tell you
as tourists what the traps are there.
The tourist traps in the 500s.
The trusting, sweet,
loving, adorable old lady.
They love to take your money.
When I was a kid, I was always looking
for a job.
So one day one time in the it said uh
the saleserson wanted so you know I'm 16
or 17 18 what I need a summer job in
summer break from school or college
whatever it was. So the idea was this
guy would train you to sell peanut
machines, you know, the kind you put a
penny into them. At those days they were
selling for $25. So the idea was you
advertise how to make a lot of money and
etc. All these retired farmers will buy
these machines for $25
and you tell them look you go there once
a month, take your money out
or you drive around to all your machines
and you empty all the money out. So this
guy figured, gee, there's an ad on TV
right now about this ATMs or something.
Another sucker bait sound like to me.
Uh, so
what you don't tell them is the peanut
machine, if it empties every couple of
years, it's going to be lucky.
How often do you think a peanut machine
empties? It empties this year, you're
lucky.
All these peanut machines, he thinks all
the money's coming in. So this guy was
obviously a con man. See? So
I I've had an uneasy feeling about this,
you know, and uh but I mean I said to
him, "Well, what about these farmers?
This is I mean this is their retirement
money, their nestic they're going to
live on the rest of their life."
He said, "Well, if we don't get it,
somebody else will."
You got it. There you go. So the
rationalization is always there. The
rationalization is always there.
Happily, I had enough integrity not to
get sucked into that one.
But um so they're out there. Now in the
spiritual world, the seduction takes
place in a different way.
How should we explain it?
My concern is that
my own students be forewarned.
It's a lack of education. You say how
can people who was up at 540 or
something uh fall for the seduction of
fame, money, power,
material goods, trappings.
It's because something was missing in
their spiritual education.
You could say, "Well, it's their fault.
They should have."
Yeah. But nobody forewarned them. So, I
don't want to go to my deathbed
thinking, "Oh my god, what I didn't
say."
If you get suckered in, I feel it's my
uh karmic responsibility, you know.
Though
that which is glamorous,
spiritual seduction takes the form of a
glamour. A lot of times there's drama,
there's theater, there's fancy titles,
fancy clothing.
I hate to say it, but most of them come
from India.
The reason is India is old at this.
Old at it. They've got it down so slick
that you wouldn't know a swami from a
swimming.
You see truth is in it is is not in need
of any trappings. Truth is not
interested in seducing anybody,
impressing anybody, glamorizing anybody.
Truth is sufficient unto itself. It
comes not from elsewhere. Therefore, you
need nothing out there. Truth has no
external teacher. There's no other
entity telling me what to say. Somebody
once said, "How do you channel all
that?"
That's funny. Anyway,
the knowingness is innate
to speak with such authority. Do you
realize the karmic consequences
of speaking an error?
So
no, the truth comes from within. It is
not given from elsewhere. There is no
other.
All the way through to the infinite
presence in which only the oness is.
No other entities along the way. No
saints, no
babas, no angels,
no others. There is no other.
No celestial teachers
arose.
Radical non-duality dispenses with all
that.
Those are all sidetracks. Those are all
illusions.
that which appears mystical, magical,
and you know it's coming when you hear
the oo and the o's.
Oh, Baba, so and so. Whoa.
You know what that means? That means
that person has been glamorized.
Glamorized.
I get letters every day. They're
heartbreaking.
every day usually with a picture of some
guru
who was a descendant of
you know they list all kinds of famous
names in history and this person is
going to save mankind and this person
believe there is or not can undo all
your negative karma
this person is an avatar who will undo
all your negative karma
and has millions of f followers in India
this is a routine letter I get every day
it's always a different swami your guru
has millions of followers in India
calibrates at 290
over and over this comes up
mama this sells mama and baba baba this
and mama that
the great mother of India is going to
save all mankind she calibrates at 300
I'm telling you that
I thought so this was disturbing for a
while I thought you know spiritual
research I wish I'd never even started
Yeah, I was perfectly happy in a state
of bliss. Frankly,
that's not the contract. The contract
was to share with that which I've
discovered for the good of all.
My that's my contract with God.
So that how can this be? one after
another gurus you know we're calibrating
a thousand things for the
next book after I and uh over and over
well-known teachers spiritual teachers
at one time 520 540 most of them were in
the high mid mid 500s
and now 180
disparity we were getting different
numbers on the same teacher
When they're young, they were this and
now they're this. Huh?
The world doesn't know that.
Often the early writings are if you
calibrate them quite high,
the teacher now is below 200.
How can this be? Hm. Well,
how can the teacher is only 280 be be
the savior of millions of India? The
great s the great avatar. It's going to
undo all your negative karma and save
mankind.
The letter infers that I should quickly
run and see this person get saved or
something.
Well, because didn't make sense till I
realized that 290 to people down here is
like a god.
Of course, you worship somebody who has
integrity,
confidence, speaks of love, is concerned
about you and your welfare. This is a
shock.
People live down here
they are like a saint.
So okay that explained it then.
So they are great whatever their
calibration is in that they serve the
world in that capacity.
So that explained that dilemma.
Therefore, it's important not to be not
to vary. You see, straight and narrow is
the way.
The Buddha said the middle path, not too
far this way, not too far this way.
Straight and narrow is the way
to be committed to integrity. Then be
forewarned that that which
is glamorous,
impressive,
theatrical,
a whole production
that has a hierarchy that you can buy
your way into
is out after your naivity.
That which comes from absolute truth has
no need of trappings. What is the
purpose of trappings and performance and
theater?
That's to entrance the audience.
Truth has no interest in an audience at
all.
If nobody hears, nobody's here. It's no
it's all the same. Makes no difference.
There's no gain, no loss.
So a lot of times you go around to
various spiritual things and there is
all kinds of theater, entertainment,
drama,
ritual,
smoke and incense and the whole deal
that goes with it. Mystical rituals.
You better calibrate it first.
The best thing to do is calibrate it. Of
course, it said sends you into a ooh
mood.
So does a good movie.
So I was getting stoned.
Lots of things make you feel good and
woozy.
There's a legitimate high from doing
mantras, from being in the company of
other holy people.
from being in a situation in which
one sees the sacredness of the beauty.
And so there is legitimate sacred
ritual.
The downside then we were trying to
research what what happened to people
who seem to be of spiritual integrity
one time. What happened to them?
Well,
the personality was still dominant. This
personality was still there
because it's not just spiritual people
that that happens too. It happened to
Napoleon.
If you calibrate Napoleon on his rise,
you know, he was a genius. He was a very
high IQ,
he calibrated around, I think 450 or
something. Very powerful. 450 is a very
big energy. Napoleon on his way up was
450 or 460, something like that. But
then once he gained the power,
he went down to like 140 or something.
So
it happens then not just the spiritual
teachers who get impressed by
edgulation of followers or
apparently money.
I hear about them all the time. This
week I heard of another spiritual
teacher who I didn't know that much
about.
What in the world would want a
somebody who is teaching truth want with
money and power?
What would you do with it?
In a really high state, which is
probably around the 800s or something
there, the temptation came in luciferic,
but it was nonverbal and non-personal.
Now that you have transcended all
personal karma karma,
all power is yours. own it.
The luciferic temptation, but that's a
very high one. That's a different one.
It was an easy one to turn down
because power would be a burden.
No thanks.
Spiritual motivators take give you
lectures on how to create abundance. My
lectures are devoted to how to handle
the problem of abundance.
Everyone here who knows what I'm saying.
I mean, it's a drag. Where do you put
it? What do you do with it? There's no
more room in the closet. You know what
I'm saying?
All the ownership certificates and the
how to do manuals that go with stuff. I
mean, it stacks up
as life goes on. You've got Christmas
presents from years back that are
unopened. You know,
the directions are printed in China in
very small faint print.
I look at it and I say, "Gee, there must
be somebody I can give this to next
Christmas, you know, the postman or
somebody, you know."
No, the trouble the pro, you know,
abundance is a problem. So, who would
want it? The same with power. Who would
want it?
But anyway, if that is unfinished within
oneself, that apparently is what we
discerned. Um, the glamour of power. Oh,
I get it. It isn't power. It's the
glamour of power. Got it. Okay.
It isn't power, it's the glamour of
power. Oh, the seduction of the glamour
of power. How nice. Thank you, Lord.
Okay. So, it isn't the power they fall
for. It's the seduction of the glamour
of power. Okay. All right. Because when
power came to me, I
see because if you're complete and total
within yourself, then you're immune to
seduction. Because seduction is based on
the fact that there's something you want
out there. If you don't want anything,
what could be offered then that would be
interesting?
As I mentioned,
70 virgins when you're 80 is not really
a great offer.
Your own personal massage therapist that
might appeal
There is nothing you need out there. The
self within is complete and total.
Has no need for anything such as the
glamour of power.
The glamour or implied whatever it is
about money that people like so much
about money.
Those are the great seductions
apparently.
to be attracted by that which is
impressive and glamorous by virtue of
its strangeness.
Master so and so on the other side you
know and he channels
by these horses
by this acorage.
Also a true teacher never advises
on personal affairs. you should leave
your wife, you should leave your
children.
That's pretty commonly done.
Now, if a relationship is unintegrous,
very, you know, really down here, and
there's a lot of them like this, you're
married to a rager and there's no peace
and you can't meditate because things
are being thrown at you all the time.
Your own commitment to your own
spiritual integrity
will eventually lead lead you to leaving
that which is non integrous.
You leave that which is non integrous
because
you evolve to that point not because
some teacher guru leader or whatever
they call himself master.
Um
so to be told that you must break up
relationship, leave your family, all
this is nonsense. These are all control
freaks
in which the relationship you see
interferes with the leader's dominance
over you. As long as there's a wife
there, she's a lot of wives are harder
to fool.
Your intuition says, you know, there's
something wrong with this guy. And he
says, oh, he's the true leader. is going
to lead me to. She says, "I don't know.
He seems a little too interested in
money for me."
She catches it years before. He finds
out years later. Now he's cleaned out
and now he goes into severe depression.
So recent years there been a whole
there's been a fall of a whole series
of teachers from the same country. Some
have come to this country and we've seen
the great consequences.
But you see the great pain and suffering
that the pe the followers go through
that it's the spiritual disillusionment
the spiritual rape
to have been raped spiritually
that once innocence has been
raped
by masterful seduction.
The techniques of spiritual seduction
have evolved in that culture
for a thousand years and thousands of
years.
Eskimos don't do it much.
The culture just doesn't contain that
kind of rigomeroll.
Okay,
now I can die peacefully. I told you.
One of the reasons we emphasize the
kinesiologic truth is because man in his
innocence has no way of knowing truth
from falsehood.
Throughout all time, man had no means of
knowing truth from falsehood.
To my view, therefore, his
responsibility was somewhat mitigated.
You be expected to sail the seas without
a compass or a sexton is asking a lot of
a sailor.
So we as mankind then can be proud that
we have survived this far without a sex
tender a compass. We now have some means
of checking out whether
this is truth or falsehood coming from
this source.
Oh, that's pretty heavy this morning,
folks. We better take a break.
We'll take a break and reconvene when
you like in a little while.
I said what I had to say.
I owed it to