Any
questions out there? Yes. Um I'm
interested in uh the stability or the
variability in moving up and down saying
in a day or a week's time.
>> Your question is does the level of
consciousness fluctuate throughout the
day?
>> Oh yes. Well, we said level
consciousness is set by spiritual
decision.
It's really the spiritual will that sets
it. So consciousness is a little more
stable than that. Emotions tend to come
and go, but your level of spiritual
commitment hasn't really changed. You
say, "Well, I'd like to kill that guy
and he deserves to get beat up and I
hope he gets his." And then you say,
"Well, would you do that?" Well, not
really.
say you were spinning off an emotion
uh but that's not who you really are. So
we inherit an emotional body which
becomes known to the world as your
persona
personality emotional body but it's not
the real you. It's sort of the eancent
play uh interaction with the world
making learned appropriate responses
etc. And but it's not the real you
because the real you is when your life
depends on it. What would you say in
this situation? And you'd say thumbs up
or thumbs down. Well, whether you vote
thumbs up or thumbs down is going to
make a big decision.
So if the gladiator out there, the crowd
says thumbs up or thumbs down, if you
vote with the thumbs down, you join the
karma of the crowd who chose his death
for the sheer thrill of watching him
bleed all over the sand.
Done thousands of times.
You, on the other hand, could be the one
who puts his thumb up. Huh? If you do,
you may get the fury of the crowd. So,
you're in a hell of a place.
The crowd will kill you if you're
putting thumbs up when they all put
thumbs down.
But if you put thumbs down, you join
their karma. So,
very often, not to not not infrequently,
you're up against a spiritual immoral uh
decision like that.
All right. So, that which interacts with
the world is not intrinsically the self,
but it certainly reflects it. that which
is uh activated on the stage right here
is the persona. It's
the learned part that knows how to
verbalize, interact, express
appropriately to get ideas and thoughts
across
and it is not
innately the same as the reality of the
self which is has no form and frankly
doesn't say anything.
If I ask my inner self what does it
think about all this? It doesn't think
about it.
Doesn't consider it thinkable.
Think thinkable is think thinkable
doesn't have thinkability.
Uh
on the other hand, if something
varies somewhat from the absolute truth
of whatever this consciousness is here
at the moment, it instantly lets you
know.
And the difficulty is we said up to 600
though condolini energy pouring up your
spine is exquisite and joy is exquisite.
You surrounded by infinite beauty and
harmony.
Everything happens synchron with
synchronicity.
When you think something, it appears.
Huh?
It's heavenly.
And
at 600 one is just immobilized by it.
All of a sudden
the sense of the presence is so
profound.
The
How the physicality persists is strictly
up to the world actually because at that
point there's no interest in it.
It seems to go um it it'll stop
breathing too. It stops the it stops all
activity and the bliss is all prevailing
and um
even breathing stops and
life goes right on.
Um if the universe if the karma I
suppose of the universe and the karma of
the individual
uh so decide then the breathing will
start because somebody comes by and
stimulates it to breathe or gets you to
eat again or something like this
otherwise you just leave it and and I
think uh we found what of those who hit
650% do leave the body half people say
just just let it fall over
And um it's wonderful whether if it
stays or it doesn't stay is totally
irrelevant.
Then beyond that usually it stays there
but sometimes it goes up to 700
or sometimes it'll start from down below
and then hit 700 and suddenly you
consciousness 700. That's Ramana
Maharshi and Nagada Maharaj
and I presume Muhammad I don't know the
story of Muhammad and Muhammad was only
700 but 700 is the world of the sage and
uh profoundly enlightened state and
usually at 700 it just stays there at
that point you don't leave the mountain
and u you don't have to wear many
clothes you can sit on a tiger skin and
eat icky food off of palm leaf
or you get a job back in New York City.
I suppose get real.
You know, my sense of humor is funny.
You know,
it it just says the most bizarre things.
People say, "You laugh at your own
jokes." And I tell them, "They're not my
jokes. I never heard them. They just
come out of the blue. They hit me. They
hit me as hilarious. Frankly, I don't
know where they come from. Some of the
funniest things have just come out of
the blue. They just knock me over cuz I
have a
sense of humor. It had nothing to do
with me. I didn't make it up. They're
not my jokes. I didn't make them up.
Yeah. It just came out of the blue.
Spontaneously. So, everything happened
spontaneously.
And then from around 700, uh it it it
usually doesn't change. I don't know why
it continued to change in this instance,
but from that point on, it is not
blissful. It is u frequently extremely
painful.
And uh one's sensitivity to the
slightest outness is exquisite.
And in case it bypasses uh your notice,
the aura be reacts with intense pain
which was quite distressing
and uh the pain often was severe and
lasted for many hours and days sometimes
until you could find out what the
outness was and correct it and then it
would go away. But the next slight
slightest thing it would start it and I
was lamenting that one time. I was
lamenting
and we were in Korea and uh Susan pulled
a Korean a Buddhist Bible out of it.
See, in Korea in the hotel room, you
open the drawer and there's not just a
holy Bible, Christian Bible, but a
Buddhist Bible, you know. So, she pull
out the Buddhist Bible and she opens it,
flips it open. And the Buddha was saying
that he was racked with pain and beset
by demons and his bones felt like they
were cracked. Instantly, I felt better
when I heard that.
Wow. Wasn't that a great moment? That
was a great moment.
And uh you see, even as I was speaking,
even I was as I was speaking, still
share with the audience, you know, the
reality of how this all works because
there's nothing mysterious about it. As
uh I got near speaking this morning, I
felt a twinge out. There was something I
could pick out. I could tell sense that
it was in the third eye of the atmic
body.
Uh there was something on the third eye
theic body resist.
Um
it was a luciferic energy resist resist.
It had to do with the spiritual ego
seeing a gain resist.
The spiritual ego was attracted to the
power
of absolute certainty. resist
right
spiritual ego was attracted. It knew
that
the absolute power absolute certainty
is considerable
and the spiritual ego instantly went for
it and I felt it go for it.
It like wants to seize the power
inherent in being a transmitter of
absolute certainty.
like the remnant of some entity wants to
hang on to that come back through
reach out towards you from
from where I don't know let's see
see we learn instant by instant I'm just
showing you how it actually works
the that spiritual ego was personal
resistance so that's the personal the
remnant of this personal spiritual ego
resist which is attracted to the thought
of power. Okay.
So you see the spiritual purification is
continuous. The more you learn,
the more astute you become at perceiving
its nooks and crannies and you you're
after it all the time.
After a while, it's like the princess
sleeping on the can feel the pee under
the mattress kind of a sensitivity.
It's like the instant it comes up, you
know there's something out about it.
You instantly look to see what it is
about it. From your knowledge of the
ego, one could presume
what is probably operating and then with
kinesiology verify if that is so and
choose the opposite. To be grateful
to be grateful for
the absoluteness of spiritual certainty
to choose that as the alternate option.
So that's the lucospheric energy. as a
as you evolved it's like some test comes
up of it you see see
go ahead
>> there all this
>> is there what
>> was it
>> touchdown
>> what
>> is there
>> oh touchdown yes
>> we're going for the kick
>> is there an absolute end for spiritual
evolution
in my understanding of the nature of
God. No, that the evolution of
consciousness is a foreverness.
It's a foreverness. All right,
we'll find out.
Uh it we have a permission acid resist.
It is a forever resist. Yes, it's a
foreverness.
So there is no
um
end in the sense of uh the limitation of
beginning and end which are concepts
and beginning and end are concepts of
languaging
and a definition and
therefore that which is infinite
would not be compatible with that which
has a beginning and an ending. So within
reality there is no endings because
there are no beginnings.
So all measurement then is an arbitrary
positionality of the ego
which says this is a beginning and this
is an ending.
When is the ending the beginning of the
next um sequence? You know what I'm
saying? We just trigger the next
sequence.
>> Any Yes.
>> I think we've asked that. We've asked
that before and it said no.
Yeah.
So, you mean you got to pay off the
mortgage whether you like it or not?
>> Let's see. We've asked this before in
front of other audiences. Anyway, the
question is,
uh, the end times are reality on this
plane. Resist. No. The end times are
reality on certain astral planes.
Resist. Yes. the end times as seen in
revelations
as seen by many psychics, channelers,
uh tarot card readers and what all it
has to do with the fact that the end
times the catal cataclysmic and what is
it called? It's got a name,
huh? whatever you call anyway the
cataclysmic end times
uh are a reality on certain astral
realms because people will who have
experienced it are very truthful and
they're telling you the reality of what
they experienced they're very convincing
they did indeed experience that reality
but it was not this realm the error was
to presume that it refers to this
planetary evolution which it does not it
does however apply at certain astral
realms. So John
John calibrates at 70. The source of the
book of revelations I think revelations
calibrates at 70. John was the
originator and revelations was an
hallucination. A very elaborate
elaborated hallucination
but he calibrated at 70 and the
hallucination calibrates at 70. And when
you ask the source of that uh
hallucination it was one of the lower
astral realms. Now what John envisioned
as and experienced as a potentiality and
a envisioned reality for the future and
all has been seen by lots of people.
There's a number of people in Sedona,
some of who I knew personally, some of
who I knew personally, who actually went
to those astral realms, thought that
they were some some kind of a divine
heaven and came back with the message,
you know, uh build underground houses
and uh wait for the end times and
California will fall off in the ocean
and Phoenix will become a seapport
and so many people did. And uh you know
the survivalist scattered to the hills
and waited for the end times and then
the the year 2000 came and went. So uh
they packed up. Did they change their
ways? No, they just changed the date.
All right. See what I I knew that some
of these people were telling the truth
from their experiential. experientially
that is what they they experienced
and they did experience it and they were
telling the truth because that's what
they experienced but it was on an astral
realm and it applies to an astral realm.
It did not apply to this realm. The
karma of earthly existence is different
than the astral.
There's an infinite number of astral
realms each with their own hierarchy.
They're semi-gods, they're demi- goods,
they're chieftains, they're masters,
they're spiritual masters. They all have
strange names usually.
Master Kok Lula and uh he's in charge of
this and then beyond him is master so
and so and beyond him is another realm.
Beyond him is not. So there's a whole
hierarchy within the astral domains.
Each one ruled by a demi a demigod. They
think they're god god but they're
actually demi demigods.
And they're very common in history.
Historical mythology is full of them.
Anyway, the astral realms there are
current realities on in in certain
dimensions.
One chooses those dimensions and in in
teaching students I tell them to avoid
them. Not that they're not intriguing.
They're quite intriguing. A lot of them
are quite clever and they have their own
hierarchies. Some of them even have
Jesus in the hierarchy. You know, Jesus
is part of their
domain as far as they're concerned.
But they're diversions. And if you check
with kinesiology and you say should I go
there you always got to know that you
can be intrigued by it sucked in by it
and become influenced by some entity on
the other side. So the way to handle
entities on the other side is to ask
what is their calibrated level of
consciousness as if they were in a
physical body
and find out what is the level of
consciousness that is being channeled
and what is the level of consciousness
of the channeler and what are the
intentions of both.
First of all you don't need anything you
don't need any information that comes
from out of body.
All the information spiritual truth that
you ever need to hear in a lifetime has
already been spoken by those in bodies.
There is no truth held by any entity on
the other side channel or otherwise who
holds some truth that you need to know
to reach salvation or enlightenment.
There are no secrets in the universe.
There are no secrets. Nobody is holding
any mystical ancient mystery knowledge
that by manipulating certain symbols in
something you're going to exhilarate,
you know, you're going to bypass karma
or some of these outlandish promises
they make. Transcend karma. Yeah. Right.
Because in trying to transcend karma,
you've just created a new karma called
trying to transcend karma. You know what
I'm saying?
To get away from these footprints in the
snow, you've merely created some new
footprints in the snow. You haven't
gotten away from leaving footprints in
the snow. So I say anything that's ever
been you ever need to know spiritually
has been said
and it's being said in a live body.
There are certain things that were taken
by inner dictation and when you
calibrate the energy field at 600. Well
any teaching that's 600 is worth
following whatever its source.
Generally though, you'll find they're in
the high 200s. Most of the channelers
and channelneled entities are in the
high 200s. No matter what titles they
may tell you, it's always master
somebody or Baba somebody. And uh but
they're all in the high 200s. There's
nothing wrong with high 200s because
what's important is integrity. Integrity
is over 200. So it can be integrous
ignorance. What is said is so, but it is
not a very high truth. And
um
un so unless you can verify the truth of
a teaching I wouldn't bother following
it.
And what can be learned that you need to
know?
I've never calibrated the Seth books.
But
is Seth going to tell you anything that
you need to know to reach enlightenment
that is not available otherwise?
Hey,
like what?
Like what? So you'll find it's
entertainment. All right. So if you
realize it's entertainment and it
probably has a certain reality within a
certain narrow sense of what's real,
then it's harmless. But I see too many
people swept aside by that which is not
so harmless. And its purpose and
intention is to deter you from the
pathway.
The difficulty with that which is denied
God, which is called the lower astral,
is that it it hates that which affirms
God.
You'll notice that as you go below 200,
you get into levels of that which hates
holiness, purity,
and spits upon it. Does there's certain
neighborhoods that'll take you there.
You just try being pure, see how long
you last.
It's despised.
The leader of Cambodia, what was his
name? Pel pot Pot or Pot pel?
>> Pot
pel. What else? Anyway, a wacko name.
Any kind of affection or love was
against the law.
You can be executed for any display of
any kind of a positive feeling. Actually
illegal to have a positive feeling or to
express it.
The Japanese, you know, in Manuria, same
thing. to bayonet an innocent baby in
the arms of his mother showed that you
had achieved the ultimate
the hard uncaring cold killer
consciousness of that which denies God.
So the lower astral is full of entities
who have made that kind of a decision.
So wanting to adopt them as your
spiritual mentor is not really the best
advice.
Oh dear. I don't know it says now when
will a certain illness remit in
spiritual evolution we said it kind of
plays a very heavy component
uh
having strangled a lot of people to
death might have you might delay your
recovery from COPD in this lifetime who
knows you know what I'm saying you'll
you'll find that behind the misfortunes
of this life
there's very often lifetimes in which
Don't forget the evolution of
consciousness throughout time. It only
got it was at 190 for centuries. And
before it was 190, it was much lower
than 190. It was way way back back or 50
or 60 or 70. It was normal in those
times to enslave or kill
those you conquered. It was normal. They
weren't going violating any social
standard or doing anything immoral.
So when you look back at previous
lifetimes, you will you're going to
discover what life was like in those
times. You can't contextualize it in
terms of the year 2002.
To execute
one's captives was normal, expected. In
fact, you get executed for not executing
them. You understand? So you have to
have a certain
context and understanding when you begin
to do any kind of karmic research and
realize what you're talking about is an
entity that lived in times when living
by your wits was the top of society.
Royalty lived by their wits and nipped
each other in the purse as often as
possible and then the bed in between.
So you can hardly be surprised to find
that
the kinds of actions that may have had
unfortunate karmic consequences in this
lifetime if you put them in the context
of the that time weren't really all that
bad. You understand?
So as to prevent yourself from attacking
yourself spiritually. So it can be that
in this particular lifetime one won't
one won't one allow a certain thing to
uh heal until one fuels one has achieved
the karmic purpose of that
and
sort of finished it you might say so you
might hang on to an illness not
consciously but karma karmic propensity
uh may may see to it that it persists
for a while so we'll know that we'll
take another break and then we'll
finish up for the afternoon. Huh?
>> Yes. I want to ask a question. Uh
the the pain in the nervous system from
800 and up is due to the fact that the
human nervous system hasn't evolved
to that level yet. Resist.
All right. But it does as a consequence
of the spiritual work resist. Okay.
Well, we answer we question we answer
questions.
Questions arrive arise constantly.
People are growing and evolving and
learning and and we do the same thing.
And so we're always asking questions.
Somebody asked why do you think the
evolution of consciousness becomes
painful beyond a certain level? It's
it's great up to about 700 then about
800 it gets painful. And um I've always
intuited that the nervous system is not
equipped for it and not evolved that
far. Could be in a few thousand years.
But um as at this point it's the nervous
system is not that evolved. However, as
you progress in consciousness, the human
the nervous system does begin to adapt
to it. It actually strengthens. The
nerves actually get thicker
and capable of handling more uh
spiritual energy.
Do we ever come back at lower levels of
consciousness? We've asked that before.
The answer we've always gotten is no.
Hindu,
the Hindus think you can come back as a
frog or something, but we've always
gotten no. You don't come back as a
lesser life form.
Uh, has Jesus Christ ever physically
reincarnated on the earth plane? Oh, we
asked before, did he have previous
lifetimes? We haven't asked, has he
reincarnated?
Jesus Christ has reincarnated
on the earth plane. Resist.
No. Um
my own understanding of the second
coming of Christ is is that it occurred
in 1986
somewhere in Brooklyn, right? You
remember remember there was a while
there was a you know the new age people
are really wild. There was a book in
fact that Jesus Christ was secretly
living in Brooklyn somewhere. I forget.
Any my understanding you see
the human being because he identifies
himself as a physicality expects that
the second coming of Christ is going to
become a phys is going to be a
physicality.
My understanding of Christ consciousness
is that it's a level of consciousness
and what reappears re reappears and
dominates the planet is Christ
consciousness.
and which is and therefore a physicality
is really irrelevant and immaterial.
In 1986 the consciousness level of
mankind for
probably has to do with the karma of
human evolution jumped from 180 to 207.
So when it jumped from that which is
negative to that which is positive to me
that's that's the real be reemergence of
the Christ consciousness. So when that
which is represents love, truth and
integrity prevails over that which is
destructive and non-intigorous to me
that's the return
or the the emergence of Christ
consciousness in the form of
consciousness whether of physicality
uh I don't know what what somebody at
the level of Christ would be interested
in physicality you might do it as a
teaching tool you know you might do it
as a teaching tool
Uh I myself wouldn't ch ch ch ch ch ch
ch ch ch ch ch ch ch ch ch ch ch ch ch
ch ch ch ch ch ch ch ch ch it ne
necessarily.
I mean you'd have to appear on TV. You
know what I'm saying? You know I don't
know.
>> Tune in to Christ on the internet, you
know. www.jc
JC
I I'm not going to ask the question, but
because whether I mean it's up to Jesus,
I don't wouldn't tell him one way or the
other what to do.
Uh is delving into past lives helpful?
Yes, we tried to demonstrate it up here.
Uh you see sometimes mysteriously
strange things happen recurrently in
your life. There's no rational
explanation.
There was one series of rather very
strange kinds of events and they kept
recurring all over in different
countries and different circumstances
and the same kind of a thing would
recur. I mean, I just knew there was
something. I didn't believe in karma in
those days, but I knew it was something
on some other level. And I would tell my
analyst about it.
And he say, "It's just your paranoia.
You're connecting this all together, you
know, is a logical sequence because
that's the quality of the human mind." I
said, "That's true." But just
statistically, it's very, very unlikely,
you know, that these strange things
would occur. And of course later on when
I did check it out karmically
uh then it just verified what I sort of
intuited as a fact. Then the question is
now what do you do about it? Well, you
pray very intensely
and whatever the defect was in a past
life that accounts for this, you refute
it. Um, declare one's choice of the
opposite,
dedicate one's life uh to the opposite.
So, if you've been miserable towards uh
little dogs, you know, let's say this
lifetime you're always getting bitten by
dogs, you know what I'm saying? You
begin to wonder. I mean, is there
something about me? The dogs hate me or
what the hell is it? You know,
you can be in the middle of nowhere and
dog comes out of somebody's apartment
and bites you in the leg. You begin to
wonder if you were once cruel to dogs
and tortured them to death or something.
And if you ask, you'll find out, yeah,
you did. You were sort of a satist in
that lifetime and chopped them up and uh
you know what I'm saying? So any anyway,
it does make it u more comprehensible.
I just wanted to, you know, when we're
talking about causality and overcoming
the illusion of causality,
then I would just explain to you how I
saw the universe when that state came on
that
the most shocking thing initially was
not only the translucence and the
oneness of all things
and the intensity of the divinity had
shown forth through all of creation.
But the awareness that everything was
happening spontaneously as as a result
of
its expression of his essence. Each
thing is the perfect expression of its
own essence as it manifests at this
moment of creation.
Everything is happening spontaneously of
its own.
And if you see that, you're get
transported to a different realm. In
this realm, the illusion is that
everything is creating something else
from elsewhere.
Everything is therefore dependent on
something outside of itself.
Everything is dependent on some external
explanation for its existence
which misses the essence of reality that
each thing is being what it is
spontaneously because that's the way it
expresses its essence
at this moment in the context of these
conditions. Huh? Understand? Is that
comprehensible?
Each thing is being merely being what it
is.
I looked at the cat and there sits his
cat and I was just struck with the
profound
perfection of his exquisite catnness.
It's sitting there
101% radiating catnness and not anything
else. And it's not that catnness is not
coming from elsewhere. is not dependent
on anything outside of itself, but it's
the unfoldment of its potentiality to be
a perfect kitty as it sit there sits
there and purr it's perfection at that
moment. It is being absolutely 100% the
infinite potentiality of kittiness at
that moment. Right?
It's not dependent on anything outside
of itself to be what it is.
of itself to be what it is. So each one
of us is at the same in the same way
free then to express the potentiality of
that which we are as we are created in
the context of our current karma and the
conditions of the world. No right.
So
uh
uh this has to do with the way the world
is going and uh as I said I I saw that
the world went from 190
we saw for one thing the world went from
190 to prevailing to 207.
That's extremely important because you
see in a balance if it's one feather to
this way or one feather to this way when
you project out a laser beam of infinite
number of millions of miles you're quite
away quite away from here under here.
You understand what I'm saying? The
slightest variation
when projected throughout the
consciousness of all of mankind over
eons of time. So the destiny of mankind
is profoundly different than what it
was. At 190 nuclear wipeout was almost
inevitable
potentiality because it's below 200. It
has innate within itself the seeds of
its own destruction
and in due time it would have brought
about its own destruction. The only
reason it hadn't succeeded in totally
destroying itself up to that time is it
didn't have a powerful enough weapon.
And once mankind invented a powerful
enough weapon, 190 would have wiped us
out. Would have wiped us out. And so at
the height of the Cold War,
um left to its own devices, 190 would
have brought about the destruction of
mankind itself. Yeah. the 90 left to its
own devices
like a locomotive with no uh gen
control would have run itself to death
and run itself off the tracks. So to go
from 190 to 207 was already profoundly
significant.
Then we found only very recently that
uh between book one and book two uh or
between book one and book three I forget
um the percentage of people below 200
dropped from 85% to 78%.
Whoa. That's a huge drop. some
percentage-wise
when you
um look at it across all of all of human
man humanity
means that what was tenable in the past
is no longer tenable to increasing
proportions of the populace.
I mean for instance we see all of Europe
now forbids capital punishment. all of
Europe.
Um,
the only thing about capital punishment
aside from its spiritual obviousness,
you know, from a practical viewpoint is
if you make a mistake, you can't undo
it.
And now with
what do you call it? Karma testing the
blood.
>> DNA. Yeah. And now with DNA, I mean, how
would you sleep? You know, you put
somebody to death and then you discover
he was the wrong guy. I mean, I don't
know. That'd be pretty hard to live
with. Uh, so it gives you no chance to
correct an error. No chance to correct
an error. Uh, all right. So, the
implication then
is quite profound that um the
consciousness level of mankind is
advancing.
the number of people below 200 is
diminishing
and the number of people over 600 has
doubled or tripled.
Uh when we wrote the book there was very
few over u 600 I think now we've got
over 30. So
the consciousness of mankind is
advancing.
It seemed to me up to uh the
consciousness level of 190
that mankind could was called homo
sapien. Homo sapien
and
the evolution of the humankind. There
was um and there was Neanderthal man and
there was Cro-Magn.
They all calibrated around 70.
Then there was Homo Homo rectus and uh
the homminid
improved till we had now homo sapiion.
The homo sapiion calibrated
at 190 up to the year 1986
and then the consciousness level jumped
to 207. A very very critical
because it changes quality just like
water at 32.
Here it's ice and solid here it's
liquid. So consciousness is 190 changes
quality when it goes over 200.
Now, it seems to me this signals the
birth of Homo Spiritus.
Homo sapiion has gone as far as he can
go.
World War II was pretty much the end of
that guy.
We saw what Homo sapiion could do. He
can create great inventions and great
bombs and great bullets and great
military machines. And what did he do
with it? Used it to destroy innocent
people.
No, it seems to me that the birth of a
spiritual awareness the level of over
200 means that man that humankind is now
rebirthed as homospiritus.
The spiritual signific significance and
meaning of life is now what is
constantly being questioned. It's even
being questioned. Do we have the right
to put people to death who are
murderers? Is it
even people like the Alquitas or the
whatever those people are the Afghani
bomber types? We uh we look out for
their human rights. We you know what I'm
saying? That's homo homosspiritus
to even question what is the right of
the accused
mass killer who would never have come up
at the lower levels. You just execute
the guy the next morning and and that
would be the end of the story, wouldn't
it? No questions asked.
Although such a question can be taken to
the political extreme of absurdity, the
mere fact that it is given countenance
in today's society means the birth of a
new greater and more intense spiritual
awareness in which we are almost asking
to be reborn from a moral viewpoint.
Certainly 911 has certainly seen the
rebirth of moral consciousness in
America. It's the endless. In fact,
that's the content of the endless debate
is what is the moral way to respond to
this? What is the moral responsible
action to take? What is the moral action
to take with a prisoner of war? And are
they prisoners of war? It seems like the
country is almost being confronted by a
re uh estimation of its moral values and
the degree to which it's committed to
moral
uh values. So, it's almost like a
rebirth of society. So to me it's the
birth of Homospiritus.
You heard it here.
I remember I was at that lecture in the
year 2002 and
you tell your grandchildren
and the doctor there said homospiritus
and by golly he was right. Oh well.
Oh golly. All right. So there are
disruptions in one's personal life.
Becoming spiritually committed can lead
to very major disruptions.
You can walk away from a very intense uh
worldly commitment and just turn your
back on it and drive off with an old
truck full of bunch of old tools.
Leave it all behind. All the oriental
rugs and the antiques and the and and
the and all that. Just walk away from
everything, which leads some of your
family members to decide that you're
mentally ill.
or you're in a middle-ag crisis or
you've just had a nervous breakdown or
you were always a little bit off and now
he's really off.
All right. Why do they say that? Because
we said these are two different
paradigms of reality. The linear
Newtonian paradigm, the one of supposed
rational
world of science and logic and the
intellect university
is one paradigm of reality. The
nonlinear is not real. is not real to
the Newtonian dimension.
It's not real. So a person whose
awareness is confined to being a oneeyed
man thinks that the vision of a two-eyed
man is bizarre.
All right.
All right. So in the world of the blind,
the oneeyed man is king. But in the
world of the oneeyed, the two-eyed man
again is strange.
So to the person limited to the
Newtonian paradigm of reality, they are
like the oneeyed man.
And as you become spiritually aware,
it's like you have two eyes and now you
have you see things in three dimensions,
whereas they only see them in two. So,
uh, yes, the family members, they can
con consider you've gone off the deep
end and, um, quite insane. But, uh,
that's all right because,
um,
how do you explain to loved ones? You
really can't.
Oh, they say, you know, he's found God.
Uhoh. Everybody shakes their head. Yeah,
I know what you mean. And I had an uncle
that did that once and he went off to
join a monastery and wacko land. So
yeah. So
to to accept people as they are, the
question here is how do you develop
tolerance for people as they are?
Uh, in as much as they are um thick,
ugly, and stupid. Is that what it says?
No, it turns out
in as much as they seem stupid, ugly,
and uh All right. Okay.
Yeah.
You see, everything in in everyone is in
a point of evolution, including one's
own perception and spiritual growth. So
compassion for the less fortunate. Let
us call the very bottom of the barrel
the less fortunate. Let's say Mr. Bin
Laden is less fortunate than us. Let's
say we question whether killing
thousands of innocent children
in order for the egotistical position
that it'll get you to heaven gets him to
heaven. But what about the other 3,000?
He didn't give that much thought. So we
we're a little shocked at that
egoentricity.
How do you see it in a compassionate way
is you have to see it as
an impersonal manifestation of the human
ego when it is unmodified by any kind of
spiritual awareness whatsoever.
It seems to have escaped spiritual
awareness alltogether.
to do it in the name of God of course is
what outrages uh everybody from the pope
on down.
The pope you know calibrates about 570
which is perfect. The pope and u the
head of great churches the best the most
ideal calibration is about 570
and I think um the head of the Tibetan
Buddhist u moved to India. What is his
name?
Yeah, it's about the same. So the head
of a world church, you see at 600,
you're not much good as the head of a
world church. You just sit there blissed
out and you're not too functional.
So be a nice figurehead to put someplace
and there people go and light candles to
you and get your blessing button. You
can't run a world church
especially with the multiple decisions
and the implications uh the
international political uh the and the
very exquisite and delicate spiritual
decisions to be made because no matter
what ma move you make it influences
millions of people
uh either adversely or beneficially from
multiple levels either economical or
political or spiritual. So they're
extremely difficult decisions to be made
and you really need
570 to do it. You need that much uh
compassion and you also need to be in
the world to that degree.
You know at 700 people would say there
is no such world. Don't worry about it.
The world of your possession has no
reality. So don't bother worrying about
it. Just perfect yourself and that's all
you can do. And that al also is on a
certain level is true. That is also on a
certain level also. The greatest gift
you can give to the world is to perfect
your own degree of consciousness.
And it is true. The world you think you
see does not exist.
It's worse than that.
Oh golly.
Oh dear.
The the use of kinesiology by yourself
is uh I think this this particular
method here is very useful for many
people. If it's an important decision, I
always tell people, well, if you can
find somebody to check it out with
traditional kinesiology, do so. You
know, if you're trying to decide whether
well, I won't even mention what that
might be. Some major life decision where
a lot hangs on it. Okay.
Uh
when we say everything is perfect uh as
it is
uh
that has to be contextualized
because you could say well isn't the ego
perfect as it is? Well it's a perfect
expression of where it is at this point
in time based on this karmic propensity
under the current conditions. Yes, it's
the perfect expression just as bin Lden
is the perfect expression of calibration
level 70. Bin Lden is the perfect 70. 70
is also the level of serial killers. All
the fable killer killers of the past,
Jack the Ripper calibrated at 70.
Um people chop up little children and
kill them by the th thousands and eat
them and the various weird and bizarre
things all calibrated around 70. He is a
perfect expression of what 70 is. The
calibration level of 70 which is the
same roughly as dinosaurs.
>> Is that a fact? Yeah, that's a fact.
Really? Uh we have permission to ask
about dinosaurs resist or 60 resist. 65
resist. 69 70 72.
The dinosaur is 70. So okay. Uh a lot of
poisonous insects come out at 70 and
So it's it's really the the energy of
hatred, hatred. It's really the spleen.
What you see is the display of the
spleen. Hatred, envy, malevolence.
And people look for the motivation.
There is no motivation.
It expresses itself that way because
that's what it is.
There's a mollisk at the bottom of the
sea. It's the most poisonous thing on
the planet.
If you if you if you examine poisons,
you'll find some interesting things.
The mamba like mamba
has 14 different poisonous enzymes. Any
one of them is enough to kill you.
Uh there's a spider. What's the name of
that spider? The most vicious spider on
the planet. Anyway, it's got something
like about 20 different poisonous
enzymes.
Any one of which will kill you. I forget
the name of that spider.
>> H. No, not a black widow. Far worse than
a black widow.
>> It's the most aggressive. No, no.
Tarantula is a mild little guy.
>> Anyway, it's a it's an aggressive spire.
Anyway, that's just leading into the the
subject. Um, but anyway, there is worse
than that. There's a mollisk at the
bottom of the sea
who bores a hole in its uh victim and
injects it with a poison
which includes 40 poisons. Every one of
those poisons is enough to kill an
elephant and it's got 40 of them.
Now would that serve any purpose from
the point of viewpoint of evolution?
No. because one killer enzyme one killer
um
neuropeptide destroyer or whatever it is
is enough. It's got 40. So it's like a
concentration of venom within one
specific life form.
Um
we see that venom that which is
poisonous then is present on the planet.
it um it always causes pain. Doesn't
just kill you.
Um
even the scorpion vibe, you just don't
go painlessly paralyzed. The pain is
agonizing.
So there is that which calibrates very
low which is poisonous and stills pain
and its purpose is is is to kill.
in contradistinction to that which
is dedicated to healing the relief of
pain and there are two contrasting ways
to go.
Um
therefore each thing is demonstrating
the essence of that which it is.
You say does it have a purpose? No.
Because purpose is teological thinking.
Purpose is saying because this seems to
result in that that is the purpose of
this to cause that. No, that is teologic
thinking which is a logical fallacy.
The error of post hawk ergo proctorhawk
because a thing follows therefore it's
caused by or it's the purpose of it.
All we're saying is that each thing
becomes
um a manifestation of that which it is.
We're up in a small town and a workman
there came up with a truck and there in
the back sat a little white dog. Little
white dog
got out of the truck and came over to
greet us and it just wiggled all over
with happiness. His tail just was going
crazy like this. It like falls in love
with you instantly.
Wasn't that dog? Just like it just fell
in love with us instantly. It just
radiated love, lovingness.
It responded to love. It was looking for
love. It seems to live in the world of
love. Looks for love, thrives on love,
gives loves, reflects love, and the tail
tells you.
It just radiates that which it is. Now,
isn't it that strange that a dog at 500
is higher than a lot of human beings at
70?
Dog kills nobody, kills nothing, brings
comfort, joy, and happiness and reflects
that. And therefore, I was surprised
when I first calibrated the wag of a
dog's tail and got 500. I said, "Whoa,
that's bigger than that's higher than
many of the people on the planet." Most
of the people on the planet don't
approach you with trust, love,
caringness, or do they respond to love?
Most people are scared to death of love.
You know, you look at a person lovingly
with a prolonged open glance and a lot
of people will shrink and get scared as
as ever. You try that at a stop stop
sign in the city of New York, you get
arrested.
You look over at the car next to you
with with love in your face and they
call the police on the cell phone.
There's a the killer raper staring in my
windows officer.
It would be totally misinterpreted,
wouldn't it?
And I got the same kick when I noticed
the kitty's purr. Had I calibrated the
kitty's purr? And it seemed to be
interested in love, looking for love,
responsive to love, and seemed to live
in a world of lovingness. So
I can't answer you why does love come
through
uh an animal except that we think of
evolution in terms of intellect and we
don't think in terms that lovingness
could be evolved
without the presence of an intellect. In
fact that which has an intellect is less
likely to be loving than something that
doesn't have an intellect in a lot of
times.
So that's interesting. Doesn't mean
anything, but
when the soul manifests from the field
of consciousness, does it carry a charge
either negative or positive that can be
termed the karma of the soul? Yes, I
think that's specifically what we were
saying this morning. And uh and uh that
that the soul automatically because of
what it has become is like a cork in
water and automatically gravitates in
the field of consciousness to that which
it to with which it identifies and uh
therefore destiny is ultimately
um
perfect. That's correct. Is it that's
correct? Yeah. Automatically. So the
soul automatically gravitates to what
it's attracted to
that with which it is compatible. Just
like the dog ran to love. If I hated
dogs, I don't know. He may have shrunk
off or he may have tried
uh
I don't know what he would have done. I
should ask him.
200 is the dividing line between force
and power.
540.
Is that the difference between ego and
one's higher calling? Well, you get
these these points are arbitrary.
Um 200 was not arbitrary. The calling it
200 was arbitrary.
It was obvious that the world could be
divided into that which makes you go
strong and that makes you go weak.
There's an interesting book called Red
World, Green B Green World by lady named
Margaret Cheney
and she said that there's people red
people and green people and there's red
foods and red food green foods. Well,
she was just using that as a way of
speaking. She's saying people divide up
into
those which react positively to certain
kinds of food and those which react
negatively. And she grouped out two
groups. There's the red people. They
respond with kinesiology positively to
the following foods. And there's the
green people and they respond positively
to the following foods. And they react
negatively to the other foods. So her
thesis was
that green people will get sick if they
keep eating red food all the time and
can't seem to get well. And when they
discover what they're eating is enimical
to their health, they will regain their
health. So,
and now she's worried because a lot of
medications are coming out in generic.
See? So, the brand name, let's say
you're a red person and the brand name
tests red. So, you say penicellin G is
good for me. Yes, I'm a red person. It's
a red the product red. Okay. So, it's
it's
so it's harmonious with my energy or
whatever. Now they put out a generic
brand of the same thing and only it it
tests out green. So now you're red
person, you're taking a green pill and
this penicellin is not helping you. So
she's worried about you. What are we
going to do now? The generics are coming
out and they're coming out in a
different category.
So kinesiology can lead you into all
kinds of conundrums. Huh?
So we we just numerically called it 200
because that worked out as far as the
logarithms go.
540 is just the the level of
unconditional love. It just happens to
be there. Love is at 500 and we say you
can be very loving but still have
conditionalities
and uh
when does love become unconditional
though so love is unconditional. We we
found that it calibrates at 540.
All right. The rest of these I think
we've answered. Now are there any
questions that we haven't answered?
Somebody asked me about
Ken uh
the book by Ken Holographic Universe.
>> Ken Wilbur. Yeah, we said that was the
high 400s. Well, we said that before.
He's probably around 480 or so. Yeah.
Right. Very high understanding of nature
of truth and
close on to spiritual merging into
spiritual truth, you know, close on to
discovering the spiritual reality which
lies just a slight bit. But the
holograph the whole concept of
holographic universe already is
um getting into the awareness of the
oneness of God as the allness of the
presidency.
Yes.
>> Christ
>> never did.
Would you like to?
>> Let's see.
Um
going to ask permission.
>> I'm going to ask permission. Yes. Uh we
have permission to ask this question. We
have permission to ask this question
before this audience. Resist. Um the
appearance of Christ on the
consciousness changed the overall level
of the consciousness of mankind. Resist.
It raised it. Resist. Okay. Before the
appearance of
when we when we say Christ, we mean the
appearance of his teaching. resist. We
don't mean the appearance of his
physicality resist. Okay? So, we're not
talking about necessarily when the baby
Jesus is sat there in the
in the swaddling clothes or something.
All right. So, before the birth of
Christ, the consciousness level of
mankind was over Oh, boy. Over 90 resist
over 95 resistance.
Before the birth of Christ, the
consciousness level of mankind as a
whole was over 95 resistant. 96 resist.
Oh, 95. What was he? Let's see. Where's
95?
>> Man lived in fear.
>> Man lived in fear. Okay. Okay. After the
birth of Christ, um
consciousness level of mankind increased
resist. increased over five points
resist 10 points resist 15 points resist
20 points resist 30 points resist 40
points resist
just the birth just the physicality of
Jesus Christ raised the consciousness
level of man or 40 points resist the
physicality of the presence of Christ on
the planet raised the consciousness
level of mankind 40 points the teachings
of Christ as they spread through the
Roman Empire
continued to increase the level of man's
consciousness. Resist raise it. Sorry.
The spread of Christianity through the
Roman Empire increased the consciousness
level of mankind another 20 points,
another 30 points, another 40 points,
another 40 points.
So the birth of Christ as a physicality
apparently was like a window to God and
radiated that energy jumped at 40 points
which is enormous.
The teachings of Christ then radiated
out and were carried throughout the
Roman Empire
and um raised the consciousness level of
mankind further.
The history of the evolution of the
Roman Empire is quite interesting from
the viewpoint of consciousness.
And some of the Roman emperors were
really quite advanced uh almost more
advanced than modern man recognizing the
equality of man, recognizing uh the
right of the slave to a trial, a
judicial trial
u tolerance for all religions.
uh except with the with the uh proviso
that you also had to acknowledge the
Roman gods. So the Roman gods were then
showed your allegiance to Rome as an
empire and to the emperor. But so long
as you did that, you could worship any
gods you wanted. So it was it was pretty
evolved.
And it's uh interesting because it is
the foundation of our um western culture
and I think it helps
uh advance one's spiritual awareness and
consciousness because it increases your
tolerance for that which differs from
yourself
when you sort of become aware of how
consciousness evolved and how the
evolution of that consciousness
expressed itself in cultures as they
spread out across the world and the
impact of the human experience. So you
in a way you're sort of owning yourself
is the totality of mankind.
There was certainly a period in the
evolution of this consciousness of
owning the self as the self and totality
of all of mankind.
And so understanding the evolution of
humanity as culture and as it express
itself over time can have quite I think
a broadening effect and make one a
little broader which means less critical
of that which differs from yourself
which makes the ego a little easier to
transcend because you sort of get off
rigid positionalities
as you become more sophisticated and see
how consciousness evolves. and express
itself through the various religions and
cultures. We become tolerant of that
which is different than oursel and see
that
coming from his position bin Laden
probably makes sense to himself. Of
course, what we're shocked by is the
egoentricity of it uh and the cost in
society, but we can perhaps understand
how it could evolve. So to be
compassionate towards all of life means
to be really relatively sophisticated
and educated about how
consciousness evolved throughout time
and then expressed itself in society in
its various ways. So as we said before
to understand society is to understand
the ego. So you're not wasting your time
in studying history or sociology because
you're seeing how the ego is out out
crops itself. How it out what do you
call it? Out something rather itself
out something itself out pictures
itself. How's that? How it expresses
itself collectively. So the collective
ego then is the individual ego projected
outward and expressed it in human in
human society on a grand scale where
it's easy to see. Yeah.
You indicate that something like 294,000
calibrations. Uh are the results of
those calibrations available somewhere?
>> Oh yes I get the question. Uh the the
book I'm working on now, well, I'm
finishing up I the book I
um
it's it the original manuscript was
revised and now I'm re revising the
revision.
they'll have to correct the revision of
the revised revision and
but in the meantime during the inter
intervals
um a book called I think I'm going to
call radical reality
in it we do about a thousand
calibrations
uh going back through history from Nero
and Caesar Caligula
uh through more recent history through
Nazi regimes and into recent events um
from Gorbachev to
current rulers
I can give you an examples uh for
instance uh FDR was 499
uh Churchill was 510
most American presence presidents are in
the mid 400s
the signers of the declaration of
independence were about 510
the constitution United States is 700.
So we can go back through the Magna
Carter. We go through the evolution of
democracy from the beginning of time. We
calibrate theologians from the founders
of the Christian church on down.
We do all the scientists from Einstein
to um
was the inventor. No, not the inventor.
Los Alamos. And we go through all the
major events in human history and
current life from MTV
uh to MTV R calibrates out 190. Anyway,
uh two uh computer games and
musicians, the great musicians,
the popular musicians and the classical
musicians. the great classical musicians
were generally in the 500s
as some were higher the great architects
we calibrated the uh great cathedrals of
the world great cathedrals of the world
the ones
when I traveled in Europe I what
attracted me was to go from cathedral to
cathedral and they calibrate around 700
so there's no you can see why they're
very attractive to travel through the
country of France and see shard
cathedral arising above the level of the
hayfields way off in the distance is an
unforgettable experience.
So we do the great cathedrals and
compare it with let's say the crystal
cathedral currently
in Los Angeles. Uh we did all the major
spiritual writers throughout history um
of ancient and recent times from
um
in the various books of the Bible and u
various things like that, various
spiritual traditions and churches and
teachers and gurus
and um we per pretty much covered all of
human society.
the scientists, the writers, the
inventors,
the great um industrialists,
the great industrialists,
uh current politicians.
I think the the highest calibration
we've got for a current head of state
is the president and current president
of Mexico.
Surprisingly enough, the current
president of Mexico calibrates around
five
very, very high, the highest on the
planet. And what does he talk about? He
talks about cooperation, mutuality.
You see, he's not against winning and
losing. He's not against make. He's not
even, you know, you Americanos are make,
you know, he's not even into make. He's
uh here's where we're at. Let's see how
we can improve from there so that
everyone benefits. Well, that's a very
advanced spiritual concept that everyone
benefits and with an idea of integrity
and fairness and equality and at the
same time everything legal and
cooperative.
So,
a lot can be learned and uh therefore I
think it's a worthy enterprise. Uh
the negatives of course in current
society are rather obvious to anybody
who's spiritually sophisticated at all
and hardly need uh calibration. Then we
calibrated a lot of the great criminal
famous criminals of ancient times you
know to find out other we're trying to
get a topography of the evolution of
mankind over recorded time.
You know what where is Jack the Ripper?
He's at 70. Where's Ben Lden? is at 70.
Where is
u a dinosaur? A dinosaur is at 70. The
instinct of the dinosaur and the
instinct of this person or this are the
same.
Jack the Ripper dismembers
and rips to death its prey. I mean, you
know, almost identical. It's almost like
um a dinosaur spirit got into a human
body. You know what I'm saying? You
begin to wonder, is there a crossover?
you know. So anyway, it's an interesting
work in that we're trying to, you know,
develop a topography, a different
dimension of understanding
human consciousness and its expression
as
society. uh from Henry Kimler in World
War II to
um Vanti Fox in today's world. We did a
lot of movie stars, famous singers songs
uh and find out what their general the
general range and then there's
exceptions.
Uh, one of the greatest singers was um,
uh, he's used in the background of
commercials in blues, black and he was
way up in the 500s.
Um,
>> huh.
>> We are strong. Yeah. Right. Way up in
the 500s. Um, the capacity to be loving
at all times in all places apparently
was the characteristic.
So it's just interesting because uh you
learn enormous amount because you see
everything in in a different dimension
now and as you see the calibration you
get oh I see I get oh yeah I see so you
it's like you create you get greater
depth spiritually in comprehending
the totality of human evolution
which in the net effect is to develop a
compassion for it as almost an
experiment of creation.
It's almost as though the evolution of
life on this planet is almost an
experiment to see where if you let it
loose without any guidance or controls,
what does it do?
It ends up as a mollisk at the bottom of
the sea that creates 40
enzymes at one time and it also creates
saints the same life. Is it the same
life energy or a different one? You know
what I'm saying? It leads to rather
profound questions. Yes.
>> Two questions.
One, how did Nelson Mandela do
and then the other was responsible for
the massive ship in 198
>> Mandela we calibrated him he's over um
I think he was over 500 he was 510 520
something forget you forget you Mahatma
Gandhi was 700 Mahatma Gandhi stood off
the British Empire the British Empire at
the time Mahatma Gandhi defeated the
British Empire was at 190 so Mahatma
stood there at 700 and the British
Empire stood there at 190 it Without
firing a shot, the British Empire
succumbed and when it went down, it took
colonialization
uh out of commission and all of Africa
became decolonate. He asked me, Mandela,
we have permission resist. Mandela's
over 520, 540, 560.
Mandela's about 550, 55, 550.
Capable of unconditional love. Yes. Huh.
and quite powerful because at 550
uh he would have sufficient power if he
just sat there to defeat u an empire
that calibrated less.
>> Yeah. Second part of the question was
>> uh 1986 what was
>> Oh yes.
>> Um
I've never fully um spent time to um
never fully uh investigated it. I just
assumed that the collective positive
karma of mankind had crested at that
level. It happened to be at the time of
the harmonic convergence.
It happened to be at the time when
Gorbachef pretty much pulled the
pulled the blocks out from underneath
the um Russian uh USSR atheistic empire.
It was also the time of other major
events which were conccommatant.
You see when you go beyond causality
then you see that let's say a
positionality here can radiate forth in
the world of manifestation
in multiple ways without one thing here
necessarily being the cause of this. In
other words, the positionality which
surfaces in this way, it doesn't mean
that the dissolution
of monolithic communism
was caused by anything outside of
itself,
but it occurred at the same time.
There's undoubtedly more to the story.
We'll we'll ask it in a general way.
First of all, I know there's more to the
story.
I want to watch the time.
>> Yeah,
>> there's more to the story. Resist. Thank
you.
>> There's more to the story. My own
feeling was that it came from higher
dimensions as a result of the
consequence of positive accumulated
karma of mankind. That's correct.
Resist. Yeah. And well, we won't go into
the details of it. Anyway,
it would be as though the collective
collective karma of mankind as a as a
whole had reached the point where it had
crossed that collective.
Perhaps the the last great finale of
negativity
was really World World War II
in which the negativity satanic energy
was massive.
um that caused almost a shock. But then
into the shock came
that which was really more luciferic in
that it was seeking power rather than
destruction
in the form of communism and the USSR
which was really seeking power. Although
it took expressions as cruelty and
Stalin really was responsible for more
deaths than Hitler.
Nevertheless, it more or less ran its
course. And of course, it was Gorbachev.
Uh, if you calibrate Gorbachev's heart
chakra, it's extremely high.
So, Gorbachev
pulled the correct stops out and the
thing collapsed of itself without a
shot. Gorbachev did not fire a shot.
So the west with all of its brave talk
about u
uh the war against communism, it was not
the war against communism that defeated
communism.
It was uh the chocks were pulled out by
Gorbachev. Let's see where Gorbachev's
heart is at. We are permission to
resist. Gorbachev's heart is over 540.
Resist 560
550.
Wow. So those people like Gandhi and
Mandela and Gorbachef people who changed
all of political history
um their power came from a heart chakra
at 550 and over.
So that is encouraging because then it
means
uh
increasing one's own capacity of
lovingness has the capacity to undo the
negativity of the world and in fact it
has the capacity to collapse whole
empires
that which collapsed the USSR that was
the very powerful empire
was the radiance of the heart chakra of
one man. However, that one man
also represented something else that we
write about
and that is um when we talk about
attractor energy fields, we say that
each of these energy fields has an
attractor pattern uh behind it
that brought us to describing what we
call critical factor analysis.
One of the values of kinesiology,
many uh interacting systems are so
complex they are not capable of
comprehension
by the human intellect nor by an
assisted computer. You see, a computer
is limited to the
Newtonian paradigm. It cannot
be programmed for the nonlinear by
definition.
Consequently,
it can only mimic the intellect. It
cannot
mimic human intelligence.
In any case, some situations are so in
enormously complex. They are beyond
comprehension.
This is a problem run into by big
governments historically.
The complexity of running the Roman
Empire was staggering and in the end it
just fell of inertia. All the soldiers
just married the local girls and settled
down and quit the army and that was the
end of the Roman Empire.
Yeah. No army could defeat the Roman
Empire. It was the most formidable army
the the world has ever seen. It was
unconquerable.
And the Roman legions ruled all of
Europe and the Mediterranean for a
thousand years.
Is an army invincible that ruled for a
And what brought it down? The kiss of a
lovely woman.
The soldiers all around here. You
swallow them all around the place.
Met the local girls, fell in love with
them, got married, and said the hell
with it, went to farming. And that and
that was the end of the Roman religions.
In any complex situation, there is what
I call the critical factor.
And the in a giant clock works, if you
know where to touch the giant clock
works, you can you can stop the entire
clock works by knowing precisely. The
clock works is so complex that even a
master watch maker can't figure it out.
Uh the same with an engineer. You see a
locomotive running down the track uh
with 100 cars behind it is an enormous
amount of force. But if you know where
to touch the control in the cab, the
engineer's cab, if you know where to
touch it, you can stop the whole freight
train.
And so if correctly positioned, then
knowing which of the
pickup sticks to pull out, the whole
thing collapses. But you have to know
which one. Gorbachev was there, Mandela
was there.
Um, each one was in a certain position,
but they also had a certain amount of
power because each one of them
calibrates around 550 and all of them
the power emanates from the heart. So
the power of love then is
transformational
and as we saw with the birth of Christ
it jumped the calibration level of
mankind 40 points just the physicality
being here and it jumped another for 40
points when his teachings began to cross
the Roman Empire and it totally changed
Europe the future of Europe and Western
civilization for all time.
So an avatar is one whose teachings and
birth and presence
recontextualize the significance of all
of
life for all of mankind throughout
thousands of years.
That's what we call an avatar.
It's not the same as like the avatar
used book company that you see running
around town. Uh, avatar. I always get a
kick people use the word avatar in the
advertising of some program or something
because it's as though they have don't
understand what avatar is. Avatar is of
such enormous power that it
changes all mankind for thousands of
years henceforth. It's the
it's the uh the ideal by which
everything else is measured. Every
action of mankind, every court decision,
every headline in the newspaper is
unconsciously if not consciously
measured according to the teachings of
the Buddha or Christ or Muhammad. So
Muhammad calibrated at 700. You see
Buddha was a thousand.
Christ was a thousand. Krishna was a
thousand.
uh the great enlightened um fable gurus
of ancient times there were asked were a
thousand
Muhammad we repeatedly calibrated at 700
so there was not the enormous power of
spiritual truth to o overcome let's say
the tribal proclivities of that part of
the world perhaps so that uh the
teaching breaks through
breaks through but don't forget it broke
through in Christianity also So in the
middle certainly the end times the
inquisition the truth of Christianity is
broken through by some primitive
negativity and savagery which expressed
itself in that way and now we see it
sort of delayed and coming from that
part of the world. So the spiritual
person now is confronted with how to
contextualize and comprehend and
understand the current world events. But
then again, it has been that way since
I've been on the planet. You know, World
War I had just expired. Then came the
Great Depression, then came World War
II, and I don't know how many wars since
then. And so, we're always confronted
with the spiritual the seeming spiritual
dilemmas of the expression of the ego uh
and its expression as the actions of
collective actions of society.
In any case, all any of us can do is
within our own heart to reach the
highest level of compassion and
understanding
and try to recontextualize it
compassionately because in so doing we
undo it. So each of those who were able
to undo great negativity did so because
in a way their heart was supported by
the hearts of all of us. They just
didn't reach 550 all by their lonesome
out there on an ice flow, you know. So
the evolution of the consciousness of
mankind is dependent on uh all the
contributions of all of us. So each one
of us counts and each one of us counts
quite decisively.
Each one of us certainly counts quite
decisively.
That's a fact. Is it?
You know, I've always been suspicious of
holy sounding religious teachings. You
know what I'm saying?
Holy sounding religious teachings. You
say, "Yeah, right. I want to see is that
a fact or is that not a fact?"
>> The changes in the astronomical
events factor into your investigations.
um
the the question of where does astrology
for instance fit into this whole
picture? Well,
if the universe is one karmic whole, one
karmic oneness, then all that's within
the universe including its physical
expressions as the planetary systems
etc. are part and parcel of that
harmony.
Therefore, the planets are also in
harmony with that universal
universality.
I I would see it that from a high level,
we said that archangels calibrate 50,000
and up. When you realize that we're
talking about logarithmic progression
here,
one archangel at 50,000, if it even
thinks of you, is likely to knock you
out of your body for some 20, 30 years.
and you you're lucky to breathe again
anyway.
So from some very higher level of of
divinity then
um
let let's say if all of the if
everything is is the interaction of
energy fields which can be represented
symbolically as an attractor field
that means that all things are therefore
in harmony so I don't see a
constellation as causing something
within human experience on this planet.
I see a third factor out here.
Because of this third factor,
this constellation is in this position
and this event is happening commonly
within the human experience. But this
astrologic position is not causing the
human experience.
Both the human experience and the
astrologic position positionalities
are expressing. So if it is the time for
great harvesting let's say
that which is supportive of life in all
its expressions is expressing itself
astrologically this way and has greater
crops on this planet at this time right
and then at a later time in the cycle
the harvesting goes down and the
astrologic position at that time is
different. So in explaining the harm of
the universe which is consistent with
the holo concept of the holographic
universe and also of the nonlinear
dimensions of reality. It isn't that
this on this side of the universe is
causing this but it is concordant and
those of you who are familiar with
advanced theoretical physics know that
the spin of an electron on and the spin
of an electron in another part of the
universe this one is not causing the
spin of this electron. But if this one
stops and reverses, so does this. But
there's no connection between the two of
them. Which means that if that which you
want to call cause, which is really just
a terminology of verbalization and a
concept in n reality. But if you want to
say there's a cause, the cause would
then be outside both the electrons. And
that which causes this electron to go
this way and this one go this way. So
it's not this electron is not causing
this. So to me, an astrologic position
does not cause,
you know, pots and pans to break. But
the timing of pots and pans breaking is
simultaneous with that but not caused by
that. You understand? Simultaneity does
not mean causality.
Just as peace appearing on the earth and
all people praying for peace, it doesn't
mean necessarily that the praying for
the peace is causing the peace.
But the
the appropriate time there's an
appropriate time for all things. And the
appropriate timing of peace appearing in
the appropriate time of appearing for
peace are probably simultaneous but not
causal.
>> Yes.
>> Last time you said that
with God all things are possible is not
true statement.
>> And I was wondering what you meant by
that. And also could you calibrate
conversations with God
>> 450 about
>> what was the first question? All things.
>> Oh, all things are. Yeah. There's a lot
of lot of sayings, you know, the
spiritual sayings that are they're not
exactly accurate. I mean, if they're all
accurate, everybody be enlightened, you
know, but
a lot of them are greatly inaccurate. To
say all things are possible with God is
usually a hypothetical statement to
counter somebody else's argument in
order to prove that you're right.
in usage
when looked at exactly it cannot be so
because that which God cannot be is not
God.
When all say you know all things are
possible with God is usually used to
explain or give some kind of reification
of the potential truth of something
preposterous.
and quite unlikely.
However, there is a correct usage to it
within the infinite power of God in
another context, in another sense.
No, it's still not true because
because of the nature of creation itself
that each thing becomes the essence of
its own potentiality is the fulfillment
of its own karma. It can't really be the
fulfillment of something else's karma or
a bird were turn into a toad.
No, a toad can only come in become a
toad.
So we could say that that which is
cannot become that which it is not.
It can only be that which it is is. That
has to do with um the selfidentity of
reality. The most difficult thing to see
about the enlightened condition let's
say
the radical sense of I
the thing that makes it the most
difficult to understand
is that everything is radically only
that which it is.
It sounds like a nonsensical statement,
but the ego cannot deal with anything
except creating that cannot make any
statement without creating a duality,
thereby negating the reality of that
which it is attempting to describe.
Even the word is is incorrect. The
radical reality of that which sits and
speaks through this isness here is is
beyond isness. It is beyond beingness.
Even a transitive
intransitive verb is incorrect.
There is neither a subject and a
predicate. There is neither
a this doing a that nor a here as
compared to a there. Those are all
positionalities within.
Mentalization. Those are all
mentalizations. No such thing can be.
The only thing that's possible is the
reality of the cat being absolutely
completely 101% cat
not caused by anything extraneous to
itself.
It needs.
The only absolute statement of truth is
possible is the word I.
To say am to suffix am to I is already a
negation of the reality of the truth of
I isness and beingness because the
radical reality of that which I am is
beyond either isness or beingness
it is beyond existence or non-existence
all such terminologies or mentations.
So the most difficult thing about seeing
the truth, the reality of who you are is
the radical identity of the self as the
self. That which you subjectively
experience as self is that and nothing
else.
Then the ego comes in and tries to
destroy that realization by adding all
kinds of adjects,
adjectives, adverbs.
I am that I am is already
deviating from truth.
Amnest beingness itself is beyond the
radical reality of the truth of that
which you really are.
Any verb at all is v is varying from
truth.
In fact, any noun is already ver varying
from truth
because each one is adding something
that is not essential to its essence to
that essence and thereby blurring the
recognition of the radical reality of
its essence.
To say to add the word am after I is
already an error. You're already it's
already off the point.
I know you were interested in that.
I have to answer it to my own
satisfaction.
Yes.
>> Can you hear her?
>> Speak up.
I'd like to know how you make life
decisions.
>> Oh,
>> that's correct.
>> That's right. The the decisions of life.
She wants to know if you're you know
spiritual student then how do you make
your life decisions? I think I think
what we all tend to do is try to make
what seems to be the highest decision
that which is most beneficial and loving
etc. We all try to make a decision which
is in our view of it the least selfish.
We try to choose win-win over win lose.
At the same time we try to clarify our
perception of
um the conditions about which we feel we
have to make a decision whether we're
seeing it in terms of either or this we
try to clarify in our inner mind is so
it's a very complex what our motivations
are
a simple thing like should I you know
pick up a new kitty at the dog pond at
the at the animal shelter is already a
decision. It's already can be quite
complex. On the other hand, it be quite
simple
because each and everything if examined
uh to the full elaboration of which the
ego is capable
uh becomes extremely complex.
There's a much easier way to do it.
It's a good thing to get a nice kitty at
the dog kitty pounder.
We We know that having a pet increases
longevity, decreases heart attacks,
drops people's blood pressure. I see a
lot of depressed people in the office
and I always ask them, "Do you have a
pet at home?" "No." H.
Well,
we know that the presence of a pet
increases longevity. We know that
they're therapeutic. We know that
they're very useful in nursing homes.
The nursing homes I liked best were ones
that had dogs running around. The
nursing home didn't have a dog running
around. It had a lower vibration. It did
really. And those which had Christian
denomin Christian denominations running
them seemed to have a higher energy and
vibration uh
and they were there was all those
friendly dogs going around. So
again it isn't that this caused that but
a higher level of
spiritual awareness whatever resulted in
greater kindness on the part of the
staff. a higher healing rate and the
presence of the dog. So you can't say
the dog caused a higher healing rate,
but that which chose to have a dog there
saw the importance of love to healing.
And any u health field people who see
the importance of love to healing are
very likely to be
more capable of bringing about healing
in their patients. So
every decision then can be seen of
course from multiple viewpoints
and um that which is most loving is
undoubtedly
you know probably what dominates most of
people in the spiritual field of
spiritual inquiry. Uh and of course
nowadays we can calibrate a thing too
but that doesn't mean it has to rule
you.
So you know calibrating things is just
verification. It's just verification.
It's it's extremely useful. It's
extremely useful as a research tool.
Research tool.
The strangeness of this particular
consciousness here was that it went
through a whole great variety of uh
experiences within the levels of
consciousness. And it happened in a
person with a scientific, medical,
psychiatric and psychoanalytic
background.
So that the curiosity of the intellect
then was the physician looked at it and
said what in the world is that
physiologically going on with the body?
The psychoanalysts wanted to look at it.
So the self-examination that went on was
from the viewpoint
which is not exactly traditional. And uh
the description of the state then was
expressed in a form that expressed the
background of the
of the entity. So
power versus force then was coming from
the awareness that the scientific world
the world of the Newtonian paradigm is
ruled by logic and reason and science.
So how to present it then first as a PhD
dissertation to a university faculty
where it will meet all the strict
requirements of a PhD doctoral
dissertation. So it was first presented
there to the most skeptical uh academic
um
uh community to pass muster there before
it went on and began to express itself
in the nonlinear domain. So what I tried
to do was create a crossover for that
great block at the at 499. The great mo
majority of spiritual seekers are in the
400s and can't seem to break through
that 499 into the 500s.
How to make that bridge comprehensible
was really the purpose of the work you
know and the purpose of the lectures.
Certain spiritual information is
transformative because it has within it
innately such powerful energy that
merely to hear it already transforms
consciousness.
So
there is the commitment on the part of
this entity to uh state all these
statements that should be made uh
knowing that to merely hear that
statement is itself
uh of significance and we'll stop very
shortly.
The consciousness level of this
community you're sitting is over 435
440 442 4445
444 What were we at? 431 We went from
431 to 444. Okay,
that's what we did as a community today.
went from 431 to 444 as a result of just
um the recontextualization of your own
spiritual understanding just from the
material itself. You understand 431 to
444 the average lifetime consciousness
advances five points. So to go from 431
to 444
I can't subtract that. What is that? 13
points.
So that's a quite enormous uh jump. So
we did that collectively. We did that
collectively.
You know, on a certain level, we all own
each other. We all own each other's
consciousness. We're all responsible for
each other's conscious. Not in a
codependent way, but in the
understanding of the unity of the
consciousness of mankind.
Every endeavor that each one of us makes
to get what was just said is helping
everybody get what was just said. My
endeavor as a teacher is to try to make
it as comprehensible as possible.
and defend the good name of God in in
the process
who has been much maligned by religion
and other people
and needs a friend. God needs a friend.
God needs a friend in all of us. Every
kind word is a good way of thanking God
for our existence. We'll take one last
question and then we'll quit.
What is the calibration of the spiritual
practice for you?
>> I don't know what it is.
>> Yeah, it's probably in the 400s, you
know. Yeah. Mhm.
It's probably I would guess in the 400s.
Most of those things that have to do
with uh you see it has to do with form.
>> Could you repeat the question?
>> Yeah.
calibration.
>> I'm not going to do it.
>> It's over 400. 420.
>> Yeah, it's in the 400s. I know. Any of
those things which follow structure and
form tend to be in the 400s. But don't
forget, you're talking about a tool.
You're not talking about the ultimate
truth that may be revealed as the use of
that tool. So many spiritual practices
um may calibrate in the 200s but um it
would be like uh calibrating the level
of a shovel. You know with a shovel you
can build a Taj Mahal. So you can't say
a shovel is a weak instrument. You can
you can build a Taj Mahal or you can dig
your grave. So the the shovel is not the
whole answer. And so the consciousness
of the person. So let's say any
particular technique that you've learned
and almost everybody in this room has
been around the around the block a
little bit with different techniques,
different teachings, different schools,
different consciousness uh uh teachers.
Um the intention the commitment the
intention of the seeker is uh with the
most profound instrument. So a person
who is profoundly committed to God and
digs with a small shovel will get
farther than a person with a small
commitment but
uh um a major capacity for intellectual
curiosity. Don't forget the intellect
itself is greedy and um many people have
many books and have not moved much in
their level of consciousness. So you
have to begin to suspect
one is suffering from intellectual
greed. The idea of having read
everything and met everybody and known
everybody and met every guru on the
planet and all uh in itself becomes an
addiction because this is um all you
have to do is understand the absolute
truth of one sentence and that's
sufficient.
All you need is one sentence.
And so I say all spiritual work can
start anywhere. You can pick out any
place because you can unravel the whole
sweater from any place on the sweater.
Isn't that correct? And if you're
willing to be forgiving,
that alone, all you have to do is be
willing to forgiving everything and
anybody, including yourself and
everybody else, no matter where in time
or space, including all of history, and
you're already there, so you don't need
anything complicated.
Um, so I thank you all for being here
today and I thank you all for
being present.