What
What were
What were you
What were you going
What were you going to
What were you going to say?
>> Um,
>> Um, I
What were you going to say?
>> Um, I had
>> Um, I had an
What were you going to say?
>> Um, I had an experience
>> Um, I had an experience coming
What were you going to say?
>> Um, I had an experience coming out
>> Um, I had an experience coming out here
very
very similar
pulled
pulled over
and
and he
and he asked
and he asked me
and he asked me he
and he asked me he said
and he asked me he said where
and he asked me he said where are
and he asked me he said where are you
going?
going? I
and he asked me he said where are you
going? I said
going? I said Arizona.
and he asked me he said where are you
going? I said Arizona. He
going? I said Arizona. He said
and he asked me he said where are you
going? I said Arizona. He said why
going? I said Arizona. He said why are
you
you going
you going there?
So
So he
you going there?
So he goes
So he goes what
you going there?
So he goes what does
So he goes what does he
consciously
consciously human
consciously human consciousness
consciously human consciousness and
consciously human consciousness and he
goes
goes you
consciously human consciousness and he
goes you know what
goes you know what I'm
consciously human consciousness and he
goes you know what I'm just
goes you know what I'm just going
consciously human consciousness and he
goes you know what I'm just going to
give
give you
give you a
give you a warning
give you a warning and
give you a warning and go
give you a warning and go ahead.
Oh
Oh golly.
>> Wait
>> Wait a
>> Wait a second.
>> If
>> If he
>> Wait a second.
>> If he asked
>> If he asked one
>> Wait a second.
>> If he asked one more
>> If he asked one more question,
>> Wait a second.
>> If he asked one more question, he
>> If he asked one more question, he came
back
back to
back to the
back to the window
back to the window and
back to the window and go
back to the window and go here
back to the window and go here and
back to the window and go here and just
walked
walked off.
He
He didn't
think
think you're
He didn't
think you're a
think you're a space
He didn't
think you're a space guy.
think you're a space guy. You
He didn't
think you're a space guy. You don't
think you're a space guy. You don't want
to
to get
to get involved.
consciousness
consciousness sounds
to get involved.
consciousness sounds like
consciousness sounds like it's
to get involved.
consciousness sounds like it's woo
consciousness sounds like it's woo woo
woo
woo by
woo by invoking
woo by invoking your
woo by invoking your name.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I
woo by invoking your name.
>> Oh, I see.
>> Oh, I see. Yes.
woo by invoking your name.
>> Oh, I see. Yes. Yes.
You're
You're pulling
You're pulling pulling
You're pulling pulling in
You're pulling pulling in the
You're pulling pulling in the energy.
Yeah.
Yeah. Right.
You're pulling pulling in the energy.
Yeah. Right. Okay.
>> This
>> This may
>> This may not
>> This may not work
>> This may not work every
>> This may not work every time.
>> Well,
>> Well, the
>> This may not work every time.
>> Well, the the
>> Well, the the the
>> This may not work every time.
>> Well, the the the energy
>> Well, the the the energy is
>> This may not work every time.
>> Well, the the the energy is one
>> Well, the the the energy is one of
loving
loving him
loving him for
loving him for what
loving him for what he's
loving him for what he's doing
loving him for what he's doing and
loving him for what he's doing and being
beautiful,
beautiful, you
loving him for what he's doing and being
beautiful, you know.
beautiful, you know. See,
loving him for what he's doing and being
beautiful, you know. See, I
beautiful, you know. See, I respect
them.
them. And
them. And when
them. And when a
them. And when a policeman
them. And when a policeman pulls
them. And when a policeman pulls me
over,
over, I
them. And when a policeman pulls me
over, I always
over, I always respect
them. And when a policeman pulls me
over, I always respect the
over, I always respect the fact
them. And when a policeman pulls me
over, I always respect the fact that
he's
he's doing
he's doing what
he's doing what he
he's doing what he is
he's doing what he is trained
he's doing what he is trained and
he's doing what he is trained and knows
he
he should
he's doing what he is trained and knows
he should do.
he should do. So,
he's doing what he is trained and knows
he should do. So, he's
he should do. So, he's being
he's doing what he is trained and knows
he should do. So, he's being integrous.
So,
So, I
So, I respect
So, I respect his
So, I respect his integrity.
>> I
>> I told
So, I respect his integrity.
>> I told him,
>> I told him, "Thank
So, I respect his integrity.
>> I told him, "Thank you."
>> I told him, "Thank you." And
So, I respect his integrity.
>> I told him, "Thank you." And I
appreciate
appreciate it.
>> That's
>> That's right.
appreciate it.
>> That's right. So,
>> That's right. So, you
appreciate it.
>> That's right. So, you respect
>> That's right. So, you respect their
appreciate it.
>> That's right. So, you respect their So,
you
you respect
you respect their
you respect their integrity.
you respect their integrity. And
you respect their integrity. And um
you respect their integrity. And um so,
as
as you
you respect their integrity. And um so,
as you respect
as you respect their
you respect their integrity. And um so,
as you respect their integrity,
as you respect their integrity, they
you respect their integrity. And um so,
as you respect their integrity, they get
they're
they're being
they're being respected.
they're being respected. And
they're being respected. And don't
forget
forget most
they're being respected. And don't
forget most of
forget most of the
they're being respected. And don't
forget most of the uh
forget most of the uh so-called
they're being respected. And don't
forget most of the uh so-called um
negative
negative experiences
negative experiences people
negative experiences people have
negative experiences people have with
policemen
policemen are
negative experiences people have with
policemen are provoked.
You
You know,
You know, you
You know, you you
You know, you you push
You know, you you push the
You know, you you push the cop
You know, you you push the cop to
You know, you you push the cop to the
point
point that
You know, you you push the cop to the
point that he's
point that he's passed
You know, you you push the cop to the
point that he's passed his
point that he's passed his self-control.
So
So now
So now he
So now he can
So now he can be
So now he can be the
So now he can be the bad
So now he can be the bad guy.
So now he can be the bad guy. So
So now he can be the bad guy. So this
So now he can be the bad guy. So this is
a
a trick
So now he can be the bad guy. So this is
a trick of
a trick of the
So now he can be the bad guy. So this is
a trick of the lower
a trick of the lower energy
So now he can be the bad guy. So this is
a trick of the lower energy fields
a trick of the lower energy fields is
So now he can be the bad guy. So this is
a trick of the lower energy fields is to
provoke
provoke that
provoke that which
provoke that which is
provoke that which is integrous
provoke that which is integrous until
provoke that which is integrous until it
blows
blows its
provoke that which is integrous until it
blows its integrity.
blows its integrity. You
provoke that which is integrous until it
blows its integrity. You see
blows its integrity. You see if
provoke that which is integrous until it
blows its integrity. You see if you
blows its integrity. You see if you can
get
get him
get him to
get him to blow
get him to blow it.
get him to blow it. Uh
get him to blow it. Uh so
get him to blow it. Uh so it's
get him to blow it. Uh so it's always
beneficial
beneficial to
get him to blow it. Uh so it's always
beneficial to um
beneficial to um give
get him to blow it. Uh so it's always
beneficial to um give the
beneficial to um give the policeman
get him to blow it. Uh so it's always
beneficial to um give the policeman the
respect
respect that
respect that is
respect that is due
respect that is due his
respect that is due his office.
respect that is due his office. You
don't
don't have
respect that is due his office. You
don't have to
don't have to get
respect that is due his office. You
don't have to get personal
don't have to get personal about
respect that is due his office. You
don't have to get personal about it.
don't have to get personal about it. The
same
same as
same as the
same as the president
same as the president of the
same as the president of the United
States,
States, the
same as the president of the United
States, the presidency
States, the presidency itself
same as the president of the United
States, the presidency itself is
States, the presidency itself is uh
worthy
worthy of
worthy of respect.
worthy of respect. And
worthy of respect. And uh
worthy of respect. And uh so
worthy of respect. And uh so attacking
the
the person
worthy of respect. And uh so attacking
the person or
the person or attacking
worthy of respect. And uh so attacking
the person or attacking the
the person or attacking the office,
worthy of respect. And uh so attacking
the person or attacking the office, you
have
have to
have to be
have to be clear
have to be clear which
have to be clear which what
have to be clear which what you're
talking
talking about.
have to be clear which what you're
talking about. And
talking about. And uh
have to be clear which what you're
talking about. And uh sometimes
political
political cartoonists
political cartoonists uh
political cartoonists uh I
political cartoonists uh I think
political cartoonists uh I think are
incorrect
incorrect because
political cartoonists uh I think are
incorrect because they're
incorrect because they're actually
attacking
attacking the
attacking the uh
attacking the uh the
attacking the uh the office
attacking the uh the office which
attacking the uh the office which in
attacking the uh the office which in a
time
time of
attacking the uh the office which in a
time of war
time of war is
attacking the uh the office which in a
time of war is not
time of war is not really
attacking the uh the office which in a
time of war is not really in
time of war is not really in terrorist
once
once you
once you protect
once you protect the
once you protect the office
once you protect the office and
once you protect the office and still
you
you can
once you protect the office and still
you can differ
you can differ with
once you protect the office and still
you can differ with the
you can differ with the person
once you protect the office and still
you can differ with the person who
you can differ with the person who holds
the
the office
the office but
the office but the
the office but the office
the office but the office itself
the office but the office itself after
all
all you're
the office but the office itself after
all you're looking
all you're looking to
the office but the office itself after
all you're looking to the
all you're looking to the you're
the office but the office itself after
all you're looking to the you're looking
to
to the
to the government
to the government of
to the government of the
to the government of the United
to the government of the United States
to
to save
to the government of the United States
to save your
to save your life
to the government of the United States
to save your life and
to save your life and provide
to the government of the United States
to save your life and provide for
to save your life and provide for your
old
old age
old age and
old age and god
old age and god knows
old age and god knows what
old age and god knows what all
old age and god knows what all give
old age and god knows what all give you
Medicare
Medicare when
old age and god knows what all give you
Medicare when you
Medicare when you get
old age and god knows what all give you
Medicare when you get old
Medicare when you get old and
old age and god knows what all give you
Medicare when you get old and you
Medicare when you get old and you you're
expecting
expecting a
expecting a lot
expecting a lot from
expecting a lot from the
expecting a lot from the government
expecting a lot from the government and
so
so they
expecting a lot from the government and
so they should
so they should give
expecting a lot from the government and
so they should give it
so they should give it a
expecting a lot from the government and
so they should give it a little
something
something in
something in return
something in return besides
something in return besides just
something in return besides just taxes.
So
So what
something in return besides just taxes.
So what we
So what we hold
something in return besides just taxes.
So what we hold integrously
So what we hold integrously tends
something in return besides just taxes.
So what we hold integrously tends to
become
become that.
become that. So
become that. So when
become that. So when we
become that. So when we say
become that. So when we say to
become that. So when we say to the
policeman,
policeman, I
become that. So when we say to the
policeman, I uh
policeman, I uh I
become that. So when we say to the
policeman, I uh I know
policeman, I uh I know you're
become that. So when we say to the
policeman, I uh I know you're doing
policeman, I uh I know you're doing what
you
you uh
you uh you're
you uh you're supposed
you uh you're supposed to
you uh you're supposed to do
you uh you're supposed to do and
you uh you're supposed to do and I
respect
respect you
you uh you're supposed to do and I
respect you for
respect you for that.
you uh you're supposed to do and I
respect you for that. You
respect you for that. You know,
you uh you're supposed to do and I
respect you for that. You know, he
appreciates
appreciates that.
And
And um
okay,
what
what is
okay,
what is the
what is the difference
okay,
what is the difference between
what is the difference between love
okay,
what is the difference between love and
joy?
joy? Well,
joy? Well, love
joy? Well, love we
joy? Well, love we as
joy? Well, love we as we
joy? Well, love we as we said
joy? Well, love we as we said takes
joy? Well, love we as we said takes many
expressions.
Um
Um many
Um many people
Um many people are
Um many people are here
Um many people are here out
Um many people are here out of
Um many people are here out of you
Um many people are here out of you know
out
out of
Um many people are here out of you know
out of the
out of the energy
Um many people are here out of you know
out of the energy field
out of the energy field of
Um many people are here out of you know
out of the energy field of love
out of the energy field of love and
Um many people are here out of you know
out of the energy field of love and what
they
they do
they do is
they do is uh
they do is uh energized
they do is uh energized by
they do is uh energized by love.
they do is uh energized by love. Joy
they do is uh energized by love. Joy is
a
a different
they do is uh energized by love. Joy is
a different state.
a different state. Joy
they do is uh energized by love. Joy is
a different state. Joy um
a different state. Joy um goes
they do is uh energized by love. Joy is
a different state. Joy um goes beyond
love
love and
love and lovingness.
love and lovingness. Love
love and lovingness. Love and
love and lovingness. Love and lovingness
you
you can
love and lovingness. Love and lovingness
you can live
you can live with
love and lovingness. Love and lovingness
you can live with all
you can live with all the
love and lovingness. Love and lovingness
you can live with all the time.
you can live with all the time. It's
sort
sort of
sort of an
sort of an evenness
sort of an evenness that
sort of an evenness that lights
sort of an evenness that lights up
everything.
Joy
Joy is
Joy is more
Joy is more uh
Joy is more uh intense.
Joy
Joy is
Joy is more uh intense.
Joy is um
Joy is um more
Joy is more uh intense.
Joy is um more exuberant.
Joy is um more exuberant. You
Joy is more uh intense.
Joy is um more exuberant. You might
Joy is um more exuberant. You might say
its
its energy
its energy is
its energy is more
it
it sort
its energy is more
it sort of
it sort of swamps
its energy is more
it sort of swamps you.
it sort of swamps you. Joy
its energy is more
it sort of swamps you. Joy sort
it sort of swamps you. Joy sort of
its energy is more
it sort of swamps you. Joy sort of takes
you
you over.
Um,
one
one can
one can be
one can be prone
one can be prone to
one can be prone to joy.
one can be prone to joy. Prone
one can be prone to joy. Prone to
one can be prone to joy. Prone to joy
without
without being
one can be prone to joy. Prone to joy
without being in
without being in that
one can be prone to joy. Prone to joy
without being in that state
without being in that state all
one can be prone to joy. Prone to joy
without being in that state all the
time.
time. You
time. You can
time. You can go
time. You can go from
time. You can go from lovingness,
unconditional
unconditional lovingness
time. You can go from lovingness,
unconditional lovingness into
unconditional lovingness into joy
time. You can go from lovingness,
unconditional lovingness into joy into
ecstasy.
We
We got
ecstasy.
We got ecstasy
We got ecstasy up
ecstasy.
We got ecstasy up there.
We got ecstasy up there. No.
ecstasy.
We got ecstasy up there. No. Okay.
We got ecstasy up there. No. Okay. Uh
anyway,
anyway, you
anyway, you can
anyway, you can as
anyway, you can as you
anyway, you can as you ascend
anyway, you can as you ascend the
anyway, you can as you ascend the scale,
you
you reach
anyway, you can as you ascend the scale,
you reach um
you reach um sort
anyway, you can as you ascend the scale,
you reach um sort of
you reach um sort of sublime
anyway, you can as you ascend the scale,
you reach um sort of sublime states.
Sort
Sort of
Sort of uh
Sort of uh states
Sort of uh states that
Sort of uh states that are
Sort of uh states that are really
Sort of uh states that are really sort
of
of sublime.
The
The ecstasy
The ecstasy is
The ecstasy is beyond
The ecstasy is beyond description
and
and hard
The ecstasy is beyond description
and hard to
handle
handle if
handle if you're
handle if you're around
handle if you're around people.
One
One time
handle if you're around people.
One time I
One time I went
handle if you're around people.
One time I went to
One time I went to a
handle if you're around people.
One time I went to a state
One time I went to a state of
handle if you're around people.
One time I went to a state of ecstasy
and
and uh
and uh the
and uh the uh
and uh the uh there's
and uh the uh there's a
and uh the uh there's a chapel
and uh the uh there's a chapel over
here.
here. The
and uh the uh there's a chapel over
here. The chapel
here. The chapel of
and uh the uh there's a chapel over
here. The chapel of uh
here. The chapel of uh something
and uh the uh there's a chapel over
here. The chapel of uh something or
other.
>> Huh?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. At
>> Yeah. At 1:00
>> Yeah. At 1:00 in
>> Yeah. At 1:00 in the
>> Yeah. At 1:00 in the morning,
>> Yeah. At 1:00 in the morning, nobody
>> Yeah. At 1:00 in the morning, nobody was
there.
there. The
>> Yeah. At 1:00 in the morning, nobody was
there. The candles
there. The candles were
>> Yeah. At 1:00 in the morning, nobody was
there. The candles were all
there. The candles were all lit
and
and there
and there was
and there was this
and there was this beautiful
and there was this beautiful music
playing
playing and
and there was this beautiful music
playing and ecstasy
playing and ecstasy reached
and there was this beautiful music
playing and ecstasy reached such
playing and ecstasy reached such a
and there was this beautiful music
playing and ecstasy reached such a state
that
that um
the
the body
that um
the body began
the body began to
that um
the body began to dance
the body began to dance with
that um
the body began to dance with ecstasy.
the body began to dance with ecstasy. I
was
was a
was a pretty
was a pretty good
was a pretty good dancer
and
and um
it
it was
it was the
it was the only
it was the only possible
it was the only possible way
it was the only possible way to
it was the only possible way to handle
it
it was
it was the only possible way to handle
it was to
it was to give
it was the only possible way to handle
it was to give it
it was to give it physical
it was the only possible way to handle
it was to give it physical expression.
One
One sort
One sort of
One sort of dance
One sort of dance was
One sort of dance was danced
One sort of dance was danced by
One sort of dance was danced by the
ecstasy
of
of the
of the glory
of the glory of
of the glory of God
of the glory of God as
of the glory of God as revealed
of the glory of God as revealed to
of the glory of God as revealed to your
own
own awareness.
Ecstatic.
Ecstatic. Ecstatic.
Ecstatic. Ecstatic. And
so
so one
Ecstatic. Ecstatic. And
so one did
so one did that
Ecstatic. Ecstatic. And
so one did that to
so one did that to express
Ecstatic. Ecstatic. And
so one did that to express to
so one did that to express to God
Ecstatic. Ecstatic. And
so one did that to express to God one's
joy
joy and
appreciation
appreciation for
joy and
appreciation for divinity.
appreciation for divinity. ones
the
the joy
the joy is
the joy is that
the joy is that one
the joy is that one has
the joy is that one has been
the joy is that one has been allowed
the joy is that one has been allowed to
experience
the
the quality
the quality of
the quality of divinity
experientially
experientially within
the quality of divinity
experientially within one's
experientially within one's own
uh
uh capacity
uh capacity to
uh capacity to experience.
So
So the
uh capacity to experience.
So the the
So the the joy
uh capacity to experience.
So the the joy is
So the the joy is almost
uh capacity to experience.
So the the joy is almost like
So the the joy is almost like an
exquisite
exquisite thankfulness
exquisite thankfulness that
exquisite thankfulness that one
exquisite thankfulness that one has
exquisite thankfulness that one has been
allowed
allowed to
exquisite thankfulness that one has been
allowed to experience
allowed to experience the
exquisite thankfulness that one has been
allowed to experience the presence
and
and one
and one wishes
and one wishes to
and one wishes to reflect
and one wishes to reflect back
and one wishes to reflect back the
thankfulness
and
and the
and the joy
and the joy at
and the joy at the
and the joy at the revelation
in
in whatever
and the joy at the revelation
in whatever manner
in whatever manner you're
and the joy at the revelation
in whatever manner you're able
in whatever manner you're able to
express
express it.
It
It says
express it.
It says joy
It says joy is
express it.
It says joy is higher
It says joy is higher on
express it.
It says joy is higher on the
It says joy is higher on the scale.
express it.
It says joy is higher on the scale. Oh
yeah
yeah it
yeah it is
yeah it is right.
yeah it is right. Uhhuh.
So
So the
yeah it is right. Uhhuh.
So the only
So the only way
yeah it is right. Uhhuh.
So the only way you
So the only way you can
yeah it is right. Uhhuh.
So the only way you can escape
So the only way you can escape joy.
Yeah.
Yeah. The
Yeah. The beyond
Yeah. The beyond joy
Yeah. The beyond joy is
Yeah. The beyond joy is ecstasy.
Yeah. The beyond joy is ecstasy. In
Yeah. The beyond joy is ecstasy. In here
is
is an
Yeah. The beyond joy is ecstasy. In here
is an ecstatic
is an ecstatic state.
Yeah. The beyond joy is ecstasy. In here
is an ecstatic state. I
is an ecstatic state. I understood
Yeah. The beyond joy is ecstasy. In here
is an ecstatic state. I understood what
Rama
Rama Krishna
Rama Krishna went
Rama Krishna went into.
Rama Krishna went into. The
Rama Krishna went into. The Rama
Rama Krishna went into. The Rama Krishna
I
I described
Rama Krishna went into. The Rama Krishna
I described the
I described the exact
Rama Krishna went into. The Rama Krishna
I described the exact state
I described the exact state and
Rama Krishna went into. The Rama Krishna
I described the exact state and uh
I described the exact state and uh he
would
would go
would go into
would go into ecstatic
would go into ecstatic states.
would go into ecstatic states. So
would go into ecstatic states. So the
ecstatic
ecstatic is
would go into ecstatic states. So the
ecstatic is beyond
ecstatic is beyond joy.
would go into ecstatic states. So the
ecstatic is beyond joy. Ecstatic
ecstatic is beyond joy. Ecstatic I
would go into ecstatic states. So the
ecstatic is beyond joy. Ecstatic I know
calibrated.
calibrated. Let's
calibrated. Let's see
calibrated. Let's see where
calibrated. Let's see where ecstatic
calibrated. Let's see where ecstatic can
calibrate.
calibrate. Ecstatic.
calibrated. Let's see where ecstatic can
calibrate. Ecstatic. Ecstatic
calibrate. Ecstatic. Ecstatic spiritual
ecstasy
ecstasy is
ecstasy is beyond
ecstasy is beyond 540,
ecstasy is beyond 540, 560,
ecstasy is beyond 540, 560, 580,
ecstasy is beyond 540, 560, 580, 585,
590,
590, 590.
Spiritual
Spiritual ecstasy
is
is exquisite
uh
uh exquisite
and
and then
and then just
and then just beyond
and then just beyond that
and then just beyond that as
and then just beyond that as I
and then just beyond that as I said
earlier
earlier in
and then just beyond that as I said
earlier in the
earlier in the lecture
just
just beyond
just beyond that
just beyond that ecstatic
just beyond that ecstatic state
just beyond that ecstatic state if
just beyond that ecstatic state if you
surrender
surrender the
just beyond that ecstatic state if you
surrender the ecstasy
surrender the ecstasy to
just beyond that ecstatic state if you
surrender the ecstasy to God
then
then the
then the infinite
then the infinite peace
then the infinite peace of
then the infinite peace of God
then the infinite peace of God comes
that
that is
then the infinite peace of God comes
that is beyond
that is beyond all.
However,
However, I
However, I wouldn't
However, I wouldn't miss
However, I wouldn't miss the
However, I wouldn't miss the the
However, I wouldn't miss the the joy
However, I wouldn't miss the the joy and
the
the ecstasy
However, I wouldn't miss the the joy and
the ecstasy on
the ecstasy on the
However, I wouldn't miss the the joy and
the ecstasy on the way.
It's
It's rather
It's rather it's
It's rather it's rather
It's rather it's rather profound.
It
It gives
It's rather it's rather profound.
It gives you
It gives you a
It's rather it's rather profound.
It gives you a certain
It gives you a certain you
It's rather it's rather profound.
It gives you a certain you see
It gives you a certain you see the
It's rather it's rather profound.
It gives you a certain you see the other
thing
thing that
thing that happens
thing that happens in
thing that happens in certain
thing that happens in certain states
thing that happens in certain states is
you
you get
thing that happens in certain states is
you get to
you get to know
uh
uh who
uh who else
uh who else is
uh who else is there
uh who else is there or
uh who else is there or who
uh who else is there or who else
uh who else is there or who else has
been
been there
uh who else is there or who else has
been there you
been there you might
uh who else is there or who else has
been there you might say.
You
You get
You get to
You get to experience
You get to experience the
You get to experience the presence
You get to experience the presence of
You get to experience the presence of a
rarified
rarified strata.
You get to experience the presence of a
rarified strata. And
rarified strata. And those
You get to experience the presence of a
rarified strata. And those who
rarified strata. And those who have
You get to experience the presence of a
rarified strata. And those who have been
there,
how
how can
there,
how can we
how can we say
there,
how can we say it?
how can we say it? It's
there,
how can we say it? It's outside
how can we say it? It's outside of
there,
how can we say it? It's outside of time.
It's
It's like
It's like they're
It's like they're still
It's like they're still there.
It's
It's like
It's like they're still there.
It's like a
It's like a shared
It's like they're still there.
It's like a shared experience
It's like a shared experience because
you
you you've
you you've transcended
you you've transcended temporality.
So
to
to go
to go into
to go into the
to go into the same
to go into the same state
to go into the same state as
to go into the same state as Christ
to go into the same state as Christ went
into
into or
to go into the same state as Christ went
into or Ramachrishna
into or Ramachrishna or
to go into the same state as Christ went
into or Ramachrishna or any
into or Ramachrishna or any of
to go into the same state as Christ went
into or Ramachrishna or any of the
into or Ramachrishna or any of the great
saints,
saints, it's
saints, it's like
saints, it's like you
saints, it's like you share
saints, it's like you share the
experience
experience with
saints, it's like you share the
experience with them.
experience with them. It's
saints, it's like you share the
experience with them. It's hard
experience with them. It's hard to
explain
explain but
explain but there's
explain but there's a
explain but there's a commonality
explain but there's a commonality of
experience
in
in which
in which your
in which your consciousness
in which your consciousness and
in which your consciousness and their
consciousness
consciousness are
in which your consciousness and their
consciousness are actually
consciousness are actually one
in which your consciousness and their
consciousness are actually one and
consciousness are actually one and the
same.
same. Um
so
in
in that
in that state
in that state one
in that state one experiences
in that state one experiences Ramach
Krishna's
Krishna's ecstasy
in that state one experiences Ramach
Krishna's ecstasy because
Krishna's ecstasy because his
in that state one experiences Ramach
Krishna's ecstasy because his ecstasy
and
and yours
and yours are
and yours are not
and yours are not different.
and yours are not different. It's
and yours are not different. It's all
the
the same.
And
And there's
And there's a
And there's a point
And there's a point I
And there's a point I call
And there's a point I call the
And there's a point I call the high
And there's a point I call the high pass
where
where you
And there's a point I call the high pass
where you get
where you get hit
And there's a point I call the high pass
where you get hit by
where you get hit by the
And there's a point I call the high pass
where you get hit by the lucid
where you get hit by the lucid or
temptation
and
and uh
temptation
and uh all
and uh all power
temptation
and uh all power is
and uh all power is yours
temptation
and uh all power is yours now
and uh all power is yours now that
you're
you're beyond
you're beyond karma.
Now
Now that
you're beyond karma.
Now that you're
Now that you're beyond,
you're beyond karma.
Now that you're beyond, you
Now that you're beyond, you don't
you're beyond karma.
Now that you're beyond, you don't have
to
to answer
to answer to
to answer to anything
to answer to anything or
to answer to anything or anyone.
to answer to anything or anyone. Now
that
that you
to answer to anything or anyone. Now
that you realize
that you realize there's
to answer to anything or anyone. Now
that you realize there's no
that you realize there's no adversarial
god
god who
god who will
god who will punish
god who will punish you
god who will punish you for
god who will punish you for anything.
And
And now
god who will punish you for anything.
And now that
And now that you're
god who will punish you for anything.
And now that you're beyond
And now that you're beyond personal
karma
karma karma,
all
all power
karma karma,
all power is
all power is yours.
karma karma,
all power is yours. Own
all power is yours. Own it.
karma karma,
all power is yours. Own it. All
all power is yours. Own it. All power
karma karma,
all power is yours. Own it. All power is
yours.
And
And in
yours.
And in that
And in that state,
yours.
And in that state, you
And in that state, you saw
yours.
And in that state, you saw exactly
And in that state, you saw exactly who
went
went through
went through and
went through and what
went through and what they
went through and what they said.
It's
It's a
went through and what they said.
It's a very
It's a very high
went through and what they said.
It's a very high test
It's a very high test and
went through and what they said.
It's a very high test and it's
It's a very high test and it's very
subtly
subtly expressed
subtly expressed by
subtly expressed by the
subtly expressed by the luciferic
subtly expressed by the luciferic energy
out
out of
subtly expressed by the luciferic energy
out of which
out of which it
subtly expressed by the luciferic energy
out of which it arises
and
and you
and you realize
and you realize that
and you realize that Jesus
and you realize that Jesus Christ
and you realize that Jesus Christ said
no
no to
and you realize that Jesus Christ said
no to it
no to it and
and you realize that Jesus Christ said
no to it and uh
no to it and uh you
and you realize that Jesus Christ said
no to it and uh you see
no to it and uh you see who
and you realize that Jesus Christ said
no to it and uh you see who else
no to it and uh you see who else said
and you realize that Jesus Christ said
no to it and uh you see who else said no
to
to it.
to it. Uh
because
because the
to it. Uh
because the falsehood
because the falsehood is
to it. Uh
because the falsehood is yes
because the falsehood is yes you're
beyond
beyond personal
beyond personal karma.
beyond personal karma. I
beyond personal karma. I mean
beyond personal karma. I mean this
presentation
presentation is
beyond personal karma. I mean this
presentation is not
presentation is not verbalized.
beyond personal karma. I mean this
presentation is not verbalized. It's
presentation is not verbalized. It's a
knowingness.
knowingness. It's
knowingness. It's a
knowingness. It's a knowingness
knowingness. It's a knowingness and
knowingness. It's a knowingness and this
knowingness
knowingness comes
knowingness. It's a knowingness and this
knowingness comes as
knowingness comes as a
knowingness. It's a knowingness and this
knowingness comes as a profound
temptation
and
and um
going
going to
going to say
going to say about
going to say about it.
The
The error
going to say about it.
The error is
The error is yes
going to say about it.
The error is yes you're
The error is yes you're beyond
going to say about it.
The error is yes you're beyond personal
karma
but
but you're
karma
but you're not
but you're not beyond
karma
but you're not beyond the
but you're not beyond the karma
karma
but you're not beyond the karma of
but you're not beyond the karma of the
infinite
infinite presence
infinite presence of
infinite presence of God
infinite presence of God whose
infinite presence of God whose context
is
is inclusive
infinite presence of God whose context
is inclusive all
is inclusive all of
infinite presence of God whose context
is inclusive all of all
is inclusive all of all that
infinite presence of God whose context
is inclusive all of all that exists.
You're
You're beyond
You're beyond your
You're beyond your personal
You're beyond your personal karma,
You're beyond your personal karma, but
you're
you're not
You're beyond your personal karma, but
you're not beyond
you're not beyond the
You're beyond your personal karma, but
you're not beyond the karma
of
of God
of God being
of God being the
of God being the infinite
of God being the infinite context
of God being the infinite context out
of God being the infinite context out of
which
which all
of God being the infinite context out of
which all all
which all all arises.
of God being the infinite context out of
which all all arises. So,
which all all arises. So, you're
of God being the infinite context out of
which all all arises. So, you're not
beyond
beyond the
beyond the karmic
um
realm
realm of
realm of God.
realm of God. You're
realm of God. You're beyond
realm of God. You're beyond personal
karma,
karma, but
realm of God. You're beyond personal
karma, but you're
karma, but you're not
realm of God. You're beyond personal
karma, but you're not beyond
karma, but you're not beyond the
realm of God. You're beyond personal
karma, but you're not beyond the karma
of
of the
of the universe.
So
So if
of the universe.
So if you
So if you make
of the universe.
So if you make that
So if you make that mistake,
of the universe.
So if you make that mistake, you
So if you make that mistake, you end
of the universe.
So if you make that mistake, you end up
along
along with
along with Lucifer
along with Lucifer and
along with Lucifer and his
along with Lucifer and his uh
along with Lucifer and his uh club
there.
there. Lucifer
along with Lucifer and his uh club
there. Lucifer club.
I
I already
I already answered
I already answered the
I already answered the next
I already answered the next question.
Um
it
it says
it says if
it says if you
it says if you as
it says if you as you
it says if you as you begin
it says if you as you begin reaching
higher
higher states,
it says if you as you begin reaching
higher states, you
higher states, you become
it says if you as you begin reaching
higher states, you become a
higher states, you become a more
it says if you as you begin reaching
higher states, you become a more um
favorable
favorable game
favorable game for
favorable game for the
favorable game for the lower
favorable game for the lower astral.
favorable game for the lower astral. you
become
become juicier
favorable game for the lower astral. you
become juicier and
become juicier and a
favorable game for the lower astral. you
become juicier and a nicer
become juicier and a nicer plum
favorable game for the lower astral. you
become juicier and a nicer plum to
become juicier and a nicer plum to haul
home.
home. So
you
you see
home. So
you see a
you see a lot
home. So
you see a lot of
you see a lot of gurus
home. So
you see a lot of gurus that
you see a lot of gurus that write
home. So
you see a lot of gurus that write books
that
that are
that are quite
that are quite well
that are quite well known.
that are quite well known. They're
that are quite well known. They're still
everybody
everybody lights
that are quite well known. They're still
everybody lights candles
everybody lights candles to
that are quite well known. They're still
everybody lights candles to them
everybody lights candles to them and
that are quite well known. They're still
everybody lights candles to them and all
and
and they
and they were
and they were in
and they were in the
and they were in the 500s
and they were in the 500s when
and they were in the 500s when they
wrote
wrote it,
and they were in the 500s when they
wrote it, but
wrote it, but they
and they were in the 500s when they
wrote it, but they they
wrote it, but they they have
and they were in the 500s when they
wrote it, but they they have gone
wrote it, but they they have gone way
down
down since.
down since. Uh
down since. Uh what
down since. Uh what do
down since. Uh what do the
down since. Uh what do the astral
down since. Uh what do the astral beings
get
get out
down since. Uh what do the astral beings
get out of
get out of that?
down since. Uh what do the astral beings
get out of that? They
get out of that? They get
down since. Uh what do the astral beings
get out of that? They get they
get out of that? They get they get
pulling
pulling pulling
pulling pulling that
pulling pulling that which
pulling pulling that which they
pulling pulling that which they hate
pulling pulling that which they hate and
that
that which
pulling pulling that which they hate and
that which is
that which is which
pulling pulling that which they hate and
that which is which they
that which is which they are
pulling pulling that which they hate and
that which is which they are jealous
back
back down.
back down. So
back down. So it's
back down. So it's like
back down. So it's like crabs.
back down. So it's like crabs. They
back down. So it's like crabs. They say
when
when you
back down. So it's like crabs. They say
when you put
when you put a
back down. So it's like crabs. They say
when you put a bunch
when you put a bunch of
back down. So it's like crabs. They say
when you put a bunch of crabs
when you put a bunch of crabs in
back down. So it's like crabs. They say
when you put a bunch of crabs in a
when you put a bunch of crabs in a pale,
as
as one
as one crab
as one crab starts
as one crab starts to
as one crab starts to get
as one crab starts to get out,
as one crab starts to get out, the
as one crab starts to get out, the other
crabs
crabs will
as one crab starts to get out, the other
crabs will pull
crabs will pull them
as one crab starts to get out, the other
crabs will pull them back
crabs will pull them back down
as one crab starts to get out, the other
crabs will pull them back down into
crabs will pull them back down into the
pale,
pale, it's
pale, it's for
pale, it's for the
pale, it's for the same
pale, it's for the same reason
pale, it's for the same reason that
anybody
anybody who's
pale, it's for the same reason that
anybody who's successful,
anybody who's successful, rich,
powerful,
powerful, etc.
powerful, etc. becomes
powerful, etc. becomes fair
powerful, etc. becomes fair target.
It's
It's um
powerful, etc. becomes fair target.
It's um you
It's um you know,
powerful, etc. becomes fair target.
It's um you know, discrimination
It's um you know, discrimination is
powerful, etc. becomes fair target.
It's um you know, discrimination is um
uh
uh politically
uh politically incorrect,
uh politically incorrect, unless
uh politically incorrect, unless you're
successful,
successful, in
uh politically incorrect, unless you're
successful, in which
successful, in which case
uh politically incorrect, unless you're
successful, in which case discrimination
and
and assault
and assault and
and assault and attack
and assault and attack and
and assault and attack and blackmail
and assault and attack and blackmail and
everything
everything else
and assault and attack and blackmail and
everything else can
everything else can be
and assault and attack and blackmail and
everything else can be thrown
everything else can be thrown at
and assault and attack and blackmail and
everything else can be thrown at you
because
because you're
because you're rich
because you're rich and
because you're rich and powerful.
because you're rich and powerful. Right?
same
same laws
because you're rich and powerful. Right?
same laws don't
same laws don't apply
because you're rich and powerful. Right?
same laws don't apply now.
Uh
so
so it
Uh
so it would
so it would be
Uh
so it would be out
so it would be out of
Uh
so it would be out of jealousy.
so it would be out of jealousy. So
Uh
so it would be out of jealousy. So it's
jealousy
jealousy and
jealousy and hatred.
jealousy and hatred. Uh
jealousy and hatred. Uh that's
jealousy and hatred. Uh that's the
motivation
motivation here
jealousy and hatred. Uh that's the
motivation here is
motivation here is jealousy
jealousy and hatred. Uh that's the
motivation here is jealousy and
motivation here is jealousy and hatred
is
is just
is just jealous.
is just jealous. It's
is just jealous. It's jealousy
is just jealous. It's jealousy and
hatred.
hatred. See
um
um they
um they don't
um they don't forget
um they don't forget that
um they don't forget that the
um they don't forget that the lower
astral
astral realm
um they don't forget that the lower
astral realm gains
astral realm gains by
um they don't forget that the lower
astral realm gains by the
astral realm gains by the more
um they don't forget that the lower
astral realm gains by the more evil
astral realm gains by the more evil they
are,
are, the
are, the more
are, the more they
are, the more they rank.
The
The game
are, the more they rank.
The game of
The game of dungeons
are, the more they rank.
The game of dungeons and
The game of dungeons and what
are, the more they rank.
The game of dungeons and what is
The game of dungeons and what is it?
Somethings
Somethings and
Somethings and dungeons.
>> Huh?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Doesn't
>> Yeah. Doesn't dragons
>> Yeah. Doesn't dragons and
>> Yeah. Doesn't dragons and dungeons
pretty
pretty well
>> Yeah. Doesn't dragons and dungeons
pretty well delineate
pretty well delineate the
>> Yeah. Doesn't dragons and dungeons
pretty well delineate the lower
pretty well delineate the lower astral.
It's
It's even
It's even got
It's even got the
It's even got the correct
It's even got the correct esoteric
terminology,
terminology, the
It's even got the correct esoteric
terminology, the names
terminology, the names for
It's even got the correct esoteric
terminology, the names for them.
terminology, the names for them. So,
It's even got the correct esoteric
terminology, the names for them. So, you
know,
know, you're
know, you're a
know, you're a made
know, you're a made guy
know, you're a made guy when
know, you're a made guy when you
know, you're a made guy when you murder
somebody
somebody in
know, you're a made guy when you murder
somebody in front
somebody in front of
know, you're a made guy when you murder
somebody in front of a
somebody in front of a witness.
know, you're a made guy when you murder
somebody in front of a witness. Now,
somebody in front of a witness. Now, you
rank
rank higher
rank higher in
rank higher in the
rank higher in the mafia.
rank higher in the mafia. Correct.
You're
You're just
rank higher in the mafia. Correct.
You're just riff
You're just riff raff
rank higher in the mafia. Correct.
You're just riff raff down
You're just riff raff down there
rank higher in the mafia. Correct.
You're just riff raff down there if
You're just riff raff down there if you
just
just rob
just rob banks
just rob banks and
just rob banks and steal
just rob banks and steal from
just rob banks and steal from from
honest
honest people,
just rob banks and steal from from
honest people, steal
honest people, steal cars
just rob banks and steal from from
honest people, steal cars and
honest people, steal cars and all.
You're
You're just
You're just punks.
You're just punks. Now
You're just punks. Now you're
You're just punks. Now you're nobody
You're just punks. Now you're nobody at
all
all till
You're just punks. Now you're nobody at
all till you
all till you are
You're just punks. Now you're nobody at
all till you are witnessed.
all till you are witnessed. So
You're just punks. Now you're nobody at
all till you are witnessed. So somebody
can
can attest
can attest to
can attest to the
can attest to the fact
can attest to the fact they
can attest to the fact they saw
can attest to the fact they saw you
murder
murder somebody
can attest to the fact they saw you
murder somebody in
murder somebody in cold
can attest to the fact they saw you
murder somebody in cold blood.
murder somebody in cold blood. Now
can attest to the fact they saw you
murder somebody in cold blood. Now you
got
got rank.
got rank. Huh?
So
So it's
got rank. Huh?
So it's the
So it's the rank
got rank. Huh?
So it's the rank of
So it's the rank of batter
got rank. Huh?
So it's the rank of batter and
So it's the rank of batter and batter
and
and better.
So
So the
and better.
So the higher
So the higher the
and better.
So the higher the captive
So the higher the captive you
and better.
So the higher the captive you can
So the higher the captive you can pull
in,
in, he
in, he now
in, he now becomes
in, he now becomes your
in, he now becomes your servant
in, he now becomes your servant and
in, he now becomes your servant and your
vassel.
vassel. So
in, he now becomes your servant and your
vassel. So you
vassel. So you gain
in, he now becomes your servant and your
vassel. So you gain power
vassel. So you gain power by
proilitizing
and
and pulling
proilitizing
and pulling people
and pulling people into
proilitizing
and pulling people into your
and pulling people into your ranks.
proilitizing
and pulling people into your ranks. I
believe
believe that's
believe that's what
believe that's what it's
believe that's what it's all
believe that's what it's all about.
That's
That's what
believe that's what it's all about.
That's what it's
That's what it's all
believe that's what it's all about.
That's what it's all about.
That's what it's all about. Resist.
That's
That's all
That's all it's
That's all it's about.
That's all it's about. It's
That's all it's about. It's just
That's all it's about. It's just the
gamemanship
gamemanship of
who
who can
who can be
who can be the
who can be the most
who can be the most evil
who can be the most evil and
who can be the most evil and therefore
ranked
ranked the
who can be the most evil and therefore
ranked the highest.
You
You know,
You know, this
You know, this history
You know, this history shows
You know, this history shows some
profound
profound examples
You know, this history shows some
profound examples we've
profound examples we've seen
You know, this history shows some
profound examples we've seen on
television.
Um
Um the
television.
Um the Japanese
Um the Japanese after
television.
Um the Japanese after they
um
the
the Japanese
um
the Japanese in
the Japanese in Nan
um
the Japanese in Nan King,
the Japanese in Nan King, the
um
the Japanese in Nan King, the uh
the Japanese in Nan King, the uh I
um
the Japanese in Nan King, the uh I think
it
it was
it was a
it was a Vietnamese
it was a Vietnamese uh
it was a Vietnamese uh soldier
bayonetting
bayonetting the
it was a Vietnamese uh soldier
bayonetting the infant
bayonetting the infant in
it was a Vietnamese uh soldier
bayonetting the infant in the
bayonetting the infant in the arms
it was a Vietnamese uh soldier
bayonetting the infant in the arms of
its
its mother
its mother took
its mother took on
its mother took on a
its mother took on a new
its mother took on a new rank.
its mother took on a new rank. the
ultimate
ultimate cruelty,
its mother took on a new rank. the
ultimate cruelty, hardness,
the
the surrendering
the surrendering to
the
the surrendering to the
the surrendering to the ultimate.
And
And that's
And that's how
And that's how you
And that's how you gain
And that's how you gain rank
And that's how you gain rank there
And that's how you gain rank there in
the
the lower
And that's how you gain rank there in
the lower Astral.
And
And when
And when you
And when you get
And when you get there,
And when you get there, you
And when you get there, you find
And when you get there, you find there's
people
people that
And when you get there, you find there's
people that are
people that are far
And when you get there, you find there's
people that are far more
people that are far more wicked
And when you get there, you find there's
people that are far more wicked than
people that are far more wicked than you
are.
And
And you're
are.
And you're not
And you're not the
are.
And you're not the top,
And you're not the top, you're
are.
And you're not the top, you're at
And you're not the top, you're at the
bottom,
bottom, baby.
the
the way
bottom, baby.
the way we
the way we tell
bottom, baby.
the way we tell you
the way we tell you what
bottom, baby.
the way we tell you what you
the way we tell you what you got
bottom, baby.
the way we tell you what you got to
the way we tell you what you got to do
to
to get
to get five
to get five at
to get five at the
to get five at the ranks.
Oh
Oh boy.
to get five at the ranks.
Oh boy. So,
Oh boy. So, you
to get five at the ranks.
Oh boy. So, you just
Oh boy. So, you just don't
to get five at the ranks.
Oh boy. So, you just don't want
Oh boy. So, you just don't want to
to get five at the ranks.
Oh boy. So, you just don't want to go
there.
Uh,
so
so the
so the lower
so the lower astrals
so the lower astrals to
so the lower astrals to keep
so the lower astrals to keep us
so the lower astrals to keep us from
being
being focused
so the lower astrals to keep us from
being focused on
being focused on enlightenment
and
and they
and they do
and they do represent
and they do represent the
and they do represent the temptations
and they do represent the temptations of
the
the de
and they do represent the temptations of
the de of
the de of the
and they do represent the temptations of
the de of the satanic
the de of the satanic and
and they do represent the temptations of
the de of the satanic and the
the de of the satanic and the lucifer.
All right.
All right. So
All right. So we
All right. So we answered
All right. So we answered those
All right. So we answered those pretty
well
well and
All right. So we answered those pretty
well and those
well and those are
All right. So we answered those pretty
well and those are things
well and those are things we've
All right. So we answered those pretty
well and those are things we've also
written
written about
written about to
written about to uh
written about to uh make
written about to uh make sure
written about to uh make sure people
comprehend
comprehend it.
Everybody
Everybody talk
Everybody talk you
Everybody talk you know
Everybody talk you know there
Everybody talk you know there tends
Everybody talk you know there tends to
be
be a
Everybody talk you know there tends to
be a a
be a a goody
Everybody talk you know there tends to
be a a goody goodiness
be a a goody goodiness about
spirituality
spirituality sometimes
that
that uh
spirituality sometimes
that uh is
that uh is a
spirituality sometimes
that uh is a form
that uh is a form of
spirituality sometimes
that uh is a form of denial
because
because the
because the spiritual
because the spiritual aspirant
because the spiritual aspirant is
because the spiritual aspirant is also
because the spiritual aspirant is also a
fair
fair target
because the spiritual aspirant is also a
fair target for
fair target for uh
because the spiritual aspirant is also a
fair target for uh that
fair target for uh that which
because the spiritual aspirant is also a
fair target for uh that which would
fair target for uh that which would like
to
to bring
to bring it
to bring it down.
to bring it down. And
to bring it down. And I
to bring it down. And I think
to bring it down. And I think every
spiritual
spiritual student
to bring it down. And I think every
spiritual student should
spiritual student should be
to bring it down. And I think every
spiritual student should be forewarned
forewarned
forewarned that
forewarned that that
forewarned that that which
forewarned that that which is
non-integorous
non-integorous will
forewarned that that which is
non-integorous will certainly
non-integorous will certainly seek
forewarned that that which is
non-integorous will certainly seek to
pull
pull you
pull you out
pull you out of
pull you out of the
pull you out of the game.
pull you out of the game. Certainly
pull you out of the game. Certainly seek
to
to pull
pull you out of the game. Certainly seek
to pull you
to pull you out
pull you out of the game. Certainly seek
to pull you out of
to pull you out of the
pull you out of the game. Certainly seek
to pull you out of the game
to pull you out of the game by
pull you out of the game. Certainly seek
to pull you out of the game by one
temptation
temptation or
temptation or another.
Is
Is it
temptation or another.
Is it best
Is it best to
temptation or another.
Is it best to avoid
Is it best to avoid pure
temptation or another.
Is it best to avoid pure people
Is it best to avoid pure people who
temptation or another.
Is it best to avoid pure people who are
spiritually
spiritually um
spiritually um uh
spiritually um uh below
spiritually um uh below integrity?
Uh
Uh that's
spiritually um uh below integrity?
Uh that's what
Uh that's what all
spiritually um uh below integrity?
Uh that's what all the
Uh that's what all the spiritual
teachers
teachers including
teachers including the
teachers including the great
teachers including the great Christian
saints
saints said
teachers including the great Christian
saints said to
saints said to not
teachers including the great Christian
saints said to not hang
saints said to not hang out
teachers including the great Christian
saints said to not hang out with
saints said to not hang out with uh
teachers including the great Christian
saints said to not hang out with uh such
people
people uh
people uh because
people uh because they
people uh because they have
people uh because they have sort
people uh because they have sort of
people uh because they have sort of a
collective
collective karma
people uh because they have sort of a
collective karma and
collective karma and just
people uh because they have sort of a
collective karma and just the
collective karma and just the fact
people uh because they have sort of a
collective karma and just the fact that
you're
you're there
you're there begins
you're there begins to
you're there begins to attract
you're there begins to attract things
you're there begins to attract things to
it.
That's
That's sort
That's sort of
That's sort of the
That's sort of the broken
That's sort of the broken window
principle
principle you
That's sort of the broken window
principle you know
principle you know which
That's sort of the broken window
principle you know which sociology
principle you know which sociology has
discovered.
The
The broken
discovered.
The broken window
The broken window you
discovered.
The broken window you see
The broken window you see this
discovered.
The broken window you see this this
takes
takes us
takes us beyond
takes us beyond causality.
What
What attracts
takes us beyond causality.
What attracts negativity
What attracts negativity is
takes us beyond causality.
What attracts negativity is the
What attracts negativity is the field.
See,
See, it's
See, it's not
See, it's not sequential
See, it's not sequential causation.
It
It isn't
See, it's not sequential causation.
It isn't that
It isn't that the
See, it's not sequential causation.
It isn't that the broken
It isn't that the broken window
See, it's not sequential causation.
It isn't that the broken window causes
something.
The
The negative
something.
The negative energy
The negative energy which
something.
The negative energy which is
The negative energy which is focused
there,
there, the
there, the attractor
there, the attractor energy
there, the attractor energy field
there, the attractor energy field which
is
is focused
there, the attractor energy field which
is focused there
is focused there brings
there, the attractor energy field which
is focused there brings about
is focused there brings about upon
itself
itself the
itself the broken
itself the broken window
itself the broken window which
itself the broken window which again
brings
brings upon
itself the broken window which again
brings upon itself
brings upon itself the
itself the broken window which again
brings upon itself the drug
brings upon itself the drug addict
itself the broken window which again
brings upon itself the drug addict which
again
again brings
again brings itself
again brings itself upon
again brings itself upon itself
again brings itself upon itself the
again brings itself upon itself the rape
which
which again
again brings itself upon itself the rape
which again brings
which again brings itself
again brings itself upon itself the rape
which again brings itself brings
which again brings itself brings upon
itself
itself the
itself the abandoned
itself the abandoned baby
uh
uh and
itself the abandoned baby
uh and those
uh and those addicted
itself the abandoned baby
uh and those addicted to
uh and those addicted to crime.
itself the abandoned baby
uh and those addicted to crime. And
uh and those addicted to crime. And it
shows
shows up,
shows up, of
shows up, of course,
shows up, of course, initially
shows up, of course, initially with
graffiti
graffiti and
shows up, of course, initially with
graffiti and broken
graffiti and broken windows
shows up, of course, initially with
graffiti and broken windows and
graffiti and broken windows and trash
shows up, of course, initially with
graffiti and broken windows and trash on
the
the streets.
the streets. But
the streets. But you
the streets. But you see,
the streets. But you see, it's
the streets. But you see, it's not
causal.
causal. It's
the streets. But you see, it's not
causal. It's not
causal. It's not that
the streets. But you see, it's not
causal. It's not that the
causal. It's not that the break
the streets. But you see, it's not
causal. It's not that the break broken
window
window causes
window causes the
window causes the rape
window causes the rape or
window causes the rape or that
window causes the rape or that the
window causes the rape or that the rape
causes
causes the
window causes the rape or that the rape
causes the crime
causes the crime or
window causes the rape or that the rape
causes the crime or that
causes the crime or that the
window causes the rape or that the rape
causes the crime or that the crime
causes
causes the
causes the drugs.
causes the drugs. And
causes the drugs. And then
causes the drugs. And then the
causes the drugs. And then the gangs
causes the drugs. And then the gangs get
into
into turf
causes the drugs. And then the gangs get
into turf war
into turf war over
causes the drugs. And then the gangs get
into turf war over who
into turf war over who owns
causes the drugs. And then the gangs get
into turf war over who owns the
building.
And
And I
building.
And I remember
And I remember the
building.
And I remember the last
And I remember the last time
building.
And I remember the last time I
And I remember the last time I saw
Brownsville
Brownsville or
Brownsville or the
Brownsville or the the
Brownsville or the the lower
Brownsville or the the lower Bronx,
Brownsville or the the lower Bronx, uh
the
the South
Brownsville or the the lower Bronx, uh
the South Bronx,
the South Bronx, it
Brownsville or the the lower Bronx, uh
the South Bronx, it was
the South Bronx, it was uh
Brownsville or the the lower Bronx, uh
the South Bronx, it was uh unbelievable.
It's
It's like
It's like you
It's like you don't
It's like you don't you
It's like you don't you say
It's like you don't you say this
It's like you don't you say this can't
be.
be. You
It's like you don't you say this can't
be. You drive
be. You drive through
It's like you don't you say this can't
be. You drive through the
be. You drive through the street
It's like you don't you say this can't
be. You drive through the street and
be. You drive through the street and you
see
see where
see where the
see where the smoke
see where the smoke has
see where the smoke has come
see where the smoke has come out
see where the smoke has come out of
see where the smoke has come out of all
these
these fire
see where the smoke has come out of all
these fire all
these fire all these
see where the smoke has come out of all
these fire all these buildings
these fire all these buildings have
see where the smoke has come out of all
these fire all these buildings have been
set
set on
set on fire.
set on fire. You
set on fire. You see
set on fire. You see where
set on fire. You see where the
set on fire. You see where the smoke
came
came out
set on fire. You see where the smoke
came out from
came out from the
set on fire. You see where the smoke
came out from the window
came out from the window and
set on fire. You see where the smoke
came out from the window and the
came out from the window and the side
set on fire. You see where the smoke
came out from the window and the side of
the
the windows
the windows side
the windows side of
the windows side of the
the windows side of the buildings
the windows side of the buildings are
all
all black
the windows side of the buildings are
all black and
all black and they're
the windows side of the buildings are
all black and they're covered
all black and they're covered with
graffiti.
graffiti. The
graffiti. The streets
graffiti. The streets are
graffiti. The streets are covered
graffiti. The streets are covered with
filth.
filth. People
graffiti. The streets are covered with
filth. People falling
filth. People falling over
graffiti. The streets are covered with
filth. People falling over with
drunkenness
drunkenness and
drunkenness and alcohol
drunkenness and alcohol and
drunkenness and alcohol and drugs
drunkenness and alcohol and drugs and
prostitution
prostitution openly
drunkenness and alcohol and drugs and
prostitution openly on
prostitution openly on the
drunkenness and alcohol and drugs and
prostitution openly on the street.
prostitution openly on the street. And
mugging
mugging mugging
mugging mugging will
mugging mugging will take
mugging mugging will take place
mugging mugging will take place right
mugging mugging will take place right in
front
front of
mugging mugging will take place right in
front of your
front of your eyes.
mugging mugging will take place right in
front of your eyes. They
front of your eyes. They don't
mugging mugging will take place right in
front of your eyes. They don't even
front of your eyes. They don't even give
a
a damn
a damn if
a damn if you
a damn if you watch
a damn if you watch amongst
a damn if you watch amongst somebody
right
right in
a damn if you watch amongst somebody
right in front
right in front of
a damn if you watch amongst somebody
right in front of your
right in front of your ass.
a damn if you watch amongst somebody
right in front of your ass. You
right in front of your ass. You say,
a damn if you watch amongst somebody
right in front of your ass. You say, "I
got
got to
got to be
got to be making
got to be making this
got to be making this up."
got to be making this up." You
got to be making this up." You know,
got to be making this up." You know, but
it's
it's like
got to be making this up." You know, but
it's like that
it's like that energy
got to be making this up." You know, but
it's like that energy field
it's like that energy field is
got to be making this up." You know, but
it's like that energy field is pulling
to
to it
to it it itself.
to it it itself. So
to it it itself. So you
to it it itself. So you see
to it it itself. So you see a
to it it itself. So you see a lifetime
where
where a
to it it itself. So you see a lifetime
where a person
where a person is
to it it itself. So you see a lifetime
where a person is born
where a person is born at
to it it itself. So you see a lifetime
where a person is born at a
where a person is born at a very
to it it itself. So you see a lifetime
where a person is born at a very low
energy
energy field.
energy field. They're
energy field. They're born
energy field. They're born into
energy field. They're born into that
kind
kind of
energy field. They're born into that
kind of a
kind of a neighborhood
energy field. They're born into that
kind of a neighborhood to
kind of a neighborhood to that
energy field. They're born into that
kind of a neighborhood to that kind
kind of a neighborhood to that kind of
parents
parents and
parents and unless
parents and unless their
parents and unless their energy
parents and unless their energy field
changes,
awful
awful things
awful things will
awful things will be
awful things will be happening
awful things will be happening to
awful things will be happening to them
throughout
throughout their
awful things will be happening to them
throughout their lifetime.
throughout their lifetime. So,
awful things will be happening to them
throughout their lifetime. So, they're
born
born into
born into a
born into a miserable
born into a miserable condition
born into a miserable condition here
born into a miserable condition here and
now
now they're
born into a miserable condition here and
now they're in
now they're in juvenile
born into a miserable condition here and
now they're in juvenile jail
now they're in juvenile jail here
born into a miserable condition here and
now they're in juvenile jail here and
they've
they've got
they've got multiple
they've got multiple misdemeanors
they've got multiple misdemeanors and
then
then that
they've got multiple misdemeanors and
then that usually
then that usually graduates
they've got multiple misdemeanors and
then that usually graduates to
then that usually graduates to a
they've got multiple misdemeanors and
then that usually graduates to a felony.
So,
So, when
So, when we
So, when we see
So, when we see a
So, when we see a person
So, when we see a person arrested,
So, when we see a person arrested, let's
say
say everybody
So, when we see a person arrested, let's
say everybody gets
say everybody gets um
So, when we see a person arrested, let's
say everybody gets um sad
say everybody gets um sad about
So, when we see a person arrested, let's
say everybody gets um sad about and
politically
politically correct
politically correct about
politically correct about three
politically correct about three times
now
now out
politically correct about three times
now out in
now out in California,
you
you know,
you know, in
you know, in the
you know, in the hell
you know, in the hell of
you know, in the hell of some
you know, in the hell of some guy,
you know, in the hell of some guy, he
he's
he's put
you know, in the hell of some guy, he
he's put away
he's put away for
you know, in the hell of some guy, he
he's put away for life
he's put away for life now
you know, in the hell of some guy, he
he's put away for life now for
he's put away for life now for stealing
a
a pizza.
a pizza. I
a pizza. I tell
a pizza. I tell you,
a pizza. I tell you, he
a pizza. I tell you, he ain't
a pizza. I tell you, he ain't being
a pizza. I tell you, he ain't being put
away
away for
a pizza. I tell you, he ain't being put
away for a
away for a pizza.
a pizza. I tell you, he ain't being put
away for a pizza. This
away for a pizza. This guy's
a pizza. I tell you, he ain't being put
away for a pizza. This guy's criminal
background
background goes
background goes back
background goes back to
background goes back to age
background goes back to age six.
background goes back to age six. He's
got
got probably
background goes back to age six. He's
got probably 49
got probably 49 misdemeanors.
He's
He's got
He's got 23
He's got 23 felonies
He's got 23 felonies that
He's got 23 felonies that nobody
detected
detected him
He's got 23 felonies that nobody
detected him detected
detected him detected yet.
Two
Two times
Two times in
Two times in prison,
Two times in prison, you
Two times in prison, you know,
Two times in prison, you know, the
Two times in prison, you know, the third
time
time is
Two times in prison, you know, the third
time is going
time is going to
Two times in prison, you know, the third
time is going to put
time is going to put you
Two times in prison, you know, the third
time is going to put you out
time is going to put you out and
Two times in prison, you know, the third
time is going to put you out and you
still
still steal
still steal a
still steal a pizza.
still steal a pizza. It
still steal a pizza. It means
still steal a pizza. It means there's
something
something missing
still steal a pizza. It means there's
something missing in
something missing in your
still steal a pizza. It means there's
something missing in your frontal
cortex,
cortex, then
cortex, then means
cortex, then means you're
cortex, then means you're not
cortex, then means you're not very
cortex, then means you're not very well
anchored
anchored in
cortex, then means you're not very well
anchored in reality.
anchored in reality. It
cortex, then means you're not very well
anchored in reality. It means
anchored in reality. It means you
cortex, then means you're not very well
anchored in reality. It means you can't
control
control your
control your own
control your own impulses.
control your own impulses. No,
control your own impulses. No, you
control your own impulses. No, you got
control your own impulses. No, you got a
disease
disease called
control your own impulses. No, you got a
disease called criminality
disease called criminality that
compulsively
compulsively you're
compulsively you're going
compulsively you're going to
compulsively you're going to keep
compulsively you're going to keep on
doing
doing it
compulsively you're going to keep on
doing it because
doing it because you
compulsively you're going to keep on
doing it because you can't
doing it because you can't learn
compulsively you're going to keep on
doing it because you can't learn from
experience
experience because
experience because you're
experience because you're not
experience because you're not afraid
experience because you're not afraid of
consequences
consequences because
experience because you're not afraid of
consequences because you
consequences because you can't
experience because you're not afraid of
consequences because you can't control
your
your own
your own impulses
because
because this
your own impulses
because this has
because this has been
your own impulses
because this has been a
because this has been a lifetime
lifestyle.
lifestyle. So
like
like the
lifestyle. So
like the pedophiles
like the pedophiles I've
lifestyle. So
like the pedophiles I've I've
like the pedophiles I've I've treated,
you
you know,
you know, he
you know, he got,
you know, he got, oh,
you know, he got, oh, I
you know, he got, oh, I only
you know, he got, oh, I only got
you know, he got, oh, I only got busted,
you
you know,
you know, he got, oh, I only got busted,
you know, one
you know, one time.
you know, he got, oh, I only got busted,
you know, one time. And
you know, one time. And then
you know, he got, oh, I only got busted,
you know, one time. And then in
you know, one time. And then in therapy
you
you find
you find out
you find out he's
you find out he's molested
you find out he's molested over
you find out he's molested over a
hundred
hundred kids.
you find out he's molested over a
hundred kids. This
hundred kids. This is
you find out he's molested over a
hundred kids. This is probably
hundred kids. This is probably number
the
the average
the average pedophile
the average pedophile I
the average pedophile I treated
the average pedophile I treated had
probably
probably molested
the average pedophile I treated had
probably molested at
probably molested at least
the average pedophile I treated had
probably molested at least 50
probably molested at least 50 or
the average pedophile I treated had
probably molested at least 50 or 60
probably molested at least 50 or 60 to
100 kids
100 kids before
100 kids before he
100 kids before he was
100 kids before he was arrested.
100 kids before he was arrested. So
100 kids before he was arrested. So he's
not
not being
100 kids before he was arrested. So he's
not being arrested
not being arrested for
100 kids before he was arrested. So he's
not being arrested for this
not being arrested for this incident.
He's
He's got
He's got a
He's got a record
He's got a record going
He's got a record going back
He's got a record going back this
He's got a record going back this time.
He
He just
He's got a record going back this time.
He just got
He just got caught
He's got a record going back this time.
He just got caught this
He just got caught this time.
He's got a record going back this time.
He just got caught this time. So
He just got caught this time. So you
have
have to
have to have
have to have the
have to have the whole
have to have the whole picture,
have to have the whole picture, the
whole
whole context.
have to have the whole picture, the
whole context. So,
whole context. So, as
have to have the whole picture, the
whole context. So, as we
whole context. So, as we said,
have to have the whole picture, the
whole context. So, as we said, the
whole context. So, as we said, the lie
is
is is
is is composed
is is composed of
is is composed of taking
is is composed of taking context
is is composed of taking context out
is is composed of taking context out of
taking
taking content
is is composed of taking context out of
taking content out
taking content out of
is is composed of taking context out of
taking content out of context.
And
And once
And once thing
And once thing you
And once thing you you'll
And once thing you you'll see
And once thing you you'll see that
And once thing you you'll see that the
media
media does
And once thing you you'll see that the
media does all
media does all the
And once thing you you'll see that the
media does all the time
media does all the time is
warp
warp reality
warp reality by
warp reality by by
warp reality by by not
warp reality by by not telling
warp reality by by not telling you
warp reality by by not telling you what
the
the context
warp reality by by not telling you what
the context was.
the context was. He
warp reality by by not telling you what
the context was. He got
the context was. He got busted
warp reality by by not telling you what
the context was. He got busted for
the context was. He got busted for a
pizza
pizza and
pizza and and
pizza and and what
pizza and and what else?
pizza and and what else? And
pizza and and what else? And he's
pizza and and what else? And he's stolen
thousands
thousands of
pizza and and what else? And he's stolen
thousands of things
thousands of things literally
pizza and and what else? And he's stolen
thousands of things literally going
thousands of things literally going back
over
over his
over his entire
over his entire lifetime.
A
A chronic
over his entire lifetime.
A chronic thief.
A chronic thief. How
over his entire lifetime.
A chronic thief. How many
A chronic thief. How many things
over his entire lifetime.
A chronic thief. How many things do
A chronic thief. How many things do you
think
think he's
think he's stolen
think he's stolen before
think he's stolen before he's
think he's stolen before he's finally
arrested?
arrested? Hundreds
think he's stolen before he's finally
arrested? Hundreds and
arrested? Hundreds and hundreds.
think he's stolen before he's finally
arrested? Hundreds and hundreds. The
rapist.
rapist. How
rapist. How many
rapist. How many times
rapist. How many times have
rapist. How many times have they
rapist. How many times have they raped?
Dozens
Dozens of
rapist. How many times have they raped?
Dozens of times.
Dozens of times. The
rapist. How many times have they raped?
Dozens of times. The pizza
Dozens of times. The pizza fell.
rapist. How many times have they raped?
Dozens of times. The pizza fell. 50,
Dozens of times. The pizza fell. 50, 100
times.
times. So,
times. So, they're
times. So, they're not
times. So, they're not going
times. So, they're not going to
times. So, they're not going to jail
times. So, they're not going to jail for
stealing
stealing this
times. So, they're not going to jail for
stealing this pizza
stealing this pizza at
times. So, they're not going to jail for
stealing this pizza at all.
What's
What's the
What's the answer?
What's the answer? I
What's the answer? I don't
What's the answer? I don't know
What's the answer? I don't know what
What's the answer? I don't know what the
answer
answer is.
What's the answer? I don't know what the
answer is. To
answer is. To keep
What's the answer? I don't know what the
answer is. To keep them
answer is. To keep them isolated
What's the answer? I don't know what the
answer is. To keep them isolated from
vulnerable
vulnerable people.
vulnerable people. As
vulnerable people. As far
vulnerable people. As far as
vulnerable people. As far as I
vulnerable people. As far as I know,
vulnerable people. As far as I know, I
don't
don't know
vulnerable people. As far as I know, I
don't know what
don't know what else
vulnerable people. As far as I know, I
don't know what else to
don't know what else to do
vulnerable people. As far as I know, I
don't know what else to do about
don't know what else to do about them.
It
It seems
It seems to
It seems to be
It seems to be an
It seems to be an incurable
It seems to be an incurable addiction.
And
And I
It seems to be an incurable addiction.
And I think
And I think it
It seems to be an incurable addiction.
And I think it comes
And I think it comes from
It seems to be an incurable addiction.
And I think it comes from the
And I think it comes from the lower
astral.
astral. These
astral. These are
astral. These are lower
astral. These are lower astrals
astral. These are lower astrals that
have
have somehow
astral. These are lower astrals that
have somehow gotten
have somehow gotten into
astral. These are lower astrals that
have somehow gotten into physical
have somehow gotten into physical bodies
for
for this.
for this. That's
for this. That's the
for this. That's the fact.
for this. That's the fact. Yeah.
for this. That's the fact. Yeah. Because
they
they have
for this. That's the fact. Yeah. Because
they have no
they have no spiritual
for this. That's the fact. Yeah. Because
they have no spiritual inclination
they have no spiritual inclination and
no
no capacity
no capacity for
no capacity for honesty.
Okay.
This
This is
This is traveling
This is traveling through
This is traveling through astral
This is traveling through astral realms,
which
which I
This is traveling through astral realms,
which I don't
which I don't recommend.
When
When did
When did Mother
When did Mother Teresa
When did Mother Teresa reach
When did Mother Teresa reach her
When did Mother Teresa reach her state
of
of bliss?
When did Mother Teresa reach her state
of bliss? Early
of bliss? Early in
When did Mother Teresa reach her state
of bliss? Early in life
of bliss? Early in life or
When did Mother Teresa reach her state
of bliss? Early in life or late
of bliss? Early in life or late in
When did Mother Teresa reach her state
of bliss? Early in life or late in life?
I
I don't
I don't know.
I don't know. Did
I don't know. Did she
I don't know. Did she ever
I don't know. Did she ever write
I don't know. Did she ever write an
autobiography
autobiography or
I don't know. Did she ever write an
autobiography or anything
autobiography or anything biographical?
Mother
Mother Teresa?
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, she
Mother Teresa?
>> Yeah, she did.
>> Did
>> Did she?
>> I
>> I don't
>> Did she?
>> I don't know
>> I don't know what
>> Did she?
>> I don't know what she
>> I don't know what she says
>> Did she?
>> I don't know what she says in
>> I don't know what she says in there
about
about when
about when she
about when she reached
about when she reached that
about when she reached that state.
about when she reached that state. Huh?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, she
about when she reached that state. Huh?
>> Oh, she doesn't
>> Oh, she doesn't talk
about when she reached that state. Huh?
>> Oh, she doesn't talk about
>> Oh, she doesn't talk about it.
about when she reached that state. Huh?
>> Oh, she doesn't talk about it. Well,
>> Oh, she doesn't talk about it. Well, we
calibrated,
calibrated, you
calibrated, you know,
calibrated, you know, that
calibrated, you know, that her
calibrated, you know, that her heart
calibrated, you know, that her heart is
extremely
extremely high.
calibrated, you know, that her heart is
extremely high. Her
extremely high. Her heart
calibrated, you know, that her heart is
extremely high. Her heart was
extremely high. Her heart was like
calibrated, you know, that her heart is
extremely high. Her heart was like 700.
Mother
Mother Teresa's
Mother Teresa's heart
Mother Teresa's heart was
Mother Teresa's heart was like
Mother Teresa's heart was like 700.
Mother Teresa's heart was like 700. It
came
came about
Mother Teresa's heart was like 700. It
came about as
came about as a
Mother Teresa's heart was like 700. It
came about as a result
came about as a result of
Mother Teresa's heart was like 700. It
came about as a result of Christian
devotion
devotion just
devotion just you
devotion just you know
devotion just you know the
devotion just you know the result
devotion just you know the result of
Christian
Christian devotion
devotion just you know the result of
Christian devotion you
Christian devotion you know
devotion just you know the result of
Christian devotion you know unswervingly
unswerving
unswerving devotion
unswerving devotion to
unswerving devotion to God
unswerving devotion to God and
unswerving devotion to God and um
there's
there's a
unswerving devotion to God and um
there's a question
there's a question about
unswerving devotion to God and um
there's a question about avoid
there's a question about avoid avoidance
you
you see
you see the
you see the ultimate
you see the ultimate state
you see the ultimate state is
you see the ultimate state is neither
attached
neither
neither attraction
neither attraction nor
neither attraction nor aversion
neither
neither attraction
neither attraction nor aversion
neither attraction nor
neither attraction nor aversion.
So
So one
So one surreners
So one surreners aversions
So one surreners aversions and
So one surreners aversions and asks
So one surreners aversions and asks to
see
see it
So one surreners aversions and asks to
see it differently
see it differently the
So one surreners aversions and asks to
see it differently the same
see it differently the same as
So one surreners aversions and asks to
see it differently the same as you
see it differently the same as you do
with
with attachments.
To
To have
with attachments.
To have an
To have an aversion
with attachments.
To have an aversion something
To have an aversion something is
with attachments.
To have an aversion something is like
the
the reverse
the reverse of
the reverse of an
the reverse of an attachment.
the reverse of an attachment. So
the reverse of an attachment. So the
ultimate
ultimate state
the reverse of an attachment. So the
ultimate state is
ultimate state is nonattached.
It
It means
It means you
It means you don't
It means you don't have
It means you don't have to
It means you don't have to be
It means you don't have to be detached.
You
You don't
It means you don't have to be detached.
You don't have
You don't have to
It means you don't have to be detached.
You don't have to avoid
You don't have to avoid it.
It means you don't have to be detached.
You don't have to avoid it. It's
You don't have to avoid it. It's okay
It means you don't have to be detached.
You don't have to avoid it. It's okay if
it
it is
it is and
it is and okay
it is and okay if
it is and okay if it
it is and okay if it isn't.
it is and okay if it isn't. Now
it is and okay if it isn't. Now that
isn't
isn't as
it is and okay if it isn't. Now that
isn't as hard
isn't as hard to
it is and okay if it isn't. Now that
isn't as hard to reach
isn't as hard to reach as
it is and okay if it isn't. Now that
isn't as hard to reach as you
isn't as hard to reach as you think
it is and okay if it isn't. Now that
isn't as hard to reach as you think it
is.
is. You
is. You see
is. You see this
is. You see this u
is. You see this u neutrality
is. You see this u neutrality is
is. You see this u neutrality is a
pretty
pretty released
is. You see this u neutrality is a
pretty released state.
pretty released state. There's
is. You see this u neutrality is a
pretty released state. There's a
teaching
teaching that
teaching that arose
teaching that arose in
teaching that arose in Sedona
teaching that arose in Sedona or
teaching that arose in Sedona or was
teaching that arose in Sedona or was in
actually
actually in
teaching that arose in Sedona or was in
actually in New
actually in New York
teaching that arose in Sedona or was in
actually in New York uh
actually in New York uh teaching
teaching that arose in Sedona or was in
actually in New York uh teaching how
actually in New York uh teaching how to
get
get to
get to neutrality,
get to neutrality, letting
get to neutrality, letting go,
get to neutrality, letting go, wanting
to
to change
get to neutrality, letting go, wanting
to change things,
to change things, control
get to neutrality, letting go, wanting
to change things, control them,
to change things, control them, make
them
them different,
them different, uh
them different, uh wanting
them different, uh wanting anything
them different, uh wanting anything uh
from
from other
them different, uh wanting anything uh
from other people.
from other people. And
them different, uh wanting anything uh
from other people. And it
from other people. And it takes
them different, uh wanting anything uh
from other people. And it takes you
right
right through
right through neutrality.
right through neutrality. You
right through neutrality. You know,
right through neutrality. You know, if
you
you get
right through neutrality. You know, if
you get the
you get the job,
right through neutrality. You know, if
you get the job, it's
you get the job, it's great.
right through neutrality. You know, if
you get the job, it's great. And
you get the job, it's great. And if
right through neutrality. You know, if
you get the job, it's great. And if you
don't,
don't, you
don't, you find
don't, you find one
don't, you find one elsewhere.
don't, you find one elsewhere. Uh
don't, you find one elsewhere. Uh so
it's
it's a
don't, you find one elsewhere. Uh so
it's a state
it's a state of
don't, you find one elsewhere. Uh so
it's a state of freedom
it's a state of freedom and
don't, you find one elsewhere. Uh so
it's a state of freedom and originally
when
when I
when I learned
when I learned the
when I learned the technique
when I learned the technique it
when I learned the technique it was
when I learned the technique it was back
east
east in
when I learned the technique it was back
east in New
east in New York
when I learned the technique it was back
east in New York and
east in New York and it
when I learned the technique it was back
east in New York and it was
east in New York and it was called
freedom.
Uh
Uh and
freedom.
Uh and it
Uh and it had
freedom.
Uh and it had to
Uh and it had to do
freedom.
Uh and it had to do with
Uh and it had to do with letting
freedom.
Uh and it had to do with letting go
attachments
attachments and
attachments and aversions
by
by letting
attachments and aversions
by letting go
by letting go wanting
attachments and aversions
by letting go wanting to
by letting go wanting to change
attachments and aversions
by letting go wanting to change them
by letting go wanting to change them in
yourself
yourself or
yourself or out
yourself or out in
yourself or out in the
yourself or out in the world.
yourself or out in the world. And
yourself or out in the world. And if
yourself or out in the world. And if you
continuously
continuously do
yourself or out in the world. And if you
continuously do that
continuously do that you
yourself or out in the world. And if you
continuously do that you become
continuously do that you become quite
detached.
detached. You
detached. You know
detached. You know it
detached. You know it is
detached. You know it is it's
detached. You know it is it's true
detached. You know it is it's true you
do
do become
detached. You know it is it's true you
do become quite
do become quite quite
detached. You know it is it's true you
do become quite quite unattached.
Uh
Uh so
Uh so all
Uh so all the
Uh so all the things
Uh so all the things that
Uh so all the things that you
Uh so all the things that you learn
Uh so all the things that you learn at
levels,
levels, you
Uh so all the things that you learn at
levels, you know,
levels, you know, it
Uh so all the things that you learn at
levels, you know, it isn't
levels, you know, it isn't that
Uh so all the things that you learn at
levels, you know, it isn't that two,
levels, you know, it isn't that two, you
know,
know, 500
know, 500 is
know, 500 is better
know, 500 is better than
know, 500 is better than 200.
know, 500 is better than 200. It's
know, 500 is better than 200. It's not
better
better than.
know, 500 is better than 200. It's not
better than. It's
better than. It's just
know, 500 is better than 200. It's not
better than. It's just you're
better than. It's just you're in
know, 500 is better than 200. It's not
better than. It's just you're in a
different
different space.
Uh
Uh like
different space.
Uh like being
Uh like being like
different space.
Uh like being like being
Uh like being like being in
different space.
Uh like being like being in a
Uh like being like being in a different
place
place on
place on the
place on the map.
place on the map. Your
place on the map. Your problem
place on the map. Your problem to
place on the map. Your problem to get
from
from here
place on the map. Your problem to get
from here to
from here to there
place on the map. Your problem to get
from here to there is
from here to there is different.
place on the map. Your problem to get
from here to there is different. If
from here to there is different. If you
start
start out
start out from
start out from Albuquerque
start out from Albuquerque or
start out from Albuquerque or you
start out from Albuquerque or you start
out
out from
start out from Albuquerque or you start
out from Denver
out from Denver or
start out from Albuquerque or you start
out from Denver or uh
out from Denver or uh you're
start out from Albuquerque or you start
out from Denver or uh you're just
out from Denver or uh you're just in
start out from Albuquerque or you start
out from Denver or uh you're just in a
different
different place
different place and
different place and therefore
different place and therefore you're
looking
looking at
different place and therefore you're
looking at different
looking at different lessons,
different place and therefore you're
looking at different lessons, but
looking at different lessons, but you
can
can go
can go from
can go from one
can go from one level
can go from one level quickly
can go from one level quickly all
can go from one level quickly all the
way
way up
can go from one level quickly all the
way up to
way up to the.
can go from one level quickly all the
way up to the. So
way up to the. So you
can go from one level quickly all the
way up to the. So you can't
way up to the. So you can't say,
can go from one level quickly all the
way up to the. So you can't say, "Well,
because
because you're
because you're at
because you're at 200
because you're at 200 this
because you're at 200 this week,
because you're at 200 this week, you
can't
can't be
because you're at 200 this week, you
can't be at
can't be at 500
because you're at 200 this week, you
can't be at 500 next
can't be at 500 next week.
because you're at 200 this week, you
can't be at 500 next week. You
can't be at 500 next week. You can
because you're at 200 this week, you
can't be at 500 next week. You can be
can't be at 500 next week. You can be at
500 on
500 on the
500 on the way
500 on the way home
500 on the way home in
500 on the way home in the
500 on the way home in the car."
Suddenly,
Suddenly, like
500 on the way home in the car."
Suddenly, like a
Suddenly, like a flash,
500 on the way home in the car."
Suddenly, like a flash, you
Suddenly, like a flash, you just
500 on the way home in the car."
Suddenly, like a flash, you just let
because
because whatever
because whatever whatever's
because whatever whatever's blocking
because whatever whatever's blocking it
the
the minute
because whatever whatever's blocking it
the minute you
the minute you let
because whatever whatever's blocking it
the minute you let it
the minute you let it go,
because whatever whatever's blocking it
the minute you let it go, then
the minute you let it go, then you
because whatever whatever's blocking it
the minute you let it go, then you open
for
for the
for the light
for the light to
for the light to come
for the light to come in
for the light to come in and
for the light to come in and the
for the light to come in and the light
comes
comes right
for the light to come in and the light
comes right in.
comes right in. So
yeah.
Yeah.
Yeah. How
yeah.
Yeah. How come
Yeah. How come a
yeah.
Yeah. How come a person
Yeah. How come a person can
yeah.
Yeah. How come a person can go
Yeah. How come a person can go from
yeah.
Yeah. How come a person can go from a
really
really great
really great state
really great state to
really great state to a
really great state to a lousy
really great state to a lousy state
really great state to a lousy state very
quickly
quickly in
really great state to a lousy state very
quickly in a
quickly in a matter
really great state to a lousy state very
quickly in a matter of
quickly in a matter of seconds?
That's
That's called
That's called being
That's called being human.
That's called being human. Huh?
That's
That's called
That's called being human. Huh?
That's called being
That's called being at
That's called being human. Huh?
That's called being at the
That's called being at the effect
That's called being human. Huh?
That's called being at the effect of
being
being a
being a human
being a human and
being a human and having
being a human and having a
being a human and having a human
being a human and having a human brain.
And
And the
being a human and having a human brain.
And the human
And the human brain
being a human and having a human brain.
And the human brain as
And the human brain as it's
being a human and having a human brain.
And the human brain as it's constructed
you
you understand
you understand is
you understand is an
you understand is an add-on.
you understand is an add-on. The
you understand is an add-on. The pre
prefrontal
prefrontal crotic
you understand is an add-on. The pre
prefrontal crotic cortex
prefrontal crotic cortex that
you understand is an add-on. The pre
prefrontal crotic cortex that which
makes
makes us
makes us human
makes us human is
makes us human is an
makes us human is an add-on
makes us human is an add-on to
makes us human is an add-on to the
makes us human is an add-on to the old
animal
animal brain.
makes us human is an add-on to the old
animal brain. The
animal brain. The reptilian
makes us human is an add-on to the old
animal brain. The reptilian brain
animal brain. The reptilian brain is
still
still there.
still there. All
still there. All the
still there. All the basic
still there. All the basic primitive
brains
brains all
still there. All the basic primitive
brains all throughout
brains all throughout the
still there. All the basic primitive
brains all throughout the eons
brains all throughout the eons from
still there. All the basic primitive
brains all throughout the eons from 40
400 million
400 million years
400 million years ago
400 million years ago uh
400 million years ago uh is
400 million years ago uh is still
400 million years ago uh is still there
and
and still
400 million years ago uh is still there
and still operative.
and still operative. And
400 million years ago uh is still there
and still operative. And um
and still operative. And um you
400 million years ago uh is still there
and still operative. And um you know
and still operative. And um you know by
choice
choice you
choice you can
choice you can become
choice you can become an
choice you can become an instant
choice you can become an instant killer.
The
The old
choice you can become an instant killer.
The old dragon
The old dragon is
choice you can become an instant killer.
The old dragon is still
The old dragon is still there
choice you can become an instant killer.
The old dragon is still there and
The old dragon is still there and uh
we've
we've learned
we've learned not
we've learned not to
we've learned not to to
we've learned not to to respond
we've learned not to to respond to
we've learned not to to respond to it.
But
But that
we've learned not to to respond to it.
But that impulse
But that impulse to
we've learned not to to respond to it.
But that impulse to kill
But that impulse to kill still
we've learned not to to respond to it.
But that impulse to kill still comes
But that impulse to kill still comes up,
doesn't
doesn't it?
doesn't it? Comes
doesn't it? Comes out
doesn't it? Comes out of the
doesn't it? Comes out of the old
amygdala
amygdala or
doesn't it? Comes out of the old
amygdala or wherever
amygdala or wherever the
doesn't it? Comes out of the old
amygdala or wherever the hell
amygdala or wherever the hell it
doesn't it? Comes out of the old
amygdala or wherever the hell it is.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Like
>> Yeah. Like the
>> Yeah. Like the what's
>> Yeah. Like the what's that
>> Yeah. Like the what's that dragon
>> Yeah. Like the what's that dragon that
one
one bite
>> Yeah. Like the what's that dragon that
one bite and
one bite and you're
>> Yeah. Like the what's that dragon that
one bite and you're you're
one bite and you're you're dead.
>> The
>> The the
>> The the m
>> The the m something
>> The the m something other
>> The the m something other dragon.
>> Kimoda
>> Kimoda dragon.
>> The the m something other dragon.
>> Kimoda dragon. Yeah.
>> Kimoda dragon. Yeah. Uh,
>> The the m something other dragon.
>> Kimoda dragon. Yeah. Uh, we
>> Kimoda dragon. Yeah. Uh, we have
permission
permission to
permission to calibrate
permission to calibrate his
permission to calibrate his energy.
Let's
Let's see.
permission to calibrate his energy.
Let's see. Komodo
Let's see. Komodo dragon.
permission to calibrate his energy.
Let's see. Komodo dragon. We
Let's see. Komodo dragon. We have
permission to calibrate his energy.
Let's see. Komodo dragon. We have It's
okay
okay to
okay to calibrate
okay to calibrate his
okay to calibrate his energy.
okay to calibrate his energy. It's
okay to calibrate his energy. It's over
20,
20, 25,
okay to calibrate his energy. It's over
20, 25, 30,
20, 25, 30, 40,
okay to calibrate his energy. It's over
20, 25, 30, 40, 45.
20, 25, 30, 40, 45. About
okay to calibrate his energy. It's over
20, 25, 30, 40, 45. About 45.
You
You get
You get bitten
You get bitten by
You get bitten by something
You get bitten by something that's
You get bitten by something that's at
45.
45. You
You get bitten by something that's at
45. You wish
45. You wish you
You get bitten by something that's at
45. You wish you hadn't.
Imagine
Imagine this
Imagine this guy.
Imagine this guy. He
Imagine this guy. He was
Imagine this guy. He was a
Imagine this guy. He was a friend
Imagine this guy. He was a friend of
Imagine this guy. He was a friend of a
smoothie
smoothie star
Imagine this guy. He was a friend of a
smoothie star or
smoothie star or something.
Imagine this guy. He was a friend of a
smoothie star or something. He
smoothie star or something. He goes
Imagine this guy. He was a friend of a
smoothie star or something. He goes into
the
the cage
the cage with
the cage with a
the cage with a Komodo
the cage with a Komodo dragon.
the cage with a Komodo dragon. Oh
the cage with a Komodo dragon. Oh my
god.
god. I
the cage with a Komodo dragon. Oh my
god. I think
god. I think with
the cage with a Komodo dragon. Oh my
god. I think with no
god. I think with no boots
the cage with a Komodo dragon. Oh my
god. I think with no boots on
god. I think with no boots on or
something.
>> Anyway,
>> Anyway, I
something.
>> Anyway, I think
>> Anyway, I think he's
something.
>> Anyway, I think he's still
>> Anyway, I think he's still alive.
So,
So, it's
So, it's possible
So, it's possible for
So, it's possible for a
So, it's possible for a person
So, it's possible for a person to
So, it's possible for a person to do
kinesiology
kinesiology with
So, it's possible for a person to do
kinesiology with a
kinesiology with a reasonable
So, it's possible for a person to do
kinesiology with a reasonable degree
kinesiology with a reasonable degree of
accuracy
accuracy by
accuracy by oneself.
accuracy by oneself. You
accuracy by oneself. You see,
accuracy by oneself. You see, one
accuracy by oneself. You see, one thing
about
about kinesiology
accuracy by oneself. You see, one thing
about kinesiology is
about kinesiology is you
accuracy by oneself. You see, one thing
about kinesiology is you can
about kinesiology is you can by
accuracy by oneself. You see, one thing
about kinesiology is you can by asking
about kinesiology is you can by asking a
question
question in
question in many
question in many different
question in many different ways.
question in many different ways. If
you're
you're doubtful
question in many different ways. If
you're doubtful about
you're doubtful about a
question in many different ways. If
you're doubtful about a question,
you're doubtful about a question, if
this
this is
this is so,
this is so, then
this is so, then that
this is so, then that over
this is so, then that over there
this is so, then that over there must
this is so, then that over there must be
so.
so. So
this is so, then that over there must be
so. So if
so. So if you
this is so, then that over there must be
so. So if you ask
so. So if you ask them
this is so, then that over there must be
so. So if you ask them independently,
you'll
you'll get
you'll get corroboration.
you'll get corroboration. So
if
if I
you'll get corroboration. So
if I was
if I was qu,
you'll get corroboration. So
if I was qu, you
if I was qu, you know,
you'll get corroboration. So
if I was qu, you know, questioning
if I was qu, you know, questioning the
level
level that
level that I
level that I got
level that I got on
level that I got on the
level that I got on the Komodo
level that I got on the Komodo dragon,
I
I would
level that I got on the Komodo dragon,
I would utilize
I would utilize other
level that I got on the Komodo dragon,
I would utilize other things
I would utilize other things I
level that I got on the Komodo dragon,
I would utilize other things I know
about
about reptilian
about reptilian life
about reptilian life and
about reptilian life and primitive
about reptilian life and primitive life
and
and primordial
about reptilian life and primitive life
and primordial life
and primordial life and
about reptilian life and primitive life
and primordial life and contextualize
and primordial life and contextualize it
now
now within
now within a
now within a whole
now within a whole field
now within a whole field of
now within a whole field of data.
now within a whole field of data. Then
if
if it
now within a whole field of data. Then
if it didn't
if it didn't fit
now within a whole field of data. Then
if it didn't fit the
if it didn't fit the data,
now within a whole field of data. Then
if it didn't fit the data, I
if it didn't fit the data, I would
now within a whole field of data. Then
if it didn't fit the data, I would have
to
to go
to go back
to go back in
to go back in and
to go back in and find
to go back in and find out
to go back in and find out why
to go back in and find out why that
to go back in and find out why that is.
So
what
what do
what do we
what do we say
what do we say the
what do we say the commod
what do we say the commod dragon
calibrated
calibrated at?
>> 45.
So
So he's
>> 45.
So he's worse
So he's worse than
>> 45.
So he's worse than um
So he's worse than um Tyrannosaurus
>> 45.
So he's worse than um Tyrannosaurus Rex.
Huh?
>> Uh
>> Uh we
Huh?
>> Uh we can
>> Uh we can do
Huh?
>> Uh we can do Tyrannosaurus
>> Uh we can do Tyrannosaurus Rex.
Huh?
>> Uh we can do Tyrannosaurus Rex. He's
over
over 65.
over 65. He's
over 65. He's over
over 65. He's over 70.
over 65. He's over 70. 75.
over 65. He's over 70. 75. Tyrannosaurus
Rex
Rex is
over 65. He's over 70. 75. Tyrannosaurus
Rex is at
Rex is at 70.
over 65. He's over 70. 75. Tyrannosaurus
Rex is at 70. And
Rex is at 70. And the
over 65. He's over 70. 75. Tyrannosaurus
Rex is at 70. And the Komodo
Rex is at 70. And the Komodo dragons
over 65. He's over 70. 75. Tyrannosaurus
Rex is at 70. And the Komodo dragons at
what?
>> 45.
>> All right.
>> All right. Mhm.
>> All right. Mhm. Well,
>> All right. Mhm. Well, I
>> All right. Mhm. Well, I mean,
>> All right. Mhm. Well, I mean, it's
>> All right. Mhm. Well, I mean, it's just
a
a curiosity,
>> All right. Mhm. Well, I mean, it's just
a curiosity, you
a curiosity, you know.
>> All right. Mhm. Well, I mean, it's just
a curiosity, you know. How
a curiosity, you know. How do
>> All right. Mhm. Well, I mean, it's just
a curiosity, you know. How do all
a curiosity, you know. How do all those
creatures
creatures line
creatures line up?
creatures line up? I
creatures line up? I don't
creatures line up? I don't want
creatures line up? I don't want to
creatures line up? I don't want to meet
one
one in
creatures line up? I don't want to meet
one in the
one in the dark.
creatures line up? I don't want to meet
one in the dark. Do
one in the dark. Do you?
creatures line up? I don't want to meet
one in the dark. Do you? The
one in the dark. Do you? The ego
creatures line up? I don't want to meet
one in the dark. Do you? The ego isn't
real,
real, is
real, is it?
real, is it? That's
real, is it? That's correct.
real, is it? That's correct. Um,
it's
it's not
real, is it? That's correct. Um,
it's not a
it's not a reality
real, is it? That's correct. Um,
it's not a reality anymore
it's not a reality anymore than
real, is it? That's correct. Um,
it's not a reality anymore than his
mind.
Both
Both mind
mind.
Both mind and
Both mind and ego
mind.
Both mind and ego are
uh
uh general
uh general terms.
uh general terms. The
uh general terms. The only
uh general terms. The only trouble
uh general terms. The only trouble with
using
using general
uh general terms. The only trouble with
using general terms
using general terms is
uh general terms. The only trouble with
using general terms is people
using general terms is people believe
uh general terms. The only trouble with
using general terms is people believe if
a
a thing
a thing has
a thing has a
a thing has a name,
a thing has a name, it
a thing has a name, it must
a thing has a name, it must have
a thing has a name, it must have an
existence
existence in
a thing has a name, it must have an
existence in reality.
That's
That's how
That's how uh
That's how uh a
That's how uh a great
That's how uh a great deal
That's how uh a great deal of
That's how uh a great deal of illusion
arises.
If
If we
If we call
If we call if
If we call if we
If we call if we have
If we call if we have a
If we call if we have a name
If we call if we have a name for
something,
something, then
If we call if we have a name for
something, then it
something, then it must
If we call if we have a name for
something, then it must be
something, then it must be real.
If we call if we have a name for
something, then it must be real. Uh
something, then it must be real. Uh a
lot
lot of
lot of names
lot of names are
lot of names are merely
lot of names are merely tautologies.
In
In other
lot of names are merely tautologies.
In other words,
In other words, it
lot of names are merely tautologies.
In other words, it means
In other words, it means what
lot of names are merely tautologies.
In other words, it means what you
In other words, it means what you define
it
it to
it to mean.
uh
uh and
it to mean.
uh and by
uh and by common
it to mean.
uh and by common usage
uh and by common usage it
it to mean.
uh and by common usage it gains
uh and by common usage it gains ground
and
and pretty
and pretty soon
and pretty soon the
and pretty soon the mind
and pretty soon the mind begins
and pretty soon the mind begins to
and pretty soon the mind begins to re
think
think it's
and pretty soon the mind begins to re
think it's a
think it's a it's
and pretty soon the mind begins to re
think it's a it's a
think it's a it's a reality.
and pretty soon the mind begins to re
think it's a it's a reality. The
think it's a it's a reality. The belief
in
in causality
in causality is
in causality is the
in causality is the most
in causality is the most um
serious
serious error
in causality is the most um
serious error in
serious error in that
in causality is the most um
serious error in that regard.
serious error in that regard. You
in causality is the most um
serious error in that regard. You see
because
because sequentially
because sequentially one
because sequentially one thing
because sequentially one thing follows
another.
another. We
because sequentially one thing follows
another. We now
another. We now impute
because sequentially one thing follows
another. We now impute from
another. We now impute from imagination
something
something mysterious
something mysterious within
something mysterious within the
something mysterious within the world
calls
calls causality.
Well,
Well, if
Well, if you
Well, if you dissect
Well, if you dissect all
Well, if you dissect all these
Well, if you dissect all these things
here,
here, you
Well, if you dissect all these things
here, you show
here, you show me
Well, if you dissect all these things
here, you show me causality,
here, you show me causality, you
Well, if you dissect all these things
here, you show me causality, you won't
find
find any
find any because
find any because there
find any because there ain't
find any because there ain't no
causality
causality there.
find any because there ain't no
causality there. Causality
is
is within
is within the
is within the belief
is within the belief system
is within the belief system of
is within the belief system of the
observer.
observer. It
is within the belief system of the
observer. It has
observer. It has no
is within the belief system of the
observer. It has no objective
independent
independent existence.
This
This is
independent existence.
This is demonstrated
This is demonstrated mathematically
independent existence.
This is demonstrated mathematically of
course
course in
course in quantum
course in quantum mathematics,
course in quantum mathematics, quantum
mechanics
where
where you
where you find
where you find what
where you find what you
where you find what you find
where you find what you find is
where you find what you find is what
where you find what you find is what you
look
look for.
What
What you
What you discover
What you discover is
What you discover is based
What you discover is based on
What you discover is based on intention.
Whatever
Whatever your
What you discover is based on intention.
Whatever your intention
Whatever your intention is
What you discover is based on intention.
Whatever your intention is is
Whatever your intention is is what
you're
you're going
you're going to
you're going to come
you're going to come up
you're going to come up with
you're going to come up with because
you're going to come up with because you
just
just defined
you're going to come up with because you
just defined it.
just defined it. By
you're going to come up with because you
just defined it. By defining
just defined it. By defining it,
you're going to come up with because you
just defined it. By defining it, you're
obviously
obviously going
obviously going to
obviously going to select
obviously going to select what
obviously going to select what you've
already
already defined.
So
So in
So in other
So in other words,
a
a pseudo
So in other words,
a pseudo objectivity
a pseudo objectivity tends
So in other words,
a pseudo objectivity tends to
a pseudo objectivity tends to reify
itself.
You
You know
itself.
You know what
You know what reify
itself.
You know what reify means?
to
to read
to read constantly
to read constantly in
to read constantly in a
to read constantly in a feedback
reinforce
reinforce itself
to read constantly in a feedback
reinforce itself because
reinforce itself because you
to read constantly in a feedback
reinforce itself because you believe
reinforce itself because you believe in
the
the reality
the reality of
the reality of something
the reality of something that
the reality of something that exists
only
only in
the reality of something that exists
only in your
only in your mind.
the reality of something that exists
only in your mind. When
only in your mind. When you
the reality of something that exists
only in your mind. When you look
only in your mind. When you look out
there,
there, you
there, you think
there, you think you
there, you think you get
there, you think you get verification
there, you think you get verification of
its
its existence
there, you think you get verification of
its existence which
its existence which you
there, you think you get verification of
its existence which you so
its existence which you so you
there, you think you get verification of
its existence which you so you get
its existence which you so you get an
amplification
amplification a
amplification a self-
amplification a self- feedback
amplification
amplification of
amplification a self- feedback
amplification of non-reality
which
which makes
which makes the
which makes the so-called
which makes the so-called ego
which makes the so-called ego difficult
to
to overcome.
Before
Before we
Before we started
Before we started the
Before we started the lecture
Before we started the lecture today,
they
they were
Before we started the lecture today,
they were over
they were over 4:35.
Before we started the lecture today,
they were over 4:35. 436.
they were over 4:35. 436. They
Before we started the lecture today,
they were over 4:35. 436. They were
they were over 4:35. 436. They were at
4.
4. Before
4. Before we
4. Before we started,
4. Before we started, we
4. Before we started, we started
4. Before we started, we started 436.
437.
437. Okay.
4. Before we started, we started 436.
437. Okay. Okay.
437. Okay. Okay. The
4. Before we started, we started 436.
437. Okay. Okay. The group
437. Okay. Okay. The group act
4. Before we started, we started 436.
437. Okay. Okay. The group act at
437. Okay. Okay. The group act at the
end
end of
end of the
end of the lecture.
end of the lecture. They
end of the lecture. They went
end of the lecture. They went up
end of the lecture. They went up over
four
four points.
end of the lecture. They went up over
four points. Five
four points. Five points,
end of the lecture. They went up over
four points. Five points, six
four points. Five points, six points,
seven
seven points,
seven points, eight
seven points, eight points,
seven points, eight points, seven
points.
points. The
seven points, eight points, seven
points. The group
points. The group went
seven points, eight points, seven
points. The group went up
points. The group went up today
seven points, eight points, seven
points. The group went up today seven
points,
points, eight
points, eight points,
points, eight points, seven
points, eight points, seven points,
seven
seven points.
points, eight points, seven points,
seven points. The
seven points. The average
points, eight points, seven points,
seven points. The average lifetime
seven points. The average lifetime is
five
five points.
five points. So
five points. So you
five points. So you went
five points. So you went up
five points. So you went up over
five points. So you went up over one
lifetime
lifetime just
five points. So you went up over one
lifetime just in
lifetime just in the
five points. So you went up over one
lifetime just in the today
lifetime just in the today today.
It
It isn't,
It isn't, you
It isn't, you know,
It isn't, you know, it
It isn't, you know, it isn't
It isn't, you know, it isn't just
It isn't, you know, it isn't just a
calibrated
calibrated level,
It isn't, you know, it isn't just a
calibrated level, you
calibrated level, you see,
It isn't, you know, it isn't just a
calibrated level, you see, because
we're
we're looking
we're looking at
we're looking at a
we're looking at a certain
we're looking at a certain fallacy
we're looking at a certain fallacy of
logic.
logic. See,
uh
uh it
uh it would
uh it would seem
uh it would seem like
uh it would seem like moving
uh it would seem like moving from
uh it would seem like moving from a
certain
certain point
uh it would seem like moving from a
certain point to
certain point to a
uh it would seem like moving from a
certain point to a certain
certain point to a certain point,
uh it would seem like moving from a
certain point to a certain point, we're
super
super superimposing
super superimposing an
super superimposing an artificiality.
thing
um
um to
um to eliminate
um to eliminate through
um to eliminate through a
um to eliminate through a a
um to eliminate through a a subtle
understanding
understanding a
um to eliminate through a a subtle
understanding a source
understanding a source of
um to eliminate through a a subtle
understanding a source of something
that's
that's been
that's been painful
that's been painful all
that's been painful all your
that's been painful all your life.
that's been painful all your life. The
payoff
payoff is
that's been painful all your life. The
payoff is enormous.
And
And is
And is that
And is that what
And is that what I'm
And is that what I'm saying?
And is that what I'm saying? Even
And is that what I'm saying? Even the
most
most subtle
And is that what I'm saying? Even the
most subtle shift
most subtle shift of
And is that what I'm saying? Even the
most subtle shift of awareness
most subtle shift of awareness about
something.
something. Now
something. Now it
something. Now it no
something. Now it no longer
something. Now it no longer has
something. Now it no longer has the
power
power to
something. Now it no longer has the
power to injure
power to injure you
something. Now it no longer has the
power to injure you or
power to injure you or harm
something. Now it no longer has the
power to injure you or harm you
power to injure you or harm you or
aggravate
aggravate you
aggravate you u
aggravate you u or
aggravate you u or make
aggravate you u or make you
aggravate you u or make you think
aggravate you u or make you think about
suicide.
suicide. Now
aggravate you u or make you think about
suicide. Now it's
suicide. Now it's a
aggravate you u or make you think about
suicide. Now it's a joke.
The
The difference
The difference between
The difference between tragedy
The difference between tragedy and
The difference between tragedy and a
joke
joke makes
The difference between tragedy and a
joke makes all
joke makes all the
The difference between tragedy and a
joke makes all the difference
joke makes all the difference in
The difference between tragedy and a
joke makes all the difference in the
world.
world. Huh?
All
All right.
world. Huh?
All right. So
All right. So re
world. Huh?
All right. So re recontextualizing
things
things may
things may only
things may only calibrate
things may only calibrate numerically
things may only calibrate numerically at
a
a certain
things may only calibrate numerically at
a certain time
a certain time but
things may only calibrate numerically at
a certain time but those
a certain time but those are
things may only calibrate numerically at
a certain time but those are germanal
ideas.
ideas. Those
ideas. Those are
ideas. Those are germanal
ideas. Those are germanal ideas.
ideas. Those are germanal ideas. So
ideas. Those are germanal ideas. So one
germanal
germanal idea
ideas. Those are germanal ideas. So one
germanal idea may
germanal idea may only
ideas. Those are germanal ideas. So one
germanal idea may only calibrate
germanal idea may only calibrate you
know
know change
know change your
know change your calibration
know change your calibration one
know change your calibration one point
but
but then
know change your calibration one point
but then because
but then because it's
know change your calibration one point
but then because it's been
but then because it's been planted
know change your calibration one point
but then because it's been planted now
it's
it's going
it's going to
it's going to transform
it's going to transform of
it's going to transform of its
it's going to transform of its own
nature
nature because
it's going to transform of its own
nature because your
nature because your intention
it's going to transform of its own
nature because your intention is
superimposed
superimposed upon
superimposed upon it.
superimposed upon it. So
superimposed upon it. So your
superimposed upon it. So your intention
will
be
be more
be more important
be more important than
be more important than whether
be more important than whether you
be more important than whether you went
up
up a
be more important than whether you went
up a few
up a few points
be more important than whether you went
up a few points or
up a few points or something
be more important than whether you went
up a few points or something like
up a few points or something like that.
What
What you
What you do
What you do with
What you do with it,
What you do with it, how
What you do with it, how you
What you do with it, how you value
What you do with it, how you value it
and
and where
What you do with it, how you value it
and where it
and where it grows
What you do with it, how you value it
and where it grows from
and where it grows from there.
What you do with it, how you value it
and where it grows from there. So
and where it grows from there. So ger
these
these things
these things become
these things become germinated
these things become germinated and
these things become germinated and then
you
you all
these things become germinated and then
you all have
you all have had
these things become germinated and then
you all have had the
you all have had the experience.
these things become germinated and then
you all have had the experience. You're
driving
driving down
driving down the
driving down the road
driving down the road and
driving down the road and all
driving down the road and all of a
sudden
sudden you
driving down the road and all of a
sudden you get
sudden you get a
driving down the road and all of a
sudden you get a complete
sudden you get a complete understanding
of
of something
of something you've
of something you've heard
of something you've heard for
of something you've heard for years
of something you've heard for years and
suddenly
suddenly you
of something you've heard for years and
suddenly you get
suddenly you get it.
of something you've heard for years and
suddenly you get it. You
suddenly you get it. You know
of something you've heard for years and
suddenly you get it. You know that's
suddenly you get it. You know that's a
joyful
joyful moment.
joyful moment. uh
joyful moment. uh it's
joyful moment. uh it's like
joyful moment. uh it's like whatever
joyful moment. uh it's like whatever was
blocking
blocking that
joyful moment. uh it's like whatever was
blocking that awareness
blocking that awareness is
joyful moment. uh it's like whatever was
blocking that awareness is removed.
blocking that awareness is removed. Now
certain
certain spiritual
certain spiritual information
certain spiritual information is
certain spiritual information is in
certain spiritual information is in and
of
of itself
certain spiritual information is in and
of itself transformational.
Okay,
Okay, let's
Okay, let's see
Okay, let's see that
certain
certain seinal
Okay, let's see that
certain seinal information
certain seinal information I
Okay, let's see that
certain seinal information I mean
certain
certain critical
certain critical information
certain critical information isn't
certain critical information isn't it
certain critical information isn't it is
in
in of
certain critical information isn't it is
in of itself
in of itself transformational
resistance.
resistance. Some
resistance. Some of
resistance. Some of what
resistance. Some of what was
resistance. Some of what was said
resistance. Some of what was said today
is
is transformational
resistance. Some of what was said today
is transformational resistance.
is transformational resistance. Okay.
resistance. Some of what was said today
is transformational resistance. Okay. So
in
in other
in other words,
in other words, all
in other words, all we
in other words, all we did,
in other words, all we did, we
in other words, all we did, we saw
in other words, all we did, we saw how
it
it shifted
in other words, all we did, we saw how
it shifted the
it shifted the blocks,
in other words, all we did, we saw how
it shifted the blocks, but
it shifted the blocks, but then
in other words, all we did, we saw how
it shifted the blocks, but then that's
going
going to
going to continue
going to continue and
going to continue and bring
going to continue and bring a
going to continue and bring a cascade.
So
that's
that's a
that's a lot
that's a lot to
that's a lot to assimilate.
It
It can
that's a lot to assimilate.
It can also
It can also be
that's a lot to assimilate.
It can also be upsetting
It can also be upsetting to
that's a lot to assimilate.
It can also be upsetting to try
It can also be upsetting to try to
assimilate
assimilate too
assimilate too much
assimilate too much too
assimilate too much too fast.
assimilate too much too fast. In
assimilate too much too fast. In a
assimilate too much too fast. In a way,
you
you have
assimilate too much too fast. In a way,
you have to
you have to like
assimilate too much too fast. In a way,
you have to like grow
you have to like grow with
assimilate too much too fast. In a way,
you have to like grow with it
you have to like grow with it and
assimilate too much too fast. In a way,
you have to like grow with it and let
you have to like grow with it and let it
sort
sort of
sort of settle
sort of settle and
sort of settle and then
sort of settle and then you're
sort of settle and then you're ready
sort of settle and then you're ready to
move
move on
sort of settle and then you're ready to
move on to
move on to the
sort of settle and then you're ready to
move on to the next
move on to the next point.
sort of settle and then you're ready to
move on to the next point. And
move on to the next point. And then
you're
you're ready
you're ready to
you're ready to move
you're ready to move on
you're ready to move on the
you're ready to move on the next
you're ready to move on the next point.
If
If you
you're ready to move on the next point.
If you jerk
If you jerk somebody
you're ready to move on the next point.
If you jerk somebody out
If you jerk somebody out right
you're ready to move on the next point.
If you jerk somebody out right out
If you jerk somebody out right out of
one
one of
one of these
one of these patterns
one of these patterns here
one of these patterns here and
one of these patterns here and throw
them
them into
one of these patterns here and throw
them into another
them into another one,
one of these patterns here and throw
them into another one, it
them into another one, it can
one of these patterns here and throw
them into another one, it can be
them into another one, it can be very
disruptive.
disruptive. Very
disruptive. Very disruptive.
So,
So, okay.
disruptive. Very disruptive.
So, okay. So,
So, okay. So, each
disruptive. Very disruptive.
So, okay. So, each person
So, okay. So, each person grows
disruptive. Very disruptive.
So, okay. So, each person grows then
So, okay. So, each person grows then at
the
the rate
the rate of
the rate of their
the rate of their own
the rate of their own capacity,
the rate of their own capacity, their
own
own intention,
the rate of their own capacity, their
own intention, their
own intention, their own
the rate of their own capacity, their
own intention, their own readiness,
their
their own
their own karmic
their own karmic rightness.
And
And each
their own karmic rightness.
And each of
And each of us
their own karmic rightness.
And each of us evolves
And each of us evolves at
their own karmic rightness.
And each of us evolves at a
And each of us evolves at a specific
rate.
rate. And
rate. And you
rate. And you don't
rate. And you don't know
rate. And you don't know what
rate. And you don't know what that
rate. And you don't know what that rate
is
is because
rate. And you don't know what that rate
is because as
is because as we
rate. And you don't know what that rate
is because as we said
um
um the
um the present
um the present has
um the present has already
um the present has already been
determined
determined by
um the present has already been
determined by the
determined by the future.
That's
That's a
That's a comfortable
That's a comfortable thought,
That's a comfortable thought, isn't
That's a comfortable thought, isn't it?
Everybody
Everybody here
That's a comfortable thought, isn't it?
Everybody here is
Everybody here is being
That's a comfortable thought, isn't it?
Everybody here is being pulled
Everybody here is being pulled by
That's a comfortable thought, isn't it?
Everybody here is being pulled by that
star,
star, the
star, the infinite
uh
uh power
star, the infinite
uh power of
uh power of enlightenment.
star, the infinite
uh power of enlightenment. That's
uh power of enlightenment. That's a
fact.
This
This entire
fact.
This entire audience
This entire audience is
fact.
This entire audience is being
This entire audience is being pulled
here
here because
here because they're
here because they're destined
here because they're destined for
enlightenment.
enlightenment. exist.
here because they're destined for
enlightenment. exist. Isn't
enlightenment. exist. Isn't that
amazing?
That's
That's annoyingness
amazing?
That's annoyingness that
That's annoyingness that I
amazing?
That's annoyingness that I never
That's annoyingness that I never checked
it
it with
it with calibration.
it with calibration. Uh
it with calibration. Uh otherwise,
there'd
there'd be
it with calibration. Uh otherwise,
there'd be no
there'd be no reason
it with calibration. Uh otherwise,
there'd be no reason to
there'd be no reason to be
it with calibration. Uh otherwise,
there'd be no reason to be here.
How
How to
How to be
How to be a
How to be a glider
How to be a glider pilot.
How to be a glider pilot. Unless
How to be a glider pilot. Unless you're
going
going to
How to be a glider pilot. Unless you're
going to fly
going to fly gliders,
How to be a glider pilot. Unless you're
going to fly gliders, you
going to fly gliders, you wouldn't
How to be a glider pilot. Unless you're
going to fly gliders, you wouldn't be
learning
learning on
learning on how
learning on how to
learning on how to be
learning on how to be a
learning on how to be a glider
learning on how to be a glider pilot,
would
would you?
learning on how to be a glider pilot,
would you? And
would you? And the
learning on how to be a glider pilot,
would you? And the the
would you? And the the spiritual
learning on how to be a glider pilot,
would you? And the the spiritual work
would you? And the the spiritual work is
quite
quite strenuous.
quite strenuous. It's
quite strenuous. It's quite
quite strenuous. It's quite difficult
quite strenuous. It's quite difficult at
times.
times. It's
quite strenuous. It's quite difficult at
times. It's very
times. It's very uplifting.
quite strenuous. It's quite difficult at
times. It's very uplifting. The
times. It's very uplifting. The overall
context
context is
context is uplifting.
context is uplifting. But
context is uplifting. But then
context is uplifting. But then what
context is uplifting. But then what that
pulls
pulls up
context is uplifting. But then what that
pulls up into
pulls up into the
context is uplifting. But then what that
pulls up into the direct
pulls up into the direct focus
context is uplifting. But then what that
pulls up into the direct focus of
pulls up into the direct focus of your
awareness
awareness can
awareness can be
awareness can be sometimes
awareness can be sometimes painful
awareness can be sometimes painful and
difficult
difficult and
awareness can be sometimes painful and
difficult and bring
difficult and bring up
awareness can be sometimes painful and
difficult and bring up temporarily
difficult and bring up temporarily guilt
and
and negative
and negative feelings.
and negative feelings. Don't
and negative feelings. Don't forget
and negative feelings. Don't forget that
our
our consciousness
and negative feelings. Don't forget that
our consciousness evolved
our consciousness evolved over
and negative feelings. Don't forget that
our consciousness evolved over the
our consciousness evolved over the ages
over
over the
over the eons
over the eons came
over the eons came up
over the eons came up through
over the eons came up through as
over the eons came up through as far
over the eons came up through as far as
we
we can
over the eons came up through as far as
we can trace
we can trace it
over the eons came up through as far as
we can trace it up
we can trace it up through
over the eons came up through as far as
we can trace it up through the
we can trace it up through the animal
world
world uh
world uh the
world uh the reptilian
world uh the reptilian world
world uh the reptilian world on
world uh the reptilian world on up
through
through the
world uh the reptilian world on up
through the mamlon.
And
And what
And what you
And what you pull
And what you pull up
And what you pull up out
And what you pull up out of
And what you pull up out of the
unconscious
unconscious then
And what you pull up out of the
unconscious then you
unconscious then you can
And what you pull up out of the
unconscious then you can spot
unconscious then you can spot where
And what you pull up out of the
unconscious then you can spot where its
origin
origin was
origin was back
origin was back in
origin was back in time
origin was back in time and
origin was back in time and stop
origin was back in time and stop beating
yourself
yourself up
origin was back in time and stop beating
yourself up with
yourself up with guilt.
origin was back in time and stop beating
yourself up with guilt. Jealousy
yourself up with guilt. Jealousy arose
long
long before
long before you
long before you hit
long before you hit this
long before you hit this planet.
long before you hit this planet. You
long before you hit this planet. You can
watch
watch any
long before you hit this planet. You can
watch any monkey
watch any monkey colony
long before you hit this planet. You can
watch any monkey colony and
watch any monkey colony and that's
you'll
you'll see
you'll see jealousy
you'll see jealousy right
you'll see jealousy right and
you'll see jealousy right and left.
you'll see jealousy right and left. This
is
is mine.
you'll see jealousy right and left. This
is mine. This
is mine. This is
you'll see jealousy right and left. This
is mine. This is mine
fighting
fighting for
fighting for the
fighting for the alpha
fighting for the alpha male
fighting for the alpha male position,
the
the alpha
fighting for the alpha male position,
the alpha female
the alpha female position.
fighting for the alpha male position,
the alpha female position. Uh
the alpha female position. Uh joining
fighting for the alpha male position,
the alpha female position. Uh joining up
in
in groups,
in groups, this
in groups, this group
in groups, this group uses
in groups, this group uses against
in groups, this group uses against them.
Uh
Uh so
in groups, this group uses against them.
Uh so you
Uh so you once
in groups, this group uses against them.
Uh so you once you
Uh so you once you see
in groups, this group uses against them.
Uh so you once you see its
Uh so you once you see its origin
in groups, this group uses against them.
Uh so you once you see its origin then
you
you stop
you stop attacking
you stop attacking yourself.
you stop attacking yourself. It's
you stop attacking yourself. It's not
personal.
personal. It's
you stop attacking yourself. It's not
personal. It's part
personal. It's part of
you stop attacking yourself. It's not
personal. It's part of the
personal. It's part of the one's
you stop attacking yourself. It's not
personal. It's part of the one's karmic
uh
uh inheritance
uh inheritance as
uh inheritance as a
uh inheritance as a human
uh inheritance as a human being
uh inheritance as a human being is
uh inheritance as a human being is to
inherit
inherit that
uh inheritance as a human being is to
inherit that configuration
inherit that configuration of
instinctual
instinctual reflexes
instinctual reflexes that
instinctual reflexes that we
instinctual reflexes that we call
instinctual reflexes that we call ego
but
but they're
instinctual reflexes that we call ego
but they're really
but they're really animal
instinctual reflexes that we call ego
but they're really animal instincts.
Everything
Everything about
Everything about the
Everything about the ego
Everything about the ego you
Everything about the ego you can
Everything about the ego you can spot
Everything about the ego you can spot in
the
the animal
Everything about the ego you can spot in
the animal kingdom
the animal kingdom and
Everything about the ego you can spot in
the animal kingdom and you
the animal kingdom and you can
Everything about the ego you can spot in
the animal kingdom and you can see
the animal kingdom and you can see where
it
it arose.
uh
uh with
it arose.
uh with the
uh with the exception
it arose.
uh with the exception of
uh with the exception of quantum
mechanics
mechanics which
mechanics which did
mechanics which did not
mechanics which did not arise
mechanics which did not arise in
mechanics which did not arise in the
animal
animal kingdom.
Now
Now we
Now we beat
Now we beat them
Now we beat them out
Now we beat them out there,
Now we beat them out there, didn't
Now we beat them out there, didn't we?
Take
Take that
Now we beat them out there, didn't we?
Take that monkeys
Take that monkeys and
Now we beat them out there, didn't we?
Take that monkeys and zebras
and
and we
and we had
and we had fun
and we had fun calibrating,
and we had fun calibrating, you
and we had fun calibrating, you know,
various
various animals
and we had fun calibrating, you know,
various animals and
various animals and uh
and we had fun calibrating, you know,
various animals and uh zebras
various animals and uh zebras and
kangaroos
kangaroos and
kangaroos and it's
kangaroos and it's very
kangaroos and it's very so
kangaroos and it's very so it's
kangaroos and it's very so it's a
kangaroos and it's very so it's a lot
kangaroos and it's very so it's a lot of
fun
fun to
kangaroos and it's very so it's a lot of
fun to calibrate
fun to calibrate the
kangaroos and it's very so it's a lot of
fun to calibrate the energy
fun to calibrate the energy field
kangaroos and it's very so it's a lot of
fun to calibrate the energy field of
fun to calibrate the energy field of all
these
these animals.
these animals. And
these animals. And uh
these animals. And uh what
these animals. And uh what was
these animals. And uh what was the
these animals. And uh what was the one
we
we did
these animals. And uh what was the one
we did with
we did with the
these animals. And uh what was the one
we did with the long
we did with the long necks?
these animals. And uh what was the one
we did with the long necks? Giraffes.
Didn't
Didn't we
Didn't we say
Didn't we say giraffes
Didn't we say giraffes were
Didn't we say giraffes were 170?
Giraffes
Giraffes were
Didn't we say giraffes were 170?
Giraffes were 170
Giraffes were 170 175.
Didn't we say giraffes were 170?
Giraffes were 170 175. Giraffes
Giraffes were 170 175. Giraffes are
Didn't we say giraffes were 170?
Giraffes were 170 175. Giraffes are 170.
Isn't
Isn't that
Isn't that interesting?
Isn't that interesting? That's
Isn't that interesting? That's That's
higher
higher than
Isn't that interesting? That's That's
higher than a
higher than a lot
Isn't that interesting? That's That's
higher than a lot of
higher than a lot of people
Isn't that interesting? That's That's
higher than a lot of people on
higher than a lot of people on the
planet,
planet, isn't
planet, isn't it?
You're
You're better
planet, isn't it?
You're better off
You're better off being
planet, isn't it?
You're better off being a
You're better off being a giraffe.
planet, isn't it?
You're better off being a giraffe. I
mean,
mean, you
mean, you wander
mean, you wander around
mean, you wander around there
mean, you wander around there and
mean, you wander around there and you
eat
eat from
mean, you wander around there and you
eat from the
eat from the trees
mean, you wander around there and you
eat from the trees and
eat from the trees and you
mean, you wander around there and you
eat from the trees and you mind
eat from the trees and you mind your
mean, you wander around there and you
eat from the trees and you mind your own
business
business and
business and a
business and a giraffe
business and a giraffe doesn't
business and a giraffe doesn't give
business and a giraffe doesn't give you
a
a problem
business and a giraffe doesn't give you
a problem unless
a problem unless you
business and a giraffe doesn't give you
a problem unless you start
a problem unless you start attacking
them.
them. And
them. And if
them. And if you
them. And if you attack
them. And if you attack a
them. And if you attack a giraffe,
them. And if you attack a giraffe, he'll
give
give you
them. And if you attack a giraffe, he'll
give you a
give you a hop
them. And if you attack a giraffe, he'll
give you a hop with
give you a hop with his
them. And if you attack a giraffe, he'll
give you a hop with his hoof
give you a hop with his hoof and
them. And if you attack a giraffe, he'll
give you a hop with his hoof and send
you
you flying.
you flying. So
that's
that's a
you flying. So
that's a pretty
that's a pretty nice
you flying. So
that's a pretty nice way
that's a pretty nice way to
you flying. So
that's a pretty nice way to be.
that's a pretty nice way to be. You
you flying. So
that's a pretty nice way to be. You just
wander
wander around
wander around eating
wander around eating from
wander around eating from the
wander around eating from the trees
wander around eating from the trees and
you
you don't
wander around eating from the trees and
you don't bother
you don't bother anybody
wander around eating from the trees and
you don't bother anybody unless
you don't bother anybody unless they
wander around eating from the trees and
you don't bother anybody unless they try
to
to unless
to unless a
to unless a lion.
to unless a lion. The
to unless a lion. The lion
to unless a lion. The lion has
to unless a lion. The lion has a
to unless a lion. The lion has a hard
time
time with
to unless a lion. The lion has a hard
time with a
time with a giraffe
to unless a lion. The lion has a hard
time with a giraffe cuz
time with a giraffe cuz a
to unless a lion. The lion has a hard
time with a giraffe cuz a giraffe's
really
really going
really going to
really going to get
really going to get annoyed
really going to get annoyed by
really going to get annoyed by a
really going to get annoyed by a lion.
So,
So, but
really going to get annoyed by a lion.
So, but it's
So, but it's interesting
really going to get annoyed by a lion.
So, but it's interesting just
So, but it's interesting just to
calibrate
calibrate different
calibrate different groups
calibrate different groups of
calibrate different groups of animals
because
because you're
calibrate different groups of animals
because you're seeing
because you're seeing and
calibrate different groups of animals
because you're seeing and you
because you're seeing and you begin
calibrate different groups of animals
because you're seeing and you begin to
recognize
recognize in
recognize in yourself
recognize in yourself where
recognize in yourself where that
recognize in yourself where that all
came
came from.
recognize in yourself where that all
came from. Within
came from. Within you
recognize in yourself where that all
came from. Within you is
came from. Within you is the
recognize in yourself where that all
came from. Within you is the happy
came from. Within you is the happy uh
vegetarian
vegetarian who
vegetarian who just
vegetarian who just like
vegetarian who just like to
vegetarian who just like to munch
vegetarian who just like to munch from
the
the trees
vegetarian who just like to munch from
the trees and
the trees and not
vegetarian who just like to munch from
the trees and not be
the trees and not be bothered
vegetarian who just like to munch from
the trees and not be bothered with
people.
people. In
people. In you
people. In you is
people. In you is also
people. In you is also the
people. In you is also the tiger.
people. In you is also the tiger. You
push
push me
people. In you is also the tiger. You
push me far
push me far enough
people. In you is also the tiger. You
push me far enough and
and
and you're
and you're going
and you're going to
and you're going to pull
and you're going to pull out
and you're going to pull out my
and you're going to pull out my claws.
So
So you
and you're going to pull out my claws.
So you see
So you see the
and you're going to pull out my claws.
So you see the origin
So you see the origin of
and you're going to pull out my claws.
So you see the origin of all
So you see the origin of all that
and you're going to pull out my claws.
So you see the origin of all that and
seeing
seeing the
seeing the origin
seeing the origin of
seeing the origin of it
seeing the origin of it then
seeing the origin of it then removes
seeing the origin of it then removes it
from
from a
seeing the origin of it then removes it
from a personal
from a personal identification.
You
You realize
You realize it's
You realize it's the
You realize it's the source
You realize it's the source of
You realize it's the source of the
consciousness
consciousness which
You realize it's the source of the
consciousness which you
consciousness which you now
You realize it's the source of the
consciousness which you now call
consciousness which you now call me.
You realize it's the source of the
consciousness which you now call me. But
its
its origin,
its origin, you
its origin, you did
its origin, you did not
its origin, you did not devise
its origin, you did not devise that.
Lions
Lions were
its origin, you did not devise that.
Lions were around.
Lions were around. Ser
its origin, you did not devise that.
Lions were around. Ser tiger
Lions were around. Ser tiger was
its origin, you did not devise that.
Lions were around. Ser tiger was around
before
before you
before you got
before you got here.
before you got here. Yeah.
>> Do
>> Do we
before you got here. Yeah.
>> Do we have
>> Do we have spiritual
before you got here. Yeah.
>> Do we have spiritual buddies
>> Do we have spiritual buddies that
before you got here. Yeah.
>> Do we have spiritual buddies that we
>> Do we have spiritual buddies that we had
to
to hang
to hang out
to hang out with?
>> What
>> What does
to hang out with?
>> What does everybody
>> What does everybody think
to hang out with?
>> What does everybody think about
>> What does everybody think about that?
>> Everybody
>> Everybody thinks
>> Everybody thinks so.
>> Everybody thinks so. We
>> Everybody thinks so. We all
>> Everybody thinks so. We all got
spiritual
spiritual pals
>> Everybody thinks so. We all got
spiritual pals we've
spiritual pals we've been
>> Everybody thinks so. We all got
spiritual pals we've been hanging
spiritual pals we've been hanging out
with
with probably
with probably for
with probably for lifetimes.
And
And uh
with probably for lifetimes.
And uh let's
And uh let's see.
with probably for lifetimes.
And uh let's see. We'll
And uh let's see. We'll ask
Uh
Uh we
Uh we got
Uh we got people
Uh we got people with
Uh we got people with whom
Uh we got people with whom we're
spiritually
spiritually aligned
Uh we got people with whom we're
spiritually aligned for
spiritually aligned for lifetimes
Uh we got people with whom we're
spiritually aligned for lifetimes with
this
this sympatico
uh
uh buddies
this sympatico
uh buddies like
uh buddies like friends.
We're
We're all
We're all in
We're all in the
We're all in the boat
We're all in the boat together
We're all in the boat together kind
We're all in the boat together kind of
thing.
thing. Yeah.
We're
We're all
We're all in
We're all in the
We're all in the boat
We're all in the boat together.
Yeah.
Yeah. And
We're all in the boat together.
Yeah. And uh
Yeah. And uh quite
We're all in the boat together.
Yeah. And uh quite a
Yeah. And uh quite a few
We're all in the boat together.
Yeah. And uh quite a few of
Yeah. And uh quite a few of us
We're all in the boat together.
Yeah. And uh quite a few of us are
Yeah. And uh quite a few of us are here
right
right now.
Yeah.
Yeah. Quite
right now.
Yeah. Quite Yeah.
Yeah. Quite Yeah. So,
right now.
Yeah. Quite Yeah. So, we're
Yeah. Quite Yeah. So, we're hanging
right now.
Yeah. Quite Yeah. So, we're hanging out
together.
together. I
together. I mean,
together. I mean, let's
together. I mean, let's see.
A
A lot
together. I mean, let's see.
A lot of
A lot of us
together. I mean, let's see.
A lot of us are
A lot of us are hanging
together. I mean, let's see.
A lot of us are hanging out
A lot of us are hanging out together
here.
here. Over
here. Over 50%,
here. Over 50%, 60%,
here. Over 50%, 60%, 70%,
here. Over 50%, 60%, 70%, 75%.
All
All this
here. Over 50%, 60%, 70%, 75%.
All this recorded
All this recorded with
here. Over 50%, 60%, 70%, 75%.
All this recorded with us
All this recorded with us have
here. Over 50%, 60%, 70%, 75%.
All this recorded with us have been
hanging
hanging out
hanging out together
hanging out together for
hanging out together for really
hanging out together for really quite
hanging out together for really quite a
long
long time
as
as an
as an expression
as an expression of
as an expression of our
as an expression of our love
as an expression of our love for
as an expression of our love for each
other.
other. You
as an expression of our love for each
other. You see,
other. You see, the
as an expression of our love for each
other. You see, the love
other. You see, the love for
as an expression of our love for each
other. You see, the love for each
other. You see, the love for each other
creates
creates the
creates the field
creates the field and
creates the field and then
creates the field and then we're
attracted
attracted to
creates the field and then we're
attracted to reincarnate
attracted to reincarnate in
creates the field and then we're
attracted to reincarnate in that
attracted to reincarnate in that field.
Um
Um because
Um because in
Um because in a
Um because in a way
Um because in a way we're
Um because in a way we're sort
Um because in a way we're sort of
evolving
evolving with
Um because in a way we're sort of
evolving with the
evolving with the field.
Um because in a way we're sort of
evolving with the field. You
evolving with the field. You know
Um because in a way we're sort of
evolving with the field. You know what
I'm
I'm saying?
>> Uh
>> Uh question
I'm saying?
>> Uh question always
>> Uh question always comes
I'm saying?
>> Uh question always comes up
>> Uh question always comes up about
soulmates
soulmates in
soulmates in relationships,
soulmates in relationships, marriages,
whatever.
whatever. Question.
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't know
>> I don't know really
>> I don't know really what
>> I don't know really what that
>> I don't know really what that means.
>> I don't know really what that means. A
soulmate.
soulmate. I
>> I don't know really what that means. A
soulmate. I don't know
soulmate. I don't know if
>> I don't know really what that means. A
soulmate. I don't know if it's
soulmate. I don't know if it's a
legitimate
legitimate question
legitimate question or
legitimate question or a
legitimate question or a romantic
fantasy.
>> What
>> What that
>> What that I
>> What that I don't
>> What that I don't know
>> What that I don't know what
>> What that I don't know what soul
>> What that I don't know what soul merely
means.
means. Um
>> What that I don't know what soul merely
means. Um well
means. Um well there
>> What that I don't know what soul merely
means. Um well there can
means. Um well there can be
>> What that I don't know what soul merely
means. Um well there can be a
means. Um well there can be a commitment
between
between two
between two people
between two people that
between two people that transcends
between two people that transcends phys
reincarnations
reincarnations resist
between two people that transcends phys
reincarnations resist can
reincarnations resist can extend
between two people that transcends phys
reincarnations resist can extend over
many
many lifetimes.
many lifetimes. Yeah,
many lifetimes. Yeah, there
many lifetimes. Yeah, there can
many lifetimes. Yeah, there can be
many lifetimes. Yeah, there can be a
commitment
commitment between
many lifetimes. Yeah, there can be a
commitment between people
commitment between people that
many lifetimes. Yeah, there can be a
commitment between people that extends
over
over many
over many lifetimes
and
and often
over many lifetimes
and often when
and often when you
over many lifetimes
and often when you re
and often when you re run
over many lifetimes
and often when you re run into
and often when you re run into them
again
again in
again in this
again in this lifetime,
again in this lifetime, you
again in this lifetime, you feel
again in this lifetime, you feel a
again in this lifetime, you feel a state
of
of great
again in this lifetime, you feel a state
of great joy.
of great joy. You
again in this lifetime, you feel a state
of great joy. You know,
of great joy. You know, you
again in this lifetime, you feel a state
of great joy. You know, you feel
of great joy. You know, you feel a
again in this lifetime, you feel a state
of great joy. You know, you feel a flash
like
like recognition.
Uh
Uh not
like recognition.
Uh not conscious,
Uh not conscious, it
like recognition.
Uh not conscious, it just
Uh not conscious, it just comes
like recognition.
Uh not conscious, it just comes up
Uh not conscious, it just comes up of
its
its own
its own like
its own like a
its own like a feeling
its own like a feeling of
its own like a feeling of joy.
its own like a feeling of joy. Just
its own like a feeling of joy. Just a
spontaneous
spontaneous feeling
its own like a feeling of joy. Just a
spontaneous feeling of
spontaneous feeling of joy
its own like a feeling of joy. Just a
spontaneous feeling of joy of
spontaneous feeling of joy of mutual
recognition.
recognition. Yeah.
recognition. Yeah. Yeah.
recognition. Yeah. Yeah. Right.
recognition. Yeah. Yeah. Right. Right.
I'll
I'll ask
recognition. Yeah. Yeah. Right. Right.
I'll ask again.
>> Well,
>> Well, I
>> Well, I know
>> Well, I know I
>> Well, I know I am
>> Well, I know I am getting
>> Well, I know I am getting tired.
>> Well, I know I am getting tired. Uh
>> Well, I know I am getting tired. Uh over
>> I
>> I remember
we
we we
we we can
we we can ask
we we can ask just
we we can ask just this
we we can ask just this one
we we can ask just this one question
about
about people
we we can ask just this one question
about people over
about people over 700.
No,
we'll
we'll leave
No,
we'll leave that
we'll leave that for
No,
we'll leave that for another
we'll leave that for another time.
No,
we'll leave that for another time. It's
in
in the
in the book
in the book anyway.
in the book anyway. It's
in the book anyway. It's in
in the book anyway. It's in the
in the book anyway. It's in the book.
But
But we
in the book anyway. It's in the book.
But we did
But we did go
in the book anyway. It's in the book.
But we did go back
But we did go back over
in the book anyway. It's in the book.
But we did go back over the
But we did go back over the figures
because
because they
because they had
because they had changed
because they had changed because
because they had changed because Oh,
yes.
yes. There
because they had changed because Oh,
yes. There was
yes. There was one
because they had changed because Oh,
yes. There was one question
yes. There was one question I
because they had changed because Oh,
yes. There was one question I wanted
yes. There was one question I wanted to
answer
answer and
answer and then
answer and then we're
answer and then we're going to
answer and then we're going to have
answer and then we're going to have to
quit.
quit. The
answer and then we're going to have to
quit. The consciousness
quit. The consciousness level
answer and then we're going to have to
quit. The consciousness level of
quit. The consciousness level of mankind
uh
uh permission
uh permission to
uh permission to ask
uh permission to ask for
uh permission to ask for the
uh permission to ask for the zoance
resist
resist is
uh permission to ask for the zoance
resist is now
resist is now over
uh permission to ask for the zoance
resist is now over 206
resist is now over 206 207
uh permission to ask for the zoance
resist is now over 206 207 208
resist is now over 206 207 208 209
uh permission to ask for the zoance
resist is now over 206 207 208 209 208
since
since uh
since uh I
since uh I did
since uh I did it
since uh I did it was
205 right
205 right 20
since uh I did it was
205 right 20 it
205 right 20 it went
since uh I did it was
205 right 20 it went up
205 right 20 it went up to
since uh I did it was
205 right 20 it went up to 207
anyway
anyway in
anyway in the
anyway in the last
anyway in the last year
anyway in the last year or
anyway in the last year or two
anyway in the last year or two it
anyway in the last year or two it has
gone
gone up
anyway in the last year or two it has
gone up from
gone up from 207
anyway in the last year or two it has
gone up from 207 to
gone up from 207 to 208
somebody
somebody mentioned
somebody mentioned they
somebody mentioned they fell
somebody mentioned they fell a
somebody mentioned they fell a shift
somebody mentioned they fell a shift of
consciousness
consciousness and
somebody mentioned they fell a shift of
consciousness and we
consciousness and we had
somebody mentioned they fell a shift of
consciousness and we had already
detected
detected that
um
um you
detected that
um you know
um you know the
detected that
um you know the spiritual
um you know the spiritual work
detected that
um you know the spiritual work you
um you know the spiritual work you do
detected that
um you know the spiritual work you do on
the
the nature
the nature of
the nature of consciousness
the nature of consciousness itself
the nature of consciousness itself don't
forget
forget you're
the nature of consciousness itself don't
forget you're affecting
forget you're affecting context
not
not content.
not content. See
not content. See spiritual
not content. See spiritual work
not content. See spiritual work designed
to
to affect
not content. See spiritual work designed
to affect content
to affect content is
not content. See spiritual work designed
to affect content is limited
to affect content is limited in
not content. See spiritual work designed
to affect content is limited in its
power.
spiritual
spiritual work
power.
spiritual work designed
spiritual work designed to
power.
spiritual work designed to advance
spiritual work designed to advance the
field
field of
field of consciousness
field of consciousness itself
lifts
lifts all
field of consciousness itself
lifts all the
lifts all the fish
field of consciousness itself
lifts all the fish in
lifts all the fish in the
field of consciousness itself
lifts all the fish in the bowl.
lifts all the fish in the bowl. You
understand
understand what
understand what I'm
understand what I'm saying?
understand what I'm saying? You're
understand what I'm saying? You're just
trying
trying to
understand what I'm saying? You're just
trying to affect
trying to affect specific
understand what I'm saying? You're just
trying to affect specific fish.
trying to affect specific fish. So,
understand what I'm saying? You're just
trying to affect specific fish. So, a
lot
lot of
lot of spiritual
lot of spiritual work,
lot of spiritual work, prayer
lot of spiritual work, prayer groups
lot of spiritual work, prayer groups and
all
all are
lot of spiritual work, prayer groups and
all are very
all are very well
lot of spiritual work, prayer groups and
all are very well intentioned,
all are very well intentioned, but
lot of spiritual work, prayer groups and
all are very well intentioned, but they
really
really don't
really don't impinge
really don't impinge what's
really don't impinge what's happening
really don't impinge what's happening in
the
the world
really don't impinge what's happening in
the world because
the world because they're
really don't impinge what's happening in
the world because they're too
the world because they're too localized.
You
You know,
You know, we're
You know, we're going
You know, we're going to
You know, we're going to pray
You know, we're going to pray for
You know, we're going to pray for peace
in
in Persia
You know, we're going to pray for peace
in Persia or
in Persia or something.
You know, we're going to pray for peace
in Persia or something. you
in Persia or something. you know
You know, we're going to pray for peace
in Persia or something. you know that's
very
very localized
very localized very
very localized very limited
to
to work
very localized very limited
to work towards
to work towards the
very localized very limited
to work towards the advancement
to work towards the advancement of
consciousness
consciousness itself
consciousness itself you
consciousness itself you know
consciousness itself you know lifts
consciousness itself you know lifts the
whole
whole game
consciousness itself you know lifts the
whole game and
whole game and then
consciousness itself you know lifts the
whole game and then whatever
whole game and then whatever content
consciousness itself you know lifts the
whole game and then whatever content is
going
going on
going on is
going on is lifted
going on is lifted by
going on is lifted by the
going on is lifted by the fact
going on is lifted by the fact that
going on is lifted by the fact that the
whole
whole game
going on is lifted by the fact that the
whole game is
whole game is being
going on is lifted by the fact that the
whole game is being lifted
whole game is being lifted I
going on is lifted by the fact that the
whole game is being lifted I think
whole game is being lifted I think if
you
you just
you just sit
you just sit around
you just sit around praying
you just sit around praying all
you just sit around praying all day
you just sit around praying all day for
peace
peace and
you just sit around praying all day for
peace and Palestine
peace and Palestine or
you just sit around praying all day for
peace and Palestine or something
peace and Palestine or something you're
probably
probably wasting
probably wasting your
probably wasting your time
first
first of
probably wasting your time
first of all
first of all they
probably wasting your time
first of all they don't
first of all they don't want
probably wasting your time
first of all they don't want it
that's
that's a
that's a fact
that's a fact is
that's a fact is Right
now
now the
that's a fact is Right
now the payoff
now the payoff from
that's a fact is Right
now the payoff from hatred
now the payoff from hatred and
that's a fact is Right
now the payoff from hatred and being
victim
victim and
victim and martyr
victim and martyr and
victim and martyr and u
victim and martyr and u getting
victim and martyr and u getting even
victim and martyr and u getting even and
revenge
revenge and
victim and martyr and u getting even and
revenge and all
revenge and all it's
victim and martyr and u getting even and
revenge and all it's a
revenge and all it's a it's
victim and martyr and u getting even and
revenge and all it's a it's a
revenge and all it's a it's a fierce
game
game and
game and very
game and very hard
game and very hard to
game and very hard to get
game and very hard to get pull
game and very hard to get pull out
game and very hard to get pull out of
it.
it. It's
game and very hard to get pull out of
it. It's very
it. It's very hard
game and very hard to get pull out of
it. It's very hard to
it. It's very hard to pull
game and very hard to get pull out of
it. It's very hard to pull out
it. It's very hard to pull out of
game and very hard to get pull out of
it. It's very hard to pull out of it
it. It's very hard to pull out of it and
the
the viciousness
the viciousness is
the viciousness is that
the viciousness is that the
the viciousness is that the one
the viciousness is that the one side
sets
sets up
the viciousness is that the one side
sets up the
sets up the other
the viciousness is that the one side
sets up the other side
sets up the other side sets
the viciousness is that the one side
sets up the other side sets them
sets up the other side sets them up
the viciousness is that the one side
sets up the other side sets them up in
such
such a
such a way
such a way that
such a way that they
such a way that they can't
such a way that they can't pull
such a way that they can't pull out
such a way that they can't pull out of
it
after
after you
after you victimized
after you victimized enough
after you victimized enough children
from
from this
after you victimized enough children
from this side.
from this side. How
after you victimized enough children
from this side. How are
from this side. How are they
after you victimized enough children
from this side. How are they going
from this side. How are they going to
get
get out
get out not
get out not avenging
a
a whole
get out not avenging
a whole school
a whole school of
get out not avenging
a whole school of children
a whole school of children purposely
destroyed?
destroyed? So
destroyed? So what
destroyed? So what you
destroyed? So what you do
destroyed? So what you do is
destroyed? So what you do is you
destroyed? So what you do is you trap
the
the other
destroyed? So what you do is you trap
the other side
the other side into
destroyed? So what you do is you trap
the other side into have
the other side into have to
destroyed? So what you do is you trap
the other side into have to come
the other side into have to come back
destroyed? So what you do is you trap
the other side into have to come back at
me.
me. You
me. You know
me. You know what
me. You know what I'm
me. You know what I'm saying?
me. You know what I'm saying? It's
really
really vicious
me. You know what I'm saying? It's
really vicious because
really vicious because uh
me. You know what I'm saying? It's
really vicious because uh it's
really vicious because uh it's poisoning
the
the well
the well and
the well and uh
the well and uh there
the well and uh there it's
the well and uh there it's a
the well and uh there it's a purposeful
intention
intention to
the well and uh there it's a purposeful
intention to prevent
intention to prevent anything
the well and uh there it's a purposeful
intention to prevent anything like
intention to prevent anything like peace
from
from arising
from arising and
from arising and being
from arising and being taken
from arising and being taken seriously.
You
You create
from arising and being taken seriously.
You create enough
You create enough horror
and
and hatred
and hatred on
and hatred on the
and hatred on the other.
and hatred on the other. You
and hatred on the other. You make
and hatred on the other. You make sure
the
the other
and hatred on the other. You make sure
the other side
the other side hates
and hatred on the other. You make sure
the other side hates you
the other side hates you enough.
and hatred on the other. You make sure
the other side hates you enough. That's
really
really a
really a lower
really a lower trick
really a lower trick to
really a lower trick to make
really a lower trick to make sure
really a lower trick to make sure that
sufficient
sufficient hatred
really a lower trick to make sure that
sufficient hatred has
sufficient hatred has been
really a lower trick to make sure that
sufficient hatred has been engendered
sufficient hatred has been engendered to
ensure
ensure the
ensure the ongoingness
ensure the ongoingness of
ensure the ongoingness of the
ensure the ongoingness of the conflict.
>> Well,
>> Well, are
ensure the ongoingness of the conflict.
>> Well, are there
>> Well, are there any
ensure the ongoingness of the conflict.
>> Well, are there any examples
>> Well, are there any examples in
ensure the ongoingness of the conflict.
>> Well, are there any examples in history
that
that where
that where that
that where that condition
that where that condition has
that where that condition has existed
and
and some
that where that condition has existed
and some sort
and some sort of
that where that condition has existed
and some sort of an
and some sort of an intervention
that where that condition has existed
and some sort of an intervention has
changed
changed it?
changed it? And
changed it? And what
changed it? And what might
>> I
>> I don't
changed it? And what might
>> I don't know.
>> I don't know. All
changed it? And what might
>> I don't know. All All
>> I don't know. All All I
changed it? And what might
>> I don't know. All All I know
>> I don't know. All All I know is
changed it? And what might
>> I don't know. All All I know is we
>> I don't know. All All I know is we can
track
track the
track the level
track the level of
track the level of consciousness
track the level of consciousness of
mankind
mankind as
track the level of consciousness of
mankind as a
mankind as a whole
track the level of consciousness of
mankind as a whole uh
mankind as a whole uh throughout
track the level of consciousness of
mankind as a whole uh throughout time.
And
And if
And if we
And if we had
And if we had enough
And if we had enough study
And if we had enough study groups,
And if we had enough study groups, we
could
could do
And if we had enough study groups, we
could do it
could do it continent
And if we had enough study groups, we
could do it continent by
could do it continent by continent,
country
country by
country by country
country by country uh
country by country uh culture
country by country uh culture by
country by country uh culture by culture
and
and see
country by country uh culture by culture
and see where
and see where it
country by country uh culture by culture
and see where it made
and see where it made major
country by country uh culture by culture
and see where it made major changes
and see where it made major changes and
then
then go
then go back
then go back in
then go back in history
then go back in history and
then go back in history and ask
then go back in history and ask which
then go back in history and ask which of
these
these things
then go back in history and ask which of
these things had
these things had an
then go back in history and ask which of
these things had an effect.
these things had an effect. It
then go back in history and ask which of
these things had an effect. It isn't
these things had an effect. It isn't a
cause
cause and
cause and and
cause and and necessarily
cause and and necessarily cause
cause and and necessarily cause and
effect.
effect. It's
cause and and necessarily cause and
effect. It's it's
effect. It's it's a
cause and and necessarily cause and
effect. It's it's a the
effect. It's it's a the matter
cause and and necessarily cause and
effect. It's it's a the matter that
certain
certain conditions
certain conditions favor
certain conditions favor certain
>> moves.
>> moves. See,
certain conditions favor certain
>> moves. See, so
>> moves. See, so instead
certain conditions favor certain
>> moves. See, so instead of
>> moves. See, so instead of causality,
what
what you
what you see
what you see is
what you see is that
what you see is that certain
what you see is that certain conditions
are
are favorable
what you see is that certain conditions
are favorable to
are favorable to certain
what you see is that certain conditions
are favorable to certain potentialities.
The
The quantum
The quantum potentiality
The quantum potentiality is
The quantum potentiality is favored.
The quantum potentiality is favored. So
rain
rain and
The quantum potentiality is favored. So
rain and sunshine
rain and sunshine doesn't
The quantum potentiality is favored. So
rain and sunshine doesn't cause
rain and sunshine doesn't cause the
plant
plant to
plant to grow,
plant to grow, but
plant to grow, but it
plant to grow, but it increases
plant to grow, but it increases the
potentiality
potentiality and
plant to grow, but it increases the
potentiality and the
potentiality and the likelihood
plant to grow, but it increases the
potentiality and the likelihood that
potentiality and the likelihood that the
germination
germination will
germination will be
germination will be successful
germination will be successful under
these
these conditions.
germination will be successful under
these conditions. But
these conditions. But you
germination will be successful under
these conditions. But you see,
these conditions. But you see, a
germination will be successful under
these conditions. But you see, a plant
is
is not
caused
caused to
is not
caused to grow
caused to grow by
is not
caused to grow by sunlight.
caused to grow by sunlight. It's
is not
caused to grow by sunlight. It's not
caused
caused to
caused to grow
caused to grow by
caused to grow by light
caused to grow by light or
caused to grow by light or caused
caused to grow by light or caused to
grow
grow by
caused to grow by light or caused to
grow by moisture.
grow by moisture. Those
caused to grow by light or caused to
grow by moisture. Those are
grow by moisture. Those are only
caused to grow by light or caused to
grow by moisture. Those are only the
condition
condition conditions
condition conditions which
condition conditions which increase
condition conditions which increase the
statistical
statistical probability
condition conditions which increase the
statistical probability of
statistical probability of a
condition conditions which increase the
statistical probability of a certain
response.
response. So
response. So you
response. So you don't
response. So you don't see
response. So you don't see cause
response. So you don't see cause and
effect.
effect. What
response. So you don't see cause and
effect. What you
effect. What you see
response. So you don't see cause and
effect. What you see is
effect. What you see is potentiation
response. So you don't see cause and
effect. What you see is potentiation of
likelihoods.
Rain
Rain and
likelihoods.
Rain and sunshine
Rain and sunshine increases
likelihoods.
Rain and sunshine increases the
likelihood
likelihood that
likelihood that the
likelihood that the potentiality
likelihood that the potentiality of
growing
growing into
likelihood that the potentiality of
growing into a
growing into a flower
likelihood that the potentiality of
growing into a flower will
growing into a flower will eventuate
into
into an
into an actuality.
So
So instead
into an actuality.
So instead of
So instead of cause
into an actuality.
So instead of cause and
So instead of cause and effect,
into an actuality.
So instead of cause and effect, what
So instead of cause and effect, what you
see
see are
see are conditions
see are conditions and
see are conditions and likelihoods
see are conditions and likelihoods and
uh
uh statistical
see are conditions and likelihoods and
uh statistical probabilities.
uh statistical probabilities. You
see are conditions and likelihoods and
uh statistical probabilities. You don't
see
see cause
see cause and
see cause and effect.
Cause
Cause and
see cause and effect.
Cause and effect
Cause and effect is
see cause and effect.
Cause and effect is an
Cause and effect is an imagination
see cause and effect.
Cause and effect is an imagination that
you
you try
you try to
you try to project
you try to project on
you try to project on because
you try to project on because you
you try to project on because you don't
really
really see
you try to project on because you don't
really see what's
really see what's going
you try to project on because you don't
really see what's going on.
>> Mhm.
>> Um
>> Um you
>> Mhm.
>> Um you know
>> Um you know earlier
>> Mhm.
>> Um you know earlier you
>> Um you know earlier you talking
>> Mhm.
>> Um you know earlier you talking about
idea
idea UFO
idea UFO is
idea UFO is not
idea UFO is not real.
idea UFO is not real. What
idea UFO is not real. What is
idea UFO is not real. What is your
idea UFO is not real. What is your sense
about
about other
idea UFO is not real. What is your sense
about other intelligent
about other intelligent beings
idea UFO is not real. What is your sense
about other intelligent beings that's
not
not on
not on planet
not on planet Earth?
not on planet Earth? Do
not on planet Earth? Do they
not on planet Earth? Do they exist?
not on planet Earth? Do they exist? And
if
if they
not on planet Earth? Do they exist? And
if they do,
if they do, are
not on planet Earth? Do they exist? And
if they do, are they
if they do, are they talking
not on planet Earth? Do they exist? And
if they do, are they talking at
if they do, are they talking at all?
>> You
>> You wish,
>> You wish, huh?
>> I
>> I don't
>> You wish, huh?
>> I don't know
>> I don't know if
>> You wish, huh?
>> I don't know if it's
>> I don't know if it's an
>> You wish, huh?
>> I don't know if it's an answerable
question.
>> In
>> In this
question.
>> In this whole
>> In this whole universe,
question.
>> In this whole universe, that's
>> In this whole universe, that's hard
question.
>> In this whole universe, that's hard for
my
>> Are
>> Are we
my
>> Are we the
>> Are we the only
my
>> Are we the only humans
>> Are we the only humans in
my
>> Are we the only humans in the
>> Are we the only humans in the universe?
>> Intelligent
>> Intelligent beings.
You
You realize
>> Intelligent beings.
You realize there's
You realize there's an
>> Intelligent beings.
You realize there's an infinite
You realize there's an infinite number
of
of universes
of universes which
of universes which are
of universes which are being
of universes which are being created
of universes which are being created at
an
an infinite
of universes which are being created at
an infinite rate
an infinite rate of
of universes which are being created at
an infinite rate of speed
an infinite rate of speed continuously
throughout
throughout all
throughout all eternity.
throughout all eternity. You
throughout all eternity. You realize
that
>> you
>> you still
>> you still want
>> you still want to
>> you still want to ask
>> you still want to ask the
>> you still want to ask the question
reality,
>> huh?
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Because
>> huh?
>> Okay. Because you
>> Okay. Because you talk
>> huh?
>> Okay. Because you talk about
>> Okay. Because you talk about the
>> huh?
>> Okay. Because you talk about the lower
astrals.
astrals. Yeah.
astrals. Yeah. All
astrals. Yeah. All infinite
astrals. Yeah. All infinite number
astrals. Yeah. All infinite number of
astrals.
astrals. Some
astrals. Yeah. All infinite number of
astrals. Some of
astrals. Some of them
astrals. Yeah. All infinite number of
astrals. Some of them might
astrals. Some of them might be
astrals. Yeah. All infinite number of
astrals. Some of them might be higher.
Some
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Well,
Some
>> Yeah. Well, we
>> Yeah. Well, we don't
Some
>> Yeah. Well, we don't care
>> Yeah. Well, we don't care about
Some
>> Yeah. Well, we don't care about astrals.
We
We just
We just all
We just all we
We just all we want
We just all we want to
We just all we want to know
We just all we want to know is
We just all we want to know is not
We just all we want to know is not to
We just all we want to know is not to go
there.
There's
There's an
There's an infinite
There's an infinite number
There's an infinite number of
There's an infinite number of universes
um
um expanding
There's an infinite number of universes
um expanding and
um expanding and being
There's an infinite number of universes
um expanding and being created
um expanding and being created at
There's an infinite number of universes
um expanding and being created at an
infinite
infinite rate
infinite rate faster
infinite rate faster than
infinite rate faster than the
infinite rate faster than the speed
infinite rate faster than the speed of
light.
light. Everybody
infinite rate faster than the speed of
light. Everybody thinks
light. Everybody thinks within
infinite rate faster than the speed of
light. Everybody thinks within the
light. Everybody thinks within the speed
of
of light.
of light. No,
there's
there's an
of light. No,
there's an infinite
there's an infinite number
of light. No,
there's an infinite number of
there's an infinite number of us
universes
universes which
universes which are
universes which are created
universes which are created continuously
at
at a
universes which are created continuously
at a rate
at a rate faster
universes which are created continuously
at a rate faster than
at a rate faster than the
universes which are created continuously
at a rate faster than the speed
at a rate faster than the speed of
universes which are created continuously
at a rate faster than the speed of light
resistance.
See
See the
resistance.
See the speed
See the speed of
resistance.
See the speed of light
See the speed of light is
resistance.
See the speed of light is just
See the speed of light is just a
resistance.
See the speed of light is just a human
invention.
Faster
Faster than
invention.
Faster than the
Faster than the speed
invention.
Faster than the speed of
Faster than the speed of light.
invention.
Faster than the speed of light. There's
an
an infinite
an infinite number
an infinite number of
an infinite number of universes.
That
That which
an infinite number of universes.
That which is
That which is God
an infinite number of universes.
That which is God is
That which is God is present
an infinite number of universes.
That which is God is present in
That which is God is present in all
an infinite number of universes.
That which is God is present in all that
exists.
The
The divinity
exists.
The divinity that
The divinity that all
exists.
The divinity that all exists
The divinity that all exists in
exists.
The divinity that all exists in all
The divinity that all exists in all that
exists
exists is
exists is itself
exists is itself has
exists is itself has the
exists is itself has the essence
exists is itself has the essence of
creativity.
That
That which
That which God
That which God creates
That which God creates has
That which God creates has within
That which God creates has within itself
the
the quality
That which God creates has within itself
the quality of
the quality of divinity
That which God creates has within itself
the quality of divinity which
the quality of divinity which in
That which God creates has within itself
the quality of divinity which in and
the quality of divinity which in and of
itself
itself then
itself then manifests
itself then manifests as
itself then manifests as the
itself then manifests as the evolution
of
of an
itself then manifests as the evolution
of an ever
of an ever unending
universe
universe of
universe of universes.
universe of universes. Infinite
galaxies,
galaxies, infinite
universe of universes. Infinite
galaxies, infinite universes
are
are expanding
are expanding and
are expanding and coming
are expanding and coming out
are expanding and coming out of
are expanding and coming out of creation
continuously.
through
through an
through an infinite
through an infinite number
through an infinite number of
dimensions.
Even
Even from
Even from advanced
Even from advanced theoretical
Even from advanced theoretical physics,
advanced
advanced mathematics,
Even from advanced theoretical physics,
advanced mathematics, you
advanced mathematics, you realize
Even from advanced theoretical physics,
advanced mathematics, you realize with
advanced mathematics, you realize with a
one
one square
one square inch
one
one square inch cube,
one square inch cube, there
one
one square inch cube, there are
one square inch cube, there are an
infinite
infinite number
infinite number of
infinite number of planes,
infinite
infinite number
infinite number of planes,
infinite number of
infinite number of dimensions
infinite number of planes,
infinite number of dimensions within
infinite number of dimensions within one
cubic
cubic inch.
Therefore,
Therefore, in
cubic inch.
Therefore, in an
Therefore, in an infinite
cubic inch.
Therefore, in an infinite series
Therefore, in an infinite series of
infinite
infinite potentialities,
the
the likelihood
infinite potentialities,
the likelihood that
the likelihood that we're
infinite potentialities,
the likelihood that we're the
the likelihood that we're the only
infinite potentialities,
the likelihood that we're the only ones
who
who can
who can think
who can think and
who can think and feel,
who can think and feel, go
who can think and feel, go to
who can think and feel, go to the
bathroom,
bathroom, go
who can think and feel, go to the
bathroom, go to
bathroom, go to bashes
who can think and feel, go to the
bathroom, go to bashes is
bathroom, go to bashes is unlikely.
who can think and feel, go to the
bathroom, go to bashes is unlikely. You
know what
know what I
know what I mean?
>> But
>> But we
know what I mean?
>> But we will
>> But we will ask
know what I mean?
>> But we will ask the
>> But we will ask the question.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. It's
>> Okay. It's um
>> Okay. It's um the
>> Okay. It's um the answer
>> Okay. It's um the answer is
>> Okay. It's um the answer is there's
>> Okay. It's um the answer is there's an
infinite
infinite number
>> Okay. It's um the answer is there's an
infinite number of
infinite number of dimensions
>> Okay. It's um the answer is there's an
infinite number of dimensions and
infinite number of dimensions and a
number
number infinite
number infinite number
number infinite number of
number infinite number of potentialities
for
for consciousness
number infinite number of potentialities
for consciousness such
for consciousness such as
number infinite number of potentialities
for consciousness such as our
for consciousness such as our own
integral.
integral. Yeah,
integral. Yeah, the
integral. Yeah, the answer
integral. Yeah, the answer is
integral. Yeah, the answer is infinite.
Yes,
Yes, everybody
integral. Yeah, the answer is infinite.
Yes, everybody likes
Yes, everybody likes that
integral. Yeah, the answer is infinite.
Yes, everybody likes that one.
>> After
>> After you
>> After you hear
>> After you hear it
>> After you hear it enough
>> After you hear it enough times,
>> After you hear it enough times, it
>> After you hear it enough times, it goes
on
on its
>> After you hear it enough times, it goes
on its own
on its own within
>> After you hear it enough times, it goes
on its own within whenever
on its own within whenever you
>> After you hear it enough times, it goes
on its own within whenever you wish
on its own within whenever you wish it
to
to be
to be there.
>> And
>> And it's
to be there.
>> And it's often
>> And it's often very
to be there.
>> And it's often very useful
>> And it's often very useful because
to be there.
>> And it's often very useful because it
takes
takes you
takes you back
takes you back into
an
an energy
takes you back into
an energy at
an energy at 740,
takes you back into
an energy at 740, the
an energy at 740, the feeling
takes you back into
an energy at 740, the feeling that
an energy at 740, the feeling that of
like
like the
like the Greek
like the Greek cathedral,
the
the exquisite
like the Greek cathedral,
the exquisite beauty
the exquisite beauty of
like the Greek cathedral,
the exquisite beauty of nature,
the
the divinity
the divinity of
the divinity of all
the divinity of all creatures
the divinity of all creatures as
created.
It's
It's more
It's more like
It's more like it
It's more like it takes
It's more like it takes you
It's more like it takes you into
It's more like it takes you into the
memory
memory of
It's more like it takes you into the
memory of that
memory of that reality
It's more like it takes you into the
memory of that reality and
memory of that reality and that
It's more like it takes you into the
memory of that reality and that sort
memory of that reality and that sort of
pulls
pulls you
pulls you out
pulls you out of
pulls you out of the
pulls you out of the crisis
pulls you out of the crisis that
pulls you out of the crisis that you're
currently
currently upset
pulls you out of the crisis that you're
currently upset about.
>> One
>> One just
>> One just experiences
the
the availability
>> One just experiences
the availability and
the availability and the
>> One just experiences
the availability and the reality
the availability and the reality of
>> One just experiences
the availability and the reality of that
field
field of
field of energy.
field of energy. But
field of energy. But it
field of energy. But it isn't
field of energy. But it isn't the
content
content of
field of energy. But it isn't the
content of the
content of the mantra.
field of energy. But it isn't the
content of the mantra. Whatever
content of the mantra. Whatever it's
saying,
>> it's
>> it's the
saying,
>> it's the energy
>> it's the energy behind
saying,
>> it's the energy behind it.
>> The
>> The essence
>> The essence of
>> The essence of devotion
>> The essence of devotion itself,
the
>> sensitivity
>> sensitivity to
>> sensitivity to exquisite
>> sensitivity to exquisite beauty.
The
The divinity
>> sensitivity to exquisite beauty.
The divinity of
The divinity of all
>> sensitivity to exquisite beauty.
The divinity of all that
The divinity of all that exists.
>> Your
>> Your willingness
>> Your willingness to
>> Your willingness to surrender
>> Your willingness to surrender to
>> Your willingness to surrender to the
love
love of
>> Your willingness to surrender to the
love of God.
In
In the
In the end
In the end it'll
In the end it'll be
>> and
>> and unto
In the end it'll be
>> and unto thee,
>> and unto thee, oh
In the end it'll be
>> and unto thee, oh Lord.
>> I
>> I surrender
>> I surrender my
>> I surrender my life
that
that which
>> I surrender my life
that which I
that which I am
>> completely
>> completely surrendered
>> completely surrendered to
>> completely surrendered to the
>> completely surrendered to the Lord.
Amen.
>> And
>> And that's
>> And that's the
>> And that's the last
>> And that's the last thing
>> And that's the last thing to
>> And that's the last thing to be
>> And that's the last thing to be answered
before
before you
>> And that's the last thing to be answered
before you walk
before you walk through
>> And that's the last thing to be answered
before you walk through the
before you walk through the final
>> And that's the last thing to be answered
before you walk through the final door.
>> The
>> The wind
>> The wind is
>> The wind is to
>> The wind is to surrender
>> The wind is to surrender your
>> The wind is to surrender your life
itself.
>> Not
>> Not not
>> Not not what
>> Not not what you
>> Not not what you think
>> Not not what you think is
>> Not not what you think is your
>> Not not what you think is your life
>> Not not what you think is your life is
physicality,
physicality, but
>> Not not what you think is your life is
physicality, but the
physicality, but the actual
>> Not not what you think is your life is
physicality, but the actual core
physicality, but the actual core of
>> Not not what you think is your life is
physicality, but the actual core of life
itself.
>> It's
>> It's like
itself.
>> It's like we
>> It's like we intuit
itself.
>> It's like we intuit it
>> It's like we intuit it where
itself.
>> It's like we intuit it where that
>> It's like we intuit it where that space
is.
There's
There's no
is.
There's no book
There's no book that
is.
There's no book that can
There's no book that can tell
is.
There's no book that can tell us
There's no book that can tell us how
is.
There's no book that can tell us how to
get
get there.
>> All
>> All the
get there.
>> All the discussions
>> All the discussions we
get there.
>> All the discussions we have
>> All the discussions we have are
get there.
>> All the discussions we have are to
>> All the discussions we have are to clear
away
away the
away the obstructions.
>> And
>> And then
away the obstructions.
>> And then the
>> And then the light
away the obstructions.
>> And then the light begins
>> And then the light begins to
away the obstructions.
>> And then the light begins to like
>> And then the light begins to like rise
in
in the
in the background
in the background and
in the background and we
in the background and we get
in the background and we get the
in the background and we get the space
of
of where
in the background and we get the space
of where all
of where all that
in the background and we get the space
of where all that takes
of where all that takes place
>> and
>> and our
>> and our willingness
>> and our willingness to
>> and our willingness to go
>> and our willingness to go there
>> and our willingness to go there is
>> and our willingness to go there is our
commitment
commitment to
>> and our willingness to go there is our
commitment to each
commitment to each other
>> as
>> as a
>> as a devotional
>> as a devotional group.
our
our willingness
>> as a devotional group.
our willingness to
our willingness to go
>> as a devotional group.
our willingness to go there
our willingness to go there for
ourselves
ourselves and
ourselves and for
ourselves and for each
ourselves and for each other
>> out
>> out of
ourselves and for each other
>> out of our
>> out of our love
ourselves and for each other
>> out of our love for
>> out of our love for each
ourselves and for each other
>> out of our love for each other
>> which
>> which is
>> which is not
>> which is not different
>> which is not different in
>> which is not different in our
>> which is not different in our love
>> which is not different in our love for
God.
So
>> thank
>> thank you
So
>> thank you for
>> thank you for being
So
>> thank you for being here
>> thank you for being here today
So
>> thank you for being here today sharing
this.
God
God bless
this.
God bless you
God bless you all.
She