We're
We're doing
We're doing all
We're doing all right.
We're doing all right. So,
We're doing all right. So, I
We're doing all right. So, I was
We're doing all right. So, I was just
got
got off
We're doing all right. So, I was just
got off on
got off on that
We're doing all right. So, I was just
got off on that tangent
got off on that tangent because
We're doing all right. So, I was just
got off on that tangent because I
got off on that tangent because I didn't
want
want people
want people to
want people to think
want people to think that
want people to think that this
want people to think that this is
want people to think that this is better
than
than that.
want people to think that this is better
than that. Uh,
than that. Uh, somebody
want people to think that this is better
than that. Uh, somebody at
than that. Uh, somebody at 700
want people to think that this is better
than that. Uh, somebody at 700 is
than that. Uh, somebody at 700 is not
suitable
suitable as
suitable as a
suitable as a carpenter,
suitable as a carpenter, is
suitable as a carpenter, is not
suitable as a carpenter, is not suitable
to
to run
suitable as a carpenter, is not suitable
to run a
to run a church,
suitable as a carpenter, is not suitable
to run a church, is
to run a church, is not
suitable as a carpenter, is not suitable
to run a church, is not suitable
to run a church, is not suitable as
suitable as a carpenter, is not suitable
to run a church, is not suitable as a
president.
president. You
president. You don't
president. You don't want
president. You don't want anybody
president. You don't want anybody at
700.
700. Most
president. You don't want anybody at
700. Most of
700. Most of them
president. You don't want anybody at
700. Most of them can't
700. Most of them can't function
president. You don't want anybody at
700. Most of them can't function at
700. Most of them can't function at all.
They
They just
They just sit
They just sit in
They just sit in their
They just sit in their ash
They just sit in their ash ram
They just sit in their ash ram and
They just sit in their ash ram and if
they
they still
They just sit in their ash ram and if
they still survive,
they still survive, people
They just sit in their ash ram and if
they still survive, people come
they still survive, people come and
They just sit in their ash ram and if
they still survive, people come and say
hello
hello to
hello to them
hello to them and
hello to them and they
hello to them and they smile
hello to them and they smile happily
hello to them and they smile happily at
them
them and
hello to them and they smile happily at
them and that's
them and that's it.
H
H anyway,
you
you don't
H anyway,
you don't want
you don't want people
H anyway,
you don't want people down
you don't want people down in
H anyway,
you don't want people down in the
bottom,
bottom, you
bottom, you know.
bottom, you know. Uh
bottom, you know. Uh there's
bottom, you know. Uh there's one
restaurant
restaurant I
bottom, you know. Uh there's one
restaurant I used
restaurant I used to
bottom, you know. Uh there's one
restaurant I used to eat
restaurant I used to eat breakfast
bottom, you know. Uh there's one
restaurant I used to eat breakfast and
restaurant I used to eat breakfast and I
stopped
stopped going
stopped going there
stopped going there because
stopped going there because the
stopped going there because the low
calibration
calibration of
stopped going there because the low
calibration of the
calibration of the waitress.
stopped going there because the low
calibration of the waitress. I
calibration of the waitress. I mean,
stopped going there because the low
calibration of the waitress. I mean, she
was
was the
was the calibration
was the calibration of
was the calibration of waitress
was the calibration of waitress so
was the calibration of waitress so bad
was the calibration of waitress so bad I
couldn't
couldn't handle
was the calibration of waitress so bad I
couldn't handle it.
couldn't handle it. I
was the calibration of waitress so bad I
couldn't handle it. I would
couldn't handle it. I would go
was the calibration of waitress so bad I
couldn't handle it. I would go there
couldn't handle it. I would go there all
the
the time
the time in
the time in Prescott
the time in Prescott and
the time in Prescott and she
the time in Prescott and she would
the time in Prescott and she would every
time
time I'd
the time in Prescott and she would every
time I'd go
time I'd go there
the time in Prescott and she would every
time I'd go there she'd
time I'd go there she'd say
the time in Prescott and she would every
time I'd go there she'd say do
time I'd go there she'd say do you
the time in Prescott and she would every
time I'd go there she'd say do you want
a
a menu?
Like
Like she
a menu?
Like she never
Like she never saw
a menu?
Like she never saw me
Like she never saw me before.
a menu?
Like she never saw me before. Do
Like she never saw me before. Do you
want
want a
want a menu
want a menu or
want a menu or a
want a menu or a confrontational?
You
You want
want a menu or a confrontational?
You want coffee?
You want coffee? I'd
want a menu or a confrontational?
You want coffee? I'd order
You want coffee? I'd order tea
want a menu or a confrontational?
You want coffee? I'd order tea the
You want coffee? I'd order tea the last
20 times.
20 times. I'm
20 times. I'm the
20 times. I'm the only
20 times. I'm the only customer
20 times. I'm the only customer in
20 times. I'm the only customer in the
restaurant
restaurant at
20 times. I'm the only customer in the
restaurant at that
restaurant at that time.
20 times. I'm the only customer in the
restaurant at that time. There's
restaurant at that time. There's nobody
else.
else. Every
else. Every Tuesday
else. Every Tuesday morning
else. Every Tuesday morning for
else. Every Tuesday morning for month
once
once I
else. Every Tuesday morning for month
once I ordered
once I ordered the
else. Every Tuesday morning for month
once I ordered the same
once I ordered the same thing.
else. Every Tuesday morning for month
once I ordered the same thing. You
once I ordered the same thing. You want
coffee?
coffee? No.
coffee? No. Idiot.
coffee? No. Idiot. I
coffee? No. Idiot. I drink
coffee? No. Idiot. I drink tea,
coffee? No. Idiot. I drink tea, you
stupid
stupid thing.
How
How stupid
How stupid she
How stupid she is.
How stupid she is. I
How stupid she is. I stopped
How stupid she is. I stopped going
there.
there. Horrible.
It's
It's right
It's right near
It's right near science
It's right near science of
It's right near science of It's
It's right near science of It's right
near
near your
It's right near science of It's right
near your church.
She
She never
She never stops
She never stops talking.
She never stops talking. She's
opinionated
opinionated about
She never stops talking. She's
opinionated about everything.
opinionated about everything. I
She never stops talking. She's
opinionated about everything. I think
opinionated about everything. I think I
can't
can't stand
can't stand the
can't stand the energy
can't stand the energy of
can't stand the energy of this
can't stand the energy of this place.
You
You know,
can't stand the energy of this place.
You know, it
You know, it was
can't stand the energy of this place.
You know, it was convenient.
You know, it was convenient. That's
can't stand the energy of this place.
You know, it was convenient. That's all.
All
All right.
All right. She
All right. She calibrates.
All right. She calibrates. I
All right. She calibrates. I don't
All right. She calibrates. I don't want
a
a calibrator.
Then
Then what
Then what about
Then what about the
Then what about the restaurant
Then what about the restaurant you
Then what about the restaurant you go?
There's
There's another
Then what about the restaurant you go?
There's another restaurant
There's another restaurant I
Then what about the restaurant you go?
There's another restaurant I go
There's another restaurant I go and
Then what about the restaurant you go?
There's another restaurant I go and they
say,
say, "Oh,
say, "Oh, hi.
say, "Oh, hi. Haven't
say, "Oh, hi. Haven't seen
say, "Oh, hi. Haven't seen you
say, "Oh, hi. Haven't seen you all
week."
week." And
say, "Oh, hi. Haven't seen you all
week." And you
week." And you want
say, "Oh, hi. Haven't seen you all
week." And you want tea?
week." And you want tea? Yeah.
say, "Oh, hi. Haven't seen you all
week." And you want tea? Yeah. Uhhuh.
And
And you
And you want
And you want your
And you want your usual?
And you want your usual? Yep.
And you want your usual? Yep. That's
where
where I
And you want your usual? Yep. That's
where I eat
where I eat every
And you want your usual? Yep. That's
where I eat every morning.
where I eat every morning. Monday,
Wednesday,
Wednesday, Friday
Wednesday, Friday morning.
Wednesday, Friday morning. They
Wednesday, Friday morning. They know
what
what you
Wednesday, Friday morning. They know
what you want.
what you want. Of
Wednesday, Friday morning. They know
what you want. Of course,
what you want. Of course, they
Wednesday, Friday morning. They know
what you want. Of course, they recognize
you.
you. You've
you. You've been
you. You've been there
you. You've been there every
you. You've been there every freaking
morning.
morning. You
you. You've been there every freaking
morning. You know,
morning. You know, see
how
how stupid
how stupid can
how stupid can you
how stupid can you get?
So
each
each each
each each level
each each level is
each each level is suitable
each each level is suitable for
each each level is suitable for that
which
which it
each each level is suitable for that
which it is.
which it is. All
each each level is suitable for that
which it is. All rights
distribution
distribution in
distribution in society
distribution in society is
distribution in society is what
distribution in society is what I
distribution in society is what I want
to
to correct.
Somebody
Somebody in
Somebody in the
Somebody in the audience
Somebody in the audience I'm
Somebody in the audience I'm sure
Somebody in the audience I'm sure is
Somebody in the audience I'm sure is a
graphic
graphic artist
Somebody in the audience I'm sure is a
graphic artist and
graphic artist and understands
Somebody in the audience I'm sure is a
graphic artist and understands computers
and
and all
and all these
and all these modern
and all these modern wonderful
and all these modern wonderful things.
Uh
Uh Betty
and all these modern wonderful things.
Uh Betty is
Uh Betty is here
and all these modern wonderful things.
Uh Betty is here and
Uh Betty is here and she
and all these modern wonderful things.
Uh Betty is here and she did
Uh Betty is here and she did the
announcements
announcements for
announcements for the
announcements for the year.
announcements for the year. Did
announcements for the year. Did a
announcements for the year. Did a great
job
job there.
announcements for the year. Did a great
job there. Here
job there. Here we
announcements for the year. Did a great
job there. Here we need
job there. Here we need a
announcements for the year. Did a great
job there. Here we need a what
job there. Here we need a what we
announcements for the year. Did a great
job there. Here we need a what we need
is
is a
is a different
is a different graphic
is a different graphic a
is a different graphic a different
is a different graphic a different way
of
of depicting
is a different graphic a different way
of depicting the
of depicting the levels
is a different graphic a different way
of depicting the levels of
consciousness.
consciousness. This
consciousness. This would
consciousness. This would be
consciousness. This would be a
distribution
distribution curve
consciousness. This would be a
distribution curve in
distribution curve in society
where
this
this is
where
this is the
this is the population
where
this is the population of
this is the population of the
where
this is the population of the earth
this is the population of the earth and
how
how the
how the levels
how the levels of
how the levels of consciousness
how the levels of consciousness are
distributed.
At
At 1,00
At 1,00 we
At 1,00 we got
At 1,00 we got nobody.
At 1,00 we got nobody. We
At 1,00 we got nobody. We got
At 1,00 we got nobody. We got like
At 1,00 we got nobody. We got like one
person
person or
At 1,00 we got nobody. We got like one
person or something
person or something over
At 1,00 we got nobody. We got like one
person or something over here
person or something over here and
At 1,00 we got nobody. We got like one
person or something over here and maybe
900 800s
900 800s there's
900 800s there's there's
900 800s there's there's a
900 800s there's there's a dozen
900 800s there's there's a dozen people
over
over here.
900 800s there's there's a dozen people
over here. Uh
over here. Uh we
900 800s there's there's a dozen people
over here. Uh we said
over here. Uh we said 500
900 800s there's there's a dozen people
over here. Uh we said 500 and
over here. Uh we said 500 and over
900 800s there's there's a dozen people
over here. Uh we said 500 and over about
2%
2% of
2% of the
2% of the population
2% of the population gets
2% of the population gets there.
2% of the population gets there. When
you
you get
2% of the population gets there. When
you get up
you get up to
2% of the population gets there. When
you get up to unconditional
you get up to unconditional love
2% of the population gets there. When
you get up to unconditional love at
you get up to unconditional love at 0.4
uh
uh unconditional
uh unconditional love
uh unconditional love let's
uh unconditional love let's see
uh unconditional love let's see is
uh unconditional love let's see is up
here
here like
uh unconditional love let's see is up
here like 540.
When
When something's
When something's being
When something's being videotaped
When something's being videotaped always
stand
stand right
When something's being videotaped always
stand right in
stand right in front
When something's being videotaped always
stand right in front of
stand right in front of what
When something's being videotaped always
stand right in front of what you're
writing
writing so
writing so the
writing so the audience
writing so the audience can't
writing so the audience can't see
writing so the audience can't see what
it
it is.
All
All right.
All right. You
All right. You notice
All right. You notice the
All right. You notice the strangeness
All right. You notice the strangeness of
this
this curve.
All right. You notice the strangeness of
this curve. The
this curve. The huge
All right. You notice the strangeness of
this curve. The huge mass
this curve. The huge mass is
All right. You notice the strangeness of
this curve. The huge mass is way
this curve. The huge mass is way over
here.
here. See,
here. See, we
here. See, we said
here. See, we said that
here. See, we said that 78,
here. See, we said that 78, no,
here. See, we said that 78, no, when
here. See, we said that 78, no, when we
wrote
wrote the
here. See, we said that 78, no, when we
wrote the book
wrote the book power
here. See, we said that 78, no, when we
wrote the book power versus
wrote the book power versus force,
here. See, we said that 78, no, when we
wrote the book power versus force, 85%
of
of the
of the world's
of the world's population
of the world's population calibrated
below
below 200.
of the world's population calibrated
below 200. 85.
So
200 would
200 would probably
So
200 would probably be
200 would probably be around
So
200 would probably be around around
200 would probably be around around here
somewhere.
somewhere. This
somewhere. This is
somewhere. This is supposed
somewhere. This is supposed to
somewhere. This is supposed to be
somewhere. This is supposed to be 85%
somewhere. This is supposed to be 85% of
the
the world's
somewhere. This is supposed to be 85% of
the world's population
the world's population over
somewhere. This is supposed to be 85% of
the world's population over here.
the world's population over here. That
leaves
leaves us
leaves us 15%
leaves us 15% here.
leaves us 15% here. The
leaves us 15% here. The 200s
leaves us 15% here. The 200s who
leaves us 15% here. The 200s who are
leaves us 15% here. The 200s who are the
builders
builders of
leaves us 15% here. The 200s who are the
builders of the
builders of the world,
leaves us 15% here. The 200s who are the
builders of the world, the
builders of the world, the construction
workers,
workers, the
workers, the steel
workers, the steel workers,
workers, the steel workers, the
workers, the steel workers, the people
who
who go
workers, the steel workers, the people
who go to
who go to work
workers, the steel workers, the people
who go to work every
who go to work every day.
workers, the steel workers, the people
who go to work every day. They're
who go to work every day. They're the
backbone
backbone of
backbone of the
backbone of the our
backbone of the our our
backbone of the our our society.
backbone of the our our society. And
backbone of the our our society. And the
200s
200s and
backbone of the our our society. And the
200s and the
200s and the 300s,
the
the 400s
the 400s are
the 400s are the
the 400s are the world
the 400s are the world of
the 400s are the world of is
the 400s are the world of is the
the 400s are the world of is the world
of
of the
the 400s are the world of is the world
of the intellect
of the intellect and
the 400s are the world of is the world
of the intellect and reason.
of the intellect and reason. It
dominates
dominates America.
500 is
500 is rare.
dominates America.
500 is rare. 540
500 is rare. 540 is
dominates America.
500 is rare. 540 is extremely
500 is rare. 540 is extremely rare.
dominates America.
500 is rare. 540 is extremely rare. And
from
from 540
from 540 and
from 540 and up
from 540 and up there's
from 540 and up there's practically
nobody
nobody really.
The
The trouble
The trouble thing
The trouble thing is
The trouble thing is that
The trouble thing is that their
The trouble thing is that their power
The trouble thing is that their power is
so
so enormous
The trouble thing is that their power is
so enormous that
so enormous that they
The trouble thing is that their power is
so enormous that they counterbalance
so enormous that they counterbalance the
rest
rest of
rest of the
rest of the whole
rest of the whole population.
The
The power
rest of the whole population.
The power of
The power of these
rest of the whole population.
The power of these higher
The power of these higher levels
rest of the whole population.
The power of these higher levels is
The power of these higher levels is so
enormous
enormous that
enormous that it
enormous that it overcomes
enormous that it overcomes the
destructiveness
destructiveness of
enormous that it overcomes the
destructiveness of these
destructiveness of these this
enormous that it overcomes the
destructiveness of these this whole
thing.
thing. This
thing. This society
thing. This society here
thing. This society here is
thing. This society here is really
supported
supported by
thing. This society here is really
supported by this
supported by this here.
They
They say
They say 1%
They say 1% of
They say 1% of the
taxpayers
taxpayers pay
They say 1% of the
taxpayers pay 85%
taxpayers pay 85% of
They say 1% of the
taxpayers pay 85% of the
taxpayers pay 85% of the world's
They say 1% of the
taxpayers pay 85% of the world's taxes,
something
something like
something like that.
something like that. The
something like that. The top
something like that. The top 2%
something like that. The top 2% of
something like that. The top 2% of the
world's
world's earners
something like that. The top 2% of the
world's earners pay
world's earners pay the
something like that. The top 2% of the
world's earners pay the taxes
world's earners pay the taxes for
everybody
everybody else.
everybody else. They
everybody else. They don't
everybody else. They don't have
everybody else. They don't have to
everybody else. They don't have to pay
taxes
taxes because
everybody else. They don't have to pay
taxes because these
taxes because these guys
everybody else. They don't have to pay
taxes because these guys are
taxes because these guys are paying
everybody else. They don't have to pay
taxes because these guys are paying it,
right?
right? They
right? They pay
right? They pay such
right? They pay such enormous
right? They pay such enormous taxes
except
except for
right? They pay such enormous taxes
except for Enron.
They
They got
They got they
They got they were
They got they were really
They got they were really smart.
They got they were really smart. They
got
got away
They got they were really smart. They
got away with
got away with no
They got they were really smart. They
got away with no tax.
got away with no tax. Plus,
They got they were really smart. They
got away with no tax. Plus, they
got away with no tax. Plus, they got
They got they were really smart. They
got away with no tax. Plus, they got the
government
government to
government to send
government to send a
government to send a 352
government to send a 352 billion
government to send a 352 billion dollar
return.
return. 250
government to send a 352 billion dollar
return. 250 million.
return. 250 million. Now,
government to send a 352 billion dollar
return. 250 million. Now, that
return. 250 million. Now, that was
really
really clever.
really clever. Pay
really clever. Pay no
really clever. Pay no taxes
really clever. Pay no taxes and
really clever. Pay no taxes and get
really clever. Pay no taxes and get a
refund
refund on
really clever. Pay no taxes and get a
refund on top
refund on top of
really clever. Pay no taxes and get a
refund on top of it.
refund on top of it. We'll
really clever. Pay no taxes and get a
refund on top of it. We'll have
refund on top of it. We'll have to
figure
figure out how
figure out how they
figure out how they did
figure out how they did that.
figure out how they did that. This
figure out how they did that. This said,
do
do for
we
we have
we have permission
we have permission to
we have permission to do
we have permission to do Enron
we have permission to do Enron resist.
Uh
Uh that
we have permission to do Enron resist.
Uh that company
Uh that company is
we have permission to do Enron resist.
Uh that company is over
Uh that company is over 200
we have permission to do Enron resist.
Uh that company is over 200 resist.
It's
It's over
It's over 160
It's over 160 165
It's over 160 165 170.
It's over 160 165 170. They're
It's over 160 165 170. They're around
165.
165. Calibrated
It's over 160 165 170. They're around
165. Calibrated level
165. Calibrated level of
It's over 160 165 170. They're around
165. Calibrated level of integrity
165. Calibrated level of integrity of
that
that company
that company is
that company is about
that company is about 165.
that company is about 165. Mhm.
All
All right.
that company is about 165. Mhm.
All right. There's
All right. There's nothing
that company is about 165. Mhm.
All right. There's nothing wrong
All right. There's nothing wrong with
that.
that. I'm
that. I'm not
that. I'm not saying
that. I'm not saying it's
that. I'm not saying it's wrong.
that. I'm not saying it's wrong. It's
just
just the
that. I'm not saying it's wrong. It's
just the way
just the way it
that. I'm not saying it's wrong. It's
just the way it is
just the way it is because
that. I'm not saying it's wrong. It's
just the way it is because we
just the way it is because we see
that. I'm not saying it's wrong. It's
just the way it is because we see the
mass
mass is
mass is over
mass is over here.
mass is over here. Right
mass is over here. Right now,
mass is over here. Right now, if
mass is over here. Right now, if we're
going
going to
mass is over here. Right now, if we're
going to do
going to do a
mass is over here. Right now, if we're
going to do a correct
going to do a correct graphic
mass is over here. Right now, if we're
going to do a correct graphic to
going to do a correct graphic to really
depict
depict the
depict the ge,
depict the ge, you
depict the ge, you know,
depict the ge, you know, how
depict the ge, you know, how the
depict the ge, you know, how the level
of
of consciousness
depict the ge, you know, how the level
of consciousness is
of consciousness is laid
depict the ge, you know, how the level
of consciousness is laid out
of consciousness is laid out within
depict the ge, you know, how the level
of consciousness is laid out within the
population,
population, this
population, this side
population, this side should
population, this side should be
population, this side should be dark
because
because we
population, this side should be dark
because we said
because we said it's
population, this side should be dark
because we said it's not
because we said it's not a
population, this side should be dark
because we said it's not a duality.
because we said it's not a duality. It's
not
not a
not a duality
not a duality of
not a duality of good
not a duality of good and
not a duality of good and evil.
not a duality of good and evil. It's
not a duality of good and evil. It's not
that
that 200
not a duality of good and evil. It's not
that 200 and
that 200 and above
not a duality of good and evil. It's not
that 200 and above is
that 200 and above is good
not a duality of good and evil. It's not
that 200 and above is good and
that 200 and above is good and 200
not a duality of good and evil. It's not
that 200 and above is good and 200 below
200 is
200 is bad.
200 is bad. It
200 is bad. It changes
200 is bad. It changes quality.
200 is bad. It changes quality. So
200 is bad. It changes quality. So here
at
at 200
200 is bad. It changes quality. So here
at 200 the
at 200 the shading
200 is bad. It changes quality. So here
at 200 the shading this
at 200 the shading this should
200 is bad. It changes quality. So here
at 200 the shading this should be
at 200 the shading this should be very
light
light over
light over here
light over here brilliantly
light over here brilliantly light
because
because they're
light over here brilliantly light
because they're the
because they're the light
light over here brilliantly light
because they're the light of
because they're the light of the
light over here brilliantly light
because they're the light of the world.
It
It gets
It gets the
It gets the it
It gets the it shades
It gets the it shades down
It gets the it shades down the
It gets the it shades down the intensity
of
of the
It gets the it shades down the intensity
of the whiteness
of the whiteness gets
It gets the it shades down the intensity
of the whiteness gets a
of the whiteness gets a bit
It gets the it shades down the intensity
of the whiteness gets a bit less
of the whiteness gets a bit less here.
There's
There's suddenly
There's suddenly quite
There's suddenly quite a
There's suddenly quite a change
There's suddenly quite a change of
There's suddenly quite a change of um
intensity
intensity of
There's suddenly quite a change of um
intensity of tone.
intensity of tone. Let's
There's suddenly quite a change of um
intensity of tone. Let's say
intensity of tone. Let's say this
suddenly
suddenly becomes
suddenly becomes quite
suddenly becomes quite a
suddenly becomes quite a bit
suddenly becomes quite a bit darker
suddenly becomes quite a bit darker and
by
by the
suddenly becomes quite a bit darker and
by the time
by the time you
suddenly becomes quite a bit darker and
by the time you get
by the time you get over
suddenly becomes quite a bit darker and
by the time you get over here
by the time you get over here it's
almost
almost solid
almost solid black.
How
How much
almost solid black.
How much light
How much light gets
almost solid black.
How much light gets through
to
to that
to that killer
mollisk?
mollisk? None.
40 different
40 different killer
40 different killer enzymes.
40 different killer enzymes. 40
different
different venoms
40 different killer enzymes. 40
different venoms in
different venoms in one
40 different killer enzymes. 40
different venoms in one little
different venoms in one little mollisk.
Huh.
Huh. Oo.
Huh. Oo. If
Huh. Oo. If I
Huh. Oo. If I understood
Huh. Oo. If I understood that.
Huh. Oo. If I understood that. I
Huh. Oo. If I understood that. I don't
want
want to
Huh. Oo. If I understood that. I don't
want to understand
want to understand that.
Huh. Oo. If I understood that. I don't
want to understand that. I
want to understand that. I don't
Huh. Oo. If I understood that. I don't
want to understand that. I don't even
want
want to
want to understand
want to understand it.
want to understand it. But
want to understand it. But anyway.
All right.
All right. So
we
we see
we see that
we see that somebody
we see that somebody like
we see that somebody like Bin
we see that somebody like Bin Laden
we see that somebody like Bin Laden has
a
a whole
we see that somebody like Bin Laden has
a whole population
a whole population to
we see that somebody like Bin Laden has
a whole population to appeal
a whole population to appeal to
we see that somebody like Bin Laden has
a whole population to appeal to because
they're
they're less
they're less than
they're less than he
they're less than he is.
they're less than he is. He
they're less than he is. He looks
powerful
powerful and
they're less than he is. He looks
powerful and attractive
powerful and attractive to
they're less than he is. He looks
powerful and attractive to them.
And
And because
And because they
And because they are
And because they are have
And because they are have nots,
And because they are have nots, it's
easy
easy to
And because they are have nots, it's
easy to get
easy to get them
And because they are have nots, it's
easy to get them to
easy to get them to hate
And because they are have nots, it's
easy to get them to hate the
easy to get them to hate the halves,
right?
right? He's
right? He's got
right? He's got an
right? He's got an enormous
right? He's got an enormous population
to
to whom
right? He's got an enormous population
to whom he's
to whom he's probably
right? He's got an enormous population
to whom he's probably quite
to whom he's probably quite attractive,
you
you know?
you know? Plus,
you know? Plus, he
you know? Plus, he promises
you know? Plus, he promises you
you know? Plus, he promises you if
you know? Plus, he promises you if you
kill
kill yourself
you know? Plus, he promises you if you
kill yourself for
kill yourself for for
you know? Plus, he promises you if you
kill yourself for for Allah,
uh,
uh, you
uh, you go
uh, you go to
uh, you go to this
uh, you go to this heaven
uh, you go to this heaven where
uh, you go to this heaven where there's
fruit
fruit and
uh, you go to this heaven where there's
fruit and money
fruit and money and
uh, you go to this heaven where there's
fruit and money and gold
fruit and money and gold and
marvelous
marvelous beauty
marvelous beauty and
marvelous beauty and all
marvelous beauty and all the
marvelous beauty and all the senses
marvelous beauty and all the senses are
delighted
delighted and
marvelous beauty and all the senses are
delighted and you
delighted and you get
marvelous beauty and all the senses are
delighted and you get 72
delighted and you get 72 virgins.
And
And you're
And you're in
And you're in your,
And you're in your, like
And you're in your, like I
And you're in your, like I said
And you're in your, like I said at
And you're in your, like I said at some
other
other meeting,
And you're in your, like I said at some
other meeting, if
other meeting, if you're
And you're in your, like I said at some
other meeting, if you're in
other meeting, if you're in your
And you're in your, like I said at some
other meeting, if you're in your 20s,
that
that sounds
that sounds pretty
that sounds pretty good.
that sounds pretty good. At
that sounds pretty good. At 75,
that sounds pretty good. At 75, you'd
rather
rather kill
that sounds pretty good. At 75, you'd
rather kill yourself.
No,
No, I'll
No, I'll tell
No, I'll tell you
No, I'll tell you the
No, I'll tell you the real
No, I'll tell you the real truth.
No, I'll tell you the real truth. I'll
tell
tell you
No, I'll tell you the real truth. I'll
tell you the
tell you the truth.
No, I'll tell you the real truth. I'll
tell you the truth. That's
tell you the truth. That's just
No, I'll tell you the real truth. I'll
tell you the truth. That's just the
joke.
He
He doesn't
joke.
He doesn't tell
He doesn't tell you
joke.
He doesn't tell you that
He doesn't tell you that the
joke.
He doesn't tell you that the 72
He doesn't tell you that the 72 virgins
are
are all
are all well
are all well over
are all well over 900
are all well over 900 years
are all well over 900 years old.
72 virgins.
72 virgins. All right.
are all well over 900 years old.
72 virgins. All right. They
72 virgins. All right. They hated
are all well over 900 years old.
72 virgins. All right. They hated men
for
for 900
for 900 years.
for 900 years. What
for 900 years. What do
for 900 years. What do you
for 900 years. What do you get
for 900 years. What do you get here,
buddy?
Uh
Uh yeah,
you
you say
Uh yeah,
you say to
you say to yourself,
Uh yeah,
you say to yourself, anybody
you say to yourself, anybody who's
looked
looked over
looked over the
looked over the Quran,
looked over the Quran, the
looked over the Quran, the beginning
looked over the Quran, the beginning of
every
every stanza,
looked over the Quran, the beginning of
every stanza, verse
every stanza, verse what
looked over the Quran, the beginning of
every stanza, verse what you
every stanza, verse what you call
looked over the Quran, the beginning of
every stanza, verse what you call it,
says
says in
says in the
says in the name
says in the name of
says in the name of Allah,
says in the name of Allah, the
says in the name of Allah, the all
merciful.
merciful. The
says in the name of Allah, the all
merciful. The all
merciful. The all merciful.
says in the name of Allah, the all
merciful. The all merciful. All
merciful.
Yeah.
So
So to
So to not
So to not even
So to not even get
So to not even get what
So to not even get what all
So to not even get what all merciful
means
means or
So to not even get what all merciful
means or what
means or what God
So to not even get what all merciful
means or what God could
means or what God could mean
So to not even get what all merciful
means or what God could mean when
means or what God could mean when you're
below
below this
below this you
below this you say
below this you say how
below this you say how can
below this you say how can people
below this you say how can people be
below this you say how can people be so
stupid
stupid to
below this you say how can people be so
stupid to think
stupid to think that
below this you say how can people be so
stupid to think that God's
stupid to think that God's going
below this you say how can people be so
stupid to think that God's going to
stupid to think that God's going to be
pleased
pleased by
pleased by massacring
pleased by massacring in
pleased by massacring in innocent
children
children women
pleased by massacring in innocent
children women and
children women and children
pleased by massacring in innocent
children women and children it's
children women and children it's because
down
down below
down below the
down below the level
down below the level of
down below the level of 200
down below the level of 200 that
down below the level of 200 that almost
makes
makes sense
down below the level of 200 that almost
makes sense to
makes sense to you
down below the level of 200 that almost
makes sense to you that
makes sense to you that makes
down below the level of 200 that almost
makes sense to you that makes sense
certainly
certainly Christianity
certainly Christianity went
certainly Christianity went through
certainly Christianity went through that
phase
phase didn't
certainly Christianity went through that
phase didn't it
kill
kill a
kill a kill
kill a kill a
an
an Arab
kill a kill a
an Arab or
an Arab or Muhammadan
kill a kill a
an Arab or Muhammadan for
an Arab or Muhammadan for for
kill a kill a
an Arab or Muhammadan for for Jesus
an Arab or Muhammadan for for Jesus and
they
they were
they were busy
they were busy killing
they were busy killing us
they were busy killing us for
they were busy killing us for and
they were busy killing us for and I
think
think I
they were busy killing us for and I
think I told
think I told another
they were busy killing us for and I
think I told another that
think I told another that brings
they were busy killing us for and I
think I told another that brings back
another
another memory
another memory of
another memory of another
another memory of another lifetime
another memory of another lifetime in
which
which uh
and
and and
and and uh
and and uh what
and and uh what the
and and uh what the world
and and uh what the world calls
and and uh what the world calls another
lifetime
lifetime anyway
and and uh what the world calls another
lifetime anyway it's
lifetime anyway it's just
and and uh what the world calls another
lifetime anyway it's just a
lifetime anyway it's just a continuation
of
of this
of this consciousness
of this consciousness and
of this consciousness and I
of this consciousness and I was
of this consciousness and I was a
Christian
Christian in
of this consciousness and I was a
Christian in the
Christian in the um
of this consciousness and I was a
Christian in the um in
Christian in the um in about
of this consciousness and I was a
Christian in the um in about 1099
Christian in the um in about 1099 I
think
think it
think it was
think it was and
think it was and uh
think it was and uh and
think it was and uh and I
think it was and uh and I was
think it was and uh and I was a
think it was and uh and I was a warrior
where
where do
think it was and uh and I was a warrior
where do you
where do you the
think it was and uh and I was a warrior
where do you the crusades
where do you the crusades yes
think it was and uh and I was a warrior
where do you the crusades yes crusades
anyway
anyway I
anyway I was
anyway I was pretty
anyway I was pretty good
anyway I was pretty good in
anyway I was pretty good in those
anyway I was pretty good in those days.
I
I was
anyway I was pretty good in those days.
I was a
I was a misamomorph.
anyway I was pretty good in those days.
I was a misamomorph. I'm
I was a misamomorph. I'm not
anyway I was pretty good in those days.
I was a misamomorph. I'm not a
I was a misamomorph. I'm not a misomorph
in
in this
in this life.
in this life. As
in this life. As you
in this life. As you can
in this life. As you can see,
in this life. As you can see, I
in this life. As you can see, I can
barely
barely move
in this life. As you can see, I can
barely move these
barely move these skeleton
in this life. As you can see, I can
barely move these skeleton around.
barely move these skeleton around. But
in this life. As you can see, I can
barely move these skeleton around. But I
was
was a
was a misamomorph
was a misamomorph and
was a misamomorph and very
was a misamomorph and very strong
was a misamomorph and very strong and
very
very ferocious.
was a misamomorph and very strong and
very ferocious. And
very ferocious. And I
was a misamomorph and very strong and
very ferocious. And I remember
very ferocious. And I remember also
was a misamomorph and very strong and
very ferocious. And I remember also the
lifetime
lifetime which
lifetime which I
lifetime which I developed
lifetime which I developed the
lifetime which I developed the capacity
for
for ferocity.
lifetime which I developed the capacity
for ferocity. And
for ferocity. And that
lifetime which I developed the capacity
for ferocity. And that was
for ferocity. And that was karate.
lifetime which I developed the capacity
for ferocity. And that was karate. I
mean
mean um
um
um what
mean um
um what do
um what do you
mean um
um what do you call
um what do you call it
mean um
um what do you call it when
um what do you call it when you've
mean um
um what do you call it when you've lost
face
and
and you
face
and you stab
and you stab yourself
face
and you stab yourself and
and you stab yourself and rip
face
and you stab yourself and rip your
and you stab yourself and rip your guts
out.
out. Huh?
>> Oh
>> Oh yeah.
out. Huh?
>> Oh yeah. God,
>> Oh yeah. God, that
out. Huh?
>> Oh yeah. God, that was
>> Oh yeah. God, that was awful.
That
That that
That that that
That that that was
That that that was the
That that that was the worst
That that that was the worst of
That that that was the worst of all.
That that that was the worst of all. But
anyway,
anyway, when
That that that was the worst of all. But
anyway, when I
anyway, when I went
That that that was the worst of all. But
anyway, when I went out
anyway, when I went out of
That that that was the worst of all. But
anyway, when I went out of body,
anyway, when I went out of body, I
That that that was the worst of all. But
anyway, when I went out of body, I was
ecstatic.
ecstatic. Nothing
ecstatic. Nothing stood
ecstatic. Nothing stood in
ecstatic. Nothing stood in my
ecstatic. Nothing stood in my way.
ecstatic. Nothing stood in my way. No
fear
fear of
ecstatic. Nothing stood in my way. No
fear of death,
fear of death, no
ecstatic. Nothing stood in my way. No
fear of death, no fear
fear of death, no fear of
ecstatic. Nothing stood in my way. No
fear of death, no fear of pain,
fear of death, no fear of pain, nothing.
And
And I
And I was
And I was from
And I was from that
And I was from that point
And I was from that point on
And I was from that point on a
And I was from that point on a very
formidable
formidable opponent.
I
I still
I still am.
When
When I
I still am.
When I go
When I go after
I still am.
When I go after a
When I go after a chicken
I still am.
When I go after a chicken in
When I go after a chicken in the
I still am.
When I go after a chicken in the end,
When I go after a chicken in the end, I
was
was I
was I get
was I get that
was I get that chicken.
Nothing
Nothing stands
was I get that chicken.
Nothing stands between
Nothing stands between me
was I get that chicken.
Nothing stands between me and
Nothing stands between me and the
intention.
intention. Nothing.
The
The karate
intention. Nothing.
The karate of
The karate of catching
intention. Nothing.
The karate of catching chickens.
I
I got
I got that
I got that chicken
I got that chicken just
I got that chicken just like
I got that chicken just like that.
I got that chicken just like that. He
didn't
didn't even
I got that chicken just like that. He
didn't even know
didn't even know I
I got that chicken just like that. He
didn't even know I was
didn't even know I was coming
I got that chicken just like that. He
didn't even know I was coming at
didn't even know I was coming at him.
I got that chicken just like that. He
didn't even know I was coming at him. I
don't
don't even
don't even look
don't even look at
don't even look at him.
don't even look at him. I
don't even look at him. I don't
don't even look at him. I don't give
don't even look at him. I don't give him
a
a vibration.
don't even look at him. I don't give him
a vibration. He
a vibration. He gets
don't even look at him. I don't give him
a vibration. He gets it.
And
And I
And I was
And I was formidable.
And I was formidable. So,
And I was formidable. So, I
And I was formidable. So, I met
And I was formidable. So, I met another
guy
guy who
And I was formidable. So, I met another
guy who was
guy who was formal
And I was formidable. So, I met another
guy who was formal as
guy who was formal as all
And I was formidable. So, I met another
guy who was formal as all hell.
guy who was formal as all hell. I
And I was formidable. So, I met another
guy who was formal as all hell. I mean,
he
he was
he was ferocious.
Uh
Uh we
he was ferocious.
Uh we could
Uh we could have
he was ferocious.
Uh we could have been
Uh we could have been the
he was ferocious.
Uh we could have been the two
Uh we could have been the two top
killers
killers uh
killers uh at
killers uh at that
killers uh at that particular
killers uh at that particular battle.
Anyway,
Anyway, we
killers uh at that particular battle.
Anyway, we were
Anyway, we were both
killers uh at that particular battle.
Anyway, we were both terrific
Anyway, we were both terrific swordsmen
and
and uh
and uh he
and uh he was
and uh he was a
and uh he was a match.
and uh he was a match. He
and uh he was a match. He was
and uh he was a match. He was a
and uh he was a match. He was a match
and
and I
and uh he was a match. He was a match
and I love
and I love him
and uh he was a match. He was a match
and I love him to
and I love him to this
and uh he was a match. He was a match
and I love him to this day.
Yeah,
Yeah, he's
Yeah, he's a
Yeah, he's a close
Yeah, he's a close buddy.
Yeah, he's a close buddy. Anyway,
Yeah, he's a close buddy. Anyway, uh
Yeah, he's a close buddy. Anyway, uh at
that
that time
Yeah, he's a close buddy. Anyway, uh at
that time we
that time we hate
Yeah, he's a close buddy. Anyway, uh at
that time we hate each
that time we hate each other.
Yeah, he's a close buddy. Anyway, uh at
that time we hate each other. He
that time we hate each other. He was
Islam
Islam and
Islam and I
Islam and I was
Islam and I was a
Islam and I was a Christian.
Islam and I was a Christian. So
Islam and I was a Christian. So I
Islam and I was a Christian. So I killed
him
him for
Islam and I was a Christian. So I killed
him for Jesus
him for Jesus and
Islam and I was a Christian. So I killed
him for Jesus and he
him for Jesus and he killed
Islam and I was a Christian. So I killed
him for Jesus and he killed me
him for Jesus and he killed me for
Islam and I was a Christian. So I killed
him for Jesus and he killed me for Allah
all
all at
all at the
all at the same
all at the same time.
all at the same time. We
all at the same time. We were
all at the same time. We were both
all at the same time. We were both very
very
very good.
all at the same time. We were both very
very good. One
very good. One error
all at the same time. We were both very
very good. One error an
very good. One error an error
all at the same time. We were both very
very good. One error an error big
very good. One error an error big enough
to
to allow
to allow me
to allow me to
to allow me to kill
to allow me to kill him
to allow me to kill him was
to allow me to kill him was created
to allow me to kill him was created the
error
error for
to allow me to kill him was created the
error for him
error for him to
to allow me to kill him was created the
error for him to kill
error for him to kill me.
Both
Both bitter
Both bitter mackerels
Both bitter mackerels and
Both bitter mackerels and we
Both bitter mackerels and we both
Both bitter mackerels and we both went
out
out of
Both bitter mackerels and we both went
out of body
out of body the
Both bitter mackerels and we both went
out of body the same
out of body the same time
Both bitter mackerels and we both went
out of body the same time and
out of body the same time and we
Both bitter mackerels and we both went
out of body the same time and we looked
at
at each
at each other
at each other and
at each other and broke
at each other and broke out
at each other and broke out in
at each other and broke out in hysteria.
It
It was
at each other and broke out in hysteria.
It was so
It was so funny.
at each other and broke out in hysteria.
It was so funny. I
It was so funny. I killed
at each other and broke out in hysteria.
It was so funny. I killed him
It was so funny. I killed him for
at each other and broke out in hysteria.
It was so funny. I killed him for Jesus.
cuz
cuz he
cuz he killed
cuz he killed me
cuz he killed me for
cuz he killed me for all
cuz he killed me for all you
cuz he killed me for all you and
cuz he killed me for all you and that
instant
instant we
cuz he killed me for all you and that
instant we transcended
instant we transcended that
cuz he killed me for all you and that
instant we transcended that whole
positionality.
Yeah,
Yeah, that
positionality.
Yeah, that was
Yeah, that was a
positionality.
Yeah, that was a great
Yeah, that was a great lifetime.
positionality.
Yeah, that was a great lifetime. So
anyway,
anyway, we're
anyway, we're great
anyway, we're great chums
anyway, we're great chums and
anyway, we're great chums and uh
anyway, we're great chums and uh I
anyway, we're great chums and uh I adore
him.
him. So
anyway, we're great chums and uh I adore
him. So anyway,
uh
uh see
uh see because
uh see because your
uh see because your greatest
uh see because your greatest foe
uh see because your greatest foe is
uh see because your greatest foe is your
greatest
greatest friend,
uh see because your greatest foe is your
greatest friend, you
greatest friend, you know,
uh see because your greatest foe is your
greatest friend, you know, and
greatest friend, you know, and course
uh see because your greatest foe is your
greatest friend, you know, and course of
miracles
miracles uh
miracles uh come
miracles uh come true.
miracles uh come true. Anyway,
miracles uh come true. Anyway, I
miracles uh come true. Anyway, I killed
him
him for
miracles uh come true. Anyway, I killed
him for for
him for for Jesus.
miracles uh come true. Anyway, I killed
him for for Jesus. Oh,
him for for Jesus. Oh, I
miracles uh come true. Anyway, I killed
him for for Jesus. Oh, I mean,
him for for Jesus. Oh, I mean, wow.
miracles uh come true. Anyway, I killed
him for for Jesus. Oh, I mean, wow. I
really
really enjoyed
really enjoyed killing
really enjoyed killing it,
really enjoyed killing it, too.
really enjoyed killing it, too. I
really enjoyed killing it, too. I mean,
wow.
Uh
Uh so
Uh so that's
Uh so that's how
Uh so that's how you
Uh so that's how you get
Uh so that's how you get caught
Uh so that's how you get caught up
Uh so that's how you get caught up in
that
that duality.
So
So you
that duality.
So you might
So you might say
that duality.
So you might say each
So you might say each lifetime
that duality.
So you might say each lifetime because
we
we were
we were asked
we were asked was
we were asked was being
we were asked was being asked
we were asked was being asked about
karma
karma then
we were asked was being asked about
karma then serves
karma then serves a
we were asked was being asked about
karma then serves a certain
karma then serves a certain purpose
to
the
the kamicazi
to
the kamicazi pilot
the kamicazi pilot calibrates
to
the kamicazi pilot calibrates high.
the
the um
the um Islamic
the um Islamic terrorist
the um Islamic terrorist who
the um Islamic terrorist who kills
himself
himself for
the um Islamic terrorist who kills
himself for Allah
himself for Allah in
the um Islamic terrorist who kills
himself for Allah in his
himself for Allah in his belief
the um Islamic terrorist who kills
himself for Allah in his belief system,
he
he calibrates
he calibrates very
he calibrates very quite
he calibrates very quite good.
Uh
Uh Bin
he calibrates very quite good.
Uh Bin Laden
Uh Bin Laden does
he calibrates very quite good.
Uh Bin Laden does not
Uh Bin Laden does not because
he calibrates very quite good.
Uh Bin Laden does not because in
Uh Bin Laden does not because in other
words,
words, they're
words, they're using
words, they're using the
words, they're using the legitimate
spiritual
spiritual uh
words, they're using the legitimate
spiritual uh devotional
spiritual uh devotional integrity
words, they're using the legitimate
spiritual uh devotional integrity and
commitment
commitment of
commitment of these
commitment of these devotees
but
but for
commitment of these devotees
but for a
but for a devious
commitment of these devotees
but for a devious end.
but for a devious end. But
commitment of these devotees
but for a devious end. But the
but for a devious end. But the devitate
the
the kamicazi
the kamicazi pilot
the kamicazi pilot who
the kamicazi pilot who did
the kamicazi pilot who did it
the kamicazi pilot who did it for
the kamicazi pilot who did it for the
sun
sun god
the kamicazi pilot who did it for the
sun god because
sun god because of
the kamicazi pilot who did it for the
sun god because of Shinto.
sun god because of Shinto. He
the kamicazi pilot who did it for the
sun god because of Shinto. He did
sun god because of Shinto. He did it
the kamicazi pilot who did it for the
sun god because of Shinto. He did it for
God
and
and he
God
and he goes
and he goes to
God
and he goes to a
and he goes to a good
God
and he goes to a good place.
All
All right.
All right. They
All right. They had
All right. They had integrity.
All right. They had integrity. That
which
which is
All right. They had integrity. That
which is over
which is over 200
All right. They had integrity. That
which is over 200 is
which is over 200 is integrity.
All right. They had integrity. That
which is over 200 is integrity. That's
integrous
integrous to
integrous to sacrifice
integrous to sacrifice your
integrous to sacrifice your life
integrous to sacrifice your life for
integrous to sacrifice your life for God
in
in that
integrous to sacrifice your life for God
in that lifetime.
in that lifetime. I
integrous to sacrifice your life for God
in that lifetime. I did
in that lifetime. I did it
integrous to sacrifice your life for God
in that lifetime. I did it so
in that lifetime. I did it so I
integrous to sacrifice your life for God
in that lifetime. I did it so I know
what
what it
what it feels
what it feels like.
Uh
Uh it
what it feels like.
Uh it is
Uh it is a
what it feels like.
Uh it is a victory
Uh it is a victory over
what it feels like.
Uh it is a victory over all
Uh it is a victory over all that
what it feels like.
Uh it is a victory over all that stands
in
in the
in the way.
in the way. And
in the way. And it
in the way. And it takes
in the way. And it takes you
in the way. And it takes you right
in the way. And it takes you right to
in the way. And it takes you right to a
very
very high
in the way. And it takes you right to a
very high state
very high state in
in the way. And it takes you right to a
very high state in the
very high state in the next
in the way. And it takes you right to a
very high state in the next lifetime.
very high state in the next lifetime. So
it
it then
it then changes
it then changes the
it then changes the polarity
it then changes the polarity of
it then changes the polarity of the
energy
energy of
it then changes the polarity of the
energy of one's
energy of one's spirit.
it then changes the polarity of the
energy of one's spirit. That
energy of one's spirit. That which
it then changes the polarity of the
energy of one's spirit. That which is
willing
willing to
willing to die
willing to die for
willing to die for God,
willing to die for God, to
willing to die for God, to die
willing to die for God, to die for
country,
to
to die
to die for
to die for honor
to die for honor is
to die for honor is already
to die for honor is already a
to die for honor is already a different
being
being than
to die for honor is already a different
being than one
being than one is
to die for honor is already a different
being than one is willing
being than one is willing to
to die for honor is already a different
being than one is willing to sell
being than one is willing to sell it
to die for honor is already a different
being than one is willing to sell it out
at
at the
at the slightest.
at the slightest. Yeah,
at the slightest. Yeah, that's
at the slightest. Yeah, that's a
different
different being.
at the slightest. Yeah, that's a
different being. Integrity,
different being. Integrity, you
at the slightest. Yeah, that's a
different being. Integrity, you can
different being. Integrity, you can be
mistaken,
mistaken, but
mistaken, but integrous.
mistaken, but integrous. Also,
mistaken, but integrous. Also, there's
mistaken, but integrous. Also, there's a
place
place in
mistaken, but integrous. Also, there's a
place in heaven
place in heaven for
mistaken, but integrous. Also, there's a
place in heaven for the
place in heaven for the atheist.
Let's
Let's do
Let's do that.
There
There is
Let's do that.
There is a
There is a special
Let's do that.
There is a special heaven
There is a special heaven for
Let's do that.
There is a special heaven for atheist.
Resist.
Resist. There's
Resist. There's a
Resist. There's a special
Resist. There's a special heaven
Resist. There's a special heaven for
atheists.
I
I mean,
I mean, if
I mean, if absolute
I mean, if absolute in
I mean, if absolute in all
I mean, if absolute in all absolute
honesty,
honesty, you
I mean, if absolute in all absolute
honesty, you just
honesty, you just can't
I mean, if absolute in all absolute
honesty, you just can't get
honesty, you just can't get this
I mean, if absolute in all absolute
honesty, you just can't get this whole
God
God bend
God bend cuz
God bend cuz I
God bend cuz I was
God bend cuz I was there,
God bend cuz I was there, too.
God bend cuz I was there, too. I
God bend cuz I was there, too. I was
there
there all
God bend cuz I was there, too. I was
there all through
there all through college.
Uh
Uh I
Uh I tried
Uh I tried hard
Uh I tried hard to
Uh I tried hard to get
Uh I tried hard to get the
Uh I tried hard to get the god
Uh I tried hard to get the god business
and
and man,
Uh I tried hard to get the god business
and man, it
and man, it was
Uh I tried hard to get the god business
and man, it was just
and man, it was just stupid.
And
And uh
And uh I
And uh I went
And uh I went through
And uh I went through a
And uh I went through a Jesuit
university,
university, got
And uh I went through a Jesuit
university, got straight
university, got straight A's
And uh I went through a Jesuit
university, got straight A's in
theology,
theology, and
theology, and all
theology, and all these
theology, and all these devout
theology, and all these devout people
were
were getting
theology, and all these devout people
were getting C's.
I
I didn't
I didn't believe
I didn't believe it,
I didn't believe it, but
I didn't believe it, but I
I didn't believe it, but I knew
I didn't believe it, but I knew what
I didn't believe it, but I knew what it
was.
was. I
I didn't believe it, but I knew what it
was. I was
was. I was an
I didn't believe it, but I knew what it
was. I was an expert
was. I was an expert in
I didn't believe it, but I knew what it
was. I was an expert in Thomas
was. I was an expert in Thomas Aquinus
and
and ethics
and ethics and
and ethics and logic.
and ethics and logic. And
and ethics and logic. And to
and ethics and logic. And to this
and ethics and logic. And to this day,
you
you know,
and ethics and logic. And to this day,
you know, it
you know, it shocks
and ethics and logic. And to this day,
you know, it shocks me
you know, it shocks me that
and ethics and logic. And to this day,
you know, it shocks me that people
violate
violate basic
violate basic spiritual
violate basic spiritual premises
violate basic spiritual premises such
violate basic spiritual premises such as
the
the injustifies
violate basic spiritual premises such as
the injustifies the
the injustifies the means
violate basic spiritual premises such as
the injustifies the means and
the injustifies the means and things
like
like that,
like that, you
like that, you know.
like that, you know. So
like that, you know. So integrity
like that, you know. So integrity means
honesty,
honesty, the
like that, you know. So integrity means
honesty, the honesty
honesty, the honesty of
like that, you know. So integrity means
honesty, the honesty of one's
convictions.
convictions. And
convictions. And if
convictions. And if uh
convictions. And if uh in
convictions. And if uh in truth
convictions. And if uh in truth you
cannot
cannot find
convictions. And if uh in truth you
cannot find God
cannot find God through
convictions. And if uh in truth you
cannot find God through the
cannot find God through the intellect
which
which is
which is I
which is I what
which is I what I
which is I what I tried
which is I what I tried to
which is I what I tried to do
which is I what I tried to do cannot
find
find God
which is I what I tried to do cannot
find God through
find God through the
which is I what I tried to do cannot
find God through the intellect
find God through the intellect and
which is I what I tried to do cannot
find God through the intellect and u
find God through the intellect and u you
have
have to
have to really
have to really warp
have to really warp logic
have to really warp logic a
have to really warp logic a little
have to really warp logic a little bit
to
to get
have to really warp logic a little bit
to get there
to get there and
have to really warp logic a little bit
to get there and um
going
going through
going through God
going through God as
going through God as first
going through God as first cause
going through God as first cause if
going through God as first cause if you
go
go back
going through God as first cause if you
go back through
go back through this
going through God as first cause if you
go back through this as
go back through this as we
going through God as first cause if you
go back through this as we were
go back through this as we were talking
about
about causality
about causality you
about causality you say
about causality you say well
about causality you say well God
about causality you say well God is
first
first cause
no
no that
no that can't
no that can't be
no that can't be because
the
the sequence
no that can't be because
the sequence is
the sequence is not
no that can't be because
the sequence is not of
the sequence is not of sameness
no that can't be because
the sequence is not of sameness you
suddenly
suddenly come
suddenly come to
suddenly come to differentness
suddenly come to differentness the
quality
quality quality
suddenly come to differentness the
quality quality of
quality quality of God
suddenly come to differentness the
quality quality of God is
quality quality of God is not
suddenly come to differentness the
quality quality of God is not the
quality quality of God is not the same
as
as the
as the quality
as the quality of
as the quality of the
as the quality of the supposed
as the quality of the supposed effects.
So
So you
as the quality of the supposed effects.
So you cannot
So you cannot find
as the quality of the supposed effects.
So you cannot find the
So you cannot find the original
as the quality of the supposed effects.
So you cannot find the original billiard
ball
ball behind
ball behind all
ball behind all the
ball behind all the billiard
ball behind all the billiard balls
because
because when
ball behind all the billiard balls
because when you
because when you get
ball behind all the billiard balls
because when you get to
because when you get to past
ball behind all the billiard balls
because when you get to past number
because when you get to past number one
there
there is
there is no
there is no billiard
there is no billiard balls
there is no billiard balls there.
there is no billiard balls there. You
will
will not
there is no billiard balls there. You
will not find
will not find another
there is no billiard balls there. You
will not find another billiard
will not find another billiard ball
behind
behind billiard
behind billiard ball
behind billiard ball number
behind billiard ball number one.
behind billiard ball number one. If
behind billiard ball number one. If you
can
can see
behind billiard ball number one. If you
can see through
can see through that
behind billiard ball number one. If you
can see through that conundrum
can see through that conundrum that's
like
like coion
like coion you'll
like coion you'll become
like coion you'll become enlightened.
All right.
So
So that
So that which
So that which is
So that which is the
So that which is the so
So that which is the so there's
So that which is the so there's no
So that which is the so there's no cause
of
of what
So that which is the so there's no cause
of what happens
of what happens but
So that which is the so there's no cause
of what happens but there
of what happens but there is
So that which is the so there's no cause
of what happens but there is a
of what happens but there is a source
the
the source
the source is
the source is the
the source is the structure
the source is the structure of
the source is the structure of the
the source is the structure of the ego
itself
itself as
the source is the structure of the ego
itself as it
itself as it sits
the source is the structure of the ego
itself as it sits within
itself as it sits within the
the source is the structure of the ego
itself as it sits within the infinite
power
power of
power of spiritual
power of spiritual consciousness
and
and that
power of spiritual consciousness
and that automatically
and that automatically sequences
what
what appears
what appears to
what appears to be
what appears to be sequence
what appears to be sequence the
what appears to be sequence the fate
what appears to be sequence the fate of
the
the spirit
and
and that
and that is
and that is the
and that is the absol
and that is the absol to
and that is the absol to the
and that is the absol to the perfection
of
of the
and that is the absol to the perfection
of the judgment
of the judgment of
and that is the absol to the perfection
of the judgment of God.
of the judgment of God. There
and that is the absol to the perfection
of the judgment of God. There is
of the judgment of God. There is no
error
error possible.
Therefore,
Therefore, there's
error possible.
Therefore, there's no
Therefore, there's no God
error possible.
Therefore, there's no God to
Therefore, there's no God to fear.
There's
There's only
There's only the
There's only the consequences
There's only the consequences of
There's only the consequences of one's
own
own actions
There's only the consequences of one's
own actions to
own actions to fear
There's only the consequences of one's
own actions to fear which
own actions to fear which then
There's only the consequences of one's
own actions to fear which then gets
projected
projected onto
projected onto a
projected onto a god
projected onto a god figure
projected onto a god figure which
projected onto a god figure which has
projected onto a god figure which has no
reality
reality and
projected onto a god figure which has no
reality and no
reality and no existence.
projected onto a god figure which has no
reality and no existence. Huh.
So
So to
So to see
So to see through
So to see through the
So to see through the illusion
So to see through the illusion of
causality
causality there's
So to see through the illusion of
causality there's nothing
causality there's nothing causing
anything
anything anything
anything anything out
anything anything out there
anything anything out there nothing
anything anything out there nothing is
causing
causing anything
anything anything out there nothing is
causing anything else
causing anything else what
anything anything out there nothing is
causing anything else what you
causing anything else what you see
anything anything out there nothing is
causing anything else what you see are
conditions
conditions for
conditions for this
conditions for this to
conditions for this to open
conditions for this to open up
conditions for this to open up this
conditions for this to open up this for
this
this flower
conditions for this to open up this for
this flower to
this flower to open
conditions for this to open up this for
this flower to open up
this flower to open up it
conditions for this to open up this for
this flower to open up it requires
this flower to open up it requires a
certain
certain temperature
certain temperature certain
certain temperature certain humidity
certain temperature certain humidity uh
certain
certain amount
certain temperature certain humidity uh
certain amount of
certain amount of sunlight
certain temperature certain humidity uh
certain amount of sunlight uh
certain amount of sunlight uh nurturance
and
and as
and as you
and as you see
and as you see it
and as you see it opening
and as you see it opening up
and as you see it opening up but
and as you see it opening up but the
sunlight
sunlight is
and as you see it opening up but the
sunlight is not
sunlight is not causing
and as you see it opening up but the
sunlight is not causing it
sunlight is not causing it to
and as you see it opening up but the
sunlight is not causing it to open
sunlight is not causing it to open the
nurturing
nurturing is
nurturing is not
nurturing is not causing
nurturing is not causing it
nurturing is not causing it to
nurturing is not causing it to open.
Nothing
Nothing is
nurturing is not causing it to open.
Nothing is causing
Nothing is causing it
nurturing is not causing it to open.
Nothing is causing it to
Nothing is causing it to open
because
because everything
because everything fulfills
because everything fulfills its
because everything fulfills its own
potential.
So
So within
So within that
So within that which
So within that which is
So within that which is created,
that
that which
So within that which is created,
that which comes
that which comes into
So within that which is created,
that which comes into existence,
part
part and
part and parcel
part and parcel of
part and parcel of its
part and parcel of its existence
part and parcel of its existence is
part and parcel of its existence is its
innate
innate capacity
to
to manifest
to manifest as
to manifest as that
to manifest as that which
to manifest as that which it
to manifest as that which it is.
to manifest as that which it is. Huh?
So
So it
the
the becoming
the becoming of
the becoming of that
the becoming of that which
comes
comes is
the becoming of that which
comes is witnessed
comes is witnessed as
the becoming of that which
comes is witnessed as existence
comes is witnessed as existence then
the becoming of that which
comes is witnessed as existence then is
merely
merely the
merely the unfolding
merely the unfolding of
merely the unfolding of the
merely the unfolding of the potentiality
of
of that
merely the unfolding of the potentiality
of that as
of that as it
merely the unfolding of the potentiality
of that as it was
of that as it was created.
merely the unfolding of the potentiality
of that as it was created. It's
of that as it was created. It's not
being
being caused
being caused by
being caused by anything
being caused by anything over
being caused by anything over here.
being caused by anything over here. It's
not
not being
being caused by anything over here. It's
not being caused
not being caused by
being caused by anything over here. It's
not being caused by anything
not being caused by anything over
being caused by anything over here. It's
not being caused by anything over there.
Is
Is that
Is that clear?
>> We
>> We have
Is that clear?
>> We have permission
>> We have permission to
Is that clear?
>> We have permission to ask
>> We have permission to ask this
Is that clear?
>> We have permission to ask this in
public.
public. Is
public. Is this
public. Is this this
public. Is this this country
public. Is this this country is
public. Is this this country is over
410?
410? This
public. Is this this country is over
410? This country
410? This country is
public. Is this this country is over
410? This country is over
410? This country is over 420.
public. Is this this country is over
410? This country is over 420. This
country
country is
country is over
country is over 440.
This
This country
country is over 440.
This country is
This country is over
country is over 440.
This country is over 435.
This country is over 435. 438.
Russia
Russia is
Russia is 438.
>> Oh,
>> let's
>> let's do
>> let's do this
>> let's do this leader.
>> let's do this leader. Do
>> let's do this leader. Do we
>> let's do this leader. Do we have
permission
permission to
>> let's do this leader. Do we have
permission to do
permission to do this
>> let's do this leader. Do we have
permission to do this leader
permission to do this leader in
>> let's do this leader. Do we have
permission to do this leader in public?
Resist.
Resist. This
Resist. This leader
Resist. This leader is
Resist. This leader is over
Resist. This leader is over 450.
Resist. This leader is over 450. 455.
450 about
in
in a
in a good
in a good place.
South
South Korea
in a good place.
South Korea is
South Korea is about
in a good place.
South Korea is about 450.
South Korea is about 450. The
civilization
civilization civilization
civilization civilization is
civilization civilization is um
civilized
civilized countries
civilization civilization is um
civilized countries are
civilized countries are in
civilization civilization is um
civilized countries are in the
civilized countries are in the around
civilization civilization is um
civilized countries are in the around in
the
the 400s,
middle
middle 400s.
Uh
Uh communist
Uh communist countries
Uh communist countries are
Uh communist countries are less
Uh communist countries are less are
always
always less
Uh communist countries are less are
always less than
always less than democratic.
Uh communist countries are less are
always less than democratic. So
always less than democratic. So South
Korea
Korea is
Korea is considerably
Korea is considerably higher
Korea is considerably higher than
Korea is considerably higher than North
Korea,
Korea, but
Korea is considerably higher than North
Korea, but they're
Korea, but they're still
Korea is considerably higher than North
Korea, but they're still in
Korea, but they're still in the
Korea is considerably higher than North
Korea, but they're still in the 400s.
Uh
Uh we
Uh we have
Uh we have some
Uh we have some very
Uh we have some very interesting
questions.
questions. Uh
Uh we have some very interesting
questions. Uh things
questions. Uh things I
Uh we have some very interesting
questions. Uh things I was
questions. Uh things I was going
Uh we have some very interesting
questions. Uh things I was going to
questions. Uh things I was going to talk
about
about anyway.
What's
What's this
about anyway.
What's this one
What's this one says?
about anyway.
What's this one says? U
>> oh
>> oh channeling.
>> oh channeling. Yeah.
>> oh channeling. Yeah. Uh
>> oh channeling. Yeah. Uh channeling
>> oh channeling. Yeah. Uh channeling some
people
people uh
>> oh channeling. Yeah. Uh channeling some
people uh in
people uh in new
>> oh channeling. Yeah. Uh channeling some
people uh in new age
people uh in new age communities
channeling
channeling is
channeling is very
channeling is very popular.
channeling is very popular. Uh
uh
uh certain
channeling is very popular. Uh
uh certain prophets
uh certain prophets uh
channeling is very popular. Uh
uh certain prophets uh biblical
uh certain prophets uh biblical prophets
scriptures
scriptures uh
scriptures uh also
scriptures uh also were
scriptures uh also were really
channelers.
channelers. They
scriptures uh also were really
channelers. They they
channelers. They they were
scriptures uh also were really
channelers. They they were channeling
channelers. They they were channeling an
entity
entity on
entity on the
entity on the other
entity on the other side.
entity on the other side. All
entity on the other side. All right.
channeling
channeling is
entity on the other side. All right.
channeling is then
channeling is then a
entity on the other side. All right.
channeling is then a capacity
channeling is then a capacity to
communicate
communicate with
communicate with uh
communicate with uh spiritual
communicate with uh spiritual energies
uh
uh that
communicate with uh spiritual energies
uh that are
uh that are not
communicate with uh spiritual energies
uh that are not within
uh that are not within the
communicate with uh spiritual energies
uh that are not within the physical
domain.
Uh
Uh they're
domain.
Uh they're based
Uh they're based however
domain.
Uh they're based however within
Uh they're based however within duality.
There
There is
There is a
There is a this
There is a this and
There is a this and a
There is a this and a that.
There is a this and a that. There's
There is a this and a that. There's a
There is a this and a that. There's a me
the
the channeler
There is a this and a that. There's a me
the channeler and
the channeler and there's
There is a this and a that. There's a me
the channeler and there's a
the channeler and there's a that
There is a this and a that. There's a me
the channeler and there's a that the
spirit.
spirit. There's
spirit. There's a
spirit. There's a duality
spirit. There's a duality there
spirit. There's a duality there which
already
already sets
spirit. There's a duality there which
already sets a
already sets a limit
spirit. There's a duality there which
already sets a limit on
already sets a limit on the
spirit. There's a duality there which
already sets a limit on the degree
already sets a limit on the degree of
every
every addition
every addition that
every addition that can
every addition that can come
every addition that can come come
through
through that
every addition that can come come
through that way.
through that way. the
every addition that can come come
through that way. the highest
a
a lot
a lot of
a lot of so
a lot of so if
a lot of so if a
a lot of so if a person
a lot of so if a person is
a lot of so if a person is going
a lot of so if a person is going to
dabble
dabble in
a lot of so if a person is going to
dabble in channeling
dabble in channeling I
a lot of so if a person is going to
dabble in channeling I don't
dabble in channeling I don't recommend
channeling
channeling but
channeling but if
channeling but if a
channeling but if a person
channeling but if a person is
channeling but if a person is going
channeling but if a person is going to
dabble
dabble in
channeling but if a person is going to
dabble in channeling
dabble in channeling always
channeling but if a person is going to
dabble in channeling always get
dabble in channeling always get the
calibration
calibration of
calibration of the
calibration of the level
calibration of the level of
calibration of the level of the
calibration of the level of the entity
on
on the
calibration of the level of the entity
on the other
on the other side
calibration of the level of the entity
on the other side and
on the other side and the
calibration of the level of the entity
on the other side and the entity
on the other side and the entity on
calibration of the level of the entity
on the other side and the entity on this
side
because
because the
side
because the lower
because the lower astral
side
because the lower astral is
because the lower astral is a
side
because the lower astral is a great
source
source of
source of channeling
psychics
psychics um
source of channeling
psychics um the
psychics um the lower
source of channeling
psychics um the lower astral
psychics um the lower astral is
source of channeling
psychics um the lower astral is made
psychics um the lower astral is made up
of
of those
of those who
of those who deny
Unite
Unite God.
of those who deny
Unite God. Let's
Unite God. Let's see.
of those who deny
Unite God. Let's see. Let's
Unite God. Let's see. Let's get
of those who deny
Unite God. Let's see. Let's get clear
about
about that.
The
The astral
about that.
The astral is
The astral is a
about that.
The astral is a different
The astral is a different dimension
about that.
The astral is a different dimension than
the
the physical.
The
The lower
the physical.
The lower astral
The lower astral is
the physical.
The lower astral is composed
The lower astral is composed of
the physical.
The lower astral is composed of those
who
who deny
who deny God
who deny God resist.
It's
It's composed
who deny God resist.
It's composed of
It's composed of those
who deny God resist.
It's composed of those who
It's composed of those who refuse
who deny God resist.
It's composed of those who refuse God
resist.
The
The refusal
resist.
The refusal of
The refusal of God
resist.
The refusal of God then.
All right,
All right, let's
All right, let's go.
All right, let's go. That
All right, let's go. That there
All right, let's go. That there is
All right, let's go. That there is there
is
is an
All right, let's go. That there is there
is an upper
is an upper astral
All right, let's go. That there is there
is an upper astral resist
is an upper astral resist that
All right, let's go. That there is there
is an upper astral resist that leads
is an upper astral resist that leads to
the
the celestial
the celestial resist.
Uh
Uh that
the celestial resist.
Uh that leads
Uh that leads to
the celestial resist.
Uh that leads to celestial
Uh that leads to celestial domains.
Resist.
Resist. The
Resist. The celestial
Resist. The celestial domain
Resist. The celestial domain is
different
different than
Resist. The celestial domain is
different than the
different than the heaven
Resist. The celestial domain is
different than the heaven of
different than the heaven of Jesus
Christ.
Christ. Resist.
Yeah,
Yeah, there
Christ. Resist.
Yeah, there are
Yeah, there are different
Christ. Resist.
Yeah, there are different dimensions.
The
The astral
The astral is
The astral is one
The astral is one of
The astral is one of them.
The astral is one of them. All
The astral is one of them. All right.
There's
There's higher
The astral is one of them. All right.
There's higher astrals
There's higher astrals who
The astral is one of them. All right.
There's higher astrals who if
There's higher astrals who if you
calibrate
calibrate them
calibrate them come
calibrate them come across
calibrate them come across very
calibrate them come across very high.
They
They are
calibrate them come across very high.
They are telling
They are telling you
calibrate them come across very high.
They are telling you certain
They are telling you certain truths.
Um,
so
so in
Um,
so in a
so in a channeling
Um,
so in a channeling there's
so in a channeling there's a
Um,
so in a channeling there's a this
so in a channeling there's a this and
Um,
so in a channeling there's a this and a
that.
that. There's
that. There's a
that. There's a me
that. There's a me and
that. There's a me and a
that. There's a me and a you.
that. There's a me and a you. There's
that. There's a me and a you. There's an
entity
entity there
that. There's a me and a you. There's an
entity there and
entity there and a
that. There's a me and a you. There's an
entity there and a and
entity there and a and something
that. There's a me and a you. There's an
entity there and a and something here.
That's
That's different
That's different than
That's different than the
That's different than the way
That's different than the way to
enlightenment
enlightenment because
That's different than the way to
enlightenment because light
enlightenment
enlightenment is
enlightenment is merely
the
the progressive
enlightenment is merely
the progressive awareness
the progressive awareness of
enlightenment is merely
the progressive awareness of the
the progressive awareness of the source
of
of one's
of one's existence
of one's existence which
of one's existence which is
of one's existence which is neither
of one's existence which is neither here
nor
nor there
of one's existence which is neither here
nor there and
nor there and has
of one's existence which is neither here
nor there and has no
positionalities.
It
It has
positionalities.
It has no
It has no personalities.
It
It has
It has no
It has no um
either
either orness.
So
So you're
So you're either
So you're either the
So you're either the channeler
So you're either the channeler or
So you're either the channeler or the
source
source etc.
So you're either the channeler or the
source etc. There's
source etc. There's no
So you're either the channeler or the
source etc. There's no either
source etc. There's no either orness
because
because that
because that which
because that which prevails
because that which prevails within
because that which prevails within all
is
is identical
because that which prevails within all
is identical within
is identical within within
because that which prevails within all
is identical within within all.
is identical within within all. I
because that which prevails within all
is identical within within all. I can't
explain
explain it
explain it other
explain it other than
explain it other than that.
Uh
Uh all
explain it other than that.
Uh all those
Uh all those sort
explain it other than that.
Uh all those sort of
Uh all those sort of new
explain it other than that.
Uh all those sort of new age
Uh all those sort of new age things
always
always calibrate
always calibrate the
always calibrate the level
always calibrate the level of
always calibrate the level of truth
first
first before
always calibrate the level of truth
first before you
first before you get
always calibrate the level of truth
first before you get involved
first before you get involved with
always calibrate the level of truth
first before you get involved with them
because
because a
because a lot
because a lot of
because a lot of them
because a lot of them are
because a lot of them are quite
intriguing.
intriguing. And
because a lot of them are quite
intriguing. And the
intriguing. And the lower
because a lot of them are quite
intriguing. And the lower astral
that
that which
that which denies
that which denies God
that which denies God is
that which denies God is in
that which denies God is in competition
with
with that
that which denies God is in competition
with that which
with that which affirms
that which denies God is in competition
with that which affirms God
with that which affirms God and
that which denies God is in competition
with that which affirms God and is
with that which affirms God and is in
competition
competition for
competition for dominion
competition for dominion of
competition for dominion of this
competition for dominion of this planet.
That's
That's a
competition for dominion of this planet.
That's a thesis
That's a thesis I'm
competition for dominion of this planet.
That's a thesis I'm working
That's a thesis I'm working out
competition for dominion of this planet.
That's a thesis I'm working out in
That's a thesis I'm working out in the
book's
book's eye.
There's
There's competition.
As
As you
As you remember
As you remember in
As you remember in power
As you remember in power versus
As you remember in power versus force,
the
the level
As you remember in power versus force,
the level of
the level of consciousness
As you remember in power versus force,
the level of consciousness of
the level of consciousness of mankind
was
at
at 190
was
at 190 for
at 190 for many
was
at 190 for many many
at 190 for many many centuries.
Mankind
Mankind never
Mankind never got
Mankind never got over
Mankind never got over beginning
Mankind never got over beginning with
Neanderthal
Neanderthal man
Mankind never got over beginning with
Neanderthal man who
Neanderthal man who calibrate
Mankind never got over beginning with
Neanderthal man who calibrate rates
around
around 70.
around 70. Chromagnon
around 70. Chromagnon man
around 70. Chromagnon man also
calibrates
calibrates only
around 70. Chromagnon man also
calibrates only about
calibrates only about 70.
around 70. Chromagnon man also
calibrates only about 70. It's
calibrates only about 70. It's only
around 70. Chromagnon man also
calibrates only about 70. It's only very
recent
recent that
recent that homo
recent that homo sapiion
recent that homo sapiion even
recent that homo sapiion even appeared
and
and homo
recent that homo sapiion even appeared
and homo homo
and homo homo sapien
recent that homo sapiion even appeared
and homo homo sapien was
and homo homo sapien was also
recent that homo sapiion even appeared
and homo homo sapien was also denomin
dominated
dominated by
dominated by the
dominated by the lower
dominated by the lower astral
dominated by the lower astral realm.
Uh
Uh and
dominated by the lower astral realm.
Uh and it
Uh and it was
dominated by the lower astral realm.
Uh and it was only
Uh and it was only in
dominated by the lower astral realm.
Uh and it was only in the
Uh and it was only in the late
dominated by the lower astral realm.
Uh and it was only in the late 80s
Uh and it was only in the late 80s that
the
the consciousness
the consciousness level
the consciousness level of
the consciousness level of mankind
the consciousness level of mankind went
over
over 200.
It's
It's as
It's as though
It's as though the
It's as though the lower
It's as though the lower astral
held
held dominion
It's as though the lower astral
held dominion over
held dominion over this
It's as though the lower astral
held dominion over this globe
held dominion over this globe and
It's as though the lower astral
held dominion over this globe and the
spiritual
spiritual energy
spiritual energy came
spiritual energy came in
spiritual energy came in and
spiritual energy came in and another
life
life came
spiritual energy came in and another
life came up
life came up through
spiritual energy came in and another
life came up through the
life came up through the lambs
spiritual energy came in and another
life came up through the lambs and
life came up through the lambs and the
herbivores
uh
uh and
herbivores
uh and reached
uh and reached full
herbivores
uh and reached full manifestation
through
through mother
through mother maternal
through mother maternal love.
And
And it's
through mother maternal love.
And it's as
And it's as though
the
the lower
the lower astral
the lower astral held
the lower astral held dominion
the lower astral held dominion over
the lower astral held dominion over this
plane
plane of
the lower astral held dominion over this
plane of this
plane of this planet
the lower astral held dominion over this
plane of this planet until
plane of this planet until the
the lower astral held dominion over this
plane of this planet until the late
'80s.
'80s. Consciousness
'80s. Consciousness level
'80s. Consciousness level then
'80s. Consciousness level then went
'80s. Consciousness level then went over
200.
200. The
'80s. Consciousness level then went over
200. The lower
200. The lower astral
'80s. Consciousness level then went over
200. The lower astral was
200. The lower astral was no
'80s. Consciousness level then went over
200. The lower astral was no longer
200. The lower astral was no longer in
total
total control.
And
And I
total control.
And I always
And I always think
total control.
And I always think of
And I always think of somebody
total control.
And I always think of somebody like
And I always think of somebody like Bin
Laden
Laden being
Laden being sort
Laden being sort of
Laden being sort of a
Laden being sort of a last
Laden being sort of a last gasp.
The
The la
Laden being sort of a last gasp.
The la the
The la the last
Laden being sort of a last gasp.
The la the last few
The la the last few dinosaurs
Laden being sort of a last gasp.
The la the last few dinosaurs going
The la the last few dinosaurs going on
Laden being sort of a last gasp.
The la the last few dinosaurs going on a
mass
mass uh
mass uh binge
mass uh binge to
mass uh binge to try
mass uh binge to try to
mass uh binge to try to regain
mass uh binge to try to regain control
of
of that
mass uh binge to try to regain control
of that which
of that which they
mass uh binge to try to regain control
of that which they they
of that which they they know
mass uh binge to try to regain control
of that which they they know they're
losing
and
and trying
losing
and trying to
and trying to get
losing
and trying to get back
and trying to get back some
losing
and trying to get back some of
and trying to get back some of its
previous
previous followers.
previous followers. Huh.
All right.
All right. That's
previous followers. Huh.
All right. That's uh
All right. That's uh the
previous followers. Huh.
All right. That's uh the story
All right. That's uh the story on
previous followers. Huh.
All right. That's uh the story on uh
channeling
channeling and
channeling and all.
There
There was
channeling and all.
There was a
There was a good
channeling and all.
There was a good question.
There was a good question. What
channeling and all.
There was a good question. What was
that?
Is
Is there
that?
Is there any
Is there any other
that?
Is there any other questions
Is there any other questions on
channeling?
channeling? Huh?
channeling? Huh? Just
channeling? Huh? Just calibrate
channeling? Huh? Just calibrate the
level
level of
channeling? Huh? Just calibrate the
level of that
level of that entity
channeling? Huh? Just calibrate the
level of that entity and
level of that entity and and
channeling? Huh? Just calibrate the
level of that entity and and the
level of that entity and and the person
who's
who's doing
who's doing the
who's doing the channeling.
who's doing the channeling. And
who's doing the channeling. And don't
forget
forget level
who's doing the channeling. And don't
forget level of
forget level of consciousness
who's doing the channeling. And don't
forget level of consciousness is
forget level of consciousness is sent
who's doing the channeling. And don't
forget level of consciousness is sent by
is
is set
is set by
is set by intention.
is set by intention. The
is set by intention. The difficulty
is set by intention. The difficulty with
many
many entities
is set by intention. The difficulty with
many entities on
many entities on the
is set by intention. The difficulty with
many entities on the other
many entities on the other side
is set by intention. The difficulty with
many entities on the other side is
many entities on the other side is what
they
they want
they want is
they want is control
they want is control over
they want is control over humans,
especially
especially lower
they want is control over humans,
especially lower astrals.
especially lower astrals. And
they want is control over humans,
especially lower astrals. And they
especially lower astrals. And they will
tell
tell you
tell you go
tell you go out
tell you go out in
tell you go out in the
tell you go out in the desert
tell you go out in the desert and
tell you go out in the desert and wait
for
for the
tell you go out in the desert and wait
for the UFOs
for the UFOs who
tell you go out in the desert and wait
for the UFOs who will
for the UFOs who will pick
tell you go out in the desert and wait
for the UFOs who will pick you
for the UFOs who will pick you up
tell you go out in the desert and wait
for the UFOs who will pick you up at
midnight.
midnight. Right?
throw
throw all
midnight. Right?
throw all your
throw all your throw
midnight. Right?
throw all your throw away
throw all your throw away all
midnight. Right?
throw all your throw away all your
throw all your throw away all your goods
and
and uh
and uh get
and uh get a
and uh get a camel
and uh get a camel and
and uh get a camel and go
and uh get a camel and go out
and uh get a camel and go out in
and uh get a camel and go out in the
middle
middle of
and uh get a camel and go out in the
middle of the
middle of the desert.
and uh get a camel and go out in the
middle of the desert. Yeah,
middle of the desert. Yeah, right.
and uh get a camel and go out in the
middle of the desert. Yeah, right. Sure.
And
And of
And of course
And of course the
And of course the enemy
And of course the enemy on
And of course the enemy on the
And of course the enemy on the other
side
side things
And of course the enemy on the other
side things with
side things with stupid
And of course the enemy on the other
side things with stupid They
they're
they're so
they're so dumb.
they're so dumb. I
they're so dumb. I mean,
they're so dumb. I mean, you
they're so dumb. I mean, you know,
they're so dumb. I mean, you know, they
really
really get
they're so dumb. I mean, you know, they
really get a
really get a kick
they're so dumb. I mean, you know, they
really get a kick out
really get a kick out of
they're so dumb. I mean, you know, they
really get a kick out of this.
really get a kick out of this. Humans
are
are so
are so stupid,
are so stupid, you
are so stupid, you know.
are so stupid, you know. They
are so stupid, you know. They they're
really
really dumb,
are so stupid, you know. They they're
really dumb, you
really dumb, you know.
>> You
>> You want
>> You want to
>> You want to talk
>> You want to talk a
>> You want to talk a little
>> You want to talk a little bit
>> You want to talk a little bit about
>> You want to talk a little bit about male
female
female energies
>> You want to talk a little bit about male
female energies that
female energies that combine
>> You want to talk a little bit about male
female energies that combine energies?
No,
No, I
No, I don't
No, I don't want
No, I don't want to
No, I don't want to get
No, I don't want to get into
No, I don't want to get into that
No, I don't want to get into that right
now.
now. Uh,
No, I don't want to get into that right
now. Uh, we'll
now. Uh, we'll do
No, I don't want to get into that right
now. Uh, we'll do that
now. Uh, we'll do that in
No, I don't want to get into that right
now. Uh, we'll do that in another
lecture
lecture because
lecture because that's
lecture because that's a
lecture because that's a whole
lecture because that's a whole different
evolution
evolution through
lecture because that's a whole different
evolution through consciousness.
Um,
I
I want
Um,
I want to
I want to handle
Um,
I want to handle some
I want to handle some more
Um,
I want to handle some more general
questions.
questions. First,
questions. First, what
questions. First, what is
questions. First, what is the
questions. First, what is the difference
between
between enlightenment
questions. First, what is the difference
between enlightenment and
between enlightenment and salvation?
That's
That's a
That's a very
That's a very u
That's a very u astute
That's a very u astute question.
That's a very u astute question. And
That's a very u astute question. And I
myself
myself went
That's a very u astute question. And I
myself went through
myself went through conflict.
That's a very u astute question. And I
myself went through conflict. Uh,
myself went through conflict. Uh, would
Jesus
Jesus be
Jesus be my
Jesus be my uh
Jesus be my uh main
Jesus be my uh main guru
Jesus be my uh main guru or
Jesus be my uh main guru or the
Jesus be my uh main guru or the Buddha?
It
It seemed
Jesus be my uh main guru or the Buddha?
It seemed like
It seemed like Jesus
Jesus be my uh main guru or the Buddha?
It seemed like Jesus stood
It seemed like Jesus stood for
Jesus be my uh main guru or the Buddha?
It seemed like Jesus stood for salvation
and
and the
and the Buddhist
and the Buddhist stood
and the Buddhist stood for
enlightenment.
Um
are
are they
Um
are they two
are they two different
Um
are they two different things?
are they two different things? Yes,
Um
are they two different things? Yes, they
are
are in
are in a
are in a way.
are in a way. Jesus
are in a way. Jesus Christ
are in a way. Jesus Christ taught
salvation.
salvation. Although
are in a way. Jesus Christ taught
salvation. Although he
salvation. Although he taught
are in a way. Jesus Christ taught
salvation. Although he taught that
salvation. Although he taught that the
presence
presence of
presence of God
presence of God is
presence of God is within
presence of God is within you,
presence of God is within you, the
mystic
mystic through
presence of God is within you, the
mystic through usually
mystic through usually through
presence of God is within you, the
mystic through usually through the
pathway
pathway of
pathway of the
pathway of the heart
pathway of the heart discovered
pathway of the heart discovered that
God
God being
pathway of the heart discovered that
God being love
God being love is
pathway of the heart discovered that
God being love is innate
God being love is innate within
pathway of the heart discovered that
God being love is innate within you
God being love is innate within you and
but
but generally
but generally what
but generally what Jesus
but generally what Jesus sort
but generally what Jesus sort of
but generally what Jesus sort of agrew
but generally what Jesus sort of agrew a
agrees
agrees with
but generally what Jesus sort of agrew a
agrees with lotus
agrees with lotus land
but generally what Jesus sort of agrew a
agrees with lotus land Buddhism
agrees with lotus land Buddhism the
Buddha
Buddha uh
Buddha uh of
Buddha uh of infinite
Buddha uh of infinite compassion
Buddha uh of infinite compassion those
of
of you
Buddha uh of infinite compassion those
of you who
of you who are
Buddha uh of infinite compassion those
of you who are Buddhists
of you who are Buddhists know
Buddha uh of infinite compassion those
of you who are Buddhists know the
of you who are Buddhists know the name
of
of it
all
all these
of it
all these different
all these different represent
of it
all these different represent ations
all these different represent ations of
Buddha
Buddha have
Buddha have different
Buddha have different names.
Buddha have different names. Anyway,
Buddha have different names. Anyway, the
pure
pure land
Buddha have different names. Anyway, the
pure land Buddhism
pure land Buddhism is
Buddha have different names. Anyway, the
pure land Buddhism is very
pure land Buddhism is very much
Buddha have different names. Anyway, the
pure land Buddhism is very much like
Christianity.
Christianity. It's
Christianity. It's assumed
Christianity. It's assumed that
Christianity. It's assumed that the
Christianity. It's assumed that the ne
negativity
negativity of
Christianity. It's assumed that the ne
negativity of this
negativity of this world
Christianity. It's assumed that the ne
negativity of this world is
negativity of this world is so
Christianity. It's assumed that the ne
negativity of this world is so severe
that
that the
that the chances
that the chances of
that the chances of reaching
enlightenment
enlightenment are
that the chances of reaching
enlightenment are perically
enlightenment are perically zero.
that the chances of reaching
enlightenment are perically zero. It
enlightenment are perically zero. It is
not
not therefore
not therefore a
not therefore a practical
not therefore a practical goal.
If
If you
not therefore a practical goal.
If you realize
If you realize that
not therefore a practical goal.
If you realize that the
If you realize that the consciousness
level
level of
level of mankind
level of mankind was
level of mankind was at
level of mankind was at 190
level of mankind was at 190 until
level of mankind was at 190 until 198
late
late 80s,
it
it means
it means that
it means that you're
it means that you're trying
it means that you're trying to
it means that you're trying to reach
it means that you're trying to reach the
highest
highest state
it means that you're trying to reach the
highest state from
highest state from a
it means that you're trying to reach the
highest state from a severely
highest state from a severely negative
gravity
gravity field.
gravity field. You
gravity field. You might
gravity field. You might say
gravity field. You might say it
gravity field. You might say it was
gravity field. You might say it was not
practical.
practical. And
gravity field. You might say it was not
practical. And certainly
practical. And certainly when
gravity field. You might say it was not
practical. And certainly when you
practical. And certainly when you look
at
at the
at the population
at the population that
at the population that in
at the population that in which
at the population that in which Jesus
taught,
taught, illiterate,
at the population that in which Jesus
taught, illiterate, nomadic,
u
u believing
u believing in
u believing in gods
u believing in gods of
u believing in gods of the
u believing in gods of the word were
sort
sort of
u believing in gods of the word were
sort of demonic.
sort of demonic. If
u believing in gods of the word were
sort of demonic. If you
sort of demonic. If you calibrate
u believing in gods of the word were
sort of demonic. If you calibrate the
gods
gods of
gods of the
gods of the Old
gods of the Old Testament,
gods of the Old Testament, they
gods of the Old Testament, they come
gods of the Old Testament, they come out
about
about 70
gods of the Old Testament, they come out
about 70 or
about 70 or 90,
vengeful,
vengeful, angry,
vain,
vain, egotistical,
vengeful, angry,
vain, egotistical, narcissistic,
primitive
primitive gods,
primitive gods, the
primitive gods, the same
primitive gods, the same as
primitive gods, the same as the
primitive gods, the same as the gods
primitive gods, the same as the gods of
ancient
ancient Rome
primitive gods, the same as the gods of
ancient Rome and
ancient Rome and other
primitive gods, the same as the gods of
ancient Rome and other primitive
societies,
societies, sort
societies, sort of
societies, sort of demonic
projections
projections out
societies, sort of demonic
projections out of
projections out of the
societies, sort of demonic
projections out of the unconscious.
That's
That's the
That's the god
That's the god that
That's the god that Freud
That's the god that Freud said
That's the god that Freud said had
That's the god that Freud said had no
reality.
uh
uh the
uh the gods
uh the gods of
uh the gods of the
uh the gods of the unconscious
uh the gods of the unconscious are
uh the gods of the unconscious are are
the
the gods
uh the gods of the unconscious are are
the gods of
the gods of the
uh the gods of the unconscious are are
the gods of the Old
the gods of the Old Testament
uh the gods of the unconscious are are
the gods of the Old Testament are
projections
projections from
projections from the
projections from the unconscious.
projections from the unconscious. Freud
said
said therefore
projections from the unconscious. Freud
said therefore then
said therefore then he
projections from the unconscious. Freud
said therefore then he made
said therefore then he made the
projections from the unconscious. Freud
said therefore then he made the mistake.
He
He said
He said therefore
He said therefore God
He said therefore God doesn't
He said therefore God doesn't exist.
What
What he
He said therefore God doesn't exist.
What he should
What he should have
He said therefore God doesn't exist.
What he should have said
What he should have said is
He said therefore God doesn't exist.
What he should have said is the
What he should have said is the negative
gods
gods are
gods are invalid.
And
And he
gods are invalid.
And he didn't.
And he didn't. He
gods are invalid.
And he didn't. He went
And he didn't. He went beyond.
gods are invalid.
And he didn't. He went beyond. He
And he didn't. He went beyond. He said
therefore
therefore God
therefore God doesn't
therefore God doesn't exist.
therefore God doesn't exist. Carl
therefore God doesn't exist. Carl Young
who
who calibrates
therefore God doesn't exist. Carl Young
who calibrates it.
Oh,
Oh, I
Oh, I got
Oh, I got it.
Oh, I got it. Freud
Oh, I got it. Freud calibrated
Oh, I got it. Freud calibrated 499.
Young
Young calibrates
Oh, I got it. Freud calibrated 499.
Young calibrates at
Young calibrates at 520.
Oh, I got it. Freud calibrated 499.
Young calibrates at 520. Young
Young calibrates at 520. Young went
beyond
beyond that.
beyond that. He
beyond that. He didn't
beyond that. He didn't say
beyond that. He didn't say that
beyond that. He didn't say that because
the
the false
beyond that. He didn't say that because
the false gods
the false gods are
beyond that. He didn't say that because
the false gods are false.
the false gods are false. Therefore,
beyond that. He didn't say that because
the false gods are false. Therefore, a
true
true god
true god doesn't
true god doesn't exist.
true god doesn't exist. On
true god doesn't exist. On the
true god doesn't exist. On the other
hand,
hand, Carl
true god doesn't exist. On the other
hand, Carl Young
hand, Carl Young cal
true god doesn't exist. On the other
hand, Carl Young cal affirmed
hand, Carl Young cal affirmed the
true god doesn't exist. On the other
hand, Carl Young cal affirmed the the
validity
validity of
validity of the
validity of the spirit,
validity of the spirit, the
validity of the spirit, the spirit
world.
world. So,
validity of the spirit, the spirit
world. So, Young
world. So, Young crossed
validity of the spirit, the spirit
world. So, Young crossed over
world. So, Young crossed over from
validity of the spirit, the spirit
world. So, Young crossed over from 499,
crossed
crossed that
crossed that great
crossed that great barrier
crossed that great barrier at
crossed that great barrier at 500.
The
The purpose
crossed that great barrier at 500.
The purpose of
The purpose of Christ
crossed that great barrier at 500.
The purpose of Christ then
The purpose of Christ then is
crossed that great barrier at 500.
The purpose of Christ then is the
The purpose of Christ then is the same
as
as Lotus
as Lotus Land
as Lotus Land Buddhism
that
that um
without
without divine
without divine help
without divine help the
without divine help the likelihood
without divine help the likelihood of
getting
getting to
without divine help the likelihood of
getting to heaven
getting to heaven is
without divine help the likelihood of
getting to heaven is slim.
If
If one
If one needs
If one needs the
If one needs the powerful
If one needs the powerful energy,
If one needs the powerful energy, the
great
great avatar
If one needs the powerful energy, the
great avatar at
great avatar at 1,00
If one needs the powerful energy, the
great avatar at 1,00 to
great avatar at 1,00 to merely
If one needs the powerful energy, the
great avatar at 1,00 to merely affirm
that
that that
that that is
that that is your
that that is your teacher
that that is your teacher who
that that is your teacher who will
that that is your teacher who will carry
you
you through.
Uh
and
and we
Uh
and we asked
and we asked this
Uh
and we asked this question
and we asked this question ourself.
Uh
and we asked this question ourself. The
Buddha
Buddha is
Buddha is teaches
Buddha is teaches the
Buddha is teaches the way
Buddha is teaches the way to
enlightenment.
enlightenment. Jesus
Buddha is teaches the way to
enlightenment. Jesus Christ
enlightenment. Jesus Christ teaches
Buddha is teaches the way to
enlightenment. Jesus Christ teaches the
way
way to
way to salvation.
way to salvation. Let's
way to salvation. Let's see
way to salvation. Let's see if
way to salvation. Let's see if that's
correct.
That
That is
That is correct.
That is correct. Is
That is correct. Is it?
That is correct. Is it? That
That is correct. Is it? That is
That is correct. Is it? That is correct.
Is
Is there
That is correct. Is it? That is correct.
Is there another
Is there another question
That is correct. Is it? That is correct.
Is there another question on
Is there another question on this
subject?
Jesus
Jesus Christ
subject?
Jesus Christ teaches
Jesus Christ teaches the
subject?
Jesus Christ teaches the way
Jesus Christ teaches the way of
salvation.
salvation. It
salvation. It is
salvation. It is even
salvation. It is even taught
salvation. It is even taught within
certain
certain schools
salvation. It is even taught within
certain schools of
certain schools of Buddhism
salvation. It is even taught within
certain schools of Buddhism and
certain schools of Buddhism and the
Hindu
Hindu that
Hindu that the
Hindu that the way
Hindu that the way which
Hindu that the way which I
Hindu that the way which I tend
Hindu that the way which I tend to
Hindu that the way which I tend to teach
the
the way
Hindu that the way which I tend to teach
the way through
the way through consciousness
Hindu that the way which I tend to teach
the way through consciousness itself
the way through consciousness itself is
not
not suitable
not suitable because
not suitable because of
not suitable because of the
not suitable because of the extent
not suitable because of the extent of
the
the negativity
not suitable because of the extent of
the negativity of
the negativity of the
not suitable because of the extent of
the negativity of the world
the negativity of the world the
one-pointedness
one-pointedness of
one-pointedness of mind
one-pointedness of mind we'll
one-pointedness of mind we'll get
one-pointedness of mind we'll get into
that
that maybe
one-pointedness of mind we'll get into
that maybe this
that maybe this afternoon
one-pointedness of mind we'll get into
that maybe this afternoon how
that maybe this afternoon how in
one-pointedness of mind we'll get into
that maybe this afternoon how in a
meditative
meditative state
meditative state to
meditative state to absolutely
meditative state to absolutely transcend
the
the ego
meditative state to absolutely transcend
the ego it
the ego it happens
meditative state to absolutely transcend
the ego it happens in
the ego it happens in a
meditative state to absolutely transcend
the ego it happens in a snap
the ego it happens in a snap like
meditative state to absolutely transcend
the ego it happens in a snap like that
um
um suddenly
um suddenly one
um suddenly one is
um suddenly one is the
um suddenly one is the source
um suddenly one is the source out
um suddenly one is the source out which
all
all that
um suddenly one is the source out which
all that it's
all that it's obvious
um suddenly one is the source out which
all that it's obvious when
all that it's obvious when one
um suddenly one is the source out which
all that it's obvious when one is
all that it's obvious when one is the
source
source out
source out of
source out of which
source out of which all
source out of which all of
source out of which all of that
manifests
manifests but
source out of which all of that
manifests but it's
manifests but it's not
source out of which all of that
manifests but it's not obvious
manifests but it's not obvious what
happens.
happens. Uh
happens. Uh the
happens. Uh the Buddha
happens. Uh the Buddha then
happens. Uh the Buddha then taught
happens. Uh the Buddha then taught a
happens. Uh the Buddha then taught a way
which
which is
happens. Uh the Buddha then taught a way
which is suitable
which is suitable for
happens. Uh the Buddha then taught a way
which is suitable for the
which is suitable for the minority.
The
The Buddha
The Buddha said
The Buddha said once
The Buddha said once you
The Buddha said once you hear
The Buddha said once you hear of
enlightenment
enlightenment you
The Buddha said once you hear of
enlightenment you will
enlightenment you will eventually
The Buddha said once you hear of
enlightenment you will eventually reach
it
it because
it because the
it because the spirit
it because the spirit will
it because the spirit will now
it because the spirit will now choose
spiritual
spiritual pathways
it because the spirit will now choose
spiritual pathways lifetime
spiritual pathways lifetime after
lifetime.
The
The Buddha
lifetime.
The Buddha did
The Buddha did not
lifetime.
The Buddha did not say
The Buddha did not say that
lifetime.
The Buddha did not say that by
The Buddha did not say that by arduous
uh
uh spiritual
uh spiritual commitment
uh spiritual commitment you're
uh spiritual commitment you're likely
uh spiritual commitment you're likely to
get
get enlightened
uh spiritual commitment you're likely to
get enlightened in
get enlightened in this
uh spiritual commitment you're likely to
get enlightened in this time
get enlightened in this time although
uh spiritual commitment you're likely to
get enlightened in this time although he
did
did uh
did uh it
did uh it did
did uh it did happen
did uh it did happen as
did uh it did happen as as
did uh it did happen as as such
the
the Buddha
did uh it did happen as as such
the Buddha represents
the Buddha represents more
did uh it did happen as as such
the Buddha represents more what
the Buddha represents more what I
did uh it did happen as as such
the Buddha represents more what I write
about
about them
about them uh
about them uh the
about them uh the realization
about them uh the realization of
about them uh the realization of the
self
self as
about them uh the realization of the
self as the
self as the source
about them uh the realization of the
self as the source of
self as the source of all
about them uh the realization of the
self as the source of all existence
one
one comes
one comes into
one comes into that
one comes into that awareness
one comes into that awareness at
one comes into that awareness at 600
as
as the
one comes into that awareness at 600
as the presence
as the presence of
one comes into that awareness at 600
as the presence of an
as the presence of an infinite
one comes into that awareness at 600
as the presence of an infinite love
as the presence of an infinite love in
the
the 700s
the 700s which
the 700s which is
the 700s which is the
the 700s which is the level
the 700s which is the level of
the 700s which is the level of the
the 700s which is the level of the sage.
One
One realizes
the 700s which is the level of the sage.
One realizes the
One realizes the self
the 700s which is the level of the sage.
One realizes the self as
One realizes the self as divinity
the
the self
the self as
the self as divinity
the self as divinity and
the self as divinity and that
the self as divinity and that there
the self as divinity and that there is
nothing
nothing but
the self as divinity and that there is
nothing but the
nothing but the self
the self as divinity and that there is
nothing but the self and
nothing but the self and that
the self as divinity and that there is
nothing but the self and that the
nothing but the self and that the rest
is
is perceptual
impressions
impressions projected
is perceptual
impressions projected by
impressions projected by the
is perceptual
impressions projected by the mind.
impressions projected by the mind. Huh?
the
the spiritual.
the spiritual. Um,
the spiritual. Um, so
it
it is
the spiritual. Um, so
it is wise
it is wise to
the spiritual. Um, so
it is wise to have
it is wise to have a
the spiritual. Um, so
it is wise to have a savior
it is wise to have a savior and
the spiritual. Um, so
it is wise to have a savior and it
it is wise to have a savior and it is
wise
wise even
wise even if
wise even if you're
wise even if you're beyond
wise even if you're beyond 600
wise even if you're beyond 600 to
wise even if you're beyond 600 to value
the
the great
wise even if you're beyond 600 to value
the great gift
the great gift and
wise even if you're beyond 600 to value
the great gift and the
the great gift and the divinity
wise even if you're beyond 600 to value
the great gift and the divinity of
the great gift and the divinity of the
savior
to
to realize
savior
to realize the
to realize the absolute
savior
to realize the absolute truth
to realize the absolute truth of
savior
to realize the absolute truth of that
which
which you
which you are.
which you are. There
which you are. There is
which you are. There is nothing
which you are. There is nothing to
which you are. There is nothing to save.
There's
There's nothing
which you are. There is nothing to save.
There's nothing to
There's nothing to save.
which you are. There is nothing to save.
There's nothing to save. I
There's nothing to save. I know
which you are. There is nothing to save.
There's nothing to save. I know you
There's nothing to save. I know you need
salvation.
All right.
That's
That's enlightenment
That's enlightenment and
That's enlightenment and salva
That's enlightenment and salva in
salvation.
salvation. Is
That's enlightenment and salva in
salvation. Is that
salvation. Is that sufficient?
Is
Is salvation
Is salvation necessary?
Is salvation necessary? Yeah.
Is salvation necessary? Yeah. Right.
You'd
You'd rather
Is salvation necessary? Yeah. Right.
You'd rather you
You'd rather you better
Is salvation necessary? Yeah. Right.
You'd rather you better be
You'd rather you better be a
Is salvation necessary? Yeah. Right.
You'd rather you better be a cork
You'd rather you better be a cork in
Is salvation necessary? Yeah. Right.
You'd rather you better be a cork in the
sea
sea instead
sea instead of
sea instead of a
sea instead of a lead
sea instead of a lead sinker.
sea instead of a lead sinker. Yeah,
sea instead of a lead sinker. Yeah, it's
very
very good.
Uh
Uh and
Uh and if
Uh and if so,
Uh and if so, what
Uh and if so, what are
Uh and if so, what are you
Uh and if so, what are you being
Uh and if so, what are you being saved
from?
from? Oh,
Uh and if so, what are you being saved
from? Oh, yes.
from? Oh, yes. Okay.
Uh and if so, what are you being saved
from? Oh, yes. Okay. Now
from? Oh, yes. Okay. Now salvation
Uh and if so, what are you being saved
from? Oh, yes. Okay. Now salvation then
has
has to
has to do
has to do with
has to do with uh
has to do with uh the
has to do with uh the level
has to do with uh the level one
has to do with uh the level one reaches
uh
uh as
has to do with uh the level one reaches
uh as you
uh as you leave
has to do with uh the level one reaches
uh as you leave the
uh as you leave the body.
has to do with uh the level one reaches
uh as you leave the body. You
uh as you leave the body. You see
has to do with uh the level one reaches
uh as you leave the body. You see Jesus
says
says those
says those who
says those who hold
says those who hold me
says those who hold me in
says those who hold me in mind
says those who hold me in mind who
says those who hold me in mind who to
whom
whom I
says those who hold me in mind who to
whom I am
whom I am now
says those who hold me in mind who to
whom I am now bound
whom I am now bound by
says those who hold me in mind who to
whom I am now bound by your
whom I am now bound by your commitment
to
to me
to me uh
to me uh I
to me uh I will
to me uh I will provide
to me uh I will provide the
to me uh I will provide the energy
to me uh I will provide the energy you
need
need to
to me uh I will provide the energy you
need to reach
need to reach the
to me uh I will provide the energy you
need to reach the heavenly
need to reach the heavenly realm.
See
See lotus
See lotus land
See lotus land and
See lotus land and Christianity
See lotus land and Christianity are
See lotus land and Christianity are both
very
very practical.
Both
Both also
Both also were
Both also were teaching
Both also were teaching in
Both also were teaching in a
Both also were teaching in a time
Both also were teaching in a time of
great
great ignorance.
Both also were teaching in a time of
great ignorance. Don't
great ignorance. Don't forget
Both also were teaching in a time of
great ignorance. Don't forget the
great ignorance. Don't forget the Buddha
was
was born
was born in
was born in 500
was born in 500 BC.
There
There was
was born in 500 BC.
There was no
There was no printing
was born in 500 BC.
There was no printing press.
There was no printing press. Nobody
was born in 500 BC.
There was no printing press. Nobody was
educated.
educated. Nobody
educated. Nobody could
educated. Nobody could read
educated. Nobody could read or
educated. Nobody could read or write.
The
The the
educated. Nobody could read or write.
The the level
The the level of
educated. Nobody could read or write.
The the level of awareness
The the level of awareness was
educated. Nobody could read or write.
The the level of awareness was probably
like
like the
like the typical
like the typical resident
like the typical resident in
Afghanistan.
Afghanistan. You
like the typical resident in
Afghanistan. You know,
Afghanistan. You know, almost
like the typical resident in
Afghanistan. You know, almost a
primitive
primitive level
primitive level of
primitive level of um
primitive level of um the
primitive level of um the basics
primitive level of um the basics of
primitive level of um the basics of life
and
and no
primitive level of um the basics of life
and no nothing
and no nothing beyond
primitive level of um the basics of life
and no nothing beyond that.
So
So lotus
So lotus land
So lotus land Buddhism
So lotus land Buddhism then
So lotus land Buddhism then is
So lotus land Buddhism then is also
So lotus land Buddhism then is also the
same
same teaching
So lotus land Buddhism then is also the
same teaching that
same teaching that you
So lotus land Buddhism then is also the
same teaching that you of
same teaching that you of your
So lotus land Buddhism then is also the
same teaching that you of your own
same teaching that you of your own are
not
not going
not going likely
not going likely going
not going likely going to
not going likely going to reach
enlightenment
enlightenment in
not going likely going to reach
enlightenment in this
enlightenment in this lifetime
not going likely going to reach
enlightenment in this lifetime because
the
the negativity
the negativity of
the negativity of life
the negativity of life here
the negativity of life here is
the negativity of life here is so
the negativity of life here is so severe
and
and the
the negativity of life here is so severe
and the commitment
and the commitment is
the negativity of life here is so severe
and the commitment is so
and the commitment is so peculiar
the negativity of life here is so severe
and the commitment is so peculiar and
particular
particular that
particular that you
particular that you know
particular that you know one
particular that you know one in
particular that you know one in 10
million
million would
particular that you know one in 10
million would actually
million would actually even
particular that you know one in 10
million would actually even do
million would actually even do that.
particular that you know one in 10
million would actually even do that. And
we'll
we'll go
we'll go into
we'll go into what
we'll go into what the
we'll go into what the techniques
we'll go into what the techniques are
involved
involved to
we'll go into what the techniques are
involved to transcend
involved to transcend the
we'll go into what the techniques are
involved to transcend the ego
involved to transcend the ego and
we'll go into what the techniques are
involved to transcend the ego and you
will
will see
will see that
will see that it's
will see that it's not
will see that it's not going
will see that it's not going to
will see that it's not going to appeal
to
to too
will see that it's not going to appeal
to too many
to too many people
not
not to
not to mention
not to mention the
not to mention the the
not to mention the the burning
not to mention the the burning wire
not to mention the the burning wire is
going
going through
not to mention the the burning wire is
going through your
going through your body
not to mention the the burning wire is
going through your body and
going through your body and good
not to mention the the burning wire is
going through your body and good god.
going through your body and good god. Uh
but
but I'll
but I'll give
but I'll give you
but I'll give you just
but I'll give you just a
but I'll give you just a taste
but I'll give you just a taste of
but I'll give you just a taste of it.
but I'll give you just a taste of it. So
it
it it
but I'll give you just a taste of it. So
it it is
it it is um
but I'll give you just a taste of it. So
it it is um so
it it is um so the
but I'll give you just a taste of it. So
it it is um so the Buddha
it it is um so the Buddha is
but I'll give you just a taste of it. So
it it is um so the Buddha is the
it it is um so the Buddha is the is
but I'll give you just a taste of it. So
it it is um so the Buddha is the is the
way
way for
way for one
way for one who
way for one who don't
way for one who don't forget
way for one who don't forget one
achieves
achieves spiritual
way for one who don't forget one
achieves spiritual merit
achieves spiritual merit by
way for one who don't forget one
achieves spiritual merit by following
the
the teachers
the teachers of
the teachers of the
the teachers of the Buddha.
the teachers of the Buddha. So
the teachers of the Buddha. So the
Buddha
Buddha doesn't
the teachers of the Buddha. So the
Buddha doesn't say
Buddha doesn't say necessarily
the teachers of the Buddha. So the
Buddha doesn't say necessarily you
Buddha doesn't say necessarily you will
reach
reach enlightenment
reach enlightenment by
reach enlightenment by following
reach enlightenment by following the
eight-fold
eight-fold path
reach enlightenment by following the
eight-fold path this
eight-fold path this this
reach enlightenment by following the
eight-fold path this this instant
eight-fold path this this instant but
he's
he's saying
he's saying that
he's saying that that
he's saying that that commitment
he's saying that that commitment will
automatically
automatically guarantee
he's saying that that commitment will
automatically guarantee that
automatically guarantee that each
lifetime
lifetime you
lifetime you are
lifetime you are on.
lifetime you are on. So
lifetime you are on. So once
lifetime you are on. So once you
lifetime you are on. So once you choose
the
the direction
lifetime you are on. So once you choose
the direction of
the direction of the
lifetime you are on. So once you choose
the direction of the light,
the direction of the light, the
lifetime you are on. So once you choose
the direction of the light, the end
the direction of the light, the end is
certain.
certain. And
certain. And I
certain. And I believe
certain. And I believe that
certain. And I believe that that
certain. And I believe that that what
the
the Buddha
said
is
why
why uh
why uh the
why uh the phenomena
why uh the phenomena happened
why uh the phenomena happened within
this
this uh
why uh the phenomena happened within
this uh lifetime.
In
In that
In that lifetime
In that lifetime I
In that lifetime I was
In that lifetime I was a
In that lifetime I was a hinana
Buddhist.
Buddhist. So
In that lifetime I was a hinana
Buddhist. So I'll
Buddhist. So I'll tell
In that lifetime I was a hinana
Buddhist. So I'll tell you
Buddhist. So I'll tell you that
In that lifetime I was a hinana
Buddhist. So I'll tell you that and
Buddhist. So I'll tell you that and then
that's
that's another
that's another story.
that's another story. But
that's another story. But in
that's another story. But in the
previous
previous lifetime,
that's another story. But in the
previous lifetime, I
previous lifetime, I was
that's another story. But in the
previous lifetime, I was a
previous lifetime, I was a Hinyana
Buddhist
Buddhist and
Buddhist and a
Buddhist and a very
Buddhist and a very devout
Buddhist and a very devout one
Buddhist and a very devout one too.
Buddhist and a very devout one too. And
uh
uh there's
Buddhist and a very devout one too. And
uh there's two
uh there's two types
Buddhist and a very devout one too. And
uh there's two types of
uh there's two types of Buddhism
Buddhist and a very devout one too. And
uh there's two types of Buddhism in
general.
general. Mahayana
general. Mahayana Hinana.
general. Mahayana Hinana. Anyway,
general. Mahayana Hinana. Anyway, my
belief
belief system
um
um my
um my belief
um my belief system
um my belief system and
um my belief system and I
um my belief system and I meditated
um my belief system and I meditated for
many
many years
um my belief system and I meditated for
many years uh
many years uh was
um my belief system and I meditated for
many years uh was that
many years uh was that uh
um my belief system and I meditated for
many years uh was that uh the
many years uh was that uh the ultimate
truth
truth was
truth was void.
Yeah,
Yeah, void
truth was void.
Yeah, void is
Yeah, void is a
truth was void.
Yeah, void is a is
Yeah, void is a is a
truth was void.
Yeah, void is a is a very
Yeah, void is a is a very tricky
concept.
void.
void. Uh
concept.
void. Uh as
void. Uh as I
concept.
void. Uh as I told
void. Uh as I told you
concept.
void. Uh as I told you before,
void. Uh as I told you before, there
concept.
void. Uh as I told you before, there is
no
no opposite
no opposite to
no opposite to God.
no opposite to God. There
no opposite to God. There is
no opposite to God. There is no
no opposite to God. There is no such
thing
thing as
no opposite to God. There is no such
thing as nothingness.
But
But there
But there is
But there is a
But there is a variety
But there is a variety of
But there is a variety of Buddhism
But there is a variety of Buddhism which
really
really confuses
But there is a variety of Buddhism which
really confuses void
really confuses void with
But there is a variety of Buddhism which
really confuses void with nothingness.
Nothingness.
Uh
Uh like
Nothingness.
Uh like it
Uh like it like
Nothingness.
Uh like it like as
Uh like it like as though
Nothingness.
Uh like it like as though there
Uh like it like as though there was
Nothingness.
Uh like it like as though there was an
opposite
opposite to
opposite to allness.
opposite to allness. That
opposite to allness. That that's
opposite to allness. That that's a
that's
that's a
opposite to allness. That that's a
that's a duality
that's a duality you
opposite to allness. That that's a
that's a duality you don't
that's a duality you don't have
opposite to allness. That that's a
that's a duality you don't have to
transcend.
transcend. You
transcend. You get
transcend. You get up
transcend. You get up in
transcend. You get up in the
transcend. You get up in the 900s,
right?
uh
uh the
uh the infinite
uh the infinite reality
uh the infinite reality is
uh the infinite reality is allness
versus
versus uh
uh the infinite reality is allness
versus uh nothingness
versus uh nothingness is
uh the infinite reality is allness
versus uh nothingness is comes
versus uh nothingness is comes up
uh the infinite reality is allness
versus uh nothingness is comes up over
900 910
900 910 about
900 910 about 900
900 910 about 900 by
900 910 about 900 by 900
900 910 about 900 by 900 would
900 910 about 900 by 900 would discern
once
once you
900 910 about 900 by 900 would discern
once you pass
once you pass that
all
all right
all right so
all right so many
all right so many of
all right so many of those
all right so many of those schools
all right so many of those schools of
Buddhism
Buddhism were
all right so many of those schools of
Buddhism were below
Buddhism were below 900
all right so many of those schools of
Buddhism were below 900 so
Buddhism were below 900 so they
all right so many of those schools of
Buddhism were below 900 so they confuse
all
all nothingness
all nothingness and
all nothingness and void
I
I was
all nothingness and void
I was very
intensely
intensely devouted
intensely devouted devoted
intensely devouted devoted in
intensely devouted devoted in those
lifetimes
and
and uh
and uh the
and uh the reality
and uh the reality the
and uh the reality the ultimate
and uh the reality the ultimate reality
was
was void.
When
When I
When I went
When I went out
When I went out of
When I went out of body
When I went out of body went
When I went out of body went into
When I went out of body went into the
void,
void, there
When I went out of body went into the
void, there was
void, there was a
When I went out of body went into the
void, there was a number
void, there was a number of
When I went out of body went into the
void, there was a number of lifetimes
where
where there's
where there's no
where there's no connection
where there's no connection between
where there's no connection between the
lifetimes.
lifetimes. There
where there's no connection between the
lifetimes. There was
lifetimes. There was awareness,
where there's no connection between the
lifetimes. There was awareness, blank
awareness,
awareness, blank
awareness, blank awareness
awareness, blank awareness that
awareness, blank awareness that happened
right
right before
awareness, blank awareness that happened
right before this
right before this lifetime.
The
The awareness
The awareness of
The awareness of existence
The awareness of existence came
The awareness of existence came out
The awareness of existence came out of
nothingness.
H
from
from nothingness
H
from nothingness existence.
Well,
Well, then
Well, then it
Well, then it all
Well, then it all solved
Well, then it all solved itself.
Well, then it all solved itself. Each
time
time I
Well, then it all solved itself. Each
time I went
time I went out
Well, then it all solved itself. Each
time I went out of
time I went out of body
in
in that
in that form
in that form of
in that form of Buddhism
in that form of Buddhism where
in that form of Buddhism where the
ultimate
ultimate reality
in that form of Buddhism where the
ultimate reality was
ultimate reality was void,
in that form of Buddhism where the
ultimate reality was void, I
ultimate reality was void, I I
experienced
experienced that
experienced that which
experienced that which my
experienced that which my own
experienced that which my own mind
created
created that
experienced that which my own mind
created that the
created that the ultimate
experienced that which my own mind
created that the ultimate reality
created that the ultimate reality is
void.
void. There
void. There is
void. There is no
void. There is no such
void. There is no such thing
void. There is no such thing as
void. There is no such thing as an
ultimate
ultimate reality
void. There is no such thing as an
ultimate reality of
ultimate reality of void.
But
But after
But after many
But after many lifetimes,
But after many lifetimes, a
But after many lifetimes, a powerful
meditation
meditation upon
But after many lifetimes, a powerful
meditation upon that
meditation upon that truth,
But after many lifetimes, a powerful
meditation upon that truth, I
meditation upon that truth, I created
voidness
voidness as.
And
And today
voidness as.
And today there
And today there are
voidness as.
And today there are mistransations
And today there are mistransations of
the
the teachings
the teachings of
the teachings of the
the teachings of the Buddha.
the teachings of the Buddha. Not
mistransations
mistransations but
the teachings of the Buddha. Not
mistransations but it's
mistransations but it's not
the teachings of the Buddha. Not
mistransations but it's not explained
mistransations but it's not explained in
a
a way
a way that
a way that would
a way that would help
a way that would help you
a way that would help you to
a way that would help you to avoid
a way that would help you to avoid this
error.
My
My own
My own profound
My own profound belief
My own profound belief that
My own profound belief that the
My own profound belief that the ultimate
reality
reality my
My own profound belief that the ultimate
reality my devotion
reality my devotion to
My own profound belief that the ultimate
reality my devotion to Buddha
reality my devotion to Buddha was
My own profound belief that the ultimate
reality my devotion to Buddha was such
that
that I
that I went
that I went into
that I went into nothingness
that I went into nothingness every
that I went into nothingness every time
I
I went
that I went into nothingness every time
I went out
I went out of
that I went into nothingness every time
I went out of body.
I went out of body. Nothing.
However,
However, because
However, because that's
However, because that's not
However, because that's not a
However, because that's not a reality.
You
You can't
However, because that's not a reality.
You can't stay
You can't stay in
However, because that's not a reality.
You can't stay in void
You can't stay in void as
However, because that's not a reality.
You can't stay in void as nothingness
void.
void. You
void. You can't
void. You can't stay
void. You can't stay there.
void. You can't stay there. It's
void. You can't stay there. It's not
void. You can't stay there. It's not a
reality.
Consequently,
Consequently, you
Consequently, you find
Consequently, you find yourself
Consequently, you find yourself back
Consequently, you find yourself back in
another
another body.
Consequently, you find yourself back in
another body. Bang.
It
It was
It was a
It was a sudden
It was a sudden explosion
It was a sudden explosion when
It was a sudden explosion when I
It was a sudden explosion when I hit
back
back this
It was a sudden explosion when I hit
back this body.
back this body. There's
It was a sudden explosion when I hit
back this body. There's a
back this body. There's a little
It was a sudden explosion when I hit
back this body. There's a little wagon
and
and this
and this body
and this body me
and this body me called
and this body me called me
and this body me called me in
and this body me called me in those
and this body me called me in those days
age
age three
and this body me called me in those days
age three or
age three or four
and this body me called me in those days
age three or four sitting
age three or four sitting in
and this body me called me in those days
age three or four sitting in this
age three or four sitting in this wagon
and
and wham.
and wham. Suddenly
sudden
sudden confrontation
and wham. Suddenly
sudden confrontation with
sudden confrontation with existence
and wham. Suddenly
sudden confrontation with existence was
like
like bang
out
out of
like bang
out of nothingness
existence.
existence. It
existence. It was
existence. It was a
existence. It was a terrific
existence. It was a terrific contrast.
All
All right.
existence. It was a terrific contrast.
All right. So
All right. So the
existence. It was a terrific contrast.
All right. So the ultimate
All right. So the ultimate reality
existence. It was a terrific contrast.
All right. So the ultimate reality is
not
not nothingness
but
but allness.
The
The totality,
The totality, the
The totality, the complete
The totality, the complete allincclusive
allness
which
which is
which is no
which is no thing.
which is no thing. No
which is no thing. No thing.
which is no thing. No thing. It
which is no thing. No thing. It is
nothing.
It
It is
It is not
It is not void.
It is not void. It's
It is not void. It's all
all
all right.
You
You know,
You know, the
You know, the Buddha
You know, the Buddha didn't
You know, the Buddha didn't speak
You know, the Buddha didn't speak of
You know, the Buddha didn't speak of God
because
because everybody
You know, the Buddha didn't speak of God
because everybody has
because everybody has belief
You know, the Buddha didn't speak of God
because everybody has belief systems
about
about God.
about God. and
about God. and your
about God. and your belief
about God. and your belief system
about God. and your belief system will
create
create what
about God. and your belief system will
create what you
create what you believe
about God. and your belief system will
create what you believe God
create what you believe God to
about God. and your belief system will
create what you believe God to be
create what you believe God to be and
you'll
you'll be
you'll be pursuing
you'll be pursuing a
you'll be pursuing a projection
you'll be pursuing a projection of
you'll be pursuing a projection of your
own
own imagination
you'll be pursuing a projection of your
own imagination and
own imagination and and
you'll be pursuing a projection of your
own imagination and and ignorance.
own imagination and and ignorance. So
the
the Buddha
the Buddha didn't
the Buddha didn't speak
the Buddha didn't speak of
the Buddha didn't speak of God.
the Buddha didn't speak of God. He
the Buddha didn't speak of God. He said
just
just forget
the Buddha didn't speak of God. He said
just forget about
just forget about that.
the Buddha didn't speak of God. He said
just forget about that. Find
just forget about that. Find the
the Buddha didn't speak of God. He said
just forget about that. Find the source
of
of your
of your own
of your own consciousness.
of your own consciousness. That
of your own consciousness. That is
of your own consciousness. That is the
Buddha
Buddha nature.
of your own consciousness. That is the
Buddha nature. Well,
Buddha nature. Well, unfortunately
called
called it
called it the
called it the Buddha
called it the Buddha nature.
called it the Buddha nature. Uh-uh.
That
That was
called it the Buddha nature. Uh-uh.
That was a
That was a mistake
called it the Buddha nature. Uh-uh.
That was a mistake too.
That was a mistake too. So
called it the Buddha nature. Uh-uh.
That was a mistake too. So you
That was a mistake too. So you call
called it the Buddha nature. Uh-uh.
That was a mistake too. So you call it
void.
void. That's
void. That's nothing.
void. That's nothing. Right?
void. That's nothing. Right? Now
void. That's nothing. Right? Now people
believe
believe that
void. That's nothing. Right? Now people
believe that nothingness
believe that nothingness is
void. That's nothing. Right? Now people
believe that nothingness is a
believe that nothingness is a reality.
And
And if
And if you
And if you really
And if you really pursue
And if you really pursue and
And if you really pursue and become
And if you really pursue and become an
adept,
adept, you're
And if you really pursue and become an
adept, you're going
adept, you're going to
And if you really pursue and become an
adept, you're going to experience
nothingness
nothingness as
nothingness as the
nothingness as the ultimate.
It's
It's very
nothingness as the ultimate.
It's very powerful.
I
I resolved
I resolved that
I resolved that conflict
I resolved that conflict one
I resolved that conflict one time.
I
I was
I resolved that conflict one time.
I was in
I was in the
I resolved that conflict one time.
I was in the conflict
I was in the conflict between
I resolved that conflict one time.
I was in the conflict between Jesus
I was in the conflict between Jesus and
Buddha,
Buddha, the
Buddha, the way
Buddha, the way of
Buddha, the way of the
Buddha, the way of the heart.
Buddha, the way of the heart. And
Buddha, the way of the heart. And I
Buddha, the way of the heart. And I had
a
a teacher
Buddha, the way of the heart. And I had
a teacher who
who
who had
who had fallen
who had fallen from
who had fallen from a
who had fallen from a higher
who had fallen from a higher level.
who had fallen from a higher level. This
is
is something
who had fallen from a higher level. This
is something else
is something else which
who had fallen from a higher level. This
is something else which is
is something else which is a
who had fallen from a higher level. This
is something else which is a uh
is something else which is a uh a
who had fallen from a higher level. This
is something else which is a uh a thing
we'll
we'll have
we'll have to
we'll have to talk
we'll have to talk about.
we'll have to talk about. There
we'll have to talk about. There are
teachers
teachers who
we'll have to talk about. There are
teachers who when
teachers who when they
we'll have to talk about. There are
teachers who when they were
teachers who when they were teaching
we'll have to talk about. There are
teachers who when they were teaching and
at
at the
at the high
at the high were
at the high were calibrated
at the high were calibrated high
at the high were calibrated high 500s,
but
but you
at the high were calibrated high 500s,
but you calibrate
but you calibrate them
at the high were calibrated high 500s,
but you calibrate them now
but you calibrate them now and
at the high were calibrated high 500s,
but you calibrate them now and they're
in
in the
in the 200s.
in the 200s. Quite
in the 200s. Quite a
in the 200s. Quite a few
in the 200s. Quite a few of
in the 200s. Quite a few of them
in the 200s. Quite a few of them and
they're
they're all
in the 200s. Quite a few of them and
they're all very
they're all very famous.
Um
Um what
Um what was
Um what was I
Um what was I saying?
>> Conflict
>> Conflict with
Um what was I saying?
>> Conflict with Jesus.
>> Oh
>> Oh yeah,
>> Oh yeah, Jesus
>> Oh yeah, Jesus and
>> Oh yeah, Jesus and Buddha.
>> Oh yeah, Jesus and Buddha. Um
>> Oh yeah, Jesus and Buddha. Um so
>> Oh yeah, Jesus and Buddha. Um so it
>> Oh yeah, Jesus and Buddha. Um so it was
a
a conflict.
>> Oh yeah, Jesus and Buddha. Um so it was
a conflict. I
a conflict. I had
>> Oh yeah, Jesus and Buddha. Um so it was
a conflict. I had a
a conflict. I had a teacher
>> Oh yeah, Jesus and Buddha. Um so it was
a conflict. I had a teacher who
a conflict. I had a teacher who had
>> Oh yeah, Jesus and Buddha. Um so it was
a conflict. I had a teacher who had at
one
one time
one time been
one time been in
one time been in a
one time been in a very
one time been in a very high
one time been in a very high state.
one time been in a very high state. I
had
had not
one time been in a very high state. I
had not realized
had not realized was
one time been in a very high state. I
had not realized was not
had not realized was not in
one time been in a very high state. I
had not realized was not in such
had not realized was not in such a
one time been in a very high state. I
had not realized was not in such a high
state
state anymore.
state anymore. Anyway,
state anymore. Anyway, he
state anymore. Anyway, he took
state anymore. Anyway, he took all
state anymore. Anyway, he took all the
attributes
attributes of
state anymore. Anyway, he took all the
attributes of God
attributes of God such
state anymore. Anyway, he took all the
attributes of God such as
attributes of God such as love,
state anymore. Anyway, he took all the
attributes of God such as love, beauty,
etc.
etc. and
etc. and said
etc. and said those
etc. and said those are
etc. and said those are all
etc. and said those are all attachments
you
you should
etc. and said those are all attachments
you should release
you should release on
etc. and said those are all attachments
you should release on those
you should release on those attachments.
Okay?
Okay? Those
Okay? Those are
Okay? Those are all
Okay? Those are all the
Okay? Those are all the attributes
Okay? Those are all the attributes of
God.
God. Right?
Anyway,
Anyway, that
Anyway, that came
Anyway, that came out
Anyway, that came out of
Anyway, that came out of that
Anyway, that came out of that same
Buddhist
Buddhist uh
Anyway, that came out of that same
Buddhist uh tradition.
Love
Love and
Love and the
Love and the attachment
Love and the attachment to
Love and the attachment to love
Love and the attachment to love are
Love and the attachment to love are two
different
different things.
Love and the attachment to love are two
different things. I
different things. I didn't
Love and the attachment to love are two
different things. I didn't realize
different things. I didn't realize that.
But
But anyway,
But anyway, at
But anyway, at the
But anyway, at the time
But anyway, at the time I
But anyway, at the time I said,
But anyway, at the time I said, "Yes,
love
love is
But anyway, at the time I said, "Yes,
love is an
love is an attachment."
But anyway, at the time I said, "Yes,
love is an attachment." He's
love is an attachment." He's telling
But anyway, at the time I said, "Yes,
love is an attachment." He's telling me,
"Let
"Let go
"Let go on
"Let go on beauty,
"Let go on beauty, love,
"Let go on beauty, love, all
"Let go on beauty, love, all that
stuff."
He's
He's looking
He's looking on
He's looking on it
He's looking on it down
He's looking on it down on
He's looking on it down on as
He's looking on it down on as an
attachment.
attachment. I
He's looking on it down on as an
attachment. I was
attachment. I was in
He's looking on it down on as an
attachment. I was in conflict
attachment. I was in conflict between
Jesus
Jesus and
Jesus and Buddha.
Jesus and Buddha. So,
Jesus and Buddha. So, I
Jesus and Buddha. So, I had
Jesus and Buddha. So, I had the
misunderstanding
misunderstanding of
Jesus and Buddha. So, I had the
misunderstanding of Buddha
misunderstanding of Buddha as
representing
representing the
representing the ultimate
representing the ultimate reality
representing the ultimate reality is
void
void and
representing the ultimate reality is
void and looking
void and looking at
representing the ultimate reality is
void and looking at Jesus
void and looking at Jesus as
love
love um
love um as
love um as an
love um as an attachment.
love um as an attachment. Huh.
I
I was
love um as an attachment. Huh.
I was in
I was in quite
love um as an attachment. Huh.
I was in quite a
I was in quite a conflict
love um as an attachment. Huh.
I was in quite a conflict about
I was in quite a conflict about it.
love um as an attachment. Huh.
I was in quite a conflict about it. Then
finally
finally I
finally I said
finally I said no
finally I said no Buddha
finally I said no Buddha is
finally I said no Buddha is higher
finally I said no Buddha is higher than
Jesus.
Jesus. Love
finally I said no Buddha is higher than
Jesus. Love is
Jesus. Love is attachment.
And
And I
And I started
And I started releasing
And I started releasing on
And I started releasing on love.
I
I went
And I started releasing on love.
I went into
I went into the
And I started releasing on love.
I went into the infinite
I went into the infinite void.
This
This time
This time not
This time not unconsciously
consciously
consciously went
This time not unconsciously
consciously went into
consciously went into the
This time not unconsciously
consciously went into the void.
consciously went into the void. And
This time not unconsciously
consciously went into the void. And I'll
tell
tell you
tell you the
tell you the void
tell you the void is
tell you the void is very
tell you the void is very very
impressive.
impressive. It
tell you the void is very very
impressive. It is
impressive. It is very
tell you the void is very very
impressive. It is very impressive.
It
It is
It is a
It is a dimension
that
that is
It is a dimension
that is beyond
that is beyond some
It is a dimension
that is beyond some puny
that is beyond some puny little
It is a dimension
that is beyond some puny little eagle.
Let
Let me
Let me tell
Let me tell you
Let me tell you the
Let me tell you the absolute
experience
experience of
Let me tell you the absolute
experience of nothingness.
experience of nothingness. Infinite
nothingness.
There
There was
nothingness.
There was one
There was one thought
nothingness.
There was one thought left.
In
In it
In it all
In it all reality
In it all reality is
In it all reality is revealed.
In it all reality is revealed. You
In it all reality is revealed. You see
everything
everything moving
In it all reality is revealed. You see
everything moving of
everything moving of its
In it all reality is revealed. You see
everything moving of its own
everything moving of its own nature
within
within the
within the infinite
within the infinite field
of
of the
within the infinite field
of the infinite
of the infinite reality.
So
So it
So it does
So it does reveal
reality
reality starkly.
But
But there
But there was
But there was something
But there was something wrong.
Some
Some innate
But there was something wrong.
Some innate spiritual
Some innate spiritual intuition
But there was something wrong.
Some innate spiritual intuition of
Some innate spiritual intuition of its
own
own realized
own realized there
own realized there was
own realized there was an
own realized there was an error.
own realized there was an error. It
didn't
didn't speak.
own realized there was an error. It
didn't speak. It
didn't speak. It was
own realized there was an error. It
didn't speak. It was just
didn't speak. It was just annoyingness.
And
And um
to
to let
And um
to let go
to let go of
And um
to let go of that
to let go of that one
And um
to let go of that one thought
to let go of that one thought would
And um
to let go of that one thought would be
like
like a
like a spaceship
like a spaceship takes
like a spaceship takes you
like a spaceship takes you out
like a spaceship takes you out into
infinite
infinite unmapped
like a spaceship takes you out into
infinite unmapped space
infinite unmapped space lets
like a spaceship takes you out into
infinite unmapped space lets you
infinite unmapped space lets you out
destroys
destroys all
destroys all map
destroys all map of
destroys all map of where
destroys all map of where they
destroys all map of where they were
destroys all map of where they were and
returns
returns to
destroys all map of where they were and
returns to it
returns to it space.
destroys all map of where they were and
returns to it space. There's
returns to it space. There's no
destroys all map of where they were and
returns to it space. There's no record
of
of your
of your even
of your even existence
of your even existence much
of your even existence much less
of your even existence much less where
there's
there's no
of your even existence much less where
there's no way
there's no way to
of your even existence much less where
there's no way to return.
there's no way to return. I
of your even existence much less where
there's no way to return. I realized
there's no way to return. I realized let
go
go of
go of that
go of that love.
go of that love. So
go of that love. So I
go of that love. So I it
go of that love. So I it took
go of that love. So I it took enormous
enor
enor enormous
go of that love. So I it took enormous
enor enormous energy,
enor enormous energy, enormous
go of that love. So I it took enormous
enor enormous energy, enormous power,
all
all the
all the power
all the power I
all the power I could
all the power I could summon
uh
uh to
all the power I could summon
uh to reinforce
uh to reinforce that
all the power I could summon
uh to reinforce that thought
uh to reinforce that thought and
all the power I could summon
uh to reinforce that thought and come
back
back out
back out of
back out of the
back out of the infinite
back out of the infinite space
back out of the infinite space of
back out of the infinite space of the
void.
void. But
back out of the infinite space of the
void. But that
void. But that time
back out of the infinite space of the
void. But that time it
void. But that time it was
back out of the infinite space of the
void. But that time it was a
void. But that time it was a conscious
experience.
A
A less
experience.
A less sophisticated
A less sophisticated or
experience.
A less sophisticated or less
A less sophisticated or less lucky
person
person would
person would be
person would be convinced
person would be convinced that
person would be convinced that that
person would be convinced that that is
the
the ultimate
person would be convinced that that is
the ultimate reality
the ultimate reality and
person would be convinced that that is
the ultimate reality and let
the ultimate reality and let go
person would be convinced that that is
the ultimate reality and let go of
the ultimate reality and let go of the
last
last thought
and
become
become as
become as nothingness
which
which is
become as nothingness
which is a
which is a paradox
become as nothingness
which is a paradox in
which is a paradox in itself
become as nothingness
which is a paradox in itself because
there's
there's nothing
there's nothing that
there's nothing that can
there's nothing that can become
nothingness.
But
But that
But that experience
But that experience of
But that experience of nothingness
But that experience of nothingness could
probably
probably you
But that experience of nothingness could
probably you could
probably you could probably
But that experience of nothingness could
probably you could probably hang
probably you could probably hang out
there
there quite
there quite a
there quite a few
there quite a few eons
there quite a few eons before
there quite a few eons before you
discovered
discovered the
there quite a few eons before you
discovered the error.
So
So what
So what was
So what was the
So what was the intuitive
So what was the intuitive knowingness
coming
coming out
So what was the intuitive knowingness
coming out of?
coming out of? It
So what was the intuitive knowingness
coming out of? It was
coming out of? It was the
So what was the intuitive knowingness
coming out of? It was the intuitive
knowingness
knowingness that
knowingness that the
knowingness that the infinite
knowingness that the infinite reality
knowingness that the infinite reality is
the
the quintessence
knowingness that the infinite reality is
the quintessence of
the quintessence of love
knowingness that the infinite reality is
the quintessence of love that
the quintessence of love that it
knowingness that the infinite reality is
the quintessence of love that it was
the quintessence of love that it was the
absence
absence of
absence of love
absence of love in
absence of love in that
absence of love in that space.
absence of love in that space. That
absence of love in that space. That was
the
the warning
absence of love in that space. That was
the warning that
the warning that signaled
absence of love in that space. That was
the warning that signaled that
the warning that signaled that it
absence of love in that space. That was
the warning that signaled that it was
not
not the
not the perfect
not the perfect space,
not the perfect space, not
not the perfect space, not the
not the perfect space, not the ultimate
reality.
as
as a
as a paper
as a paper boy
as a paper boy when
as a paper boy when I
as a paper boy when I had
as a paper boy when I had all
as a paper boy when I had all I
as a paper boy when I had all I was
frozen
frozen to
as a paper boy when I had all I was
frozen to death
frozen to death you
as a paper boy when I had all I was
frozen to death you know
frozen to death you know I
as a paper boy when I had all I was
frozen to death you know I went
frozen to death you know I went into
as a paper boy when I had all I was
frozen to death you know I went into a
divine
divine space
divine space and
divine space and the
divine space and the most
divine space and the most profound
divine space and the most profound thing
of
of it
divine space and the most profound thing
of it beyond
of it beyond all
divine space and the most profound thing
of it beyond all time
of it beyond all time beyond
divine space and the most profound thing
of it beyond all time beyond all
of it beyond all time beyond all you
realize
that
that that
realize
that that you
that that you always
realize
that that you always existed
that that you always existed before
realize
that that you always existed before all
universes
universes I
universes I am
universes I am and
universes I am and after
universes I am and after all
universes I am and after all universes
have
have gone
universes I am and after all universes
have gone I
have gone I will
universes I am and after all universes
have gone I will still
have gone I will still prevail
universes I am and after all universes
have gone I will still prevail that's
for
for sure
universes
universes are
for sure
universes are just
universes are just nothing
for sure
universes are just nothing you
universes are just nothing you know
for sure
universes are just nothing you know that
in
in that
in that space
in that space but
in that space but the
in that space but the most
in that space but the most profound
thing
thing is
in that space but the most profound
thing is like
thing is like an
in that space but the most profound
thing is like an enormous
thing is like an enormous love
in that space but the most profound
thing is like an enormous love of
thing is like an enormous love of such
in that space but the most profound
thing is like an enormous love of such a
quality
quality that
quality that there
quality that there is
quality that there is no
quality that there is no ever
quality that there is no ever mistaking
it
it for
quality that there is no ever mistaking
it for anything
it for anything else
quality that there is no ever mistaking
it for anything else again
it for anything else again and
quality that there is no ever mistaking
it for anything else again and that
it for anything else again and that the
vibration
vibration of
vibration of that
vibration of that love
vibration of that love was
vibration of that love was absent
vibration of that love was absent in
that
that infinite
vibration of that love was absent in
that infinite void.
that infinite void. So
vibration of that love was absent in
that infinite void. So that
that infinite void. So that sort
vibration of that love was absent in
that infinite void. So that sort of
answers
answers the
answers the difference
answers the difference between
answers the difference between salvation
and
and enlightenment.
The
The infinite
The infinite reality
The infinite reality as
The infinite reality as allness
The infinite reality as allness rather
than
than voidness.
The
The void
The void means
The void means void
The void means void of
The void means void of all
The void means void of all form.
The void means void of all form. Void
The void means void of all form. Void of
all
all form
The void means void of all form. Void of
all form because
all form because that
The void means void of all form. Void of
all form because that which
all form because that which you
The void means void of all form. Void of
all form because that which you are
all form because that which you are is
void
void of
void of all
void of all form.
void of all form. There
void of all form. There that
void of all form. There that is
void of all form. There that is correct.
So
So there's
void of all form. There that is correct.
So there's a
So there's a couple
void of all form. There that is correct.
So there's a couple of
So there's a couple of little
misunderstandings
misunderstandings of
misunderstandings of Buddhism
misunderstandings of Buddhism is
important
important to
misunderstandings of Buddhism is
important to understand.
important to understand. The
misunderstandings of Buddhism is
important to understand. The ultimate
void
void means
void means void
void means void of
void means void of dimension.
void means void of dimension. It
void means void of dimension. It means
it's
it's nondualistic
because
because it
because it is
because it is no
because it is no thing.
because it is no thing. It
because it is no thing. It can
because it is no thing. It can that's
why
why it
because it is no thing. It can that's
why it is
why it is all
because it is no thing. It can that's
why it is all all
to
to be
to be all.
to be all. You
to be all. You can
to be all. You can be
to be all. You can be no
to be all. You can be no thing.
to be all. You can be no thing. Nothing.
No
No thing.
to be all. You can be no thing. Nothing.
No thing. Void
No thing. Void of
to be all. You can be no thing. Nothing.
No thing. Void of all
No thing. Void of all form.
to be all. You can be no thing. Nothing.
No thing. Void of all form. Void
No thing. Void of all form. Void of
to be all. You can be no thing. Nothing.
No thing. Void of all form. Void of all
qualities.
qualities. Void
qualities. Void of
qualities. Void of all
qualities. Void of all conditions.
qualities. Void of all conditions. void
of
of all
qualities. Void of all conditions. void
of all descriptions.
That's
That's why
That's why it's
That's why it's all
That's why it's all that
That's why it's all that is
to
to be
That's why it's all that is
to be everywhere.
to be everywhere. You
That's why it's all that is
to be everywhere. You cannot
to be everywhere. You cannot be
That's why it's all that is
to be everywhere. You cannot be any
particular
particular place
particular place because
particular place because if
particular place because if you're
particular place because if you're any
particular
particular place,
particular place because if you're any
particular place, you
particular place, you can't
particular place because if you're any
particular place, you can't be
everywhere.
everywhere. So
everywhere. So that's
everywhere. So that's my
everywhere. So that's my uh
understanding
understanding of
everywhere. So that's my uh
understanding of we'll
understanding of we'll ask
everywhere. So that's my uh
understanding of we'll ask the
understanding of we'll ask the Buddha
everywhere. So that's my uh
understanding of we'll ask the Buddha if
that's
that's right.
that's right. Buddha,
that
that explanation
that's right. Buddha,
that explanation is
that explanation is correct.
that's right. Buddha,
that explanation is correct. Is
that explanation is correct. Is it?
Thank
Thank you.
Oh
Oh dear.
Thank you.
Oh dear. All
Oh dear. All right.
Thank you.
Oh dear. All right. So,
Oh dear. All right. So, movement
Thank you.
Oh dear. All right. So, movement up
Oh dear. All right. So, movement up the
scale
scale then,
scale then, cuz
scale then, cuz we
scale then, cuz we only
scale then, cuz we only got
scale then, cuz we only got a
scale then, cuz we only got a couple
minutes.
minutes. Um,
scale then, cuz we only got a couple
minutes. Um, how
minutes. Um, how does
scale then, cuz we only got a couple
minutes. Um, how does one
minutes. Um, how does one move
scale then, cuz we only got a couple
minutes. Um, how does one move up
minutes. Um, how does one move up the
scale?
scale? You
scale? You do
scale? You do it
scale? You do it by
scale? You do it by choice,
scale? You do it by choice, by
commitment,
commitment, by
scale? You do it by choice, by
commitment, by attraction.
commitment, by attraction. It's
scale? You do it by choice, by
commitment, by attraction. It's merely
commitment, by attraction. It's merely a
matter
matter of
matter of you
matter of you choose
matter of you choose the
matter of you choose the light
matter of you choose the light rather
than
than the
matter of you choose the light rather
than the darkness.
than the darkness. That's
matter of you choose the light rather
than the darkness. That's all
than the darkness. That's all it
matter of you choose the light rather
than the darkness. That's all it is.
than the darkness. That's all it is. You
choose
choose light
choose light over
choose light over darkness.
Um,
you
you cho
you cho you
you cho you choose
you cho you choose light
you cho you choose light over
you cho you choose light over darkness.
And
And even
you cho you choose light over darkness.
And even if
And even if you
you cho you choose light over darkness.
And even if you choose
And even if you choose light
you cho you choose light over darkness.
And even if you choose light over
darkness,
darkness, you
darkness, you can
darkness, you can still
darkness, you can still make
darkness, you can still make great
mistakes
mistakes and
darkness, you can still make great
mistakes and it
mistakes and it won't
darkness, you can still make great
mistakes and it won't make
mistakes and it won't make I
darkness, you can still make great
mistakes and it won't make I made
mistakes and it won't make I made a
darkness, you can still make great
mistakes and it won't make I made a I
remember
remember a
remember a mistake.
remember a mistake. You
remember a mistake. You can
remember a mistake. You can make
remember a mistake. You can make great
mistakes.
mistakes. See,
remember a mistake. You can make great
mistakes. See, because
mistakes. See, because the
remember a mistake. You can make great
mistakes. See, because the calibrated
level
level is
level is intention.
One
One time
level is intention.
One time I
One time I was
level is intention.
One time I was in
One time I was in a
level is intention.
One time I was in a war,
a
a battlefield
a battlefield war.
a battlefield war. This
a battlefield war. This was
a battlefield war. This was with
a battlefield war. This was with spears.
And
And uh
I
I killed
I killed the
I killed the I
I killed the I I
I killed the I I I
I killed the I I I skewered
I killed the I I I skewered the
I killed the I I I skewered the enemy
right
right in
I killed the I I I skewered the enemy
right in the
right in the groin.
And
And uh
but
but I
And uh
but I couldn't
but I couldn't bring
And uh
but I couldn't bring my
but I couldn't bring my I
And uh
but I couldn't bring my I lacked
but I couldn't bring my I lacked the
courage
courage to
courage to kill
courage to kill him.
Um
I
I couldn't
I couldn't bring
I couldn't bring myself
I couldn't bring myself to
I couldn't bring myself to kill
I couldn't bring myself to kill him.
I couldn't bring myself to kill him. So
he
he was
I couldn't bring myself to kill him. So
he was left
he was left to
I couldn't bring myself to kill him. So
he was left to die
he was left to die of
I couldn't bring myself to kill him. So
he was left to die of his
he was left to die of his wounds.
Horrible.
Came
Came back
Horrible.
Came back in
Came back in this
Horrible.
Came back in this lifetime.
Came back in this lifetime. I
Horrible.
Came back in this lifetime. I had
Came back in this lifetime. I had two
Horrible.
Came back in this lifetime. I had two or
three
three hernia
three hernia in
three hernia in the
three hernia in the same
three hernia in the same place
three hernia in the same place without
anesthesia
anesthesia and
three hernia in the same place without
anesthesia and I
anesthesia and I experienced
three hernia in the same place without
anesthesia and I experienced the
anesthesia and I experienced the agony
he
he went
he went through.
he went through. Uh
he went through. Uh so
he went through. Uh so that
he went through. Uh so that was
he went through. Uh so that was a
mistake
mistake about
he went through. Uh so that was a
mistake about the
mistake about the nature
he went through. Uh so that was a
mistake about the nature of
mistake about the nature of compassion.
The
The compassionate
The compassionate thing
The compassionate thing would
The compassionate thing would have
The compassionate thing would have been
to
to kill
The compassionate thing would have been
to kill him,
to kill him, you
The compassionate thing would have been
to kill him, you know,
to kill him, you know, release
The compassionate thing would have been
to kill him, you know, release him
to kill him, you know, release him from
his
his agony
his agony and
his agony and misery.
his agony and misery. So
his agony and misery. So at
his agony and misery. So at that
his agony and misery. So at that moment
there
there was
his agony and misery. So at that moment
there was spiritual
there was spiritual cowardice.
Uh
Uh that
Uh that spiritual
Uh that spiritual cowardice
Uh that spiritual cowardice came
Uh that spiritual cowardice came great
guilt.
guilt. In
Uh that spiritual cowardice came great
guilt. In this
guilt. In this lifetime
Uh that spiritual cowardice came great
guilt. In this lifetime I
guilt. In this lifetime I undid
Uh that spiritual cowardice came great
guilt. In this lifetime I undid it
guilt. In this lifetime I undid it by
living
living it
living it through.
living it through. It
living it through. It actually
living it through. It actually went
through
through her
living it through. It actually went
through her without
through her without any
living it through. It actually went
through her without any anesthesia.
Uh
Uh so
what
what was
Uh so
what was I
what was I saying
Uh so
what was I saying that
what was I saying that for?
Uh so
what was I saying that for? I
what was I saying that for? I forget.
>> Moving
>> Moving up
>> Moving up the
>> Moving up the scale.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Moving up the scale.
>> Oh, yeah. Moving
>> Oh, yeah. Moving up
>> Moving up the scale.
>> Oh, yeah. Moving up the
>> Oh, yeah. Moving up the scale.
>> Moving up the scale.
>> Oh, yeah. Moving up the scale. The
intention
intention was
intention was okay.
intention was okay. The
intention was okay. The intention
intention was okay. The intention was
all
all right.
intention was okay. The intention was
all right. The
all right. The intention
intention was okay. The intention was
all right. The intention was
all right. The intention was uh
intention was okay. The intention was
all right. The intention was uh not
all right. The intention was uh not to
kill
kill him,
kill him, but
kill him, but it
kill him, but it was
kill him, but it was not
kill him, but it was not the
kill him, but it was not the greatest
expression
expression of
kill him, but it was not the greatest
expression of mercy.
expression of mercy. If
kill him, but it was not the greatest
expression of mercy. If I'd
expression of mercy. If I'd been
kill him, but it was not the greatest
expression of mercy. If I'd been really
merciful,
merciful, I
merciful, I would
merciful, I would have
merciful, I would have put
merciful, I would have put him
merciful, I would have put him to
merciful, I would have put him to sleep.
Yeah.
Yeah. And
merciful, I would have put him to sleep.
Yeah. And then
Yeah. And then when
merciful, I would have put him to sleep.
Yeah. And then when I
Yeah. And then when I went
merciful, I would have put him to sleep.
Yeah. And then when I went out
Yeah. And then when I went out of
merciful, I would have put him to sleep.
Yeah. And then when I went out of body,
he'd
he'd shake
he'd shake my
he'd shake my hand
he'd shake my hand say
he'd shake my hand say Jesus,
he'd shake my hand say Jesus, thanks.
However,
However, so
he'd shake my hand say Jesus, thanks.
However, so you
However, so you can
he'd shake my hand say Jesus, thanks.
However, so you can be
However, so you can be wrong,
he'd shake my hand say Jesus, thanks.
However, so you can be wrong, but
However, so you can be wrong, but if
your
your intention
your intention is
your intention is right,
your intention is right, as
your intention is right, as I
your intention is right, as I say,
your intention is right, as I say, the
kamicazi
kamicazi pilot,
your intention is right, as I say, the
kamicazi pilot, let's
kamicazi pilot, let's do
your intention is right, as I say, the
kamicazi pilot, let's do them.
kamicazi pilot, let's do them. Let's
just
just because
just because I
just because I want
just because I want people
just because I want people to
just because I want people to see
just because I want people to see the
integrity
integrity is
just because I want people to see the
integrity is powerful.
Kamicazi
Kamicazi pilot
Kamicazi pilot is
Kamicazi pilot is over
Kamicazi pilot is over 200
Kamicazi pilot is over 200 resist.
Kamicazi pilot is over 200 resist. He's
over
over 300
Kamicazi pilot is over 200 resist. He's
over 300 resist.
over 300 resist. He's
Kamicazi pilot is over 200 resist. He's
over 300 resist. He's over
over 300 resist. He's over 350
Kamicazi pilot is over 200 resist. He's
over 300 resist. He's over 350 resist.
He's
He's over
He's over 360
He's over 360 resist,
He's over 360 resist, 370
He's over 360 resist, 370 resist,
He's over 360 resist, 370 resist, 380
resist,
resist, 390
He's over 360 resist, 370 resist, 380
resist, 390 resist.
resist, 390 resist. The
He's over 360 resist, 370 resist, 380
resist, 390 resist. The kamicazi
resist, 390 resist. The kamicazi pilot
is
is over
is over 400
is over 400 resist,
is over 400 resist, 420,
is over 400 resist, 420, 440,
is over 400 resist, 420, 440, 480.
Kamicazi
Kamicazi pilot
is over 400 resist, 420, 440, 480.
Kamicazi pilot is
Kamicazi pilot is pretty
is over 400 resist, 420, 440, 480.
Kamicazi pilot is pretty high.
Um,
Um, so
Um, so the
Um, so the atheist,
Um, so the atheist, the
Um, so the atheist, the kamicazi
Um, so the atheist, the kamicazi pilot,
the
the mistaken
Um, so the atheist, the kamicazi pilot,
the mistaken warrior,
the mistaken warrior, you
Um, so the atheist, the kamicazi pilot,
the mistaken warrior, you can
the mistaken warrior, you can make
mistakes.
mistakes. But
mistakes. But if
mistakes. But if your
mistakes. But if your decision
mistakes. But if your decision is
mistakes. But if your decision is based
on
on integrity,
mistakes. But if your decision is based
on integrity, you
on integrity, you can
mistakes. But if your decision is based
on integrity, you can make
on integrity, you can make that
mistakes. But if your decision is based
on integrity, you can make that up.
on integrity, you can make that up. You
may
may have
may have to
may have to go
may have to go through
may have to go through through
may have to go through through an
operation
operation without
may have to go through through an
operation without anesthesia.
operation without anesthesia. But
may have to go through through an
operation without anesthesia. But that
undid
undid that
undid that one
undid that one anyway.
undid that one anyway. It
undid that one anyway. It didn't
undid that one anyway. It didn't change
my
my direction.
undid that one anyway. It didn't change
my direction. Didn't
my direction. Didn't change
undid that one anyway. It didn't change
my direction. Didn't change my
direction.
direction. All right.
direction. All right. So,
direction. All right. So, you're
attracted
attracted by
direction. All right. So, you're
attracted by the
attracted by the light
direction. All right. So, you're
attracted by the light and
attracted by the light and then
direction. All right. So, you're
attracted by the light and then So,
attracted by the light and then So, all
right.
right. So
right. So the
right. So the lower
right. So the lower astral
right. So the lower astral then
right. So the lower astral then is
people
people who
right. So the lower astral then is
people who have
people who have the
right. So the lower astral then is
people who have the opportunity
to
to choose
to choose the
to choose the light
to choose the light and
to choose the light and consciously
to choose the light and consciously make
a
a decision
to choose the light and consciously make
a decision to
a decision to turn
to choose the light and consciously make
a decision to turn from
a decision to turn from the
to choose the light and consciously make
a decision to turn from the light.
That's
That's it.
That's it. That's
That's it. That's why
That's it. That's why you
That's it. That's why you don't
That's it. That's why you don't want
That's it. That's why you don't want to
get
get involved
That's it. That's why you don't want to
get involved with
get involved with them
That's it. That's why you don't want to
get involved with them in
get involved with them in the
That's it. That's why you don't want to
get involved with them in the new
get involved with them in the new age
astral
astral circus
astral circus in
astral circus in which
astral circus in which there
astral circus in which there are
astral circus in which there are all
kinds
kinds of
astral circus in which there are all
kinds of lower
kinds of lower astrals
astral circus in which there are all
kinds of lower astrals uh
kinds of lower astrals uh looking
astral circus in which there are all
kinds of lower astrals uh looking to
kinds of lower astrals uh looking to get
your
your money
your money and
your money and get
your money and get dominion
your money and get dominion over
your money and get dominion over you
your money and get dominion over you and
get
get you
your money and get dominion over you and
get you to
get you to invest
your money and get dominion over you and
get you to invest in
get you to invest in thoroughbred
horses.
horses. So
horses. So yeah.
All
All right.
horses. So yeah.
All right. So,
All right. So, we'll
horses. So yeah.
All right. So, we'll take
All right. So, we'll take a
horses. So yeah.
All right. So, we'll take a break.
All right. So, we'll take a break. Then
we'll
we'll have
we'll have lunch
we'll have lunch uh
we'll have lunch uh from
we'll have lunch uh from 12
we'll have lunch uh from 12 to
we'll have lunch uh from 12 to 1.
we'll have lunch uh from 12 to 1. We'll
resume
resume with
we'll have lunch uh from 12 to 1. We'll
resume with a
resume with a short
we'll have lunch uh from 12 to 1. We'll
resume with a short lecture
resume with a short lecture and
we'll have lunch uh from 12 to 1. We'll
resume with a short lecture and we're
going
going to
going to spend
going to spend more
going to spend more time
going to spend more time on
going to spend more time on questions
and
and answers.
going to spend more time on questions
and answers. I
and answers. I want
going to spend more time on questions
and answers. I want everybody's
questions
questions answered
questions answered to
questions answered to the
questions answered to the best
questions answered to the best of
questions answered to the best of our
ability
ability because
questions answered to the best of our
ability because every
ability because every question
questions answered to the best of our
ability because every question you
ability because every question you see
brings
brings forth
brings forth a
brings forth a whole
brings forth a whole subject
brings forth a whole subject and
brings forth a whole subject and you
have
have to
brings forth a whole subject and you
have to explain
have to explain the
brings forth a whole subject and you
have to explain the context.
have to explain the context. Um
brings forth a whole subject and you
have to explain the context. Um as
have to explain the context. Um as a
spiritual
spiritual teacher,
spiritual teacher, my
spiritual teacher, my my
spiritual teacher, my my commitment
spiritual teacher, my my commitment is
to
to fortify
spiritual teacher, my my commitment is
to fortify truth
to fortify truth with
spiritual teacher, my my commitment is
to fortify truth with sufficient
explanation
explanation that
explanation that it
explanation that it does
explanation that it does not
explanation that it does not become
distorted
distorted over
explanation that it does not become
distorted over time.
Many
Many of
Many of the
Many of the greatest
Many of the greatest teachings,
Many of the greatest teachings, the
greatest
greatest teachers
Many of the greatest teachings, the
greatest teachers that
greatest teachers that ever
Many of the greatest teachings, the
greatest teachers that ever lived
greatest teachers that ever lived have
become
become distorted
become distorted into
become distorted into the
become distorted into the opposite
become distorted into the opposite of
their
their meaning.
become distorted into the opposite of
their meaning. You
their meaning. You know,
become distorted into the opposite of
their meaning. You know, it's
their meaning. You know, it's because
become distorted into the opposite of
their meaning. You know, it's because we
only
only had
only had the
only had the bare
only had the bare bones.
only had the bare bones. The
only had the bare bones. The only
only had the bare bones. The only reason
I'm
I'm glad
only had the bare bones. The only reason
I'm glad I'm
I'm glad I'm alive
only had the bare bones. The only reason
I'm glad I'm alive is
I'm glad I'm alive is I
only had the bare bones. The only reason
I'm glad I'm alive is I get
I'm glad I'm alive is I get a
only had the bare bones. The only reason
I'm glad I'm alive is I get a chance
I'm glad I'm alive is I get a chance to
explain
explain and
explain and defend
explain and defend God,
explain and defend God, you
explain and defend God, you know,
because
because it's
explain and defend God, you know,
because it's been
because it's been so
explain and defend God, you know,
because it's been so worked.
because it's been so worked. So
explain and defend God, you know,
because it's been so worked. So I
because it's been so worked. So I felt
the
the spiritual
the spiritual teachers,
the spiritual teachers, you
the spiritual teachers, you know,
the spiritual teachers, you know, don't
b
b buttress
the spiritual teachers, you know, don't
b buttress their
b buttress their work
the spiritual teachers, you know, don't
b buttress their work with
b buttress their work with a
the spiritual teachers, you know, don't
b buttress their work with a with
b buttress their work with a with a
mountain
mountain of
mountain of of
mountain of of ex
mountain of of ex explanation
mountain of of ex explanation that
mountain of of ex explanation that it
makes
makes hard
mountain of of ex explanation that it
makes hard for
makes hard for an
mountain of of ex explanation that it
makes hard for an enemy
makes hard for an enemy of
mountain of of ex explanation that it
makes hard for an enemy of truth
makes hard for an enemy of truth to
attack
attack and
attack and destroy.
attack and destroy. If
attack and destroy. If you
attack and destroy. If you only
attack and destroy. If you only put
attack and destroy. If you only put out
a
a thin
attack and destroy. If you only put out
a thin bone,
a thin bone, anybody
attack and destroy. If you only put out
a thin bone, anybody can
a thin bone, anybody can distort
attack and destroy. If you only put out
a thin bone, anybody can distort that.
But
But if
But if you
But if you fortify
But if you fortify it
But if you fortify it with
But if you fortify it with a
But if you fortify it with a massive
explanation,
explanation, which
But if you fortify it with a massive
explanation, which is
explanation, which is what
But if you fortify it with a massive
explanation, which is what I
explanation, which is what I try
But if you fortify it with a massive
explanation, which is what I try to
explanation, which is what I try to do,
it
it makes
it makes it
it makes it very
it makes it very hard
it makes it very hard to
it makes it very hard to disagree
it makes it very hard to disagree with
what
what you
it makes it very hard to disagree with
what you can
what you can validate
it makes it very hard to disagree with
what you can validate by
what you can validate by spiritual
experience,
experience, by
experience, by the
experience, by the reality
experience, by the reality of
experience, by the reality of that
experience, by the reality of that which
I
I know.
experience, by the reality of that which
I know. And
I know. And we
experience, by the reality of that which
I know. And we use
I know. And we use coniality
experience, by the reality of that which
I know. And we use coniality to
I know. And we use coniality to just
verify
verify it
verify it even
verify it even further.
verify it even further. You
verify it even further. You see
verify it even further. You see what
verify it even further. You see what I'm
saying?
saying? So
verify it even further. You see what I'm
saying? So that
saying? So that somebody
verify it even further. You see what I'm
saying? So that somebody can't
saying? So that somebody can't come
along
along later
along later 500
along later 500 years
along later 500 years from
along later 500 years from now
along later 500 years from now and
along later 500 years from now and and
turn
turn you
along later 500 years from now and and
turn you into
turn you into a
along later 500 years from now and and
turn you into a demon,
turn you into a demon, which
along later 500 years from now and and
turn you into a demon, which is
turn you into a demon, which is a
along later 500 years from now and and
turn you into a demon, which is a lot
turn you into a demon, which is a lot of
the
the great
the great speeches
the great speeches teachers
the great speeches teachers of
the great speeches teachers of time.
Their
Their words
the great speeches teachers of time.
Their words have
Their words have been
the great speeches teachers of time.
Their words have been turned
Their words have been turned around
the great speeches teachers of time.
Their words have been turned around into
almost
almost demonic.
almost demonic. You
almost demonic. You know,
kill
kill a
almost demonic. You know,
kill a Christian
kill a Christian for
almost demonic. You know,
kill a Christian for uh
kill a Christian for uh Allah.
almost demonic. You know,
kill a Christian for uh Allah. I
kill a Christian for uh Allah. I mean,
how
how bizarre
how bizarre can
how bizarre can you
how bizarre can you get?
how bizarre can you get? There's
how bizarre can you get? There's people
actually
actually believe
how bizarre can you get? There's people
actually believe that.
I
I believed
I believed it
I believed it one
I believed it one time.
I believed it one time. I
I believed it one time. I killed
I believed it one time. I killed a
killed
killed out
I believed it one time. I killed a
killed out herb
killed out herb for
I believed it one time. I killed a
killed out herb for Jesus.
killed out herb for Jesus. So
I believed it one time. I killed a
killed out herb for Jesus. So I
killed out herb for Jesus. So I can
I believed it one time. I killed a
killed out herb for Jesus. So I can see
you
you can
you can fall
you can fall for
you can fall for it
you can fall for it because
you can fall for it because the
you can fall for it because the zealot
is
is over
you can fall for it because the zealot
is over devote
is over devote over
you can fall for it because the zealot
is over devote over you
is over devote over you know
you can fall for it because the zealot
is over devote over you know it's
is over devote over you know it's an
excess
excess it's
excess it's imbalance
excess it's imbalance the
excess it's imbalance the devotion
excess it's imbalance the devotion has
become
become excessive
excess it's imbalance the devotion has
become excessive and
become excessive and now
excess it's imbalance the devotion has
become excessive and now it's
become excessive and now it's become
excess it's imbalance the devotion has
become excessive and now it's become a
distortion
distortion that
distortion that can
distortion that can be
distortion that can be used
distortion that can be used by
distortion that can be used by others
for
for political
distortion that can be used by others
for political purpose
for political purpose other
distortion that can be used by others
for political purpose other people
for political purpose other people for
so
so the
so the religious
so the religious zeal
so the religious zeal is
so the religious zeal is easily
so the religious zeal is easily bought
by
by others
so the religious zeal is easily bought
by others who
by others who all
so the religious zeal is easily bought
by others who all you
by others who all you have
so the religious zeal is easily bought
by others who all you have to
by others who all you have to do
so the religious zeal is easily bought
by others who all you have to do is
by others who all you have to do is line
him
him up
him up with
him up with a
him up with a parade
him up with a parade and
him up with a parade and he'll
him up with a parade and he'll get
him up with a parade and he'll get out
there
there and
him up with a parade and he'll get out
there and fight
there and fight for
him up with a parade and he'll get out
there and fight for the
there and fight for the slogan.
Thank
Thank you.
>> Um
>> Um in
Thank you.
>> Um in that
>> Um in that place
Thank you.
>> Um in that place where
>> Um in that place where is
Thank you.
>> Um in that place where is the
>> Um in that place where is the void
Thank you.
>> Um in that place where is the void when
you
you reach
you reach the
you reach the void?
>> Yes.
>> Is
>> Is is
>> Is is that
>> Is is that the
>> Is is that the place
>> Is is that the place where
>> Is is that the place where with
>> Is is that the place where with light
and
and love
>> Is is that the place where with light
and love and
and love and intention
that
that void
that void can
that void can exist
and
and then
that void can exist
and then you
and then you can
that void can exist
and then you can cocreate
and then you can cocreate with
that void can exist
and then you can cocreate with source
from
from there
from there because
from there because isn't
from there because isn't God
from there because isn't God always
moving
moving and
from there because isn't God always
moving and changing?
>> No.
>> Through
>> Through that.
>> No,
>> No, it's
>> No, it's void.
>> No, it's void. Void.
>> It's
>> It's void.
>> No, it's void. Void.
>> It's void. void.
>> There's
>> There's nobody
>> There's nobody there
>> There's nobody there to
>> There's nobody there to make
>> There's nobody there to make any
decisions
decisions and
>> There's nobody there to make any
decisions and there's
decisions and there's no
>> There's nobody there to make any
decisions and there's no direction
decisions and there's no direction to
move.
>> There's
>> There's nothingness.
There's
There's nothingness.
>> So,
>> So, where
There's nothingness.
>> So, where does
>> So, where does cocreation
There's nothingness.
>> So, where does cocreation come
>> So, where does cocreation come from?
>> That's
>> That's a
>> That's a concept
>> That's a concept somebody
>> That's a concept somebody invented.
>> Let's
>> Let's see.
God
God needs
God needs us
God needs us as
God needs us as co-creators.
God needs us as co-creators. Is
God needs us as co-creators. Is this
>> He
>> He does
God needs us as co-creators. Is this
>> He does need
>> He does need us
God needs us as co-creators. Is this
>> He does need us as
>> He does need us as co-creators.
as
as the
as the manifestation
as the manifestation of
as the manifestation of his
as the manifestation of his creation
resistance.
resistance. Yeah.
as the manifestation of his creation
resistance. Yeah. So
resistance. Yeah. So that's
as the manifestation of his creation
resistance. Yeah. So that's what
resistance. Yeah. So that's what we
as the manifestation of his creation
resistance. Yeah. So that's what we do
by
by our
by our choice.
by our choice. People
by our choice. People say
by our choice. People say how
by our choice. People say how do
by our choice. People say how do you
by our choice. People say how do you go
up
up and
by our choice. People say how do you go
up and down?
up and down? You
by our choice. People say how do you go
up and down? You you
up and down? You you choose
by our choice. People say how do you go
up and down? You you choose the
up and down? You you choose the light,
you
you choose
you choose the
you choose the light
you choose the light instead
you choose the light instead of
you choose the light instead of the
darkness.
darkness. That's
you choose the light instead of the
darkness. That's all.
darkness. That's all. You
you choose the light instead of the
darkness. That's all. You choose
darkness. That's all. You choose the
light
light instead
light instead of
light instead of the
light instead of the darkness.
And
And uh
light instead of the darkness.
And uh as
And uh as the
light instead of the darkness.
And uh as the Buddha
And uh as the Buddha said,
light instead of the darkness.
And uh as the Buddha said, if
And uh as the Buddha said, if you
light instead of the darkness.
And uh as the Buddha said, if you once
you
you choose
you choose the
you choose the light,
you choose the light, the
you choose the light, the end
you choose the light, the end is
certain.
certain. So
you choose the light, the end is
certain. So why
certain. So why worry?
I
I stop
I stop worrying.
I stop worrying. Right.
I stop worrying. Right. We'll
I stop worrying. Right. We'll come
I stop worrying. Right. We'll come back
at
at 1:00.
I stop worrying. Right. We'll come back
at 1:00. Okay.
So,
So, questions
So, questions came
So, questions came up
So, questions came up and
So, questions came up and uh
So, questions came up and uh we'll
So, questions came up and uh we'll we'll
talk
talk for
So, questions came up and uh we'll we'll
talk for a
talk for a while
So, questions came up and uh we'll we'll
talk for a while and
talk for a while and then
So, questions came up and uh we'll we'll
talk for a while and then we're
talk for a while and then we're going to
have
have more
have more questions
have more questions and
have more questions and answers.
have more questions and answers. We
have more questions and answers. We can
have
have them
have more questions and answers. We can
have them spontaneously
have them spontaneously from
have more questions and answers. We can
have them spontaneously from the
have them spontaneously from the floor.
I'll
I'll just
I'll just repeat
I'll just repeat them
I'll just repeat them so
I'll just repeat them so that
I'll just repeat them so that it
records.
Um
someone
someone who
Um
someone who came
someone who came all
Um
someone who came all the
someone who came all the way
Um
someone who came all the way from
Michigan,
Michigan, uh
Michigan, uh a
Michigan, uh a friend
Michigan, uh a friend of
Michigan, uh a friend of mine
Michigan, uh a friend of mine asked
Michigan, uh a friend of mine asked what
about
about what
Michigan, uh a friend of mine asked what
about what is
about what is the
Michigan, uh a friend of mine asked what
about what is the what
about what is the what does
Michigan, uh a friend of mine asked what
about what is the what does it
about what is the what does it mean
radical
radical subjectivity?
radical subjectivity? Well,
radical subjectivity? Well, that's
really
really the
radical subjectivity? Well, that's
really the next
really the next sub
radical subjectivity? Well, that's
really the next sub next
really the next sub next lecture,
radical subjectivity? Well, that's
really the next sub next lecture, but
really the next sub next lecture, but uh
It's
It's really
It's really the
It's really the core
It's really the core of
It's really the core of that
It's really the core of that which
It's really the core of that which um
I
I teach
It's really the core of that which um
I teach uh
I teach uh or
It's really the core of that which um
I teach uh or research
I teach uh or research whatever
It's really the core of that which um
I teach uh or research whatever you
I teach uh or research whatever you want
to
to say
to say convey
to say convey to
to say convey to people.
Um
the
the presence
the presence of
the presence of God
the presence of God uh
reaches
reaches awareness
the presence of God uh
reaches awareness by
reaches awareness by virtue
the presence of God uh
reaches awareness by virtue of
reaches awareness by virtue of the
the presence of God uh
reaches awareness by virtue of the fact
that
that you
that you are
that you are aware
that you are aware that
that you are aware that you
that you are aware that you are.
The
The difficulty
that you are aware that you are.
The difficulty with
The difficulty with religion
that you are aware that you are.
The difficulty with religion is
The difficulty with religion is it
that you are aware that you are.
The difficulty with religion is it leads
you
you elsewhere.
The
The pathway,
you elsewhere.
The pathway, in
The pathway, in fact,
you elsewhere.
The pathway, in fact, we
The pathway, in fact, we might
you elsewhere.
The pathway, in fact, we might even
The pathway, in fact, we might even call
it
it the
it the pathway
it the pathway of
it the pathway of radical
it the pathway of radical subjectivity.
The
The presence
it the pathway of radical subjectivity.
The presence of
The presence of God
it the pathway of radical subjectivity.
The presence of God is
The presence of God is knowable,
is
is obvious
via
via radical
is obvious
via radical subjectivity.
In
In other
In other words,
In other words, consciousness
In other words, consciousness devoid
In other words, consciousness devoid of
content
is
is only
is only aware
is only aware that's
is only aware that's it's
is only aware that's it's aware.
is only aware that's it's aware. All
truth
truth is
is only aware that's it's aware. All
truth is subjective.
truth is subjective. There
is only aware that's it's aware. All
truth is subjective. There is
truth is subjective. There is no
is only aware that's it's aware. All
truth is subjective. There is no such
thing
thing as
thing as objective
thing as objective truth.
The
The radical
thing as objective truth.
The radical materialist
The radical materialist says
if
if unless
if unless it
if unless it can
if unless it can be
if unless it can be measured
if unless it can be measured and
if unless it can be measured and weighed
or
or defined
uh
uh it's
uh it's not
uh it's not real.
uh it's not real. That's
uh it's not real. That's m
uh it's not real. That's m you
uh it's not real. That's m you know
scientific
scientific materialism
sort
sort of
sort of unfortunately
sort of unfortunately the
sort of unfortunately the direction
sort of unfortunately the direction that
psychiatry
psychiatry is
sort of unfortunately the direction that
psychiatry is going.
psychiatry is going. Psychiatry
sort of unfortunately the direction that
psychiatry is going. Psychiatry is
dumbing
dumbing down.
dumbing down. It's
dumbing down. It's going
dumbing down. It's going to
dumbing down. It's going to be
dumbing down. It's going to be a
dumbing down. It's going to be a good
time
time to
dumbing down. It's going to be a good
time to leave
time to leave it.
But
But the
But the time
But the time I
But the time I leave
But the time I leave it
But the time I leave it I'll
But the time I leave it I'll say
But the time I leave it I'll say good
God.
God. He
But the time I leave it I'll say good
God. He was
God. He was inspirational
But the time I leave it I'll say good
God. He was inspirational back
God. He was inspirational back in
But the time I leave it I'll say good
God. He was inspirational back in the
30s
30s and
30s and the
30s and the 40s.
30s and the 40s. I
30s and the 40s. I mean
30s and the 40s. I mean there
30s and the 40s. I mean there was
30s and the 40s. I mean there was Freud
and
and Young
30s and the 40s. I mean there was Freud
and Young and
and Young and the
30s and the 40s. I mean there was Freud
and Young and the great
and Young and the great psychoanalysts
who
who asked
who asked who
who asked who who
who asked who who is
who asked who who is man
who asked who who is man and
who asked who who is man and why
who asked who who is man and why what
makes
makes him
who asked who who is man and why what
makes him human
makes him human and
who asked who who is man and why what
makes him human and what
makes him human and what runs
who asked who who is man and why what
makes him human and what runs him
makes him human and what runs him and
who asked who who is man and why what
makes him human and what runs him and so
it
it was
it was an
it was an exciting
it was an exciting you
it was an exciting you know
psychoanalysis
psychoanalysis was
it was an exciting you know
psychoanalysis was exciting.
psychoanalysis was exciting. If
it was an exciting you know
psychoanalysis was exciting. If you
think
think there's
think there's no
think there's no edible
think there's no edible complex
think there's no edible complex try
lying
lying down
think there's no edible complex try
lying down on
lying down on an
think there's no edible complex try
lying down on an analyst
lying down on an analyst couch
think there's no edible complex try
lying down on an analyst couch for
lying down on an analyst couch for an
hour
hour every
hour every day
hour every day for
hour every day for a
hour every day for a couple
hour every day for a couple of
hour every day for a couple of years
hour every day for a couple of years and
you
you what
hour every day for a couple of years and
you what comes
you what comes up?
Whoa.
You
You don't
Whoa.
You don't think
You don't think you
Whoa.
You don't think you got
You don't think you got an
Whoa.
You don't think you got an apple
complex,
complex, huh?
complex, huh? Well,
complex, huh? Well, let
complex, huh? Well, let me
complex, huh? Well, let me Anybody
complex, huh? Well, let me Anybody want
to
to try
complex, huh? Well, let me Anybody want
to try it?
to try it? You'll
complex, huh? Well, let me Anybody want
to try it? You'll see.
to try it? You'll see. All
complex, huh? Well, let me Anybody want
to try it? You'll see. All right.
to try it? You'll see. All right. Uh,
the
the most
the most radical
the most radical materialist
can
can only
the most radical materialist
can only say
that
that only
that only the
that only the material
that only the material is
that only the material is real
because
because subjectively
that only the material is real
because subjectively that
because subjectively that seems
that only the material is real
because subjectively that seems so.
because subjectively that seems so. You
understand?
understand? In
understand? In the
understand? In the end,
understand? In the end, you
understand? In the end, you always
understand? In the end, you always end
up
up back
understand? In the end, you always end
up back with
up back with subjectivity.
understand? In the end, you always end
up back with subjectivity. Who
up back with subjectivity. Who concludes
that?
that? And
that? And what
that? And what is
that? And what is it
that? And what is it about
that? And what is it about you
that? And what is it about you that
that? And what is it about you that is
concluding
concluding that?
that? And what is it about you that is
concluding that? Instantly,
concluding that? Instantly, he's
that? And what is it about you that is
concluding that? Instantly, he's thrown
back
back into
back into the
back into the fact
back into the fact that
back into the fact that every
back into the fact that every statement
is
is purely
back into the fact that every statement
is purely subjective.
is purely subjective. You
back into the fact that every statement
is purely subjective. You can
is purely subjective. You can weigh
back into the fact that every statement
is purely subjective. You can weigh all
the
the evidence,
the evidence, but
the evidence, but there
the evidence, but there has
the evidence, but there has to
the evidence, but there has to be
something
something there
the evidence, but there has to be
something there that
something there that agrees
the evidence, but there has to be
something there that agrees and
something there that agrees and says
the evidence, but there has to be
something there that agrees and says yes
or
or no.
or no. So
or no. So the
or no. So the inner
or no. So the inner the
or no. So the inner the inner
or no. So the inner the inner condition
that
that is
or no. So the inner the inner condition
that is necessary
that is necessary before
or no. So the inner the inner condition
that is necessary before anything
that is necessary before anything can
or no. So the inner the inner condition
that is necessary before anything can be
said
said or
said or known
said or known even
said or known even your
said or known even your own
said or known even your own existence
is
radical
radical subject
radical subject subjectivity.
The
The knowingness
all
all that
all that is
all that is here
all that is here that
all that is here that you
all that is here that you call
all that is here that you call yourself
is
is your
all that is here that you call yourself
is your presence.
is your presence. Your
all that is here that you call yourself
is your presence. Your physicality
happens
happens to
happens to be
happens to be the
happens to be the baggage
happens to be the baggage in
happens to be the baggage in this
domain.
But
what
what makes
But
what makes you
what makes you here
But
what makes you here is
what makes you here is the
But
what makes you here is the your
presence.
presence. Let's
presence. Let's say
presence. Let's say you
presence. Let's say you go
presence. Let's say you go to
presence. Let's say you go to visit
presence. Let's say you go to visit a
friend
friend and
presence. Let's say you go to visit a
friend and and
friend and and you
presence. Let's say you go to visit a
friend and and you come
friend and and you come back
presence. Let's say you go to visit a
friend and and you come back again
friend and and you come back again and
your
your wife
your wife says,
your wife says, "Uh,
your wife says, "Uh, well,
your wife says, "Uh, well, did
your wife says, "Uh, well, did you
your wife says, "Uh, well, did you see
George?"
George?" No,
your wife says, "Uh, well, did you see
George?" No, he
George?" No, he was
your wife says, "Uh, well, did you see
George?" No, he was asleep.
George?" No, he was asleep. If
your wife says, "Uh, well, did you see
George?" No, he was asleep. If he's
asleep,
asleep, you
asleep, you didn't
asleep, you didn't see
asleep, you didn't see George.
asleep, you didn't see George. Even
though
though his
asleep, you didn't see George. Even
though his body's
though his body's laying
asleep, you didn't see George. Even
though his body's laying there,
though his body's laying there, you
didn't
didn't meet
didn't meet with
didn't meet with George.
didn't meet with George. Why?
didn't meet with George. Why? Because
he's
he's not
didn't meet with George. Why? Because
he's not present.
Well,
Well, if
Well, if his
Well, if his body
Well, if his body was
Well, if his body was who
Well, if his body was who he
Well, if his body was who he was,
Well, if his body was who he was, you'd
say,
say, "Yeah,
Well, if his body was who he was, you'd
say, "Yeah, I
say, "Yeah, I saw
Well, if his body was who he was, you'd
say, "Yeah, I saw George."
They
They know
They know he
They know he was
They know he was taking
They know he was taking a
They know he was taking a nap.
Uh
Uh the
They know he was taking a nap.
Uh the presence
Uh the presence is
They know he was taking a nap.
Uh the presence is that
Uh the presence is that we
They know he was taking a nap.
Uh the presence is that we appreciate
Uh the presence is that we appreciate in
each
each other
each other is
each other is is
each other is is the
each other is is the presence
each other is is the presence of
each other is is the presence of your
consciousness.
consciousness. Okay.
each other is is the presence of your
consciousness. Okay. So,
consciousness. Okay. So, the
each other is is the presence of your
consciousness. Okay. So, the difference
between
between the
between the two
between the two waitresses
between the two waitresses is
uh
uh the
between the two waitresses is
uh the one
uh the one waitress
between the two waitresses is
uh the one waitress is
uh the one waitress is mechanical.
between the two waitresses is
uh the one waitress is mechanical. She
she
she probably
she probably calibrates
she probably calibrates at
she probably calibrates at 200.
she probably calibrates at 200. Let's
see
see what
she probably calibrates at 200. Let's
see what she
see what she calibrates
she probably calibrates at 200. Let's
see what she calibrates at.
see what she calibrates at. The
she probably calibrates at 200. Let's
see what she calibrates at. The lady
always
always asks
always asks me,
always asks me, "Are
always asks me, "Are you
always asks me, "Are you going
always asks me, "Are you going to
always asks me, "Are you going to have
coffee?"
coffee?" She
always asks me, "Are you going to have
coffee?" She calibrates
coffee?" She calibrates over
always asks me, "Are you going to have
coffee?" She calibrates over 200
coffee?" She calibrates over 200 resist.
2011 resist.
2011 resist. She's
2011 resist. She's right
2011 resist. She's right at
2011 resist. She's right at 200.
2011 resist. She's right at 200. She
2011 resist. She's right at 200. She She
never
never looks
2011 resist. She's right at 200. She She
never looks you
never looks you in
2011 resist. She's right at 200. She She
never looks you in the
never looks you in the eye.
2011 resist. She's right at 200. She She
never looks you in the eye. Uh
never looks you in the eye. Uh yeah.
2011 resist. She's right at 200. She She
never looks you in the eye. Uh yeah. You
going
going to
going to have
going to have coffee?
going to have coffee? Now,
going to have coffee? Now, I
going to have coffee? Now, I haven't
going to have coffee? Now, I haven't had
coffee
coffee the
going to have coffee? Now, I haven't had
coffee the last
coffee the last 20
going to have coffee? Now, I haven't had
coffee the last 20 times
coffee the last 20 times I
going to have coffee? Now, I haven't had
coffee the last 20 times I was
coffee the last 20 times I was in
going to have coffee? Now, I haven't had
coffee the last 20 times I was in here,
you
you idiot.
you idiot. No,
you idiot. No, that's
you idiot. No, that's what
she
she never
you idiot. No, that's what
she never looks
she never looks at
you idiot. No, that's what
she never looks at you.
That
That which
That which is
That which is unloving
That which is unloving has
That which is unloving has a
That which is unloving has a very
That which is unloving has a very hard
time
time being
That which is unloving has a very hard
time being open
time being open and
That which is unloving has a very hard
time being open and looking
time being open and looking at
That which is unloving has a very hard
time being open and looking at you
time being open and looking at you and
revealing
revealing to
revealing to you
revealing to you who
revealing to you who they
revealing to you who they are.
revealing to you who they are. when
revealing to you who they are. when you
look
look at
revealing to you who they are. when you
look at them,
look at them, they
revealing to you who they are. when you
look at them, they quickly
look at them, they quickly look
revealing to you who they are. when you
look at them, they quickly look away.
They
They cannot
They cannot sustain
They cannot sustain a
They cannot sustain a gaze,
They cannot sustain a gaze, a
They cannot sustain a gaze, a direct
gaze.
gaze. It's
They cannot sustain a gaze, a direct
gaze. It's like
gaze. It's like frightening.
They cannot sustain a gaze, a direct
gaze. It's like frightening. And
gaze. It's like frightening. And uh
the
the subjectivity
the subjectivity then
the subjectivity then is
the subjectivity then is the
the subjectivity then is the presence
the subjectivity then is the presence of
that
that which
the subjectivity then is the presence of
that which you
that which you are.
the subjectivity then is the presence of
that which you are. The
that which you are. The one
the subjectivity then is the presence of
that which you are. The one who
that which you are. The one who comes
and
and says,
and says, "Oh,
and says, "Oh, hey,
and says, "Oh, hey, I
and says, "Oh, hey, I haven't
and says, "Oh, hey, I haven't seen
and says, "Oh, hey, I haven't seen you
all
all week.
and says, "Oh, hey, I haven't seen you
all week. You're
all week. You're going
and says, "Oh, hey, I haven't seen you
all week. You're going to
all week. You're going to have
and says, "Oh, hey, I haven't seen you
all week. You're going to have a
all week. You're going to have a usual."
She's
She's very
She's very present.
She's very present. You
She's very present. You understand
She's very present. You understand what
I'm
I'm saying?
She's very present. You understand what
I'm saying? She's
I'm saying? She's present.
She's very present. You understand what
I'm saying? She's present. The
I'm saying? She's present. The other
person
person is
person is not
person is not present.
You
You know,
person is not present.
You know, it's
You know, it's hiding
person is not present.
You know, it's hiding behind
You know, it's hiding behind the
physicality
physicality of
physicality of life
physicality of life and
physicality of life and the
physicality of life and the bare
physicality of life and the bare bones
form
form of
physicality of life and the bare bones
form of life.
form of life. But
physicality of life and the bare bones
form of life. But that
form of life. But that person
physicality of life and the bare bones
form of life. But that person out
form of life. But that person out of
fear
fear or
fear or lack
fear or lack of
fear or lack of evolution
fear or lack of evolution of
consciousness
consciousness probably
fear or lack of evolution of
consciousness probably uh
consciousness probably uh just
fear or lack of evolution of
consciousness probably uh just isn't
that
that much
that much there.
Radical
Radical truth
that much there.
Radical truth then
Radical truth then is
that much there.
Radical truth then is an
Radical truth then is an purely
subjective
subjective state.
subjective state. There
subjective state. There is
subjective state. There is no
subjective state. There is no this
subjective state. There is no this that
experiences
experiences a
subjective state. There is no this that
experiences a that.
The
The only
The only difficulty
The only difficulty I
The only difficulty I have
The only difficulty I have with
The only difficulty I have with Islam
The only difficulty I have with Islam is
or
or Hinduism
The only difficulty I have with Islam is
or Hinduism is
or Hinduism is that
The only difficulty I have with Islam is
or Hinduism is that concept
or Hinduism is that concept of
The only difficulty I have with Islam is
or Hinduism is that concept of union
yoga
yoga as
yoga as union
of
of a
yoga as union
of a self
of a self with
yoga as union
of a self with God.
of a self with God. You
yoga as union
of a self with God. You see
of a self with God. You see self
yoga as union
of a self with God. You see self with
God
God right
God right away
God right away you
God right away you got
God right away you got two
God right away you got two right
God right away you got two right there's
you
you and
God right away you got two right there's
you and then
you and then there's
God right away you got two right there's
you and then there's God.
you and then there's God. No
God right away you got two right there's
you and then there's God. No to
you and then there's God. No to realize
that
that the
that the self
that the self with
that the self with capital
that the self with capital S
that the self with capital S is
that the self with capital S is the
expression
expression of
that the self with capital S is the
expression of God
expression of God as
that the self with capital S is the
expression of God as your
expression of God as your existence.
That
That is
That is enlightenment.
The
The source
and
and the
and the manifestation
and the manifestation of
and the manifestation of that
and the manifestation of that source
and the manifestation of that source are
one
one and
and the manifestation of that source are
one and the
one and the same
and the manifestation of that source are
one and the same thing.
one and the same thing. You
and the manifestation of that source are
one and the same thing. You understand?
If
If we
If we have
If we have time,
If we have time, we'll
If we have time, we'll sort
If we have time, we'll sort of
If we have time, we'll sort of describe
how
how you
If we have time, we'll sort of describe
how you can
how you can reach
If we have time, we'll sort of describe
how you can reach that
how you can reach that state
If we have time, we'll sort of describe
how you can reach that state in
how you can reach that state in a
If we have time, we'll sort of describe
how you can reach that state in a rather
rapid.
>> All
>> All right.
rapid.
>> All right. Well,
>> All right. Well, might
rapid.
>> All right. Well, might as
>> All right. Well, might as well
rapid.
>> All right. Well, might as well get
enlightened.
enlightened. Hey,
enlightened. Hey, we're
enlightened. Hey, we're only
>> We'll
>> We'll take
enlightened. Hey, we're only
>> We'll take 45
>> We'll take 45 minutes
enlightened. Hey, we're only
>> We'll take 45 minutes to
>> We'll take 45 minutes to get
enlightened.
enlightened. Okay.
enlightened. Okay. Looks
enlightened. Okay. Looks like
now
now this
enlightened. Okay. Looks like
now this is
now this is a
enlightened. Okay. Looks like
now this is a very
now this is a very simple
enlightened. Okay. Looks like
now this is a very simple thing.
All
All the
All the stuff
All the stuff you
All the stuff you read
All the stuff you read about
All the stuff you read about and
All the stuff you read about and what
most
most of
All the stuff you read about and what
most of the
most of the world
All the stuff you read about and what
most of the world follows
most of the world follows is
entertainment.
It's
It's entertainment
entertainment.
It's entertainment to
It's entertainment to go
entertainment.
It's entertainment to go to
It's entertainment to go to Stonehenge.
It's
It's entertainment
It's entertainment to
It's entertainment to go
It's entertainment to go to
It's entertainment to go to patch
It's entertainment to go to patch patchu
patchu
patchu patchu.
It's entertainment to go to patch patchu
patchu patchu. What
patchu patchu. What is
It's entertainment to go to patch patchu
patchu patchu. What is that?
Anyway,
Anyway, I
Anyway, I was
Anyway, I was there.
Anyway, I was there. I
Anyway, I was there. I fell
Anyway, I was there. I fell in
Anyway, I was there. I fell in love
Anyway, I was there. I fell in love with
llamas.
llamas. Now
Anyway, I was there. I fell in love with
llamas. Now I
llamas. Now I have
Anyway, I was there. I fell in love with
llamas. Now I have seven
llamas. Now I have seven llamas.
Anyway, I was there. I fell in love with
llamas. Now I have seven llamas. So
llamas. Now I have seven llamas. So what
did
did I
did I get
did I get out
did I get out of
did I get out of going
did I get out of going to
did I get out of going to Machu
did I get out of going to Machu Picchu?
Well,
Well, besides
did I get out of going to Machu Picchu?
Well, besides being
Well, besides being I
did I get out of going to Machu Picchu?
Well, besides being I was
Well, besides being I was afraid
did I get out of going to Machu Picchu?
Well, besides being I was afraid of
heights
heights in
heights in those
heights in those years.
heights in those years. It
heights in those years. It was
terrifying.
terrifying. Just
heights in those years. It was
terrifying. Just a
terrifying. Just a bunch
heights in those years. It was
terrifying. Just a bunch of
terrifying. Just a bunch of damn
heights in those years. It was
terrifying. Just a bunch of damn stones
and
and these
and these beautiful
and these beautiful llamas
and these beautiful llamas around.
And
And I
and these beautiful llamas around.
And I got
And I got home
and these beautiful llamas around.
And I got home uh
And I got home uh and
and these beautiful llamas around.
And I got home uh and now
And I got home uh and now I
and these beautiful llamas around.
And I got home uh and now I got
And I got home uh and now I got llamas.
So
when
when I
So
when I got
when I got out
So
when I got out of
when I got out of Machu
So
when I got out of Machu Picchu
when I got out of Machu Picchu was
llamas
llamas and
llamas and and
llamas and and it
llamas and and it intensified
llamas and and it intensified my
llamas and and it intensified my fear
llamas and and it intensified my fear of
fights.
I'm
I'm going
I'm going to
I'm going to do
I'm going to do a
I'm going to do a llama.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, llamas.
>> Uh
>> Uh I'm
>> Uh I'm thinking
>> Uh I'm thinking of
>> Uh I'm thinking of our
>> Uh I'm thinking of our llamas
>> Uh I'm thinking of our llamas at
>> Uh I'm thinking of our llamas at home.
Uh
Uh we
>> Uh I'm thinking of our llamas at home.
Uh we have
Uh we have permission.
>> Uh I'm thinking of our llamas at home.
Uh we have permission. resist.
Uh we have permission. resist. They
calibrate
calibrate over
calibrate over 200
calibrate over 200 resist
calibrate over 200 resist 300
calibrate over 200 resist 300 resist
305.
305. The
calibrate over 200 resist 300 resist
305. The llamas,
305. The llamas, curiously
calibrate over 200 resist 300 resist
305. The llamas, curiously enough,
calibrate
calibrate about
calibrate about 305.
calibrate about 305. Huh.
calibrate about 305. Huh. Isn't
calibrate about 305. Huh. Isn't that
interesting?
A
A llama
A llama is
A llama is sort
A llama is sort of
A llama is sort of a
A llama is sort of a strange
A llama is sort of a strange creature.
Just
Just sort
A llama is sort of a strange creature.
Just sort of
Just sort of looks
A llama is sort of a strange creature.
Just sort of looks at
Just sort of looks at you
A llama is sort of a strange creature.
Just sort of looks at you like
Just sort of looks at you like that.
Doesn't
Doesn't come
Doesn't come over
Doesn't come over and
Doesn't come over and touch
Doesn't come over and touch the
Doesn't come over and touch the noses.
It's
It's not
Doesn't come over and touch the noses.
It's not 500.
It's not 500. And
Doesn't come over and touch the noses.
It's not 500. And it
It's not 500. And it doesn't
Doesn't come over and touch the noses.
It's not 500. And it doesn't think
It's not 500. And it doesn't think about
you.
you. It's
you. It's not
you. It's not in
you. It's not in the
you. It's not in the 400s,
but
but it's
you. It's not in the 400s,
but it's very
but it's very aware
you. It's not in the 400s,
but it's very aware that
but it's very aware that you're
you. It's not in the 400s,
but it's very aware that you're there.
In
In fact,
In fact, this
In fact, this real
In fact, this real present
In fact, this real present to
In fact, this real present to you
In fact, this real present to you is
In fact, this real present to you is its
awareness
awareness of
In fact, this real present to you is its
awareness of your
awareness of your presence.
In fact, this real present to you is its
awareness of your presence. It's
awareness of your presence. It's very
aware
aware that
aware that you're
aware that you're present
aware that you're present and
aware that you're present and it
registers
registers every
aware that you're present and it
registers every tiny
registers every tiny little
aware that you're present and it
registers every tiny little thing
registers every tiny little thing about
your
your presence.
It
It looks
your presence.
It looks at
It looks at you
your presence.
It looks at you like
It looks at you like that.
I
I say
I say to
I say to myself,
I say to myself, why
I say to myself, why do
I say to myself, why do I
I say to myself, why do I love
I say to myself, why do I love them?
They're
They're so
I say to myself, why do I love them?
They're so stupid.
They're so stupid. They
I say to myself, why do I love them?
They're so stupid. They just
They're so stupid. They just stand
I say to myself, why do I love them?
They're so stupid. They just stand there
looking
looking at
looking at me.
They're
They're not
looking at me.
They're not like
They're not like a
looking at me.
They're not like a dog
They're not like a dog that
looking at me.
They're not like a dog that wags
They're not like a dog that wags his
tail
tail and
tail and hugs
tail and hugs you.
tail and hugs you. No,
tail and hugs you. No, a
tail and hugs you. No, a llama
tail and hugs you. No, a llama won't
tail and hugs you. No, a llama won't hug
you
you at
tail and hugs you. No, a llama won't hug
you at all.
They
They just
They just stand
They just stand there
They just stand there but
They just stand there but they're
extremely
extremely aware
They just stand there but they're
extremely aware of
extremely aware of your
They just stand there but they're
extremely aware of your awareness
extremely aware of your awareness of
their
their awareness.
their awareness. So
their awareness. So there's
their awareness. So there's a
their awareness. So there's a mutual
awareness
awareness and
their awareness. So there's a mutual
awareness and there's
awareness and there's a
their awareness. So there's a mutual
awareness and there's a very
awareness and there's a very subtle
awareness.
awareness. They
awareness. They stand
awareness. They stand there
awareness. They stand there amongst
themselves
themselves and
awareness. They stand there amongst
themselves and one
themselves and one just
awareness. They stand there amongst
themselves and one just goes
themselves and one just goes like
awareness. They stand there amongst
themselves and one just goes like this
and
and then
and then that's
and then that's a
and then that's a big
and then that's a big signal
and then that's a big signal for
and then that's a big signal for the
others
others who
and then that's a big signal for the
others who then
others who then go
and
and this
and this one
and this one goes
and this one goes that's
and this one goes that's a
and this one goes that's a conversation
amongst
amongst all
and this one goes that's a conversation
amongst all these
and
and and
and and the
and and the one
and and the one who
and and the one who rules
and and the one who rules the
and and the one who rules the rules
and and the one who rules the rules she
goes
and
and everybody
and everybody just
and everybody just you
and everybody just you all
and everybody just you all back
and everybody just you all back off
and everybody just you all back off and
if
if you
and everybody just you all back off and
if you don't
if you don't back
and everybody just you all back off and
if you don't back off
if you don't back off she
and everybody just you all back off and
if you don't back off she spits
if you don't back off she spits at
and everybody just you all back off and
if you don't back off she spits at Yeah.
Oh
Oh golly.
Well,
Well, the
Oh golly.
Well, the discovery
Well, the discovery that
Oh golly.
Well, the discovery that animals
Well, the discovery that animals are
capable
capable of
capable of love,
capable of love, you
capable of love, you know,
capable of love, you know, is
capable of love, you know, is something
we
we just
capable of love, you know, is something
we just discovered
we just discovered ourself.
capable of love, you know, is something
we just discovered ourself. Okay.
Everybody
Everybody knows
Everybody knows that
Everybody knows that on
Everybody knows that on a
Everybody knows that on a common
Everybody knows that on a common basis,
but
but I
Everybody knows that on a common basis,
but I mean
but I mean to
Everybody knows that on a common basis,
but I mean to validate
but I mean to validate it.
All
All right.
All right. The
All right. The way
All right. The way to
All right. The way to reach
enlightenment
enlightenment is
All right. The way to reach
enlightenment is very
enlightenment is very simple.
First
First of
First of all,
First of all, one
First of all, one chooses
First of all, one chooses it.
uh
uh one
First of all, one chooses it.
uh one tries
uh one tries to
First of all, one chooses it.
uh one tries to find
uh one tries to find a
First of all, one chooses it.
uh one tries to find a teacher
uh one tries to find a teacher that
calibrates
uh
uh at
calibrates
uh at a
uh at a level
calibrates
uh at a level that
uh at a level that you
calibrates
uh at a level that you can
uh at a level that you can resonate
with.
Just
Just because
with.
Just because a
Just because a teacher
with.
Just because a teacher is
Just because a teacher is calibrates
very
very high
very high doesn't
very high doesn't mean
very high doesn't mean you're
necessarily
necessarily going
very high doesn't mean you're
necessarily going to
necessarily going to resonate
very high doesn't mean you're
necessarily going to resonate with
necessarily going to resonate with him.
Your
Your best
Your best teacher
Your best teacher may
Your best teacher may be
Your best teacher may be somebody
Your best teacher may be somebody um
who's
who's just
Your best teacher may be somebody um
who's just a
who's just a great
Your best teacher may be somebody um
who's just a great pal.
who's just a great pal. It
Your best teacher may be somebody um
who's just a great pal. It makes
who's just a great pal. It makes you
Your best teacher may be somebody um
who's just a great pal. It makes you and
makes
makes you
makes you change
makes you change your
makes you change your mind.
makes you change your mind. You're
makes you change your mind. You're not
going
going to
makes you change your mind. You're not
going to do
going to do any
makes you change your mind. You're not
going to do any more
going to do any more mugging
makes you change your mind. You're not
going to do any more mugging anymore.
He's
He's a
He's a great
He's a great great
He's a great great teacher.
He's a great great teacher. There
He's a great great teacher. There was
He's a great great teacher. There was a
famous
famous teacher
He's a great great teacher. There was a
famous teacher of
famous teacher of the
He's a great great teacher. There was a
famous teacher of the course
famous teacher of the course of
He's a great great teacher. There was a
famous teacher of the course of miracles
who
who used
who used to
who used to be
who used to be a
who used to be a mugger
who used to be a mugger and
who used to be a mugger and he
who used to be a mugger and he died
who used to be a mugger and he died some
years
years ago
who used to be a mugger and he died some
years ago and
years ago and uh
who used to be a mugger and he died some
years ago and uh he
years ago and uh he would
who used to be a mugger and he died some
years ago and uh he would always
years ago and uh he would always say
who used to be a mugger and he died some
years ago and uh he would always say you
know
know he
know he was
know he was a
know he was a mugger
know he was a mugger on
know he was a mugger on the
know he was a mugger on the streets
know he was a mugger on the streets of
New
New York
know he was a mugger on the streets of
New York City.
New York City. He'd
know he was a mugger on the streets of
New York City. He'd say
New York City. He'd say we
know he was a mugger on the streets of
New York City. He'd say we stay
New York City. He'd say we stay on
know he was a mugger on the streets of
New York City. He'd say we stay on the
street
street corner
street corner and
street corner and we
street corner and we just
street corner and we just knew
street corner and we just knew who
street corner and we just knew who was
muggable.
muggable. We
street corner and we just knew who was
muggable. We just
muggable. We just knew
street corner and we just knew who was
muggable. We just knew you
muggable. We just knew you know
street corner and we just knew who was
muggable. We just knew you know this
muggable. We just knew you know this one
was
was easy
and
and uh
was easy
and uh he
and uh he then
was easy
and uh he then later
and uh he then later sort
was easy
and uh he then later sort of
and uh he then later sort of converted
and
and became
and became a
and became a teacher
and became a teacher of
and became a teacher of the
and became a teacher of the course
and became a teacher of the course of
miracles
miracles and
and became a teacher of the course of
miracles and interesting.
Anyway,
Anyway, we
Anyway, we all
Anyway, we all we
Anyway, we all we all
Anyway, we all we all do
Anyway, we all we all do we
Anyway, we all we all do we all
interested
interested in
Anyway, we all we all do we all
interested in spirituality
interested in spirituality as
Anyway, we all we all do we all
interested in spirituality as a
interested in spirituality as a subject
as
as a
as a as
as a as a
as a as a direction
as a as a direction to
as a as a direction to go.
So
So most
as a as a direction to go.
So most people
So most people are
as a as a direction to go.
So most people are reasonably
intelligent
intelligent who
intelligent who choose
intelligent who choose this
intelligent who choose this kind
intelligent who choose this kind of
intelligent who choose this kind of a
pathway
pathway and
intelligent who choose this kind of a
pathway and they
pathway and they may
intelligent who choose this kind of a
pathway and they may check
pathway and they may check it
intelligent who choose this kind of a
pathway and they may check it out.
pathway and they may check it out. Some
people
people go
people go directly
people go directly into
people go directly into a
people go directly into a religion
people go directly into a religion and
just
just follow
people go directly into a religion and
just follow that
just follow that religion
people go directly into a religion and
just follow that religion uh
just follow that religion uh sort
people go directly into a religion and
just follow that religion uh sort of
rotely.
rotely. Other
rotely. Other people
rotely. Other people there's
rotely. Other people there's a
rotely. Other people there's a certain
period
period of
rotely. Other people there's a certain
period of searching
period of searching certain
rotely. Other people there's a certain
period of searching certain turning
around
around looking
around looking for
around looking for greater
around looking for greater meaning
around looking for greater meaning in
life
life or
around looking for greater meaning in
life or they
life or they maybe
around looking for greater meaning in
life or they maybe read
life or they maybe read something
around looking for greater meaning in
life or they maybe read something that
inspires
inspires them
inspires them but
inspires them but and
inspires them but and for
inspires them but and for karmic
inspires them but and for karmic reasons
uh
uh unknown
or
or there
or there may
or there may be
or there may be a
or there may be a period
or there may be a period of
or there may be a period of life
or there may be a period of life you
or there may be a period of life you may
life
life may
or there may be a period of life you may
life may be
life may be very
or there may be a period of life you may
life may be very unspiritual
life may be very unspiritual then
suddenly
suddenly wham
suddenly wham you're
suddenly wham you're suddenly
suddenly wham you're suddenly interested
it's
it's as
suddenly wham you're suddenly interested
it's as though
it's as though that
suddenly wham you're suddenly interested
it's as though that cycle
it's as though that cycle of
suddenly wham you're suddenly interested
it's as though that cycle of life
it's as though that cycle of life has
come
come up
come up now
come up now and
come up now and now
come up now and now this
come up now and now this priority
come up now and now this priority is
coming
coming up
you
you find
you find a
you find a teacher
you find a teacher that
you find a teacher that to
you find a teacher that to whom
you find a teacher that to whom you
you find a teacher that to whom you can
relate
This
This needs
This needs to
This needs to make
This needs to make sense.
It
It has
This needs to make sense.
It has to
It has to be
This needs to make sense.
It has to be a
It has to be a person
This needs to make sense.
It has to be a person that
It has to be a person that you
This needs to make sense.
It has to be a person that you can
relate
relate to.
relate to. Then
relate to. Then um
relate to. Then um the
relate to. Then um the next
relate to. Then um the next thing
relate to. Then um the next thing would
be
be to
relate to. Then um the next thing would
be to check
be to check that
relate to. Then um the next thing would
be to check that person
be to check that person out
relate to. Then um the next thing would
be to check that person out with
kinesiology
or
or get
kinesiology
or get somebody
or get somebody that
kinesiology
or get somebody that knows
or get somebody that knows how
kinesiology
or get somebody that knows how to
or get somebody that knows how to do
kinesiology
or get somebody that knows how to do it.
As
As I
As I say,
As I say, kinesiology
As I say, kinesiology is
As I say, kinesiology is boring,
As I say, kinesiology is boring, but
there's
there's a
As I say, kinesiology is boring, but
there's a lot
there's a lot of
As I say, kinesiology is boring, but
there's a lot of people
there's a lot of people do
As I say, kinesiology is boring, but
there's a lot of people do it.
Or
Or I'm
Or I'm going
Or I'm going to
Or I'm going to try
Or I'm going to try to
Or I'm going to try to list
Or I'm going to try to list everyone
Or I'm going to try to list everyone I
can
can think
Or I'm going to try to list everyone I
can think of
can think of in
Or I'm going to try to list everyone I
can think of in this
can think of in this next
Or I'm going to try to list everyone I
can think of in this next book
can think of in this next book I'm
to
to come
to come out
to come out with.
to come out with. And
to come out with. And you
to come out with. And you can
to come out with. And you can just
to come out with. And you can just look
them
them up
to come out with. And you can just look
them up and
the
the stand
the stand on
the stand on your
the stand on your head
the stand on your head and
the stand on your head and breathe
through
through your
the stand on your head and breathe
through your nose
through your nose group.
the stand on your head and breathe
through your nose group. We
through your nose group. We go
the stand on your head and breathe
through your nose group. We go with
through your nose group. We go with the
calibrate.
calibrate. Okay.
calibrate. Okay. Uh
calibrate. Okay. Uh because
calibrate. Okay. Uh because there's
calibrate. Okay. Uh because there's all
kinds
kinds of
calibrate. Okay. Uh because there's all
kinds of strange
kinds of strange teachings.
calibrate. Okay. Uh because there's all
kinds of strange teachings. Some
kinds of strange teachings. Some of
calibrate. Okay. Uh because there's all
kinds of strange teachings. Some of them
are
are so
are so outlandish.
are so outlandish. I
are so outlandish. I don't
are so outlandish. I don't know.
are so outlandish. I don't know. Anybody
could
could assume
are so outlandish. I don't know. Anybody
could assume there
could assume there there's
are so outlandish. I don't know. Anybody
could assume there there's any
could assume there there's any truth
are so outlandish. I don't know. Anybody
could assume there there's any truth to
them,
them, but
them, but they
them, but they do.
them, but they do. So
them, but they do. So the
them, but they do. So the fact
them, but they do. So the fact that
them, but they do. So the fact that it's
in
in a
them, but they do. So the fact that it's
in a spiritual
in a spiritual library
them, but they do. So the fact that it's
in a spiritual library or
in a spiritual library or a
them, but they do. So the fact that it's
in a spiritual library or a spiritual
bookstore
bookstore doesn't
bookstore doesn't mean
bookstore doesn't mean anything.
bookstore doesn't mean anything. And
I've
I've said
bookstore doesn't mean anything. And
I've said many
I've said many a
bookstore doesn't mean anything. And
I've said many a time
I've said many a time and
bookstore doesn't mean anything. And
I've said many a time and everybody's
heard
heard me
heard me say
heard me say it.
heard me say it. Uh
heard me say it. Uh you
heard me say it. Uh you can
heard me say it. Uh you can go
heard me say it. Uh you can go through
your
your spiritual
heard me say it. Uh you can go through
your spiritual booksh
your spiritual booksh uh
heard me say it. Uh you can go through
your spiritual booksh uh bookstore
your spiritual booksh uh bookstore at
home
home and
home and all
home and all the
home and all the books
home and all the books that
home and all the books that make
home and all the books that make you
home and all the books that make you go
weak
weak throw
home and all the books that make you go
weak throw them
weak throw them in
home and all the books that make you go
weak throw them in one
weak throw them in one pile
home and all the books that make you go
weak throw them in one pile and
weak throw them in one pile and all
home and all the books that make you go
weak throw them in one pile and all the
books
books that
books that make
books that make you
books that make you strong
books that make you strong throw
books that make you strong throw them
books that make you strong throw them in
another
another pile
books that make you strong throw them in
another pile and
another pile and you
books that make you strong throw them in
another pile and you will
another pile and you will see
books that make you strong throw them in
another pile and you will see right
another pile and you will see right away
what
what is
what is sort
what is sort of
what is sort of astral
what is sort of astral diversion
what is sort of astral diversion and
that
that which
what is sort of astral diversion and
that which is
that which is truth.
what is sort of astral diversion and
that which is truth. All
that which is truth. All the
what is sort of astral diversion and
that which is truth. All the books
that which is truth. All the books about
the
the end
the end times
the end times coming
the end times coming and
the end times coming and all
the end times coming and all you'll
the end times coming and all you'll find
they
they all
the end times coming and all you'll find
they all end
they all end up
the end times coming and all you'll find
they all end up on
they all end up on this
the end times coming and all you'll find
they all end up on this pile
they all end up on this pile over
the end times coming and all you'll find
they all end up on this pile over here.
Uh
Uh a
Uh a lot
Uh a lot of
Uh a lot of channelings
Uh a lot of channelings by
Uh a lot of channelings by Baba
Uh a lot of channelings by Baba this
Uh a lot of channelings by Baba this and
Baba
Baba that.
Uh a lot of channelings by Baba this and
Baba that. The
Baba that. The word
Uh a lot of channelings by Baba this and
Baba that. The word Baba
Baba that. The word Baba for
Uh a lot of channelings by Baba this and
Baba that. The word Baba for some
Baba that. The word Baba for some reason
itself
itself is
itself is not
itself is not so
itself is not so great.
Baba
Baba cal
itself is not so great.
Baba cal the
Baba cal the term
itself is not so great.
Baba cal the term Baba
Baba cal the term Baba calates
itself is not so great.
Baba cal the term Baba calates over
Baba cal the term Baba calates over 200
resist
resist the
resist the term
resist the term Baba
resist the term Baba as
resist the term Baba as used
resist the term Baba as used in
resist the term Baba as used in modern
America
America is
resist the term Baba as used in modern
America is over
America is over 200
resist the term Baba as used in modern
America is over 200 resist
America is over 200 resist 202
baba
baba is
baba is not
baba is not such
baba is not such a
baba is not such a great
baba is not such a great title.
baba is not such a great title. So
baba is not such a great title. So okay,
uh
anyway,
anyway, you
anyway, you you
anyway, you you try
anyway, you you try to
anyway, you you try to find
anyway, you you try to find somebody
anyway, you you try to find somebody who
who
who you
anyway, you you try to find somebody who
who you can
who you can resonate,
anyway, you you try to find somebody who
who you can resonate, make
who you can resonate, make sense.
anyway, you you try to find somebody who
who you can resonate, make sense. Um
uh
uh if
uh if there's
uh if there's a
uh if there's a teacher
uh if there's a teacher around,
uh if there's a teacher around, great.
Uh
Uh find
uh if there's a teacher around, great.
Uh find one
Uh find one that
uh if there's a teacher around, great.
Uh find one that calibrates
Uh find one that calibrates uh
reasonably
reasonably high.
And
And then
reasonably high.
And then see
And then see enlightenment
reasonably high.
And then see enlightenment is
And then see enlightenment is different
than
than salvation.
It
It doesn't
than salvation.
It doesn't have
It doesn't have anything
than salvation.
It doesn't have anything to
It doesn't have anything to do
than salvation.
It doesn't have anything to do with
It doesn't have anything to do with good
personhood.
Has
Has nothing
personhood.
Has nothing to
Has nothing to do
personhood.
Has nothing to do with
Has nothing to do with good
personhood.
Has nothing to do with good personhood.
It
It has
It has to
It has to do
It has to do with
It has to do with a
It has to do with a a
It has to do with a a drive
It has to do with a a drive to
It has to do with a a drive to realize
the
the truth.
It has to do with a a drive to realize
the truth. Um
the
the teachings
the teachings of
the teachings of the
the teachings of the Buddha
the teachings of the Buddha are
the teachings of the Buddha are of
course
course the
the teachings of the Buddha are of
course the traditional
course the traditional the
the teachings of the Buddha are of
course the traditional the ancient
course the traditional the ancient vidas
have
have uh
have uh uh
have uh uh profound
have uh uh profound truth.
You
You try
have uh uh profound truth.
You try to
You try to find
have uh uh profound truth.
You try to find something
You try to find something that
have uh uh profound truth.
You try to find something that there's
enough
enough information
enough information so
enough information so as
enough information so as to
enough information so as to be
comprehensible.
There
There are
There are a
There are a number
There are a number of
There are a number of teachers
There are a number of teachers in
There are a number of teachers in the
700s
700s who
There are a number of teachers in the
700s who I
700s who I respect
There are a number of teachers in the
700s who I respect and
700s who I respect and uh
There are a number of teachers in the
700s who I respect and uh refer
700s who I respect and uh refer to.
Their
Their teachings
Their teachings are
Their teachings are cryptic.
Their teachings are cryptic. Uh
there's
there's no
Their teachings are cryptic. Uh
there's no explanation.
there's no explanation. So
Their teachings are cryptic. Uh
there's no explanation. So that
there's no explanation. So that um
Their teachings are cryptic. Uh
there's no explanation. So that um you
can't
can't make
can't make it
can't make it work
can't make it work for
can't make it work for you.
can't make it work for you. You
can't make it work for you. You just
start
start to
can't make it work for you. You just
start to feel
start to feel bad
can't make it work for you. You just
start to feel bad that
start to feel bad that you
can't make it work for you. You just
start to feel bad that you haven't
reached
reached the
reached the level
reached the level where
reached the level where you
reached the level where you can
understand
understand what
reached the level where you can
understand what that
understand what that means.
reached the level where you can
understand what that means. But
understand what that means. But it
doesn't
doesn't there
doesn't there isn't
doesn't there isn't sufficient
doesn't there isn't sufficient meat
doesn't there isn't sufficient meat to
the
the bones.
doesn't there isn't sufficient meat to
the bones. So
the bones. So some
doesn't there isn't sufficient meat to
the bones. So some teachings
the bones. So some teachings to
doesn't there isn't sufficient meat to
the bones. So some teachings to me
the bones. So some teachings to me are
just
just too
just too too
just too too much
just too too much bones.
Um
Um so
just too too much bones.
Um so anyway
Um so anyway you
just too too much bones.
Um so anyway you want
Um so anyway you want to
just too too much bones.
Um so anyway you want to calibrate
Um so anyway you want to calibrate the
level
level of
level of the
level of the teacher
level of the teacher or
level of the teacher or the
level of the teacher or the writing
level of the teacher or the writing of
the
the book
level of the teacher or the writing of
the book the
the book the the
level of the teacher or the writing of
the book the the mantra
the book the the mantra whatever
level of the teacher or the writing of
the book the the mantra whatever way
you're
you're following
the
the the
you're following
the the direct
the the direct path
you're following
the the direct path the
the the direct path the direct
you're following
the the direct path the direct path
is
is through
is through consciousness
is through consciousness itself.
There
There is
is through consciousness itself.
There is a
There is a teacher
is through consciousness itself.
There is a teacher I
There is a teacher I hold
is through consciousness itself.
There is a teacher I hold in
There is a teacher I hold in high
is through consciousness itself.
There is a teacher I hold in high esteem
in
in Korea.
in Korea. If
in Korea. If you
in Korea. If you ask
in Korea. If you ask her
in Korea. If you ask her what
in Korea. If you ask her what school
in Korea. If you ask her what school do
you
you represent?
in Korea. If you ask her what school do
you represent? She
you represent? She says
in Korea. If you ask her what school do
you represent? She says none.
Well
Well right
Well right that
Well right that that
Well right that that sounded
Well right that that sounded good.
Well right that that sounded good. I
said,
said, "So
Well right that that sounded good. I
said, "So what
said, "So what do
Well right that that sounded good. I
said, "So what do you
said, "So what do you do?"
Well right that that sounded good. I
said, "So what do you do?" She
said, "So what do you do?" She said,
Well right that that sounded good. I
said, "So what do you do?" She said, "We
just
just meditate."
just meditate." Wow,
just meditate." Wow, that
just meditate." Wow, that was
just meditate." Wow, that was great.
just meditate." Wow, that was great. All
right.
right. So
just meditate." Wow, that was great. All
right. So her
right. So her ways
just meditate." Wow, that was great. All
right. So her ways then
right. So her ways then is
just meditate." Wow, that was great. All
right. So her ways then is to
right. So her ways then is to discover
the
the truth
the truth through
the truth through consciousness
the truth through consciousness itself,
which
which is
the truth through consciousness itself,
which is what
which is what I
the truth through consciousness itself,
which is what I wrote
which is what I wrote about
the truth through consciousness itself,
which is what I wrote about in
which is what I wrote about in eye
the truth through consciousness itself,
which is what I wrote about in eye of
the
the eye
the eye or
the eye or else
the eye or else I
the eye or else I wrote
the eye or else I wrote it
the eye or else I wrote it in
the eye or else I wrote it in I
the eye or else I wrote it in I I
the eye or else I wrote it in I I forget
which.
which. But
when
when you
when you sit
when you sit down
when you sit down to
when you sit down to meditate,
when you sit down to meditate, you
notice
notice that
when you sit down to meditate, you
notice that the
notice that the mind
when you sit down to meditate, you
notice that the mind is
notice that the mind is constantly
racing
racing and
racing and running
racing and running around
racing and running around and
racing and running around and um
racing and running around and um a
racing and running around and um a lot
of
of teachings
racing and running around and um a lot
of teachings try
of teachings try to
racing and running around and um a lot
of teachings try to teach
of teachings try to teach you
racing and running around and um a lot
of teachings try to teach you how
of teachings try to teach you how to
control
control it.
control it. You
control it. You can't
control it. You can't control
control it. You can't control it.
control it. You can't control it. You
don't
don't have
control it. You can't control it. You
don't have any
don't have any control
control it. You can't control it. You
don't have any control over
don't have any control over the
control it. You can't control it. You
don't have any control over the mind.
The
The mind
The mind uh
The mind uh exists
The mind uh exists of
The mind uh exists of its
The mind uh exists of its own
The mind uh exists of its own nature
The mind uh exists of its own nature and
it
it just
The mind uh exists of its own nature and
it just runs
it just runs about
The mind uh exists of its own nature and
it just runs about and
it just runs about and does
The mind uh exists of its own nature and
it just runs about and does its
it just runs about and does its own
thing
thing just
thing just like
thing just like the
thing just like the body
thing just like the body does.
thing just like the body does. There's
no
no point
thing just like the body does. There's
no point to
no point to try
thing just like the body does. There's
no point to try to
no point to try to control
thing just like the body does. There's
no point to try to control it.
What
What you
What you do
What you do is
What you do is you
What you do is you you
What you do is you you observe
What you do is you you observe what
What you do is you you observe what is
what
what is
What you do is you you observe what is
what is it
what is it that's
What you do is you you observe what is
what is it that's witnessing
what is it that's witnessing and
What you do is you you observe what is
what is it that's witnessing and aware
of
of the
of the thoughts.
of the thoughts. The
of the thoughts. The first
of the thoughts. The first thing
of the thoughts. The first thing to
of the thoughts. The first thing to do
is
is realize
of the thoughts. The first thing to do
is realize I'm
is realize I'm not
of the thoughts. The first thing to do
is realize I'm not the
is realize I'm not the body.
of the thoughts. The first thing to do
is realize I'm not the body. The
is realize I'm not the body. The next
thing
thing is
thing is to
thing is to realize
thing is to realize I
thing is to realize I am
thing is to realize I am not
thing is to realize I am not the
thoughts.
You
You know
You know you're
You know you're not
You know you're not the
You know you're not the thoughts.
You know you're not the thoughts. And
you
you know
You know you're not the thoughts. And
you know you're
you know you're not
You know you're not the thoughts. And
you know you're not the
you know you're not the mind
You know you're not the thoughts. And
you know you're not the mind because
you know you're not the mind because if
you
you told
you told the
you told the mind
you told the mind stop
you told the mind stop thinking
you told the mind stop thinking if
you told the mind stop thinking if you
were
were the
you told the mind stop thinking if you
were the mind
were the mind it
you told the mind stop thinking if you
were the mind it would
were the mind it would stop.
Try
Try telling
Try telling your
Try telling your mind
Try telling your mind stop
Try telling your mind stop thinking.
Couldn't
Couldn't care
Try telling your mind stop thinking.
Couldn't care less
Couldn't care less what
Try telling your mind stop thinking.
Couldn't care less what you
Couldn't care less what you said.
Try telling your mind stop thinking.
Couldn't care less what you said. Goes
right
right on
right on thinking.
Now
Now if
right on thinking.
Now if you
Now if you were
right on thinking.
Now if you were the
Now if you were the mind
right on thinking.
Now if you were the mind it
Now if you were the mind it would
right on thinking.
Now if you were the mind it would just
obey
obey you
obey you and
obey you and you
obey you and you would
obey you and you would say
obey you and you would say and
obey you and you would say and it
obey you and you would say and it would
stop
stop thinking.
obey you and you would say and it would
stop thinking. The
stop thinking. The fact
obey you and you would say and it would
stop thinking. The fact that
stop thinking. The fact that it
obey you and you would say and it would
stop thinking. The fact that it doesn't
stop
stop thinking
stop thinking is
stop thinking is because
stop thinking is because you
stop thinking is because you you
stop thinking is because you you are
stop thinking is because you you are not
the
the mind.
stop thinking is because you you are not
the mind. You
the mind. You the
stop thinking is because you you are not
the mind. You the mind
the mind. You the mind belongs
stop thinking is because you you are not
the mind. You the mind belongs to
the mind. You the mind belongs to the
world
world like
world like the
world like the body
world like the body does.
Uh
Uh you
world like the body does.
Uh you can
Uh you can tell
world like the body does.
Uh you can tell the
Uh you can tell the body
world like the body does.
Uh you can tell the body go
Uh you can tell the body go without
oxygen
oxygen but
oxygen but it
oxygen but it won't
oxygen but it won't last
oxygen but it won't last long.
The
The body
oxygen but it won't last long.
The body is
The body is a
oxygen but it won't last long.
The body is a manifestation
The body is a manifestation of
oxygen but it won't last long.
The body is a manifestation of the
The body is a manifestation of the world
and
and so
and so is
and so is the
and so is the mind
and so is the mind and
and so is the mind and its
and so is the mind and its content
and so is the mind and its content is
programmed
programmed by
and so is the mind and its content is
programmed by society
and
and uh
and uh you
and uh you don't
and uh you don't have
and uh you don't have any
and uh you don't have any control
and uh you don't have any control over
that
that either.
There
There is
There is a
There is a substrate.
There is a substrate. What
There is a substrate. What is
There is a substrate. What is it
There is a substrate. What is it that
got
got programmed
There is a substrate. What is it that
got programmed there?
got programmed there? So
There is a substrate. What is it that
got programmed there? So the
got programmed there? So the innate
nature
nature of
nature of the
nature of the mind
nature of the mind is
nature of the mind is the
nature of the mind is the hardware.
nature of the mind is the hardware. The
thoughts
thoughts are
nature of the mind is the hardware. The
thoughts are the
thoughts are the software.
nature of the mind is the hardware. The
thoughts are the software. What
thoughts are the software. What happens
is
is the
is the innocent
is the innocent mind
is the innocent mind comes
is the innocent mind comes in
consciousness
consciousness with
is the innocent mind comes in
consciousness with no
consciousness with no content.
However,
However, it
However, it has
However, it has proclivities
However, it has proclivities which
However, it has proclivities which are
karmic
karmic proclivities
However, it has proclivities which are
karmic proclivities but
karmic proclivities but no
However, it has proclivities which are
karmic proclivities but no specific
content.
content. Then
content. Then society
content. Then society starts
content. Then society starts to
content. Then society starts to program
it
it and
content. Then society starts to program
it and so
it and so the
content. Then society starts to program
it and so the software
it and so the software begins
content. Then society starts to program
it and so the software begins to
it and so the software begins to pour
in.
in. So
in. So when
in. So when you
in. So when you start
in. So when you start to
in. So when you start to meditate
in. So when you start to meditate what
you're
you're what's
in. So when you start to meditate what
you're what's happening
you're what's happening is
in. So when you start to meditate what
you're what's happening is sort
you're what's happening is sort of
in. So when you start to meditate what
you're what's happening is sort of that
your
your hardware
your hardware is
your hardware is looking
your hardware is looking at
your hardware is looking at your
software.
The
The innate
The innate innocence
The innate innocence the
the
the capacity
The innate innocence the
the capacity for
the capacity for awareness
The innate innocence the
the capacity for awareness without
the capacity for awareness without any
content
content is
content is still
content is still existent
content is still existent within
content is still existent within you.
The
The only
content is still existent within you.
The only reason
The only reason you
content is still existent within you.
The only reason you realize
The only reason you realize that
content is still existent within you.
The only reason you realize that the
mind
mind is
mind is thinking
mind is thinking is
mind is thinking is because
mind is thinking is because the
thinkingness
thinkingness is
mind is thinking is because the
thinkingness is happening
thinkingness is happening against
mind is thinking is because the
thinkingness is happening against the
background
background of
background of non-thinkingness.
The
The only
background of non-thinkingness.
The only reason
The only reason you
background of non-thinkingness.
The only reason you can
The only reason you can hear
background of non-thinkingness.
The only reason you can hear sound
The only reason you can hear sound is
because
because sound
because sound occurs
because sound occurs against
because sound occurs against the
background
background of
because sound occurs against the
background of silence.
Uh
Uh the
Uh the u
the
the generally
Uh the u
the generally the
the generally the paths
Uh the u
the generally the paths to
the generally the paths to God
Uh the u
the generally the paths to God are
described
described as
described as through
described as through the
described as through the heart
described as through the heart and
through
through the
described as through the heart and
through the mind.
through the mind. We're
described as through the heart and
through the mind. We're going
through the mind. We're going to
described as through the heart and
through the mind. We're going to stop
through the mind. We're going to stop in
about
about two
about two seconds.
You
You can
about two seconds.
You can see
You can see that
about two seconds.
You can see that they
You can see that they are
about two seconds.
You can see that they are combined.
You
You have
You have to
You have to love
You have to love the
You have to love the way
You have to love the way of
You have to love the way of the
You have to love the way of the mind
enough
enough to
You have to love the way of the mind
enough to go
enough to go through
You have to love the way of the mind
enough to go through the
enough to go through the sacrifice
because
because once
because once you
because once you get
because once you get on
because once you get on the
because once you get on the edge
because once you get on the edge of
because once you get on the edge of the
knife,
knife, you
because once you get on the edge of the
knife, you cannot
knife, you cannot stop.
The
The other
The other thing
The other thing about
The other thing about spiritual
The other thing about spiritual work
that
that people
The other thing about spiritual work
that people don't
that people don't understand
The other thing about spiritual work
that people don't understand is
that people don't understand is it's
The other thing about spiritual work
that people don't understand is it's not
just
just a
just a sporadic
just a sporadic thing
just a sporadic thing you
just a sporadic thing you do
just a sporadic thing you do now
just a sporadic thing you do now and
then.
then. When
just a sporadic thing you do now and
then. When you
then. When you decide
just a sporadic thing you do now and
then. When you decide to
then. When you decide to go
just a sporadic thing you do now and
then. When you decide to go for
then. When you decide to go for it,
you're
you're on
you're on the
you're on the edge
you're on the edge of
you're on the edge of the
you're on the edge of the knife
you're on the edge of the knife and
you're on the edge of the knife and you
cannot
cannot stop.
This
This is
This is it.
You
You let
This is it.
You let go
You let go and
This is it.
You let go and surrender
You let go and surrender everything.
Every
Every tone
Every tone as
Every tone as it
Every tone as it arises
Every tone as it arises is
Every tone as it arises is let
Every tone as it arises is let go
Every tone as it arises is let go of.
You're
You're not
Every tone as it arises is let go of.
You're not going
You're not going to
Every tone as it arises is let go of.
You're not going to sit
You're not going to sit back
Every tone as it arises is let go of.
You're not going to sit back and
You're not going to sit back and enjoy
the
the melody
the melody of
the melody of the
the melody of the symphony.
the melody of the symphony. Because
the melody of the symphony. Because as
the
the note
the melody of the symphony. Because as
the note arises,
the note arises, you've
the melody of the symphony. Because as
the note arises, you've already
the note arises, you've already let
the melody of the symphony. Because as
the note arises, you've already let it
go.
go. You
go. You see,
go. You see, you
go. You see, you would
go. You see, you would have
go. You see, you would have to
go. You see, you would have to hold
go. You see, you would have to hold it
to
to compare
go. You see, you would have to hold it
to compare it
to compare it with
go. You see, you would have to hold it
to compare it with the
to compare it with the other
go. You see, you would have to hold it
to compare it with the other notes
to compare it with the other notes in
order
order to
order to get
order to get music
order to get music out
order to get music out of
order to get music out of it.
order to get music out of it. You
order to get music out of it. You hear
the
the sound
order to get music out of it. You hear
the sound of
the sound of the
order to get music out of it. You hear
the sound of the music,
the sound of the music, but
order to get music out of it. You hear
the sound of the music, but you're
the sound of the music, but you're not
going
going to
going to hear
going to hear the
going to hear the mu.
going to hear the mu. You
going to hear the mu. You hear
going to hear the mu. You hear the
sound,
sound, but
going to hear the mu. You hear the
sound, but you're
sound, but you're not
going to hear the mu. You hear the
sound, but you're not going
sound, but you're not going to
going to hear the mu. You hear the
sound, but you're not going to hear
sound, but you're not going to hear the
music.
music. You're
music. You're going to
music. You're going to hear
music. You're going to hear the
music. You're going to hear the tone.
Can
Can it
music. You're going to hear the tone.
Can it be
Can it be done?
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't know.
>> I don't know. Yes,
>> I don't know. Yes, it
>> I don't know. Yes, it can
>> I don't know. Yes, it can be
>> I don't know. Yes, it can be done.
You
You see,
because
because the
because the real
because the real energy
because the real energy behind
because the real energy behind the
because the real energy behind the love
is
is joy.
because the real energy behind the love
is joy. Yeah,
is joy. Yeah, the
because the real energy behind the love
is joy. Yeah, the joy
is joy. Yeah, the joy of
because the real energy behind the love
is joy. Yeah, the joy of it
is joy. Yeah, the joy of it isn't
because the real energy behind the love
is joy. Yeah, the joy of it isn't just
the
the love
the love of
the love of God.
the love of God. It's
the love of God. It's the
the love of God. It's the joy
which
which is
the love of God. It's the joy
which is the
which is the love
the love of God. It's the joy
which is the love of
which is the love of God.
the love of God. It's the joy
which is the love of God. manifests
within
within yourself
within yourself as
within yourself as the
within yourself as the joy
within yourself as the joy of
within yourself as the joy of spiritual
work.
work. So
within yourself as the joy of spiritual
work. So the
work. So the real
within yourself as the joy of spiritual
work. So the real energy
work. So the real energy that
within yourself as the joy of spiritual
work. So the real energy that gets
work. So the real energy that gets you
going
going and
going and keeps
going and keeps you
going and keeps you going
going and keeps you going is
going and keeps you going is the
going and keeps you going is the joy
going and keeps you going is the joy of
spiritual
spiritual work
going and keeps you going is the joy of
spiritual work itself.
Each
Each instant
Each instant is
Each instant is the
Each instant is the source
Each instant is the source of
Each instant is the source of its
Each instant is the source of its own
joy.
joy. So
Each instant is the source of its own
joy. So you
joy. So you have
Each instant is the source of its own
joy. So you have no
joy. So you have no need
Each instant is the source of its own
joy. So you have no need for
joy. So you have no need for anything
out
out in
out in the
out in the world.
out in the world. You
out in the world. You see
out in the world. You see joy
out in the world. You see joy arises
from
from the
out in the world. You see joy arises
from the awareness
from the awareness of
out in the world. You see joy arises
from the awareness of the
from the awareness of the divinity
out in the world. You see joy arises
from the awareness of the divinity of
your
your existence
your existence in
your existence in this
your existence in this moment.
Therefore,
Therefore, as
your existence in this moment.
Therefore, as you
Therefore, as you walk
your existence in this moment.
Therefore, as you walk the
Therefore, as you walk the edge
your existence in this moment.
Therefore, as you walk the edge of
Therefore, as you walk the edge of the
knife,
knife, you're
knife, you're outside
knife, you're outside of
knife, you're outside of time.
Time
Time is
knife, you're outside of time.
Time is irrelevant.
Time is irrelevant. When
knife, you're outside of time.
Time is irrelevant. When you're
Time is irrelevant. When you're on
knife, you're outside of time.
Time is irrelevant. When you're on a
tight
tight rope,
time,
time, space,
tight rope,
time, space, all
time, space, all the
tight rope,
time, space, all the stuff
time, space, all the stuff that
tight rope,
time, space, all the stuff that the
time, space, all the stuff that the mind
usually
usually plays
usually plays with
usually plays with is
usually plays with is no
usually plays with is no longer
relevant.
relevant. You're
usually plays with is no longer
relevant. You're just
relevant. You're just fixed.
usually plays with is no longer
relevant. You're just fixed. Like
the
the other
the other analogy
the other analogy I
the other analogy I use
the other analogy I use for
the other analogy I use for it
the other analogy I use for it is
the other analogy I use for it is like
the
the prow
the other analogy I use for it is like
the prow of
the prow of a
the other analogy I use for it is like
the prow of a ship.
the prow of a ship. See,
the other analogy I use for it is like
the prow of a ship. See, the
the prow of a ship. See, the prow
the other analogy I use for it is like
the prow of a ship. See, the prow of
the prow of a ship. See, the prow of the
ship
ship is
ship is consistent.
ship is consistent. No matter
ship is consistent. No matter what
ship is consistent. No matter what the
wave,
wave, no matter
ship is consistent. No matter what the
wave, no matter how
wave, no matter how high
ship is consistent. No matter what the
wave, no matter how high the
wave, no matter how high the wave,
matter
matter what
matter what the
matter what the wind.
So
So your
matter what the wind.
So your it's
So your it's called
matter what the wind.
So your it's called one-pointedness
So your it's called one-pointedness of
mind.
mind. So
mind. So that
mind. So that onepointedness
mind. So that onepointedness of
mind. So that onepointedness of mind
mind. So that onepointedness of mind is
a
a fixity
mind. So that onepointedness of mind is
a fixity of
a fixity of intention.
It
It gets
It gets its
It gets its energy
It gets its energy from
It gets its energy from the
It gets its energy from the surrender
the
the devotion
It gets its energy from the surrender
the devotion to
the devotion to the
It gets its energy from the surrender
the devotion to the joy
the devotion to the joy of
It gets its energy from the surrender
the devotion to the joy of the
the devotion to the joy of the presence
of
of God
of God which
of God which you
of God which you intuit
of God which you intuit it
of God which you intuit it but
of God which you intuit it but which
does
does not
of God which you intuit it but which
does not become
does not become a
of God which you intuit it but which
does not become a stunning
does not become a stunning awareness
until
until the
until the mind
until the mind disappears.
In
In theta,
until the mind disappears.
In theta, the
In theta, the background
until the mind disappears.
In theta, the background being
In theta, the background being that
which
which you
which you are,
it
it stands
which you are,
it stands out
it stands out and
which you are,
it stands out and the
it stands out and the form
is
sort
sort of
is
sort of translated.
It's
It's when
It's when somebody
It's when somebody speaks,
see
see what
It's when somebody speaks,
see what prevails
see what prevails is
It's when somebody speaks,
see what prevails is the
see what prevails is the silence,
then
then this
then this form
then this form comes
then this form comes about.
then this form comes about. Somebody's
mouth
mouth opens
then this form comes about. Somebody's
mouth opens and
mouth opens and all
then this form comes about. Somebody's
mouth opens and all this
mouth opens and all this form
then this form comes about. Somebody's
mouth opens and all this form comes
mouth opens and all this form comes out.
I
I don't
I don't know
I don't know what
I don't know what they're
I don't know what they're talking
I don't know what they're talking about.
And
And uh
I don't know what they're talking about.
And uh there's
And uh there's a
I don't know what they're talking about.
And uh there's a slight
And uh there's a slight delay
and
and then
and then there's
and then there's a
and then there's a knowingness
and then there's a knowingness of
and then there's a knowingness of what
is
is said
and then there's a knowingness of what
is said and
the
the the
the the Holy
the the Holy Spirit
the the Holy Spirit acts
the the Holy Spirit acts as
the the Holy Spirit acts as a
translator.
That's
That's a
That's a fact.
That's a fact. Is
That's a fact. Is it
you're
you're you're you're
That's a fact. Is it
you're you're you're like
you're you're you're like heart
That's a fact. Is it
you're you're you're like heart of
healing
healing hearing
healing hearing and
healing hearing and absent-
healing hearing and absent- minded
healing hearing and absent- minded and
you're
you're not
healing hearing and absent- minded and
you're not always
you're not always sure
healing hearing and absent- minded and
you're not always sure where
you're not always sure where your
healing hearing and absent- minded and
you're not always sure where your body
is
is in
is in space
is in space but
is in space but with
is in space but with practice
you
you get
is in space but with practice
you get better
you get better at
is in space but with practice
you get better at maneuvering
you get better at maneuvering it.
So
So there
So there are
So there are physiologic
So there are physiologic changes
there.
there. There's
So there are physiologic changes
there. There's no
there. There's no need
So there are physiologic changes
there. There's no need to
there. There's no need to eat.
Uh
there's
there's no
Uh
there's no need
there's no need to
Uh
there's no need to eat
there's no need to eat at
Uh
there's no need to eat at all.
there's no need to eat at all. Today
Uh
there's no need to eat at all. Today I
didn't
didn't eat
didn't eat anything.
didn't eat anything. I
didn't eat anything. I don't
didn't eat anything. I don't even
didn't eat anything. I don't even notice
it.
But
But I
But I tell
But I tell myself
But I tell myself that
But I tell myself that uh
But I tell myself that uh for
But I tell myself that uh for survival
of
of the
But I tell myself that uh for survival
of the body
of the body uh
But I tell myself that uh for survival
of the body uh at
of the body uh at 5:00
But I tell myself that uh for survival
of the body uh at 5:00 you
of the body uh at 5:00 you should
But I tell myself that uh for survival
of the body uh at 5:00 you should eat
something
something or
something or thereabouts.
Frankly,
Frankly, I
something or thereabouts.
Frankly, I could
Frankly, I could do
something or thereabouts.
Frankly, I could do without
Frankly, I could do without it.
something or thereabouts.
Frankly, I could do without it. So
there's
there's no
there's no desiringness
there's no desiringness for
there's no desiringness for things.
Everything
Everything is
there's no desiringness for things.
Everything is complete
Everything is complete and
there's no desiringness for things.
Everything is complete and total
Everything is complete and total at
there's no desiringness for things.
Everything is complete and total at this
instant.
Therefore,
because
because every
because every instant
because every instant is
because every instant is completely
fulfilled
fulfilled and
because every instant is completely
fulfilled and completely
fulfilled and completely total,
if
if something
if something stops
if something stops right
if something stops right there,
if something stops right there, there's
no
no loss
if something stops right there, there's
no loss because
no loss because it
if something stops right there, there's
no loss because it is
no loss because it is at
if something stops right there, there's
no loss because it is at all
no loss because it is at all times
continuously
continuously complete.
continuously complete. You
continuously complete. You understand?
Uh
Uh if
continuously complete. You understand?
Uh if the
Uh if the doorbell
continuously complete. You understand?
Uh if the doorbell rings,
Uh if the doorbell rings, you
continuously complete. You understand?
Uh if the doorbell rings, you can
Uh if the doorbell rings, you can drop
the
the piece
the piece of
the piece of pie
the piece of pie and
the piece of pie and never
the piece of pie and never go
the piece of pie and never go back
the piece of pie and never go back to
the piece of pie and never go back to it
and
and don't
the piece of pie and never go back to it
and don't miss
and don't miss the
the piece of pie and never go back to it
and don't miss the last
and don't miss the last half
the piece of pie and never go back to it
and don't miss the last half of
and don't miss the last half of the
piece
piece of
piece of pie
piece of pie because
piece of pie because every
piece of pie because every bite
piece of pie because every bite of
piece of pie because every bite of the
pie
pie is
piece of pie because every bite of the
pie is equally
pie is equally fulfilling.
piece of pie because every bite of the
pie is equally fulfilling. There's
pie is equally fulfilling. There's no
better
better or
better or worse.
So,
So, there's
better or worse.
So, there's physiologic
So, there's physiologic changes.
Um,
Um, there's
Um, there's a
Um, there's a loss
Um, there's a loss of
Um, there's a loss of t
Um, there's a loss of t startle
response.
Uh,
Uh, tennis
Uh, tennis cement
Uh, tennis cement could
Uh, tennis cement could drop
Uh, tennis cement could drop right
behind
behind his
Uh, tennis cement could drop right
behind his body
behind his body and
Uh, tennis cement could drop right
behind his body and then
behind his body and then wouldn't
Uh, tennis cement could drop right
behind his body and then wouldn't even
notice.
notice. Well,
notice. Well, it
notice. Well, it would
notice. Well, it would hear
notice. Well, it would hear it
notice. Well, it would hear it but
wouldn't
wouldn't react
notice. Well, it would hear it but
wouldn't react to
wouldn't react to it.
notice. Well, it would hear it but
wouldn't react to it. Lack
wouldn't react to it. Lack of
notice. Well, it would hear it but
wouldn't react to it. Lack of startle
response.
There's
There's a
response.
There's a slowing
There's a slowing down
response.
There's a slowing down of
There's a slowing down of the
response.
There's a slowing down of the brain
waves.
There
There is
waves.
There is not
There is not being
waves.
There is not being run
There is not being run by
waves.
There is not being run by physiologic
processes
processes processes.
Um
and
and there's
and there's a
and there's a long
and there's a long period
and there's a long period of
and there's a long period of adjustment
which
which required
and there's a long period of adjustment
which required leaving
which required leaving New
and there's a long period of adjustment
which required leaving New York
which required leaving New York City
where
where the
where the life
where the life was
where the life was quite
where the life was quite complex
where the life was quite complex and
moving
moving to
where the life was quite complex and
moving to a
moving to a very
where the life was quite complex and
moving to a very quiet
moving to a very quiet place
where the life was quite complex and
moving to a very quiet place uh
moving to a very quiet place uh and
getting
getting adjusted
getting adjusted and
getting adjusted and used
getting adjusted and used to
getting adjusted and used to it
getting adjusted and used to it all.
Yeah.
Now
Now we
Now we did
Now we did the
Now we did the archangel.
Now we did the archangel. Let's
Now we did the archangel. Let's see.
We'll
We'll make
Now we did the archangel. Let's see.
We'll make sure
We'll make sure we're
Now we did the archangel. Let's see.
We'll make sure we're going
We'll make sure we're going to
Now we did the archangel. Let's see.
We'll make sure we're going to answer
everybody's
everybody's question.
Uh
what
what holds
what holds up
what holds up spiritual
what holds up spiritual progress
what holds up spiritual progress is
resistance.
resistance. Huh?
what holds up spiritual progress is
resistance. Huh? This
resistance. Huh? This resistance
what holds up spiritual progress is
resistance. Huh? This resistance is
automatic.
automatic. You
automatic. You can
automatic. You can presume
automatic. You can presume that
automatic. You can presume that it's
going
going to
automatic. You can presume that it's
going to go
going to go about
automatic. You can presume that it's
going to go about go
going to go about go on
automatic. You can presume that it's
going to go about go on its
going to go about go on its way
automatic. You can presume that it's
going to go about go on its way because
the
the ego
the ego as
the ego as I
the ego as I explained
the ego as I explained before
the ego as I explained before has
the ego as I explained before has a
vested
vested interest
the ego as I explained before has a
vested interest in
vested interest in positions.
I
I mean
I mean the
I mean the vested
I mean the vested interest
I mean the vested interest in
I mean the vested interest in being
right.
You
You know
You know what
You know what I
You know what I mean?
You know what I mean? Hey,
You know what I mean? Hey, I'm
You know what I mean? Hey, I'm right
now.
now. People
You know what I mean? Hey, I'm right
now. People are
now. People are willing
You know what I mean? Hey, I'm right
now. People are willing to
now. People are willing to die
You know what I mean? Hey, I'm right
now. People are willing to die for
now. People are willing to die for being
right.
right. So
right. So you're
right. So you're not
right. So you're not talking
right. So you're not talking about
something
something very
right. So you're not talking about
something very this
something very this mild.
The
The ego
The ego would
The ego would just
The ego would just soon
The ego would just soon see
The ego would just soon see you
The ego would just soon see you dead
The ego would just soon see you dead as
long
long as
The ego would just soon see you dead as
long as it
long as it remains
The ego would just soon see you dead as
long as it remains right.
long as it remains right. And
The ego would just soon see you dead as
long as it remains right. And it
long as it remains right. And it kills
people
people right
people right and
people right and left
people right and left every
people right and left every day,
people right and left every day, doesn't
it?
Rather
Rather be
Rather be rather
Rather be rather die
Rather be rather die than
Rather be rather die than say
Rather be rather die than say you're
wrong.
wrong. So
Rather be rather die than say you're
wrong. So the
wrong. So the investment
Rather be rather die than say you're
wrong. So the investment that
wrong. So the investment that the
Rather be rather die than say you're
wrong. So the investment that the ego
has
has is
has is its
has is its own
has is its own survival.
The
The ego
has is its own survival.
The ego is
The ego is not
has is its own survival.
The ego is not interested
The ego is not interested in
has is its own survival.
The ego is not interested in your
survival.
You
You know
survival.
You know that
You know that your
survival.
You know that your own
You know that your own mind
survival.
You know that your own mind is
You know that your own mind is not
survival.
You know that your own mind is not even
interested
interested in
interested in your
interested in your own
interested in your own survival.
who
who put
interested in your own survival.
who put you
who put you over
interested in your own survival.
who put you over the
who put you over the cliff
interested in your own survival.
who put you over the cliff anytime
who put you over the cliff anytime it
wants
wants to
wants to to
wants to to prove
wants to to prove a
wants to to prove a point.
It's
It's not
wants to to prove a point.
It's not your
It's not your friend.
wants to to prove a point.
It's not your friend. It's
It's not your friend. It's uh
wants to to prove a point.
It's not your friend. It's uh it's
interested
interested in
interested in its
interested in its own
interested in its own narcissistic
self-satisfactions.
Its
Its prime
satisfaction,
satisfaction, its
Its prime
satisfaction, its prime
satisfaction, its prime delusion
is
the
the main
is
the main resistance
the main resistance is
the
the narcissistic
the narcissistic core.
the narcissistic core. The
the narcissistic core. The ego
is
is its
belief
belief in
belief in its
belief in its own
belief in its own sovereignty.
Becoming
Becoming enlightened
belief in its own sovereignty.
Becoming enlightened is
Becoming enlightened is really
overcoming
overcoming the
overcoming the claim
overcoming the claim and
overcoming the claim and the
overcoming the claim and the domination
of
of the
overcoming the claim and the domination
of the ego
of the ego to
overcoming the claim and the domination
of the ego to maintain
of the ego to maintain its
overcoming the claim and the domination
of the ego to maintain its sovereignty.
It
It will
It will maintain
It will maintain its
It will maintain its sovereignty
It will maintain its sovereignty at
It will maintain its sovereignty at the
price
price of
It will maintain its sovereignty at the
price of your
price of your physical
It will maintain its sovereignty at the
price of your physical life.
It
It will
It will put
It will put you
It will put you to
It will put you to death
It will put you to death anytime
It will put you to death anytime rather
than
than become
It will put you to death anytime rather
than become let
than become let you
It will put you to death anytime rather
than become let you become
than become let you become enlightened.
The
The refusal
The refusal to
The refusal to accept
The refusal to accept that
The refusal to accept that God
The refusal to accept that God is
The refusal to accept that God is the
sole
sole source
The refusal to accept that God is the
sole source of
sole source of all
The refusal to accept that God is the
sole source of all that
sole source of all that is
The refusal to accept that God is the
sole source of all that is is
sole source of all that is is the
The refusal to accept that God is the
sole source of all that is is the ego's
the
the ego
the ego would
the ego would like
the ego would like to
the ego would like to tell
the ego would like to tell you
the ego would like to tell you that
the ego would like to tell you that it
is
the
the originator
the originator of
the originator of your
the originator of your movements
the originator of your movements and
actions.
actions. Huh?
If
If we
If we look
If we look at
If we look at the
If we look at the ego,
I
I think
If we look at the ego,
I think I
I think I in
If we look at the ego,
I think I in the
I think I in the last
If we look at the ego,
I think I in the last book
I think I in the last book of
If we look at the ego,
I think I in the last book of the
I think I in the last book of the one
I'm
I'm writing
I'm writing now,
I'm writing now, I
I'm writing now, I did
I'm writing now, I did a
I'm writing now, I did a pretty
I'm writing now, I did a pretty good
I'm writing now, I did a pretty good job
in
in describing
I'm writing now, I did a pretty good job
in describing the
in describing the ego.
I'm writing now, I did a pretty good job
in describing the ego. I
in describing the ego. I got
I'm writing now, I did a pretty good job
in describing the ego. I got dead
in describing the ego. I got dead to
rights.
And
And uh
rights.
And uh the
And uh the ego
rights.
And uh the ego uh
maintains
maintains the
maintains the illusion
maintains the illusion of
maintains the illusion of sovereignty.
What
What do
maintains the illusion of sovereignty.
What do I
What do I mean
maintains the illusion of sovereignty.
What do I mean by
What do I mean by that?
maintains the illusion of sovereignty.
What do I mean by that? Well,
What do I mean by that? Well, the
maintains the illusion of sovereignty.
What do I mean by that? Well, the ego's
functions
functions are
functions are very
functions are very complex.
Uh
Uh the
functions are very complex.
Uh the ego
Uh the ego has
functions are very complex.
Uh the ego has to
Uh the ego has to sort
functions are very complex.
Uh the ego has to sort millions
Uh the ego has to sort millions of
functions are very complex.
Uh the ego has to sort millions of bits
of
of data
continuously
in
in milliseconds.
in milliseconds. It's
in milliseconds. It's processing
all
all that
in milliseconds. It's processing
all that you've
all that you've ever
in milliseconds. It's processing
all that you've ever known,
all that you've ever known, all
in milliseconds. It's processing
all that you've ever known, all your
perceptions,
perceptions, all
perceptions, all your
perceptions, all your belief
perceptions, all your belief systems,
comparing
comparing it
perceptions, all your belief systems,
comparing it with
comparing it with past,
perceptions, all your belief systems,
comparing it with past, calculating,
comparing it with past, calculating, and
it's
it's an
it's an extremely
it's an extremely complex
it's an extremely complex and
it's an extremely complex and incredible
organism
organism mechanism.
The
The ego
The ego presumes
The ego presumes that
The ego presumes that there
The ego presumes that there is
The ego presumes that there is a
The ego presumes that there is a there
is
is a
The ego presumes that there is a there
is a there
is a there is
The ego presumes that there is a there
is a there is a
is a there is a central
The ego presumes that there is a there
is a there is a central office
is a there is a central office to
The ego presumes that there is a there
is a there is a central office to its
functions.
to
to the
functions.
to the ego
to the ego has
functions.
to the ego has all
to the ego has all these
functions.
to the ego has all these complex
capacities.
capacities. Memory
capacities. Memory comparison.
capacities. Memory comparison. If
capacities. Memory comparison. If you
look
look at
capacities. Memory comparison. If you
look at a
look at a zebra,
capacities. Memory comparison. If you
look at a zebra, instantly
look at a zebra, instantly your
capacities. Memory comparison. If you
look at a zebra, instantly your mind
look at a zebra, instantly your mind is
compared
compared with
compared with every
compared with every other
compared with every other zebra
compared with every other zebra you've
ever
ever seen.
compared with every other zebra you've
ever seen. Uh
ever seen. Uh a
compared with every other zebra you've
ever seen. Uh a TV
ever seen. Uh a TV thing
compared with every other zebra you've
ever seen. Uh a TV thing about
ever seen. Uh a TV thing about zebras
comes
comes up.
comes up. Uh
comes up. Uh the
comes up. Uh the camouflage
comes up. Uh the camouflage value
comes up. Uh the camouflage value of
black
black and
comes up. Uh the camouflage value of
black and white
black and white and
comes up. Uh the camouflage value of
black and white and you
black and white and you fact
comes up. Uh the camouflage value of
black and white and you fact that
black and white and you fact that you
think
think it's
think it's BS
think it's BS theory,
think it's BS theory, it's
think it's BS theory, it's all
think it's BS theory, it's all this
passes
passes through
think it's BS theory, it's all this
passes through your
passes through your mind.
think it's BS theory, it's all this
passes through your mind. It's
passes through your mind. It's all
sorted
sorted and
sorted and and
sorted and and the
sorted and and the the
sorted and and the the the
sorted and and the the the ego
sorted and and the the the ego is
sorted and and the the the ego is a
sorted and and the the the ego is a very
complex
complex operation.
Extremely
Extremely complex.
Extremely complex. No
Extremely complex. No way
Extremely complex. No way a
Extremely complex. No way a computer
Extremely complex. No way a computer can
even
even get
Extremely complex. No way a computer can
even get near
even get near imitating
Extremely complex. No way a computer can
even get near imitating it.
even get near imitating it. Artificial
intelligence
intelligence can
intelligence can only
intelligence can only take
intelligence can only take a
intelligence can only take a small
strand
strand of
intelligence can only take a small
strand of it
strand of it which
intelligence can only take a small
strand of it which you
strand of it which you can
intelligence can only take a small
strand of it which you can follow
strand of it which you can follow with
with
with logic
with logic and
with logic and within
with logic and within the
with logic and within the differential
calculus
calculus but
with logic and within the differential
calculus but it
calculus but it cannot
with logic and within the differential
calculus but it cannot go
calculus but it cannot go to
with logic and within the differential
calculus but it cannot go to the
nonlinear
nonlinear domain
nonlinear domain because
nonlinear domain because the
nonlinear domain because the nonlinear
domain
domain by
nonlinear domain because the nonlinear
domain by definition
domain by definition is
nonlinear domain because the nonlinear
domain by definition is not
domain by definition is not knowable
nonlinear domain because the nonlinear
domain by definition is not knowable in
in
in a
in a sequential
in a sequential way.
in a sequential way. So
this
this complex
in a sequential way. So
this complex ego
this complex ego function
in a sequential way. So
this complex ego function presumes
this complex ego function presumes a
central
central control
central control office.
central control office. Hey,
central control office. Hey, this
central
central control
central control office. Hey, this
central control where
central control where all
central control office. Hey, this
central control where all its
central control where all its massive
functions
functions uh
functions uh like
functions uh like the
functions uh like the central
functions uh like the central command
functions uh like the central command is
presumed
presumed to
functions uh like the central command is
presumed to be
presumed to be the
functions uh like the central command is
presumed to be the eye.
At
At all
At all times
At all times the
At all times the ego
At all times the ego claims
At all times the ego claims to
At all times the ego claims to be
At all times the ego claims to be the
author
author of
all
all these
all these phenomena.
When
When a
all these phenomena.
When a person
When a person says
all these phenomena.
When a person says I,
When a person says I, what
all these phenomena.
When a person says I, what they're
talking
talking about
talking about is
talking about is the
talking about is the central
talking about is the central organizing
core
core of
talking about is the central organizing
core of their
core of their ego.
talking about is the central organizing
core of their ego. Yeah.
This
This central
This central organizing
This central organizing core
like
like the
This central organizing core
like the Wizard
like the Wizard of
This central organizing core
like the Wizard of Oz
like the Wizard of Oz is
This central organizing core
like the Wizard of Oz is behind
like the Wizard of Oz is behind the
screen
screen and
screen and manipulating
screen and manipulating all
screen and manipulating all this
screen and manipulating all this stuff.
Claims
Claims to
screen and manipulating all this stuff.
Claims to be
Claims to be sovereign.
screen and manipulating all this stuff.
Claims to be sovereign. Sovereign.
It
It is
It is God.
It is God. So
the
the person
It is God. So
the person then
the person then claims
It is God. So
the person then claims credit
the person then claims credit and
It is God. So
the person then claims credit and takes
blame
because
because it's
blame
because it's claimed
because it's claimed that
blame
because it's claimed that the
because it's claimed that the eye
blame
because it's claimed that the eye is
responsible.
The
The giving
responsible.
The giving up
The giving up of
responsible.
The giving up of that
The giving up of that illusion
responsible.
The giving up of that illusion is
The giving up of that illusion is what
the
the ego
the ego fights
the ego fights to
the ego fights to the
the ego fights to the death
the ego fights to the death and
the ego fights to the death and it's
really
really um
the ego fights to the death and it's
really um who
really um who is
the ego fights to the death and it's
really um who is sovereign
really um who is sovereign God
the ego fights to the death and it's
really um who is sovereign God or
really um who is sovereign God or the
ego.
The
The resistance
ego.
The resistance is
The resistance is surrendering
this
this illusion
this illusion of
this illusion of sovereignty
this illusion of sovereignty of
this illusion of sovereignty of the
narcissistic
eye
eye of
eye of the
eye of the ego
and
and realizing
that
that your
that your survival
that your survival from
that your survival from moment
that your survival from moment to
that your survival from moment to moment
everything
everything you
that your survival from moment to moment
everything you do
everything you do and
that your survival from moment to moment
everything you do and think
everything you do and think is
that your survival from moment to moment
everything you do and think is a
everything you do and think is a result
of
of the
of the presence
of the presence of
of the presence of the
of the presence of the self
of the presence of the self with
of the presence of the self with a
capital
capital S.
Small
Small self
Small self claims
Small self claims credit,
Small self claims credit, but
Small self claims credit, but it's
Small self claims credit, but it's the
the
the greater
Small self claims credit, but it's the
the greater self
the greater self that
Small self claims credit, but it's the
the greater self that is
the greater self that is the
Small self claims credit, but it's the
the greater self that is the great
sustainer
sustainer of
sustainer of your
sustainer of your life.
I
I caught
sustainer of your life.
I caught the
I caught the ego
sustainer of your life.
I caught the ego doing
I caught the ego doing that.
sustainer of your life.
I caught the ego doing that. I
I caught the ego doing that. I caught
it.
One
One time
it.
One time a
One time a rabbit
it.
One time a rabbit ran
One time a rabbit ran in
it.
One time a rabbit ran in front
One time a rabbit ran in front of
it.
One time a rabbit ran in front of the
car.
car. Instantly
car. Instantly the
car. Instantly the brake
car. Instantly the brake stopped
car. Instantly the brake stopped and
car. Instantly the brake stopped and I
caught
caught the
car. Instantly the brake stopped and I
caught the ego
caught the ego claiming
car. Instantly the brake stopped and I
caught the ego claiming credit
caught the ego claiming credit for
saving
saving the
saving the life
saving the life of
saving the life of the
saving the life of the of
saving the life of the of the
saving the life of the of the of
saving the life of the of the of the
rabbit.
rabbit. It
saving the life of the of the of the
rabbit. It claimed
rabbit. It claimed credit
saving the life of the of the of the
rabbit. It claimed credit for
rabbit. It claimed credit for making
saving the life of the of the of the
rabbit. It claimed credit for making the
it
it claimed
it claimed that
it claimed that it
it claimed that it made
it claimed that it made the
it claimed that it made the decision
it claimed that it made the decision to
put
put the
it claimed that it made the decision to
put the brake
put the brake on
it claimed that it made the decision to
put the brake on and
put the brake on and save
it claimed that it made the decision to
put the brake on and save the
put the brake on and save the rabbit's
life.
But
But it
life.
But it happened
But it happened already.
life.
But it happened already. I
But it happened already. I caught
life.
But it happened already. I caught it.
But
But it
But it was
But it was that
But it was that split
But it was that split second
But it was that split second that
But it was that split second that Buddha
was
was talking
But it was that split second that Buddha
was talking about.
was talking about. Let's
But it was that split second that Buddha
was talking about. Let's see
was talking about. Let's see how
But it was that split second that Buddha
was talking about. Let's see how long
that
that split
that split second
that split second is.
that split second is. Huh?
That
That split
that split second is. Huh?
That split second
is
is one
150 one
150 one 10,000
is one
150 one 10,000 of
150 one 10,000 of a
is one
150 one 10,000 of a second
150 one 10,000 of a second resistance.
It's
It's more
It's more than
It's more than 110th
It's more than 110th of
It's more than 110th of a
It's more than 110th of a second
resistance.
resistance. It's
It's more than 110th of a second
resistance. It's 120,000
resistance. It's 120,000 of
It's more than 110th of a second
resistance. It's 120,000 of a
resistance. It's 120,000 of a second.
It's
It's one
I
I can't
It's one
I can't follow
I can't follow numbers.
It's one
I can't follow numbers. It's
I can't follow numbers. It's 1/5if
It's one
I can't follow numbers. It's 1/5if of
I can't follow numbers. It's 1/5if of a
second
second resistance.
One/10enth
One/10enth of
second resistance.
One/10enth of a
One/10enth of a second
second resistance.
One/10enth of a second resistance.
Anyway,
Anyway, it's
Anyway, it's a
Anyway, it's a small
Anyway, it's a small fraction.
Anyway, it's a small fraction. The
Anyway, it's a small fraction. The hell
was
was it?
So
So when
So when the
So when the ego,
So when the ego, you
So when the ego, you know,
So when the ego, you know, I
So when the ego, you know, I told
So when the ego, you know, I told you
So when the ego, you know, I told you in
the
the days
So when the ego, you know, I told you in
the days when
the days when I
So when the ego, you know, I told you in
the days when I had
the days when I had read
So when the ego, you know, I told you in
the days when I had read about
the days when I had read about the
Buddha
Buddha and
Buddha and in
Buddha and in enlightenment
Buddha and in enlightenment was
Buddha and in enlightenment was the
space
space between
Buddha and in enlightenment was the
space between two
space between two thoughts.
Buddha and in enlightenment was the
space between two thoughts. I
space between two thoughts. I was
Buddha and in enlightenment was the
space between two thoughts. I was trying
to
to catch
to catch that
to catch that one
to catch that one 10,000th
to catch that one 10,000th of
to catch that one 10,000th of a
to catch that one 10,000th of a second,
you
you know.
to catch that one 10,000th of a second,
you know. Well,
you know. Well, no
to catch that one 10,000th of a second,
you know. Well, no matter
you know. Well, no matter how
to catch that one 10,000th of a second,
you know. Well, no matter how fast
you know. Well, no matter how fast you
are,
are, you
are, you can't
are, you can't catch
are, you can't catch that
are, you can't catch that one
are, you can't catch that one 10
are, you can't catch that one 10 seconds
because
because it
are, you can't catch that one 10 seconds
because it just
because it just left
are, you can't catch that one 10 seconds
because it just left you
because it just left you just
are, you can't catch that one 10 seconds
because it just left you just as
because it just left you just as you
were
were reaching
were reaching for
were reaching for it.
were reaching for it. But
were reaching for it. But it's
were reaching for it. But it's gone
already.
Uh
so
so the
Uh
so the essence
so the essence of
Uh
so the essence of resistance
so the essence of resistance somebody's
asking
asking that
asking that is
asking that is the
asking that is the is
asking that is the is the
asking that is the is the ego's
insistence
insistence that
asking that is the is the ego's
insistence that it
insistence that it is
asking that is the is the ego's
insistence that it is it
insistence that it is it is
asking that is the is the ego's
insistence that it is it is the
insistence that it is it is the arbit
arbittor
the
the arbitrator
arbittor
the arbitrator of
the arbitrator of the
arbittor
the arbitrator of the source.
Yes.
Yes. So
Yes. So this
Yes. So this had
Yes. So this had to
Yes. So this had to do
Yes. So this had to do with
Yes. So this had to do with why
Yes. So this had to do with why we
Yes. So this had to do with why we were
talking
talking about
Yes. So this had to do with why we were
talking about eliminating
talking about eliminating causality
be
be as
be as a
be as a as
be as a as a
be as a as a basic
be as a as a basic structure
be as a as a basic structure of
be as a as a basic structure of the
be as a as a basic structure of the ego.
You
You see
be as a as a basic structure of the ego.
You see because
You see because the
be as a as a basic structure of the ego.
You see because the ego
You see because the ego is
be as a as a basic structure of the ego.
You see because the ego is always
claiming
claiming there
claiming there is
claiming there is an
claiming there is an eye
behind
behind this
claiming there is an eye
behind this ego
behind this ego claims
claiming there is an eye
behind this ego claims that
behind this ego claims that it
claiming there is an eye
behind this ego claims that it is
behind this ego claims that it is the
author
author of
author of all
author of all your
author of all your thoughts
author of all your thoughts and
author of all your thoughts and etc.
author of all your thoughts and etc. See
if
if you
author of all your thoughts and etc. See
if you meditate
if you meditate the
author of all your thoughts and etc. See
if you meditate the way
if you meditate the way I
author of all your thoughts and etc. See
if you meditate the way I was
if you meditate the way I was explaining
you
you will
you will notice
you will notice that
you will notice that there's
you will notice that there's no
you will notice that there's no author
at
at all.
you will notice that there's no author
at all. This
at all. This is
you will notice that there's no author
at all. This is all
at all. This is all happening
you will notice that there's no author
at all. This is all happening of
at all. This is all happening of its
own.
own. There's
own. There's an
own. There's an author
own. There's an author of
own. There's an author of your
own. There's an author of your thoughts.
They're
They're just
own. There's an author of your thoughts.
They're just going
They're just going by
own. There's an author of your thoughts.
They're just going by themsel
They're just going by themsel like
own. There's an author of your thoughts.
They're just going by themsel like a
computer
computer that's
computer that's gone
computer that's gone crazy.
There
There isn't
computer that's gone crazy.
There isn't any
There isn't any eye
computer that's gone crazy.
There isn't any eye behind
There isn't any eye behind the
computer that's gone crazy.
There isn't any eye behind the thinking.
There
There isn't
There isn't any
There isn't any decider
There isn't any decider behind
There isn't any decider behind the
deciding.
The
The actions
The actions are
The actions are happening
The actions are happening of
The actions are happening of their
The actions are happening of their own.
We
We said
The actions are happening of their own.
We said that
We said that everything
The actions are happening of their own.
We said that everything is
We said that everything is merely
The actions are happening of their own.
We said that everything is merely that
which
which it
which it is
which it is expressing
which it is expressing its
which it is expressing its potentiality
as
as it
which it is expressing its potentiality
as it comes
as it comes out
which it is expressing its potentiality
as it comes out of
as it comes out of the
which it is expressing its potentiality
as it comes out of the creation.
as it comes out of the creation. Was
there
there an
there an eye
there an eye that
there an eye that just
there an eye that just decided
there an eye that just decided to
there an eye that just decided to make
up
up that
there an eye that just decided to make
up that sentence?
up that sentence? No.
The
The sense
The sense spoke
The sense spoke itself
in
in response
The sense spoke itself
in response to
in response to the
The sense spoke itself
in response to the energy
in response to the energy in
The sense spoke itself
in response to the energy in the
in response to the energy in the room
and
and the
and the prevailing
and the prevailing electromagnetic
gravity
gravity of
and the prevailing electromagnetic
gravity of the
gravity of the presence
and the prevailing electromagnetic
gravity of the presence of
gravity of the presence of God
in
in response
in response to
in response to somebody's
in response to somebody's thought
in response to somebody's thought comes
forth
forth as
in response to somebody's thought comes
forth as those
forth as those words.
in response to somebody's thought comes
forth as those words. There's
forth as those words. There's no
in response to somebody's thought comes
forth as those words. There's no that
has
has nothing
has nothing to
has nothing to do
has nothing to do with
has nothing to do with this
has nothing to do with this person.
There's
There's no
has nothing to do with this person.
There's no personage
There's no personage here.
has nothing to do with this person.
There's no personage here. There's
There's no personage here. There's no
doer
doer behind
doer behind the
doer behind the doings.
There's
There's no
doer behind the doings.
There's no thinker
There's no thinker behind
doer behind the doings.
There's no thinker behind the
There's no thinker behind the thought.
There's
There's no
There's no thinker
There's no thinker behind
There's no thinker behind the
There's no thinker behind the thought.
The
The thoughts
There's no thinker behind the thought.
The thoughts are
The thoughts are thinking
There's no thinker behind the thought.
The thoughts are thinking themselves.
The
The speaking
The speaking is
The speaking is speaking
The speaking is speaking of
The speaking is speaking of its
The speaking is speaking of its own.
The speaking is speaking of its own. You
understand?
There's
There's nobody
There's nobody deciding
There's nobody deciding to
There's nobody deciding to breathe.
You're
You're not
There's nobody deciding to breathe.
You're not nobody
You're not nobody in
There's nobody deciding to breathe.
You're not nobody in this
You're not nobody in this room
There's nobody deciding to breathe.
You're not nobody in this room is
deciding
deciding to
deciding to breathe
deciding to breathe at
deciding to breathe at all.
deciding to breathe at all. That
breathing
breathing is
deciding to breathe at all. That
breathing is happening
breathing is happening of
deciding to breathe at all. That
breathing is happening of its
breathing is happening of its own.
deciding to breathe at all. That
breathing is happening of its own. Huh?
Is
Is it
Is it not?
All
All these
Is it not?
All these phenomena
All these phenomena occur
Is it not?
All these phenomena occur of
All these phenomena occur of their
Is it not?
All these phenomena occur of their own.
Person
Person says,
Person says, well,
Person says, well, without
Person says, well, without an
Person says, well, without an ego,
Person says, well, without an ego, how
would
would I
Person says, well, without an ego, how
would I survive?
would I survive? you
Person says, well, without an ego, how
would I survive? you would
would I survive? you would survive
Person says, well, without an ego, how
would I survive? you would survive very
well
well because
well because you
well because you survive
well because you survive in
well because you survive in spite
well because you survive in spite of
well because you survive in spite of the
ego,
ego, not
well because you survive in spite of the
ego, not because
ego, not because of
well because you survive in spite of the
ego, not because of it.
We're
We're all
We're all alive
We're all alive in
We're all alive in spite
We're all alive in spite of
We're all alive in spite of the
We're all alive in spite of the ego.
We're all alive in spite of the ego. The
ego
ego have
We're all alive in spite of the ego. The
ego have you
ego have you think
We're all alive in spite of the ego. The
ego have you think if
ego have you think if it
We're all alive in spite of the ego. The
ego have you think if it wasn't
ego have you think if it wasn't for
We're all alive in spite of the ego. The
ego have you think if it wasn't for me,
you
you wouldn't
you wouldn't be
you wouldn't be alive,
you wouldn't be alive, man.
you wouldn't be alive, man. You
you wouldn't be alive, man. You wouldn't
get
get your
you wouldn't be alive, man. You wouldn't
get your flu
get your flu shots
you wouldn't be alive, man. You wouldn't
get your flu shots or
get your flu shots or anything.
you wouldn't be alive, man. You wouldn't
get your flu shots or anything. I'm
get your flu shots or anything. I'm the
one
one that's
one that's saving
one that's saving your
one that's saving your life.
No,
No, because
survival
survival comes
survival comes out
survival comes out of
survival comes out of inspiration.
survival comes out of inspiration. And
that
that inspiration
survival comes out of inspiration. And
that inspiration comes
that inspiration comes out
survival comes out of inspiration. And
that inspiration comes out of
that inspiration comes out of the
survival comes out of inspiration. And
that inspiration comes out of the divine
presence
presence which
presence which automatically
presence which automatically selects
that
that which
presence which automatically selects
that which is
that which is necessary.
presence which automatically selects
that which is necessary. All
that which is necessary. All that
presence which automatically selects
that which is necessary. All that is
happening
happening of
happening of its
happening of its own.
It's
It's all
happening of its own.
It's all happening
It's all happening of
happening of its own.
It's all happening of its
It's all happening of its own.
happening of its own.
It's all happening of its own. There's
no
no thinker
no thinker behind
no thinker behind the
no thinker behind the thoughts.
no thinker behind the thoughts. There's
no
no doer
no thinker behind the thoughts. There's
no doer behind
no doer behind the
no thinker behind the thoughts. There's
no doer behind the actions.
All
All right.
Somebody
Somebody asked
All right.
Somebody asked about
Somebody asked about the
uh
uh the
uh the sound
uh the sound ah.
uh the sound ah. Well,
uh the sound ah. Well, we
uh the sound ah. Well, we did
uh the sound ah. Well, we did u
uh the sound ah. Well, we did u we
uh the sound ah. Well, we did u we did.
Uh
Uh the
uh the sound ah. Well, we did u we did.
Uh the sound
Uh the sound ah
uh the sound ah. Well, we did u we did.
Uh the sound ah has
Uh the sound ah has a
uh the sound ah. Well, we did u we did.
Uh the sound ah has a strengthening
effect.
effect. Uh
effect. Uh with
effect. Uh with kinesiology
effect. Uh with kinesiology if
effect. Uh with kinesiology if you
effect. Uh with kinesiology if you think
ah
ah the
effect. Uh with kinesiology if you think
ah the sound
ah the sound ah
effect. Uh with kinesiology if you think
ah the sound ah let's
ah the sound ah let's try
effect. Uh with kinesiology if you think
ah the sound ah let's try it.
ah the sound ah let's try it. I
effect. Uh with kinesiology if you think
ah the sound ah let's try it. I spoke
ah the sound ah let's try it. I spoke in
the
the book
the book about
the book about Dr.
the book about Dr. Diamond
the book about Dr. Diamond you
the book about Dr. Diamond you know
showed
showed us
the book about Dr. Diamond you know
showed us the
showed us the thyic
the book about Dr. Diamond you know
showed us the thyic pump.
Oh
Oh dear.
Oh dear. Okay.
Oh dear. Okay. Let
Oh dear. Okay. Let me
Oh dear. Okay. Let me think.
>> Huh.
>> All
>> All right.
>> All right. Okay.
>> All right. Okay. Um
um
uh
uh think
uh think uh
uh think uh image
uh think uh image uh
uh think uh image uh bin
uh think uh image uh bin louden
uh think uh image uh bin louden and
uh think uh image uh bin louden and now
resist.
resist. Okay.
uh think uh image uh bin louden and now
resist. Okay. Sound
resist. Okay. Sound sound.
uh think uh image uh bin louden and now
resist. Okay. Sound sound. The
resist. Okay. Sound sound. The sound
uh think uh image uh bin louden and now
resist. Okay. Sound sound. The sound in
your
your mind.
your mind. Ah.
You
You got
your mind. Ah.
You got it
You got it going.
your mind. Ah.
You got it going. All right.
You got it going. All right. Now
your mind. Ah.
You got it going. All right. Now picture
Ben
Ben Louden.
Ben Louden. Resist.
Ben Louden. Resist. Uhhuh.
Ben Louden. Resist. Uhhuh. The
Ben Louden. Resist. Uhhuh. The sound
Ben Louden. Resist. Uhhuh. The sound ah
negates
negates that.
Mhm.
All right.
All right. Think
Mhm.
All right. Think the
All right. Think the sound.
Um,
I'll
I'll picture
Um,
I'll picture Ben
I'll picture Ben Len
Um,
I'll picture Ben Len and
I'll picture Ben Len and resist.
All right.
All right. Okay.
If
If you're
All right. Okay.
If you're caught
If you're caught in
All right. Okay.
If you're caught in an
If you're caught in an emotional
emergency,
emergency, the
emergency, the best
emergency, the best way
emergency, the best way to
emergency, the best way to do
emergency, the best way to do is
emergency, the best way to do is to
breathe
breathe the
emergency, the best way to do is to
breathe the energy
breathe the energy up
emergency, the best way to do is to
breathe the energy up from
breathe the energy up from usually
emergency, the best way to do is to
breathe the energy up from usually it's
your
your solar
your solar plexus
your solar plexus instead
your solar plexus instead of
your solar plexus instead of panic.
Breathe
Breathe the
your solar plexus instead of panic.
Breathe the so
Breathe the so the
your solar plexus instead of panic.
Breathe the so the energy
Breathe the so the energy in
your solar plexus instead of panic.
Breathe the so the energy in your
Breathe the so the energy in your solar
plexus
plexus up
plexus up to
plexus up to the
plexus up to the crown
plexus up to the crown chakra.
plexus up to the crown chakra. And
plexus up to the crown chakra. And while
you
you do
plexus up to the crown chakra. And while
you do that,
you do that, go
and
and sound.
And
And as
and sound.
And as you
And as you breathe
and sound.
And as you breathe the
And as you breathe the energy
and sound.
And as you breathe the energy up,
And as you breathe the energy up, you
you're
you're out
you're out of
you're out of the
you're out of the panic
you're out of the panic right
you're out of the panic right away.
You're
You're out
you're out of the panic right away.
You're out of
You're out of the
you're out of the panic right away.
You're out of the upset.
Uh
I'm
I'm going
Uh
I'm going to
I'm going to do
Uh
I'm going to do this
I'm going to do this with
Uh
I'm going to do this with the
microphone.
microphone. You
microphone. You thump
microphone. You thump over
microphone. You thump over the
microphone. You thump over the thymus
gland.
gland. Those
microphone. You thump over the thymus
gland. Those are
gland. Those are everybody.
microphone. You thump over the thymus
gland. Those are everybody. Has
everybody
everybody know
everybody know what
everybody know what I'm
everybody know what I'm talking
everybody know what I'm talking about?
Anybody
Anybody who
everybody know what I'm talking about?
Anybody who doesn't
Anybody who doesn't know.
everybody know what I'm talking about?
Anybody who doesn't know. Okay.
Anybody who doesn't know. Okay. The
thymus
thymus gland
thymus gland is
thymus gland is the
thymus gland is the controller
thymus gland is the controller of
thymus gland is the controller of the
acupuncture
acupuncture system
thymus gland is the controller of the
acupuncture system and
acupuncture system and the
thymus gland is the controller of the
acupuncture system and the immune
system.
uh
uh it's
system.
uh it's right
uh it's right behind
system.
uh it's right behind the
uh it's right behind the breast
system.
uh it's right behind the breast bone.
The
The sound
The sound ah
The sound ah makes
The sound ah makes you
The sound ah makes you go
The sound ah makes you go strong
The sound ah makes you go strong with
kinesiology
kinesiology as
The sound ah makes you go strong with
kinesiology as does
kinesiology as does love.
The sound ah makes you go strong with
kinesiology as does love. So
kinesiology as does love. So if
The sound ah makes you go strong with
kinesiology as does love. So if you
kinesiology as does love. So if you want
to
to come
to come out
to come out of
to come out of a
to come out of a bad
to come out of a bad energy
to come out of a bad energy state
um
um you
to come out of a bad energy state
um you go
um you go you
to come out of a bad energy state
um you go you think
um you go you think of
to come out of a bad energy state
um you go you think of somebody
um you go you think of somebody you
to come out of a bad energy state
um you go you think of somebody you love
and
and you
and you go
now
now if
and you go
now if I
now if I test
and you go
now if I test you
now if I test you with
and you go
now if I test you with kinesiology
you'll
you'll go
you'll go strong.
So,
So, if
you'll go strong.
So, if you
So, if you get
you'll go strong.
So, if you get caught
So, if you get caught in
you'll go strong.
So, if you get caught in a
So, if you get caught in a in
you'll go strong.
So, if you get caught in a in a
So, if you get caught in a in a in
you'll go strong.
So, if you get caught in a in a in a
So, if you get caught in a in a in a sub
I
I was
I was going
I was going to
I was going to say
I was going to say a
I was going to say a subway
I was going to say a subway car.
I was going to say a subway car. If
I was going to say a subway car. If you
get
get caught
I was going to say a subway car. If you
get caught with
get caught with uh
I was going to say a subway car. If you
get caught with uh what's
get caught with uh what's that
mechanical
mechanical rock
mechanical rock that
mechanical rock that makes
mechanical rock that makes everybody
mechanical rock that makes everybody go
weak.
weak. What
mechanical rock that makes everybody go
weak. What do
weak. What do you
mechanical rock that makes everybody go
weak. What do you call
weak. What do you call that?
mechanical rock that makes everybody go
weak. What do you call that? Rock.
Machine
Machine rock.
Machine rock. Steel
Machine rock. Steel rock.
Machine rock. Steel rock. Mechanical
rock.
rock. Something.
Machine rock. Steel rock. Mechanical
rock. Something. What's
rock. Something. What's that
Machine rock. Steel rock. Mechanical
rock. Something. What's that rock?
>> Rock
>> Rock music.
>> Rock music. Huh?
>> There.
>> There. There
>> Rock music. Huh?
>> There. There you
>> There. There you got
>> Rock music. Huh?
>> There. There you got it.
>> There. There you got it. If
>> Rock music. Huh?
>> There. There you got it. If you
>> There. There you got it. If you get
caught,
it'll
it'll blow
caught,
it'll blow out
it'll blow out your
caught,
it'll blow out your acupuncture
it'll blow out your acupuncture system,
you
you know.
Let's
Let's say
you know.
Let's say you
Let's say you get
you know.
Let's say you get caught
Let's say you get caught in
you know.
Let's say you get caught in an
Let's say you get caught in an elevator
and
and you're
and you're forced
and you're forced to
and you're forced to listen
and you're forced to listen to
and you're forced to listen to it.
and you're forced to listen to it. If
and you're forced to listen to it. If we
test
test you
and you're forced to listen to it. If we
test you with
test you with kinesiology,
and you're forced to listen to it. If we
test you with kinesiology, you're
to
to go
to go weak.
to go weak. But
to go weak. But if
to go weak. But if you
to go weak. But if you do
to go weak. But if you do the
to go weak. But if you do the haha,
you'll
you'll instantly
to go weak. But if you do the haha,
you'll instantly go
you'll instantly go strong.
to go weak. But if you do the haha,
you'll instantly go strong. So
you'll instantly go strong. So it's
to go weak. But if you do the haha,
you'll instantly go strong. So it's a
way
way of
way of coming
way of coming out
way of coming out of
way of coming out of a
negative
negative energy
way of coming out of a
negative energy field.
So
So that
So that sound
So that sound ah
So that sound ah amen.
So that sound ah amen. So
So that sound ah amen. So amen
So that sound ah amen. So amen has
So that sound ah amen. So amen has two
sounds.
sounds. It
So that sound ah amen. So amen has two
sounds. It has
sounds. It has ah
So that sound ah amen. So amen has two
sounds. It has ah which
sounds. It has ah which makes
So that sound ah amen. So amen has two
sounds. It has ah which makes you
sounds. It has ah which makes you go
strong
strong and
strong and it
strong and it has
strong and it has m
strong and it has m which
strong and it has m which makes
strong and it has m which makes you
strong and it has m which makes you go
strong.
strong. Um,
we
we test
we test somebody.
we test somebody. I
we test somebody. I never
we test somebody. I never test
we test somebody. I never test anybody.
Amen.
Amen. Think.
You
You got
Amen. Think.
You got it
You got it going.
Amen. Think.
You got it going. All right.
You got it going. All right. Picture
Amen. Think.
You got it going. All right. Picture Bin
Laden.
Laden. Is
Laden. Is this
a
a man's
Laden. Is this
a man's a
a man's a good
Laden. Is this
a man's a good thing
a man's a good thing to
Laden. Is this
a man's a good thing to think,
a man's a good thing to think, huh?
Somebody
Somebody wrote
Somebody wrote this
Somebody wrote this long
Somebody wrote this long thing
Somebody wrote this long thing here.
Somebody wrote this long thing here. I
don't
don't know if
Somebody wrote this long thing here. I
don't know if I
don't know if I can
Somebody wrote this long thing here. I
don't know if I can read
don't know if I can read this
Somebody wrote this long thing here. I
don't know if I can read this whole
darn.
Um,
we're
we're going
we're going to
we're going to try
we're going to try and
we're going to try and answer
we're going to try and answer all
we're going to try and answer all these.
Um,
I
I know
I know some
I know some of
I know some of these
I know some of these are
I know some of these are sort
I know some of these are sort of
hypothetical
hypothetical questions.
I know some of these are sort of
hypothetical questions. I
hypothetical questions. I can't
I know some of these are sort of
hypothetical questions. I can't answer
the
the hypothetical.
You'll
You'll notice
the hypothetical.
You'll notice the
You'll notice the ego
the hypothetical.
You'll notice the ego likes
You'll notice the ego likes to
the hypothetical.
You'll notice the ego likes to deal
You'll notice the ego likes to deal in
the
the hypothetical.
the hypothetical. The
the hypothetical. The reason
the hypothetical. The reason it
the hypothetical. The reason it deals
the hypothetical. The reason it deals in
the
the hypothetical
the hypothetical. The reason it deals in
the hypothetical is
the hypothetical is it
the hypothetical. The reason it deals in
the hypothetical is it always
the hypothetical is it always wins.
In
In the
In the hypothetical,
you
you know
In the hypothetical,
you know what?
you know what? If
it
it doesn't
it doesn't have
it doesn't have to
it doesn't have to deal
it doesn't have to deal with
it doesn't have to deal with reality,
it doesn't have to deal with reality, so
it
it can
it doesn't have to deal with reality, so
it can do
it can do anything
it doesn't have to deal with reality, so
it can do anything it
it can do anything it wants.
it doesn't have to deal with reality, so
it can do anything it wants. The
it can do anything it wants. The ego
loves
loves the
loves the hypothetical.
loves the hypothetical. And
loves the hypothetical. And you
loves the hypothetical. And you hear
loves the hypothetical. And you hear it
all
all the
loves the hypothetical. And you hear it
all the time
all the time on
loves the hypothetical. And you hear it
all the time on on
all the time on on television
loves the hypothetical. And you hear it
all the time on on television program.
Well,
Well, what
Well, what if
Well, what if what
Well, what if what if
Well, what if what if every
Well, what if what if every what
Well, what if what if every what if
Well, what if what if every what if all
of
of us
Well, what if what if every what if all
of us did
of us did that?
Well, what if what if every what if all
of us did that? Well,
of us did that? Well, all
Well, what if what if every what if all
of us did that? Well, all of
of us did that? Well, all of us
Well, what if what if every what if all
of us did that? Well, all of us don't
of us did that? Well, all of us don't do
that.
that. So,
that. So, it's
that. So, it's a
that. So, it's a stupid
that. So, it's a stupid question,
that. So, it's a stupid question, you
know.
What
What if
What if you
What if you know?
What if you know? All
What if you know? All right.
What if you know? All right. So,
What if you know? All right. So, what
What if you know? All right. So, what if
is
is not
What if you know? All right. So, what if
is not constrained
is not constrained by
What if you know? All right. So, what if
is not constrained by reality
is not constrained by reality and
therefore
therefore it
therefore it has
therefore it has no
therefore it has no validity.
Uh
the
the hypothetical
the hypothetical question
the hypothetical question cannot
the hypothetical question cannot be
answered
answered because
the hypothetical question cannot be
answered because it
answered because it has
One
One has
One has to
One has to do
One has to do with
One has to do with the
One has to do with the evolution
One has to do with the evolution of
consciousness
consciousness on
One has to do with the evolution of
consciousness on the
consciousness on the planet.
One has to do with the evolution of
consciousness on the planet. We
consciousness on the planet. We notice
that
that we
that we notice
that we notice that
that we notice that the
that we notice that the prevailing
energy
energy of
that we notice that the prevailing
energy of life
energy of life forms
that we notice that the prevailing
energy of life forms uh
as
as we
as we said
as we said Neanderthal
as we said Neanderthal man
as we said Neanderthal man is
as we said Neanderthal man is 70.
as we said Neanderthal man is 70. Um,
if
if we
as we said Neanderthal man is 70. Um,
if we go
if we go back
as we said Neanderthal man is 70. Um,
if we go back to
if we go back to early
as we said Neanderthal man is 70. Um,
if we go back to early life
if we go back to early life forms,
they're
they're very
they're very very
they're very very low.
they're very very low. And
they're very very low. And we
they're very very low. And we come
they're very very low. And we come up
from
and and
and and we
and and we go
and and we go through
and and we go through the
and and we go through the Komodo
and and we go through the Komodo dragon
and
and and
and and we go through the Komodo dragon
and and and
and and and sporting
and and we go through the Komodo dragon
and and and sporting uh
and and and sporting uh entities
and and we go through the Komodo dragon
and and and sporting uh entities like
that.
that. Imagine
that. Imagine a
that. Imagine a guy
that. Imagine a guy going
that. Imagine a guy going going
that. Imagine a guy going going into
that. Imagine a guy going going into a
cage
cage with
that. Imagine a guy going going into a
cage with the
cage with the Komodo
that. Imagine a guy going going into a
cage with the Komodo dragon
cage with the Komodo dragon with
that. Imagine a guy going going into a
cage with the Komodo dragon with no
shoes
shoes on.
shoes on. Wacko
shoes on. Wacko wacko.
shoes on. Wacko wacko. I
shoes on. Wacko wacko. I don't
shoes on. Wacko wacko. I don't know
shoes on. Wacko wacko. I don't know what
the
the karma
shoes on. Wacko wacko. I don't know what
the karma that
the karma that was,
shoes on. Wacko wacko. I don't know what
the karma that was, but
the karma that was, but he
shoes on. Wacko wacko. I don't know what
the karma that was, but he of
the karma that was, but he of course
shoes on. Wacko wacko. I don't know what
the karma that was, but he of course got
bit
bit because
bit because what
bit because what does
bit because what does a
bit because what does a karma
bit because what does a karma commoded
dragon
dragon do?
bit because what does a karma commoded
dragon do? It
dragon do? It bites
bit because what does a karma commoded
dragon do? It bites everything
dragon do? It bites everything that's
around
around it.
That's
That's the
around it.
That's the way
That's the way it
around it.
That's the way it survives.
That's the way it survives. So
anyway,
anyway, we
anyway, we see
anyway, we see the
anyway, we see the evolution
anyway, we see the evolution of
consciousness
consciousness uh
anyway, we see the evolution of
consciousness uh on
consciousness uh on the
anyway, we see the evolution of
consciousness uh on the planet
consciousness uh on the planet over
millions
millions of
millions of years
millions of years evolving
millions of years evolving into
millions of years evolving into higher
higher
higher levels.
millions of years evolving into higher
higher levels. We
higher levels. We see
millions of years evolving into higher
higher levels. We see that
higher levels. We see that in
millions of years evolving into higher
higher levels. We see that in the
higher levels. We see that in the late
80s
80s it
80s it crossed
80s it crossed over
80s it crossed over from
80s it crossed over from 190
80s it crossed over from 190 to
80s it crossed over from 190 to 207
that's
that's an
80s it crossed over from 190 to 207
that's an enormous
that's an enormous jump
80s it crossed over from 190 to 207
that's an enormous jump and
that's an enormous jump and therefore
80s it crossed over from 190 to 207
that's an enormous jump and therefore we
can
can presume
can presume that
can presume that the
can presume that the progression
can presume that the progression of
consciousness.
So
So in
So in the
So in the book
I
I think
So in the book
I think I
I think I that
So in the book
I think I that I'm
I think I that I'm just
So in the book
I think I that I'm just finishing
I think I that I'm just finishing uh
then
then next
then next to
then next to the
then next to the last
then next to the last chapter
then next to the last chapter I
then next to the last chapter I think
then next to the last chapter I think is
called
called homospiritus.
So
So a
So a man
So a man came
So a man came up
So a man came up homo
So a man came up homo erectus
So a man came up homo erectus cal
So a man came up homo erectus cal cal
calibrates
calibrates only
So a man came up homo erectus cal cal
calibrates only at
calibrates only at 70.
Uh
Uh then
Uh then we
Uh then we come
Uh then we come into
Uh then we come into homo
Uh then we come into homo sapiion.
Homo
Homo sapiion
Uh then we come into homo sapiion.
Homo sapiion uh
Homo sapiion uh homo
Uh then we come into homo sapiion.
Homo sapiion uh homo sapien
Homo sapiion uh homo sapien for
Uh then we come into homo sapiion.
Homo sapiion uh homo sapien for many
millennia
millennia were
millennia were the
millennia were the mongol
millennia were the mongol hordes.
Everybody
Everybody was
millennia were the mongol hordes.
Everybody was savaging
Everybody was savaging everybody
millennia were the mongol hordes.
Everybody was savaging everybody else.
So
So that
So that all
So that all that
So that all that Homo
So that all that Homo sapiion
So that all that Homo sapiion did
So that all that Homo sapiion did was
sort
sort of
So that all that Homo sapiion did was
sort of a
sort of a refined
So that all that Homo sapiion did was
sort of a refined dragon
sort of a refined dragon himself.
So that all that Homo sapiion did was
sort of a refined dragon himself. Uh
whether
whether a
whether a Mongol
whether a Mongol horde
whether a Mongol horde or
whether a Mongol horde or Tyrannosaurus
Rex
Rex is
whether a Mongol horde or Tyrannosaurus
Rex is your
Rex is your preference.
whether a Mongol horde or Tyrannosaurus
Rex is your preference. It
Rex is your preference. It wouldn't
whether a Mongol horde or Tyrannosaurus
Rex is your preference. It wouldn't make
much
much difference,
much difference, would
much difference, would it?
much difference, would it? They
much difference, would it? They were
pretty
pretty much
much difference, would it? They were
pretty much the
pretty much the same.
Then
Then we
Then we see
Then we see the
Then we see the evolution
Then we see the evolution of
Then we see the evolution of love
Then we see the evolution of love and
the
the progressive
Then we see the evolution of love and
the progressive elevation
the progressive elevation of
Then we see the evolution of love and
the progressive elevation of the
the progressive elevation of the level
of
of consciousness.
of consciousness. So
of consciousness. So we
of consciousness. So we can
of consciousness. So we can the
presumption
presumption is
of consciousness. So we can the
presumption is then
presumption is then that
of consciousness. So we can the
presumption is then that the
presumption is then that the destiny
of consciousness. So we can the
presumption is then that the destiny of
consciousness
consciousness itself
as
as it
consciousness itself
as it expresses
as it expresses itself
consciousness itself
as it expresses itself in
as it expresses itself in man
consciousness itself
as it expresses itself in man man
becomes
becomes born
becomes born spiritually
becomes born spiritually and
becomes born spiritually and he
becomes born spiritually and he becomes
he's
he's no
becomes born spiritually and he becomes
he's no longer
he's no longer homoerectus
becomes born spiritually and he becomes
he's no longer homoerectus he's
he's no longer homoerectus he's no
longer
longer homo
longer homo sapien
longer homo sapien he's
longer homo sapien he's now
longer homo sapien he's now homospiritus
homospiritus
homospiritus is
longer homo sapien he's now homospiritus
homospiritus is a
homospiritus is a different
longer homo sapien he's now homospiritus
homospiritus is a different animal
homospiritus is a different animal than
homo
homo sapien
homo sapien homo
homo sapien homo or
homo sapien homo or chromagnant
homo sapien homo or chromagnant man
different
different person
homo sapien homo or chromagnant man
different person altogether
different person altogether not
homo sapien homo or chromagnant man
different person altogether not the
different person altogether not the same
at
uh
uh there's
uh there's an
uh there's an awakening
uh there's an awakening of
a
a reality
uh there's an awakening of
a reality on
a reality on a
uh there's an awakening of
a reality on a completely
a reality on a completely different
level.
level. The
level. The nonlinear
uh
uh the
level. The nonlinear
uh the energy
uh the energy of
level. The nonlinear
uh the energy of the
uh the energy of the spirit
level. The nonlinear
uh the energy of the spirit now
uh the energy of the spirit now begins
to
to prevail
to prevail as
to prevail as a
to prevail as a motivator,
to prevail as a motivator, as
to prevail as a motivator, as a
to prevail as a motivator, as a goal,
to prevail as a motivator, as a goal, as
a
a destiny,
as
as a
as a guide.
as a guide. Um
Neanderthal
Neanderthal was
as a guide. Um
Neanderthal was not
Neanderthal was not guided
as a guide. Um
Neanderthal was not guided by
Neanderthal was not guided by that.
There's
There's no
There's no spiritual
There's no spiritual awareness
There's no spiritual awareness in
There's no spiritual awareness in our
definition
definition of
There's no spiritual awareness in our
definition of spiritual.
definition of spiritual. So
There's no spiritual awareness in our
definition of spiritual. So once
definition of spiritual. So once you
cross
cross over
cross over 200,
cross over 200, it
cross over 200, it seems
cross over 200, it seems that
cross over 200, it seems that a
cross over 200, it seems that a new
cross over 200, it seems that a new era
has
has dawned
cross over 200, it seems that a new era
has dawned upon
has dawned upon the
cross over 200, it seems that a new era
has dawned upon the planet
that
that the
that the evolution
that the evolution of
that the evolution of consciousness.
that the evolution of consciousness. You
cannot
cannot predict
that the evolution of consciousness. You
cannot predict the
cannot predict the future,
that the evolution of consciousness. You
cannot predict the future, but
cannot predict the future, but we
that the evolution of consciousness. You
cannot predict the future, but we can
predict
predict what
predict what is
predict what is the
predict what is the nature
predict what is the nature of
consciousness
consciousness itself.
predict what is the nature of
consciousness itself. Consciousness
is
is created
is created in
is created in such
is created in such a
is created in such a manner
is created in such a manner that
is created in such a manner that of
is created in such a manner that of its
own
what
what it
what it is
what it is it
what it is it evolves
what it is it evolves is
what it is it evolves is it?
what it is it evolves is it? Okay.
what it is it evolves is it? Okay. So
the
the progression
what it is it evolves is it? Okay. So
the progression of
the progression of consciousness
what it is it evolves is it? Okay. So
the progression of consciousness is
the progression of consciousness is not
due
due to
due to mankind.
due to mankind. God
due to mankind. God doesn't
due to mankind. God doesn't need
due to mankind. God doesn't need you
due to mankind. God doesn't need you as
co-creator
co-creator of
due to mankind. God doesn't need you as
co-creator of what's
co-creator of what's happening
due to mankind. God doesn't need you as
co-creator of what's happening on
co-creator of what's happening on the
planet
planet at
planet at all.
It's
It's the
planet at all.
It's the nature
It's the nature of
planet at all.
It's the nature of consciousness
It's the nature of consciousness itself
and
and the
and the common
and the common view
and the common view is
and the common view is to
and the common view is to return
and the common view is to return to
and the common view is to return to its
source.
I
I want
I want to
I want to co
I want to co clarify
I want to co clarify the
I want to co clarify the question
I want to co clarify the question we
I want to co clarify the question we had
before
before about
I want to co clarify the question we had
before about co-creator.
before about co-creator. Co-creator
indicates
indicates two.
indicates two. There's
indicates two. There's this
indicates two. There's this and
indicates two. There's this and there's
that
that which
indicates two. There's this and there's
that which co-
that which co- means
indicates two. There's this and there's
that which co- means two.
that which co- means two. Mankind
indicates two. There's this and there's
that which co- means two. Mankind is
that which co- means two. Mankind is not
really
really a
really a co-creator
really a co-creator in
really a co-creator in the
really a co-creator in the meaning
really a co-creator in the meaning of
two
two different
really a co-creator in the meaning of
two different entities.
two different entities. God
really a co-creator in the meaning of
two different entities. God doesn't
two different entities. God doesn't need
you
you as
you as a
you as a co-creator
you as a co-creator at
you as a co-creator at all.
you as a co-creator at all. What
you as a co-creator at all. What it
means
means is
you as a co-creator at all. What it
means is that
means is that the
you as a co-creator at all. What it
means is that the essence
means is that the essence of
you as a co-creator at all. What it
means is that the essence of that
means is that the essence of that which
you
you are
because
because you
you are
because you are
because you are created
you are
because you are created as
because you are created as a
you are
because you are created as a seed
because you are created as a seed of
God.
God. You
God. You contain
God. You contain the
God. You contain the same
God. You contain the same seeds
God. You contain the same seeds as
God. You contain the same seeds as God
and
and have
God. You contain the same seeds as God
and have the
and have the power
God. You contain the same seeds as God
and have the power of
and have the power of creation.
God. You contain the same seeds as God
and have the power of creation. So
you're
you're not
you're not co-creating
you're not co-creating with
you're not co-creating with God.
You
You know,
you're not co-creating with God.
You know, like
You know, like in
you're not co-creating with God.
You know, like in tandem,
You know, like in tandem, you
you're not co-creating with God.
You know, like in tandem, you know what
I'm
I'm saying?
I'm saying? God
I'm saying? God doesn't
I'm saying? God doesn't say,
I'm saying? God doesn't say, "Gee,
I'm saying? God doesn't say, "Gee, I
need
need help
I'm saying? God doesn't say, "Gee, I
need help here.
need help here. Don't
I'm saying? God doesn't say, "Gee, I
need help here. Don't fix
need help here. Don't fix up
I'm saying? God doesn't say, "Gee, I
need help here. Don't fix up to
need help here. Don't fix up to this
planet."
planet." No,
planet." No, you
planet." No, you are
planet." No, you are because
planet." No, you are because of
planet." No, you are because of the
planet." No, you are because of the the
divinity
divinity of
planet." No, you are because of the the
divinity of your
divinity of your source
planet." No, you are because of the the
divinity of your source are
divinity of your source are the
extension
extension of
extension of the
extension of the lineage
extension of the lineage of
extension of the lineage of that
extension of the lineage of that out
extension of the lineage of that out of
which
which you
extension of the lineage of that out of
which you created.
which you created. And
extension of the lineage of that out of
which you created. And therefore
which you created. And therefore you
have
have the
have the same
have the same powers
depending
depending upon
how
how spiritually
how spiritually advanced
how spiritually advanced you
how spiritually advanced you are.
Oh,
one
one cannot
one cannot just
one cannot just decide
one cannot just decide to
one cannot just decide to shift
one cannot just decide to shift from
one cannot just decide to shift from a
low
low to
one cannot just decide to shift from a
low to a
low to a high
one cannot just decide to shift from a
low to a high energy
low to a high energy level.
one cannot just decide to shift from a
low to a high energy level. It's
low to a high energy level. It's a
one cannot just decide to shift from a
low to a high energy level. It's a it's
a
a matter
a matter of
a matter of spiritual
a matter of spiritual work
a matter of spiritual work and
a matter of spiritual work and endless
decision
decision making.