So we'll get back to these questions.
So you see, spiritual truth doesn't come out of historical cause and effectness.
That's the downside of religion.
It's back there, and it's there.
The upside of religion is that it embodies
the acknowledgement of holiness and sacredness,
the respect for that which is sacred.
The one thing religion does get is the divinity of God
and the sacredness of that divinity.
The great cathedrals of the world, which, you know,
right now we're calibrating a thousand things.
She's calibrating a thousand things.
I'm asking a thousand questions.
Anyway, when you calibrate the great cathedrals of the world,
they're high, 700s.
700 is very, very unlikely as an occurrence in this planet.
Few are the beings who ever even reach 700.
But the great cathedrals, Chartres,
the great cathedrals are stunning.
When you walk into them, you're enveloped in this aura of sacredness,
worship, devotion, and the energy of that prevails.
It's hard to be smart-ass in Chartres Cathedral.
Yeah.
It's hard in, I spoke one time in Westminster Abbey.
As you walk through Westminster Abbey,
the great beings that have ever walked the planet,
there's their tomb, there they lay there.
I mean, as you walk across the floor,
there's a plate there that tells you who's under there.
You think, my God, I shouldn't be stepping on that.
Here's Shakespeare and here's Napoleon.
All these great beings, you know.
Oh, Lord.
All right, so the great cathedrals.
So, the value of religion is it recognizes the sacredness of beauty.
The sacredness and the divinity of beauty.
So, beauty is one of the fastest ways to the sense of the presence of God.
That music that we just played is 700,
and it's almost impossible to function on that level.
In these lectures, I'm training myself to do that.
It's hard to speak when you're weeping
because the beauty just wipes you out.
The sacredness of divinity then is acknowledged
through the self-sacrifice of the thousands and thousands of workmen.
Some of those cathedrals took over a thousand years,
a thousand years, and they're still working on them.
An entire lifetime is devoted to carving this one pulpit.
It's in three dimensions.
There's figures here and then figures...
Behind those figures, then figures behind them.
All done in hard wood.
One entire lifetime just to carve this one gift to God.
It's a gift.
The sense, the devotion of those whose devotion was so extreme
brings the energy of their devotion into your own inner experience,
and you get what it is.
You get what it is.
The worship and the recognition and the acknowledgement of the sacredness,
of that which is.
That which is divine.
That's a road which anyone can take.
The appreciation for beauty.
A great aria in an opera can just wipe you out.
We're going to see Hansel and Gretel.
The children's chorus from Hansel and Gretel wakes you out.
La Boheme.
There's an aria where he realizes that Mimi has just died,
and he screams Mimi.
You break out crying every time you hear it.
I've seen that opera 10 or 12, 15 times.
Every time.
The same.
The intensity of the love.
We experience the presence of God through love,
through beauty,
through that which is sacred.
So we are worshipful,
and we respect the sacredness of all of life.
We worship God when we turn the black beetle over
from his back onto his tummy,
so he can walk away,
instead of living in the air with his legs wobbling in the air.
Out of that act, we worship God because
he's a god.
He's a god.
Life, so long as it exists in this form, is sacred.
And you realize the sacredness.
So it's an act of worship.
All that we do that supports life
is a recognition of the respect for the sacredness of life.
And that's really all that's required.
Is it possible to transform the physical body into a spiritual body?
Well, oh, it means as Jesus did.
My experience and understanding is,
as one goes out of body,
one's in the etheric body and the spiritual body.
My guess would be that with the opening of the third eye,
the disciples were able to witness,
usually when somebody goes out of physicality into the etheric realm,
you can't see them anymore.
My guess would be that with the opening of the third spiritual eye,
they witnessed the spirit body of the Lord.
We have permission to ask that.
The disciples did have the opening of the third eye
and witnessed the etheric body.
So they merely saw the spirit leaving the physicality.
It isn't that the physical body is transformed into a spiritual body.
It's that the spiritual body which inhabits the physical body
during its physical life leaves it.
So it isn't like this physicality is transformed into the spirituality.
It just leaves it, is my understanding.
Can kinesiology be used for future related questions?
No.
It can't be used for the hypothetical.
And it can't be used for the future.
The reason is they're not real.
The problem with the hypothetical question is that
no answer is really possible
because it doesn't exist in reality.
What if mankind had four eyes?
Then what would happen to them?
There's no answer to that.
Hypothetically,
the hypothetical has no existence in reality.
It's just a nonsense question.
A lot of politics is that.
In which one quality is extracted
and then that's supposed to be the most important thing
about your human being, you know.
I got to do this for them.
Those people who talk from such ivory towers
should travel the slums of the world.
You see how much high pollutants
the political ideology appeals to the people.
They're eating grubs to stay alive.
And you want them to die for the vote?
Vote for what?
They're so far from that as a reality.
To really exist from day to day is,
you know, rags tied together over branches.
And four families live in there
taking turns sleeping on the dirt floor
while they go about and eat actually more grubs than worms.
Unbelievable.
Covered with scabs
and the bones all stick out.
And by age five or six they're dead already.
Old age almost.
In some parts of the world,
I remember the people are all very small.
There isn't much oxygen there anyway,
so it's a good thing they're small.
And the only way you can survive there
is chewing cocoa leaf
because you can only work all day long
with nothing to eat.
The cocoa leaf, it eliminates your hunger.
If you had nothing to eat,
you'd be stupid not to chew cocoa leaf, wouldn't you?
Of course.
So this way you can at least survive.
And this little old lady walked by,
this little old lady with the ear pads
hanging down like this and all,
and they all pad about very quietly like this.
The descendants of the Incas,
they live up in the mountains in Peru.
The government wants to get them down from there,
but they don't want to come down
because they're smart.
Anyway.
Join the movement.
Join the big cities in the civilization.
This little old crone walks across there
and I said to somebody,
how old is she?
She's 38.
38, you're an old crone.
By 40, you're dead of old age.
This one vitamin tablet
would probably increase her lifespan by 10 years.
Tuberculosis is eating them up.
They don't eat because of the cocoa leaf.
And if they do have some money,
they spend it on beer.
And there's a red feather hanging out of a shop
where you can buy beer.
It's just a different lifestyle.
And all that we consider important to them
is so irrelevant,
they don't even know what you're talking about.
You should all vote.
Vote for what?
They're trying to get through
through till noon,
you know what I mean?
Our political system means absolutely nothing to them.
So,
the downside of politics is
we're not aware of the consciousness level
of the people we're talking to.
See, the egocentricity,
we're so enamored of our own scheme of things.
Oh, we're so superior.
Superior to what?
Well,
when you're talking to people,
you have to be aware of their level of consciousness
so that you can speak meaningfully to them.
So, a lot of the diplomatic catastrophes of history
are because of the resumption.
That other people are like us.
I'll tell you folks, they are not like us.
They did not go to an Ivy League college.
They did not play Marquis of Queensberry rules.
They're street people.
They made you sign a peace treaty with them.
You idiot, you turn around and they cut your throat.
That's the reason they got you to sign the peace treaty.
Because as you leave the table,
they got you.
Sucker.
So, those are the realities of the world.
So,
it has to do with the sheep
and the wolf in sheep's clothing.
The vulnerability of the spiritual seeker
is that of naivete.
Especially in the beginning years
where you're enamored of the sudden discovery
of the whole spiritual dimension.
And it's intriguing and it's exciting.
And in that space,
one can go into denial
about the realities of this world
and become a sitting duck.
And that's why I
always counsel these classes.
Don't be a plump little chicken.
Because they are out to get you.
What is grace?
What is the function of grace?
Well,
we said that the infinite totality
of all of creation then
radiates these energy fields.
To get us out of good and bad
and see things as gradations,
I made up this chart.
See?
You could say up here is preferable
and this is less preferable.
You can do that.
People say, well, this, this,
the calibration of levels of consciousness
could be used judgmentally.
Well, that's true.
It better be.
Is one thing better than another?
It isn't that it's better than another.
From what viewpoint?
When it's cold, heat is preferable to chilly.
When it's hot, chilly is preferable to hot.
So, from what you choose then,
everything gets rated.
People say, well,
that's not fair
that things are judged
one thing better than another.
I'll tell you a fact about this world.
Everything is better than something else.
And everything is worse than something else.
Because that's all in your head.
So, those who object to rating
people as good or bad or whatever,
politically speaking, etc.,
are playing a game of pretense,
of naivety.
Again, the wolf is hidden
in the sheep's clothing.
Because that's denial of spiritual reality.
Some things are, frankly,
a hell of a lot better than other things.
Not from an abstract point of view,
no.
From the abstract viewpoint,
you could say that all that exists is equal
by virtue of its existence.
But you don't see that
until you reach calibration level,
the top of the deck,
until you reach a great...
In the state of oneness,
in the state of the allness of creation,
you see that all things are equal.
But they are equal
in a different meaning of the term equal
than what is usually
used in common language.
It doesn't mean they are of different value.
It means each thing is
perfectly that which it is.
And beauty prevails throughout.
A stick is equal to a diamond.
It's of no difference.
You see, as you walk through the woods,
this weed that stands there.
Once you see what it is,
its architecture, its design,
is incredible.
It stands there in absolute perfection.
Now you don't call it weed anymore.
You see it as an incredible sculpture.
The incredible sculpture of all that exists
is equal to everything else that exists.
And I remember walking down the streets
of New York into the alley
and struck by the incredible beauty of the alley.
All the garbage cans and everything.
It was like
a French impressionistic painting almost.
There was the garbage can
all dented over like that
and the garbage hung out the side
and the little mouse ran across
and there was the banana peel.
So, there is a level in which you see
the beauty and perfection of all that exists.
When that begins to happen,
you tell your friends
that you're going to the retreat.
You're not safe on the streets.
You can get arrested.
Grace then is the presence,
the potentiality,
the presence of a very high energy
frequency and vibration
which through good fortune
one picks up in one's own aura
as an intentionality.
As an intentionality
by agreement, by design, by subscription.
You'd go to see the Karmapa
because the Karmapa transmits a blessing
whether he does or doesn't is irrelevant
because your intention was
to reach God through every available avenue
and even if the Karmapa wasn't there
he is now by virtue of your intention.
Grace in a way is the opportunity
to surrender to that which is intrinsic
to salvation and enlightenment.
It's walking down the street
and suddenly you get
all you had to do was
start smiling at people
and you've just transformed the world.
Anybody can do that
walking down the streets
of New York City or Chicago.
You just start smiling at everybody
and instantly everything happens.
It changes.
It goes from this world to this world.
You did a smile at everybody
and everybody goes, wow.
So it's the transformative opportunity
of a spiritual energy
which energizes options
that would perhaps
not come to mind at the time.
In the last lecture we will talk about
there's an important point
in the evolution of consciousness
where that grace is crucial.
Crucial.
At that one ten-thousandth of a second
that presence is crucial.
Can you really describe
the physical sensations of the nervous system
that you may feel
as one progresses in the spiritual path?
Well, they can be all kinds of
ailments.
All kinds of ailments
and weird and strange physical sensations.
As one gets really quite advanced
I think it's because the nervous system
is being taxed by this spiritual energy.
There is a period of time
I think it's probably in the high five-hundreds.
What I'm thinking about now
is in the high five-hundreds.
It was coming on after six-hundreds.
It was coming on after seven-hundreds.
It starts at five-hundreds.
It starts at five-forty.
It starts at five-fifty.
It starts at five-eighty.
It starts at five-seventy-five.
Five-seventy, five-sixty-five.
Okay.
At energy level around five-sixty-five
which would be like saintliness
A Course in Miracles calibrates at six-hundreds.
If you do it assiduously
you get transported into that level.
And what is traditionally called the kundalini energy
a spiritual energy begins to flow of its own.
I think it's also facilitated by meditation.
Let's see if it is so.
The flow of the kundalini is also facilitated by meditation.
Through devotion, worship, spiritual intention
and by meditation
this incredible energy begins to flow up your back.
It's unbelievable.
It's exquisite.
Better than an orgasm.
It's just beyond imagination.
It flows as exquisite, joyful pleasure
up the back
and you feel it flowing into the brain.
In fact, you can direct where the energy goes
by just sort of focusing your attention
to the left side of the brain
to teach the flow over there.
Focus on the right side of the brain.
It flows up your back
and into the brain.
That's all I can explain.
Instead, you witness this lady hobbling along.
This energy flows out intensely
and it's an exquisite sensation.
It flows out, flows in
and you see the lady.
She stops hobbling and she walks away.
It happens of its own.
One is merely the witness.
This energy is what does it.
The energy did it for years.
And the
irrecoverable, most hopelessly advanced,
serious, psychotic, insane,
degenerated, neurologic,
bizarre creatures would be brought in
from all over the world,
wrapped up in wet sheets,
squirming on the ground
and
like that.
And this energy would
connect with
the self within the being there
and
you would feel the inner healing.
The inner being was
in the state of peace and grace.
What happened to the physicality
is irrelevant.
That's why I tell people
when you do the Course in Miracles,
whether it cures you or something,
if the Course is successful,
it's irrelevant.
Once the Course takes hold,
what happens to the physicality
is totally irrelevant.
It may or may not heal itself.
If it does, fine.
If it doesn't, fine.
Because it's irrelevant.
It's irrelevant.
The kundalini energy is what...
I mean, I call it kundalini energy
because that's what
Gopi Krishna wrote about it.
It seems like we just
determined it.
It's in the high 500s.
And it just is an exquisite state.
And in that state,
you can only see and experience
love and beauty.
Nothing else exists.
The garbage cans are beautiful.
Everything...
You can see the architectural,
artistic beauty of the garbage cans.
You can see how every weed
is perfection.
And to this day,
it makes no difference to me
whether a thing is a weed or a diamond.
Neither one.
Frankly, I don't need either one.
But they're equal.
From that point on,
you don't need anything from this world
or from anyone.
You don't need anything from this world.
There's nothing that this world has
that has any appeal to it.
That's why.
In the infinite presence,
there is no lack.
So there's no...
There's nothing you would want to reach out for.
There's nothing that you want or need.
There is nothing temptable.
And that's why it's hard to understand
why some gurus have fallen.
Because in that state,
there's nothing that can appeal to you.
So what was appealed to
must have been some remnant.
So that kundalini energy then pours in.
In the beginning,
there may be aches and pains.
I think it's because the human nervous system
is not made for that.
And I think we calibrated it
in a previous meeting.
The human nervous system is made
for spiritual energies
that calibrate up to 600.
And beyond that,
you should go to other realms.
Go to other realms.
It's designed for other realms.
So we said homo spiritus
and the new emerging advance
of homo sapien
is in the process of developing
a stronger nervous system
that can actually handle
more advanced spiritual energies.
Right now, up to about 600
is all that's comfortable.
It's comfortable up to around 700.
And then beyond that,
it becomes painful.
Beyond that, there's,
like the Buddha said,
you're beset by demons.
There's aches and pains and fiery,
fiery,
fiery.
I can only liken it to
barbed wire
that's running electricity through it
and it's red hot.
And your whole nervous system
becomes like that
and it's agonizing.
And that means
there's something out
and you've got to find out
what that is
and you've got to clear that
through very intense puritano.
So the human nervous system, then,
is made to handle energies
up to 600,
up to 700, actually.
And how should we pray?
Well, we should pray
by the way we are in the world to respect and have reverence for all of life and the sanctity
of all that exists is the epitome of prayer to acknowledge god as the source and the presence
of all existence in all of its expressions is the epitome of prayer people think of
prayers in terms of asking for favors oh god i want a mercedes-benz
she was something else wasn't she when she sang ball and chain the whole audience was just
suspended there's a long pause there in the music and everybody that sits on the edge of
their seats so they stand on their seats and then she finally she comes through with that note and
they all go oh to my mind prayer is not just a recitation see the intention of the recitation
is undoubtedly quite powerful just like prayer reels
it's the intention of the prayer reel that gives it its virgin power resist right so whether you
burn sticks uh walk back and forth around the squares and the floor of the cathedral
whatever you do in the name of god for the sake of god is like karma yoga having been done
for the old lord and for the old lord do i thusly peel potatoes back in the floor so for the
sake of god i'm going to take some pains of this body write thank you letters send christmas cards
pay my taxes whatever i do if i do it in the name of god in my because by doing that your
your understanding of the nature of god keeps expanding keeps expanding and that in itself
is a grace to see the opportunity and to follow that opportunity in itself is positive karma
is itself grace other people walk through great opportunities and don't see them they're blind
and we can only feel sorry for them that they don't see the great opportunity there
what is the difference between attachment and detachment well attachment is one of the biggest
problems in getting rid of the ego and probably the most important one if you can get rid of
attachments then you've saved yourself years of spiritual work
attachment itself is to some illusion to what you get out of something detachment is uh to say no to
it to negate it to refuse it attachment means to be hooked on it detachment would be indifference
detachment very often is the pathway of no asceticism which is also cool
it could be real happy with a cot a box candle and an apple a day
no money it's easy it's terrific you walk around free as a bird you walk into town somebody says
hey my mother just made some donuts you want one all right you walked somebody somebody said you
want to ride somewhere and i said yeah i was thinking going down just everything happens
mystically just wonderful don't need anything the downside of asceticism is that one can
get attached to asceticism you get off you get off on holiness and bone being bony
never taking a shower never washing your hair you can sit there cross-legged this bag of bones
and maybe the you know the ascetics of indiana are the best example
i don't know that god's pleased by that or not probably not
i'm just kidding i've been into asceticism and uh you can get high on asceticism let's say you do
you don't need anything it's fantastic you can walk out of the house without a
a nickel, nothing to eat, and everything gets provided day after day. It just happens. The
miraculous becomes constant. Of course, when you're detached, you're not attached to the
survival of life and the body, which can be annoying to your family. They want you to
take care of it and eat and all kinds of strange things, get haircuts, take their medicine,
see the doctor. It's a drag. Anyway, anybody forces you to take all these measures, you
do it because you love them. Frankly, that's why you do it. Left to your own, you wouldn't
bother. Left to my own, I wouldn't bother eating. I mean, what would you bother eating
for? I used to not eat for long periods of time, and it would only dawn on me. I hadn't
eaten all week.
And it's like you didn't
need food. What do you want food
for? The perfect state is
neither attraction nor aversion.
Neither attachment nor
detachment necessarily,
but non-attachment.
So the present
state is
to be not attached. You don't have an aversion
nor do you have an attraction.
And if there's something for
dinner, that's great.
And if there isn't something for dinner, that's also
great, because you're not attached
one way or the other.
Non-attachment. It means you're not run
by it anymore. You're not run by
it. And tapas,
the traditional way of
P-A-P-A-S, is
the practice of non-attachment to
things. If you always have to have
your dinner at 5.30,
then you stop doing that until you get over
that yin that it's got to be on the table at
5.30 or your whole life's
going to be upset.
When you say
divine intervention is needed,
to save us, I hear divinity
as something other.
But there is no other to save
us from what? Okay.
Divine intervention
is just a style of speech.
It means, out of good
karma, out of the karma which may
arise out of the good karma of this instant,
I ask God to help me.
Came out of what must be
horrific negative karma, to end
up in the depths of hell.
Perhaps in that instant was all the karma
by grace.
Well, it requires
with the one act,
from here to there. Heaven and hell are a
tenth of an inch apart, says Zen.
Absolutely correct.
Hitting bottom may be the
fastest way to heaven. That's why
intervening and
being an enabler
is interfering with the other person's
karmic lesson. You keep
running in and saving them and hauling them
off to the hospital and
give me a break. The mother used to
call me up. The family called me up.
You want to stop drinking?
I said, you know what to do?
Buy him a case of whiskey and put him
in a hotel room. Call me back
when he's done. Right. That's the
best way to help this guy.
And when he runs out of a case of whiskey, buy him
another case of whiskey. Pretty soon
the voices are after me, Mom.
Help, help. Okay, Junior.
Now we'll take you to the hospital.
I mean, when you're not ready,
you're not ready, folks. You know what I mean?
So,
that's it.
That's true. Buy him a case of whiskey and leave him
be. You know, why are you messing with this guy
and interfering with his karma?
Why? Because the good karma
only comes when he surrenders to God.
When he says, God, I've gone
as far as I can go.
If there is a God, I ask him to help me.
That stops the
insanity.
When you admit that you, of your own
nature, you, your little lone
ego in the middle of the universe, can't
hack it, can't do it.
That's truth. That's integrity.
So,
you cross over the line
of integrity. I, myself,
cannot do it. No.
Only by
grace. And you realize
that you've been insane.
And you ask God to help
you and you surrender your life to God.
From that moment on, your
life is transformed. And this
room is full of people whose lives have been
transformed in just
that way.
So, the grace, then, is that that is
present and available
to you.
Every moment. It doesn't mean that it's
going to be answered at every moment.
You can pray up a storm for 20 years
and nothing happens.
And you say, the heck with prayer. I give it up.
And at that instant...
And then you realize you've been
trying to control God with prayer.
You've been trying to control
him, control. That you weren't
really surrendering. Because if you totally
surrender to God, it doesn't matter whether the
Romantism continues or not.
I mean, the ailments that you have are really,
really irrelevant, you know, unless
they interfere with functioning. Today, I had to
speak, and all week long, I had some terrible
virus. Terrible virus.
Anyway, I thought,
well, either you speak Saturday or you don't speak.
If you don't speak, you don't speak.
If you don't speak,
you won't say anything.
In which case, we'll just sit together and pray, maybe.
This asks
about beings below the 200s.
We said, this world seems,
from my personal viewpoint,
in fact, you can use the term personal
in its usual vernacular,
the world seems
purgatorial in design.
Why? Because you
go from the very lowest
element, the reptile,
the great dinosaurs
at 70 lived by
ravaging and slashing and killing.
They live
solely by the death of others.
The dinosaur lives
only,
only by killing you.
Its sole purpose is to kill
you, because you are food.
That's about as low as you can get, right?
I guess worse would be
kill you and not eat you.
At least they eat you.
That's starting
somewhere, anyway.
Anyway, we get to
all we can say is
that consciousness evolved
on this planet. It seemed
to come up from,
and there are still beings
at the bottom of the sea
who are really
awesomely awesome.
And we see that it evolved
over great eons of time,
millions of years,
400 million years,
for instance.
And then we see consciousness
slowly come up to where
it has been.
And we see that life
on this earth has been
a reflection.
All right. So life, we said
that the world of form
is the consequence
of that which is held
in consciousness.
This is a world of effects.
It's not a world of causality.
It's a world of effects
in which that which is held
in consciousness creates this,
and then this, and then this,
and then this.
And as you walk down the path,
you think it's sequential.
It's not sequential.
It's continuous.
Creation is continuous.
All things are constantly
the result of an ongoing,
ongoing creation
which is continuous.
Creation to be creation
cannot start and stop.
That which is outside of time
has no capacity
to start and stop.
Thusly, everything that is happening
is the continuous expression
of creation,
the divinity,
the infinite power of God,
bringing potentiality
into manifestation.
And consciousness,
as it evolved then,
reached 190,
for centuries.
Now it's at 207,
and life has changed.
Discuss the Trinity,
God's Son and Holy Spirit.
That's interesting
because it caused the great division
of the Christian Church,
the Eastern and the Western,
Constantinople and Rome,
split over this whole concept.
And it has a theological name,
I forget what the argument is about.
There's three different ways
of looking at things.
Because reality is a total,
complete oneness,
it cannot have a triune quality.
It can have a triune quality
from a certain perception,
from a certain level of perception.
We see the triune quality
of divinity in the world's religions.
Brahma, Vishnu, Shiva,
we see it in Christianity,
Father, God, the Son,
and God, the Holy Spirit.
God, the Holy Spirit,
When we say God, the Son,
we're talking about divinity
as it is expressed in form.
That divinity can express itself
through the human,
through the great avatar.
We see that God is invisible
to ordinary perception
as that which is transcendent.
God is imminent then
within the avatar.
And what makes it imminent
is the Holy Spirit,
itself.
So the Holy Spirit would be like
the radiance of God,
the energy field of God,
which may then express itself,
at least to a limited degree,
within a physicality.
It's the invisible context.
When we pray,
that's what we're referring to,
is we've changed
the quantum potentiality.
How does prayer work?
It changes the quantum potentiality.
If you follow quantum mechanics,
you realize that merely to witness
or observe a thing already
changes it.
The past and the present
and the future change.
The future now becomes the past,
and the past becomes the future, etc.
Because you're out of linearity.
The human mind really can't conceive,
doesn't really understand quantum mechanics.
Because only the spiritually evolved person
gets what it's saying.
That which you are
is influenced by the quantum mechanics.
That which you are is influenced
by influencing everything else that exists.
By the virtue of that which you are,
you change the charge and the potentiality,
and therefore the likelihood
of a thing coming into actuality
and form,
depending on local conditions.
Every one of us then,
by their style of life,
by their devotion,
by their witness to the acknowledgement
of the sacredness of all of life,
lifts the consciousness of all of mankind.
All of mankind.
All of mankind is benefited.
Nothing goes unobserved.
Not a hair on your head
shall be missed.
That turned out to be accurate.
I remember when I first discovered
the capacity of kinesiology
to tell truth from falsehood.
And I realized that everything that ever existed
is registered forever
in the field of consciousness.
I said, whoa.
Every hair on your head
shall be counted.
Whoa. It's the truth.
It's a fact. Every squirrel that falls,
is noted.
Intrinsic divinitive existence
is equal in all.
Is equal in all.
Witnessed, acknowledged by all.
When we say God imminent,
God transcendent,
when we talk about Trinity,
God, Son, Holy Spirit,
those are only linguistic,
conceptual,
rationalistic positionalities
from which to approach the subject.
When you read,
theology, realize
what a difficult job that is
to try to describe the non-linear
in terms that are linear.
To describe that which is indefinable.
Let's see how you can define the indefinable.
That's what theology is about.
Class, we will define the indefinable.
Okay.
So, you see the difficulty.
However, you see,
you can also see the
devotion in that.
Because, many of the great intellectual,
spiritual teachers of history,
in the religious thing,
were very learned.
They were doctors of theology.
Their devotion was to the truth,
and it took the form of a seeking truth
through the intellect and reason and logic.
So, one can still be respectful of the devotion
behind the endeavor to try to reach,
you know,
if you read about the books,
you know, it'll discuss whether God is imminent or transcendent.
Well, this is an artifact of mentation.
It couldn't possibly be either or.
God being the essence of all that exists,
the allness throughout and beyond all time,
could hardly be limited,
could hardly be divided into transcendent,
which is out there,
and imminent, which is in here.
Those are obviously just artifacts of human mentation.
We've sort of touched upon prayer.
We need the Newtonian versus the,
to put it within conceptual basis,
I don't want to spend much time at this,
but it's worth,
for the doubting Thomas,
there are people who are stuck in their intellect,
and victims of it.
Can't get out of my brain, dog.
Can't get out of logic, you know.
I know you can't.
But God in his infinite mercy knows that,
that you are stuck in your head.
For those who are stuck in their head then,
it's okay to be spiritual
because we now have a scientific explanation
for the reality of the spiritual.
This is the Newtonian paradigm of reality on the left,
in which things are discrete, orderly, logical,
definable, measurable,
and it's what the material reductionist,
the hardcore scientist says is what's real.
You can't measure it.
You can't weigh it.
You can't locate it in time and space.
It's not real.
That's sort of taking great liberties with the word real.
In fact, it's really missing what real is about,
but anyway, that's beside the point.
So this is the world that we presume to be reality,
except that actually we don't
because nobody lives on that level.
We entertain ourselves with that level,
but we all know we live on the experiential,
either like the plum pudding or you don't.
Got too much this in it or too much that.
The liver is fried too hard
and it's tough as leather or it isn't.
You know what I'm saying?
So this is where we live over here.
We live in the infinite quantum potentiality.
You know, as we get smaller and smaller
below the atom, below the sub-particles,
sub-particle physics,
we get to like potentiality.
Like potential energies that are so minute
that they cannot be measured.
And we enter a different realm.
We enter a different realm.
We enter the world where we live.
Where we live is in spirituality.
People say, I don't believe in spirituality.
Idiot, you live there all day long.
In fact, what just said you don't live in spirituality
is what spirituality is.
It's a subjective conclusion
and how did that come about?
It's the totality of all one's thinkingness
throughout all of time,
one's karmic inheritance
and what your consciousness level is now
that leads you to feel that way within yourself
that gives it that sense of truth
that you say this is so highly complex,
completely non-linear.
So where we live is really disorderly.
Anything can happen within your experiential life.
You can go to your favorite opera
and be disappointed instead of ecstatic.
You can buy your best ice cream
that you've always liked your whole life
and you decide it's disgusting.
You can't really predict what's going to happen.
It's creative. It's free.
It's imaginative. It's progressive.
It's diffuse. It's non-local.
It's experiential.
It's expansive.
It's the context out of which we live.
It's the subjective state.
And at all times we're really poised
for the next instant.
The context of our life then is unlimited.
At every moment we're poised for the next instant.
Without even being conscious and aware that we're poised,
at every instant everybody here is ready to jump!
That jumping-ness can happen out of non-jumping-ness.
Nothing said jump in the head.
It just jumped. See?
So everything is happening spontaneously
as an expression of the essence of...
the reality of that which it is.
This entire lecture was prepared exactly
one ten-thousandth of a second ago.
Jump wasn't in it. You know what I mean?
Here's some things about the downside of social life.
The downside of social life.
There are those things which are preferable
and those things which are not preferable.
See, if we can get beyond good and evil,
we can say there's the things that we want
and we call them good.
And there's the things we don't want
and we call them bad.
Now here we've got, which we had before
but we didn't talk about.
See, good and bad, just like talking about the Trinity,
depends on where you want to start from.
And what you're talking about is the perception
and what you're talking about is the point
from which you're approaching the subject.
If you desire it, you say it's good,
and if you don't desire it, you say it's bad.
So the things that we consider tragic about society,
about human life,
war and the downside of the judiciary system,
yes, there is a downside to it,
are because we don't want those things.
So we choose what we want
and we repel that which we don't want.
In the highest state, they're all the same,
as we said.
War and peace, it's all the same.
Whether you all go off with an atomic bomb, bang,
or you slowly strangle to death from old age,
what's the difference?
I mean, you're going to leave here quick and easy
or slow and horrible, you know what I'm saying?
Leaving is leaving.
And whatever karmic merit there is
and the style that's chosen,
but that's a very advanced state.
But there is a certain level at which you can see
that it really doesn't matter
because this being a karmic theater,
this being a theater of great opportunity,
then we can choose that which we choose
and not choose that which we mean to avoid.
I myself wouldn't want the karma
of being a judge in a murder case.
No, thank you.
I wouldn't want the karma
of being the one that says,
this person dies or doesn't die or something.
So I think the difficulty with leading a moral
or an ethical or spiritual life in the West,
in the Western world,
is the lack of the understanding of karma,
the lack of the understanding of the nature of God,
that everything and every moment
determines one's spiritual destiny.
That everything, every moment
is an act that is witnessed by the entire universe.
The entire universe witnesses every single act
and every single choice
and records it forever.
Consequently, in the demonstrations we do of kinesiology
and the potentiality of it
as a research tool,
we go back in history,
any human being that ever lived,
what they thought or felt,
what they did,
why they made the choice,
nothing is hidden.
Nothing is hidden.
So from the infinite eye of the divine,
nothing is hidden.
On the other hand,
neither does it need to be.
And that's the blessing.
So we'll break for lunch.
We'll see you again later.
About an hour or so.
I did it.
Be able to function
in the presence of the beauty of God
is difficult and takes practice.
And by Lecture 11,
I've made good progress.
It used to be
I could either deal with the music
or talk, but not both.
How to not be wiped out by it?
Question number one.
Is it the mind-boggler of all time?
How does one truly find themself?
Well, it's a snap, folks.
You just realize you're the infinite allness
of all existence beyond all time and expression.
There you are.
Didn't take long, did it?
After many lifetimes,
I got a neat letter from somebody the other day.
He says,
I've been meditating for 30 years,
and suddenly,
boom.
How neat.
There's questions about prayer.
There's questions about meditation.
Wonderful questions.
He said that the ultimate form of prayer
is the way in which you conceptualize,
the way in which you contextualize
your own existence from instant to instant.
Meditation and prayer
is more like a mudra
than a recitation.
It's more like a posture
in which you pose your existence
in the context of divinity.
It's the style in which you are
out of the awareness of the presence of God
and once surrendered to be of service to God.
That sanctifies all actions.
It is by your dedication of yourself
to that intention
that you sanctify all your actions.
That's it.
And then the last thing,
the last thing that I want to do
is ask you a question
that I must ask.
What is it from you
to do with your action?
What is your action?
Do you have an action?
Is the action you do
to help you relax?
Yes.
Actually,
I'm trying to give you
a few different answers.
It's a strange question.
It really is.
I don't know
if it's the same or a different answer.
It really is.
If I do something wrong,
that person
There's a sense of wholesomeness about it.
If it's made by a machine, there's certain brands of bread
that you could blindfold me,
and the minute you put it in your mouth, it tastes dead.
Twinkies. I'm very disappointed in Twinkies.
I mean, Twinkies came to mind.
When I was a kid, you'd go out for, you know,
your mom would put a Twinkie in there,
and at lunch you'd have your Twinkie,
and you'd squeeze that banana-flavored goodness out of it.
Twinkies were great.
One day, out of madness, I decided to buy a Twinkie for old-time's sake.
Man, it was deader than a mackerel.
I mean, it is not the same Twinkie that I grew up with.
Food that is blessed carries a different energy,
so the human energy does something to the energy of the food itself.
So witness the mother who lovingly makes the chicken soup.
It actually does cure your cold.
And the tea that's made it,
and the tea that's made it home has cured this cold.
It's because of the energy of love within it.
So we transform everything that we touch.
We know that people who have a green thumb, you know,
it's like they see the sacredness of beauty.
They dedicate their life to the cultivation of beauty for its own sake.
We sanctify that which we do then by the dedication of our life
to be conscious that all one's actions are in the presence of God
and that every action is in the presence of God.
And that every action affects all of mankind.
So your life no longer is trivial.
Your life is no longer trivial.
The fact that you're out on a river fishing,
as you look over and you appreciate the beauty of that river and the surroundings,
your appreciation of that beauty is radiating out and lifting all of mankind.
So even as you sit in the rowboat thinking that you're doing nothing,
your acknowledgement of the beauty of creation itself
is an act of love.
It's an act of sanctifying all of life
and affirming its value and increasing its value.
And that's how the consciousness level of mankind evolves
is because those who are more conscious tend to lift all of mankind.
We said that the top of the levels of consciousness are numerically small,
but their power outweighs...
but their power outweighs all the rest of the population.
One person who dedicates themself to life
and sees the sacredness of all of life
and thereby sanctifies all of life as they go about the day
is lifting the consciousness of thousands of other people.
Somewhere in Biatra, some little kid is laying there,
slowly dying of starvation and AIDS.
And out of his hopelessness and grief and apathy,
suddenly there's a little spark of hope.
And death is okay.
Where did that come from?
It came from the fisherman sitting there appreciating the beauty.
You see, because the context of life is non-linear,
so in the infinite quantum potentiality,
every intention on your part alters the context for everyone.
Every hair on your head is counted.
Every moment of your life contributes this way
or it pulls it down this way.
The number of people who are living in this world,
the number of people who are living in this world,
the number of people who calibrate on the high levels
has increased since 1980, 1990, whatever it was,
1990s when I did it, early 1990s.
And the calibration of the level of all of mankind is going up.
And we see, as we said, at 207, integrity no longer,
people don't wink at it anymore.
They put it on the front cover of Fortune magazine.
Integrity is being called for by everyone.
So what do you say to God
when you pray?
I don't know what other people say to God when they pray.
I could use a few more bucks, God.
Rent's due next week.
I mean, I'm sure God doesn't take offense at that.
It's really a serious question of how does one pray.
The most effective prayer, as far as I know, is non-verbal.
It is to position oneself.
You know what a mudra is?
A mudra is...
You see, divine statues.
A mudra is this.
Mudra is the dance of Shiva.
Mudra is a posture.
A mudra is blessing.
Mudra is...
So it's one's...
The way you position your existence vis-a-vis divinity.
It's like there's an...
If you picture an invisible self,
what would be the posture of your invisible self?
I guess...
Probably...
in the presence of God.
That's how.
Let's ask.
We have permission to ask about that
form of prayer resist.
It's more effective than
verbalization resist.
More effective than verbalization.
It's like a supplication of your spirit
to God's will.
The surrender to God's will
is a form of prayer.
When you say,
for what reason I don't know, Lord,
but I, whatever,
in thy name, see?
If it's the undoing of some bad karma,
you might say,
I don't know what the reason for this suffering is,
but I dedicate it for, you know,
the undoing of whatever karma
it may be undoing, you know?
You try to have everything
subserve the good of all.
The next question is about meditation.
I've got them backwards.
No wonder I can't read.
As you see,
to hold your existence
in a certain,
it's almost like a benediction.
It's almost like
sanctifying one's own existence
by your posture vis-a-vis God.
As far as sitting meditation,
so this, in a way, is a meditation.
This is a way of being in the world
in which one,
as everything arises,
one surrenders it to God
because to avoid
attractions and aversions,
then one becomes detached
and one surrenders
all possibility to God.
If this happens,
you'll go bankrupt.
Well, if I go bankrupt,
I go bankrupt.
Lots of people survive bankruptcy.
They still tend to be breathing and eating.
If that's what it takes,
if that's what it takes
to get off materiality,
to get off pride of advantage,
to get off the vanity of materialism,
then I guess if it takes bankruptcy to do it,
so let it be.
Bankruptcy is one of the ways to God.
After you get rid of all the money
and all the big cars
and all the crap,
you know, you say,
I'm still me
and I still enjoy fishing
and life hasn't really changed at all.
You know what I'm saying?
Because love remains.
Love.
There is formal meditation.
There's meditation as a lifestyle.
So what I just described to you
was meditation as a mudra,
as a lifestyle,
which is itself a meditation.
Contemplation would be the next
more focused level
in which one is aware
of the rising and the falling away
of the feelings, thoughts, and events
as they occur.
The focus is on that which is a priority.
That which is just before the arising,
just before the arising of the thought and the feeling.
And then let go wanting to change it.
Let go resisting it.
And it rises, it crests,
and then it falls away
with no commentary.
That's a complete surrender to God
in the everyday activities.
So you dedicate your life to God
by the way in which you are with the world,
with the dedication,
with the reverence
with which you do everything
from digging a ditch
to peeling a potato
to making dinner.
It's all the same.
But it makes a difference.
The potato that's fueled by love
and cooked with love
is a different potato
than one that is chopped up by a machine.
That's a fact.
Anybody can check it out for themselves.
More formal sitting meditation,
a la Zen,
is a more disciplined,
conscious, focused, concentrated,
time-out from life
in which the focus can be
a one-pointedness of mind
on the thoughts as they arise.
And in this condition,
one becomes,
one transcends from the experience.
We have a chart that shows it.
We showed it before.
You transcend identification
with the thoughts
and you become that which witnesses the thoughts.
Ah.
Well, these are really,
really the levels of consciousness
that strict meditation will take you through.
Strict meditation,
the mentation goes on and on.
There's no way you can stop the mentation.
The mentation proliferates faster
than you can counter it.
So therefore,
one has to transcend
to become that which is
witnessing the mentation as it goes by.
The memories,
the fantasies,
the daydreams,
little bits of music,
ibbity-dibbity,
boom,
heady-fishies in an itty-bitty bowl,
all this crap goes through your head.
You can't stop it.
You know,
Hitler,
the third world war,
I mean,
all the wars,
everything goes through your mind.
Little bits from childhood,
little pieces of music,
some vignette from a television commercial,
Bow Flux commercial.
I posed for that years ago
and they're still using it.
They asked me to do
a geriatric version of it.
In which you only lose five pounds,
not 400 pounds.
Five pounds will do.
So at first you're preoccupied with form
and you begin to see that
as we tried to stop your thoughts before,
they won't stop.
They won't stop.
Something is registering those thoughts
and recognizing them
and you realize,
that that within you is,
while thoughts and all this is going on,
something is witnessing them.
You say,
you know,
George,
I'm thinking about so-and-so.
Who knows or what is it
that knows what you're thinking about?
So there's something beyond the thinkingness
that is the witness of the thinkingness.
So you let go identifying with the thoughts.
I mean,
you can't be the thoughts.
If you were the thoughts,
when you told them to stop,
they'd stop.
So,
no,
you're the victim of the thoughts.
You're the victim of the thoughts.
What is it that's the victim of the thoughts?
The watcher,
the experiencer.
How do you know
that this watcher or experiencer
can report what it's reporting?
It's because there's a quality
and what we're looking for is a quality.
A non-personal quality
of awareness
behind the observer and the witness.
So in meditation,
you're trying to sense.
What is it that exists
prior to the thought?
What is it that the thoughts,
how is it that they register?
There is within, then,
a quality to the consciousness.
The quality of consciousness itself,
which itself is silent.
It's because of the silence,
the background silence,
that you can hear sound.
All right,
you can focus either on the sound
or the silence that makes detecting
the sound possible.
Similarly,
you can focus on consciousness,
which itself is without form,
but which illuminates all form.
And you begin to withdraw from the thoughts.
The thoughts are changing all the time.
That can't be who you are.
You would have been dead a long time ago.
So one withdraws one's identification
to the more detached.
We use the analogy also
of content versus context.
The thoughts themselves
are the content.
But what is the overall context
which is holding this capacity
for thought and feeling and all
in the first place?
What is a priority?
What is more prior?
You go through the whole story
of your job with so-and-so
and how they screwed you
and didn't give you the raise you would do.
So you go through these stories,
laments from the past,
or daydreams of the future,
but they're all stories.
Now the willingness to surrender
the storiness of this recollection to God
begins to shorten it.
Letting go of the wanting to think.
So you'll find that thinking
is coming out of a wanting to think.
There's a desire to think.
First of all,
we think thoughts are wonderful.
The reason we think they're wonderful
is because they're our thoughts.
Somebody else's thoughts
are not really all that charming
when you think of it.
Honey, would you like to hear
what I think?
What do you think about now?
Okay, so we're enamored of thoughts
because they're our thoughts.
If they're our thoughts,
they're wonderful, precious, and valuable.
If they're somebody else's thoughts,
they're stupid.
So we get to the core of thinking this,
which is the narcissistic,
egocentric investment in them.
Thoughts are wonderful, valuable,
and valid
because they're ours.
My thoughts.
The way you get off that,
is you realize that thinkingness
is happening of itself.
They aren't your thoughts at all.
As you look at the energy fields of consciousness,
there are huge thought fields
in which your consciousness is immersed.
And the thinkingness of all of mankind
is what's programming your head,
together with last night's TV news, etc.
We get off the vanity.
So there's a secret vanity
to the thinkingness.
The thinkingness also brings us back to the thought.
It brings up a feelingness.
And you'll notice that all thinkingness has a payoff.
You're getting one up on something.
You're getting even with something.
When you think negative thoughts about people,
secretly you're punishing them.
That crazy old bitch.
That nutty old man.
He deserves arthritis.
We get a secret getting even kind of feeling.
We write wrongs.
We write these wonderful stories in our head.
How we write these wrongs.
How the guilty are made to pay.
So, all right.
You see, this thinkingness happens
because there's a desire to think.
Because there's a secret payoff to thinkingness.
Because we think that thinkingness is valuable.
It's coming from an energy.
There's a root to thinkingness.
As you let go,
wanting to dramatize
everything into the form of thinkingness,
into the form of a story,
you'll see the self-indulgence of that
and the egocentricity if you look at it.
As your head manufactures these stories,
it's strictly egocentric.
It's strictly narcissistic.
It's very self-indulgent.
You see that the ego is in love with itself.
It's getting an enormous payoff
from all this thinkingness.
You decide to turn the pleasure,
the secret pleasure of thinkingness
over and surrender it to God.
As you let go,
wanting to make stories,
they become paragraphs.
As you let go,
wanting to write paragraphs,
they become short sentences.
And then you begin to see
the unloggy of thoughts as they arise.
It's like there's a primordial energy bed
which is not yet into form.
It wants to come into form.
It starts to think dog.
Then it thinks about old Bawa,
and you remember how old Bawa was sick.
You remember how Bawa used to bring the paper in.
You remember how the kids used to play with Bawa.
And there's a whole story about Bawa.
Pretty soon you're weeping
thinking about when Bawa died.
Whoa, I mean, it just grows, right?
All right, so there has to be a willingness
to surrender all that.
The sentimentality,
the validation of yourself
as the good pet owner or whatever.
The letting go of the sadness
of the thinking of the good old days, etc.
Anyway, the long story about Bawa
borrows down to a paragraph,
then it comes down to a sentence.
Then you catch the mind
starting to think about Bawa,
and you surrender it at that point.
So there's a constant surrenderingness.
As you do this,
what happens is you nip thoughts in the bud.
You'll see they're coming out
of a formless unloggy,
free form, you might say.
It isn't quite dogginess yet.
And the word dog doesn't exist yet.
But image of dogginess,
all this happens very rapidly,
but it's continuous.
So there's like a continuous fount
of thinkingness coming out of a
energy field that we could just call
thinkingness,
the energy like a fountain
out of which proliferates
thinkingness endlessly.
One surrenders this to God
at greater and greater depth
until finally one gets to the very core
of thinkingness itself.
And one surrenders
the identification of self
as thinkingness
and surrenders thinkingness to God.
That is quite a sacrifice.
Would you be willing to become
a dumb animal who doesn't think?
You can become a happy dog,
but you're not going to be able
to think again.
You can be a happy purring kitty,
but you won't be allowed
to think anymore.
Wow.
I can't think if I'm a kitty?
You can purr.
I can't.
I can't think anymore, God?
I don't want to be a kitty.
Because the identification of self
is thinkingness is part and parcel
of identifying yourself as ego,
as human ego.
And you'll see the great reluctance
with which you let go
and the tenacity with which you let
hang on to thinkingness
despite your lamenting it.
Everybody laments their thoughts.
I was laying in bed
and I couldn't go to sleep.
I kept coming back and back.
Everybody laments their thoughts.
If you really lamented your thoughts,
they would stop.
So you think you're lamenting your thoughts,
but you're secretly delighting
in their torment.
And you have to give up
the secret delight in the torment.
So in really intense meditation then,
there is a willingness
to surrender everything to God.
Thinkingness itself.
So what you end up surrendering
is mind.
The willingness to surrender mind,
mind.
Itself to God.
Then you discover
there isn't such a thing as mind anyway.
There's only thoughts.
And as thoughts disappear,
so does mind.
There's no such thing as mind
any more than there is such a thing as ego.
But for spiritual work,
we call the ego the ego
at least for a period of time.
And then we reach a certain level
where we realize there is no such structure
and only our belief systems
work.
And then we start holding it in place
and that it is not really an it at all.
It doesn't have any independent existence.
Formal sitting meditation
is in itself an end.
And many people have spent
many a lifetime,
many years in a strict meditation.
I myself spent
I don't know how many lifetimes
in meditation.
It is, of course, classically
the way of non-duality,
the royal road to God through non-duality.
The quote is,
the core is Zen practice,
and many other practices,
not just Zen.
Any one of the meditative practices
can bring you into various levels of satori.
These levels of satori
are sudden flashes where you transcend mind.
Ambiguities are resolved
because you see the positionality
that was creating the apparent opposites
and they suddenly collapse.
And
so meditation itself
is certainly a worthy endeavor.
One's dedication of meditation to God
instead of looking for a benefit.
So the other block to get out of the way
is to stop meditating for something.
One cannot meditate in order to reach satori,
in order to reach enlightenment,
in order to realize one's Buddha nature.
One meditates for the sake of meditation
period.
Not because it will get you anything,
get you anywhere,
not for any alleged or imagined gain.
That is a sacrifice.
To sacrifice all goal.
I meditate
out of devotion to Thee, O Lord.
Period.
Formal sitting meditation can last.
I did it for 20 years,
an hour in the morning,
an hour at night.
When you had more time,
I used to meditate six hours a day
or eight hours a day
and then I went into
24 hour day meditation.
Since then I haven't meditated at all.