Anytime you can get yourself into the
victim position of victim,
there's a big payoff. You get sympathy,
you get attention, you get to be on
channel 15, you get the blubber all
over,
and you get a million-doll lawsuit.
Yeah.
So the difficulty here then people say
how can I get away from all this stuff?
You can get away from it if you get the
secret to it. Today is the secret.
Today's the day we give secrets away
with every pound of tea.
Remember pirates and pzants? Today's the
day we give babies. No, today's the way
we give babies away with every pound of
tea. Yeah, today we're giving away a
pound of tea with every All right. So,
how do you get out of the bottom part of
the pit?
You see that it's the pound of tea you
get out of all this stuff, folks.
It isn't shame. You just love to
and shame and and guilt and apathy and
shake all over with fear and blubber all
over Channel 15 with all this tragedy.
And I think Melissovich is the greatest
example of pride on the planet today. I
mean, he's just magnificent.
No actor could do it with the I mean,
when he gets there, what is this? the
International Tribunal. And he goes and
he goes,
"You have no right to judge me. You're
talking about the whole world. The whole
world has no right to judge me."
I mean, if that isn't the ultimate,
right? Well, the juice he gets out of
that is what propagates it. So
to transcend then the lower levels of
the ego it doesn't mean to to go beyond
all these things. It means to let go
what you get out of it. You get a lot
out of despising things. You get a lot
out of hatred.
Vindictive is what runs all these
people.
We love to condemn people. Make them
wrong. Look down on them. Laugh at them.
Spit on them. put them in prison, get
even. There you go. Getting even is the
whole Middle East, isn't it?
Or we can put them down with ignoring
them.
So, it's really the willingness and to
to make make it coincide with the course
of miracles, which many people here have
done, is then to let go the pleasure of
judgmentalism. That's how you get out of
it. You get off it.
And you you let go of the pleasure
because you see it's irrelevant.
You see that you're trying to get
pleasure out of something that has no
basis in reality. When you see that it's
an arbitrary positionality,
you realize that it's fake.
It's fake for me to stand here and tell
you that they're wrong in the Middle
East. That's fake, isn't it? It has
nothing to do with right and wrong. You
know, it's irrelevant.
It's like trying to measure water with a
ruler. You know, it's just the wrong
instrument.
Judge judgmentalism is just the wrong
instrument to apply to human life. Why?
Because human life is coming out of an
incredible complexity. The evolution of
consciousness and all of its karmic
expressions throughout all of time is
what accounts for this piece of dust
here at this moment. What can you say
about that?
earring that you see is the result of
the evolution
of all that has ever been throughout all
of time since the beginning of time.
For a piece of dust to be here,
this air has to be here. The barometric
pressure has to be here. This room has
to be here.
Sedona has to be here. Has to be
Arizona. Arizona has to be in the
country. All that has to be on the
globe. All that has to be in a uni
planetary system whirling around the
universe.
For this globe to be here at this moment
and for the light to be where it is and
the sun to be where it is and the
barometric pressure,
an infinite number of things has to have
evolved throughout all of time to
account for this particular moment.
So to be judgmental about it seems sort
of inappropriate, right? We don't know
what the karma of the people is in the
middle of east middle east. Maybe they
should be doing that,
right? Imagine what those people have
done to himself throughout many a
lifetime, right? Maybe it's time they
got up and killed each other.
Well, 70 isn't the bottom, is it?
Down here, you've got apathy
down here, you've got apathy. You've got
the old lady sitting there in the
rocking chair. She stopped eating. She
won't answer the telephone.
She's lost all interest in life. She's
going to die.
You can see her in the nursing home.
Unless you pour energy into her, she's
going to die.
Maybe these people are coming out of
apathy.
People born in Bafra,
the middle countries of Europe,
aren't even up to 70. You realize that?
Many of the babies you see there that
with their stomachs all swollen up with
starvation and they're born with AIDS,
you know, and they're they're not going
to live past 3 months of age or 6 months
or maybe 3 years at all at all. They're
born at 30 30 calibrated level 30. Is
that right? Let's see.
My guess is that what I'm looking at in
my mind calibrates over 25 calibrates 30
cal about 30. All right. So you think 70
is low. Millions are coming into this
planet at 30. Africa is a continent that
comes in at 30. You're lucky if you live
to be 20 in Africa.
So maybe the people that are into a
furious angriness at each other and a
vengeful
hatred
and rage are at least coming up to 70.
Huh? If you come up to rage and
angriness,
you can at least move yourself out of
apathy. That's the value of television.
You see all those beautiful things there
on TV? All the people that are into
apathy. Hey, look what those people
there have, Nelly. You know, Pete, let's
let's get one of them there. Toasters.
Well, you got to have money for that.
That means you got to go to work, right?
You got to whittle some chairs and sell
them something.
I've been in parts of the world up in
the Andes where the annual wage, this is
back in the 70s,
was 25 cents a week. That's it. 25 cents
a week.
And on Saturday morning, you'd see the
two of them. They apparently hadn't even
heard of the wheel there yet.
Up in the Andes, I didn't in the 70s, I
didn't even see wheels. You can see the
couple trudging down the road and
they've got two sticks with a blanket
between them and they're dragging it
along and their week's produce for the
week. Two two squashes,
three potatoes
and about 10 ft of rope that they
braided by hand and they're going to
sell it Saturday morning in the in the
market.
And they take turns. One Saturday
morning
she drags the stuff and it's his day to
drink. We go to market and he gets drunk
because when they drink they just pass
out. So by noon he's out cold and when
you see them coming back she's dragging
him. He's in the blanket. The next
Saturday they swap. The next Saturday he
drags her. By noon they're out. I mean
11:00 in the morning they're out
already. I mean out cold. Out cold. And
they swap Saturdays. Market there is
every other s every Saturday.
Not even a horse, not a wheel. They're
still dragging the sticks.
And uh the average age of death is
probably 30. They all have advanced
tuberculosis, malnutrition.
And of course, they chew cocoa. So they
have no appetite. So they don't eat.
They all have severe malnutrition as a
consequence of which they are prone to
tuberculosis.
So you see an old lady up there in the
Andes, an old lady walk across the
street and one of the people there I
said, "How old is she?" He said, "She's
31." 31. Looked like 61, 71, 81, even
for a jeria. So you're dead already. Um,
so we put down, we say these people are
evil because they're killing each other.
Innocent people are getting killed.
Well, innocent is a judgmental. Well,
how you know they're innocent?
Maybe all those little kids that just
got blown up on the street were some
horrific villains in a previous
lifetime. Nazi Nazi torturers or
something. And then and
so
because you don't know. All right. So
the willingness then to surrender to not
knowingness.
So what does humility means? Spiritual
work. Humility is of profound
importance.
It means I of myself as an ego and
completely unable to comprehend reality.
I have no way of knowing the truth of
anything. Much less can I discern its
karma. Therefore, all judgment is up to
God.
Judgment is mine, sayth the Lord.
Why? Because you're not capable of it.
Not capable of it. You would have to
know the totality of all of existence
throughout all of time up to the point
of this little piece of dust right here
to explain one piece of dust, much less
anything as complex
as the tribal wars that have been going
on in the Middle East for thousands of
years and will probably continue to.
Why? Because it serves that purpose.
If life on Earth is purgatorial,
certainly not heavenly.
If human life on this planet is an
aspect of purgatory,
then that which seems horrible to us is
necessary.
It's only when you've had enough
suffering that you say, "Hey, there must
be a better way."
It's only because you find out this all
leads you into agony that you finally
give it up. Right? How does the spirit
hit bottom and make a choice for God
instead of
worshiping itself as the ego as
megalomania?
Consequently, we can't even judge the
purpose of human life itself, much less
anything that occurs in it.
Oh boy.
We have permission to ask this question.
Resist in front of this audience. We
have to we have the purpose. We we have
permission to ask about the purgatorial
purpose of human life. Resist. The
purpose of human life as we know it on
this planet is primarily purgatorial.
Resist. Wow. You don't have to worry
about purgatory. You're in it.
Everybody worries about purgatory. It
makes me laugh. Yeah.
All right. So, it means then that
karmically we've earned the right to be
in a place
where we have a choice
and we can determine our own destiny by
the choices we make.
So the absolute
benevolence of divinity is that by one's
own choice, one determines one's own
karmic destiny,
not some arbitrary god who hates you and
throws you into hell or beats you up.
Most of the religions of the world
believe in a god who beats you up, you
know, even bad. Boom, boom, boom.
No, you get to determine it yourself. So
the freedom then to realize the source
of your own existence is that you have
infinite freedom than infinite freedom
is there's no limit upon your choice and
that you are reborn as the Buddhist said
there's no greater
thing to be grateful for for the
likelihood of being born a human on this
planet is is extremely rare.
To be born a human on this planet and to
have heard of enlightenment
is rarer still.
Therefore, waste no time.
So all of us here have accepted that
awareness that we're all here
and we've accepted that we are spiritual
beings and that choice is within our own
hands and that our the freedom then to
become
more evolved is merely a choice.
All right.
The choice is then simplified. So we
repeat how simple it is.
so that we don't look like dumbbells
when we leave this planet.
That's I picture God
dumbbells.
Anyway,
the dumbbells bel. All right. So, it's a
simple thing then. We give up the
pleasure of judgmentalism. That secret
little feeling of glee of you're being
right, the other person being wrong.
That's a hard one to let go of.
It's a hard one to let go of. So, the
ego persists because it's addicted to
the juice. It gets out of its positions.
Let's see if that's right.
I never called it addicted before. We
have permission to ask resist. The ego
is addicted to the payoffs. It gets
resist. Well, yeah, it's addicted. Hey,
we're all hooked on the ego. The ego is
hooked on the juice that gets out of
stuff.
I mean, there's nobody juice nothing
more than a than a than a victim. You
see a victim on TV, oh man, they juice
it for all it's worth, man. all the
melodrama and the tears and the
vindictiveness and how wrong they were
and how right they are and how the world
owes them now and
tens of millions they're going to get to
I mean it's good luck to get played with
by a Catholic priest right what I'm
saying it's
I think I remember it myself.
I just got back a repressed memory.
Well, anyhow, in those days, we didn't
get paid for it, so it didn't happen
that often.
Now, old deagle loves this. And so, what
honesty, you know, spiritual evolution
requires honesty. What do we need to be
honest about? Most people think well I
need to be honest in looking at my the
sinful side my negative side my bad side
comes ownorous
in 12step groups they have a fourth step
and a lot of people would rather die
than take the fourth step because fourth
step is where you take a spiritual
inventory
a strict honest spiritual inventory and
most people hate fourth step four and
we'd rather stay drunk and die than uh
become honest about
It's because they think they're going to
have to go through a guilt trip. A guilt
trip. So, if we recontextualize it, you
don't have to fear a guilt trip in
admitting spiritual honesty. What you're
really going to do is admit that the ego
is an evolution from the animal world.
It has all the characteristics of the
animal world. It needed to do that for
survival.
Those survival techniques have now
become elaborated into levels of human
expression.
Institutions, the government, the
courts, the departments, the bureaus,
all now serve the function that was once
served by sneering
in the wolf back. Let's do our llamas.
Here's how here's how we got seven
llamas. And the way the llamas do this,
they're big woolly eyes, you know.
They're very interesting. The llamas are
adorable.
Llamas have such a wonderful coat of
fur, then in the middle of winter, it'll
snow and they got this much snow on
their back. Huh? You come back tomorrow
and the same snow is still sitting
there. Hasn't even melted. Warmth of
their body doesn't even get through
their fur to melt the snow on their
back. It's really amazing. What was I
going to ask you?
>> Oh, yes. Well, those this is the way the
llamas communicate. They go
It's just what they do. It's hysterical.
Get to be the alpha female.
Now, if if this female doesn't give in
to the alpha me female, she spits at
her. That's why they spit.
They don't spit at humans unless they're
not trained right.
When they're real little, you don't play
with them a lot because then they think
you're another llama, includes you in
the in their family pack. They then
treat you as a peer and will spit at
you. But if you wait till they're a year
or two old before you play with them,
then you are not one of them. And they
don't spit at you because you're not one
of them. So
anyway, I knew you just needed to know
that. But anyway,
What's interesting about watching the
world and in the animal world
especially, there's so much spiritual
information in watching the animal
channel.
Uh
because you watch you're seeing how the
ego plays itself out and it's easy to
see because it's not you, it's them. You
see? So society, the newspapers and the
TV and all is interesting because you
see the ego displayed out there because
it's not a personal you. It's very easy
to see how it's how it plays. You see in
your own life it's a little harder to
see how it plays
because uh that person deserves it.
That's harder to see.
But on TV projected, you can see you can
see the ego games going on. And the ego,
you know, is so human life is the is
really the game board of the ego. The
ego is just a game board. And you see
the llamas, what they're doing is this
whole oneupmanship deal. You know, who's
the more dominant one?
Uh, and that's because they value
dominance. I don't value dominance.
Somebody tells me he's got a bigger car,
more money, and
and he's governor of the state. I think
that's all interesting. But, you know, I
don't react to it because so in other
words, you would have to adopt that
value to be competitive about it. You
understand? So, as human beings, we have
choices the animal doesn't have and we
can choose whether
social status is important to us or not.
At a certain point of life, it's
probably pathologic that it doesn't. And
beyond a certain point of life, it's
pathologic if it persists.
If you're young, you don't care about
it. You're probably in apathy.
Yeah. And uh but then when you reach a
certain point of life, you know, such
things as status and all become rather
meaningless.
All right. So we transcend these things
by giving up the fact that they don't
have any payoff anymore.
Having status and a big house, a lot of
money, it doesn't have any payoff. When
it doesn't have any payoff, you let it
go. It doesn't mean anything anymore.
You can walk away from it and not really
feel any loss because you've already
juiced it and you see what's there and
you don't need it anymore. So the secret
then to transcending levels of
consciousness is to just see that the
ego is
the residual of the animal world. It's
not personal. It's built into your
brain. In the back of your brain is the
old reptile brain. Nothing you can do
about that, folks.
Wanting to kill a guy that pulls in
front of you in in traffic, that's
normal.
Any good dinosaur would chop them up and
eat them.
The only thing is you're not a dinosaur
anymore. So anyway, you're not supposed
to be anyway. Some people really still
are though. You actually those are the
people pull in front of you. They're
still dinosaurs and they deserve to die.
Everybody
horrible deaths. Yeah. All right.
So you see, you develop a sense of
humor, a light-heartedness because
you're not identifying the value of
humor. Humor is a way of disidentifying
and getting distance from things.
The more evolved you get spiritually,
the more greater your sense of humor
becomes because everything becomes
ludicrous, ridiculous, and absurd when
seems from a certain viewpoint because
you're not identifying with it anymore.
So the llamas out there as they do their
whole thing, you know, are very
entertaining. That's because we're not
llamas. If we were llamas, we wouldn't
think it's so entertaining.
It'd be life or death for us, right? And
it' be life or death.
All right? So getting even being
addictive, all those things,
you only persist in them so long as
you're getting a payoff. So there's only
one thing we have to surrender and let
go, and that is uh the willingness to
get the payoff of these various
spiritual positions. If you're willing
to let go of the payoff, then suddenly
that which is prevails and the reward is
10 million times greater than anything
you ever let go of. One instant in that
presence is worth all the pain and
suffering of all the spiritual work you
ever did.
the knowingness that comes out of it
that one is safe forever that one is uh
there's nothing ever to fear ever again
the reality of that which you are if
you're context then you're then you're
immune to content right that sounds
rather abstract but if you as you walk
around in the world realize that you're
context and not content then you realize
you're absolute safe because it's only
as content as you're in danger at any
The fact that the store is staying open
and that you're there and Walmarts is
running is not going to be changed by
you and the clerk and what goes on.
In other words, that which prevails
continues to prevail. So you identify
more with that which is prevailing
than the details of it. And that takes
you out of the line of fire. Takes you
out of the line of fire. And
instinctively you'll know it. And
a lot of times you go through diaresis
in spiritual work. You find yourself
building up tension and gaining weight
and retaining salt and then suddenly you
reach a state of realization and wow you
just pee up a storm for a day or two.
You let go retaining all that sodium
chloride and uh yeah you do. So you'll
see the fluctuations in spiritual work
and just when you think you're not
making any progress that's the time to
continue straight ahead. The one
training that is of ultimate value is to
walk straight ahead no matter what.
And at the finally this this you need to
know because anybody doing spiritual
work you can reach the final doorway
totally unexpected. You can be just
muddling along getting absolutely
nowhere along
and one day you start doing some
spiritual practice or looking at
suddenly and suddenly
you're looking at the infinite
possibility of letting go
of the sense of eye that you're familiar
with. And at that last moment, at that
last moment, you need the words to walk
straight ahead.
No matter what you run into in spiritual
work, walk right through it because it's
all illusion. Any fear that you can come
up with is illusurary because in reality
there is no fear. Consequently, if you
experience fear,
that's an imagination of the ego.
Therefore, there's no danger of walking
through
any kind of fear that arises during
meditation.
Anybody who does spiritual work can be
confronted with that last moment right
before enlightenment where
the fear of letting go the sense of I as
who I am comes up at that moment you'll
remember to walk through the fear you're
absolutely safe when you let go of all
that you think you are then you realize
the truth of what you absolutely are and
you're beyond fear forever All
right. So, we'll stop for lunch and then
we'll resume afterwards and then we'll
have questions questions and discussions
later. That's enough
lecturing for this morning.
Well, I have all these questions and
each one takes a full afternoon. So,
I'll have to start.
We thought maybe if people like the
lectures, you know, next year we would
do them maybe four times during the year
instead of 12
and maybe do it 10 to two with a
continental breakfast and then 10 to two
and then spend the rest of the
afternoon, you know, talking more
individual and greeting people and
talking with them individually.
That would sounds like good.
Uh but I thought the first year we
should cover the entire material sort of
you see and those who aren't here catch
up via the tapes you know uh so we would
all be at the same starting place.
Um there's a friend of mine here, Lou.
Lou stand up. Lou Lou uh has a uh is
facilitating
uh groups, study groups all around the
country. And those of you that are
interested in joining a study group and
internet,
um say hello to Lou and give me your
phone or address, your internet,
whatever you do on the internet.
>> Or I can give you my contact.
>> Yeah. I don't know how that thing works
but and I don't trust it at all but
for one thing you have to be able to
type so I forget that. So anyway I leave
it up to people to understand those
things. Uh
you see the the reality is that
everything is happening of its own.
We mentioned it before. As you
concentrate more and more on the
peripheral, on the space in which
everything is happening instead of on
the specifics of what's happening,
you become detached from uh
the yin and yang, the pull and the push
of solar plexus interaction of the world
in which everybody's trying to
manipulate response out of you. And
as you identify more with the space
And as you get into the habit of that,
it's like a walking meditation
and then all of a sudden you notice
everything is happening of its own.
Nothing is causing anything else. All is
happening of its own. Everything is
happening spontaneously.
And
everything
is merely being that which it is.
Nothing is causing anything.
Each thing is fulfilling its potential
to be what it is. That's why the bird
flies. It's not caused to fly. Doesn't
even have any purpose to fly.
It just flies because that's what birds
do.
We did a lecture prior on causality,
the basic illusion of the ego. You don't
get really beyond causality to an
extremely high level. But
I think it jumps
uh to to to
be aware always of the space in which
all is happening instead of the content
of the space
takes you sort of out of it. get get you
out of that solar plexus
uh yin-yang g the grasp of the world
which is always trying to manipulate
your emotions and usually it's through
the solar plexus you know
although they appeal to the spleen a lot
too you know feel sorry for me and
getting with them and all that
all right so we'll let that be for
whatever that is
uh I get asked this often the pendulum
is very often a very adequate
substitute. Uh thing about a pendulum is
I I think I don't think you should uh
uh dows uh things that are negative
extremely negative. I would get you can
ask yes or no. You're just asking
yourself yes or no.
Uh
there's a specific from the course of
miracles
that the human body is a indication of
the belief and separation from God. Well
yes and no. Yes it is. uh as I said the
uh the body evolves as a it belongs to
the planet. It is part of the physical
universe. The body is an evolution of uh
the animal world. Uh
and u
the self
the small self identifies with it as
being separate.
Did the small self think it was separate
before it identified with the body?
Well, yes, it would have. Otherwise, it
wouldn't have chosen a body.
Um,
I mean to say no to my father and
reactivate the body
was
taking that chance
that when you reidentify
with the physicality that you'll believe
you're separate from the one.
That's the risk in doing that and
generally it's not advisable
what actually happens when people
worldwide pray for peace. Well, that was
you know the uh harmonic convergence.
I said the consciousness level jumped
from 190 to 207
in the late 80s. That was the time it
was it coincided with a harmonic
convergence
which coincided with the time when
a great many a high percentage of
spiritually evolved people on the planet
all prayed for peace simultaneously. We
all got up at 4 in the morning or
something. I forget what it was. Yeah, I
think it was 4 in the morning or
something. And uh that jump occurred
about that same time.
Now as I said
uh causality is an illusion of the ego.
So you can't say that all those people
praying for peace caused it to jump to
nor that the harmonic convergence caused
it to happen or any particular alignment
of the planets
caused it to happen. No, it's more that
something outside of all these events
simultaneously brought them all into
existence. So,
it has to do more with advanced
theoretical physics understanding that
the spinning electron on this side of
the universe doesn't cause the one on
the other side of the universe to spin.
That that which is outside both of them
but encompasses both of them uh is
simultaneously. So people ask me about
astrology and uh the alignment of the
planets of course is a perceptual
illusion. There's no alignment of the
planets. It's all in your head. Uh if
you go up there in a spaceship, you're
not going to see any Pegasus up there.
There ain't no such animal.
But it can be that at that which brings
on a state of peace at and in other
words, the two are happening
simultaneously. It's not that the
alignment of the planets is causing
this, but that which is concordant, the
blooming of flowers is concordant with
the spring. You know what I'm saying? Uh
let's let's ask about the um
I've never asked actually asked about
it. I just had my own understanding
about it. Uh we can ask questions about
this. Resist resist. Okay. Um
the intention the
the conjoined intention did play a part
in raising the consciousness in the late
' 80s. Resist. Oh, it did. Okay.
It did.
Uh
so we have quite a diversity of
questions here. Um
uh in the in the book Eye of the Eye, it
says I mentioned that the
book of Revelations is an aberration in
the New Testament. Um things that I I
warned there's a caveat in the beginning
of the book. It says traditional
religionists may be disturbed by this
and then they're better read something
else.
The evolution of religion, you see, came
out of primitive,
you know, all of life came out of a
primitive condition. And primitive man
uh when he heard thundering and thunder
and lightning uh as he evolved uh began
to think it was the angry gods. And so
we see the Incas sacrificing virgins. We
see the ancient tribes of Israel. is a
primitive manu uh considering God from
an anthropomorphic
position. And why wouldn't he? So, we
can't make man wrong for doing that. If
you're primitive man and it thunders and
lightnings and all, you figure the gods
must be angry. So, you sacrifice a few
more virgins and uh to pacify the gods.
And this is done. Ancient Hebrews did
it. sacrificing lambs to to the western
cult behind the curtain and all that
things. So the anthropomorphic images of
God of course uh were common.
They're projections from the
unconscious. They're also projections of
the concept of causality. Of course,
what man forgets is that all these
catastrophes and floods and volcanoes
and hail and all that went on long
before mankind appeared on this planet.
They've only been here 400,000 years.
Well, for millions of years, all this
has been going on. So, obviously, it's
not done by an angry god to get even
with man because man wasn't even here
yet.
Okay.
So the primitive belief then is that the
pro it projects
uh its fears onto a divinity and then
imagines that he they will have to meet
this divinity which is a projection of
their own unconscious. So every culture
has it you know we get the lord of the
underworld
weighing your sins etc.
Every culture has its primitive origins
as some persist.
Some tribal belief systems still persist
and are revered.
Others paradoxically are quite evolved.
Native American
traditional beliefs were quite evolved.
Uh
Chief Detroit calibrates at 700. He gave
a very famous address which uh is of a
very high level of spiritual
understanding. So the great white spirit
of the Native American was already
considerably more evolved than many
supposedly more advanced civilizations.
The American Indian saw the divinity of
all of life. That's why it prays and
asked the deer for forgiveness. That
uh I have to eat you for dinner. Well,
the deer doesn't mind.
uh the purpose of the deer's life is to
give life back to the Indian. So they
there's a mutuality. So the so some
seemingly primitive tribes had pretty um
advanced consciousness and understanding
that uh the divine spirit is present in
all that lives is a pretty advanced
state of awareness. Um
um the difficulty with uh
uh Christianity considerably has been
uh the decision to include the Old
Testament with the New. Well, the Old
Testament is full of all the tribal
anthropomorphic projections of God as an
angry, vengeful, jealous, insecure,
paranoid.
And uh
there's only three books of the Old
Testament that make you go strong with
kinesiology. Psalms, Proverbs,
and um
>> Huh.
>> Yeah. Right.
Proverb. Proverbs is in the 300s. And I
like Proverbs. It's full of really pathy
saints or like Ben Franklin, you know. I
like proverbs. Psalms of course is is
beautiful and poetic and mystical and
lovely. And Genesis comes forth with the
first statement of that which man really
needs to know and that is that you're
created by God.
The importance importance of that
statement
uh over surpasses everything.
Why it was included with the New
Testament is beyond me. But anyway,
historical reasons being what they are.
The difficulty with uh revelations is
John who was the source of revelations
uh had lower those are lower astral
hallucinations.
If you calibrate new the revelations it
comes out as 70.
70 is the spleen. 70 is coming from the
lower astral. So when we said this
morning there's an infinite universe of
universes.
Uh these universes have different
dimensions higher and lower astrals
astral the most common commonly known to
man because man has contacted those
domains through hallucinations
hallucinogenic drugs nightmares
delusions.
Um so mankind has been able to contact
the higher astral where there's divas
and beautiful channelers of uh uh sort
of angelic level
and rather evolved beings. Uh
and then of course the dimensions in the
astral go down the same as they do here.
And so you have the lower astral realms
of the demons and uh the devils and the
various no goods.
A lot of these uh entities in the lower
astral like to to hook humans. Now what
is the lower astral made up of? The
lower astral is made up of those who
deny God. No, not deny God. those who
refuse God
because you can be a truthful
atheist and agnostic and say I just
really don't know. Uh that's not
refusing God. That's saying
honestly because the limitation of my
intellect and my personal experience I
cannot get into the question one way or
the other meaningfully and therefore
honestly I decline it. I was an agnostic
for many years.
Um,
what was I going to say? Oh, yeah. So,
the lower astral, however, is is made up
of people who have had the opportunity
and the capacity to accept God but have
refused it. Refused God. Okay, let's
make sure if that's correct.
The lower astral, we have permission to
ask in front of this audience today and
here and now. Resist. The lower astral
is made up of those who refuse God.
Resist.
It is not the same as those who deny God
resist. Those who deny God can still go
to good places resist.
There's hope for everybody. There's an
honest man's level of heaven
where all good atheists and agnostics
go. Well, we all know people who are
ethical principle and you trouble trust
them with your bank bank account. But
when it comes to the religion and all
that, they say, "I just I don't know. I
just can't handle it. I got a patient
like that and he's getting older and
older and he knows he's going to die and
he says, "Doc, I just wish I could
believe the way you believe. I don't
know. I was brought up by the Catholic
Church and somehow I just can't get over
it."
I said, "Well, you got to forgive it.
Forgive your upbringing because it
wasn't really the Catholic Church. It's
the way man held religion back in the
20s and the 30s. You know, we all grew
up with one of the beliefs of becoming
an atheist or an agnostic, whatever. I
was I think I was first an atheist and
then I got more sophisticated became
agnostic was the great relief of uh fear
and guilt about sin you know and sin was
a spot on your soul my mother would say
and uh if you sin
uh you get this spot on your soul oh my
god and then if you went to communion
with his spot on your soul god knows
what happens to you
it's too awful to imagine
all right So
the lower astral is very common in
Sedona. Uh
the ch there's chandlers all over uh
from all kinds of dimensions on the
other side. God bless them. There's Baba
this and Baba that on the other side and
um and all kinds of controllers and um
trans mediums and
it's something I warn about in the books
I write. As a teacher, it's my
responsibility to um advise people of
the various pitfalls because uh many
spiritual seekers, you know, are
enthused and very naive. And a lot of it
sounds very glamorous, glamorous and
entrancing.
I went to get a psychic reading and he
told me all about my grandmother's false
teeth and how could he have known? He
must have known. I mean, you know, it's
very impressive when you walk into it.
And of course, there are some people who
are very in intuitive and they do guess
quite a few things right. However,
they've been very wrong. I'll tell you
too.
One time
says, "Your grandmother says you should
eat more greens or you'll get
arthritis."
It could have been, you know,
you need to know the calibrated level of
what's on the other side and you need to
know the calibrated level of what's on
this side, the trans medium and and the
source.
Um, there's a glamour and a trap in it
all. in that the lower astral is see one
of the uh benefits of being a human is
that the human has the choice of
returning to god. Uh the lower astral by
having refused it does not have the
choice. So the lower astral hates the
human because the human has no glass
ceiling no topside
and is not condemned to the hells that
they exist in. So, one thing a lower
astral loves is to get a naive spiritual
seeker, especially one who's making good
progress,
and get control over them and lead them
astray. The delight is that of mischief.
the devil. The devil uh little devils
love to pull somebody off the pathway
and watch them go and sit out in their
car in the middle of the desert waiting
for the
um uh what you call it from other
planets to come and pick them up.
>> What do you call those people from other
planets?
>> Aliens.
>> Aliens. Yes. Sitting out in the desert
waiting for the aliens to come and get
you. I mean, good god. I mean, you know,
it's it happens every day. And uh so the
naive are are pulled in. Uh I had a
teacher who said never trust anything
unless it's in a body. In other words,
unless you can see who you're talking to
or their writings, let's say if they but
somebody who either does or has existed
in human form because you have no idea
what you're dealing with. And other
universes are extremely complex, subtle,
and ingenious.
Spiritual deception is a long and
honored tradition in India. They've been
at it for thousands of years before you
were even thought of. They were expert
at it in those years and they are expert
in it today. It's a tradition.
All kinds of manipulations of seemingly
magical and wondrous events. Huh.
All
the spiritual seeker is best to stay
with that which is safe, that which is
uh calibrates over 200. For instance,
the course of miracles calibrates at
600.
All right. 600 is a pretty pure pathway
to follow. Uh so if you know the
calibrated level of that which you're
following,
uh you avoid the lower astral.
The oliver hates that which is you might
say hates love and hates divinity
and it seeks to subvert truth. So the
lower astral influences are what
convince Islamics to think that killing
people for Allah will get them to
heaven.
I mean it's an obvious severe
distortion.
And yet if you get people young enough
and small enough and begin brain
brainwashing them with this belief they
will believe it by the time they grew up
you know goble G gobles German Nazi
Germany did it with the German youth uh
they didn't know any different didn't
know any better and so it seems so it
seems to me that revelations was a way
in which the Lord astral got into the
new testament which was a huge threat to
it the new Testament if you especially
if you do the if you read the
translation from the Aramaic rather than
from the Greek
uh calibrates extremely high if you take
out revelations. Take out revelations
it calibrates extremely high and it has
extreme power.
So
to
sort of disable it to some degree,
uh that which is its opposite was placed
right in the middle. And you'll notice
that the extreme right wing of
Christianity
plays off revelations. That's it get its
fe, you know, when it shakes its fist
with hatred of the sinner and death and
hellfire.
That all plays out of the revelations.
out of revelations. So that particular
wing of Christianity
uh would feel threatened if you
diminish the validity of uh revelations.
Yeah. You understand? Because that's
their whole ministry is based on that.
This whole ministry is based on hatred
and the hatred of sin. Well, it sounds
very pious to hate sin except that
hatred is hatred, isn't it?
To hate a bad man is the same as hating
a a good man. I mean what holds you down
is the hatred itself. So to hate sin is
is really not a very cool place to be.
Anyway, the the visions that uh that
John had, John himself calibrated at 70
just like the book of Revelations
calibrates at 70. The vision that John
had is a lower astral reality.
It was related to me by a very
well-known teacher in Sedona.
who uh was in that place saw what was
going to happen. He brought all his ga
gathered all his uh followers. They
prepared for the end times and all that.
So the end times
was uh oh let's see when was that maybe
the late 70s uh 80s. The end times had a
great big play again with all the
psychics. Everybody who got a reading
heard about the end times and how New
York was going to crack down 14th
Street. There was a big uh fault under
14th Street,
right under the best German restaurant
in New York City
on 14th Street.
California was going to fall off in the
ocean. The Phoenix was going to become a
a seapport. Remember all that?
People were building underground houses
and the dome houses. And uh so that was
an asteria that spread. And so that kind
of teaching
how to how to tell that teaching right
off the bat without calibrating it is
simple. That which comes from God brings
peace.
And anything that brings anything other
than peace and love is not of God. That
is the rule of discernment.
So you don't have to calibrate
everything because perceptual as the
third eye of the Buddha body opens up.
One perceives that which is of God and
that which is not of God. You see and
that which is not of God becomes an an
absurdity.
But there were all kinds of people. Oh
there's they're still practicing in
Sedona by the way. I see their name and
somebody gave me a list of their names
off the internet. So the same creatures
that were predicting the California
falling off in the ocean and god knows
what all the
little people from other planets coming
to get us and all are still practicing.
They're still they didn't go out. So
when they predicted end of the world
came and they world end world didn't
come to an end they just changed the
story. It's not going to be 87. It's
going to be 93. Then 93 came and went.
Yeah.
All right. So, lots of people have tuned
in on that lower astral thing, seeing
the end of the world, the great
apocalypse and all. And on that astral
level, it is a reality. On that level,
it is a reality. Okay, let's see
the level which was perceived by John is
a reality. Resist on the lower astral
level. Resist. It is a reality on this
planet. Resist.
Sorry, wrong universe. Okay,
it is the truth, but not for this
planet, folks. So, we said this morning,
there are many dimensions and what's
true in one dimension, you see, there's
movies going on in each dimension. And
their movie is not our movie, but was
seen by those people. Now, the person
that told me that uh out here in Sedona
was a well-known teacher and he
literally believed it because he
experienced it. And I'm sure John who
gave us revelations, it was a literal
experience. All right.
There are many mental disorders due to
genetic a genetic problem. All mental
disorders are due to brain chemistry on
the operational level.
A third of the planet has a
insufficiency of serotonin. Not enough
serotonin in their brain that essential
neurotransmitter to keep them out of
depression, addiction, gambling, sex
addiction, pedophilia, whatever.
Uh there's not enough serotonin and they
go into depression. Depression is the
most prevalent and largest illness in
the United States. Onethird of the
population is subject to depression.
And I believe operationally the best
thing to do with it is like you wear
glasses if you're nearsighted. You just
take something that raises the serotonin
because you're making up for a genetic
defect.
All right? I'm sure it has karmic
anticedants as well.
So I tell people in the office, do what
you can to raise the neurotransmitter
and do what you can to evolve as far as
you can spiritually.
Also, we're not talking about karma
today, but karmic research will almost
always take you back to the lifetime
that precipitated the depression in this
lifetime.
The penance that you're paying now for
what you said or did in that lifetime.
One can also go into
the lower astral
through psychic events, uh, drugs, LSD.
The so-called bad trip is nothing but a
trip in the lower astral.
Nightmares, hallucinations,
imaginations.
Uh so one can plunge unwittingly into
the lower astral. Nightmares are
probably the one the commonest ones.
One can have difficulty with other
neurotransmitters in the brain. the
normal brain.
See, there there's an infinite number of
transmissions going on psychically as
well as electronically and otherwise in
a multitude of an infinite multitude of
universes.
So, the brain wouldn't know what in the
world to pick up. Uh
when I was young, radio was new. Radio
was a novelty
like the internet internet is now. It
was a novelty.
Uh, I remember when we got a radio and
in fact we didn't have a radio, so I
made one a crystal radio and um, we own
the coils ourself and all did all that.
We had a cat whisker that you poked
around till you got a station.
Oh god. And but you had to afford
earphones, which I didn't have the money
for earphones, so I'd have to buy
earphones to play with this thing. But
anyway, what your radio does is has
limiter circuits. the radio, you look at
your station dial on the radio, the
oldfashioned radio am
li limiting circuits. Otherwise, every
time you turn your radio on, you're
going to get about eight stations at
once. Eight stations coming in at once.
So, these limiting circuits are to
screen out other frequencies. Well,
there are certain kinds of mental
disorders where that neurotransmitter
that energizes that system to keep out
other frequencies is missing or
deficient or due to some life event it
gets diminished and uh there's I'm sure
there's some karmic propensity
and the people will literally experience
one of the levels of hell. So I always
tell people if such a thing should occur
to you just presume that it just take my
say so in some other lifetime you curse
somebody to hell and that karma is
coming back
and therefore here's what I would do if
you get into a hellish state
start praying up a storm and say dear
God in that lifetime I did not realize
what I was doing when I cursed somebody
to hell and I asked for forgiveness and
I asked that person's forgiveness and I
forgive myself for that ignorance
and Because in a way one can bring hell
upon oneself by cursing another to hell.
So right.
So you simultaneously undo the karma the
best you can. You try to undo whatever
you might have done. Whenever anything
negative befalls you, it's always very
practical to presume it's some kind of
karma coming back.
If you treat it as though it's some
karma from a previous lifetime, you
don't have to literally know it. just
guess that's likely so and do what you
can to undo that via forgiveness. Uh
forgiving yourself, forgiving the other
person
below level 600 is not likely that a
person is going to remember a past
lifetime.
I never asked that question
whether people actually remember the
past lifetime. Well, I guess they do.
People under 600 do remember past
lifetimes resist. Yeah. Especially
infants resist. Yeah. Especially
children. Yeah. People do remember that.
But let's say something befalls you in
this lifetime. Uh you may not recall,
you know, what went on in some lifetime.
But you're in pretty good grounds to to
presume that that that is the likelihood
and handle it as though that is what
occurred. Yeah.
thing things occur because of such
complex conditions. Now we said nothing
causes anything else.
So an event here you might say
precipitates a climate and that climate
is what interacts with that which you
are to precipitate a certain event. you
understand that it's not causing it.
It's a favorable condition in which that
can come forth.
Many things that you think is a calamity
is something that actually due to your
spiritual commitment, you've brought
back because of your wish to undo it. I
went through surgery for a hernia
without anesthesia.
It was excruciating.
And I remembered exactly what I had
done. I was reliving exactly what I'd
done
in that war.
You know, with a sword, I'd goured this
guy through the groin.
And
that wasn't the error. He was down and
out. The error was I didn't finish him
off.
The guilt of that lasted to this
lifetime.
Out of true compassion, I would have
finished it for him so he didn't have to
die a slow lingering death of infection
and days and weeks of agonizing pain
before he went. But I didn't. I lacked
the moral courage to do
the honest thing. In another lifetime, I
didn't make that mistake.
He and I killed each other at the same
time. I told you about him. Yeah.
Anyway,
so the undoing then the forgiveness of
that, the guilt of that brought back the
the opportunity to reexperience and to
give my forgive myself
because the guilt of that to a warrior's
conscience, not to another person's
conscience, but to the consciousness of
a warrior. That was a cowardly thing to
do. And the coward is of not killing him
off that lasted all those lifetimes. It
wasn't that many lifetimes ago. But
anyway,
so you just got me talking about karma
here. Sorry. We started off in
Revelation and ended up
I told you already told you about the
the Mo Muhammad and the Islam guy that I
he and I got into it during the Crusades
and killed each other at the same time,
you know. Yeah. I killed him for Jesus
and he killed me for Allah. And uh at
the same time we were good and uh I got
him right through the heart and he
killed me dinner in the mackerel and we
went out of body and both started it was
hysterical laughing you know he said I
did it for Jesus he said I did it for
all we just broke us up you know it was
hysterical
we've been great pals for many a
lifetime okay
uh what is the most direct path to the
conscious level 500 well we did it this
morning the willing to let go the
payoffs of the ego, the gratifications,
the feeling of justification, the the
the willingness to feel victorious at
another person's expense.
Um what you have to remind yourself is
although this what you're getting out of
this ego position has a certain
pleasure, it is not happiness.
You get pleasure out of
turning the knife in somebody's back,
but you don't get happiness out of it.
So, if you let go the pleasure of
revenge, let's say, what you get is the
happiness of being a free a freer, more
loving, and therefore self-loving
spirit. So, there is an enormous payoff.
You get back far more than you let go
of.
Um
this asked how can you avoid getting
false answers in the kinesiology
process. Uh I explained it before the
it's your intention. Uh you see you have
I would have to go back and explain the
physics of uh kinesiology.
Now, physics of kinesiology
has to do with the fact that
consciousness
recognizes that which is and it does not
recognize that which is not.
Therefore, that which is false because
it is not gets no response.
The intentions of the two people. When
you do kinesiology,
it's best to not care one way or the
other about the answer. And you won't
always get the answer that pleases you
or the answer that you think you'll get.
The answer you get is irrespective of
the test subject and it's really
irrespective of your own belief system
because we've tested it over many times.
And I've done it on uh videotapes which
many of you probably have home in which
we test things out which are completely
the opposite of what everybody believes
and we still get the correct answer
and we've done it you know in front of
large populations and it's been done by
thousands of practitioners for many
years. Uh, one
I remember it was done in Korea in which
we held up two apples and or no, there
was a two packages of cabbage, right?
Somebody gave us a package of cabbage. I
held it up and we we're all ones and
twos, you know, made everybody go
strong. Then we held up the other
cabbage and made everybody go weak. I
didn't know what it was. She said,
"Well, this one's got pesticide and this
one doesn't." See, so it's irrespective
of your belief system. The best test
subjects are children. And I think in
power versus force volume one can uh
video we test organic tobacco versus
commercial tobacco and we test uh
picture of Hitler in a brown envelope
and all. Uh we used a little uh little
child and of course the answers were all
correct.
Um
how is discernment different than
judgment? Well discernment is spiritual
discernment is the opening of the third
eye. It's one of the gifts of the
spirit.
Um,
and it has nothing to do with judgment.
Discernment is noticing whether it's a
rainy day or a sunny day. And it's not a
moral judgmental matter. Uh, judgment is
bringing in um an additional dimension
of ethics, morality, uh, spiritual
belief systems, etc.
Okay.
In dealing with the so-called new age
community and all of its um attractions,
it's a carnival. Uh it has many
attractions.
Uh discernment is uh considerable.
Usually judgment is not involved because
many of these people who have all these
various practices, you know, themselves
believe in it. I mean they're not at the
Kanye but because they themselves are
part of the cadre that have been caught
into the belief system themselves
there there's one currently on the
internet about a local spiritual group
and u
with a description of how this group
operates. It was right out of the book
I'd written on how to recognize a cult.
It was like right out of the Yeah. And
uh
and the the leader of this group gets uh
messages from the other side. He's got
uh I don't know, they always call him
Michael or
Baba something other. Anyway, so his his
spirit on the other side. So this guy
goes and writes up four facious
statements
and and goes to this guy who consults
his spirit guide. His spirit guide gives
him a reading on these four questions.
All of them were facious
about the spirit of his four-year-old
daughter. He never had a four-year-old
daughter.
Went up with his first wife. He never
was married before.
All four were totally facious. And yet
he got an elaborate reading on each and
every one of them. You know what I'm
saying?
Uh what are the names of individuals who
currently calibrate over 700 currently
living? I I guess that means living. I
really don't know. Uh I don't know when
I people over 700.
I don't know what people calibrated at.
So I wouldn't know if they calibrate
over 700. Um I wouldn't know the names
of them. What we've asked is how many.
So we're trying to get the distribution
of the levels of consciousness on the
planet, how it plays out. Uh
so we were asking that mainly to see how
the levels play out
and uh
I don't know who they would be. All I
know is that there's approximate numbers
approximate numbers but um we can ask
about it. There's a graph here that
shows it somehow.
Well, this is generally sort of a graph
which of course will get upside down.
Right. Okay. and backwards. All right.
H upside down and backwards. Yes. All
right. So there there's not too many as
you can see. It's just a statistically
statistically. So we asked how many
people are there. It has changed by the
way. First of all, this change was u the
number of people who calibrate over 200
since 1995 has shifted.
Um
the number of people below 200 is now
only 78%. It was like 85%. 7% of the
population since we first wrote the book
has shifted from the negative to the
positive positive range. The number of
people over 600 has also increased.
Uh let's see. I forgot what I wrote now.
It probably changes. Uh over we have
permission to ask I guess we should ask
over what does this say over 700 over
700 there's more than 50 people resist
is more than 30 people resist more than
20 people resist 21 22 23 24 25 26 27 28
All right so at this moment it says
there's 29 people on the planet over 700
Huh?
What are their names?
I probably can't pronounce them.
>> Let's see.
>> Let's ask because I I revised this every
couple of years because of a new book. I
have to revise the figures. We have
permission. How many did we say?
>> Somebody write this down cuz I will
remember later. Uh, okay. Over 800. We
have permission to ask that. Resist.
>> Over 800. There's more than 12.
There's more than seven. More than
eight. More than nine. More than 10.
More than 11. More than 12. 11. 11.
Okay. I don't know what figures we got
at home.
>> Over 800. There's 11 beings resist. 12
being resist. Okay. Somebody's writing
this down. Okay. Yeah,
>> cuz I won't remember it. All right. Over
900. There's more than six. Seven. Six.
Currently, there's six over 900 resist.
There's seven resist. There's six over
900. That's pretty good.
Uh, one time I think there was only one.
Okay. Um, we'll go up to 950. Let's see.
What do we say? Six. Okay.
>> Did we ask permission?
>> Okay. We have permission to ask this.
Resist in front of this audience here
and now. Resist.
>> No.
>> Okay. We went up to 800.
>> We We asked the number over 700. That
was correct. Resist. That was
permissible resist. The number over 800
was permissible resist. The number over
900 is permissible resist. The number
over 950 is permissible resist. No.
Anyway, that's what it says.
The importance of it was that
that the positivity of the higher few
counterbalances the total total
negativity of the masses. That was the
point of it that it counterbalances it.
All right.
uh in the uh sense of the silence. The
silence
the the sense of oneness is all is one
and the same thing. The silence the self
that which you are all of existence
is a totality of which there is no
witness.
The witness and that which is witnessed
are one and the same. There's no
and there isn't a this witnessing of
that because there is no this and that.
There is only that which is
there would have to be a this witnessing
of that which is is not is not the way
it works.
Yeah.
Uh here's one about serotonin deficiency
as does one-third of the do I recommend
antid-depressants? Yes, I think so. I
don't see any point to suffer
needlessly.
And um if you get out of the depression,
then you can go back to uh establishing
a life that is as supportive as you can.
And depressions are periodic. They come
on cyclically. They come on for many
reasons unknown.
Um many of them are temporary and some
are biological bi bipolar disorder.
There's a genetic factor and the
depression will just recurve its own
under the best of circumstances.
So because it's like diabetes for which
you take insulin or migraine headaches
for which you take imitatrix. There's no
point to lie on the bed all day with a
migraine when there's now some
medications that will cure it within an
hour. There's no point to suffering.
Um because a person who is spiritually
committed all their intentions because
of the spiritual intention
of the spiritual will
all that occurs can be made to serve
one's spiritual intention. All suffering
all seeming misfortune
has a coloration an aspect a
significance if contextualized in a
certain way it can be made to serve
one's spiritual purpose.
Can a person evolve up the scale of
consciousness without experiencing the
lower level of it? Well, I don't know.
Can you be a human being without once
having been a worm? I don't know.
It isn't that the person so much
evolves. It's that consciousness
evolves. So that consciousness at this
level would choose this kind of uh
animal or body or plant or wherever that
consciousness is at that time.
Um we did an interesting thing. We'll
confirm this also for the fun of it. We
have permission to ask about the spirit
entering the fetus resist. The spirit
enters the human spirit enters the fetus
before the first month. Resist
before the second month. Resist before
the third month. Resist.
The human spirit enters the embryo after
Human spirit. So the embryo is a
potential home for
the human spirit. But it's not till the
third month that it actually chooses to
energize and join with that embryo. Huh.
So it could be that one more or less
chooses an incarnation that's consistent
with one's level of consciousness.
Had the body been that of a worm there
in the snowbank, I probably would not
have gone back in it. Even if my father
was there,
it just wouldn't have been suitable. You
know what I mean?
Uh mantra is a different meditation you
know we'll talk about meditation uh
techniques later on in the courses.
Uh mantra is a very specific thing. Um
many times it's the teaching of a very
specific school in which the
consciousness level of the school itself
plays a part. The consciousness level of
the teacher plays a part.
We recently did one. We calibrated the
level uh that were of a
dear a Sanskrit classic
translated by I think Sacha Dandanda.
Yeah.
All right. That certainly would sound
legitimate, right? Okay. And in there
Oh, I know. The teachings of Pangelli.
All right. teachings of the sutras are
proud and jolly. All right. So in there
it suggests that we it suggests
a mantra.
We have permission to do this resist.
Um
all right the mantra ohm calibrates over
over 600
over 700.
Oh, over 740.
Oh, about 700. Oh, about 700.
All right. But the way it was written in
this translation from the sutras of
Polly
was okay.
A calibrates over 200 resist.
So whether you're going a all day or
going all day
means you go to heaven or hell folks.
I hate to tell you you get the wrong
book.
It's curtains.
All right. So I would test out the u
level of mantra.
Uh there are many mantras that make you
go weak.
Test out the level. See, you would say,
well, you see how you instantly get
blinded? Well, the suture is a pot
jelly. Amen. Right. Translated by Sacha.
Amen. It's got to be the absolute truth.
No, don't trust it. I don't care if it's
Sachianda. I don't care who wrote it.
I don't care if his beard goes across
the room. Doesn't mean anything.
You got to have bald head and a beard
goes from him, robes and incense going.
and the sound of in the background and
then the great Baba Bjum comes forth.
Smoke shoots out of his ears and the
miraculous occurs,
right?
India's full of it.
After studying at so and so's asham for
three years, they come back from India
and mainly they've got mimic dysentery.
the TM meditation with those of us
who've done TM, we were given a private
uh mantra. Um
uh I never investigated it. Um I never
investigated it. I don't suppose there
something I could really ask. Uh the TM
mantra that I was given,
>> I have permission to ask.
>> Ask. Yeah.
>> Okay. I have permission to ask it
resist. The TM mantra I was given is
over 200 resistance.
>> Never asked that one.
>> It was over 300 resist 350 390.
Anyway, it was over 200. So,
well, let's see. You see, a thing
doesn't have to calibrate at 800 to be
worth studying because things are not
useful except at your own level. If
you're worrying about how to forgive
your mother-in-law,
reading something by Krishna, you know,
the Bavagita is not going to help you
much.
Krishna says, I'm the supreme being, the
ultimate reality of all. Does that help
you with your mother-in-law? Not much.
Might do a lot better to pick a
spiritual program that calibrates around
300 and tells you how to get off
personalizing other people's problems.
You might do better going through an
Alanon group or
um you know because
so just that a calibration doesn't mean
anything except that it's it's pertinent
to that level.
You know, I think I've told you in a
previous lecture when I was born or or
when I was born into this body, I was
three. The body was three. And suddenly
out of the void, the nothingness
of the hinana voidness, which I believed
was the ultimate truth from those
lifetimes.
And suddenly there was the stunning
awareness of existence. Awareness of
existence as existence. I was conscious
that I existed.
Instantly came the fear of
non-existence.
First of all, I wasn't happy to exist in
the first place.
To be in a body again was not a delight.
To be alive as a human being was not a
pleasure at all.
I was not happy with existence. But even
though I wasn't happy with existence as
a physical human being, the fear of
non-existence then came up.
Well, the duality of existence of the
self, the reality of the self is
existence versus non-existence is not a
problem till you get to 8:40.
That's a problem that doesn't arise till
about level 840. Yeah, it's not a
problem till 8:40. So you really don't
have to study
how to transcend existence versus
non-existence
until you get there any more than you
need a map to Cincinnati when you're not
even Ohio yet. So
I think one should
look what are the kind of problems I'm
having right now the and then of course
most people in spiritual work are aware
you know have met and mingled with
others
if you're having trouble forgiving your
mother-in-law then what you really need
is the course of miracles right you
don't really need p the sutures of poti
all spiritual work is beneficial because
of the intention behind it. Because of
the intention,
it's the intention that sets the
calibrated level.
So when you seek out a spiritual
practice teaching group
and many of us as we evolve go through a
number of groups. We've checked out
Reiki, we've checked out the Boy Scouts,
the Course of Miracles, all of them.
We've checked them all out and each one
of them has had a value,
but it's not designed to take you all
the way to enlightenment. However, you
can't get to the top floor without
walking the stairs. Right? So, you can't
get from the second floor to the fourth
floor without going through the third
floor. So, each spiritual practice and
teaching has its own intrinsic value and
beauty. intrinsic value and beauty even
though I became an atheist later on. Uh
as a child I was brought up high
episcopal and it was in the cathedral
and it was gorgeous stained glass
windows incredible architecture.
Uh in later life when I when I tour
Europe I go from cathedral to cathedral.
I go from Cologne to RES to my interest
in Europe is the cathedrals because it
is the greatest uh creative uh
work of man. It's very artistic work of
manu. It combines the incredible
architecture, incredible uh beauty,
incredible commitment and work,
incredible fresco and paintings,
carvings.
You can look at a carving that a man
spent his entire lifetime carving that
puppet. One entire lifetime. Everything
in third and fourth dimension.
Magnificent. And then of course the
incense over the couple hundred years
embeds itself in the wood. And then of
course you have the pageantry of the uh
parade of the bishop and the miter and
the incense and and I was I was the
bishop's um boat boy, you know, and he
would incense the I was going to say the
audience, the parishioners
and I was the little guy with a long cut
on. I held up the incense, you know, and
he would put it over the charcoal.
So those things were inspirational.
You might say it reinforces a love of
beauty. And one part of spiritual
practice, I think, is an increasing
sensitivity to beauty. And certainly by
the time you get to the high 500s, the
beauty is stunning. In fact, it is
incapacitating.
You can of course get incapacitated
along the way. The high 500s is one
place you can get incapacitated.
As you get up around 580 or 590, the
stunning beauty of the world makes you
cry all the time. You can turn a corner
and there is just
the beauty of it just knocks you out and
you're really not too functional in the
world. And a lot of people come out to
Sedona in that level. You know, you just
can't function in the world anymore. Or
a couple look at each other. You're in
the airport and uh this couple look at
each other and you can see the love
between them and just the this the sight
of that love just knocks you out. you're
just overwhelmed.
So that's the level of the high 500s
which is um approaching bliss
and your sensitivity to beauty. You can
see beauty in everything. And I say the
easiest place to see beauty is the
Kleenex box. And
you pull the Kleenex box half out and
you see it's like a painting by George
O'Keefe. If you really see the beauty of
the Kleenex box, you see it's incredible
beauty stands there. See, because you're
beyond form now, and what you're seeing
is the intrinsic beauty and perfection
of all of creation.
Every Kleenex box is an opportunity to
see God.
That's truth.
And uh at the very high high 500s uh I
can remember walking down alleys and I
was just struck by the beauty of it. It
was like a surrealistic no an
impressionistic painting and the garbage
can is all lumped over like that and
it's like a piece of sculpture. You see
all the world turns into a beautiful
sculpture. Everything you look at is you
can see the perfection and the intrinsic
beauty of existence. All that exists has
an intrinsic incredible beauty.
The capacity to see it then is like a
gift, a spiritual gift. As you go maybe
around 560, 570,
uh the incredible beauty of everything
knocks you out and that makes it very
hard to function in the world. It does.
And I remember in New York City looking
down this what the world would call a
disgusting filthy al alley probably full
of dead cats and rats and goodies and it
was just like an incredible French
impressionistic painting. Everything
stands there. There's a movie the Red
Shoes Ballet which was done many many
years ago. Oh, I think the Saddler Wells
ballet played in it, played the ballet.
And in there, I think there's a street
scene and the newspaper is blowing down
the street. And
as the wind blows it down this dusty
street, you see this newspaper doing a
dance all of its own. And it's just
intriguing and entrancing
called the Red Shoes Ballet. It was made
in Europe. I don't know if it's
available in the video stores. was
probably not, but uh the famous
ballerina of the Saddler Wells in those
days played the lead part in the Swan
Lake Ballet, which was incredible.
And so the the increasing attraction of
beauty, the ability to see beauty in all
that exists is part of spiritual
evolution, I think.
Um,
that's enough questions. Anybody have
any more questions? Um,
any more questions?
Uh,
>> can you talk about the Holy Spirit? You
mentioned it in your book. Is it are you
talking about what the course of
miracles talks about?
>> Uh, my understanding of it.
Um, yeah.
Classically, God is described as being
transcendent or imminent.
The experience of God within is the
pathway of enlightenment.
Religion is traditionally devoted to the
experience of God transcendent
in which case God gets displaced in
time.
The traditional religionist believes
that you leave it God set up the
universe
and like a bunch of billyard balls has
been running itself ever since. You live
a lifetime and then you go to heaven. So
in the meantime, so God started the
universe, took off and is waiting for
you in heaven. Hopefully you've led a
good life in which it will be a pleasant
encounter.
Otherwise, God help you.
The presence of God within is the
providence of the mystic. Huh? The
tradition of religion is a very
interesting paradox because
it is the presence of God within. And it
was the mystic that is the source of all
the world's religions who then claimed
that the only valid god is a
transcendent one
other than Christianity where Christ
says
that heaven is within you.
In the Muslim world that you see
Muhammad calibrates at 700 and um
that in the Muslim world the
enlightenment of the mystic is
considered a heresy.
to claim it's considered to be a claim.
Well, to the unenlightened person,
such a statement seems like a claim, but
the person to whom that's a reality, it
is it has nothing to do with the claim.
There is nothing to claim and no one
claiming it because it is ordinary
reality.
It's ordinary reality, you know,
just as a big strong man can pick up a
100 pounds like it's nothing. And that's
just normal to him. That's not an
exceptional thing. That's not an
accomplishment. That's not something
that he looks to the world for a claim
for. It's just that he's born that way
and he is that way and he can pick up
100 pounds like it's nothing.
Was a big ball basketball player. I read
that he was 350 lbs and 6'8. I thought,
"My god,
he's got a French sounding name. Chhatil
or chenille or
>> huh?"
>> Anyway, I He's 7 feet tall and he weighs
380 lbs or something. He could probably
just lift this thing up like it was
nothing. You know what I mean? My eyes
would bulge. So,
to a person whose eyes would bulge
trying to lift this up, it would seem
like an incredible accomplishment. To
him, it would be a snap. You understand?
So the reality of the mystic is only the
way it is to the mystic. It is nothing
particularly unusual or important. When
it comes on, it knocks you out. I guess
when it starts, but after as the years
go by and you learn how to live with it,
it's just ordinary. It's just ordinary.
The Holy Spirit then is the expression
of God within
as it becomes known. You might say I
look at the Holy Spirit as the
connection between the infinite
nonlinear
and the linear.
It's like
the connection between the infinite
nonlinear.
What is the connection between form and
nonform?
Within all form is nonform. Yeah,
we said that from a scientific
viewpoint,
the quantum potentiality is the space.
Ah, there we got the Holy Spirit and the
quantum potentiality.
We know the Holy Spirit hears about
this.
That's where it's at. resist. By God,
that's where it's at.
Just discovered it a few weeks ago. I
was reading something. I said, "God,
that's the quantum potentiality, man."
Where the infinite potentiality of the
manifest
context contexts the manifest and
influences it. Huh?
I always think of the Holy Spirit is in
that 110,000th of a second between two
thoughts that the Buddha talked about. I
remember when I first read that, that
was so frustrating. I was really mad. I
tried meditating and finding a tenth of
a second between two thoughts and you
can't do it.
Like trying to chase a dog chasing his
tail. The harder you try to create a
space between th two thoughts, the more
impossible it becomes.
And yet the Buddha said that's where you
glimpse eternity.
And it is a fact. It is a fact. And in
that instant, the Holy Spirit takes
advantage of that space and um it leaps
in with that knowingness. So the
presence of God as it expresses through
the perushia the Sanskrit which for the
presence of parushia is is uh what would
we say people say when you're talking
what is it that's talking because there
is no personal self that's talking the
talkingness is happening of its own
there is no talker talking there is no
this doing the that the talkingness
is complete and spontaneous happening of
its own
in in the spiritual teacher that's
classically in Sanskrit called the
parushia the knowingness within the self
with a capital S which speaks and is
able to express
is to me an aspect of what the course of
miracles calls the holy spirit
in the presence of the the let's see the
awareness of spiritual Spiritual truth
comes about spontaneously as a
knowingness. It doesn't come about as a
progression of logical thought.
Um it's a knowingness you might say as
the small self dissolves
into the larger self. This the larger
self because it know it is all things
knows all things. So a question then
in the mind uh like finesses
a response just as the kinesiologic
test does.
The knowingness is absolute and certain.
Therefore, the consciousness, the
awareness and the teaching of a mystic
is completely different than a
religionist because the religionist has
obtained the information from elsewhere
from an authority somewhere in time.
So, religion then comes from an
authoritative base in which the teacher
of religion is not speaking from that
which is within the teacher but what one
has heard. Therefore, it's vulnerable.
Therefore, it has to be defended.
Therefore, it's presented in an
authoritarian way.
The spiritual reality is absolute. The
certainty is absolute. And therefore, no
authority is necessary. Nor is it
arguable. Nor does it make any
difference whether anybody listens or
believes it or not is completely
inconsequential.
So one is in a different position than
than religion in which
uh
authority has to be cited and you need a
whole ecclesiastic structure to with
titles to warrant the authority. Um but
the authority does not come from within.
However, there are certainly excellent
teachers uh who have not experienced the
truth which they're teaching, but they
are excellent teachers of that which
they have heard about. So, long as they
say
they quote the source of the teaching,
they're they're uh authentic and they're
integrous.
If the source of what one is teaching is
a certain doctrine and one quotes that
as the doctrine then you that's
integrous because that is the source of
your your teaching and it may or may not
be integrous. I mean you may or it may
not be accurate. You don't know. You'd
have to test it with kinesiology to see
if it's actually conf to confirm whether
it's true
within the spiritual experience of the
absolute. You don't need there's no need
to test anything because it is glaringly
the reality of one's existence and of
that all around you. So
every question then answers itself.
It doesn't have to be defended. So it's
not arguable. No one has to defend any
doctrine because there is no doctrine.
Is only that which is which is
absolutely glaringly obvious.
That which is absolutely glaringly
obvious only needs acknowledgement
u of that which it is. You know what I'm
saying?
Anything else?
We got off into a serious vein here.
Those questions are just too serious.
Begin to sound like some kind of a what?
Um yeah if if we're just witnessing and
everything is happening on its own.
>> Yes.
>> What is the function of decision and
spiritual will making a decision? Is
that just the t right time theme or
the um we said that the karma is set by
spiritual intention and commitment.
Everything that happens in the universe
then is set by that which it is. And
when you affirm or make a certain
decision,
then you've like changed the
charge on your little particle
and your fate in the universe will be
different because you just changed the
particle.
When you come out of the pit of wherein
in the pit of hell
whose agony is beyond any description,
there's no verbal description of hell
that comes anywhere near it.
Although Dante was pretty close.
But in the absolute pits of hell to when
a voice comes up and says, "If there is
a god, I ask him to help me." That
changed the polarity of that particle
instantly. that particle
and the infinite mag magnetic power of
God pulled that particle right into the
space of infinite splendor and the ego
died
and uh
one/tenth of a second before that the
entity was in hell.
Uh you say how can in any of these in
the pits of hell despair and agony and
black total despair which went on
forever forever
then excess a space that is
uh indescribably magnificent
because first of all there is no temp
reality to temporality. So what seems to
be sequential
was only a perceptual it was only a
perceptual sequence didn't happen in
reality
but that was the seeming sequence
seeming sequence
so to commit then from
I am all there is there is no god to I
ask a god to help me is surrendering
one's will and as
Ramana Maharshi says there's two ways to
get to enlightenment one is to ask who
is who am I and the other is to
completely totally surrender one's ego
to God one's will to God so that was the
instant surrendering the will to God at
that instant
there was certainly no thought that the
self was
um divinity imminent. It was seemed like
a very comical joke in hell.
Very comical.
>> Can you give an example of a spiritual
intention and how to go about having
one?
>> Yes. All right. Let's say you you you if
you grew up in the Midwest in the 30s
like I did in the 20s, uh if you hit
your thumb with a hammer, my father
would say, "God damn it, like that." My
grandfather would also do that. All my
grandfathers did that. It was a male
thing. Women didn't do that. They said,
"My gracious.
My grandmother cut her thumb when she
was baking." Oh my gracious me. She say,
"Goodness to heavens." Well, my
grandparents, my grandfathers would
curse up a blue storm. Oh, damn. I had
one grandfather when he got mad. He
would build up a mad. He'd go a long
time and then he'd get mad and he'd sit
down there next to his plants. God damn
it, Mary. He'd say my grandmother's
name, god damn it, this that and then
and you would just curse a blue streak
and we just go on, you know,
and she'd say, "Frank, Frank the
children.
Frank, Frank the children, you know, and
I was about this big, you know, and my
ears like pictures I'm listening to."
The ear was turning blue. I mean, I
wouldn't want to get near my
grandfather. He was mad. I'll tell you,
he was something. Well, that impresses
the psyche of the boy who identifies
with the father figure. Later on in
life, you hit your thumb with a hammer
and you find yourself saying the thing
same thing.
Well, to use the name of God in vain is
uh is a violation of uh is that isn't
that one of the 12 something or others?
>> Oh, 12 commandments.
You're not supposed to do that anyway.
All right. So, it's like an instant
reflex. It's an expletative. You see,
you're not really
uh blaspheming in the way that blasphem
is meant. Blasphemy as blasphemy is a
conscious decision to boil that or think
that or say that. Now, this is sort of a
dumb reflex, but anyway, it brings up
guilt every time it happens. You not
have to go to confession high Episcopal
every Saturday afternoon. You got to go
confession just like Catholicism
and tell the father I've sinned. What
have you said, my boy? I've used the
name of the Lord in vain. Oh jeez. 12
Hail Marys, six rosaries.
Everybody else is playing ball. You got
to go back there and do these 12
rosaries or something. So
anyway, eventually your intention is to
stop doing that.
All right. So your intention is it's
happening really against your spiritual
will. Your spiritual will is not is not
to do that. See?
All right. So you work on it and you
work on it and sometimes it takes uh
years and years to get off that
spontaneous expletive because it is
programmed so quickly and intensely
uh when you're at an impressionable age
and it's part of your whole
ident identification with the macho
maleness and the father figures and all
that you know talking. So the whole uh
the whole uh society goes with that
identification. It's like smoking in
World War II. I mean, to not smoke, you
must be a wimper. Really weird, you
know. And it's hard to get over it
because it's an identification with the
whole generation, the whole ambiance,
the whole lifestyle of World War II, the
bonding of men to men. And,
you know, guy gets his leg shot off and
as they bring him off, you know, and put
him on the deck, he says, "Christ, they
got a cigarette."
That's literally what the guy was.
Anybody got a camel? Oh god. Leg gone
and he wants a cigarette. I don't know.
It gave him the great relief. Why?
Because he bonded with the courage of
all of men everywhere who suffered.
That's all.
Uh, you know, and I was going through
that surgery.
Uh, I've had other major surgeries which
were totally painless, but this one was
agonizing. The one in which I remember
goring that poor son of a gun in the
groin.
And uh I identified with all the men on
the battlefield in the Civil War. I
pictured all the men laying there with
their limbs torn off
and uh without any narcotics.
Uh they're going through surgery getting
their legs sawed off by the surgeon. I
said, "If they can do it, I can do it."
So we gained great strength then. And my
wife says when she went through Jabber,
she thought of all the women through all
the time that have done this and
therefore it's possible and if it's
possible, it gave her the courage to do
it. So we get that courage and that
conviction from our identifications and
that comes out of our intention that
comes out of our attention to transcend
our fear of pain and our capacity to
experience out anything even without
anesthesia.
And you come out of it with a new
knowingness that you're capable of
almost anything if you decide to do it.
Resolution.
So spiritual decision then is different.
The spiritual decision is how you set
the compass in the ship, you know, and I
was in a mind sweeper. So and I was at
the wheel cuz I was a boss mate. So 3°
to starboard. Three areas to starboard.
So you set it three degrees to
starboard. But the ship is not always
going to stay there. the prowl's going
up and down and she yaws and she heaves
and but you keep bringing her back to
three degrees off, you know, and uh so
your intention is to bring her back on
course. It doesn't mean that you've come
gone off every wave didn't put you off
course. So there's no point in excessive
spiritual guilt and attacking yourself
uh every time you use an expletative
when you hit your thumb because that's
not your intention.
So, your intention is what gets you to
where you're going. And one degree off
course makes a big difference. One
degree off course and after a couple
weeks at sea, you're going to end up at
a different continent.
Not only you going to miss the port, but
you're going to miss the whole island.
So,
see, we sit on the calibrated levels of
consciousness because they're
logarithmic. These are logarithmic
numbers. One degree, one point makes a
big difference. One little change of
spiritual intention
makes a big difference. Uh,
see, I got it right this time. Wow,
that's fantastic.
See, uh, this is a logarithm. So, the
difference between log 200 and log 202
or 203 is very considerable because
you're not talking arithmetic. You're
talking about 10 to the 200th power. two
points up would be 10 to the 2022nd
power. That's a lot of space, a lot of
difference.
So even a minor decision like I I want
to give up using the name of the Lord in
vain. Huh?
Do I think the Lord is sensitive? I'm
going to get all upset by that. No,
I consider the God invincible without
positionality, without personality.
certainly not sensitive veining or
anything else
for the good of the believer one. It's
for the it's for the good of the
spiritual aspirant
to revere divinity and therefore to use
the name of divinity in vain diminishes
one's own spiritual integrity. That's
why it's not good.
The naive person coming from ego
translates it that God's going to be
offended and mad about that. I mean, why
would
the infinite presence is like the sky?
It's like infinite space.
Would the sky take offense at a cloud? I
mean, sky is unaffected by the cloud.
You know,
the im
the infinite divinity of God is beyond
man's comprehension. And he keeps
imagining that God is some kind of a
super person
with a huge ego,
a divine ego,
sensitive,
paranoid,
insecure,
prone to rages
and partiality.
Also this god of ancient times has
favored ge geography
and real estate and favors people who
live in this real estate or not that
real estate or promises them if they do
this or that this is your real estate.
Now you can tell me what an infinite
divinity infinite context out of which
the whole universe arises would have any
special
heritism as to who gets what real
estate.
God's not in the real estate business.
He's not sensitive. He's not paranoid.
Uh does not have a depressed serotonin
level in his brain.
Even though that's a reality, there's
nothing wrong with reverence for
that which plays in our life as God
which even if it is not identical with
the reality of God as Krishna says that
the earned virtue is all the same. Even
those who are devout in their pursuit
of demigods or gods of let's say higher
astral realms but not the infinite
supreme
because of their devotion and
uh surrender to me will be equally loved
and favored. you know
the baabita is uh calibrates at 900 and
something so it's worth paying attention
to
it's one of the highest spiritual
readings available
is over 950 I think something like that
was all a question about
the Holy Spirit
>> huh
All right. So, we'll take a break and
then we'll finish up with any other
questions and we'll talk to people
individually that may have wanted to say
hello or have a question. Can
>> I ask you a question?