we'll resume. Uh we'll have questions.
I'll answer the questions that we have.
You know, we have a wonderful staff that
assists us in putting on the uh these
lectures. They spent actually days
getting ready to get everything over
here for the lecture that we needed for
today. Took three trucks. three vehicles
like a to get all the things over here.
They're necessary.
So, I want to thank them very much.
We we have a staff full-time, you know,
that works uh every day of the week
practically until all hours making
copies of tapes and correspondence and
phone calls and orders and various
things.
Um
there's another conference of interest
Hay House as this Hay House Mishka
Productions I think it's called is going
to have a conference in November at the
Double Tree Resort in Scottdale right
some weekend at which um
>> I think it's 15 16
>> well I don't know and I don't know how
they contact it but anyway um
in which there'll meet some well-known
speakers. I'll do three workshops that
weekend. Um the motivational speaker is
going to be there.
>> Wayne Dyer.
>> Oh yes, Wayne Dwire is going to be Wayne
Dyer is going to be there and other
people. Anyway, there's a it's in
Scottdale in November at the Double Tree
Resort.
I don't know how you uh arranged for it,
but I just thought I'd tell you about
it.
Um
now, what else were we doing? I think we
took care of the announcements,
acknowledgements, and uh
um I want to answer any questions people
have.
>> Thank for taking our picture.
>> And
that was a wonderful birthday party, I
don't think, in terms of birthday
parties. And uh it was out of this
world. And beautiful picture. You know,
Morgan
did that. Who did it?
>> Morgan's sitting right in the front,
didn't she? Yeah. Morgan. Anyway, she's
done some very beautiful um photography.
Uh and I want to thank her for that. And
she did some very beautiful work.
Let's see what else we needed to say. I
think we've said it, have we? Mhm.
>> All right. Now, we wanted to answer some
of the questions. See, each question is
an opening into a hole. You know, you
could do a whole lecture on each one.
That one we did answer. Okay. So, here's
what is left to go. Correct.
>> That's a bad check.
>> Yeah. Well, that's a bad check.
We've gotten a lot of mileage out of
that check. I tell you, it's worth a lot
more than it was written for. We've done
it over and over again.
Well, let's see. Some of these are sort
of constructs, but we'll do the best we
can. You said to know something, to
really know with a capital K, you you
have to actually be it be it.
Um,
if Christ lived one lifetime, how could
he experience so much? Well, that I
don't know.
Uh
our our research merely was that Christ
literally did come down from heaven
um to reveal the truth to mankind
as
most beneficially
he was capable of knowing it at the
time.
Um
I mean Christ was born
you know at a time and in a culture
that determined to what to some extent
what he said
he you know he didn't talk about karma
specifically he did mention that
somebody rather Elijah was was a
reincarnation of John the Baptist so he
did acknowledge in Thomas uh gospel
according to St. Thomas
that somebody was reincarnation of a
previously well-known
person.
From our own research though, Jesus had
never been prior
a u a human being, never had a human
embodiment, whereas the Buddha in
contrast had had many. So they serve two
different purposes, two different
messages.
You know, in general, my understanding
of lotus land Buddhism and Christianity
is that is the acknowledgment that the
negativity of mankind is so
pre
so prevalent
that the likelihood of reaching
enlightenment from this level is very
slim.
Now, I never calibrated what was the
energy level of mankind at the time of
Christ.
We know it was at 190 for centuries.
Let's see what it was. At the time of
Christ's birth,
um we have permission to ask this in
front of this audience. Resist. At the
time of that Jesus was born, the
conscious level of mankind was less than
190. Resist. was less than 180, less
than 160, less than 140, less than 120,
less than 100. My god, consciousness
level of mankind at the time of Christ's
birth was only 100. What are you going
to say to people who calibrated 100?
Huh? that would have any uh
they sort of lived, you know, past past
history is all about greed, hatred,
uh the guillotine, uh remorse, guilt,
despair.
Uh we have whole continents right now.
If we calibrate central Africa,
what's um
>> Africa? We have permission to do Africa
resist. Africa is over
120 resist.
Africa is over 110.
Africa right now the pre prevailing
consciousness level of Africa is about
100 110.
The life expectancy if you're born in
Bafra or some place like that you your
life expectancy is probably 28 or
something. You know what I mean? Infant
mortality is extremely high. Everybody's
got AIDS. Everybody's starving to death.
Malnutrition is rampant.
Somebody from one of those countries was
on TV the other night. He and his wife,
they're in their early 30s and they've
got nine children. So, he's staying
there pleading for his poverty.
Well, he's, you know, wetted himself
right into poverty. He's got nine kids
already and they're only their 30s. You
know, give him another 10 years. Talk
about poverty. He's going to be below
the poverty level. Uh
so the responsibility there isn't the
conscious awareness.
You haven't come up to integrity where
you take responsibility for your actions
and their consequences. You see if I got
nine kids and I can't afford them.
I've got to be up to 200 to get that I
really got to stop making more kids. You
know now that seems to us, you know, a
given. Most people apparently don't
believe that. So all right, what did we
say the level of consciousness was of
mankind when Christ was born? 100
approximately 100.
All right. So he was born into
uh tribal culture
which held to
the belief in u sort of a malevolent
kind of gods. The gods of the Old
Testament are prone to malevolence,
anger, revenge, favoritism.
In the midst of all that, he's supposed
to bring the message of heaven, the
reality of God, and the reachability of
heaven.
And what kind of behaviors will lead you
in this direction? And what kind of
behaviors will lead you in that
direction
that there is the destiny of heaven or
hell following physic physical
existence.
So that was sort of a very basic message
he gave very basic message and at the
time even then it was very very
revolutionary.
He didn't speak of karma. Um I doubt
very much it would have had any meaning
at all to people in a culture like that.
The Buddha was born in a culture on the
border of Nepal
you know where the Aryan culture was
already quite ancient and the experience
of the presence of God as the self
to be enlightened had already
been a prior experience in that culture.
So in the culture in which the Buddha
was born, the concept of karma was not
novel or revolutionary. He was born into
a form. So India has a far more ancient
uh uh spiritual culture
than the western world and certainly the
Islamic world.
Um,
other than that, I don't know. You'd
have to ask him
to experience the totality of the
consciousness of mankind
is what went on with Jesus Christ.
to to comprehend its downside to could
to
uh sweat blood. It just uh looking at it
um meant that he owned it as a as a
totality the totality of the energy
field of what it is to be human without
necessarily experiencing
it serially, you know. And karma would
be the reincarnation sort of
reexperiencing the to what it means to
be human sort of serially. What is it
like to be a slaver? What's it like to
be a slave? What's it like to be each
thing individually?
Is am I a vegetarian?
Um and can you eat meat and achieve
self-realization etc.
Uh the question of vegetarianism which I
haven't run into in a while uh comes up
periodically
the same with celibacy the same with
work uh anything having to do with
ordinary world person becomes
spiritually aware or interested they're
going they first of all they're going to
start off at different levels somebody
may start off at 100 some people may
start off at 300 some people may start
off at 400 so the questions each one is
like a cohen like a zen cohen
Um what is the meaning?
Well, if you see physicality as life, uh
and that if life is limited to
physicality, then then being a
vegetarian would certainly make sense.
One doesn't want to kill anything
uh in order to survive. If
so, at a certain level where you think
the animal's dying and sacrificing
itself to you, it would be wrong. Later
on, you see the animal doesn't die
anyway. And in fact, if you didn't eat
it, it wouldn't even exist. And it
doesn't even hardly notice going out of
body.
Let's say you're going to eat a steak,
right? You say, "Poor cow. Poor cow's
going to die because they eat the steak.
You know, there wouldn't be any cattle
out there. If nobody ate steak, there
wouldn't be any cattle. So, hundreds of
millions of cattle would never know what
it is to exist. It's only because you
eat steak that they get to be here. You
understand what I'm saying?
Nobody eats meat and I wouldn't be here,
would I?
It's the cow.
You're going to pay for that when we get
home.
>> I was thinking the cow over in the
invisible domain, you know.
Well, that's the cow.
Uh we have permission to ask about the
cattle. Resist. The cow um notices it
when he leaves the physical and goes
into the other domain. Resist. He
doesn't notice it.
If you swat a fly, the fly just goes
right on flying. He's in his astral body
and he doesn't etheric body. He doesn't
notice that he went physical. He comes
back.
The only uh the witness would notice the
difference. But the fly doesn't notice
the difference.
When you go out of body at death,
all you notice is that the physicality
is laying there. But there's no
discontinuity in in in in the sense of
self. There's no discontinuity.
There's no discontinuity in the sense of
self at death. Resist. That's correct.
The cattle So the cow doesn't even know
that it just got eliminated from the
physicality. That is a fact. It's a
fact. C doesn't know it. goes right on
going along in his etheric body and has
no interest in the whole deal.
If you asked the more evolved cow
I was in a high state one time, probably
the high 500s somewhere a few.
Um,
this is a statement of fact.
it is my joy to give up my physicality
for thee, oh Lord.
That's a fact.
Out of choice,
I do sacrifice my physicality
for that which is higher than myself.
And in so doing I join that which is
divinity and share in that awareness. So
the by surrendering its physicality to a
higher being it supports the evolution
of consciousness and karmically earns
the right
to that awareness itself.
Let's see. We call that
um within the animal kingdom
uh that exists as animal grace.
Grace
that's the grace of the animal. You know
what's meant by animal grace?
>> Huh?
>> Animal grace is apparent. You look at a
you look at a a deer and it stands there
in its incredible grace, beauty and
magnificence
because it is completely its own
potentiality.
It feels no tension between what it is
and what it thinks it could be. It
already is completely its potentiality.
So it has infinite serenity.
You know my cat that sits there is in a
Buddha state.
It's still it's completely what it is
with no anxiety or strain.
It's called animal grace. Mhm.
That is correct. Is it? Yeah. All right.
So, the grace of the animal is that it
is the completion of its
karmic potentiality.
It is
it is itself
the perfection of the fulfillment of the
potentiality of its essence.
And that's why it has the Buddha nature.
Let's say we never have a lot of these
things in public.
The animal
is at one with Buddha nature resist.
So you don't have to worry about the
animal.
All right? So if you think you're at the
point where you think that
you're killing life, it would be wrong
to eat meat. When you see that that's
all illusion, that no life is
sacrificed. It's not possible to kill
life. Life only shifts form shifts
dimension.
Um then it doesn't make any difference
anymore because you're doing a cow cow a
favor by eating the cow. That cow will
not come into existence. You understand
that? Nobody will raise cattle if nobody
eats them.
>> Huh?
>> What about killing a human?
>> Killing a human is a more sophisticated
question.
killing a human. You see the um the
calibration of a thing depends on its um
intention
intentionality.
The belief that you're killing another
human being and willfully defy God and
do so then has a great karmic
consequence.
If you're already enlightened, you see
that no such a thing is possible.
First of all, you wouldn't do it because
of your sense of spiritual reality.
So the question arises, is it
possible on the level of the highest
reality
to kill another human being? What could
you kill? You could kill
um this embodiment.
Let's go. We better change our chairs
around.
>> Okay.
>> If they're going to be asking questions,
you come. You come over here. If you
come over here and I I'll sit there.
>> Where?
>> You come over here. Yeah.
>> Um, where was the question?
Oh, okay. It's possible to We have the
permission to ask this question. Resist.
It's possible to actually kill another
human being in reality. Resist.
It's possible to kill their physicality.
Resist.
It's possible.
Let's see what do I think is the
reality. The reality is that um you're
valitionally forcing the person out of
physicality. That's what's happening.
Resist. Okay. You're it's not possible
to kill the the human being as a
discrete entity. Resist. It's not
possible. Okay. It's not possible. You
can force the person out of a
physicality.
Let's say the person's riding along in
the horse and you shoot him and now in
his he suddenly the horse goes riding
off with his physical body which topples
off and the entity witnesses all this.
Well, what right did he have to knock me
out of the physical body? I mean, I was
still in the game, you know. So, you get
knocked off the game board is what I see
happening.
I mean my understanding is you get
knocked off the chessboard the game
board of this time in this place in our
physicality
but nothing else happens and it was
probably a karmic debt you paid off in
doing that you know
>> the karma
>> karma comes into that
>> that's what I'm saying yeah the whole
karmic uh drama of it
>> why doesn't that same karma apply to
come to that
>> what does that say
>> why does Doesn't the same karma apply to
killing an animal?
>> Well, you're talking about different
dimensions.
Um,
the belief that one is killing an animal
when one kills it is why at a certain
level of consciousness people are
vegetarians.
I was a vegetarian for 10 or 15 years.
But one day in a restaurant, I suddenly
realized what the truth of it all was.
And I thought, "This is ridiculous. Here
I'm worrying about eating meat, and I am
meat.
My physicality is meat.
Why should I be concerned about it?" So
then you shift to a different spiritual
dimension in which no such thing is
happening anyway. So there's nothing to
worry about.
Yeah.
You don't have to worry about meat
because you are meat.
Any lion will tell you that
you're delicious.
Delicious, delicious, delicious.
the the understanding then comes out of
the level of consciousness out of which
the question arises not the answer.
Um and therefore multiple answers are
possible to the same question. It's
because of the intentionality of the
question the consciousness level at
which it is arising the context of it.
So there isn't like an absolute question
with an absolute answer.
The question and the answer constantly
change depending on how you look at it,
how you contextualize it, who's asking
the question at what time, in what
space, and in what context. Do you
understand what I'm saying? At one
level, it would be, let's say, wrong to
eat meat. At another, it would be wrong
to not eat meat. At another level, it's
totally irrelevant.
It doesn't arise as a question in one's
mind.
H let's see I can't read all these h
oh yes
of what what importance to give the body
in spiritual work
well the body you would you would have
the same reverence for the body as you
would any other valuable possession any
other living thing. I try to treat my
body as well as I do my kitty.
Not always as well as the kitty, but
generally as well as the kitty.
Uh because it's like a pet and um you
take you take good care of it. I mean, I
I take care of it because
if I don't, I get told to. If if you
haven't eaten all day, somebody says,
"You haven't eaten a thing all day." I
say, "Oh, all right."
uh
all all these questions are uh are
significant only at certain levels. You
see to the degree to which you think
your reality is your physicality
would then determine how important that
physicality is. Washing it and putting
it through purifications and various
interesting things. Colonic irrigation
as I said the colon is not always the
fastest way to God but you want
You go through periods of purification.
People go into purification fits for
years. You know, they're purifying their
body of moles and fungi and what is all
the crap that they don't eat mushrooms
and
>> right
>> what what is it? Cox
>> what is it?
>> Candida.
>> Candida. They get candida
there. They imagine that there's toxins
in the blood, blood poisons. You got to
go for a blood cleanser. a blood
cleanser. What it
>> metal poisoning?
>> Metal poisoning. There's all kinds of
myasmas. Night air. It used to be the
night air. Uh
used to catch tuberculosis from living
in poverty neighborhoods. You know what
I mean? There's all kinds of these
illusions.
How much reality to give them is really
answered by the course of miracles.
They have as much importance as you give
them. The power of belief is what gives
them any validity whatsoever.
About lesson 76 or so, it says, "I'm
only subject to what I hold in mind."
Right? They're only subject to what I
hold in mind. So, if you think these mo
if you think moles will kill you, then
you better avoid moles because they'll
kill you. And
so, we go we go through a period though
and I think it's sort of normal. People
go through a period of physical concern.
All kinds of cleansings, washings,
purifications, and things. And then of
course you realize you're not your
physical body. And that's all sort of
irrelevant. It's sort of like washing
your car.
And washing your car won't necessarily
get you to heaven. But if you think that
washing your car will get you to heaven,
then the belief that it will get you to
heaven will actually get you to heaven.
Wash the more often you wash the car,
the higher you're going to get
spiritually.
At a certain point, I think it's
everybody's concern that the idea that
the blood is full of toxins and poisons
and you have to take blood cleansers and
blood gastrointestinal purification.
People eat all kinds of weird things,
soap and and powdered pummus and weird
crap with chlorophyll in it, you know,
to clean out their intestinal tract. If
you succeed in clearing out your
intestinal tract, folks, I'm going to
tell you, you're going to die
because it's only because of the
bacteria that live there, the the little
creatures that live there and digest the
food and all that enables you to live.
So, I wouldn't go cleansing out your
colon too much without killing yourself
and cleansing out your blood and various
things like that. You know, I would try
and lead sort of a normal life. Undo
attention. Undo attention to the
physicality.
Uh, I don't pay much attention to the
thing. You know, you do what you need to
do with it. And um, I say it's sort of a
toy. It's a pit. It's certainly
enjoyable. I mean, if I didn't have a
body, I couldn't play with the kitty,
could I? I mean,
I couldn't cut the cake this morning.
So, I mean, you know, it's good for good
for certain things, you know, but I
wouldn't overemphasize the body. you
know certain meditative practices
there's a great deal of attention to the
body posture
all kinds of fancy breathing exercises
visualizations
um sitting on certain things and not on
other things you know I don't think
sitting on tiger skins is really cool
anymore
you tell people well this isn't a real
tiger skin this is a makebelieve tiger
skin okay
um and wearing lots of clothes you know
In India, picture people's picture of a
guru is long hair and um naked except
for a loin cloth sitting cross-legged on
a tiger skin, right?
I guess you're arrested in Sedona.
No, it's okay to get a haircut. It's
okay to take a shower. Uh it's okay to
sit on a bath towel. It doesn't have to
be a tire skin. And all these things
that are traditional you see those are
those are not spiritual those are ethnic
and a lot of spirituality is confused
with the e ethnic background out of
which it arose you know the country of
its origin
uh the national identificate identities
of that country etc. Um, spirituality is
more the realization we talked about
this morning. That one is
the context
in which content
arises.
There's more a more advanced stage. Yet
there is the negation
of content as self.
The realization of context is self.
Then
the even more advanced realization that
one is both context and content
but not limited thereby by that in
content is the essence of context.
The formless is innate within form and
that one is not just beyond form and
just the formless.
Nor is one just the form which one
thought be before one became
enlightened. But is one is both form and
formless. And therefore
one no longer
um it separates form and formless.
Um one is not only context
but also content but one is the
is the formless within form. That which
one is is the formless within form.
without which form could not exist and
yet one is not limited by that form.
One both is and is not at the same time
because those are only categories of
thought with no intrinsic reality, no
self
selfs substanti reality.
Those are only points of observation.
Yeah.
Is it appropriate
or integrous
to use kinesiology to help the
government? Here's a good question.
Yeah, the FBI and the CIA, right? That
comes up every once in a while. Well, we
did a, you know, video tape, I think,
called volume one, power versus force.
And I think at that time we calibrated.
We did do that. We checked out the FBI
and the CIA and the
uh
>> ATF.
ATF.
Yeah. And um then the the news later on
revealed what we'd already discovered in
kinesiology.
I don't know whether we're allowed to do
that anymore or not. I don't know
whether this is something we can do or
not do. We'll have to ask. Um these are
questions we we we have permission to
ask in this front of this audience.
Resist. Oh okay.
So you don't always get permission. Um
in other words the technique would have
to be used integrously
and um and even if you let's say wrote
Washington say you know we use
kinesiology and we found that there was
a
terrorist working in the Minneapolis
office. They'd say yeah right.
I doubt very much it would meet with
much credibility. Why is that? Because
it comes out of the nonlinear
uh nonlinear reality and government
agencies like science live within linear
reality. So it would sound sort of
hoo-ha to them sort of peculiar, weird,
far out, strange.
Um
we just use it for our own information
for our own information. And whenever we
ask, you know, can we use it for the
public good or something? So far, we've
always gotten no. I don't know why. It
could be that the gift is a gift
primarily for spiritual for spiritual
growth. Okay.
Um the kinesiologic method of uh which
we're using is a gift primarily for
spiritual uh intention.
It's a gift for a greater than just
spiritual intention resistance.
Uh
we always got to know about um
demonstrating it for
government reasons. Resist. That's true.
We always got to know. I don't know why.
Um
we don't need to know why. Resist. You
don't need to know. Oh, that's a break.
I'm always relieved when I get that, you
know, the door is shut. It says, "Don't
ask about that. Thank you." Uh, now
you're dismissed from any
responsibility. I mean, what if you're
at home and you find out there's a guy
named Joe and he's working the
Minneapolis office and he's really
working for the so- and so. What's your
life going to become like?
Probably not too good, huh?
You'd be worrying about, shouldn't I
reveal this? Shouldn't I run to
Washington? Shouldn't I knock on doors?
I mean maybe it would not be so peaceful
or good for anything or anyone.
Uh as we said if the if if the world as
we see it is the unfoldment of a karmic
coherence.
If there's a karmic coherence unfolding
itself then one could be interfering
with the karmic destiny of other people,
agencies, entities, countries,
civilizations, cultures. You know what
I'm saying?
you don't necessarily have the karmic
entitlement
to
to um
put a wrench in the monkey works.
There's a nice way of putting it.
So, that's a relief, folks, isn't it? We
don't have to
save the world.
Um,
I'd like to know any more of the
questions you
uh have because I want to make sure we
complete them all and then I want to
meet with any people that want to meet
with me.
The idea of treating the body as a
temple is a construction
because everything is a temple if you
see it as such
because all everything is divinity
coming into existence fulfilling its
potentiality
in the discernable world of form.
Everything is a temple.
The kitty's kittiness and body is the
temple of the kitty, right? Is it not?
It's God in God's intention of kittiness
manifesting as kitty. The kitty's body
is the kitty's temple. Resist. Yep. So
because you see
you see
you see the divinity of all that exists.
All that exists only does so by virtue
of
the creator.
That which comes into existence comes
into existence
as a result of the creation as a
creation by God. So all that exists is
divine by virtue of the source of its
existence. Nothing comes into existence
except as a creation of God.
Consequently, all that exists is divine
innately.
The fact that it can be perceived
differently doesn't change its innate
reality.
A dagger is a dagger. It is neither good
nor bad.
How one constructs it and perceives of
the dagger then makes the dagger appear
to be what it is to to your
intentionality on your previous
programming.
However, in and of itself, the dagger is
just the perfect expression of
daggerness. Being a dagger,
it has the capacity to come in to
existence.
All that exists exists because of the
divinity of its creator.
Um,
I can't always read all these questions.
Um
yeah okay there there's there's a
question about dealing with uh the
esoteric
my recommend
I I recommend generally to avoid the
exotic the esoteric the occult
um
you know in the Bible it says um to
avoid the supernatural doesn't deny it
doesn't deny that supernatural exists or
that there is a supernatural
that Ouija boards that don't work. That
psychics aren't frequently correct.
What it says, it doesn't say that it's
not that that it has no reality. It just
says don't go there. Why don't go there?
Because first of all, it's an invisible
realm. You have no idea who or what
you're dealing with, what you're talking
to. You're dealing with astral realms
that are full of
things that are beyond your
comprehension.
If you calibrate the
energy field of various astral
enterprises, uh entities on the other
side, supposed masters, teachers, and
all these things,
if you calibrate the energy level,
you'll find they're usually lower
astral. Lower astral
Some of them become quite famous over
time, legendary almost.
But when you calibrate the energy level
of that entity,
it becomes apparent
that your enlightenment is not what it's
interested in.
you know, invest in thoroughbred horses
is not exactly whatever.
Uh,
so first of all, you're not equipped to
deal with it. You're not equipped to
deal with it. Secondly, it's invisible.
Uh, unless you calibrate it, you have no
idea of the level of integrity.
My own experience or understanding of it
is or experience with it has been the
lower astral is filled with those
energies which have denied God and hate
God.
Refused God. Refuse God.
The way you get to lower astral is you
refuse or you hate God. And one reason
you do this is you're envious of God
because
you think that the core of your own ego
is God.
The refusal to give up the
imaginary
divinity of the ego and surrender it to
God is the refusal that gets you to the
lower astral.
The lower astral is made up of those who
refuse God and hate God,
but who are aware that having done so,
they have now denied themsel access.
The human
by virtue of the nature of being the
human has the potentiality to evolve to
heaven and to the presence and the
awareness of God
and therefore is hated for that.
The best way to the human from
doing that is to
ensnare him.
So that the most worthy
prey of the lower astero
is the evolving spiritual student.
The spiritual student who is on their
way
seriously committed and starts going
into botific spaces.
Tracks them right out of the lower
astral like bang
like gravity. They come right out like
jackals waiting for the prey.
What makes you vulnerable to them is
your innocence.
the spiritual
naivity of um I am I trying to think of
a word
spiritual maturity comes at considerable
cost.
A true teacher tries to
by advisement
give you the information you need to
bypass those snares. If you get caught
in the snare, the evolution of
consciousness will proceed, but it can
be exquisitly awful and painful and
agonizing for great lengths of time. All
right. So the evolving spiritual
aspirant
the naivity is the downside
in which they are attacked and get
hooked.
All kinds of ext of very outlandish
schemes are presented.
The way to get to heaven is to kill
Americans and blow them up. You know
people buy that. They buy that out of
spiritual naivity.
Naivity.
They actually believe it. Let's see if
they actually believe it. You think
they're just brainwashed?
They actually believe that by killing
Americans, you get to heaven and you
serve Allah. They actually believe that.
Resist.
There you go.
If I can convince you that going out and
killing innocent people and children
is serving God, then you'll do it.
Hitler did it with a whole nation of
people. Got them all to march through
their death.
World War II, we saw
whole generations, whole nations
marching off to death. And those weren't
even spiritual gurus. Those were just
political ones.
So you see how vulnerable the human
psyche is.
Basically the human psyche is innocent.
It's like the hardware and you can
program it with any software.
Start early enough. You can program any
consciousness to believe anything.
Even when confronted by its opposite, it
will sit there and refuse it.
I see in this week's Time magazine, the
Japanese
spiritual leader who released the Sarin
gas in the Japanese subway.
The very interesting followup article
having gassed all these innocent people
for no reason whatsoever, not even a
spiritual justification, not even
rationalization, he has no lack of
followers.
How do you explain that? did an
interview with a woman there who joined
that Japanese pseudo spiritual cult
after he did that.
When asked why, she said because she's
afraid of death.
Weird, huh?
All right.
So even somebody demonstrabably demonic,
even a 5-year-old would know that this
is a demonic entity, still has no lack
of followers.
So the downside of human naivity then
makes us all vulnerable. If it wasn't
for the fact we were all vulnerable, we
all would have become Buddhas thousands
of years ago.
It's because we didn't know any better
out of ignorance and innocence that one
is prey to those who are more
advanced in deception.
Don't fool yourself that you are smarter
than the deceptive capacity of lower
astrals. You're not.
The first salv thing that will save you
is humility. You are not smarter.
These entities have been added for
millennia.
They can sense the slightest weakness in
your psyche and know just how to pull
that out. And they'll have you licking
their boots thinking you're serving God.
All right? I don't want to build them up
to greater be greater than what they
are, but they are extremely clever.
Extremely clever. All right? So the only
thing that will guard you against it is
spiritual education and fistication. One
of the reasons that I have been ch a
champion of the kinesiologic method is
because man can't tell truth from
falsehood
unless you're intuitively quite advanced
spiritually. You just don't get that
that's out. You don't get that that's
out. Sedon is full of people naively led
by the nose through all kinds of astral
circus stunts
by all kinds of incredulous unbelievable
entities on the other side
sacrificing wife children families
can't have sex with each other but you
can have with me I mean the delusional
craziness that goes on you say nobody
believe that oh yes they do they believe
it they believe it
in this lifetime Um,
we we've seen gurus go up and go down.
We've seen them uh collect millions of
dollars worth of vehicles, cars,
millions of dollars of money and then
tell the public that they're higher than
Jesus and crash. Higher than Jesus. Come
on.
You'd have to calibrate a thousand to be
higher than Jesus.
No. So, we've seen them crash and burn
one after another.
Because we're innocent, we believe in
purity and goodness and all these kind
of things. We're not on our guard about
such things.
One time I was in New York City in the
Three Guys restaurant and I met a
well-known guru.
Um
at that time time I was enthused about a
certain technique and I said um I'd like
I think we should share this with the
world. Share this with the world. See I
believe in discovering the thing and
then sharing it with the world. I mean
that's what the purpose of discovering
it then to share it with the world. At
this point he became livid livid.
Give it away for free.
I thought
monasteries and the priesthood,
everybody's struggling with sin. And
here's a way of letting go of sin as an
attachment. Sin nothing but an
attachment.
We'll take it to the monasteries. We'll
take it to the priests. We'll take it to
the public.
At that point,
the strangest thing happened. All of a
sudden, another voice came through him.
I'd known this guy for years. Another
voice came through him and spoke in a
totally different energy field. And it
was like the door of hell opened up. A
horrible energy accompanied this and it
said,
"Anything worth anything is worth if you
give it away, you you you say that it's
valueless." This and that. Then the
voice went on to tell me how Jesus and
the Buddha were just astrals and how
Henry Ford had done more for mankind
than on the Jesus Christ and Buddha and
all the other and Krishna and all of
them together went on and on and on like
that.
So it's almost like you reach a certain
level of spiritual awareness you trigger
it's
uh you might say it's opposite you know
you want to give it away for free
instantly it wants you to sell it you
know I'm saying strange you know
totally unexpected out of the blue
we all know that spiritual wisdom says
leave Ouija boards alone
is that universal or on agreement.
You've all heard that. Have anybody told
you that playing with Ouija boards is
good for your spiritual awareness?
No. Universally, it's condemned.
Everybody says stay away from Ouija
boards. It doesn't say they don't work.
It says stay away from them.
It's because the astral looks to
dominate you. Pretty soon, you're
beginning to want to serve the astral on
the other side. And the astronity loves
to gain power over a human and delay his
progression to God. He says you're on
your way as a human being. Your destiny
is ultimately
salvation and heaven etc.
The entity who has cut themsself off
from that potentiality
gains credit in its own domain by
holding you back.
You understand what I'm saying? The more
converts it can take out of the
spiritual legitimate spiritual
dimension, the greater becomes its
power. Greater becomes its power. So the
ruler rulers of great astral domains are
extremely clever.
Never try to pit your wits against them.
They've been at it for millennia,
millennia. They're experts at
manipulating,
dissimulating,
um, sounding pious, all kinds of fancy
names,
mystery entities from ancient
Greek mysteries, the ancient something
in the ancient mystery is always another
way of. So these are called
glamorizations.
Falsity by glamorization.
I am master so and so from ancient
Greece. Yeah, right. We know that the
universe
it consists of the various astral
domains, the inner so-called
interplanes. We know where you go from
heaven to the higher astral to the lower
middle astral lower astral. So we know
that there's heavens and hells and we
know that there's purgatories because
certainly life the life experience of
the average human being here is
purgatorial.
You can go from the pits of severe pain
to uh the highest ecstasy. You can pick
the luciferic and the satanic and the
demonic or you can pick uh
enlightenment. So this an earthly res
existence is almost purgatorial in that
you have a choice
of all dimensions from here you can go
anywhere.
Um
and the temptations then arise uh from
all these various dimensions
and by choice then your own buoyancy in
the sea of choices. The karmic
potentiality of evolution of
consciousness is decided from moment to
moment. Every single decision changes
the infinite potentiality.
What purpose does it serve? I don't see
that it serves any purpose.
I can live without it myself.
Like a broken ankle. I mean, I get along
so well without it.
I think uh a teacher should share what
he he's learned about the downside
because I hear that sucking sound as
people go down.
And people that were once great teachers
and you calibrate their early books and
now you calibrate what their
consciousness level is now or before it
was before they died and you saw that
they crashed and burned.
It would be like spiritual evolution is
the enemy of that which is grossly
negative
and it seeks to pull you down.
It seeks to pull you down.
It hates that which it sees as more
powerful and more evolved than itself.
That's about all I can figure out of it.
Does it serve any purpose? Not any that
I can see.
The seduction, the seduction of the
glamorous, the spiritually, the pseudo
spiritually glamorous is seductive.
the trappings,
the gizmos that go with it.
That's one reason, one of the main
reasons, in fact, the main reason that I
I I wrote about the levels of
consciousness, kinesiologic technique.
I'm going to think about a famous entity
around Sedona right now. He's well
known.
I have permission, if I don't mention
his name, to calibrate his energy
resistance. His energy is over 200
resist.
The entity,
his master on the other side is over
200. Resist.
Yeah. This is a guy with all kinds of
followers, all kinds of crap. He talks
to Master Baba on the other side and
full of crap, man. Tell pure 100% BS.
100% BS. The naive are sucked in by the
oo au. You know, the first time you get
a psychic reading, it's a knockout,
isn't it? or somebody reads the cards,
you say, "Wow." Somebody reads the tarot
cards. I see your grandmother has a very
advanced case of something. Wow, your
grandmother does. You go, "Wow, Zel." I
mean, it's a biogler, right? To the
naive, it's a boggler.
Doesn't mean the aster doesn't exist. It
just means its effect on your life is
going to be dilitarious because pretty
soon the entity on the other side will
have control over you. You're going to
want its approval. told you're going to
follow its advice.
You're going to be investing your money
in raceh horses.
We're going to have to call it to an
end. Uh you get me going on a subject
that um I have a considerable interest
in because you know in Sedona this is
rampant.
The facious
um the facious masquerades as the real
a spiritual student. one of his
responsibilities so he doesn't go down
the tubes
because you're you're juicy pluckings. A
group like this is juicy pluckings. It's
just what the lower astros are waiting
for. Master hoo-ha is waiting for you.
Card tricks, magic stones, magic gems,
magic
all kinds of magic stones, rituals,
the glamour of it all. And you see, you
come out of a a a world of reason and
logic and you come into the supernatural
world, everybody's knocked out about it.
You know, the first time you get a
psychic reading, it boggles everybody's
minds first time you get the tarot cards
read. How did she know my uncle had
cancer? You know what I'm saying? How'd
she know that?
Well, because there's more than one
dimension, folks. And yet, if you hold
it in mind, it's held in mind in other
invisible domains as well. So what you
think is secret and unknowable except to
yourself, you know, is out there.
Anybody can read it.
And with a little training, you yourself
can read other people's psyches and
there's nothing to it.
So the the serious spiritual student has
to abide by
the cautions of the great teachers. All
the great teachers have said it isn't
that it doesn't exist and that it has no
reality. They say don't go there. You're
not equipped to go there. You're not
trained to deal with
lower astrals. They can dissimulate in
in ways that is so convincing that
unless you're quite ariodite.
I was in a very advanced state.
I mean a very advanced state at one time
beyond all form
in a state of infinite power.
Um,
how would we describe the state? It was
a great beyond a state beyond all form,
beyond all wantingness, beyond all
individuality.
It was at one with the infinite power of
the universe.
And a knowingness came on, not an
entity. I've never seen any entities.
A knowingness came on. The knowingness
spoke bestly.
Now that you realize you're beyond
individual karma
and that there is no god to which you
are answerable
in as much as you have no karma to begin
with and no such god as religion
believes in even exists anyway
you're beyond all karma. You're
answerable to nothing. All power is
yours.
Own it. That's what the knowingness came
to me as
answerable to nothing. You've got no
karma to answer for
and no arbitrary god up there who's
going to punish you. Even if you did
have karma to answer for. You don't
believe in the God of the Old Testament.
You're beyond form.
You're beyond individual personal karma.
That was true. At that point I was
totally beyond all personal karma,
answerable to nothing and to no one.
The power
was really based on relinquishing love
as any kind of reality and seeing love
as
a limitation.
If you let go of any kind, if you let go
of love itself, then all power is yours.
All power in the universe is yours.
That's a fact. Same same temptation that
Jesus Christ was presented with. Not
many people been through that pass. It
was like a very high pass. I saw who had
been through there and I saw the answer
they had given.
And the defect was to try to own the
power of God
and without owning the love of God.
God is infinite power also infinite
love. So the luciferic energy
tries to
seal the power of God but escape the
love of God because that would be a
limitation.
You can't kill off millions of people if
you're still capable of love. You have
to eliminate lovingness and now you can
kill them and have infinite domain over
them.
Anyway, at that space,
the knowingness
of this consciousness was already
sufficiently advanced to negate that
temptation and say no to it. Can never
be used for personal gain.
I saw Jesus Christ had been there and
said no to it. I saw some other gurus
throughout history who had said yes to
it and I saw why they say yes. It's
because they had not had the karmic
um gain of having been
educated by their own teacher in advance
to know better.
So I feel it's my responsibility to
share such things
that such a thing will not befall you.
Why? Because these things come
unannounced, unexpected. You're just
sitting there meditating or releasing on
something, uh, chanting, uh, maybe doing
the Jesus prayer, walking through the
woods, and all of a sudden it comes to
you. You got no time to think it over.
How am I going to answer this? How I'm
going to handle it? Unless you've heard
about it before, and bring it right up.
It'll come up. It'll come up. Having
heard it, having heard it, it comes up
at the time. Having heard it, you've
heard it now. When that comes to you,
the knowingness arises out of beyond
thinkingness.
Having heard it, one is now protected.
One is now protected. So those that have
fallen,
I feel a compassion for. They were
somehow unprotected.
Their teachers did not share with them.
Maybe their teachers didn't know.
And so they fell they fell over the
abyss. The way back from over the abyss
is hellish and can be awful and take
long, long periods of time, longer than
anybody in this audience can know what I
mean by long long eons of time to come
back from the serious fall of grace.
Uh so um I say this out of respect for
the evolution of the consciousness of
everybody in this room because everybody
in this room has reached the point of
plump desiraability
by that which grows fatter and stronger
on your plump little innocent spirit.
And so I don't want any of my chickens
eaten by them.
Why it's inappropriate to reveal a name
to someone like that who would be such a
negative influence all
>> I don't get what he's saying
>> the the person that we were calibrating
you wouldn't say the name of
>> um because it's sort of everyone's
karmic responsibility to discover these
things themselves see and if we had a
different relationship don't for this is
a public meeting let's say if we work
together as a small group of people in
which we shared confidences and
discoveries such as I do with Susan
let's say uh it's a different thing it
could be that there's a different
consequence of speaking publicly for one
thing it could be
um shocking to somebody so a lot of
times people will ask me what is such
and such a guru book calibrate I want
them to find out for themsel because
there's there could be like a shock
shock
could be like a shock.
I went through a shock like that one
time. It was horrible.
I discovered the guru that I've been
following the heart chakra was zero. He
had zero energy in the heart chakra.
Suddenly everything that he'd said took
on a whole different context.
So all right. Um
we are preparing a book where we're
going to do a thousand calibrations and
again it's iffy. We have to ask
constantly ask should we share this? Can
we share this? Is this sharable? Is this
beneficial to the world? Is it
beneficial to society?
Could such a thing have uh you know like
an unexpected negative um
uh result?
Uh, so you can't be like um the bull in
the in the china shop. You know what I'm
saying? We could use the method in like
a bull in the china shop. You know, go
right through society like the grim
reaper. You know what I mean? And but
that's not the purpose. We get that the
purpose is merely educational.
Each of us needs to take responsibility
for the evolution of our own
consciousness. And in so doing, we earn
a certain karmic merit. All I want
people to do is to be aware. Don't be
naively foolish. Fall for anything. Be
aware that there is a downside. Uh a
certain amount of fallacy out there that
masquerades as the legitimate. Jesus
Christ said the same thing. He said,
"Beware the wolf in sheep's clothing."
Right?
He didn't know kinesiology.
He didn't tell you how said the
Frenchman. Yes, he did. By their fruits
ye shall know them. Okay. So, all we've
had to go as far as discernment,
spiritual discernment over the ages has
been by their fruits we shall know them.
We could say killing 3,000 innocent
people would indicate
that this is probably not of the most
pure and delicate. you know,
uh, by their fruits we shall know them.
All right? So, that's all we've had to
go by. And by karmic merit, apparently
in the late 1980s,
we were like given a way of telling the
wolf from the sheep. We never had one
before. And of course, the desire to
write the book Power Versus Force came
from the excitement of discovering my
god, we got a way of telling the wolf in
the sheep's clothing from the sheep from
the wolf for the first time.
And as I said, I spent some years
agonizing over uh how to share it and
whether I should share it and in what
style and how to best present it and to
give it the most um
possible respect. I went through all the
work of getting a PhD and putting it
through uh routine scientific
presentation as quantitative and
qualitative analysis and calibration of
levels of human consciousness
to a university faculty. So that and I
had all the statistics done by a
statistical firm that ran it through all
their computers etc. So I made sure
first that it was solid on a scientific
rational logical basis because from that
we were then then moved through the
levels of consciousness from the linear
Newtonian domain to the nonlinear
spiritual domain the reality of which
was already apparent to me having
totally experienced it
at age 37.
whenever he came on. The totality of the
absoluteness of the presence of God was
so stunning and profound. It staggered
me out for 10 years and I never did
mention it for 30 years. In fact, never
did mention it.
Um, so I think we're safe if we respect
the we owe it to the divinity within us.
I say I owe it to God to share what I
have learned. I owe to God
uh to share what I have learned with
others for whatever benefit I to share
whatever benefit I have gained with them
that mankind will not be led down the
dark path to hell the way he has in the
past because he certainly has been
seduced into hell in the past has he not
great seducers of mankind are
historically historic figures
many of them little celebrated.
All right. So, that is where we'll
conclude today. I've tried to share all
that I can that I feel would be most
beneficial and helpful
and to be guarded on your way to have
the breastplate of truth as Jesus said.
Isn't that what he said? The breastplate
of truth. Uh to guard one against um
what I call spiritual seduction.
Spiritual seduction. and to be aware
that there are those entities within the
universe who do not have your
enlightenment
uh as their interest. They are not
interested in your salvation or your
enlightenment.
In fact, they gain their power, prestige
and domains
by destroying yours.
You see that in the criminal hierarchy.
What is a made guy? A made guy has
proven that he's more evil than a less
evil guy. Your status comes from killing
another human being with a witness. Not
just robbing a
convenience store. Convenience store
your way down in the hierarchy, aren't
you? So the more wicked you can be, the
more you rise in the hierarchies of the
lower astral realms. So we have you
understand there's a paradoxical
if you can bring down a really evolved
guru then your
reign in the world of power which is was
what was presented to me becomes higher
becomes higher
so these entities want I just want to
give you a little paranoia for the month
these entities want to juice you baby
just keep yourself on guard
All right. Thank you for today, folks. I
love you.