Now
Now we
Now we have
Now we have some
Now we have some specific
Now we have some specific questions
about
about illnesses.
Illnesses
Illnesses seem
Illnesses seem to
Illnesses seem to be
Illnesses seem to be karmic
consequences.
consequences. Uh
Illnesses seem to be karmic
consequences. Uh they
consequences. Uh they take
Illnesses seem to be karmic
consequences. Uh they take a
consequences. Uh they take a very
specific
specific form.
specific form. They
specific form. They have
specific form. They have a
specific form. They have a very
specific form. They have a very specific
duration.
Most
Most illnesses
Most illnesses are
Most illnesses are cyclic
Most illnesses are cyclic in
Most illnesses are cyclic in nature.
If
the
the illness
the illness did
the illness did not
the illness did not exist
the illness did not exist before
the illness did not exist before and
the illness did not exist before and you
have
have it
the illness did not exist before and you
have it now,
have it now, it's
the illness did not exist before and you
have it now, it's obvious
have it now, it's obvious not
the illness did not exist before and you
have it now, it's obvious not a
have it now, it's obvious not a it's
obviously
obviously not
obviously not permanent.
obviously not permanent. So
obviously not permanent. So if
obviously not permanent. So if it's
cycled
cycled in,
obviously not permanent. So if it's
cycled in, it
cycled in, it can
obviously not permanent. So if it's
cycled in, it can also
cycled in, it can also cycle
obviously not permanent. So if it's
cycled in, it can also cycle out.
cycled in, it can also cycle out. So
what
what I
what I tell
what I tell patients
what I tell patients in
what I tell patients in the
what I tell patients in the office,
what I tell patients in the office, no
matter
matter what
what I tell patients in the office, no
matter what ills
matter what ills you
what I tell patients in the office, no
matter what ills you if
matter what ills you if it
what I tell patients in the office, no
matter what ills you if it cycled
matter what ills you if it cycled into
your
your life,
your life, it
your life, it can
your life, it can also
your life, it can also cycle
your life, it can also cycle out.
As
As you
your life, it can also cycle out.
As you involve
As you involve evolve
your life, it can also cycle out.
As you involve evolve in
As you involve evolve in consciousness,
it
it doesn't
it doesn't matter
it doesn't matter whether
it doesn't matter whether it
it doesn't matter whether it cycles
it doesn't matter whether it cycles in
or
or out.
it doesn't matter whether it cycles in
or out. It
or out. It doesn't
it doesn't matter whether it cycles in
or out. It doesn't matter
or out. It doesn't matter anymore.
it doesn't matter whether it cycles in
or out. It doesn't matter anymore. Um
people
people do
people do the
people do the course
people do the course of
people do the course of miracles
people do the course of miracles in
order
order to
people do the course of miracles in
order to recover
order to recover from
people do the course of miracles in
order to recover from certain
order to recover from certain illnesses.
And
And I
And I tell
And I tell him,
And I tell him, if
And I tell him, if you're
And I tell him, if you're successful
with
with the
And I tell him, if you're successful
with the course
with the course of
And I tell him, if you're successful
with the course of miracles,
with the course of miracles, you
And I tell him, if you're successful
with the course of miracles, you won't
care
care whether
care whether the
care whether the illness
care whether the illness leaves
care whether the illness leaves or
care whether the illness leaves or not
because
because the
care whether the illness leaves or not
because the transcendent.
And
And uh
And uh you
And uh you lived
And uh you lived well,
And uh you lived well, you
And uh you lived well, you know,
And uh you lived well, you know, you
learned
learned how
And uh you lived well, you know, you
learned how to
learned how to live
And uh you lived well, you know, you
learned how to live with
learned how to live with various
physical
physical things.
physical things. And
physical things. And they're
physical things. And they're they're
they're
they're because
physical things. And they're they're
they're because you
they're because you don't
physical things. And they're they're
they're because you don't focus
they're because you don't focus on
physical things. And they're they're
they're because you don't focus on them.
They're
They're irrelevant.
They're irrelevant. I
They're irrelevant. I got,
They're irrelevant. I got, you
They're irrelevant. I got, you know,
right
right now
They're irrelevant. I got, you know,
right now two
right now two or
They're irrelevant. I got, you know,
right now two or three
right now two or three things
They're irrelevant. I got, you know,
right now two or three things that
right now two or three things that if
They're irrelevant. I got, you know,
right now two or three things that if I
think
think about
think about it
think about it Oh,
think about it Oh, yes.
think about it Oh, yes. And
think about it Oh, yes. And uh
think about it Oh, yes. And uh uh
think about it Oh, yes. And uh uh I
think about it Oh, yes. And uh uh I had
to
to do
think about it Oh, yes. And uh uh I had
to do an
to do an exercise
think about it Oh, yes. And uh uh I had
to do an exercise to
to do an exercise to get
think about it Oh, yes. And uh uh I had
to do an exercise to get off
to do an exercise to get off the
think about it Oh, yes. And uh uh I had
to do an exercise to get off the rug
this
this morning
this morning because
this morning because my
this morning because my back
this morning because my back went
this morning because my back went out
from
from shoveling
this morning because my back went out
from shoveling the
from shoveling the other
this morning because my back went out
from shoveling the other day.
Where
Where is
Where is trivia
Where is trivia like
Where is trivia like that,
Where is trivia like that, but
Where is trivia like that, but that's
it's
it's all
Where is trivia like that, but that's
it's all trivia.
And
I'm
I'm sure
And
I'm sure every
I'm sure every thing
And
I'm sure every thing like
I'm sure every thing like that
And
I'm sure every thing like that serves
multiple
multiple purposes.
I
I like
multiple purposes.
I like the
I like the lesson
multiple purposes.
I like the lesson in
I like the lesson in the
multiple purposes.
I like the lesson in the course
I like the lesson in the course of
miracles.
miracles. It
miracles. It says
miracles. It says you're
miracles. It says you're only
miracles. It says you're only subject
miracles. It says you're only subject to
what
what you
miracles. It says you're only subject to
what you hold
what you hold in
miracles. It says you're only subject to
what you hold in mind.
It
It doesn't
It doesn't mean
It doesn't mean you're
It doesn't mean you're going
It doesn't mean you're going to
It doesn't mean you're going to be
It doesn't mean you're going to be able
to
to discover
It doesn't mean you're going to be able
to discover consciously
to discover consciously what
It doesn't mean you're going to be able
to discover consciously what you're
holding
holding in
holding in mind.
or
or from
holding in mind.
or from what
or from what lifetime
but
but it
but it is
but it is an
but it is an avenue
but it is an avenue approaching
but it is an avenue approaching which
offers
offers some
but it is an avenue approaching which
offers some hope
offers some hope for
but it is an avenue approaching which
offers some hope for relief
offers some hope for relief and
but it is an avenue approaching which
offers some hope for relief and in
offers some hope for relief and in my
own
own life
own life it
own life it really
own life it really worked
own life it really worked quite
own life it really worked quite well.
He
He says,
own life it really worked quite well.
He says, "When
He says, "When you're
own life it really worked quite well.
He says, "When you're doing
He says, "When you're doing kinesiology,
are
are you
are you looking
are you looking without,
are you looking without, within,
are you looking without, within, or
what?"
what?" I'm
are you looking without, within, or
what?" I'm not
what?" I'm not looking
are you looking without, within, or
what?" I'm not looking anywhere.
So,
So, I'll
So, I'll just
So, I'll just explain
So, I'll just explain kinesiology
So, I'll just explain kinesiology one
last
last time.
So, I'll just explain kinesiology one
last time. The
last time. The next
So, I'll just explain kinesiology one
last time. The next person
last time. The next person who
So, I'll just explain kinesiology one
last time. The next person who asks
about
about it
about it is
about it is going
about it is going to
about it is going to really
about it is going to really get
about it is going to really get it.
Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. what
>> Okay. what I'm
>> Okay. what I'm holding
>> Okay. what I'm holding in
>> Okay. what I'm holding in what
>> Okay. what I'm holding in what I'm
holding
holding in
>> Okay. what I'm holding in what I'm
holding in mind
holding in mind is
>> Okay. what I'm holding in what I'm
holding in mind is true.
holding in mind is true. He
>> Okay. what I'm holding in what I'm
holding in mind is true. He says,
holding in mind is true. He says, "Thank
you."
you." Now,
you." Now, she
you." Now, she did
you." Now, she did not
you." Now, she did not hear
you." Now, she did not hear what
you." Now, she did not hear what I'm
holding
holding in
you." Now, she did not hear what I'm
holding in mind.
holding in mind. So,
you." Now, she did not hear what I'm
holding in mind. So, that
holding in mind. So, that answers
you." Now, she did not hear what I'm
holding in mind. So, that answers the
question.
question. Isn't
question. Isn't what
question. Isn't what the
question. Isn't what the test
question. Isn't what the test subject
believes
believes going
question. Isn't what the test subject
believes going to
believes going to influence
question. Isn't what the test subject
believes going to influence your
believes going to influence your answer?
The
The answer
The answer is
The answer is no.
I
I didn't
The answer is no.
I didn't tell
I didn't tell her
The answer is no.
I didn't tell her what
I didn't tell her what it
The answer is no.
I didn't tell her what it is.
I
I said,
I said, "Is
I said, "Is this
I said, "Is this audience
I said, "Is this audience over
I said, "Is this audience over 431?"
Yes,
Yes, it
I said, "Is this audience over 431?"
Yes, it is.
Yes, it is. And
I said, "Is this audience over 431?"
Yes, it is. And you
Yes, it is. And you can
I said, "Is this audience over 431?"
Yes, it is. And you can use
Yes, it is. And you can use it
I said, "Is this audience over 431?"
Yes, it is. And you can use it with
children.
children. You
children. You can
children. You can put
children. You can put Bin
children. You can put Bin Laden's
children. You can put Bin Laden's I
children. You can put Bin Laden's I love
Bin
Bin Laden.
We
We used
We used to
We used to use
We used to use Hitler
We used to use Hitler all
We used to use Hitler all the
We used to use Hitler all the time,
We used to use Hitler all the time, but
he
he went
We used to use Hitler all the time, but
he went and
he went and got
We used to use Hitler all the time, but
he went and got out
he went and got out of
We used to use Hitler all the time, but
he went and got out of here.
he went and got out of here. Now
We used to use Hitler all the time, but
he went and got out of here. Now we
he went and got out of here. Now we we
got
got a
got a new
got a new one.
got a new one. Ben
got a new one. Ben Ben
got a new one. Ben Ben is
got a new one. Ben Ben is when
got a new one. Ben Ben is when you
got a new one. Ben Ben is when you had
got a new one. Ben Ben is when you had a
bad
bad example,
got a new one. Ben Ben is when you had a
bad example, you
bad example, you tried
got a new one. Ben Ben is when you had a
bad example, you tried him
bad example, you tried him out.
got a new one. Ben Ben is when you had a
bad example, you tried him out. You
what
what I
what I mean?
what I mean? Um
what I mean? Um if
what I mean? Um if he
what I mean? Um if he gets
what I mean? Um if he gets killed
what I mean? Um if he gets killed off,
we'll
we'll have
what I mean? Um if he gets killed off,
we'll have to
we'll have to find
what I mean? Um if he gets killed off,
we'll have to find a
we'll have to find a new
what I mean? Um if he gets killed off,
we'll have to find a new evil
we'll have to find a new evil one.
what I mean? Um if he gets killed off,
we'll have to find a new evil one. You
know,
know, anyway,
know, anyway, Ben
know, anyway, Ben been
know, anyway, Ben been loud
know, anyway, Ben been loud in
know, anyway, Ben been loud in the
service.
service. His
know, anyway, Ben been loud in the
service. His picture
service. His picture in
know, anyway, Ben been loud in the
service. His picture in a
service. His picture in a manila
envelope
envelope held
envelope held over
envelope held over a
envelope held over a child's
envelope held over a child's solar
plexus
plexus will
envelope held over a child's solar
plexus will make
plexus will make the
envelope held over a child's solar
plexus will make the child
plexus will make the child go
envelope held over a child's solar
plexus will make the child go weak.
plexus will make the child go weak. So
that
that answers
that answers what
that answers what you're
that answers what you're holding
that answers what you're holding in
that answers what you're holding in mind
is
is going
that answers what you're holding in mind
is going to
is going to influence
that answers what you're holding in mind
is going to influence the
is going to influence the result.
Uh
Uh those
Uh those are
Uh those are questions
Uh those are questions that
Uh those are questions that first
Uh those are questions that first come
up
up when
Uh those are questions that first come
up when you
up when you first
Uh those are questions that first come
up when you first learn
up when you first learn kinesiology.
Uh those are questions that first come
up when you first learn kinesiology. The
first
first class
first class I
first class I ever
first class I ever went
first class I ever went to
first class I ever went to that
first class I ever went to that came
first class I ever went to that came up
of
of course
first class I ever went to that came up
of course and
of course and it's
first class I ever went to that came up
of course and it's been
of course and it's been looked
first class I ever went to that came up
of course and it's been looked at
of course and it's been looked at and
answered
answered by
answered by thousands
answered by thousands and
answered by thousands and thousands
answered by thousands and thousands of
practitioners
practitioners over
answered by thousands and thousands of
practitioners over many
practitioners over many years.
And
And the
And the answer
And the answer is
And the answer is always
And the answer is always the
And the answer is always the same.
And the answer is always the same. No.
It's
It's it's
And the answer is always the same. No.
It's it's the
It's it's the reaction
And the answer is always the same. No.
It's it's the reaction of
It's it's the reaction of consciousness
itself
itself to
itself to the
itself to the presence
itself to the presence of
itself to the presence of truth.
And
And a
itself to the presence of truth.
And a no
And a no answer
itself to the presence of truth.
And a no answer is
And a no answer is not
itself to the presence of truth.
And a no answer is not a
And a no answer is not a no.
itself to the presence of truth.
And a no answer is not a no. It's
And a no answer is not a no. It's that
truth
truth is
truth is not
truth is not present.
truth is not present. So
truth is not present. So it's
truth is not present. So it's not
truth is not present. So it's not yes
versus
versus no.
truth is not present. So it's not yes
versus no. It's
versus no. It's yes
truth is not present. So it's not yes
versus no. It's yes versus
versus no. It's yes versus not
truth is not present. So it's not yes
versus no. It's yes versus not yes.
Otherwise
Otherwise we
Otherwise we get
Otherwise we get into
Otherwise we get into the
polarity
polarity of
Otherwise we get into the
polarity of the
polarity of the opposites.
Truth
Truth is
Truth is either
Truth is either present
Truth is either present or
Truth is either present or it
Truth is either present or it is
Truth is either present or it is not
present.
The
The electric
The electric is
The electric is either
The electric is either on
The electric is either on or
The electric is either on or not
The electric is either on or not on.
There
There is
The electric is either on or not on.
There is no
There is no condition
The electric is either on or not on.
There is no condition of
There is no condition of electricity
called
called offness.
called offness. So
called offness. So we're
called offness. So we're not
called offness. So we're not testing
onness
onness versus
called offness. So we're not testing
onness versus offness.
Onness
Onness is
Onness is either
Onness is either present
Onness is either present or
Onness is either present or not
Onness is either present or not present.
Light
Light bulb
Onness is either present or not present.
Light bulb goes
Light bulb goes on.
Onness is either present or not present.
Light bulb goes on. So
Light bulb goes on. So is
Onness is either present or not present.
Light bulb goes on. So is that
Light bulb goes on. So is that clear?
Otherwise
Otherwise we
Otherwise we get
Otherwise we get into
Otherwise we get into the
Otherwise we get into the dualities
Otherwise we get into the dualities of
you
you know
Otherwise we get into the dualities of
you know good
you know good versus
Otherwise we get into the dualities of
you know good versus bad
you know good versus bad and
Otherwise we get into the dualities of
you know good versus bad and all
you know good versus bad and all the
rest
rest of
rest of that.
Um
this
this next
this next question
this next question is
this next question is is
this next question is is I'll
this next question is is I'll put
this next question is is I'll put it
this next question is is I'll put it out
generically.
Uh
Uh how
Uh how can
Uh how can our
Uh how can our actions
bring
bring about
Uh how can our actions
bring about changes
bring about changes in
Uh how can our actions
bring about changes in the
bring about changes in the world
Uh how can our actions
bring about changes in the world if
bring about changes in the world if we
if
if it
if it it's
if it it's not
if it it's not via
if it it's not via the
if it it's not via the mechanism
if it it's not via the mechanism of
cause?
How
How do
How do actions
How do actions have
How do actions have consequences?
uh
uh we
How do actions have consequences?
uh we see
uh we see that
How do actions have consequences?
uh we see that actions
that
that one
that one action
that one action has
that one action has followed
that one action has followed another.
that one action has followed another. So
from
from a
that one action has followed another. So
from a strictly
from a strictly scientific
that one action has followed another. So
from a strictly scientific viewpoint
we
we could
we could say
we could say they
we could say they were
we could say they were sequential.
Sequential
Sequential to
we could say they were sequential.
Sequential to what?
Sequential to what? Sequential
we could say they were sequential.
Sequential to what? Sequential to
observation.
observation. Can't
observation. Can't say
observation. Can't say in
observation. Can't say in of
observation. Can't say in of themselves
sequential
sequential because
observation. Can't say in of themselves
sequential because that's
sequential because that's just
observation. Can't say in of themselves
sequential because that's just a
sequential because that's just a concept
that
that you're
that you're rejecting.
If
If certain
that you're rejecting.
If certain conditions
If certain conditions prevail,
that you're rejecting.
If certain conditions prevail, then
If certain conditions prevail, then we
have
have noticed
have noticed throughout
have noticed throughout time
have noticed throughout time a
have noticed throughout time a certain
sequence
sequence of
have noticed throughout time a certain
sequence of perceptions.
From
From a
From a strictly
ultra
ultra scientific
From a strictly
ultra scientific viewpoint,
ultra scientific viewpoint, that's
From a strictly
ultra scientific viewpoint, that's all
you
you can
you can say
you can say about
you can say about it.
I
I hear
you can say about it.
I hear a
I hear a ring
you can say about it.
I hear a ring in
I hear a ring in this
getting
getting feedback.
getting feedback. Um,
to
to be
getting feedback. Um,
to be strictly
to be strictly truthful,
getting feedback. Um,
to be strictly truthful, all
to be strictly truthful, all you
getting feedback. Um,
to be strictly truthful, all you can
ever
ever say
ever say is
is
is what
ever say is
is what you
is what you observe,
ever say is
is what you observe, what
is what you observe, what appears
ever say is
is what you observe, what appears to
is what you observe, what appears to be.
Because
to
to know
Because
to know that
to know that something
Because
to know that something is
to know that something is happening
there,
there, the
there, the only
there, the only way
there, the only way you'd
there, the only way you'd know
there, the only way you'd know it
there, the only way you'd know it is
you'd
you'd have
there, the only way you'd know it is
you'd have to
you'd have to be
there, the only way you'd know it is
you'd have to be it.
you'd have to be it. You
there, the only way you'd know it is
you'd have to be it. You have
you'd have to be it. You have to
there, the only way you'd know it is
you'd have to be it. You have to be
you'd have to be it. You have to be it.
That
That is
That is a
That is a subtle
That is a subtle point
That is a subtle point of
That is a subtle point of course
That is a subtle point of course in
That is a subtle point of course in the
jump
jump into
That is a subtle point of course in the
jump into quantum
jump into quantum mechanics
That is a subtle point of course in the
jump into quantum mechanics is
jump into quantum mechanics is there's
observables
in
in our
observables
in our language
in our language is
observables
in our language is catching
in our language is catching up
observables
in our language is catching up and
in our language is catching up and I'm
very
very pleased
very pleased with
very pleased with it.
very pleased with it. The
very pleased with it. The word
very pleased with it. The word p
perceived
perceived perceived
very pleased with it. The word p
perceived perceived is
perceived perceived is now
very pleased with it. The word p
perceived perceived is now entering
perceived perceived is now entering our
language.
language. A
language. A perceived
language. A perceived this
language. A perceived this a
language. A perceived this a perceived
that
that that
language. A perceived this a perceived
that that show
that that show that
language. A perceived this a perceived
that that show that leaves
that that show that leaves room
language. A perceived this a perceived
that that show that leaves room for
that that show that leaves room for the
subjectivity.
So
So it's
subjectivity.
So it's closer
So it's closer to
subjectivity.
So it's closer to reality.
So it's closer to reality. The
subjectivity.
So it's closer to reality. The perceived
event,
event, the
event, the perceived
event, the perceived witness
perceived
perceived event.
That
That means
That means you've
That means you've introduced
That means you've introduced back
That means you've introduced back into
uh
uh a
That means you've introduced back into
uh a personless
uh a personless uh
That means you've introduced back into
uh a personless uh dead
uh a personless uh dead world
subjectivity
because
because it
subjectivity
because it is
because it is only
subjectivity
because it is only subjectivity
because it is only subjectivity that
subjectivity
because it is only subjectivity that has
any
any reality
any reality to
any reality to it.
observables
observables all
any reality to it.
observables all depend
observables all depend on
any reality to it.
observables all depend on the
observables all depend on the observer
and
and the
and the point
and the point of
and the point of observation
and the point of observation and
and the point of observation and the
definitions
definitions and
and the point of observation and the
definitions and symbols
definitions and symbols and
and the point of observation and the
definitions and symbols and it
definitions and symbols and it is
and the point of observation and the
definitions and symbols and it is far
removed
removed from
removed from the
removed from the actuality
removed from the actuality itself.
removed from the actuality itself. So
when
when we
removed from the actuality itself. So
when we say
when we say a
removed from the actuality itself. So
when we say a perceived
when we say a perceived event
removed from the actuality itself. So
when we say a perceived event that
when we say a perceived event that is
certainly
certainly closer
certainly closer to
certainly closer to reality
uh
it's
it's choice
it's choice it's
it's choice it's choice
it's choice it's choice to
it's choice it's choice to let
it's choice it's choice to let that
which
which is
it's choice it's choice to let that
which is non-intigorous
which is non-intigorous go
it's choice it's choice to let that
which is non-intigorous go from
which is non-intigorous go from one's
life
in
in many
life
in many people's
in many people's spiritual
life
in many people's spiritual evolution
this
this is
this is a
this is a crucial
this is a crucial area
crucial
crucial area
this is a crucial area
crucial area crucial
crucial area crucial spiritual
this is a crucial area
crucial area crucial spiritual area
crucial area crucial spiritual area and
we
we see
we see many
we see many people
we see many people in
we see many people in a
we see many people in a town
we see many people in a town like
we see many people in a town like Sedona
for
for instance
we see many people in a town like Sedona
for instance who
for instance who leave
we see many people in a town like Sedona
for instance who leave everything
for instance who leave everything and
everyone
everyone and
everyone and all
everyone and all their
everyone and all their titles
everyone and all their titles and
buildings
buildings and
everyone and all their titles and
buildings and money
buildings and money and
everyone and all their titles and
buildings and money and relationships
and
and everything
and everything and
and everything and give
and everything and give up
and everything and give up everything
for
for God
and
and then
and then drive
and then drive a
and then drive a bus
to
to make
and then drive a bus
to make ends
to make ends meet.
So
So we
So we see
So we see the
So we see the willingness
So we see the willingness to
So we see the willingness to sacrifice
everything
everything for
So we see the willingness to sacrifice
everything for God.
If
If that
If that everything
If that everything if
If that everything if whatever
If that everything if whatever it
If that everything if whatever it is
If that everything if whatever it is is
non-integrous,
non-integrous, it
If that everything if whatever it is is
non-integrous, it has
non-integrous, it has to
If that everything if whatever it is is
non-integrous, it has to go
non-integrous, it has to go sooner
If that everything if whatever it is is
non-integrous, it has to go sooner or
later.
later. It
later. It has
later. It has to
later. It has to go.
later. It has to go. And
it's
it's sort
later. It has to go. And
it's sort of
it's sort of a
later. It has to go. And
it's sort of a test.
it's sort of a test. The
later. It has to go. And
it's sort of a test. The willingness
it's sort of a test. The willingness to
surrender
surrender everything
surrender everything to
surrender everything to God,
surrender everything to God, to
surrender everything to God, to step
over
over one's
surrender everything to God, to step
over one's own
over one's own children
at
at every
at every level.
Walk
Walk away
at every level.
Walk away from
Walk away from that
at every level.
Walk away from that which
Walk away from that which is
at every level.
Walk away from that which is nonigous.
One
One may
One may have
One may have to
One may have to walk
One may have to walk away
One may have to walk away from
One may have to walk away from one's
One may have to walk away from one's own
child.
That
That to
That to God.
Well,
Well, God
That to God.
Well, God is
Well, God is your
That to God.
Well, God is your problem
Well, God is your problem now.
You
You go
You go to
You go to Helen
You go to Helen and
You go to Helen and learn
You go to Helen and learn that
You go to Helen and learn that one.
That's
That's his
You go to Helen and learn that one.
That's his problem.
That's his problem. And
You go to Helen and learn that one.
That's his problem. And I'm
That's his problem. And I'm going
You go to Helen and learn that one.
That's his problem. And I'm going to
live
live my
live my life.
live my life. Okay.
live my life. Okay. It
live my life. Okay. It isn't
live my life. Okay. It isn't that
live my life. Okay. It isn't that you
plug
plug the
live my life. Okay. It isn't that you
plug the leak
plug the leak leak
live my life. Okay. It isn't that you
plug the leak leak it
plug the leak leak it that
live my life. Okay. It isn't that you
plug the leak leak it that you
plug the leak leak it that you make
live my life. Okay. It isn't that you
plug the leak leak it that you make it.
You
You make
You make a
You make a choice
You make a choice and
You make a choice and and
You make a choice and and you
You make a choice and and you don't
You make a choice and and you don't do
it
it out
You make a choice and and you don't do
it out of
it out of a
You make a choice and and you don't do
it out of a make
it out of a make wrong.
You make a choice and and you don't do
it out of a make wrong. See,
it out of a make wrong. See, because
You make a choice and and you don't do
it out of a make wrong. See, because at
the
the same
the same time
the same time you're
the same time you're seeing
the same time you're seeing innocence.
The
The reason
the same time you're seeing innocence.
The reason we're
The reason we're talking
the same time you're seeing innocence.
The reason we're talking about
The reason we're talking about this
the same time you're seeing innocence.
The reason we're talking about this is
because
because spiritually
because spiritually spiritual
because spiritually spiritual people
because spiritually spiritual people as
they
they evolve
because spiritually spiritual people as
they evolve become
they evolve become very
because spiritually spiritual people as
they evolve become very they
they evolve become very they have
because spiritually spiritual people as
they evolve become very they have big
areas
areas of
areas of naive.
The
The uh
areas of naive.
The uh the
The uh the devote
areas of naive.
The uh the devote the
The uh the devote the the
areas of naive.
The uh the devote the the initiate
The uh the devote the the initiate is
areas of naive.
The uh the devote the the initiate is a
long
long way
long way from
long way from the
long way from the spiritual
long way from the spiritual master.
long way from the spiritual master. A
lot
lot of
long way from the spiritual master. A
lot of gray
lot of gray hairs
long way from the spiritual master. A
lot of gray hairs to
lot of gray hairs to go
long way from the spiritual master. A
lot of gray hairs to go through
lot of gray hairs to go through before
you
you go
you go from
you go from initiate
you go from initiate to
you go from initiate to master.
So
So there
you go from initiate to master.
So there is
So there is an
you go from initiate to master.
So there is an a
So there is an a period
you go from initiate to master.
So there is an a period of
So there is an a period of naivity
and
it
it comes
and
it comes when
it comes when you
and
it comes when you see
it comes when you see the
and
it comes when you see the innocence
it comes when you see the innocence and
lovability
lovability of
lovability of all
lovability of all things.
lovability of all things. So
lovability of all things. So it's
lovability of all things. So it's really
a
a vulnerability.
lovability of all things. So it's really
a vulnerability. What
a vulnerability. What happened
lovability of all things. So it's really
a vulnerability. What happened to
a vulnerability. What happened to our
scale?
scale? Somebody
scale? Somebody stole
scale? Somebody stole our
scale? Somebody stole our scale.
scale? Somebody stole our scale. Check
everybody
everybody at
scale? Somebody stole our scale. Check
everybody at the
everybody at the door.
Anyway,
it
it it's
Anyway,
it it's a
it it's a it's
Anyway,
it it's a it's it's
it it's a it's it's a
Anyway,
it it's a it's it's a risk
it it's a it's it's a risk up
Anyway,
it it's a it's it's a risk up here.
When
When you
When you get
When you get into
When you get into the
When you get into the lovingness,
When you get into the lovingness, you
can
can only
When you get into the lovingness, you
can only see
can only see the
When you get into the lovingness, you
can only see the innocence
can only see the innocence and
lovableness
lovableness and
lovableness and beauty
lovableness and beauty of
lovableness and beauty of all
lovableness and beauty of all that
exists.
And
And you
And you think
And you think the
And you think the guy
And you think the guy who
And you think the guy who just
saw
saw your
And you think the guy who just
saw your car
saw your car is
And you think the guy who just
saw your car is great.
He
He looks
He looks just
He looks just like
He looks just like my
He looks just like my dad,
He looks just like my dad, you
He looks just like my dad, you know what
I
I mean?
He looks just like my dad, you know what
I mean? Sweet
I mean? Sweet old
He looks just like my dad, you know what
I mean? Sweet old man.
And
And he
And he just
And he just walked
And he just walked off
And he just walked off with
And he just walked off with the
And he just walked off with the keys
And he just walked off with the keys to
your
your car.
So
So there
So there is
So there is that
So there is that gap.
So there is that gap. And
so
so what
So there is that gap. And
so what you
so what you see
So there is that gap. And
so what you see is
so what you see is the
So there is that gap. And
so what you see is the the
so what you see is the the you
So there is that gap. And
so what you see is the the you see
so what you see is the the you see the
innocence
innocence of
innocence of all
innocence of all beings
innocence of all beings which
innocence of all beings which you
innocence of all beings which you really
need
need to
innocence of all beings which you really
need to see
need to see to
innocence of all beings which you really
need to see to transcend
need to see to transcend to
innocence of all beings which you really
need to see to transcend to an
enlightened
enlightened state.
Intrinsically
all
all that
all that lives
all that lives is
all that lives is its
all that lives is its own
all that lives is its own nature
all that lives is its own nature is
innocent.
It
It does
It does what
It does what it's
It does what it's programmed
It does what it's programmed to
It does what it's programmed to do.
It does what it's programmed to do. Some
of
of the
It does what it's programmed to do. Some
of the behaviors
of the behaviors are
It does what it's programmed to do. Some
of the behaviors are programmed
of the behaviors are programmed by
evolution
evolution itself,
evolution itself, by
evolution itself, by the
evolution itself, by the very
evolution itself, by the very function
of
of the
evolution itself, by the very function
of the brain
of the brain itself.
The
The lion
chases
chases its
The lion
chases its lunch
chases its lunch and
The lion
chases its lunch and eats.
chases its lunch and eats. It
The lion
chases its lunch and eats. It doesn't
kill
kill anything.
kill anything. Understand?
kill anything. Understand? It's
kill anything. Understand? It's innocent
in
in what
kill anything. Understand? It's innocent
in what it
in what it does.
kill anything. Understand? It's innocent
in what it does. It
in what it does. It just
kill anything. Understand? It's innocent
in what it does. It just it's
in what it does. It just it's just
kill anything. Understand? It's innocent
in what it does. It just it's just being
a
a lion.
If
If you're
a lion.
If you're a
If you're a lion,
a lion.
If you're a lion, rabbits
If you're a lion, rabbits look
a lion.
If you're a lion, rabbits look numb.
And
And we
And we we
And we we decided
And we we decided at
And we we decided at the
And we we decided at the last
And we we decided at the last lecture
that
that lady
And we we decided at the last lecture
that lady that
that lady that had
And we we decided at the last lecture
that lady that had the
that lady that had the Lifetime
And we we decided at the last lecture
that lady that had the Lifetime Lion
that lady that had the Lifetime Lion and
they
they wrote
they wrote a
they wrote a book
they wrote a book about
they wrote a book about her
they wrote a book about her and
they wrote a book about her and a
they wrote a book about her and a movie
and
and all.
they wrote a book about her and a movie
and all. In
and all. In the
they wrote a book about her and a movie
and all. In the end,
and all. In the end, the
they wrote a book about her and a movie
and all. In the end, the lion
and all. In the end, the lion ate
they wrote a book about her and a movie
and all. In the end, the lion ate her
because
because he
because he loved
because he loved her.
because he loved her. We
because he loved her. We checked
because he loved her. We checked that
out,
out, right?
because he loved her. We checked that
out, right? He
out, right? He didn't
because he loved her. We checked that
out, right? He didn't kill
out, right? He didn't kill her
because he loved her. We checked that
out, right? He didn't kill her because
he
he hated
he hated her.
he hated her. He
he hated her. He loved
he hated her. He loved her
he hated her. He loved her so
he hated her. He loved her so much
he hated her. He loved her so much he
just
just I
he hated her. He loved her so much he
just I could
just I could eat
he hated her. He loved her so much he
just I could eat you
just I could eat you up.
he hated her. He loved her so much he
just I could eat you up. And
just I could eat you up. And he
he hated her. He loved her so much he
just I could eat you up. And he did.
enjoy
it
it every
enjoy
it every bite.
it every bite. Oh,
enjoy
it every bite. Oh, man.
All right.
All right. So,
All right. So, even
All right. So, even though
All right. So, even though you
All right. So, even though you love
All right. So, even though you love the
lion
lion and
All right. So, even though you love the
lion and you
lion and you see
All right. So, even though you love the
lion and you see its
lion and you see its in
All right. So, even though you love the
lion and you see its in intrinsic
innocence,
innocence, it
innocence, it can
innocence, it can eat
innocence, it can eat you.
And
And in
innocence, it can eat you.
And in the
And in the end,
innocence, it can eat you.
And in the end, if
And in the end, if you're
innocence, it can eat you.
And in the end, if you're not
And in the end, if you're not aware,
innocence, it can eat you.
And in the end, if you're not aware, it
can
can eat
can eat you.
can eat you. So
can eat you. So I
can eat you. So I see
can eat you. So I see these
can eat you. So I see these uh
can eat you. So I see these uh trainers,
you
you know,
can eat you. So I see these uh trainers,
you know, put
you know, put their
can eat you. So I see these uh trainers,
you know, put their head
you know, put their head in
can eat you. So I see these uh trainers,
you know, put their head in the
you know, put their head in the mouth
can eat you. So I see these uh trainers,
you know, put their head in the mouth of
an
an alligator
an alligator and
an alligator and for
an alligator and for the
an alligator and for the camera
an alligator and for the camera and
an alligator and for the camera and they
put
put their
an alligator and for the camera and they
put their head
put their head in
an alligator and for the camera and they
put their head in the
put their head in the mouth
an alligator and for the camera and they
put their head in the mouth of
put their head in the mouth of the
an alligator and for the camera and they
put their head in the mouth of the lion
and
and you
and you know
and you know it's
and you know it's only
and you know it's only a
and you know it's only a matter
and you know it's only a matter of
and you know it's only a matter of time
before
before his
and you know it's only a matter of time
before his head's
before his head's going
and you know it's only a matter of time
before his head's going to
before his head's going to get
and you know it's only a matter of time
before his head's going to get eaten
off.
I
I know
off.
I know the
I know the alligator's
off.
I know the alligator's going
I know the alligator's going to
off.
I know the alligator's going to bite
I know the alligator's going to bite his
head
head off
head off one
head off one day.
head off one day. I
head off one day. I just
head off one day. I just know
head off one day. I just know it.
head off one day. I just know it. Why?
Because
Because an
head off one day. I just know it. Why?
Because an alligator
Because an alligator is
head off one day. I just know it. Why?
Because an alligator is an
Because an alligator is an alligator.
Don't
Don't you
Don't you get
Don't you get it?
Don't you get it? He's
Don't you get it? He's not
Don't you get it? He's not going
Don't you get it? He's not going to
become
So
So all
So all right.
So all right. So
So all right. So this
So all right. So this idea
So all right. So this idea of
So all right. So this idea of safety
let's
let's say
we
we see
we see the
we see the innate
we see the innate innocence
we see the innate innocence of
we see the innate innocence of all
we see the innate innocence of all that
is
including
including people
including people that
including people that are
including people that are overcome
including people that are overcome by
insanity
religious
religious insanity.
religious insanity. One
religious insanity. One of
religious insanity. One of the
religious insanity. One of the forms
religious insanity. One of the forms of
insanity
insanity is
religious insanity. One of the forms of
insanity is religious
insanity is religious mania
religious insanity. One of the forms of
insanity is religious mania and
insanity is religious mania and it
religious insanity. One of the forms of
insanity is religious mania and it can
become
become almost
become almost epidemic.
become almost epidemic. We
become almost epidemic. We saw
become almost epidemic. We saw it
become almost epidemic. We saw it in
Europe.
Europe. Religious
become almost epidemic. We saw it in
Europe. Religious mania
Europe. Religious mania became
become almost epidemic. We saw it in
Europe. Religious mania became epidemic.
Now
Now we
Now we see
Now we see it
Now we see it in
Now we see it in the
Now we see it in the far
Now we see it in the far in
Now we see it in the far in the
Now we see it in the far in the Middle
East.
where
where religious
where religious delusions
where religious delusions become
where religious delusions become almost
epidemic.
epidemic. You
where religious delusions become almost
epidemic. You know,
epidemic. You know, they
where religious delusions become almost
epidemic. You know, they all
epidemic. You know, they all begin
where religious delusions become almost
epidemic. You know, they all begin to
believe
believe in
believe in that
believe in that and
believe in that and Europe
believe in that and Europe went
believe in that and Europe went through
that
that with
believe in that and Europe went through
that with Christianity
that with Christianity and
believe in that and Europe went through
that with Christianity and various
perversions
perversions of
perversions of Christianity.
So
So the
perversions of Christianity.
So the person
So the person whose
perversions of Christianity.
So the person whose mind
So the person whose mind is
perversions of Christianity.
So the person whose mind is taken
So the person whose mind is taken over
by
by delusional
by delusional thinking,
the
the reason
by delusional thinking,
the reason his
the reason his mind
by delusional thinking,
the reason his mind is
the reason his mind is taken
by delusional thinking,
the reason his mind is taken over
the reason his mind is taken over by
delusional
delusional thinking
delusional thinking is
delusional thinking is because
delusional thinking is because it
delusional thinking is because it has
delusional thinking is because it has no
way
way of
delusional thinking is because it has no
way of protecting
way of protecting itself.
delusional thinking is because it has no
way of protecting itself. It
way of protecting itself. It doesn't
know
know truth
know truth from
know truth from falsehood.
you
you watched
know truth from falsehood.
you watched um
you watched um on
know truth from falsehood.
you watched um on TV
you watched um on TV channel
know truth from falsehood.
you watched um on TV channel the
you watched um on TV channel the how
know truth from falsehood.
you watched um on TV channel the how the
the
the German
the German children
the German children were
the German children were trained
the German children were trained in
the German children were trained in the
1930s.
It
It was
It was fantastic.
It was fantastic. I
It was fantastic. I wish
It was fantastic. I wish I
It was fantastic. I wish I was
It was fantastic. I wish I was there,
you
you know.
It was fantastic. I wish I was there,
you know. I
you know. I watched
It was fantastic. I wish I was there,
you know. I watched I
you know. I watched I said,
It was fantastic. I wish I was there,
you know. I watched I said, "Wow,
you know. I watched I said, "Wow, what
It was fantastic. I wish I was there,
you know. I watched I said, "Wow, what a
childhood."
childhood." They
childhood." They like
childhood." They like go
childhood." They like go to
childhood." They like go to camp
childhood." They like go to camp and
they
they around
childhood." They like go to camp and
they around the
they around the campfire
childhood." They like go to camp and
they around the campfire and
they around the campfire and they
childhood." They like go to camp and
they around the campfire and they sing
Deutsch
Deutsch Nales
Deutsch Nales and
Deutsch Nales and Hidle
Deutsch Nales and Hidle to
Deutsch Nales and Hidle to the
Deutsch Nales and Hidle to the Furer
who's
who's our
Deutsch Nales and Hidle to the Furer
who's our savior.
who's our savior. It's
Deutsch Nales and Hidle to the Furer
who's our savior. It's a
who's our savior. It's a fantastic
Deutsch Nales and Hidle to the Furer
who's our savior. It's a fantastic life.
I
I mean,
I mean, it
I mean, it was
I mean, it was a
I mean, it was a great
I mean, it was a great life.
I mean, it was a great life. Just
I mean, it was a great life. Just like
being
being the
I mean, it was a great life. Just like
being the Boy
being the Boy Scouts
I mean, it was a great life. Just like
being the Boy Scouts around
being the Boy Scouts around the
I mean, it was a great life. Just like
being the Boy Scouts around the clock,
you
you know
you know what
you know what I
you know what I mean?
you know what I mean? Whatever
you know what I mean? Whatever you
you know what I mean? Whatever you do,
you're
you're serving
you know what I mean? Whatever you do,
you're serving your
you're serving your country.
you know what I mean? Whatever you do,
you're serving your country. And
you're serving your country. And the
you know what I mean? Whatever you do,
you're serving your country. And the the
pride,
the
the fact
pride,
the fact the
the fact the leader
pride,
the fact the leader was
the fact the leader was not
pride,
the fact the leader was not integrous,
how
how would
how would they
how would they know
how would they know that?
how would they know that? How
how would they know that? How would
how would they know that? How would they
know
know that?
how would they know that? How would they
know that? They're
know that? They're only
how would they know that? How would they
know that? They're only a
know that? They're only a child.
So,
So, how
So, how can
So, how can you
So, how can you blame
So, how can you blame them?
So, how can you blame them? So,
you
you see
So, how can you blame them? So,
you see the
you see the innocence
So, how can you blame them? So,
you see the innocence of
you see the innocence of all
So, how can you blame them? So,
you see the innocence of all that
you see the innocence of all that lives.
And
And you
And you have
And you have to
And you have to tie
And you have to tie up
And you have to tie up your
And you have to tie up your camel.
Anybody
Anybody know
And you have to tie up your camel.
Anybody know that
Anybody know that quote?
And you have to tie up your camel.
Anybody know that quote? Who
Anybody know that quote? Who knows
And you have to tie up your camel.
Anybody know that quote? Who knows the
quote?
quote? You
quote? You know
quote? You know the
quote? You know the quote?
quote? You know the quote? What
quote? You know the quote? What is
quote? You know the quote? What is the
quote?
>> I
>> I believe
>> I believe in
>> I believe in God,
>> I believe in God, but
>> I believe in God, but I
>> I believe in God, but I tie
>> I believe in God, but I tie up
>> I believe in God, but I tie up my
>> I believe in God, but I tie up my own
camel.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, there
>> Yeah, there it
>> Yeah, there it is.
>> Yeah, there it is. Okay.
>> Yeah, there it is. Okay. All right.
That's
That's a
>> Yeah, there it is. Okay. All right.
That's a good
That's a good lesson.
>> Yeah, there it is. Okay. All right.
That's a good lesson. We
That's a good lesson. We tie
>> Yeah, there it is. Okay. All right.
That's a good lesson. We tie up
That's a good lesson. We tie up our
>> Yeah, there it is. Okay. All right.
That's a good lesson. We tie up our own
camel
camel because
camel because we
camel because we don't
camel because we don't want
camel because we don't want to
camel because we don't want to mix
levels.
levels. We
camel because we don't want to mix
levels. We don't
levels. We don't want
camel because we don't want to mix
levels. We don't want to
levels. We don't want to mix
camel because we don't want to mix
levels. We don't want to mix levels.
levels. We don't want to mix levels. And
although
although the
although the uh
although the uh person
although the uh person is
although the uh person is uh
although the uh person is uh basically
innocent
innocent and
although the uh person is uh basically
innocent and probably
innocent and probably taken
although the uh person is uh basically
innocent and probably taken over
innocent and probably taken over by
although the uh person is uh basically
innocent and probably taken over by some
lower
lower astral
lower astral possessing
lower astral possessing spirit,
I'm
I'm thinking
lower astral possessing spirit,
I'm thinking of
I'm thinking of a
lower astral possessing spirit,
I'm thinking of a killer
I'm thinking of a killer right
lower astral possessing spirit,
I'm thinking of a killer right now.
I'm thinking of a killer right now. Mhm.
We
We have
We have permission
We have permission to
We have permission to ask
We have permission to ask resist
We have permission to ask resist taken
over
over by
We have permission to ask resist taken
over by a
over by a lower
We have permission to ask resist taken
over by a lower Astro
over by a lower Astro resist.
We have permission to ask resist taken
over by a lower Astro resist. Okay.
over by a lower Astro resist. Okay. All
right.
right. So
right. So almost
right. So almost all
right. So almost all the
right. So almost all the famous
right. So almost all the famous killers
that
that you
right. So almost all the famous killers
that you read
that you read about
and
and they
and they usually
and they usually give
and they usually give them
and they usually give them nicknames,
you
you know,
and they usually give them nicknames,
you know, killer
you know, killer John
and they usually give them nicknames,
you know, killer John or
you know, killer John or something
and they usually give them nicknames,
you know, killer John or something like
that.
that. Uh
that. Uh and
that. Uh and he's
that. Uh and he's killed
that. Uh and he's killed 20
that. Uh and he's killed 20 or
that. Uh and he's killed 20 or 30
that. Uh and he's killed 20 or 30 by
that. Uh and he's killed 20 or 30 by now
by
by the
that. Uh and he's killed 20 or 30 by now
by the time
by the time they
that. Uh and he's killed 20 or 30 by now
by the time they catch
by the time they catch him.
that. Uh and he's killed 20 or 30 by now
by the time they catch him. And
by the time they catch him. And uh
anyway,
anyway, what
anyway, what about
anyway, what about his
anyway, what about his innocence?
anyway, what about his innocence? Was
there
there some
anyway, what about his innocence? Was
there some part
there some part of
anyway, what about his innocence? Was
there some part of him
there some part of him that
anyway, what about his innocence? Was
there some part of him that said
there some part of him that said yes
anyway, what about his innocence? Was
there some part of him that said yes to
him?
him? Well,
him? Well, to
him? Well, to that
him? Well, to that entity,
him? Well, to that entity, um,
him? Well, to that entity, um, there's
some
some vulnerability.
him? Well, to that entity, um, there's
some vulnerability. He
some vulnerability. He left
him? Well, to that entity, um, there's
some vulnerability. He left a
some vulnerability. He left a he
him? Well, to that entity, um, there's
some vulnerability. He left a he left
some vulnerability. He left a he left a
hole
hole open
hole open there
hole open there somewhere,
hole open there somewhere, right,
hole open there somewhere, right, where
that
that entity
hole open there somewhere, right, where
that entity came
that entity came in
hole open there somewhere, right, where
that entity came in and
that entity came in and took
hole open there somewhere, right, where
that entity came in and took over
that entity came in and took over his
consciousness.
consciousness. How
consciousness. How do
consciousness. How do we
consciousness. How do we know
consciousness. How do we know that?
Because
Because very
consciousness. How do we know that?
Because very often
Because very often on
consciousness. How do we know that?
Because very often on TV,
Because very often on TV, you'll
consciousness. How do we know that?
Because very often on TV, you'll hear
him
him say,
him say, "I
him say, "I didn't
him say, "I didn't do
him say, "I didn't do it.
him say, "I didn't do it. It
him say, "I didn't do it. It wasn't
him say, "I didn't do it. It wasn't me
that
that did
him say, "I didn't do it. It wasn't me
that did it."
that did it." You
him say, "I didn't do it. It wasn't me
that did it." You hear
that did it." You hear him
him say, "I didn't do it. It wasn't me
that did it." You hear him say,
that did it." You hear him say, "It
wasn't
wasn't me.
Wasn't
Wasn't me
wasn't me.
Wasn't me that
Wasn't me that did
wasn't me.
Wasn't me that did it."
Wasn't me that did it." I
wasn't me.
Wasn't me that did it." I believe
they're
they're right.
they're right. Uh,
they're right. Uh, it
they're right. Uh, it wasn't
they're right. Uh, it wasn't me.
they're right. Uh, it wasn't me. It
they're right. Uh, it wasn't me. It was
some
some other
they're right. Uh, it wasn't me. It was
some other aspect
some other aspect from
they're right. Uh, it wasn't me. It was
some other aspect from some
some other aspect from some other
they're right. Uh, it wasn't me. It was
some other aspect from some other realm.
But
But he
But he left
But he left that
But he left that port
But he left that port hole
But he left that port hole open
But he left that port hole open for
But he left that port hole open for it
to
to come
But he left that port hole open for it
to come in.
to come in. Very
But he left that port hole open for it
to come in. Very often
to come in. Very often it's
But he left that port hole open for it
to come in. Very often it's drugs.
to come in. Very often it's drugs. Very
often
often it's
often it's some
often it's some crime.
often it's some crime. Sometimes
often it's some crime. Sometimes it's
something
something innocent
often it's some crime. Sometimes it's
something innocent like
something innocent like brain
often it's some crime. Sometimes it's
something innocent like brain injury.
something innocent like brain injury. So
there's
there's many
there's many karmic
there's many karmic reasons
there's many karmic reasons why
there's many karmic reasons why the
there's many karmic reasons why the port
hole
hole was
there's many karmic reasons why the port
hole was left
hole was left over
there's many karmic reasons why the port
hole was left over for
hole was left over for the
there's many karmic reasons why the port
hole was left over for the entity
hole was left over for the entity to
there's many karmic reasons why the port
hole was left over for the entity to get
in.
As
As we
in.
As we become
As we become more
in.
As we become more responsible,
As we become more responsible, then
there's
there's a
there's a point
there's a point at
there's a point at which
there's a point at which we
there's a point at which we really
there's a point at which we really do
have
have to
there's a point at which we really do
have to go
have to go through
there's a point at which we really do
have to go through our
have to go through our spiritual
there's a point at which we really do
have to go through our spiritual library
and
and take
and take out
and take out the
and take out the energy
and take out the energy of
and take out the energy of that
and take out the energy of that which
and take out the energy of that which is
non
non integrous.
all
all the
all the end
all the end of
all the end of the
all the end of the world
all the end of the world uh
all the end of the world uh books
all the end of the world uh books and
the
the world's
all the end of the world uh books and
the world's ending
the world's ending in
all the end of the world uh books and
the world's ending in 19
I've
I've lived
I've lived through
I've lived through so
I've lived through so many
I've lived through so many ends
I've lived through so many ends of
I've lived through so many ends of the
world
world I
I've lived through so many ends of the
world I mean
world I mean you
I've lived through so many ends of the
world I mean you know
world I mean you know it's
I've lived through so many ends of the
world I mean you know it's in
world I mean you know it's in Sedona
there's
there's a
there's a new
there's a new end
there's a new end of
there's a new end of the
there's a new end of the world
there's a new end of the world every
lecture
lecture series
there's a new end of the world every
lecture series you
lecture series you know
you
you got
you got it
you got it from
you got it from some
you got it from some entity
you got it from some entity on
you got it from some entity on the
you got it from some entity on the other
side
side and
you got it from some entity on the other
side and the
side and the year
you got it from some entity on the other
side and the year 19
side and the year 19 I've
you got it from some entity on the other
side and the year 19 I've been
side and the year 19 I've been through
20 of
20 of them
20 of them already
20 of them already in
20 of them already in Sedona
20 of them already in Sedona California
was
was falling
20 of them already in Sedona California
was falling off
was falling off the
20 of them already in Sedona California
was falling off the ocean
was falling off the ocean earthquakes
were
were happening
were happening uh
were happening uh the
were happening uh the the
were happening uh the the vortexes
were happening uh the the vortexes were
going
going to
were happening uh the the vortexes were
going to explode
going to explode and
were happening uh the the vortexes were
going to explode and spaceships
going to explode and spaceships were
going
going in
going in and
going in and out
going in and out I
going in and out I I
going in and out I I mean,
going in and out I I mean, there's
going in and out I I mean, there's no
end
end to
going in and out I I mean, there's no
end to that
but
but it
but it brings
but it brings them
but it brings them in.
but it brings them in. I'll
but it brings them in. I'll tell
but it brings them in. I'll tell you.
but it brings them in. I'll tell you. It
brings
brings them
but it brings them in. I'll tell you. It
brings them in.
brings them in. Yeah.
Let's
Let's go
Let's go out,
Let's go out, baby,
Let's go out, baby, and
Let's go out, baby, and watch
Let's go out, baby, and watch the
spaceships
spaceships tonight.
Let's go out, baby, and watch the
spaceships tonight. Okay.
spaceships tonight. Okay. Hey,
Let's go out, baby, and watch the
spaceships tonight. Okay. Hey, see
spaceships tonight. Okay. Hey, see those
lights
lights in
lights in this
lights in this guy?
lights in this guy? They're
lights in this guy? They're speaking
lights in this guy? They're speaking to
me.
me. And
lights in this guy? They're speaking to
me. And uh
you're
you're supposed
you're supposed to
you're supposed to eat
you're supposed to eat nothing
you're supposed to eat nothing but
radishes,
radishes, live
you're supposed to eat nothing but
radishes, live in
radishes, live in the
you're supposed to eat nothing but
radishes, live in the desert,
radishes, live in the desert, and
you're supposed to eat nothing but
radishes, live in the desert, and wait
for
for them
for them to
for them to come
for them to come and
for them to come and get
for them to come and get you.
They've
They've already
for them to come and get you.
They've already got
They've already got you,
for them to come and get you.
They've already got you, folks.
They've already got you, folks. I
for them to come and get you.
They've already got you, folks. I hate
to
to tell
to tell you.
How
How do
to tell you.
How do they
How do they got
to tell you.
How do they got you?
How do they got you? They
to tell you.
How do they got you? They want
How do they got you? They want to
to tell you.
How do they got you? They want to They
want
want you
want you to
want you to be
want you to be in
want you to be in their
want you to be in their power
want you to be in their power with
want you to be in their power with this
mystification.
So
So that
So that which
So that which has
So that which has a
So that which has a circus-like
atmosphere,
atmosphere, that
So that which has a circus-like
atmosphere, that which
atmosphere, that which sounds
So that which has a circus-like
atmosphere, that which sounds far
atmosphere, that which sounds far out
and
and bizarre,
and bizarre, you
and bizarre, you know
and bizarre, you know what
and bizarre, you know what it
and bizarre, you know what it is?
if
if it
and bizarre, you know what it is?
if it sounds
if it sounds nonsensical.
Uh,
Uh, all
Uh, all right.
So,
So, to
Uh, all right.
So, to be
So, to be on
Uh, all right.
So, to be on guide
So, to be on guide then
Uh, all right.
So, to be on guide then is
So, to be on guide then is something
that
that leads
that leads from
that leads from spiritual
that leads from spiritual naiv.
The
The spiritually
that leads from spiritual naiv.
The spiritually naive
The spiritually naive are
that leads from spiritual naiv.
The spiritually naive are drawn
The spiritually naive are drawn to
places
places like
places like Sedona
places like Sedona where
places like Sedona where the
places like Sedona where the astral
circus
circus is
places like Sedona where the astral
circus is a
circus is a continuous
places like Sedona where the astral
circus is a continuous round
circus is a continuous round the
places like Sedona where the astral
circus is a continuous round the clock
seven
seven days
seven days a
seven days a week.
seven days a week. There's
seven days a week. There's a
seven days a week. There's a psychic
reading
reading on
seven days a week. There's a psychic
reading on every
reading on every street
seven days a week. There's a psychic
reading on every street corner.
Read
Read your
Read your ruins,
Read your ruins, read
Read your ruins, read your
Read your ruins, read your stones,
Read your ruins, read your stones, read
your
your knobs,
Read your ruins, read your stones, read
your knobs, read
your knobs, read your
Read your ruins, read your stones, read
your knobs, read your dizzy
your knobs, read your dizzy atom
Read your ruins, read your stones, read
your knobs, read your dizzy atom to
your knobs, read your dizzy atom to me,
read
read your
read your toes.
read your toes. You
read your toes. You know
read your toes. You know what
read your toes. You know what I
read your toes. You know what I mean?
read your toes. You know what I mean? I
got
got a
read your toes. You know what I mean? I
got a new
got a new breathing
read your toes. You know what I mean? I
got a new breathing technique.
got a new breathing technique. Bricks
six
six times.
six times. Count
six times. Count to
six times. Count to seven
six times. Count to seven three
six times. Count to seven three times.
six times. Count to seven three times. I
told
told you
six times. Count to seven three times. I
told you about
told you about how
six times. Count to seven three times. I
told you about how I
told you about how I used
six times. Count to seven three times. I
told you about how I used to
told you about how I used to stop
six times. Count to seven three times. I
told you about how I used to stop when
told you about how I used to stop when I
was
was hitchhiking.
was hitchhiking. I'd
was hitchhiking. I'd go
was hitchhiking. I'd go 7
was hitchhiking. I'd go 7 seven77
was hitchhiking. I'd go 7 seven77 and
was hitchhiking. I'd go 7 seven77 and I
turn
turn around
was hitchhiking. I'd go 7 seven77 and I
turn around seven
turn around seven times
was hitchhiking. I'd go 7 seven77 and I
turn around seven times and
turn around seven times and the
was hitchhiking. I'd go 7 seven77 and I
turn around seven times and the truck
would
would stop
would stop and
would stop and pick
would stop and pick me
would stop and pick me up
would stop and pick me up hitchhiking.
All
All that
would stop and pick me up hitchhiking.
All that magic.
7*
7* 7
7* 7 that
7* 7 that would
7* 7 that would stop
7* 7 that would stop the
7* 7 that would stop the truck.
7* 7 that would stop the truck. And
7* 7 that would stop the truck. And I
was
was way
7* 7 that would stop the truck. And I
was way out
was way out in
7* 7 that would stop the truck. And I
was way out in the
was way out in the country,
7* 7 that would stop the truck. And I
was way out in the country, you
was way out in the country, you know,
and
and it
and it was
and it was 10
and it was 10 below
and it was 10 below zero.
and it was 10 below zero. And
and it was 10 below zero. And I'd
and it was 10 below zero. And I'd hear
the
the there
and it was 10 below zero. And I'd hear
the there was
the there was a
and it was 10 below zero. And I'd hear
the there was a car
the there was a car every
and it was 10 below zero. And I'd hear
the there was a car every 10
the there was a car every 10 minutes.
and it was 10 below zero. And I'd hear
the there was a car every 10 minutes. So
when
when a
when a truck
when a truck going,
when a truck going, you
when a truck going, you could
when a truck going, you could hear
when a truck going, you could hear it
coming.
coming. It
when a truck going, you could hear it
coming. It was
coming. It was exciting,
when a truck going, you could hear it
coming. It was exciting, huh?
coming. It was exciting, huh? And
when a truck going, you could hear it
coming. It was exciting, huh? And I'd
wave
wave out
wave out there
wave out there like
wave out there like this
wave out there like this hitchhacking,
you
you know,
wave out there like this hitchhacking,
you know, and
you know, and then
wave out there like this hitchhacking,
you know, and then I'd
you know, and then I'd hear
wave out there like this hitchhacking,
you know, and then I'd hear him
you know, and then I'd hear him hit
wave out there like this hitchhacking,
you know, and then I'd hear him hit the
air
air brakes.
Soon
Soon as
air brakes.
Soon as I
Soon as I hit
air brakes.
Soon as I hit those,
Soon as I hit those, heard
air brakes.
Soon as I hit those, heard those
Soon as I hit those, heard those hair
brakes,
brakes, I
brakes, I knew
brakes, I knew I
brakes, I knew I had
brakes, I knew I had a
brakes, I knew I had a ride.
brakes, I knew I had a ride. You
brakes, I knew I had a ride. You know,
it
it was
brakes, I knew I had a ride. You know,
it was great.
What
What we
What we know
What we know about
What we know about kinesiologic
What we know about kinesiologic test
then
then is
What we know about kinesiologic test
then is that
then is that it's
What we know about kinesiologic test
then is that it's limited
then is that it's limited to
What we know about kinesiologic test
then is that it's limited to certain
people
people probably
people probably for
people probably for certain
people probably for certain reasons.
people probably for certain reasons. You
know,
know, there's
people probably for certain reasons. You
know, there's many
know, there's many other
people probably for certain reasons. You
know, there's many other ways
know, there's many other ways to
people probably for certain reasons. You
know, there's many other ways to find
out
out the
out the truth.
out the truth. You
out the truth. You begin
out the truth. You begin to
out the truth. You begin to realize
out the truth. You begin to realize that
the
the truth
out the truth. You begin to realize that
the truth is
the truth is that
out the truth. You begin to realize that
the truth is that which
the truth is that which brings
out the truth. You begin to realize that
the truth is that which brings you
the truth is that which brings you love
and
and happiness,
and happiness, and
and happiness, and anything
and happiness, and anything else
and happiness, and anything else is
facious.
facious. Um
there's
there's probably
there's probably some
there's probably some other
there's probably some other way
there's probably some other way we're
going
going to
there's probably some other way we're
going to be
going to be able
there's probably some other way we're
going to be able to
going to be able to uh
uh
uh substitute
uh substitute for
uh substitute for people
uh substitute for people who
uh substitute for people who are
uh substitute for people who are not
themselves
themselves adept
uh substitute for people who are not
themselves adept at
themselves adept at it.
How
How do
How do you
How do you uh
How do you uh handle
How do you uh handle people
How do you uh handle people that
How do you uh handle people that are
How do you uh handle people that are in
your
your life
How do you uh handle people that are in
your life that
your life that are
How do you uh handle people that are in
your life that are non-intigorous?
Uh
Uh well,
Uh well, Jesus
Uh well, Jesus said
Uh well, Jesus said to
Uh well, Jesus said to avoid
Uh well, Jesus said to avoid them.
uh
uh you
Uh well, Jesus said to avoid them.
uh you join
uh you join any
Uh well, Jesus said to avoid them.
uh you join any serious
uh you join any serious spiritual
Uh well, Jesus said to avoid them.
uh you join any serious spiritual order,
they're
they're going
they're going to
they're going to tell
they're going to tell you
they're going to tell you you're
they're going to tell you you're going
to
to have
they're going to tell you you're going
to have to
to have to leave
they're going to tell you you're going
to have to leave them.
Uh
Uh what
Uh what if
Uh what if you
Uh what if you have
Uh what if you have to
Uh what if you have to work
Uh what if you have to work with
Uh what if you have to work with them?
If
If you
Uh what if you have to work with them?
If you have
If you have to
Uh what if you have to work with them?
If you have to work
If you have to work with
Uh what if you have to work with them?
If you have to work with them,
then
then you
then you are
then you are coming
then you are coming from
then you are coming from a
then you are coming from a certain
specific
specific role,
then you are coming from a certain
specific role, a
specific role, a certain
then you are coming from a certain
specific role, a certain archetype.
You're
You're coming
You're coming from
You're coming from the
You're coming from the healer.
That's
That's different
than
than having
than having an
than having an affair
than having an affair with
than having an affair with them.
That's
That's what
than having an affair with them.
That's what the
That's what the affairs
than having an affair with them.
That's what the affairs of
That's what the affairs of patients
than having an affair with them.
That's what the affairs of patients say.
All
All right,
All right, let's
All right, let's see.
All right, let's see. The
All right, let's see. The healer
All right, let's see. The healer is
protected
protected by
All right, let's see. The healer is
protected by the
protected by the archetype,
All right, let's see. The healer is
protected by the archetype, by
protected by the archetype, by the
All right, let's see. The healer is
protected by the archetype, by the role
of
of the
of the healer
of the healer from
of the healer from being
of the healer from being damaged
of the healer from being damaged by
of the healer from being damaged by the
patient
patient resist.
Yet,
Yet, there
Yet, there are
Yet, there are some
Yet, there are some patients
Yet, there are some patients that
Yet, there are some patients that um
Thank
Thank you.
>> I
>> I was
>> I was going
>> I was going to
>> I was going to ask
>> I was going to ask a
>> I was going to ask a question.
>> I was going to ask a question. I
>> I was going to ask a question. I changed
my
my mind.
>> I was going to ask a question. I changed
my mind. Yeah,
>> I
>> I myself
>> I myself have
>> I myself have stopped
>> I myself have stopped taking
>> I myself have stopped taking patients
>> I myself have stopped taking patients of
a
a certain
>> I myself have stopped taking patients of
a certain calibrated
a certain calibrated role
>> I myself have stopped taking patients of
a certain calibrated role and
a certain calibrated role and frankly
>> I myself have stopped taking patients of
a certain calibrated role and frankly we
test
test them
test them out
test them out between
test them out between before
test them out between before kinesiology
before
before I
test them out between before kinesiology
before I even
before I even call
test them out between before kinesiology
before I even call them
before I even call them back
test them out between before kinesiology
before I even call them back and
uh
it's
it's just
uh
it's just it's
it's just it's an
uh
it's just it's an unwillingness
it's just it's an unwillingness on
uh
it's just it's an unwillingness on my
part
part anymore
part anymore to
part anymore to deal
part anymore to deal with
part anymore to deal with what
part anymore to deal with what I've
dealt
dealt with
part anymore to deal with what I've
dealt with for
dealt with for so
part anymore to deal with what I've
dealt with for so many
dealt with for so many years
and
and that's
and that's just
and that's just a
and that's just a personal
and that's just a personal choice
but
but that's
and that's just a personal choice
but that's exactly
but that's exactly what
and that's just a personal choice
but that's exactly what we
but that's exactly what we do.
and that's just a personal choice
but that's exactly what we do. We
but that's exactly what we do. We check
them
them out.
them out. So
them out. So and
them out. So and so
them out. So and so wants
them out. So and so wants his
appointment.
appointment. I
them out. So and so wants his
appointment. I check
appointment. I check him
them out. So and so wants his
appointment. I check him out
appointment. I check him out of
them out. So and so wants his
appointment. I check him out of there.
No.
No. Okay.
No. Okay. I
No. Okay. I don't
No. Okay. I don't ask
No. Okay. I don't ask why.
No. Okay. I don't ask why. I
No. Okay. I don't ask why. I just
No. Okay. I don't ask why. I just assume
that
that God's
No. Okay. I don't ask why. I just assume
that God's will
that God's will for
No. Okay. I don't ask why. I just assume
that God's will for me
that God's will for me is
No. Okay. I don't ask why. I just assume
that God's will for me is that
that God's will for me is that this
No. Okay. I don't ask why. I just assume
that God's will for me is that this is
not
not the
not the kind
not the kind of
not the kind of person
not the kind of person that
not the kind of person that I
not the kind of person that I should
probably
probably spend
not the kind of person that I should
probably spend time
probably spend time with.
Uh
these
these various
Uh
these various states
these various states of
Uh
these various states of consciousness
are
are we
are we are
are we are there
are we are there are
are we are there are their
are we are there are their own
are we are there are their own reality.
They
They are
are we are there are their own reality.
They are their
They are their own
are we are there are their own reality.
They are their own reality.
on
on an
on an experiential
on an experiential basis.
The
The experience
on an experiential basis.
The experience of
The experience of hell
on an experiential basis.
The experience of hell is
The experience of hell is extremely
hellish.
These
These are
hellish.
These are all
These are all different
hellish.
These are all different levels
These are all different levels of
consciousness.
Each
Each one
consciousness.
Each one is
Each one is valid
consciousness.
Each one is valid within
Each one is valid within its
consciousness.
Each one is valid within its own
Each one is valid within its own domain.
Each
Each one
Each one is
Each one is valid
Each one is valid within
Each one is valid within itself.
the
the teachings
Each one is valid within itself.
the teachings of
the teachings of all
Each one is valid within itself.
the teachings of all the
the teachings of all the great
Each one is valid within itself.
the teachings of all the great teachers.
You
You know
You know what
You know what Jesus
You know what Jesus taught
You know what Jesus taught was
avoid
avoid anything
You know what Jesus taught was
avoid anything that
avoid anything that calibrates
You know what Jesus taught was
avoid anything that calibrates below
200.
200. That's
200. That's all
200. That's all he
200. That's all he said,
right?
right? That's
200. That's all he said,
right? That's all
right? That's all he
200. That's all he said,
right? That's all he said.
And
And traditionally,
And traditionally, it's
And traditionally, it's called
And traditionally, it's called sin.
But
But it
And traditionally, it's called sin.
But it really
But it really is
And traditionally, it's called sin.
But it really is just
But it really is just everything
And traditionally, it's called sin.
But it really is just everything under
200.
200. Greed,
200. Greed, avarice,
200. Greed, avarice, malice,
200. Greed, avarice, malice, hatred,
all
all these
200. Greed, avarice, malice, hatred,
all these things.
all these things. He
200. Greed, avarice, malice, hatred,
all these things. He said
all these things. He said avoid
200. Greed, avarice, malice, hatred,
all these things. He said avoid all
all these things. He said avoid all that
because
because if
because if you
because if you hang
because if you hang out
because if you hang out in
because if you hang out in it
because if you hang out in it when
because if you hang out in it when you
leave
leave the
because if you hang out in it when you
leave the body
leave the body you
because if you hang out in it when you
leave the body you will
leave the body you will go
because if you hang out in it when you
leave the body you will go to
leave the body you will go to the
because if you hang out in it when you
leave the body you will go to the realm
that
that calibrates
that calibrates at
that calibrates at that
that calibrates at that level.
You
You will
that calibrates at that level.
You will go
You will go to
that calibrates at that level.
You will go to the
You will go to the realm
like
like a
like a cork
like a cork in
like a cork in water
like a cork in water is
like a cork in water is the
like a cork in water is the way
like a cork in water is the way I
like a cork in water is the way I said.
You
You don't
like a cork in water is the way I said.
You don't have
You don't have to
like a cork in water is the way I said.
You don't have to worry
You don't have to worry about
like a cork in water is the way I said.
You don't have to worry about what
happens
happens to
happens to your
happens to your soul,
happens to your soul, at least
happens to your soul, at least the
happens to your soul, at least the body,
because
because it's
happens to your soul, at least the body,
because it's like
because it's like a
happens to your soul, at least the body,
because it's like a cork
because it's like a cork in
happens to your soul, at least the body,
because it's like a cork in water.
because it's like a cork in water. And
because
because of
because of the
because of the absolute
because of the absolute justice
because of the absolute justice of
because of the absolute justice of all
of
of creation,
because of the absolute justice of all
of creation, it
of creation, it will
because of the absolute justice of all
of creation, it will automatically
gravitate
gravitate to
gravitate to that
gravitate to that to
gravitate to that to which
gravitate to that to which it
gravitate to that to which it is
aligned.
It
It will
It will automatically
It will automatically gravitate
It will automatically gravitate to
It will automatically gravitate to that
which
which is
It will automatically gravitate to that
which is aligned.
which is aligned. There
It will automatically gravitate to that
which is aligned. There is
which is aligned. There is nothing
arbitrary
arbitrary going
arbitrary going on
arbitrary going on in
arbitrary going on in the
arbitrary going on in the universe.
arbitrary going on in the universe. Huh?
There's
There's nothing
arbitrary going on in the universe. Huh?
There's nothing arbitrary.
The
The justice
The justice of
The justice of God
The justice of God is
The justice of God is absolute,
infinite,
infinite, and
The justice of God is absolute,
infinite, and impeccable.
infinite, and impeccable. Each
The justice of God is absolute,
infinite, and impeccable. Each thing
only
only experiences
out
out of
only experiences
out of its
out of its own
spiritual
spiritual decisions
spiritual decisions that
spiritual decisions that which
spiritual decisions that which it
spiritual decisions that which it has
chosen.
Having
Having experienced
Having experienced that,
Having experienced that, it
Having experienced that, it may
Having experienced that, it may change
its
its mind.
and
and how
in
in the
and how
in the pit
in the pit of
and how
in the pit of hell
in the pit of hell I
and how
in the pit of hell I said
if
if there
if there is
if there is a
if there is a god
if there is a god I
if there is a god I ask
if there is a god I ask him
if there is a god I ask him for
if there is a god I ask him for help
that
that was
if there is a god I ask him for help
that was when
that was when the
if there is a god I ask him for help
that was when the last
that was when the last possible
anythingness
was
was removed
when
when you
when you see
when you see that
when you see that hell
when you see that hell goes
when you see that hell goes on
when you see that hell goes on for
eternity
eternity forever
when you see that hell goes on for
eternity forever without
eternity forever without any
when you see that hell goes on for
eternity forever without any possibility
under
under any
under any circumstance
under any circumstance of
under any circumstance of escaping
under any circumstance of escaping from
it.
There
There goes
There goes your
There goes your last
card
card of
There goes your last
card of this
card of this week.
Then
Then he
Then he took
Then he took that
Then he took that before
Then he took that before you
Then he took that before you said
Then he took that before you said if
there
there is
Then he took that before you said if
there is a
there is a god
Then he took that before you said if
there is a god I
there is a god I ask
Then he took that before you said if
there is a god I ask him
there is a god I ask him to
Then he took that before you said if
there is a god I ask him to help
there is a god I ask him to help me.
And
And then
And then to
And then to the
And then to the opposite
And then to the opposite end
And then to the opposite end of
And then to the opposite end of the
spectrum.
So
So each
So each is
So each is its
So each is its reality
So each is its reality on
So each is its reality on its
So each is its reality on its own
So each is its reality on its own level.
The
The spectacular
So each is its reality on its own level.
The spectacular presence,
The spectacular presence, the
So each is its reality on its own level.
The spectacular presence, the infinite
realization.
It's
It's like
realization.
It's like God
It's like God pres
realization.
It's like God pres It's
It's like God pres It's not
realization.
It's like God pres It's not like
It's like God pres It's not like like
God
God presents
God presents its
God presents its divinity
God presents its divinity to
God presents its divinity to you.
God presents its divinity to you. It
isn't
isn't that
God presents its divinity to you. It
isn't that you
isn't that you seek
God presents its divinity to you. It
isn't that you seek it.
isn't that you seek it. It
God presents its divinity to you. It
isn't that you seek it. It shines
isn't that you seek it. It shines forth
and
and stares
and stares at
and stares at you
and stares at you and
and stares at you and like
and stares at you and like a
and stares at you and like a shock.
and stares at you and like a shock. You
realize
realize it.
and stares at you and like a shock. You
realize it. You
realize it. You realize
and stares at you and like a shock. You
realize it. You realize what
realize it. You realize what it
and stares at you and like a shock. You
realize it. You realize what it is
you're
you're looking
you're looking at.
So
So each
you're looking at.
So each thing
So each thing is
you're looking at.
So each thing is what
So each thing is what it
you're looking at.
So each thing is what it is
So each thing is what it is on
you're looking at.
So each thing is what it is on its
So each thing is what it is on its own
level.
Uh
Uh now
level.
Uh now to
Uh now to call
level.
Uh now to call it
Uh now to call it say
level.
Uh now to call it say that
Uh now to call it say that is
level.
Uh now to call it say that is an
illusion
illusion leaves.
illusion leaves. See
illusion leaves. See the
illusion leaves. See the question
illusion leaves. See the question is
illusion leaves. See the question is is
there
there hell
illusion leaves. See the question is is
there hell or
there hell or is
illusion leaves. See the question is is
there hell or is there
there hell or is there only
illusion leaves. See the question is is
there hell or is there only illusion
there hell or is there only illusion of
the
the ego?
the ego? Any
the ego? Any condition
the ego? Any condition can
the ego? Any condition can be
the ego? Any condition can be defined.
You
You see
the ego? Any condition can be defined.
You see these
You see these different
the ego? Any condition can be defined.
You see these different points
You see these different points of
the ego? Any condition can be defined.
You see these different points of view
experientially
experientially it
experientially it was
experientially it was as
experientially it was as real
experientially it was as real or
experientially it was as real or more
more
more real
experientially it was as real or more
more real than
more real than anything
experientially it was as real or more
more real than anything I'd
more real than anything I'd ever
experienced
experienced in
experienced in my
experienced in my life.
hopeless,
hopeless, endless
experienced in my life.
hopeless, endless agony
hopeless, endless agony that
experienced in my life.
hopeless, endless agony that went
hopeless, endless agony that went on
experienced in my life.
hopeless, endless agony that went on for
eons.
That
That certainly
eons.
That certainly would
That certainly would knock
eons.
That certainly would knock out
That certainly would knock out any
questions
questions about
questions about whether
questions about whether there
questions about whether there is
questions about whether there is a
questions about whether there is a hell.
Guess
Guess that
questions about whether there is a hell.
Guess that answered
Guess that answered that
questions about whether there is a hell.
Guess that answered that question,
didn't
didn't it,
didn't it, boy?
didn't it, boy? Yeah.
All right.
All right. So,
didn't it, boy? Yeah.
All right. So, we
All right. So, we don't
didn't it, boy? Yeah.
All right. So, we don't want
All right. So, we don't want to
challenge
challenge hell,
challenge hell, folks.
challenge hell, folks. It's
challenge hell, folks. It's just
challenge hell, folks. It's just not
challenge hell, folks. It's just not a
good
good thing.
Um,
Um, the
Um, the level
Um, the level of
Um, the level of consciousness
Um, the level of consciousness of
mankind
mankind is
Um, the level of consciousness of
mankind is still
mankind is still 107
Um, the level of consciousness of
mankind is still 107 108
mankind is still 107 108 108,
Um, the level of consciousness of
mankind is still 107 108 108, right?
Okay.
>> I'm
>> I'm 20.
>> I
>> I mean
>> I mean 208.
>> I mean 208. I
>> I mean 208. I keep
>> I mean 208. I keep saying
>> I mean 208. I keep saying that.
>> I mean 208. I keep saying that. I'm
>> I mean 208. I keep saying that. I'm so
>> uh
>> uh Anyway,
>> I mean 208. I keep saying that. I'm so
>> uh Anyway, I'm
>> uh Anyway, I'm very
>> I mean 208. I keep saying that. I'm so
>> uh Anyway, I'm very uh
it's
it's a
it's a little
it's a little hard
it's a little hard being
it's a little hard being with
it's a little hard being with the
it's a little hard being with the world
this
this morning.
it's a little hard being with the world
this morning. Anyway,
this morning. Anyway, I'm
it's a little hard being with the world
this morning. Anyway, I'm doing
this morning. Anyway, I'm doing pretty
good.
Uh
Uh the
good.
Uh the consciousness
Uh the consciousness level
good.
Uh the consciousness level of
Uh the consciousness level of mankind.
good.
Uh the consciousness level of mankind. I
don't
don't think
don't think I
don't think I explained
don't think I explained that
don't think I explained that correctly
enough
enough or
don't think I explained that correctly
enough or well
enough or well enough
don't think I explained that correctly
enough or well enough in
enough or well enough in the
don't think I explained that correctly
enough or well enough in the book.
The
The average
The average average
The average average for
The average average for mankind
The average average for mankind as
The average average for mankind as a
whole
whole per
The average average for mankind as a
whole per generation
whole per generation is
The average average for mankind as a
whole per generation is about
whole per generation is about five
points.
points. That's
points. That's an
points. That's an answer
points. That's an answer I
points. That's an answer I get
points. That's an answer I get with
kinesiology.
kinesiology. It's
points. That's an answer I get with
kinesiology. It's not
kinesiology. It's not a
points. That's an answer I get with
kinesiology. It's not a mathematical
derivation.
derivation. See,
people
people individually
derivation. See,
people individually however
people individually however can
derivation. See,
people individually however can make
enormous
enormous jumps
enormous jumps of
enormous jumps of hundreds
enormous jumps of hundreds of
enormous jumps of hundreds of points
enormous jumps of hundreds of points in
one
one lifetime.
enormous jumps of hundreds of points in
one lifetime. In
one lifetime. In fact,
enormous jumps of hundreds of points in
one lifetime. In fact, in
one lifetime. In fact, in one
enormous jumps of hundreds of points in
one lifetime. In fact, in one instant,
probably
probably from
probably from minus
probably from minus 50,000,
probably from minus 50,000, I
probably from minus 50,000, I went
probably from minus 50,000, I went up
probably from minus 50,000, I went up to
like
like probably
probably from minus 50,000, I went up to
like probably it
like probably it was
probably from minus 50,000, I went up to
like probably it was 700
like probably it was 700 or
probably from minus 50,000, I went up to
like probably it was 700 or 800,
like probably it was 700 or 800, you
probably from minus 50,000, I went up to
like probably it was 700 or 800, you can
jump
jump hundreds
jump hundreds of
jump hundreds of points.
Uh,
Uh, and
jump hundreds of points.
Uh, and people
Uh, and people do
jump hundreds of points.
Uh, and people do it
Uh, and people do it all
jump hundreds of points.
Uh, and people do it all the
Uh, and people do it all the time.
jump hundreds of points.
Uh, and people do it all the time. I
mean,
mean, in
mean, in these
mean, in these lectures,
mean, in these lectures, people
mean, in these lectures, people jump
hundreds
hundreds of
mean, in these lectures, people jump
hundreds of points
hundreds of points very
mean, in these lectures, people jump
hundreds of points very often.
hundreds of points very often. The
average
average for
average for the
average for the whole,
average for the whole, however,
let's
let's say
average for the whole, however,
let's say for
let's say for a
average for the whole, however,
let's say for a lecture
let's say for a lecture is
average for the whole, however,
let's say for a lecture is around
let's say for a lecture is around 10
average for the whole, however,
let's say for a lecture is around 10 or
15,
15, something
15, something like
15, something like that.
15, something like that. That's
15, something like that. That's the
average.
See,
See, faster
See, faster is
See, faster is not
See, faster is not better.
See, faster is not better. Faster
See, faster is not better. Faster is
See, faster is not better. Faster is not
better.
better. Many
See, faster is not better. Faster is not
better. Many of
better. Many of these
See, faster is not better. Faster is not
better. Many of these leaps
better. Many of these leaps leave
See, faster is not better. Faster is not
better. Many of these leaps leave you
completely
completely disorganized.
completely disorganized. It
completely disorganized. It takes
completely disorganized. It takes you
couple
couple years
completely disorganized. It takes you
couple years to
couple years to get
completely disorganized. It takes you
couple years to get re
couple years to get re re,
completely disorganized. It takes you
couple years to get re re, you
couple years to get re re, you know,
reestablished.
reestablished. I
reestablished. I mean,
reestablished. I mean, just,
reestablished. I mean, just, you
reestablished. I mean, just, you know,
the
the higher
reestablished. I mean, just, you know,
the higher levels
the higher levels of
reestablished. I mean, just, you know,
the higher levels of love
the higher levels of love knock
reestablished. I mean, just, you know,
the higher levels of love knock you
the higher levels of love knock you out.
You
You know,
You know, it's
You know, it's very
You know, it's very hard
You know, it's very hard to
You know, it's very hard to function.
Everything
Everything you
You know, it's very hard to function.
Everything you see
Everything you see is
blisses
blisses you
blisses you out.
You're
You're walking
blisses you out.
You're walking around
You're walking around like
blisses you out.
You're walking around like in
You're walking around like in the
blisses you out.
You're walking around like in the days,
you
you know,
you know, you
you know, you will
you know, you will think,
you know, you will think, "Oh,
you know, you will think, "Oh, for
you know, you will think, "Oh, for a
while
while people
you know, you will think, "Oh, for a
while people thought
while people thought I
you know, you will think, "Oh, for a
while people thought I was
while people thought I was high
you know, you will think, "Oh, for a
while people thought I was high on
something."
something." You
something." You know,
something." You know, they
something." You know, they said,
something." You know, they said, "Man,
he's
he's really
something." You know, they said, "Man,
he's really high
he's really high on
something." You know, they said, "Man,
he's really high on something."
he's really high on something." You
know,
know, by
know, by the
know, by the time
know, by the time I
know, by the time I left
know, by the time I left the
know, by the time I left the east,
know, by the time I left the east, you
know,
know, by
know, by the time I left the east, you
know, by the
know, by the time
know, by the time I left the east, you
know, by the time I
know, by the time I left
know, by the time I left the east, you
know, by the time I left the
know, by the time I left the east,
everybody
everybody thought
everybody thought he
everybody thought he must
everybody thought he must be
everybody thought he must be high
everybody thought he must be high on
something.
something. You
everybody thought he must be high on
something. You know,
something. You know, I
everybody thought he must be high on
something. You know, I was
something. You know, I was all
everybody thought he must be high on
something. You know, I was all right.
something. You know, I was all right. If
I
I told
I told them
I told them what
I told them what it
I told them what it really
I told them what it really was,
I told them what it really was, they
would
would have
I told them what it really was, they
would have thought
would have thought I
I told them what it really was, they
would have thought I was
would have thought I was really
I told them what it really was, they
would have thought I was really crazy.
So,
So, I
So, I didn't
So, I didn't tell
So, I didn't tell them.
The
The presence
So, I didn't tell them.
The presence of
The presence of God
So, I didn't tell them.
The presence of God is
The presence of God is really
uh
uh intoxicating.
that
that all
uh intoxicating.
that all my
that all my colleagues
uh intoxicating.
that all my colleagues would
that all my colleagues would have
uh intoxicating.
that all my colleagues would have really
thought
thought I'd
thought I'd lost
thought I'd lost it.
These
These inner
thought I'd lost it.
These inner states,
These inner states, there's
thought I'd lost it.
These inner states, there's not
These inner states, there's not many
people
people in
people in the
people in the world
people in the world that
people in the world that will
people in the world that will understand
them.
them. And
people in the world that will understand
them. And that's
them. And that's the
people in the world that will understand
them. And that's the value
them. And that's the value of
people in the world that will understand
them. And that's the value of a
spiritual
spiritual community
spiritual community as
spiritual community as well.
spiritual community as well. Other
people
people have
spiritual community as well. Other
people have had
people have had these
spiritual community as well. Other
people have had these states
people have had these states and
spiritual community as well. Other
people have had these states and they
know
know what
know what it
know what it is
know what it is where
know what it is where you
know what it is where you can't
know what it is where you can't stop
crying
crying for
know what it is where you can't stop
crying for a
crying for a couple
know what it is where you can't stop
crying for a couple years.
crying for a couple years. You
know what it is where you can't stop
crying for a couple years. You know,
everything
everything you
everything you look
everything you look at
everything you look at um
everything you look at um there's
certain
certain music
everything you look at um there's
certain music uh
certain music uh I
everything you look at um there's
certain music uh I don't
certain music uh I don't know
everything you look at um there's
certain music uh I don't know how
certain music uh I don't know how you
would
would not
would not be
would not be able
would not be able to
would not be able to uh
would not be able to uh function
would not be able to uh function and
listen
listen to
would not be able to uh function and
listen to that
listen to that music.
would not be able to uh function and
listen to that music. There's
listen to that music. There's one
would not be able to uh function and
listen to that music. There's one piece
piece
piece Brock
piece Brock put
piece Brock put a
piece Brock put a piece
piece Brock put a piece of
piece Brock put a piece of music
piece Brock put a piece of music at
piece Brock put a piece of music at the
end
end of
piece Brock put a piece of music at the
end of this
end of this Amna
piece Brock put a piece of music at the
end of this Amna Shiva
end of this Amna Shiva tape
piece Brock put a piece of music at the
end of this Amna Shiva tape and
end of this Amna Shiva tape and uh
piece Brock put a piece of music at the
end of this Amna Shiva tape and uh uh
end of this Amna Shiva tape and uh uh if
I'm
I'm going
I'm going to
I'm going to function
I'm going to function I
I'm going to function I have
I'm going to function I have to
I'm going to function I have to get
I'm going to function I have to get out
of
of the
I'm going to function I have to get out
of the room
of the room because
I'm going to function I have to get out
of the room because it's
of the room because it's beauty
I'm going to function I have to get out
of the room because it's beauty is
of the room because it's beauty is just
paralyzing.
paralyzing. You
paralyzing. You just
paralyzing. You just can't
paralyzing. You just can't move.
paralyzing. You just can't move. So
paralyzing. You just can't move. So you
have
have to
paralyzing. You just can't move. So you
have to get
have to get used
paralyzing. You just can't move. So you
have to get used to
have to get used to these
paralyzing. You just can't move. So you
have to get used to these states
have to get used to these states learn
how
how to
how to function.
how to function. The
how to function. The next
how to function. The next lecture
how to function. The next lecture I'm
going
going to
how to function. The next lecture I'm
going to have
going to have to
how to function. The next lecture I'm
going to have to learn
going to have to learn how
how to function. The next lecture I'm
going to have to learn how do
going to have to learn how do you
how to function. The next lecture I'm
going to have to learn how do you talk
about
about that
about that which
about that which paralyzes
about that which paralyzes you
about that which paralyzes you with
exquisite
bliss.
How
How do
bliss.
How do you
How do you talk
bliss.
How do you talk about
How do you talk about it?
At
At the
At the same
At the same time
At the same time you're
At the same time you're experiencing
At the same time you're experiencing I
don't
don't know
At the same time you're experiencing I
don't know find
don't know find out
At the same time you're experiencing I
don't know find out next
don't know find out next time.
At the same time you're experiencing I
don't know find out next time. I
don't know find out next time. I have
idea
idea how
idea how it'll
idea how it'll happen.
So
So most
idea how it'll happen.
So most human
So most human humans
idea how it'll happen.
So most human humans then
So most human humans then there's
idea how it'll happen.
So most human humans then there's no
limit
limit to
limit to the
limit to the level
limit to the level at
limit to the level at which
limit to the level at which your
consciousness
consciousness can
limit to the level at which your
consciousness can leap.
consciousness can leap. There
limit to the level at which your
consciousness can leap. There are
certainly
certainly karmic
certainly karmic influences.
The
The most
certainly karmic influences.
The most intense
The most intense thing
certainly karmic influences.
The most intense thing is
The most intense thing is the
willingness
willingness to
willingness to surrender
willingness to surrender to
willingness to surrender to God
willingness to surrender to God at
extreme
extreme depth.
Extreme
Extreme depths.
Extreme depths. And
Extreme depths. And perhaps
Extreme depths. And perhaps what
Extreme depths. And perhaps what was
shocking
shocking in
Extreme depths. And perhaps what was
shocking in the
shocking in the evolution
Extreme depths. And perhaps what was
shocking in the evolution of
shocking in the evolution of this
consciousness
consciousness was
consciousness was the
consciousness was the the
consciousness was the the degree
consciousness was the the degree of
consciousness was the the degree of the
depths
depths to
consciousness was the the degree of the
depths to which
depths to which it
consciousness was the the degree of the
depths to which it had
depths to which it had to
consciousness was the the degree of the
depths to which it had to go.
depths to which it had to go. It
consciousness was the the degree of the
depths to which it had to go. It was
depths to which it had to go. It was u
beyond
beyond all
beyond all imagination
beyond all imagination to
beyond all imagination to have
beyond all imagination to have to
beyond all imagination to have to have
to
to go
beyond all imagination to have to have
to go to
to go to that
beyond all imagination to have to have
to go to that depth
to go to that depth to
beyond all imagination to have to have
to go to that depth to let
to go to that depth to let go
beyond all imagination to have to have
to go to that depth to let go of
whatever
whatever that
whatever that blockage
whatever that blockage was.
whatever that blockage was. I
whatever that blockage was. I never
whatever that blockage was. I never went
back
back and
whatever that blockage was. I never went
back and checked
back and checked out
whatever that blockage was. I never went
back and checked out with
back and checked out with kinesiology
what
what was
what was the
what was the blockage
what was the blockage that
what was the blockage that made
what was the blockage that made it
what was the blockage that made it so
uh
uh necessary
what was the blockage that made it so
uh necessary to
uh necessary to go
what was the blockage that made it so
uh necessary to go to
uh necessary to go to such
what was the blockage that made it so
uh necessary to go to such a
uh necessary to go to such a great
depth.
depth. you
depth. you know,
depth. you know, hitting
depth. you know, hitting bottom.
depth. you know, hitting bottom. How,
you
you know,
depth. you know, hitting bottom. How,
you know, how
you know, how deep
depth. you know, hitting bottom. How,
you know, how deep does
you know, how deep does the
depth. you know, hitting bottom. How,
you know, how deep does the bottom
you know, how deep does the bottom have
to
to be?
to be? I
to be? I mean,
to be? I mean, and
to be? I mean, and yet
to be? I mean, and yet we
to be? I mean, and yet we see
to be? I mean, and yet we see it
to be? I mean, and yet we see it every
day.
day. People
to be? I mean, and yet we see it every
day. People who've
day. People who've lost
to be? I mean, and yet we see it every
day. People who've lost everything.
They've
They've had
They've had a,
They've had a, you
They've had a, you know,
They've had a, you know, I
They've had a, you know, I see
They've had a, you know, I see people
They've had a, you know, I see people at
the
the counseling
They've had a, you know, I see people at
the counseling center.
the counseling center. He's
They've had a, you know, I see people at
the counseling center. He's been
the counseling center. He's been five
times
times in
times in prison
times in prison now.
times in prison now. His
times in prison now. His wife
times in prison now. His wife has
times in prison now. His wife has left
him.
him. His
times in prison now. His wife has left
him. His children
him. His children have
times in prison now. His wife has left
him. His children have left
him. His children have left him.
times in prison now. His wife has left
him. His children have left him. His
health
health is
health is gone.
health is gone. He's
health is gone. He's got
health is gone. He's got all
health is gone. He's got all kinds
health is gone. He's got all kinds of
charges
charges hanging
health is gone. He's got all kinds of
charges hanging over
charges hanging over him.
health is gone. He's got all kinds of
charges hanging over him. And
charges hanging over him. And he
health is gone. He's got all kinds of
charges hanging over him. And he sits
there
there and
there and he
there and he says,
there and he says, "I
there and he says, "I don't
there and he says, "I don't have
there and he says, "I don't have a
problem
problem with
there and he says, "I don't have a
problem with alcohol."
And
And you
And you go,
And you go, "What
And you go, "What does
And you go, "What does it
And you go, "What does it take,
And you go, "What does it take, man?
What
What does
And you go, "What does it take, man?
What does it
What does it take?"
And you go, "What does it take, man?
What does it take?" You
What does it take?" You know,
And you go, "What does it take, man?
What does it take?" You know, we
What does it take?" You know, we have
And you go, "What does it take, man?
What does it take?" You know, we have to
chop
chop off
chop off each
chop off each finger
chop off each finger one
chop off each finger one by
chop off each finger one by one.
chop off each finger one by one. Get
chop off each finger one by one. Get to
toe
toe number
chop off each finger one by one. Get to
toe number eight
toe number eight before
chop off each finger one by one. Get to
toe number eight before he
toe number eight before he says,
chop off each finger one by one. Get to
toe number eight before he says, "Yeah,
I
I got
I got a
I got a problem
I got a problem with
I got a problem with alcohol."
I got a problem with alcohol." What
I got a problem with alcohol." What is
it
it going
I got a problem with alcohol." What is
it going to
it going to take?
I got a problem with alcohol." What is
it going to take? I
it going to take? I don't
I got a problem with alcohol." What is
it going to take? I don't know.
it going to take? I don't know. The
unmanifest
unmanifest has
unmanifest has within
unmanifest has within it
the
the quality,
unmanifest has within it
the quality, the
the quality, the potentiality
of
of becoming
manifest.
Now
Now the
Now the question
Now the question really
Now the question really is
Now the question really is is
Now the question really is is what
Now the question really is is what moves
divinity
divinity from
Now the question really is is what moves
divinity from the
divinity from the unmanifest
Now the question really is is what moves
divinity from the unmanifest to
divinity from the unmanifest to the
manifest?
I
I don't
manifest?
I don't know.
Amusement
Amusement maybe.
Nothing
Nothing more
Amusement maybe.
Nothing more comical
Nothing more comical than
Amusement maybe.
Nothing more comical than the
Nothing more comical than the human
race.
race. Huh?
I
I think
race. Huh?
I think I'm
I think I'm bored.
race. Huh?
I think I'm bored. I
I think I'm bored. I think
race. Huh?
I think I'm bored. I think I'll
I think I'm bored. I think I'll make
mankind
mankind sit
mankind sit back
mankind sit back and
mankind sit back and it's
mankind sit back and it's like
mankind sit back and it's like watching
his
his animal
mankind sit back and it's like watching
his animal channel.
his animal channel. Huh?
Can
Can a
Can a person
Can a person go
Can a person go down
Can a person go down in
Can a person go down in consciousness?
Yes.
Yes. Unfortunately,
people
people can.
people can. It
people can. It happens
people can. It happens to
people can. It happens to spiritual
teachers
teachers very
people can. It happens to spiritual
teachers very often.
Very
Very often,
Very often, you
Very often, you see
Very often, you see they
Very often, you see they write
Very often, you see they write a
Very often, you see they write a book
Very often, you see they write a book up
here
here five00s
and
and then
and then you
and then you check
and then you check them
and then you check them out
and then you check them out years
and then you check them out years later
and
and you
and then you check them out years later
and you find
and you find that
and then you check them out years later
and you find that they
and you find that they calibrate
and then you check them out years later
and you find that they calibrate at
and you find that they calibrate at one.
Where
Where do
Where do they
Where do they calibrate?
Where do they calibrate? Down
Where do they calibrate? Down here
someplace.
Uh
Uh so
Uh so that
Uh so that which
Uh so that which begins
Uh so that which begins to
Uh so that which begins to have
Uh so that which begins to have an
impact
impact and
Uh so that which begins to have an
impact and dispel
impact and dispel negativity
Uh so that which begins to have an
impact and dispel negativity begins
impact and dispel negativity begins to
you
you might
you might say
you might say a
you might say a power
you might say a power struggle
you might say a power struggle between
uh
uh for
you might say a power struggle between
uh for dominion
uh for dominion over
you might say a power struggle between
uh for dominion over man.
If
If a
If a person's
If a person's evolution
If a person's evolution of
If a person's evolution of their
consciousness
consciousness gets
If a person's evolution of their
consciousness gets high
consciousness gets high enough,
If a person's evolution of their
consciousness gets high enough, it
begins
begins to
begins to threaten
begins to threaten the
begins to threaten the dominance
begins to threaten the dominance of
negativity
who
who which
who which then
who which then fights
who which then fights back
and
and says
having
having sex
having sex with
having sex with your
having sex with your devotees
having sex with your devotees is
having sex with your devotees is a
having sex with your devotees is a way
of
of blessing
having sex with your devotees is a way
of blessing them
of blessing them and
having sex with your devotees is a way
of blessing them and sharing
of blessing them and sharing God's
exquisite
exquisite presence
exquisite presence as
exquisite presence as love.
>> Next
>> Next thing
exquisite presence as love.
>> Next thing you
>> Next thing you know,
exquisite presence as love.
>> Next thing you know, the
>> Next thing you know, the guru
exquisite presence as love.
>> Next thing you know, the guru is
>> Next thing you know, the guru is on
exquisite presence as love.
>> Next thing you know, the guru is on the
other
other tape
other tape internet.
other tape internet. He's
other tape internet. He's having
other tape internet. He's having sex
with
with this
other tape internet. He's having sex
with this person,
with this person, that
other tape internet. He's having sex
with this person, that person.
Wealth
Wealth is
Wealth is an
Wealth is an expression
Wealth is an expression of
Wealth is an expression of God's
abundance.
Accumulate
Accumulate the
Accumulate the millions.
Accumulate the millions. You
Accumulate the millions. You know what
Accumulate the millions. You know what I
mean?
mean? They
Accumulate the millions. You know what I
mean? They fall.
mean? They fall. And
Accumulate the millions. You know what I
mean? They fall. And we've
mean? They fall. And we've already
expressed
expressed that
expressed that in
expressed that in previous
expressed that in previous things.
expressed that in previous things. Each
one
one when
expressed that in previous things. Each
one when you
one when you sort
expressed that in previous things. Each
one when you sort of
one when you sort of get
expressed that in previous things. Each
one when you sort of get to
one when you sort of get to a
expressed that in previous things. Each
one when you sort of get to a certain
level,
level, it's
level, it's like
level, it's like the
level, it's like the test
level, it's like the test of
level, it's like the test of its
opposite
opposite comes
level, it's like the test of its
opposite comes up.
It's
It's like
It's like the
It's like the test
It's like the test of
It's like the test of fame,
It's like the test of fame, fortune,
power
power over
It's like the test of fame, fortune,
power over others,
power over others, glamour,
It's like the test of fame, fortune,
power over others, glamour, falling
power over others, glamour, falling for
your
your own
your own publicity.
your own publicity. Those
your own publicity. Those are
your own publicity. Those are all
your own publicity. Those are all the
dangers.
dangers. So
your own publicity. Those are all the
dangers. So there
dangers. So there could
your own publicity. Those are all the
dangers. So there could be
dangers. So there could be a
your own publicity. Those are all the
dangers. So there could be a in
the
the armor.
the armor. You
the armor. You see,
the armor. You see, that's
the armor. You see, that's where
something
something non-integrous
the armor. You see, that's where
something non-integrous allowed
something non-integrous allowed some
entity
entity or
entity or energy
entity or energy to
entity or energy to come
entity or energy to come in.
And
nobody
nobody except
nobody except people
nobody except people who
nobody except people who are
nobody except people who are like
students
students in
nobody except people who are like
students in these
students in these classes
to
to my
to my knowledge
to my knowledge are
to my knowledge are sufficiently
to my knowledge are sufficiently warned
in
in advance
to my knowledge are sufficiently warned
in advance of
in advance of what's
to my knowledge are sufficiently warned
in advance of what's going
in advance of what's going to
to my knowledge are sufficiently warned
in advance of what's going to come
in advance of what's going to come up
and
and how
and how it's
and how it's going
and how it's going to
and how it's going to come
and how it's going to come up
and how it's going to come up and
and how it's going to come up and how
and how it's going to come up and how to
look
look at
and how it's going to come up and how to
look at it
look at it and
and how it's going to come up and how to
look at it and what's
look at it and what's out
and how it's going to come up and how to
look at it and what's out about
look at it and what's out about it.
and how it's going to come up and how to
look at it and what's out about it. And
what's
what's out
what's out about
what's out about it
what's out about it is
what's out about it is that
what's out about it is that the
what's out about it is that the context
is
is out
what's out about it is that the context
is out about
is out about it.
what's out about it is that the context
is out about it. Content
is out about it. Content only.
what's out about it is that the context
is out about it. Content only. The
luciferic
luciferic is
luciferic is very
luciferic is very very very
luciferic is very very very clever.
It
It can
luciferic is very very very clever.
It can present
It can present something
luciferic is very very very clever.
It can present something so
It can present something so convincingly
that
that you're
that you're sure
that you're sure that
that you're sure that Jesus
that you're sure that Jesus himself
would
would agree
that you're sure that Jesus himself
would agree with
would agree with it.
Some
Some knowingness
Some knowingness somewhere
warns
warns you
and
and then
and then as
and then as you
and then as you refuse
and then as you refuse the
and then as you refuse the temptation
the
the context
and then as you refuse the temptation
the context shines
the context shines forth
and then as you refuse the temptation
the context shines forth and
the context shines forth and you
and then as you refuse the temptation
the context shines forth and you see
what
what the
what the error
what the error was.
what the error was. The
what the error was. The error
what the error was. The error is
what the error was. The error is one
what the error was. The error is one of
context.
context. I
what the error was. The error is one of
context. I remember
context. I remember in
what the error was. The error is one of
context. I remember in this
context. I remember in this lifetime
what the error was. The error is one of
context. I remember in this lifetime the
luciferic
luciferic coming
luciferic coming up
and
and it
luciferic coming up
and it was
and it was the
luciferic coming up
and it was the same
and it was the same luciferic
luciferic coming up
and it was the same luciferic sentence
that
that I've
that I've seen
that I've seen other
that I've seen other gurus
that I've seen other gurus and
that I've seen other gurus and in
that I've seen other gurus and in fact
some
some of
that I've seen other gurus and in fact
some of them
some of them I've
that I've seen other gurus and in fact
some of them I've met
some of them I've met they
that I've seen other gurus and in fact
some of them I've met they fell
some of them I've met they fell for
that I've seen other gurus and in fact
some of them I've met they fell for the
exact
exact phrase
exact phrase I
exact phrase I recognized
exact phrase I recognized the
exact phrase I recognized the phrase
exact phrase I recognized the phrase and
I
I know
exact phrase I recognized the phrase and
I know what
I know what phrase
exact phrase I recognized the phrase and
I know what phrase it
I know what phrase it was
exact phrase I recognized the phrase and
I know what phrase it was and
I know what phrase it was and how
exact phrase I recognized the phrase and
I know what phrase it was and how it
came
came up
came up now
came up now that
came up now that you're
came up now that you're beyond
came up now that you're beyond personal
karma
karma karma
came up now that you're beyond personal
karma karma and
karma karma and there
came up now that you're beyond personal
karma karma and there is
karma karma and there is no
came up now that you're beyond personal
karma karma and there is no wrathful
karma karma and there is no wrathful god
to
to answer
to answer for
all
all power
to answer for
all power is
all power is yours
to answer for
all power is yours own
And
And that's
And that's where
And that's where they
And that's where they fall.
I
I was
And that's where they fall.
I was all
I was all by
And that's where they fall.
I was all by myself.
I was all by myself. It's
And that's where they fall.
I was all by myself. It's like
I was all by myself. It's like you're
all
all alone
all alone on
all alone on a
all alone on a I
all alone on a I don't
all alone on a I don't know
all alone on a I don't know what
all alone on a I don't know what level
of
of consciousness
all alone on a I don't know what level
of consciousness that
of consciousness that comes
all alone on a I don't know what level
of consciousness that comes in
of consciousness that comes in at.
all alone on a I don't know what level
of consciousness that comes in at. Uh
but
but it's
but it's sort
but it's sort of
but it's sort of retaining
but it's sort of retaining it
but it's sort of retaining it comes
but it's sort of retaining it comes in.
And
the
the error
the error there
the error there is
the error there is you
the error there is you may
the error there is you may be
the error there is you may be beyond
personal
personal karma,
the error there is you may be beyond
personal karma, but
personal karma, but you
the error there is you may be beyond
personal karma, but you are
personal karma, but you are not
the error there is you may be beyond
personal karma, but you are not beyond
the
the karma
of
of the
the karma
of the presence
of the presence of
the karma
of the presence of God
of the presence of God as
the karma
of the presence of God as the
of the presence of God as the totality
of
of the
of the universe.
You
You may
of the universe.
You may be
You may be on
of the universe.
You may be on your
You may be on your personal
of the universe.
You may be on your personal crap
You may be on your personal crap from
previous
previous lifetimes,
previous lifetimes, but
previous lifetimes, but you
previous lifetimes, but you sure
previous lifetimes, but you sure as
previous lifetimes, but you sure as are
not
not beyond
previous lifetimes, but you sure as are
not beyond the
not beyond the infinite
previous lifetimes, but you sure as are
not beyond the infinite justice
not beyond the infinite justice of
previous lifetimes, but you sure as are
not beyond the infinite justice of God,
which
which is
which is infinite.
But
But the
which is infinite.
But the temptation
But the temptation is
which is infinite.
But the temptation is now
But the temptation is now that
which is infinite.
But the temptation is now that you've
transcended
transcended personal
transcended personal karma,
transcended personal karma, which
transcended personal karma, which at
that
that point
transcended personal karma, which at
that point you
that point you have,
transcended personal karma, which at
that point you have, that
that point you have, that you're
transcended personal karma, which at
that point you have, that you're sub
subject
subject to
subject to being
subject to being a
subject to being a consciousness
within
within the
subject to being a consciousness
within the domain
within the domain of
subject to being a consciousness
within the domain of the
within the domain of the reality
subject to being a consciousness
within the domain of the reality of
within the domain of the reality of the
infinity
infinity of
infinity of the
infinity of the allness
infinity of the allness of
infinity of the allness of God
infinity of the allness of God himself.
So,
So, and
infinity of the allness of God himself.
So, and besides
So, and besides these
infinity of the allness of God himself.
So, and besides these temptations
So, and besides these temptations come
up
up and
up and what
up and what do
up and what do they
up and what do they want
up and what do they want to
up and what do they want to give
up and what do they want to give you?
Power.
I
I came
I came up
I came up with
I came up with that.
I came up with that. What
I came up with that. What do
I came up with that. What do I
I came up with that. What do I want
power
power for?
I came up with that. What do I want
power for? Power
power for? Power for
I came up with that. What do I want
power for? Power for what?
All
All power
All power is
All power is yours.
All power is yours. Own
All power is yours. Own it.
All power is yours. Own it. All
All power is yours. Own it. All you're
doing
doing is
All power is yours. Own it. All you're
doing is validating
doing is validating your
All power is yours. Own it. All you're
doing is validating your own
doing is validating your own divinity.
Very
Very convincing.
If
If you
Very convincing.
If you can
If you can manifest
Very convincing.
If you can manifest abundantly,
If you can manifest abundantly, have
Very convincing.
If you can manifest abundantly, have 90
Mercedes
Mercedes Benzes
Mercedes Benzes or
Mercedes Benzes or whatever.
very
very appealing.
Mercedes Benzes or whatever.
very appealing. If
very appealing. If you're
Mercedes Benzes or whatever.
very appealing. If you're beyond
very appealing. If you're beyond sin,
why
why not
why not have
why not have sex
why not have sex with
why not have sex with dozens,
right?
All right.
So,
So, it
All right.
So, it comes
So, it comes on
All right.
So, it comes on in
So, it comes on in a
All right.
So, it comes on in a very
So, it comes on in a very convincing
All right.
So, it comes on in a very convincing way
except
except that
except that the
except that the context
context
context is
except that the context
context is facious.
context is facious. The
except that the context
context is facious. The error
context is facious. The error is
except that the context
context is facious. The error is one
context is facious. The error is one of
context.
context. So
context. So the
context. So the spiritually
context. So the spiritually naive
context. So the spiritually naive person
has
has evolved
context. So the spiritually naive person
has evolved as
has evolved as far
context. So the spiritually naive person
has evolved as far as
has evolved as far as content,
context. So the spiritually naive person
has evolved as far as content, but
has evolved as far as content, but their
understanding
understanding of
understanding of context
understanding of context hasn't
understanding of context hasn't expanded
enough
enough to
understanding of context hasn't expanded
enough to fortify
enough to fortify them
understanding of context hasn't expanded
enough to fortify them against
enough to fortify them against that
temptation.
What
What would
temptation.
What would you
What would you want
temptation.
What would you want power
What would you want power for?
temptation.
What would you want power for? I
What would you want power for? I mean,
it's
it's a
it's a drag.
it's a drag. It's
it's a drag. It's like
it's a drag. It's like money.
it's a drag. It's like money. It's
it's a drag. It's like money. It's the
more
more you
it's a drag. It's like money. It's the
more you own,
more you own, the
it's a drag. It's like money. It's the
more you own, the more
more you own, the more horrible
it's a drag. It's like money. It's the
more you own, the more horrible it
more you own, the more horrible it is.
You
You know
You know what
You know what I'm
You know what I'm saying?
You know what I'm saying? You
You know what I'm saying? You got
You know what I'm saying? You got a
You know what I'm saying? You got a bad
life
life of
You know what I'm saying? You got a bad
life of one
life of one car,
You know what I'm saying? You got a bad
life of one car, it's
life of one car, it's going
You know what I'm saying? You got a bad
life of one car, it's going to
life of one car, it's going to get
You know what I'm saying? You got a bad
life of one car, it's going to get worse
at
at two.
at two. Get
at two. Get up
at two. Get up to
at two. Get up to four.
Right
Right now,
at two. Get up to four.
Right now, we
Right now, we have
at two. Get up to four.
Right now, we have four
Right now, we have four or
at two. Get up to four.
Right now, we have four or five.
Right now, we have four or five. I
at two. Get up to four.
Right now, we have four or five. I think
it's
it's it's
it's it's horrible.
it's it's horrible. We're
it's it's horrible. We're going
it's it's horrible. We're going to
it's it's horrible. We're going to It's
horrible.
horrible. It's
it's it's horrible. We're going to It's
horrible. It's really
horrible. It's really awful.
it's it's horrible. We're going to It's
horrible. It's really awful. You
horrible. It's really awful. You got
it's it's horrible. We're going to It's
horrible. It's really awful. You got all
these
these dependent.
these dependent. It's
these dependent. It's like
these dependent. It's like a
these dependent. It's like a bunch
these dependent. It's like a bunch of
dependence
dependence that
these dependent. It's like a bunch of
dependence that you
dependence that you got
these dependent. It's like a bunch of
dependence that you got to
dependence that you got to take
these dependent. It's like a bunch of
dependence that you got to take care
dependence that you got to take care of.
You
You know,
You know, everything
You know, everything you
You know, everything you own
You know, everything you own now
You know, everything you own now becomes
like
like a
You know, everything you own now becomes
like a chain
like a chain that
You know, everything you own now becomes
like a chain that owns
like a chain that owns you.
You know, everything you own now becomes
like a chain that owns you. You
like a chain that owns you. You know,
You know, everything you own now becomes
like a chain that owns you. You know, I
mean,
so
so why
mean,
so why would
so why would you
mean,
so why would you want
so why would you want power
mean,
so why would you want power and
so why would you want power and wealth
and
and all
and all those?
and all those? All
and all those? All right.
Uh
Uh but
and all those? All right.
Uh but that
Uh but that is
and all those? All right.
Uh but that is a
Uh but that is a convincing
and all those? All right.
Uh but that is a convincing kind.
Uh but that is a convincing kind. So,
and all those? All right.
Uh but that is a convincing kind. So, as
we
we go
we go up,
we go up, we're
we go up, we're tempted
we go up, we're tempted by
we go up, we're tempted by um
we go up, we're tempted by um we're
we're
we're tempted
we go up, we're tempted by um we're
we're tempted by
we're tempted by chinks
we go up, we're tempted by um we're
we're tempted by chinks in
we're tempted by chinks in our
we go up, we're tempted by um we're
we're tempted by chinks in our armor.
we're tempted by chinks in our armor. We
have
have to
have to become
have to become really
have to become really quite
have to become really quite ariodite
have to become really quite ariodite and
quite
quite sophisticated
have to become really quite ariodite and
quite sophisticated to
quite sophisticated to survive
spiritually.
As
As you
spiritually.
As you get
As you get up
spiritually.
As you get up to
As you get up to lovingness,
spiritually.
As you get up to lovingness, the
challenges
challenges are
challenges are going
challenges are going to
challenges are going to come
challenges are going to come up.
challenges are going to come up. You
know,
know, challenges
challenges are going to come up. You
know, challenges are
know, challenges are going
challenges are going to come up. You
know, challenges are going to
know, challenges are going to come
challenges are going to come up. You
know, challenges are going to come up.
And
And finally,
And finally, you
And finally, you come
And finally, you come up
And finally, you come up to
And finally, you come up to a
And finally, you come up to a point
where
where you
And finally, you come up to a point
where you say,
where you say, "I
And finally, you come up to a point
where you say, "I love
where you say, "I love you.
And finally, you come up to a point
where you say, "I love you. I
where you say, "I love you. I love
And finally, you come up to a point
where you say, "I love you. I love you.
And
And you
And you must
And you must leave
And you must leave by
And you must leave by tomorrow
And you must leave by tomorrow or
And you must leave by tomorrow or I'll
call
call the
And you must leave by tomorrow or I'll
call the sheriff."
It
It isn't
It isn't I
It isn't I don't
It isn't I don't love
It isn't I don't love the
It isn't I don't love the person.
It isn't I don't love the person. That's
the
the problem.
It isn't I don't love the person. That's
the problem. The
the problem. The problem
It isn't I don't love the person. That's
the problem. The problem is
the problem. The problem is that
It isn't I don't love the person. That's
the problem. The problem is that I
the problem. The problem is that I love
the
the person.
the person. That
the person. That is
the person. That is the
the person. That is the problem.
The
The problem
the person. That is the problem.
The problem is
The problem is I
the person. That is the problem.
The problem is I see
The problem is I see the
the person. That is the problem.
The problem is I see the innate
The problem is I see the innate in
innocence.
innocence. The
innocence. The person
innocence. The person doesn't
innocence. The person doesn't know
better.
better. Can
innocence. The person doesn't know
better. Can a
better. Can a psychopath
innocence. The person doesn't know
better. Can a psychopath help
better. Can a psychopath help being
innocence. The person doesn't know
better. Can a psychopath help being a
psychopath?
psychopath? I
psychopath? I don't
psychopath? I don't think
psychopath? I don't think so.
psychopath? I don't think so. I
psychopath? I don't think so. I think
there's
there's something
psychopath? I don't think so. I think
there's something in
there's something in the
psychopath? I don't think so. I think
there's something in the pre
there's something in the pre current
science
science shows
science shows that
science shows that the
science shows that the frontal
science shows that the frontal lobe,
frontal
frontal cortex.
science shows that the frontal lobe,
frontal cortex. There's
frontal cortex. There's deficiency
science shows that the frontal lobe,
frontal cortex. There's deficiency in
the
the psychopath.
It
It shows
the psychopath.
It shows up
It shows up at
the psychopath.
It shows up at age
It shows up at age 1
the psychopath.
It shows up at age 1 and
It shows up at age 1 and a
the psychopath.
It shows up at age 1 and a half,
It shows up at age 1 and a half, age
three,
three, no
three, no capacity,
three, no capacity, delay
three, no capacity, delay gratification,
impulsivity,
impulsivity, all
three, no capacity, delay gratification,
impulsivity, all these
impulsivity, all these things
three, no capacity, delay gratification,
impulsivity, all these things in
impulsivity, all these things in this,
you
you know.
you know. So
now
now getting
you know. So
now getting rid
now getting rid of
you know. So
now getting rid of that
now getting rid of that which
you know. So
now getting rid of that which you
now getting rid of that which you love
that's
that's what's
that's what's hard
because
because it's
that's what's hard
because it's now
because it's now required.
that's what's hard
because it's now required. It's
because it's now required. It's an
exercise
exercise you
exercise you learn
exercise you learn how
exercise you learn how to
exercise you learn how to do.
exercise you learn how to do. You
exercise you learn how to do. You let
you
you go
exercise you learn how to do. You let
you go your
you go your attachment
exercise you learn how to do. You let
you go your attachment to
you go your attachment to that
exercise you learn how to do. You let
you go your attachment to that person,
that
that relative,
that car,
that car, that
that relative,
that car, that spouse,
that car, that spouse, whatever
that relative,
that car, that spouse, whatever it
that car, that spouse, whatever it is,
you're
you're not
you're not going
you're not going to
you're not going to reach
you're not going to reach a
you're not going to reach a great
you're not going to reach a great deal
of
of enlightenment
you're not going to reach a great deal
of enlightenment if
of enlightenment if this
you're not going to reach a great deal
of enlightenment if this person
of enlightenment if this person keeps
pulling
pulling you
pulling you back
pulling you back into
pulling you back into this
pulling you back into this energy
pulling you back into this energy field
over
over and
pulling you back into this energy field
over and over
over and over and
pulling you back into this energy field
over and over and over
over and over and over again.
pulling you back into this energy field
over and over and over again. All right?
So
So that's
So that's it.
So that's it. We
So that's it. We um
So that's it. We um the
So that's it. We um the demand
So that's it. We um the demand becomes
different
different as
So that's it. We um the demand becomes
different as you
different as you progress
So that's it. We um the demand becomes
different as you progress spiritually.
You
You progress
You progress in
You progress in from
You progress in from spiritual
You progress in from spiritual naivity
that
that stops
You progress in from spiritual naivity
that stops at
that stops at every
You progress in from spiritual naivity
that stops at every street
that stops at every street corner
You progress in from spiritual naivity
that stops at every street corner for
that stops at every street corner for a
psychic
psychic reading
psychic reading and
psychic reading and you
psychic reading and you go
psychic reading and you go through
naivity
naivity and
psychic reading and you go through
naivity and then
naivity and then through
psychic reading and you go through
naivity and then through often
naivity and then through often painful
experiences
you
you develop
experiences
you develop spiritual
you develop spiritual maturity.
experiences
you develop spiritual maturity. You
don't
don't become
don't become a
don't become a spiritual
don't become a spiritual you
don't become a spiritual you don't
don't become a spiritual you don't own
your
your own
don't become a spiritual you don't own
your own spiritual
your own spiritual mastery
don't become a spiritual you don't own
your own spiritual mastery from
your own spiritual mastery from the
level
level of
level of naivity.
you
you know,
oh,
oh, do
oh, do I
oh, do I believe
oh, do I believe the
oh, do I believe the US
oh, do I believe the US has
oh, do I believe the US has the
oh, do I believe the US has the right
oh, do I believe the US has the right to
determine
determine outcomes
oh, do I believe the US has the right to
determine outcomes of
determine outcomes of conflicts
oh, do I believe the US has the right to
determine outcomes of conflicts in
determine outcomes of conflicts in other
countries?
countries? And
countries? And what
countries? And what would
countries? And what would God
countries? And what would God say?
countries? And what would God say? Well,
I
I asked
countries? And what would God say? Well,
I asked them
I asked them the
countries? And what would God say? Well,
I asked them the the
I asked them the the other
countries? And what would God say? Well,
I asked them the the other day,
I asked them the the other day, in
countries? And what would God say? Well,
I asked them the the other day, in fact,
just
just this
just this very
just this very question.
And
And to
just this very question.
And to me,
And to me, that
just this very question.
And to me, that situation
And to me, that situation is
just this very question.
And to me, that situation is people
working
working their
working their way
working their way out
working their way out of
working their way out of the
working their way out of the 70s.
We're
We're we're
working their way out of the 70s.
We're we're talking
We're we're talking about
working their way out of the 70s.
We're we're talking about people
We're we're talking about people caught
in
in the
in the spleen.
in the spleen. See,
so
so it's
in the spleen. See,
so it's like
so it's like an
in the spleen. See,
so it's like an astral
so it's like an astral dimension
in the spleen. See,
so it's like an astral dimension that's
manifesting
manifesting on
manifesting on this
manifesting on this physical
manifesting on this physical universe.
Nobody
Nobody there
manifesting on this physical universe.
Nobody there is
Nobody there is interested
manifesting on this physical universe.
Nobody there is interested in
Nobody there is interested in peace.
manifesting on this physical universe.
Nobody there is interested in peace. In
fact,
fact, the
fact, the biggest
fact, the biggest enemies
fact, the biggest enemies they
fact, the biggest enemies they have
fact, the biggest enemies they have or
peace.
peace. If
fact, the biggest enemies they have or
peace. If you
peace. If you get
fact, the biggest enemies they have or
peace. If you get out
peace. If you get out there
fact, the biggest enemies they have or
peace. If you get out there and
peace. If you get out there and shout
about
about peace,
about peace, they
about peace, they assassinate
about peace, they assassinate you.
You're
You're a
about peace, they assassinate you.
You're a threat
You're a threat to
about peace, they assassinate you.
You're a threat to everything.
You're a threat to everything. Their
whole
whole lifestyle
whole lifestyle is
whole lifestyle is under
whole lifestyle is under threat.
whole lifestyle is under threat. What
would
would they
whole lifestyle is under threat. What
would they want
would they want peace
whole lifestyle is under threat. What
would they want peace for?
would they want peace for? Uh
whole lifestyle is under threat. What
would they want peace for? Uh you
would they want peace for? Uh you know,
in
in a
in a prize
in a prize fight,
in a prize fight, you
in a prize fight, you want
in a prize fight, you want they
in a prize fight, you want they want
somebody
somebody come
in a prize fight, you want they want
somebody come up
somebody come up and
in a prize fight, you want they want
somebody come up and say,
somebody come up and say, "Stop
in a prize fight, you want they want
somebody come up and say, "Stop hitting
each
each I
each I mean
each I mean the
each I mean the price
each I mean the price point
each I mean the price point for
each I mean the price point for it.
That's
That's what
each I mean the price point for it.
That's what it's
That's what it's about,
each I mean the price point for it.
That's what it's about, isn't
That's what it's about, isn't it?
Because
these
these are
Because
these are people
these are people that
Because
these are people that are
these are people that are evolving
their
their calibrated
their calibrated that
their calibrated that calibrated
their calibrated that calibrated level
of
of consciousness
their calibrated that calibrated level
of consciousness of
of consciousness of that
their calibrated that calibrated level
of consciousness of that conflict.
of consciousness of that conflict. Let's
just
just do
just do it
just do it and
just do it and then
just do it and then be
just do it and then be done
just do it and then be done with
just do it and then be done with the
sub.
sub. We
just do it and then be done with the
sub. We have
sub. We have permission
just do it and then be done with the
sub. We have permission to
sub. We have permission to do
just do it and then be done with the
sub. We have permission to do that
conflict
conflict is
conflict is just
conflict is just it's
conflict is just it's over
conflict is just it's over 70.
conflict is just it's over 70. It's
conflict is just it's over 70. It's over
80.
It's
It's along
It's along it's
It's along it's around
It's along it's around about
It's along it's around about the
It's along it's around about the level
of
uh
uh the
uh the reptile
uh the reptile 70
uh the reptile 70 savage
uh the reptile 70 savage hatred
uh the reptile 70 savage hatred evil
uh the reptile 70 savage hatred evil the
spleen.
spleen. So
uh the reptile 70 savage hatred evil the
spleen. So they're
spleen. So they're living
uh the reptile 70 savage hatred evil the
spleen. So they're living out
spleen. So they're living out the
uh the reptile 70 savage hatred evil the
spleen. So they're living out the world
of
of the
of the spleen.
So
So you
of the spleen.
So you don't
So you don't transcend
of the spleen.
So you don't transcend the
So you don't transcend the spleen
of the spleen.
So you don't transcend the spleen until
you
you evolve
you evolve past
you evolve past the
you evolve past the spleen.
you evolve past the spleen. So
you evolve past the spleen. So I
you evolve past the spleen. So I suppose
there's
there's some
you evolve past the spleen. So I suppose
there's some lifetime
there's some lifetime in
you evolve past the spleen. So I suppose
there's some lifetime in which
there's some lifetime in which you've
got
got to
got to be
got to be very
got to be very splenic.
got to be very splenic. You
got to be very splenic. You got
got to be very splenic. You got to
got to be very splenic. You got to learn
how
how to
got to be very splenic. You got to learn
how to hate,
how to hate, learn
got to be very splenic. You got to learn
how to hate, learn how
how to hate, learn how to
got to be very splenic. You got to learn
how to hate, learn how to kill.
So
So I
So I just
So I just wouldn't
So I just wouldn't vacation
So I just wouldn't vacation there.
So I just wouldn't vacation there. The
holy
holy lands
So I just wouldn't vacation there. The
holy lands are
holy lands are not
So I just wouldn't vacation there. The
holy lands are not too
holy lands are not too good.
I
I think
I think in
I think in the
I think in the book
I think in the book we
I think in the book we said
I think in the book we said the
I think in the book we said the holy
lands
lands cal
I think in the book we said the holy
lands cal rate
lands cal rate about
I think in the book we said the holy
lands cal rate about 90.
Everybody
Everybody go
Everybody go back
Everybody go back wants
Everybody go back wants a
Everybody go back wants a pilgrimage
Everybody go back wants a pilgrimage to
the
the holy
Everybody go back wants a pilgrimage to
the holy lands
the holy lands which
Everybody go back wants a pilgrimage to
the holy lands which is
the holy lands which is about
Everybody go back wants a pilgrimage to
the holy lands which is about 90.
The
The uh
The uh Empire
The uh Empire State
The uh Empire State Building
The uh Empire State Building calibrates
at
at 425.
The uh Empire State Building calibrates
at 425. So
at 425. So if
The uh Empire State Building calibrates
at 425. So if you
at 425. So if you want
The uh Empire State Building calibrates
at 425. So if you want to
at 425. So if you want to go
The uh Empire State Building calibrates
at 425. So if you want to go to
at 425. So if you want to go to a
The uh Empire State Building calibrates
at 425. So if you want to go to a holy
place
place to
place to meditate,
place to meditate, I
place to meditate, I suggest
and
and the
place to meditate, I suggest
and the 8
and the 8 102nd
place to meditate, I suggest
and the 8 102nd floor
and the 8 102nd floor for
place to meditate, I suggest
and the 8 102nd floor for some
and the 8 102nd floor for some reason
calibrates
calibrates higher
calibrates higher than
calibrates higher than the
calibrates higher than the 86th
calibrates higher than the 86th floor.
The
The 86th
calibrates higher than the 86th floor.
The 86th floor
The 86th floor of
calibrates higher than the 86th floor.
The 86th floor of the
The 86th floor of the Empire
calibrates higher than the 86th floor.
The 86th floor of the Empire State
Building
Building is
Building is where
Building is where most
Building is where most people
Building is where most people get
Building is where most people get out.
Then
Then there's
Building is where most people get out.
Then there's a
Then there's a little
Building is where most people get out.
Then there's a little tiny
Then there's a little tiny elevator.
Building is where most people get out.
Then there's a little tiny elevator. If
you
you want
you want to
you want to you
you want to you can
you want to you can go
you want to you can go up
you want to you can go up 102
you want to you can go up 102 to
you want to you can go up 102 to 102.
For
For some
you want to you can go up 102 to 102.
For some reason
For some reason that
you want to you can go up 102 to 102.
For some reason that calibrates
For some reason that calibrates about
you want to you can go up 102 to 102.
For some reason that calibrates about 20
points
points higher.
points higher. I
points higher. I don't
points higher. I don't know
points higher. I don't know why
points higher. I don't know why but
points higher. I don't know why but it
does.
Robert
Robert less
Robert less idiots
Robert less idiots less
Robert less idiots less cowards
Robert less idiots less cowards up
Robert less idiots less cowards up there
only.
only. Who
Robert less idiots less cowards up there
only. Who knows
only. Who knows what
Robert less idiots less cowards up there
only. Who knows what it
only. Who knows what it is.
Robert less idiots less cowards up there
only. Who knows what it is. I
only. Who knows what it is. I don't
know.
know. So,
know. So, what
know. So, what are
know. So, what are the
know. So, what are the best
know. So, what are the best ways
know. So, what are the best ways to
know. So, what are the best ways to heal
shame?
shame? Shame,
know. So, what are the best ways to heal
shame? Shame, uh,
shame? Shame, uh, I'm
know. So, what are the best ways to heal
shame? Shame, uh, I'm glad
shame? Shame, uh, I'm glad that
know. So, what are the best ways to heal
shame? Shame, uh, I'm glad that somebody
asked
asked me
asked me that
asked me that because
asked me that because that
asked me that because that is
asked me that because that is a
asked me that because that is a tough
one
one until
asked me that because that is a tough
one until you
one until you recontextualize
asked me that because that is a tough
one until you recontextualize it.
one until you recontextualize it. Shame
is
is really
is really vanity.
is really vanity. Pride.
Shame
Shame is
is really vanity. Pride.
Shame is pride
Shame is pride projected
is really vanity. Pride.
Shame is pride projected onto
Shame is pride projected onto society
and
and then
and then visit
and then visit it
and then visit it back
and then visit it back upon
and then visit it back upon yourself.
You
You let
and then visit it back upon yourself.
You let go
You let go the
and then visit it back upon yourself.
You let go the pridefulness
and
and own
and own that
and own that being
and own that being a
and own that being a human
and own that being a human lead
and own that being a human lead you
and own that being a human lead you to
be
be fallible.
It's
It's okay
It's okay to
It's okay to be
It's okay to be stupid,
It's okay to be stupid, make
It's okay to be stupid, make terrible
mistakes.
mistakes. It's
It's okay to be stupid, make terrible
mistakes. It's inevitable.
mistakes. It's inevitable. How
It's okay to be stupid, make terrible
mistakes. It's inevitable. How can
mistakes. It's inevitable. How can you
not
not How
not How can
not How can you
not How can you evolve
not How can you evolve unless
not How can you evolve unless you
not How can you evolve unless you make
really
really bad
not How can you evolve unless you make
really bad mistakes?
really bad mistakes? Huh?
not How can you evolve unless you make
really bad mistakes? Huh? You
really bad mistakes? Huh? You can't.
So
So shame
So shame is
So shame is then
looking
looking at
So shame is then
looking at your
looking at your own
So shame is then
looking at your own behavior
looking at your own behavior from
So shame is then
looking at your own behavior from the
viewpoint
viewpoint of
viewpoint of pride.
viewpoint of pride. See,
viewpoint of pride. See, from
viewpoint of pride. See, from pride,
this
this looks
viewpoint of pride. See, from pride,
this looks like
this looks like disgraceful
viewpoint of pride. See, from pride,
this looks like disgraceful behavior.
But
But if
But if you
But if you let
But if you let go
But if you let go of
But if you let go of pride,
But if you let go of pride, it
But if you let go of pride, it looks
more
more like
But if you let go of pride, it looks
more like stupidity.
Stupidity
Stupidity is
Stupidity is innate
Stupidity is innate to
Stupidity is innate to the
Stupidity is innate to the human
condition.
Ignorance
Ignorance is
Ignorance is what
Ignorance is what we're
Ignorance is what we're all
Ignorance is what we're all born
Ignorance is what we're all born here
with.
with. We
Ignorance is what we're all born here
with. We have
we
we have
hardware
hardware computer
we have
hardware computer with
hardware computer with no
we have
hardware computer with no programs
hardware computer with no programs on
it,
it, right?
it, right? When
it, right? When we
it, right? When we get
it, right? When we get born
it, right? When we get born here.
All
All right.
it, right? When we get born here.
All right. So,
All right. So, we're
it, right? When we get born here.
All right. So, we're obviously
shame
shame is
shame is a
shame is a technique
shame is a technique used
shame is a technique used by
shame is a technique used by parents.
See,
See, it's
shame is a technique used by parents.
See, it's a
See, it's a a
shame is a technique used by parents.
See, it's a a misfortunate
See, it's a a misfortunate one.
shame is a technique used by parents.
See, it's a a misfortunate one. Shame
See, it's a a misfortunate one. Shame on
you.
you. You
you. You know,
you. You know, to
you. You know, to teach
you. You know, to teach the
you. You know, to teach the child
you. You know, to teach the child to
shame
shame oneself
you. You know, to teach the child to
shame oneself is
shame oneself is sort
you. You know, to teach the child to
shame oneself is sort of
shame oneself is sort of a
you. You know, to teach the child to
shame oneself is sort of a not
shame oneself is sort of a not not
you. You know, to teach the child to
shame oneself is sort of a not not too
great
great a
great a technique.
great a technique. And
great a technique. And uh
great a technique. And uh it's
great a technique. And uh it's good
great a technique. And uh it's good for
my
my business.
great a technique. And uh it's good for
my business. I
my business. I pres
all
all this
all this stuff
all this stuff really
all this stuff really helps
all this stuff really helps helps
all this stuff really helps helps her
with
with shame.
all this stuff really helps helps her
with shame. So
with shame. So they
all this stuff really helps helps her
with shame. So they they
with shame. So they they build
all this stuff really helps helps her
with shame. So they they build up
with shame. So they they build up my
business,
business, but
business, but it's
business, but it's not
business, but it's not really
business, but it's not really a
business, but it's not really a very
good
good technique
because
because what
because what happens
because what happens is
because what happens is we
because what happens is we make
because what happens is we make mistakes
out
out of
because what happens is we make mistakes
out of ignorance.
out of ignorance. And
because what happens is we make mistakes
out of ignorance. And what
out of ignorance. And what is
because what happens is we make mistakes
out of ignorance. And what is the
out of ignorance. And what is the why
are
are we
are we ignorant?
are we ignorant? Because
are we ignorant? Because we
are we ignorant? Because we were
are we ignorant? Because we were born
with
with a
are we ignorant? Because we were born
with a Pablo
with a Pablo Raza.
are we ignorant? Because we were born
with a Pablo Raza. We're
with a Pablo Raza. We're born
are we ignorant? Because we were born
with a Pablo Raza. We're born with
with a Pablo Raza. We're born with the
hardware
hardware of
hardware of a
hardware of a computer
hardware of a computer and
hardware of a computer and no
programming.
programming. So
hardware of a computer and no
programming. So we're
programming. So we're now
hardware of a computer and no
programming. So we're now at
programming. So we're now at the
hardware of a computer and no
programming. So we're now at the effect
we're
we're victims
we're victims of
we're victims of our
we're victims of our own
we're victims of our own programming.
That's
That's how
we're victims of our own programming.
That's how you
That's how you can
we're victims of our own programming.
That's how you can have
That's how you can have compassion
we're victims of our own programming.
That's how you can have compassion for
all
all of
all of mankind.
all of mankind. You
all of mankind. You see
all of mankind. You see that
all of mankind. You see that everyone,
every
every innocent
all of mankind. You see that everyone,
every innocent little
every innocent little bin
all of mankind. You see that everyone,
every innocent little bin Laden
every innocent little bin Laden who
all of mankind. You see that everyone,
every innocent little bin Laden who was
once
once a
once a happy
once a happy little
once a happy little baby
once a happy little baby boy
once a happy little baby boy got
programmed
programmed by
once a happy little baby boy got
programmed by all
programmed by all this
once a happy little baby boy got
programmed by all this crap.
programmed by all this crap. So
once a happy little baby boy got
programmed by all this crap. So he
programmed by all this crap. So he is
now
now the
now the victim
now the victim of
now the victim of his
now the victim of his own
now the victim of his own ego.
now the victim of his own ego. He's
now the victim of his own ego. He's the
victim
victim of
now the victim of his own ego. He's the
victim of his
victim of his own
now the victim of his own ego. He's the
victim of his own facious
victim of his own facious belief
systems.
He's
He's a
systems.
He's a victim.
Yeah.
So
So we
Yeah.
So we don't
So we don't feel
Yeah.
So we don't feel sorry
So we don't feel sorry for
Yeah.
So we don't feel sorry for him.
So we don't feel sorry for him. We
Yeah.
So we don't feel sorry for him. We don't
make
make excuses
make excuses for
make excuses for him
make excuses for him and
make excuses for him and we
make excuses for him and we avoid
make excuses for him and we avoid them.
But
But we
make excuses for him and we avoid them.
But we also
But we also see
make excuses for him and we avoid them.
But we also see that
But we also see that despite
make excuses for him and we avoid them.
But we also see that despite that
But we also see that despite that degree
of
of negativity,
of negativity, the
of negativity, the innate
of negativity, the innate innocence
of negativity, the innate innocence is
still
still there.
of negativity, the innate innocence is
still there. Otherwise,
still there. Otherwise, you
of negativity, the innate innocence is
still there. Otherwise, you couldn't
program
program them.
program them. You
program them. You couldn't
program them. You couldn't train
program them. You couldn't train all
those
those little
program them. You couldn't train all
those little children
those little children in
program them. You couldn't train all
those little children in Germany
those little children in Germany to
become
become good
become good Nazis
unless
unless they
become good Nazis
unless they were
unless they were innocent
become good Nazis
unless they were innocent and
unless they were innocent and trusting
to
to begin
to begin with.
to begin with. It
to begin with. It was
to begin with. It was their
to begin with. It was their innocence
and
and trust.
What
What comes
What comes to
What comes to my
What comes to my mind
What comes to my mind about
What comes to my mind about that
What comes to my mind about that kind
What comes to my mind about that kind of
thing
thing though
What comes to my mind about that kind of
thing though is
thing though is Jesus
What comes to my mind about that kind of
thing though is Jesus Christ
thing though is Jesus Christ said,
What comes to my mind about that kind of
thing though is Jesus Christ said, "Woe
to
to those
to those who
to those who rape
to those who rape the
to those who rape the innocent
to those who rape the innocent of
children.
children. Woe
to those who rape the innocent of
children. Woe to
children. Woe to those
to those who rape the innocent of
children. Woe to those who
children. Woe to those who abuse
to those who rape the innocent of
children. Woe to those who abuse the
innocence
innocence of
innocence of children,
innocence of children, for
innocence of children, for their
innocence of children, for their fate
innocence of children, for their fate is
pretty
pretty grim.
So
So don't
So don't the
So don't the religious
So don't the religious zealots
So don't the religious zealots who
program
program the
So don't the religious zealots who
program the innocence
program the innocence of
So don't the religious zealots who
program the innocence of children
program the innocence of children to
believe
believe such
believe such negativity?
believe such negativity? It
believe such negativity? It seems
believe such negativity? It seems to
believe such negativity? It seems to me
it's
it's rather
believe such negativity? It seems to me
it's rather karmically
it's rather karmically horrific.
believe such negativity? It seems to me
it's rather karmically horrific. It
would
would scare
would scare the
would scare the wits
would scare the wits out
would scare the wits out of
would scare the wits out of me.
would scare the wits out of me. Scare
the
the wits
would scare the wits out of me. Scare
the wits out
the wits out of
would scare the wits out of me. Scare
the wits out of me
the wits out of me to
would scare the wits out of me. Scare
the wits out of me to tell
the wits out of me to tell somebody
would scare the wits out of me. Scare
the wits out of me to tell somebody to
kill
kill somebody
kill somebody else
kill somebody else for
kill somebody else for God.
kill somebody else for God. You
kill somebody else for God. You know,
kill somebody else for God. You know, I
mean,
mean, what
kill somebody else for God. You know, I
mean, what if
mean, what if you
kill somebody else for God. You know, I
mean, what if you were
mean, what if you were wrong?
kill somebody else for God. You know, I
mean, what if you were wrong? You
what
what I
what I mean?
what I mean? Even
what I mean? Even with
what I mean? Even with kinesiology,
what I mean? Even with kinesiology, I
wouldn't
wouldn't believe
what I mean? Even with kinesiology, I
wouldn't believe it.
wouldn't believe it. You
what I mean? Even with kinesiology, I
wouldn't believe it. You know,
the
the karmic
the karmic consequence
the karmic consequence of
the karmic consequence of raping
the karmic consequence of raping the
innocence
innocence of
the karmic consequence of raping the
innocence of the
innocence of the consciousness
the karmic consequence of raping the
innocence of the consciousness of
innocence of the consciousness of the
naive
naive is
naive is the
naive is the negative
naive is the negative karma.
naive is the negative karma. Then
uh
and
and why
and why we
and why we have
and why we have to
and why we have to avoid
and why we have to avoid uh
and why we have to avoid uh that
and why we have to avoid uh that which
is
is not
and why we have to avoid uh that which
is not integrous
the
the false
the false guru.
the false guru. It
the false guru. It scares
the false guru. It scares me
the false guru. It scares me in
the false guru. It scares me in the
the false guru. It scares me in the name
of
of God
the false guru. It scares me in the name
of God to
of God to teach
the false guru. It scares me in the name
of God to teach people
of God to teach people to
the false guru. It scares me in the name
of God to teach people to do
of God to teach people to do that
the false guru. It scares me in the name
of God to teach people to do that which
is
is non-integrous
is non-integrous and
is non-integrous and rationalize
is non-integrous and rationalize it
is non-integrous and rationalize it with
some
high
high sounding
high sounding thing
high sounding thing is
high sounding thing is not
high sounding thing is not too
high sounding thing is not too good.
The
The good
high sounding thing is not too good.
The good of
The good of dreams.
high sounding thing is not too good.
The good of dreams. What
The good of dreams. What is
high sounding thing is not too good.
The good of dreams. What is the
The good of dreams. What is the dream
state?
state? I
state? I am
state? I am not
state? I am not an
state? I am not an expert
state? I am not an expert on
state? I am not an expert on dreams.
I've
I've never
state? I am not an expert on dreams.
I've never trusted
I've never trusted dreams.
I
I once
I once when
I once when I
I once when I was
I once when I was a
I once when I was a in
I once when I was a in psychoanalytic
training
training wrote
I once when I was a in psychoanalytic
training wrote a
training wrote a reputation
I once when I was a in psychoanalytic
training wrote a reputation or
training wrote a reputation or refu
I once when I was a in psychoanalytic
training wrote a reputation or refu I
refuted
refuted Freud's
refuted Freud's theory
refuted Freud's theory of
refuted Freud's theory of of
refuted Freud's theory of of dreams.
refuted Freud's theory of of dreams. You
know
I
I thought
to
to me
I thought
to me dream
to me dream dreams
I thought
to me dream dreams are
to me dream dreams are are
I thought
to me dream dreams are are an
to me dream dreams are are an automatic
consequence
consequence of
consequence of the
consequence of the brain
consequence of the brain clearing
consequence of the brain clearing itself
at
at the
consequence of the brain clearing itself
at the end
at the end of
consequence of the brain clearing itself
at the end of the
at the end of the day.
consequence of the brain clearing itself
at the end of the day. However,
at the end of the day. However, its
value
value in
value in psychoanalysis
value in psychoanalysis is
value in psychoanalysis is that
value in psychoanalysis is that it
value in psychoanalysis is that it acts
like
like a
value in psychoanalysis is that it acts
like a roarshock
like a roarshock card.
value in psychoanalysis is that it acts
like a roarshock card. In
like a roarshock card. In other
value in psychoanalysis is that it acts
like a roarshock card. In other words,
even
even if
even if your
even if your dream
even if your dream was
even if your dream was created
even if your dream was created by
even if your dream was created by a
mechanical
mechanical dream
even if your dream was created by a
mechanical dream generator
mechanical dream generator and
even if your dream was created by a
mechanical dream generator and then
mechanical dream generator and then we
hypnotize
hypnotize you
hypnotize you and
hypnotize you and say
hypnotize you and say that
hypnotize you and say that was
hypnotize you and say that was your
dream,
dream, you
hypnotize you and say that was your
dream, you say,
dream, you say, "Well,
hypnotize you and say that was your
dream, you say, "Well, what
dream, you say, "Well, what does
hypnotize you and say that was your
dream, you say, "Well, what does a
giraffe
giraffe remind
giraffe remind you
giraffe remind you of?"
giraffe remind you of?" We
giraffe remind you of?" We would
giraffe remind you of?" We would get
giraffe remind you of?" We would get a
lot
lot of
giraffe remind you of?" We would get a
lot of very
lot of very valuable
giraffe remind you of?" We would get a
lot of very valuable information
lot of very valuable information out
giraffe remind you of?" We would get a
lot of very valuable information out of
it
it because
it because now
it because now your
it because now your dream
it because now your dream serves
it because now your dream serves like
it because now your dream serves like a
rshot
rshot card.
it because now your dream serves like a
rshot card. So
rshot card. So your
it because now your dream serves like a
rshot card. So your associations,
rshot card. So your associations, what
you
you see
you see there
you see there are
you see there are the
you see there are the projections
you see there are the projections from
your
your own
you see there are the projections from
your own unconscious.
your own unconscious. Let's
you see there are the projections from
your own unconscious. Let's ask
your own unconscious. Let's ask about
dreams.
We
We have
dreams.
We have permission
We have permission to
dreams.
We have permission to ask
We have permission to ask about
dreams.
We have permission to ask about dreams.
Resist
Resist friend
Resist friend in
Resist friend in this
Resist friend in this audience
Resist friend in this audience now
resist
resist dreams
Resist friend in this audience now
resist dreams are
resist dreams are the
Resist friend in this audience now
resist dreams are the um
resist dreams are the um what
Resist friend in this audience now
resist dreams are the um what should
resist dreams are the um what should we
say
say the
say the the
say the the clearingness
say the the clearingness of
say the the clearingness of the
apparatus
apparatus of
say the the clearingness of the
apparatus of the
apparatus of the brain
say the the clearingness of the
apparatus of the brain resist
apparatus of the brain resist yeah
that's
that's what
that's what it
that's what it is
that's what it is see
of
of course
that's what it is see
of course it
of course it picks
that's what it is see
of course it picks up
of course it picks up whatever
that's what it is see
of course it picks up whatever is
of course it picks up whatever is lying
around
around to
around to clear
around to clear it
around to clear it up
around to clear it up it's
around to clear it up it's sort
around to clear it up it's sort of
around to clear it up it's sort of like
there's
there's something
around to clear it up it's sort of like
there's something in
there's something in the
around to clear it up it's sort of like
there's something in the electronic
world
world I
world I forget
world I forget what
world I forget what it
world I forget what it is
world I forget what it is that
world I forget what it is that when
world I forget what it is that when you
turn
turn it
world I forget what it is that when you
turn it off
turn it off it
world I forget what it is that when you
turn it off it has
turn it off it has to
world I forget what it is that when you
turn it off it has to clear
turn it off it has to clear itself
world I forget what it is that when you
turn it off it has to clear itself it's
like
like to
like to me
like to me the
like to me the clearing
like to me the clearing this
like to me the clearing this clearing
that
that it's
like to me the clearing this clearing
that it's not
that it's not uh
like to me the clearing this clearing
that it's not uh let's
And
And yet
And yet within
And yet within it
And yet within it we
And yet within it we could
And yet within it we could pick
And yet within it we could pick up
And yet within it we could pick up the
prophetic
prophetic resist
And yet within it we could pick up the
prophetic resist and
prophetic resist and we
And yet within it we could pick up the
prophetic resist and we do
prophetic resist and we do pick
And yet within it we could pick up the
prophetic resist and we do pick up
prophetic resist and we do pick up the
prophetic.
prophetic. Yes.
prophetic. Yes. So
prophetic. Yes. So there's
prophetic. Yes. So there's all
prophetic. Yes. So there's all right.
prophetic. Yes. So there's all right. So
if
if I
prophetic. Yes. So there's all right. So
if I um
come
come back
come back another
come back another lifetime
come back another lifetime I'll
come back another lifetime I'll spend
that
that one
come back another lifetime I'll spend
that one on
that one on dreams
come back another lifetime I'll spend
that one on dreams the
that one on dreams the meaning
come back another lifetime I'll spend
that one on dreams the meaning of
that one on dreams the meaning of dreams
how
how they
how they tie
how they tie in
how they tie in with
how they tie in with various
how they tie in with various levels
how they tie in with various levels of
consciousness
consciousness and
how they tie in with various levels of
consciousness and karmic
consciousness and karmic propensity
how they tie in with various levels of
consciousness and karmic propensity and
levels
levels of
levels of consciousness
levels of consciousness and
levels of consciousness and symbolism
and
and that
levels of consciousness and symbolism
and that would
and that would make
levels of consciousness and symbolism
and that would make a
and that would make a whole
levels of consciousness and symbolism
and that would make a whole PhD
and that would make a whole PhD you
levels of consciousness and symbolism
and that would make a whole PhD you know
uh
uh work.
uh work. So
uh work. So it's
uh work. So it's really
uh work. So it's really quite
uh work. So it's really quite an
interesting
interesting thing
uh work. So it's really quite an
interesting thing and
interesting thing and I've
uh work. So it's really quite an
interesting thing and I've vacasillated
about
about the
about the meaning
about the meaning and
about the meaning and value
about the meaning and value of
about the meaning and value of dreams
throughout
throughout my
about the meaning and value of dreams
throughout my professional
throughout my professional lifetime
about the meaning and value of dreams
throughout my professional lifetime and
in
in psychoanalysis
in psychoanalysis of
in psychoanalysis of course
in psychoanalysis of course we
in psychoanalysis of course we use
in psychoanalysis of course we use them
quite
quite extensively
and
and uh
and uh the
and uh the resolution
and uh the resolution of
and uh the resolution of my
and uh the resolution of my own
psychoanalysis
psychoanalysis was
and uh the resolution of my own
psychoanalysis was accomplished
psychoanalysis was accomplished via
and uh the resolution of my own
psychoanalysis was accomplished via a
dream
dream very
dream very literally
dream very literally so
dream very literally so I
dream very literally so I think
dream very literally so I think I
dream very literally so I think I told
you
you that
dream very literally so I think I told
you that dream
you that dream was
dream very literally so I think I told
you that dream was a
you that dream was a famous
dream very literally so I think I told
you that dream was a famous dream
you that dream was a famous dream in
fact
fact it
fact it got
fact it got published
fact it got published in
fact it got published in the
international
international psychoanalytic
fact it got published in the
international psychoanalytic journals
and
and u
and u I'll
and u I'll say
and u I'll say if
and u I'll say if you
and u I'll say if you don't
and u I'll say if you don't believe
and u I'll say if you don't believe in
the
the edible
and u I'll say if you don't believe in
the edible complex
the edible complex try
and u I'll say if you don't believe in
the edible complex try lang
the edible complex try lang analyst
and u I'll say if you don't believe in
the edible complex try lang analyst his
couch
couch one
couch one hour
couch one hour a
couch one hour a day,
couch one hour a day, 5
couch one hour a day, 5 days
couch one hour a day, 5 days a
couch one hour a day, 5 days a week
couch one hour a day, 5 days a week for
a
a couple
couch one hour a day, 5 days a week for
a couple years
a couple years and
couch one hour a day, 5 days a week for
a couple years and see
a couple years and see what
couch one hour a day, 5 days a week for
a couple years and see what comes
a couple years and see what comes up.
Yeah.
Yeah. All
Yeah. All right.
Fred
Fred didn't
Yeah. All right.
Fred didn't make
Fred didn't make it
Yeah. All right.
Fred didn't make it up.
Fred didn't make it up. It's
Yeah. All right.
Fred didn't make it up. It's what
Fred didn't make it up. It's what came
out
out of
out of the
out of the unconscious.
out of the unconscious. You
out of the unconscious. You know,
out of the unconscious. You know, I
out of the unconscious. You know, I can
never
never remember
out of the unconscious. You know, I can
never remember a
never remember a terrifying
out of the unconscious. You know, I can
never remember a terrifying dream.
never remember a terrifying dream. You
out of the unconscious. You know, I can
never remember a terrifying dream. You I
was
was in
was in by
was in by the
was in by the second
was in by the second or
was in by the second or third
was in by the second or third year
was in by the second or third year of
psycho
psycho analysis.
was in by the second or third year of
psycho analysis. I
psycho analysis. I saw
was in by the second or third year of
psycho analysis. I saw him
psycho analysis. I saw him every
was in by the second or third year of
psycho analysis. I saw him every day
psycho analysis. I saw him every day of
the
the week.
the week. He used
the week. He used to
the week. He used to lay
the week. He used to lay on
the week. He used to lay on the
the week. He used to lay on the couch
and
and preassociate.
And
And um
And um anyway,
And um anyway, I
And um anyway, I got
And um anyway, I got worse
And um anyway, I got worse and
And um anyway, I got worse and worse.
And um anyway, I got worse and worse. I
get
get phobic.
And um anyway, I got worse and worse. I
get phobic. I
get phobic. I couldn't
And um anyway, I got worse and worse. I
get phobic. I couldn't drive
get phobic. I couldn't drive over
And um anyway, I got worse and worse. I
get phobic. I couldn't drive over the
bridges.
bridges. I
bridges. I couldn't
bridges. I couldn't go
bridges. I couldn't go under
bridges. I couldn't go under the
bridges. I couldn't go under the tunnel.
I
I was
bridges. I couldn't go under the tunnel.
I was afraid
I was afraid of
bridges. I couldn't go under the tunnel.
I was afraid of crowds.
I was afraid of crowds. I
bridges. I couldn't go under the tunnel.
I was afraid of crowds. I was
I was afraid of crowds. I was afraid
bridges. I couldn't go under the tunnel.
I was afraid of crowds. I was afraid of
being
being alone.
being alone. I
being alone. I was
being alone. I was had
being alone. I was had claustrophobia,
agorophobia.
And
And my
And my analyst
And my analyst was
And my analyst was very
And my analyst was very pleased.
Terrific
Terrific progress.
And my analyst was very pleased.
Terrific progress. I
Terrific progress. I say,
And my analyst was very pleased.
Terrific progress. I say, "I'm
Terrific progress. I say, "I'm getting
worse."
worse." He
worse." He says,
worse." He says, "You're
worse." He says, "You're doing
terrific."
And
And then
And then the
And then the worst
And then the worst of
And then the worst of all
And then the worst of all nightmares.
And
And I
And then the worst of all nightmares.
And I lay
And I lay on
And then the worst of all nightmares.
And I lay on the
And I lay on the couch
And then the worst of all nightmares.
And I lay on the couch and
And I lay on the couch and as
And then the worst of all nightmares.
And I lay on the couch and as I'm
telling
telling him
telling him this
telling him this nightmare,
telling him this nightmare, in
telling him this nightmare, in the
nightmare,
nightmare, I'm
telling him this nightmare, in the
nightmare, I'm this
nightmare, I'm this lion
telling him this nightmare, in the
nightmare, I'm this lion is
nightmare, I'm this lion is killing
telling him this nightmare, in the
nightmare, I'm this lion is killing me.
There's
There's some
There's some woman
There's some woman off
There's some woman off vaguely
There's some woman off vaguely in
There's some woman off vaguely in the
background.
background. And
There's some woman off vaguely in the
background. And the
background. And the lion
There's some woman off vaguely in the
background. And the lion is
background. And the lion is attacking
and
and killing
and killing me.
and killing me. And
and killing me. And I
and killing me. And I jump
and killing me. And I jump off
and killing me. And I jump off the
couch,
couch, you
and killing me. And I jump off the
couch, you know.
couch, you know. My
and killing me. And I jump off the
couch, you know. My heart
couch, you know. My heart is
and killing me. And I jump off the
couch, you know. My heart is pounding
like
like that.
like that. He
like that. He says,
like that. He says, "What
like that. He says, "What do
like that. He says, "What do you
like that. He says, "What do you think
it?
it? What
like that. He says, "What do you think
it? What does
it? What does it
like that. He says, "What do you think
it? What does it remind
it? What does it remind you
like that. He says, "What do you think
it? What does it remind you of?"
it? What does it remind you of?" I
like that. He says, "What do you think
it? What does it remind you of?" I said,
"I
"I don't
"I don't know.
"I don't know. My
"I don't know. My mind
"I don't know. My mind is
"I don't know. My mind is blank."
"I don't know. My mind is blank." He
says,
says, "What
"I don't know. My mind is blank." He
says, "What about
says, "What about the
"I don't know. My mind is blank." He
says, "What about the lion?"
says, "What about the lion?" I
"I don't know. My mind is blank." He
says, "What about the lion?" I said,
says, "What about the lion?" I said, "I
don't
don't know.
don't know. Lion.
don't know. Lion. What
don't know. Lion. What the
don't know. Lion. What the hell?
don't know. Lion. What the hell? What?
don't know. Lion. What the hell? What? I
don't
don't know."
don't know. Lion. What the hell? What? I
don't know." He
don't know." He says,
don't know. Lion. What the hell? What? I
don't know." He says, "What's
don't know." He says, "What's my
don't know. Lion. What the hell? What? I
don't know." He says, "What's my name?"
I
I said,
I said, "Your
I said, "Your name
I said, "Your name is
I said, "Your name is Lionel
I said, "Your name is Lionel Oloy."
I said, "Your name is Lionel Oloy." Oh,
lion.
lion. Oh
I said, "Your name is Lionel Oloy." Oh,
lion. Oh my
lion. Oh my god.
I said, "Your name is Lionel Oloy." Oh,
lion. Oh my god. In
lion. Oh my god. In conscious
I said, "Your name is Lionel Oloy." Oh,
lion. Oh my god. In conscious terror
lion. Oh my god. In conscious terror of
the
the endless,
the endless, the
the endless, the father
the endless, the father figure
the endless, the father figure killing
me
me for
the endless, the father figure killing
me for desiring
me for desiring or
the endless, the father figure killing
me for desiring or fantasying
me for desiring or fantasying the
the endless, the father figure killing
me for desiring or fantasying the woman
in
in his
in his life.
in his life. I
in his life. I never
in his life. I never met
in his life. I never met her.
in his life. I never met her. You
in his life. I never met her. You don't
believe
believe in
in his life. I never met her. You don't
believe in the
believe in the noble
in his life. I never met her. You don't
believe in the noble complex?
believe in the noble complex? I
in his life. I never met her. You don't
believe in the noble complex? I got
believe in the noble complex? I got news
for
for you.
That's
That's how
for you.
That's how you
That's how you get
for you.
That's how you get gray
That's how you get gray hairs
for you.
That's how you get gray hairs as
That's how you get gray hairs as an
analyst.
So
dreams
dreams in
dreams in my
dreams in my own
dreams in my own experience
dreams in my own experience them
dreams in my own experience them were
very
very profoundly
beneficial.
On
On the
beneficial.
On the other
On the other hand,
beneficial.
On the other hand, I
On the other hand, I have
beneficial.
On the other hand, I have a
On the other hand, I have a certain
doubt
doubt about
doubt about them.
Uh
Uh well
doubt about them.
Uh well now
Uh well now to
doubt about them.
Uh well now to overcome
Uh well now to overcome the
doubt about them.
Uh well now to overcome the effects
Uh well now to overcome the effects of
negativity
negativity in
negativity in your
negativity in your life
negativity in your life requires
spiritual
spiritual work.
negativity in your life requires
spiritual work. And
spiritual work. And what
negativity in your life requires
spiritual work. And what you
spiritual work. And what you do
negativity in your life requires
spiritual work. And what you do is
utilize
utilize every
utilize every technique
utilize every technique and
utilize every technique and thing
utilize every technique and thing that
you
you know
utilize every technique and thing that
you know you
you know you know
utilize every technique and thing that
you know you know you
you know you know you can
utilize every technique and thing that
you know you know you can smudge
you know you know you can smudge the
room.
room. That's
room. That's classic.
room. That's classic. Let's
room. That's classic. Let's see
room. That's classic. Let's see if
that's
that's useful.
Smudging
Smudging the
Smudging the room
Smudging the room with
Smudging the room with uh
Smudging the room with uh sage
Smudging the room with uh sage is
useful.
useful. It
Smudging the room with uh sage is
useful. It does
useful. It does repel
Smudging the room with uh sage is
useful. It does repel negative
useful. It does repel negative energies.
It
It is.
It is. All
It is. All right.
It is. All right. So
It is. All right. So we
It is. All right. So we start
It is. All right. So we start with
It is. All right. So we start with the
most
most primitive.
Just
Just smudge
Just smudge the
Just smudge the room.
Just smudge the room. That
Just smudge the room. That gets
Just smudge the room. That gets the
energies
energies out.
Just smudge the room. That gets the
energies out. You
energies out. You pray.
Just smudge the room. That gets the
energies out. You pray. You
energies out. You pray. You use
Just smudge the room. That gets the
energies out. You pray. You use prayer.
You
You use
You use all
You use all all
You use all all the
You use all all the things.
You use all all the things. You
You use all all the things. You ask
You use all all the things. You ask for
a
a miracle.
The
The consequences
The consequences of
The consequences of course
also
also fulfill
The consequences of course
also fulfill certain
also fulfill certain needs
The consequences of course
also fulfill certain needs within
yourself.
There's
There's a
yourself.
There's a need
There's a need to
yourself.
There's a need to come
There's a need to come out
yourself.
There's a need to come out of
There's a need to come out of spiritual
naive
naive into
naive into spiritual
naive into spiritual wisdom.
naive into spiritual wisdom. The
naive into spiritual wisdom. The only
way
way you
naive into spiritual wisdom. The only
way you can
way you can do
naive into spiritual wisdom. The only
way you can do that
way you can do that is
naive into spiritual wisdom. The only
way you can do that is if
way you can do that is if enough
naive into spiritual wisdom. The only
way you can do that is if enough people
steal
steal your
steal your shoes.
steal your shoes. You
steal your shoes. You finally
steal your shoes. You finally get
steal your shoes. You finally get You
can't
can't trust
steal your shoes. You finally get You
can't trust every
can't trust every monk
steal your shoes. You finally get You
can't trust every monk with
can't trust every monk with your
steal your shoes. You finally get You
can't trust every monk with your shoes.
Holy
Holy robes
Holy robes do
Holy robes do not
Holy robes do not uh
sooner
sooner or
Holy robes do not uh
sooner or later
sooner or later a
Holy robes do not uh
sooner or later a monk's
sooner or later a monk's going
Holy robes do not uh
sooner or later a monk's going to
sooner or later a monk's going to steal
your
your shoes.
your shoes. That's
your shoes. That's right.
your shoes. That's right. And
your shoes. That's right. And you
your shoes. That's right. And you go,
"Oh,
"Oh, I
your shoes. That's right. And you go,
"Oh, I have
"Oh, I have to
your shoes. That's right. And you go,
"Oh, I have to learn
"Oh, I have to learn discernment."
your shoes. That's right. And you go,
"Oh, I have to learn discernment." So
everything
everything that
everything that happens
everything that happens in
everything that happens in your
everything that happens in your life
everything that happens in your life has
its
its upside,
everything that happens in your life has
its upside, its
its upside, its seeming
everything that happens in your life has
its upside, its seeming downside
its upside, its seeming downside is
everything that happens in your life has
its upside, its seeming downside is the
annoyance,
annoyance, the
annoyance, the pain,
annoyance, the pain, the
annoyance, the pain, the seeming
annoyance, the pain, the seeming loss.
But
But don't
annoyance, the pain, the seeming loss.
But don't forget
But don't forget that
annoyance, the pain, the seeming loss.
But don't forget that every
But don't forget that every loss
annoyance, the pain, the seeming loss.
But don't forget that every loss is
But don't forget that every loss is a
gain.
gain. Every
gain. Every loss
gain. Every loss is
gain. Every loss is a
gain. Every loss is a gain.
gain. Every loss is a gain. So
gain. Every loss is a gain. So grief,
gain. Every loss is a gain. So grief, do
we
we have
gain. Every loss is a gain. So grief, do
we have grief
we have grief in
gain. Every loss is a gain. So grief, do
we have grief in here?
we have grief in here? Yeah,
gain. Every loss is a gain. So grief, do
we have grief in here? Yeah, we
we have grief in here? Yeah, we have
grief.
grief. Don't
grief. Don't forget
grief. Don't forget that
grief. Don't forget that every
grief. Don't forget that every grief,
every
every grief,
grief. Don't forget that every grief,
every grief, every
every grief, every loss
grief. Don't forget that every grief,
every grief, every loss is
every grief, every loss is a
grief. Don't forget that every grief,
every grief, every loss is a gain.
every grief, every loss is a gain. Where
there
there was
there was a
there was a something,
there was a something, there
there was a something, there is
there was a something, there is now
freedom.
With
With total
With total freedom,
With total freedom, you
With total freedom, you lose
With total freedom, you lose everything.
By
By the
With total freedom, you lose everything.
By the time
By the time you
With total freedom, you lose everything.
By the time you reach
By the time you reach reach
enlightenment,
enlightenment, you've
enlightenment, you've you've
enlightenment, you've you've let
enlightenment, you've you've let go
enlightenment, you've you've let go of
everything,
even
even your
even your own
even your own existence,
even your own existence, even
even your own existence, even your
even your own existence, even your own
physicality.
uh
uh the
uh the dominion
uh the dominion of
uh the dominion of the
uh the dominion of the core
uh the dominion of the core of
uh the dominion of the core of the
uh the dominion of the core of the ego
as
as the
uh the dominion of the core of the ego
as the sense
as the sense of
uh the dominion of the core of the ego
as the sense of eye.
as the sense of eye. As
uh the dominion of the core of the ego
as the sense of eye. As you
as the sense of eye. As you walk
uh the dominion of the core of the ego
as the sense of eye. As you walk towards
that
that gate,
that gate, you
that gate, you know
that gate, you know you're
that gate, you know you're dying.
that gate, you know you're dying. You
actually
actually die.
that gate, you know you're dying. You
actually die. You
actually die. You literally
that gate, you know you're dying. You
actually die. You literally actually
experience
experience dying
and
and you
experience dying
and you realize
and you realize it
experience dying
and you realize it is
and you realize it is the
experience dying
and you realize it is the first
and you realize it is the first time
experience dying
and you realize it is the first time you
have
have ever
have ever died
and
and you
have ever died
and you are
and you are actually
have ever died
and you are actually facing
and you are actually facing certain
death.
The
The certainty
death.
The certainty of
The certainty of this
death.
The certainty of this death
The certainty of this death is
absolutely
absolutely certain.
And
And beyond
absolutely certain.
And beyond it,
And beyond it, you
absolutely certain.
And beyond it, you have
And beyond it, you have only
absolutely certain.
And beyond it, you have only the
And beyond it, you have only the trust
in
in the
in the spiritual
presence
innate
innate within
innate within your
innate within your own
innate within your own consciousness
heard
heard from
innate within your own consciousness
heard from some
heard from some teacher
innate within your own consciousness
heard from some teacher at
heard from some teacher at some
innate within your own consciousness
heard from some teacher at some time
heard from some teacher at some time to
walk
walk straight
walk straight through
walk straight through no
walk straight through no matter
walk straight through no matter what.
And
And so
walk straight through no matter what.
And so that
And so that faith
walk straight through no matter what.
And so that faith takes
And so that faith takes you
walk straight through no matter what.
And so that faith takes you through
And so that faith takes you through the
terror
terror because
terror because the
terror because the the
terror because the the last
terror because the the last moment
terror because the the last moment it
was
was in
terror because the the last moment it
was in this
was in this experience
terror because the the last moment it
was in this experience a
was in this experience a terror
terror because the the last moment it
was in this experience a terror because
it
it was
it was death
it was death itself
it was death itself and
it was death itself and you
it was death itself and you realized
you've
you've never
it was death itself and you realized
you've never died
you've never died before.
it was death itself and you realized
you've never died before. Every
you've never died before. Every time
it was death itself and you realized
you've never died before. Every time you
left
left the
left the body
left the body it
left the body it was
left the body it was like
left the body it was like terrific
and
and this
left the body it was like terrific
and this is
and this is real
left the body it was like terrific
and this is real death.
and this is real death. So
left the body it was like terrific
and this is real death. So there
and this is real death. So there has
left the body it was like terrific
and this is real death. So there has to
be
be a
be a willingness
be a willingness to
be a willingness to surrender
everything
everything all
be a willingness to surrender
everything all the
everything all the way
be a willingness to surrender
everything all the way down
everything all the way down to
be a willingness to surrender
everything all the way down to the
absolute
absolute bottom.
Uh
there's
there's some
there's some question
there's some question here
there's some question here about
silence.
silence. Um
there's some question here about
silence. Um several
silence. Um several questions
there's some question here about
silence. Um several questions about
silence
and
and then
silence
and then we're
and then we're going
silence
and then we're going to
and then we're going to have
silence
and then we're going to have to
and then we're going to have to break
for
for lunch.
for lunch. Um
a
a as
for lunch. Um
a as quietude
a as quietude prevails.
for lunch. Um
a as quietude prevails. As
a as quietude prevails. As quietude
prevails.
Have
Have you
prevails.
Have you got
Have you got that
prevails.
Have you got that um
Have you got that um CD?
I
I like
I like the
I like the You
I like the You want
I like the You want to
I like the You want to put
I like the You want to put it
I like the You want to put it on
I like the You want to put it on it
again?
again? All right.
I like the You want to put it on it
again? All right. Um
the
the substrate
the substrate of
the substrate of the
the substrate of the existence
the substrate of the existence of
the substrate of the existence of all
the substrate of the existence of all of
us
us at
the substrate of the existence of all of
us at this
us at this moment
is
is silent.
The
The source
is silent.
The source of
The source of our
is silent.
The source of our existence
The source of our existence is
is silent.
The source of our existence is silent.
The
The rug
The rug is
The rug is silent.
This
This is
The rug is silent.
This is silent.
This is silent. Everything
The rug is silent.
This is silent. Everything about
This is silent. Everything about it.
>> You
>> You get
>> You get what
>> You get what I'm
>> You get what I'm saying?
>> It's
>> It's a
>> You get what I'm saying?
>> It's a lucky
>> It's a lucky break
>> You get what I'm saying?
>> It's a lucky break to
>> It's a lucky break to be
>> You get what I'm saying?
>> It's a lucky break to be deaf.
>> All right.
>> All right. So
>> All right. So out
>> All right. So out of
>> All right. So out of that
>> All right. So out of that innate
>> All right. So out of that innate silence
then
is
is where
as
as you
is where
as you expand
as you expand context
is where
as you expand context you
as you expand context you begin
is where
as you expand context you begin to
as you expand context you begin to own
the
the silence
the silence as
the silence as yourself
and
and that
the silence as yourself
and that which
and that which is
the silence as yourself
and that which is interfering
and that which is interfering with
the silence as yourself
and that which is interfering with the
silence
silence as
silence as the
silence as the notself.
The
The sound
silence as the notself.
The sound becomes
The sound becomes the
silence as the notself.
The sound becomes the content.
The sound becomes the content. It's
silence as the notself.
The sound becomes the content. It's only
because
because of
because of the
because of the silence
because of the silence that
because of the silence that you
because of the silence that you can
because of the silence that you can hear
any
any sound.
And
And you
And you begin
And you begin to
And you begin to identify
And you begin to identify with
And you begin to identify with the
silence
silence is
And you begin to identify with the
silence is that
silence is that which
And you begin to identify with the
silence is that which you
silence is that which you are.
It
It comes
It comes on
It comes on profoundly.
The
The oneness
It comes on profoundly.
The oneness with
The oneness with the
It comes on profoundly.
The oneness with the silence
The oneness with the silence is
It comes on profoundly.
The oneness with the silence is one's
own
own existence
own existence beyond
own existence beyond all
own existence beyond all time.
own existence beyond all time. That
which
which I
own existence beyond all time. That
which I am
which I am existed
own existence beyond all time. That
which I am existed prior
which I am existed prior to
own existence beyond all time. That
which I am existed prior to this
universe
and
and will
universe
and will be
and will be here
universe
and will be here long
and will be here long after
universe
and will be here long after this
universe expires.
Because
Because universes
universe expires.
Because universes come
Because universes come and
universe expires.
Because universes come and go
like
like the
like the dreams
like the dreams of
like the dreams of Indra.
The
The illusion
like the dreams of Indra.
The illusion of
The illusion of it
like the dreams of Indra.
The illusion of it all
The illusion of it all comes
like the dreams of Indra.
The illusion of it all comes and
The illusion of it all comes and goes
and
and creating
and creating and
and creating and unfolding
and creating and unfolding universes
and creating and unfolding universes is
how
how I
and creating and unfolding universes is
how I enjoy
how I enjoy myself.
That's
That's my
That's my prerogative,
That's my prerogative, right?
That's
That's a
That's my prerogative, right?
That's a prerogative.
I
I choose
I choose to
I choose to do
I choose to do that.
When
When you
I choose to do that.
When you choose
When you choose it,
I choose to do that.
When you choose it, you're
When you choose it, you're not
I choose to do that.
When you choose it, you're not at
When you choose it, you're not at the
effect
effect of
effect of it.
effect of it. So,
effect of it. So, you
effect of it. So, you choose
effect of it. So, you choose to
experience
experience this
effect of it. So, you choose to
experience this existence
experience this existence as
effect of it. So, you choose to
experience this existence as you
experience
experience it.
And
And in
experience it.
And in so
And in so doing,
experience it.
And in so doing, you
And in so doing, you let
experience it.
And in so doing, you let go
And in so doing, you let go resisting
it.
it. And
it. And as
it. And as you
it. And as you let
it. And as you let go
it. And as you let go resisting
it. And as you let go resisting it,
it. And as you let go resisting it, you
dissolve
dissolve it.
And
And you
And you go
And you go back
And you go back into
And you go back into that
And you go back into that which
And you go back into that which you
And you go back into that which you are
prior
prior to
And you go back into that which you are
prior to this
prior to this existence.
That
That is
That is the
That is the meaning
That is the meaning of
That is the meaning of the
That is the meaning of the silence.
To
To be
That is the meaning of the silence.
To be that
To be that which
That is the meaning of the silence.
To be that which you
To be that which you are
That is the meaning of the silence.
To be that which you are now
To be that which you are now you
That is the meaning of the silence.
To be that which you are now you have
To be that which you are now you have to
be
be the
be the whole
be the whole universe
because
because it's
be the whole universe
because it's all
because it's all part
be the whole universe
because it's all part of
because it's all part of the
be the whole universe
because it's all part of the whole
picture.
So
So Indra's
picture.
So Indra's dream
on
on the
on the inb
on the inb breath
on the inb breath the
on the inb breath the creation
on the inb breath the creation arises
on the inb breath the creation arises on
an
an out
on the inb breath the creation arises on
an out breath
an out breath the
on the inb breath the creation arises on
an out breath the creation
an out breath the creation no
on the inb breath the creation arises on
an out breath the creation no it's
an out breath the creation no it's the
other
other way
other way on
other way on out
other way on out breath
other way on out breath the
other way on out breath the creation
arises
arises and
other way on out breath the creation
arises and on
arises and on the
other way on out breath the creation
arises and on the inb
arises and on the inb breath
other way on out breath the creation
arises and on the inb breath it
disappears
over
over the
disappears
over the millennia
millennia
millennia done
millennia done it
millennia done it for
millennia done it for millennia
millennia done it for millennia all
millennia done it for millennia all it
is
is is
millennia done it for millennia all it
is is remembering
is is remembering who
millennia done it for millennia all it
is is remembering who you
is is remembering who you are
that's
that's your
that's your oneness
that's your oneness with
that's your oneness with the
that's your oneness with the creator
here.
So
So now
So now we
So now we we've
So now we we've created
So now we we've created lunch
So now we we've created lunch for
So now we we've created lunch for oursel
and
and what's
So now we we've created lunch for oursel
and what's the
and what's the after
So now we we've created lunch for oursel
and what's the after lunch
there's
there's no
there's no really
there's no really perfect
there's no really perfect way
there's no really perfect way of
answering
answering questions.
there's no really perfect way of
answering questions. you
answering questions. you know,
there's no really perfect way of
answering questions. you know, you
there's
there's the
there's the style
there's the style where
there's the style where the
there's the style where the microphone
goes
goes around
there's the style where the microphone
goes around the
goes around the audience
there's the style where the microphone
goes around the audience and
goes around the audience and that
there's the style where the microphone
goes around the audience and that gives
everybody
everybody a
everybody a chance
everybody a chance to
everybody a chance to hear,
everybody a chance to hear, but
everybody a chance to hear, but that
doesn't
doesn't record
everybody a chance to hear, but that
doesn't record very
doesn't record very well.
everybody a chance to hear, but that
doesn't record very well. So,
doesn't record very well. So, we're
using
using the
using the 3x5
using the 3x5 cards
um
um as
using the 3x5 cards
um as a
um as a means
using the 3x5 cards
um as a means of
um as a means of presenting
using the 3x5 cards
um as a means of presenting questions
and
and people
and people in
and people in spiritual
and people in spiritual work
and people in spiritual work have
and people in spiritual work have all
kinds
kinds of
and people in spiritual work have all
kinds of questions
kinds of questions that
and people in spiritual work have all
kinds of questions that don't
kinds of questions that don't make
and people in spiritual work have all
kinds of questions that don't make any
sense
sense to
sense to other
sense to other people,
but
but makes
sense to other people,
but makes sense
but makes sense if
sense to other people,
but makes sense if you've
but makes sense if you've been
sense to other people,
but makes sense if you've been through
it.
For
For instance,
it.
For instance, let's
For instance, let's say
Prozac
Prozac would
Prozac would affect
Prozac would affect your
Prozac would affect your level
Prozac would affect your level of
consciousness
consciousness adversely.
Prozac would affect your level of
consciousness adversely. Let's
consciousness adversely. Let's see.
We
We have
We have permission.
It
It would
We have permission.
It would not
It would not affect
We have permission.
It would not affect your
It would not affect your level
We have permission.
It would not affect your level of
consciousness
consciousness adversely.
No.
No. Why
consciousness adversely.
No. Why is
No. Why is that?
Because
Because uh
Because uh the
Because uh the the
Because uh the the energy
Because uh the the energy field
Because uh the the energy field is
Because uh the the energy field is we
don't
don't have
Because uh the the energy field is we
don't have the
don't have the energy
Because uh the the energy field is we
don't have the energy field
don't have the energy field on
Because uh the the energy field is we
don't have the energy field on there
anymore.
The
The energy
anymore.
The energy field
The energy field is
anymore.
The energy field is set
The energy field is set by
anymore.
The energy field is set by uh
The energy field is set by uh the
spiritual
spiritual will.
The
The spiritual
spiritual will.
The spiritual will
The spiritual will is
spiritual will.
The spiritual will is what
The spiritual will is what sets
spiritual will.
The spiritual will is what sets one's
level
level of
level of consciousness.
level of consciousness. So,
level of consciousness. So, Prozac
level of consciousness. So, Prozac would
be
be maybe
level of consciousness. So, Prozac would
be maybe even
be maybe even useful
level of consciousness. So, Prozac would
be maybe even useful because
be maybe even useful because there
level of consciousness. So, Prozac would
be maybe even useful because there are
phases
phases in
phases in spiritual
phases in spiritual work
phases in spiritual work where
phases in spiritual work where you
phases in spiritual work where you can
go
go into
phases in spiritual work where you can
go into periods
go into periods of
phases in spiritual work where you can
go into periods of dispondency
go into periods of dispondency and
despair
despair and
despair and depression
despair and depression and
your
your neurotransmitters
despair and depression and
your neurotransmitters become
overwhelmed.
And
And so
overwhelmed.
And so there's
And so there's nothing
overwhelmed.
And so there's nothing wrong
And so there's nothing wrong with
overwhelmed.
And so there's nothing wrong with using
it
it temporarily.
Um
but
but apparently
but apparently the
but apparently the answer
but apparently the answer to
but apparently the answer to the
question
question is
but apparently the answer to the
question is no,
question is no, it
but apparently the answer to the
question is no, it doesn't
question is no, it doesn't adversely
affect
affect it
affect it because
affect it because a
affect it because a person
affect it because a person would
affect it because a person would only
what
what is
affect it because a person would only
what is the
what is the reason
affect it because a person would only
what is the reason the
what is the reason the person
affect it because a person would only
what is the reason the person is
what is the reason the person is taking
it?
it? It's
it? It's just
it? It's just they
it? It's just they want
it? It's just they want to
it? It's just they want to feel
it? It's just they want to feel better.
It's
It's a
it? It's just they want to feel better.
It's a rather
It's a rather simple
it? It's just they want to feel better.
It's a rather simple thing.
It's a rather simple thing. Uh
but
but those
but those are
but those are the
but those are the kind
but those are the kind of
but those are the kind of questions
but those are the kind of questions that
when
when you're
but those are the kind of questions that
when you're in
when you're in spiritual
but those are the kind of questions that
when you're in spiritual work
when you're in spiritual work become
important
important and
important and to
important and to somebody
important and to somebody else
ridiculous
ridiculous but
important and to somebody else
ridiculous but you
ridiculous but you know
important and to somebody else
ridiculous but you know you
ridiculous but you know you lie
important and to somebody else
ridiculous but you know you lie awake
ridiculous but you know you lie awake at
night
night and
night and say
night and say that's
night and say that's going
night and say that's going to
night and say that's going to affect
night and say that's going to affect my
level
level of
night and say that's going to affect my
level of consciousness.
level of consciousness. So
night and say that's going to affect my
level of consciousness. So let's
level of consciousness. So let's have
some
some of
some of the
some of the other
some of the other ones
some of the other ones that
some of the other ones that we
some of the other ones that we didn't
finish
finish this
some of the other ones that we didn't
finish this morning
finish this morning and
some of the other ones that we didn't
finish this morning and then
finish this morning and then we'll
launch
launch into
launch into some
launch into some other
launch into some other subjects.
Um
now
now what
now what is
now what is the
now what is the best
now what is the best way
now what is the best way to
influence
influence events
now what is the best way to
influence events in
influence events in the
now what is the best way to
influence events in the world
influence events in the world favorably?
Well,
Well, uh,
first
first of
Well, uh,
first of all,
first of all, you
Well, uh,
first of all, you could
first of all, you could ask
Well, uh,
first of all, you could ask yourself
first of all, you could ask yourself why
you
you want
you want to
you want to change
you want to change events
you want to change events in
you want to change events in the
you want to change events in the world.
Um,
Um, then
you want to change events in the world.
Um, then you'd
Um, then you'd have
you want to change events in the world.
Um, then you'd have to
Um, then you'd have to realize
you want to change events in the world.
Um, then you'd have to realize that
Um, then you'd have to realize that what
you
you mean
you mean is
you mean is your
you mean is your perception
you mean is your perception of
you mean is your perception of events
you mean is your perception of events in
the
the world.
The
The way
The way you
The way you see
The way you see it,
The way you see it, you're
The way you see it, you're making
certain
certain presumptions
The way you see it, you're making
certain presumptions and
certain presumptions and because
The way you see it, you're making
certain presumptions and because of
certain presumptions and because of the
way
way you
way you see
way you see it
way you see it and
way you see it and your
way you see it and your presumptions,
you
you want
way you see it and your presumptions,
you want to
you want to do
way you see it and your presumptions,
you want to do something
you want to do something about
way you see it and your presumptions,
you want to do something about it.
you want to do something about it. So
all
all those
all those steps
all those steps are
all those steps are subjects
all those steps are subjects for
spiritual
spiritual to
all those steps are subjects for
spiritual to to
spiritual to to transcend.
The
The world
The world that
The world that you
The world that you see
is
is not
The world that you see
is not a
is not a world
The world that you see
is not a world of
is not a world of reality.
The world that you see
is not a world of reality. It's
is not a world of reality. It's a
The world that you see
is not a world of reality. It's a world
of
of perception.
of perception. Yours
of perception. Yours and
of perception. Yours and other
of perception. Yours and other people.
It's
It's the
of perception. Yours and other people.
It's the acting
It's the acting out
of perception. Yours and other people.
It's the acting out of
It's the acting out of a
of perception. Yours and other people.
It's the acting out of a melodrama.
Uh
and
and everyone
Uh
and everyone if
and everyone if you
Uh
and everyone if you try
and everyone if you try check
Uh
and everyone if you try check out
and everyone if you try check out your
prior
lies
lies will
prior
lies will find
lies will find find
prior
lies will find find that
lies will find find that you
prior
lies will find find that you were
involved
involved in
involved in similar
involved in similar things.
and
and for
involved in similar things.
and for the
and for the same
involved in similar things.
and for the same reasons
and for the same reasons that
involved in similar things.
and for the same reasons that people
and for the same reasons that people are
involved
involved in
involved in them
involved in them now.
involved in them now. So
involved in them now. So you
involved in them now. So you might
involved in them now. So you might say
on
on the
involved in them now. So you might say
on the planet
on the planet there
involved in them now. So you might say
on the planet there are
on the planet there are people
involved in them now. So you might say
on the planet there are people that
on the planet there are people that go
well
well where's
well where's our
well where's our distribution
well where's our distribution of
consciousness
consciousness thing
well where's our distribution of
consciousness thing on
consciousness thing on the
well where's our distribution of
consciousness thing on the planet
consciousness thing on the planet there
are
are people
are people that
are people that go
are people that go from
are people that go from near
enlightenment
enlightenment or
are people that go from near
enlightenment or enlightenment
enlightenment or enlightenment all
are people that go from near
enlightenment or enlightenment all the
way
way down
way down to
way down to the
way down to the bottom
way down to the bottom of
way down to the bottom of the
way down to the bottom of the pile.
way down to the bottom of the pile. What
we
we look
way down to the bottom of the pile. What
we look at
we look at is
way down to the bottom of the pile. What
we look at is the
we look at is the bottom
way down to the bottom of the pile. What
we look at is the bottom of
we look at is the bottom of the
way down to the bottom of the pile. What
we look at is the bottom of the pile.
we look at is the bottom of the pile. Uh
we
we look
we look at
we look at them
we look at them as
we look at them as the
we look at them as the bottom
we look at them as the bottom of
we look at them as the bottom of the
pile
pile but
we look at them as the bottom of the
pile but that's
pile but that's from
we look at them as the bottom of the
pile but that's from our
pile but that's from our point
we look at them as the bottom of the
pile but that's from our point of
observation.
That's
That's from
observation.
That's from their
That's from their point
observation.
That's from their point of
That's from their point of observation.
And
And you
And you get
And you get a
And you get a person
And you get a person out
And you get a person out of
And you get a person out of apathy
up
up to
And you get a person out of apathy
up to angryness,
up to angryness, they're
And you get a person out of apathy
up to angryness, they're making
up to angryness, they're making good
progress.
So,
So, let's
progress.
So, let's see
So, let's see what
progress.
So, let's see what happened
So, let's see what happened to
progress.
So, let's see what happened to our
So, let's see what happened to our our
transparency
transparency we
transparency we had
transparency we had on
transparency we had on there.
Hey,
Hey, the
transparency we had on there.
Hey, the other
Hey, the other one.
Well,
Well, these
Well, these are
Well, these are hard
Well, these are hard to
Well, these are hard to see
Well, these are hard to see because
Well, these are hard to see because this
is
is a
Well, these are hard to see because this
is a black
is a black top
Well, these are hard to see because this
is a black top on
is a black top on this
Well, these are hard to see because this
is a black top on this piano.
The
The tape
The tape doesn't
The tape doesn't show
The tape doesn't show up
The tape doesn't show up too
The tape doesn't show up too good
The tape doesn't show up too good on
The tape doesn't show up too good on the
black
black top.
All
All I
All I want
All I want is
All I want is this
All I want is this good
All I want is this good old
All I want is this good old uh
All I want is this good old uh reliable
here.
There's
There's good
There's good old
There's good old reliable.
There's good old reliable. No,
There's good old reliable. No, that's
not
not the
There's good old reliable. No, that's
not the one
not the one I
There's good old reliable. No, that's
not the one I want
not the one I want either.
There's good old reliable. No, that's
not the one I want either. Well,
not the one I want either. Well, this
one
one will
one will do
because
because we
one will do
because we refer
because we refer to
one will do
because we refer to this
because we refer to this one
one will do
because we refer to this one rather
often.
Uh
Uh but
often.
Uh but if
Uh but if you
often.
Uh but if you see
Uh but if you see the
often.
Uh but if you see the distribution
Uh but if you see the distribution of
the
the levels
the levels of
the levels of consciousness
the levels of consciousness on
the levels of consciousness on the
planet,
planet, you
the levels of consciousness on the
planet, you realize
planet, you realize that
the levels of consciousness on the
planet, you realize that the
planet, you realize that the majority
the levels of consciousness on the
planet, you realize that the majority of
people
people are
people are somewhere
people are somewhere down
people are somewhere down the
people are somewhere down the line,
farther
farther back
people are somewhere down the line,
farther back on
farther back on the
people are somewhere down the line,
farther back on the road,
farther back on the road, however
people are somewhere down the line,
farther back on the road, however you
want
want to
want to picture
want to picture it.
want to picture it. You
want to picture it. You understand?
And
And what
want to picture it. You understand?
And what do
And what do you
want to picture it. You understand?
And what do you suppose
And what do you suppose they're
want to picture it. You understand?
And what do you suppose they're supposed
to
to be
to be doing
to be doing all
to be doing all day
to be doing all day to
to be doing all day to keep
to be doing all day to keep busy?
What
What are
to be doing all day to keep busy?
What are all
What are all these
to be doing all day to keep busy?
What are all these people
What are all these people going
to be doing all day to keep busy?
What are all these people going to
What are all these people going to be
doing?
doing? You
doing? You know,
doing? You know, let's
doing? You know, let's see.
Oh,
Oh, that's
doing? You know, let's see.
Oh, that's the
Oh, that's the one
doing? You know, let's see.
Oh, that's the one I
Oh, that's the one I was
doing? You know, let's see.
Oh, that's the one I was missing
Oh, that's the one I was missing was
doing? You know, let's see.
Oh, that's the one I was missing was on
the
the floor.
So,
So, let's
the floor.
So, let's see.
The
The the
The the people
The the people in
The the people in this
The the people in this room
The the people in this room are
The the people in this room are way
The the people in this room are way over
on
on the
The the people in this room are way over
on the right
on the right hand
The the people in this room are way over
on the right hand side
on the right hand side there.
The the people in this room are way over
on the right hand side there. What
on the right hand side there. What about
the
the rest
the rest of
the rest of the
the rest of the people
the rest of the people have
the rest of the people have a
the rest of the people have a heart,
the rest of the people have a heart, you
know?
They
They need
They need they
They need they need
They need they need somebody
They need they need somebody to
They need they need somebody to kill
They need they need somebody to kill and
hate
hate and
They need they need somebody to kill and
hate and all
hate and all that.
I
I mean,
I mean, where
I mean, where would
I mean, where would you
I mean, where would you be
I mean, where would you be without
I mean, where would you be without an
enemy?
enemy? You
in
in the
in the Middle
in the Middle East?
Nobody
Nobody to
in the Middle East?
Nobody to bomb.
Nobody to bomb. I
in the Middle East?
Nobody to bomb. I mean,
Nobody to bomb. I mean, it'd
in the Middle East?
Nobody to bomb. I mean, it'd be
horrible.
Your
Your life
horrible.
Your life would
Your life would lose
horrible.
Your life would lose meaning.
So,
So, there
So, there seems
So, there seems to
So, there seems to be
So, there seems to be a
So, there seems to be a hand
So, there seems to be a hand on
So, there seems to be a hand on this
picture,
picture, honey.
Oh,
all right.
all right. So,
Oh,
all right. So, all
all right. So, all these
Oh,
all right. So, all these people
all right. So, all these people live
here.
here. So,
here. So, we
here. So, we said,
here. So, we said, what's
here. So, we said, what's his
here. So, we said, what's his name?
here. So, we said, what's his name? Is
around
around 70.
here. So, we said, what's his name? Is
around 70. Where's
around 70. Where's my
here. So, we said, what's his name? Is
around 70. Where's my wonderful
around 70. Where's my wonderful t-shirt?
Yeah.
Yeah. So
all
all right.
Yeah. So
all right. So
all right. So how
Yeah. So
all right. So how do
all right. So how do you
Yeah. So
all right. So how do you evolve
all right. So how do you evolve in
consciousness?
consciousness? You
consciousness? You have
consciousness? You have to
consciousness? You have to go
consciousness? You have to go through
the
the levels.
consciousness? You have to go through
the levels. You
the levels. You have
consciousness? You have to go through
the levels. You have to
the levels. You have to go
consciousness? You have to go through
the levels. You have to go through
the levels. You have to go through the
levels.
People
People give
levels.
People give up
People give up a
levels.
People give up a level
People give up a level when
levels.
People give up a level when they
People give up a level when they hit
bottom.
bottom. When
bottom. When this
bottom. When this is
bottom. When this is not
bottom. When this is not the
bottom. When this is not the way
bottom. When this is not the way you
want
want to
bottom. When this is not the way you
want to live,
want to live, when
bottom. When this is not the way you
want to live, when this
want to live, when this is
bottom. When this is not the way you
want to live, when this is not
want to live, when this is not when
bottom. When this is not the way you
want to live, when this is not when you
when
when it
when it finally
when it finally gets
when it finally gets you.
when it finally gets you. I
when it finally gets you. I was
when it finally gets you. I was going
when it finally gets you. I was going to
make
make some
when it finally gets you. I was going to
make some signs
make some signs for
when it finally gets you. I was going to
make some signs for today.
make some signs for today. One's
when it finally gets you. I was going to
make some signs for today. One's called
Palestine.
Palestine. The
Palestine. The other
Palestine. The other one's
Palestine. The other one's called
Israel.
Israel. And
Palestine. The other one's called
Israel. And then
Israel. And then in
Palestine. The other one's called
Israel. And then in the
Israel. And then in the middle
Palestine. The other one's called
Israel. And then in the middle is
attacks
attacks and
attacks and gets
attacks and gets even
attacks and gets even with
attacks and gets even with and
attacks and gets even with and they
attacks and gets even with and they just
switch
switch the
attacks and gets even with and they just
switch the cards
switch the cards hour
attacks and gets even with and they just
switch the cards hour by
switch the cards hour by hour.
Palestine.
Palestine. You
Palestine. You know
Palestine. You know yesterday
Palestine. You know yesterday was
Palestine. You know yesterday was day
every
every day
Palestine. You know yesterday was day
every day you
every day you just
Palestine. You know yesterday was day
every day you just change
every day you just change these
Palestine. You know yesterday was day
every day you just change these two
cards
cards and
cards and because
cards and because the
cards and because the the
cards and because the the news
cards and because the the news doesn't
change
hates
hates and
hates and gets
hates and gets even
hates and gets even with
hates and gets even with and
hates and gets even with and you
hates and gets even with and you just
change
change Palestine
hates and gets even with and you just
change Palestine does
change Palestine does the
hates and gets even with and you just
change Palestine does the Israel
change Palestine does the Israel does
Palestine
Palestine you
Palestine you just
Palestine you just go
Palestine you just go back
Palestine you just go back and
Palestine you just go back and forth
like
like this
Palestine you just go back and forth
like this one
like this one day
Palestine you just go back and forth
like this one day somebody
like this one day somebody says
Palestine you just go back and forth
like this one day somebody says you
like this one day somebody says you know
this
this is
this is stupid
hey
hey this
this is stupid
hey this is
hey this is not
this is stupid
hey this is not getting
hey this is not getting us
this is stupid
hey this is not getting us anywhere
and
and that's
and that's how
and that's how you
and that's how you give
and that's how you give it
and that's how you give it up
and that's how you give it up people
give
give up
and that's how you give it up people
give up drinking
give up drinking that
and that's how you give it up people
give up drinking that way
give up drinking that way people
and that's how you give it up people
give up drinking that way people give
give up drinking that way people give up
bad
bad lives
bad lives bad
bad lives bad marriages
bad
bad lif
bad lives bad marriages
bad lif lifestyles.
And
And here
And here is
And here is a
And here is a wonderful
And here is a wonderful t-shirt.
He
He comes
And here is a wonderful t-shirt.
He comes to
He comes to all
And here is a wonderful t-shirt.
He comes to all the
He comes to all the lectures
And here is a wonderful t-shirt.
He comes to all the lectures and
He comes to all the lectures and he's
very
very ingenious.
very ingenious. Here's
very ingenious. Here's uh
very ingenious. Here's uh Ben
very ingenious. Here's uh Ben Lden
very ingenious. Here's uh Ben Lden on
the
the upper
very ingenious. Here's uh Ben Lden on
the upper left
the upper left here.
very ingenious. Here's uh Ben Lden on
the upper left here. It
the upper left here. It says,
very ingenious. Here's uh Ben Lden on
the upper left here. It says, "Hey,
the upper left here. It says, "Hey, do
you
you want
you want a
you want a muscle
you want a muscle test
you want a muscle test to
you want a muscle test to see
you want a muscle test to see which
you want a muscle test to see which one
of
of us
you want a muscle test to see which one
of us calibrates
of us calibrates higher?"
What
What do
What do you
What do you call
What do you call this
What do you call this guy
What do you call this guy here?
>> What
>> What is
What do you call this guy here?
>> What is it?
>> Huh?
>> Dinosaur.
>> Dinosaur. Dinosaur.
>> Dinosaur. Yes.
>> Dinosaur. Yes. Right.
>> Dinosaur. Yes. Right. Yeah,
>> Dinosaur. Yes. Right. Yeah, dinosaur,
right?
right? So
>> Dinosaur. Yes. Right. Yeah, dinosaur,
right? So he
right? So he says,
>> Dinosaur. Yes. Right. Yeah, dinosaur,
right? So he says, "You
right? So he says, "You want
>> Dinosaur. Yes. Right. Yeah, dinosaur,
right? So he says, "You want a
right? So he says, "You want a muzzle
test?
test? See
test? See which
test? See which one
test? See which one of
test? See which one of us
test? See which one of us is
test? See which one of us is higher,
test? See which one of us is higher, the
dinosaur?"
dinosaur?" And
test? See which one of us is higher, the
dinosaur?" And the
dinosaur?" And the next
test? See which one of us is higher, the
dinosaur?" And the next scene
dinosaur?" And the next scene you
test? See which one of us is higher, the
dinosaur?" And the next scene you see
the
the dinosaur
the dinosaur is
the dinosaur is saying,
the dinosaur is saying, "No,
the dinosaur is saying, "No, not
particularly."
particularly." And
the dinosaur is saying, "No, not
particularly." And dim
particularly." And dim mountains
the dinosaur is saying, "No, not
particularly." And dim mountains is
between
between his
between his jaws.
He
He just
between his jaws.
He just ate
He just ate him
between his jaws.
He just ate him and
He just ate him and said,
between his jaws.
He just ate him and said, "No,
He just ate him and said, "No, I'm
between his jaws.
He just ate him and said, "No, I'm not
really
really that."
You
You see,
really that."
You see, the
You see, the dinosaur
really that."
You see, the dinosaur can't
You see, the dinosaur can't help
really that."
You see, the dinosaur can't help being
You see, the dinosaur can't help being a
dinosaur.
dinosaur. You
dinosaur. You understand?
dinosaur. You understand? He
dinosaur. You understand? He just
dinosaur. You understand? He just he
does
does dinosaur
dinosaur. You understand? He just he
does dinosaur things
does dinosaur things because
dinosaur. You understand? He just he
does dinosaur things because he
does dinosaur things because he is
dinosaur. You understand? He just he
does dinosaur things because he is one.
So
now
now don't
So
now don't ask
now don't ask me
So
now don't ask me why
now don't ask me why it
So
now don't ask me why it is.
It's
It's God's
It's God's problem
It's God's problem why
It's God's problem why the
It's God's problem why the universe
It's God's problem why the universe is
the
the way
It's God's problem why the universe is
the way it
the way it is.
I
I don't
I don't know.
I don't know. It's
I don't know. It's like
I don't know. It's like a
I don't know. It's like a little
I don't know. It's like a little egg.
There's
There's a
I don't know. It's like a little egg.
There's a little
There's a little egg
I don't know. It's like a little egg.
There's a little egg and
There's a little egg and it
I don't know. It's like a little egg.
There's a little egg and it gets
There's a little egg and it gets bigger
and
and bigger
and bigger and
and bigger and then
and bigger and then a
and bigger and then a big
and bigger and then a big egg
and bigger and then a big egg and
and bigger and then a big egg and then
it
it hatches.
and bigger and then a big egg and then
it hatches. It's
it hatches. It's a
and bigger and then a big egg and then
it hatches. It's a furry
it hatches. It's a furry thing
and bigger and then a big egg and then
it hatches. It's a furry thing and
it hatches. It's a furry thing and it
gets
gets bigger
gets bigger and
gets bigger and bigger
gets bigger and bigger and
gets bigger and bigger and bigger
gets bigger and bigger and bigger and
then
then it
gets bigger and bigger and bigger and
then it lays
then it lays an
gets bigger and bigger and bigger and
then it lays an egg
then it lays an egg and
gets bigger and bigger and bigger and
then it lays an egg and then
then it lays an egg and then the
gets bigger and bigger and bigger and
then it lays an egg and then the little
bitty
bitty egg
bitty egg gets
bitty egg gets bigger
bitty egg gets bigger and
bitty egg gets bigger and bigger.
bitty egg gets bigger and bigger. Now
don't
don't ask
bitty egg gets bigger and bigger. Now
don't ask me
don't ask me why.
Why
Why is
Why is it
Why is it that
Why is it that way?
I
I guess
Why is it that way?
I guess that
I guess that the
Why is it that way?
I guess that the infinite
I guess that the infinite potentiality
of
of the
of the energy
of the energy field
of the energy field of
of the energy field of life
of the energy field of life itself.
Life
Life takes
of the energy field of life itself.
Life takes all
Life takes all kinds
of the energy field of life itself.
Life takes all kinds of
Life takes all kinds of forms
of the energy field of life itself.
Life takes all kinds of forms and
Life takes all kinds of forms and there
doesn't
doesn't seem
doesn't seem to
doesn't seem to be
doesn't seem to be any
doesn't seem to be any rules
doesn't seem to be any rules about
doesn't seem to be any rules about it.
Life
Life can
doesn't seem to be any rules about it.
Life can go
Life can go wherever
doesn't seem to be any rules about it.
Life can go wherever it
Life can go wherever it wants
doesn't seem to be any rules about it.
Life can go wherever it wants to
Life can go wherever it wants to go.
doesn't seem to be any rules about it.
Life can go wherever it wants to go. It
can
can come
can come out
can come out of
can come out of spouts,
can come out of spouts, heat
can come out of spouts, heat spouts
can come out of spouts, heat spouts at
the
the bottom
can come out of spouts, heat spouts at
the bottom of
the bottom of the
can come out of spouts, heat spouts at
the bottom of the ocean
the bottom of the ocean at
can come out of spouts, heat spouts at
the bottom of the ocean at 540
the bottom of the ocean at 540 degrees
and
and life
and life can
and life can emerge,
and life can emerge, you
and life can emerge, you know,
and life can emerge, you know, is
and life can emerge, you know, is found
in
in lava
and life can emerge, you know, is found
in lava at
in lava at incredible
and life can emerge, you know, is found
in lava at incredible uh
in lava at incredible uh temperatures.
Why
Why there?
Why there? So
Why there? So why
Why there? So why is
Why there? So why is that
Why there? So why is that the
Why there? So why is that the correct
question?
Why
Why is
Why is why
Why is why not
Why is why not the
Why is why not the correct
Why is why not the correct question?
Because
Because why
Why is why not the correct question?
Because why is
Because why is never
Why is why not the correct question?
Because why is never a
Because why is never a correct
Why is why not the correct question?
Because why is never a correct question.
There
There is
There is no
There is no answer
There is no answer to
There is no answer to the
There is no answer to the question
There is no answer to the question why.
Yes.
And
And um
And um thank
And um thank you
And um thank you whoever
And um thank you whoever gave
And um thank you whoever gave me
And um thank you whoever gave me that
And um thank you whoever gave me that u
I
I was
And um thank you whoever gave me that u
I was going
I was going to
And um thank you whoever gave me that u
I was going to mention
I was going to mention that
And um thank you whoever gave me that u
I was going to mention that because
I was going to mention that because why
you
you see
you see is
you see is an
you see is an intellectualization
in
in which
you see is an intellectualization
in which you're
in which you're dealing
you see is an intellectualization
in which you're dealing with
in which you're dealing with tautologies
and
and the
and the hypothetical
and
and you
and the hypothetical
and you can
and you can be
and the hypothetical
and you can be extremely
and you can be extremely clever
and the hypothetical
and you can be extremely clever at
and you can be extremely clever at it
but
but there
but there is
but there is no
but there is no answer
but there is no answer to
but there is no answer to why
you
you can
but there is no answer to why
you can ask
you can ask how
but there is no answer to why
you can ask how by
you can ask how by what
but there is no answer to why
you can ask how by what means
you can ask how by what means or
but there is no answer to why
you can ask how by what means or but
you can ask how by what means or but why
there
there is
there is no
there is no answer
Why
Why is
there is no answer
Why is one
Why is one of
there is no answer
Why is one of the
Why is one of the uh
there is no answer
Why is one of the uh bull
Why is one of the uh bull works
there is no answer
Why is one of the uh bull works of
Why is one of the uh bull works of the
ego?
Why
Why me
ego?
Why me god?
Every
Every time
Every time somebody
Every time somebody asks
Every time somebody asks that
Every time somebody asks that I
Every time somebody asks that I say
Every time somebody asks that I say why
not
not you
Every time somebody asks that I say why
not you stupid?
not you stupid? Why
Every time somebody asks that I say why
not you stupid? Why not
not you stupid? Why not stupid?
Every time somebody asks that I say why
not you stupid? Why not stupid? Why
not you stupid? Why not stupid? Why not
you?
Why
Why not?
you?
Why not? Why
Why not? Why not?
Uh
Uh so
Uh so why
Uh so why am
Uh so why am I
Uh so why am I going
Uh so why am I going through
Uh so why am I going through this?
Uh so why am I going through this? Well,
the
the answer
Uh so why am I going through this? Well,
the answer is
the answer is because
Uh so why am I going through this? Well,
the answer is because that's
the answer is because that's the
Uh so why am I going through this? Well,
the answer is because that's the nature
of
of the
of the evolution
of the evolution of
of the evolution of consciousness.
of the evolution of consciousness. It
automatically
automatically so
apparently
apparently uh
apparently uh the
apparently uh the world
apparently uh the world population
apparently uh the world population can't
get
get to
apparently uh the world population can't
get to here.
get to here. It
apparently uh the world population can't
get to here. It starts
get to here. It starts out
apparently uh the world population can't
get to here. It starts out here
get to here. It starts out here and
comes
comes out
comes out of
comes out of the
comes out of the the
comes out of the the ooze
comes out of the the ooze and
comes out of the the ooze and evolves
comes out of the the ooze and evolves up
to
to hominid.
Uh
Uh we
Uh we don't
Uh we don't see
Uh we don't see the
Uh we don't see the first
Uh we don't see the first homid
Uh we don't see the first homid about
here,
here, the
Uh we don't see the first homid about
here, the ape
here, the ape uh
Uh we don't see the first homid about
here, the ape uh ape
here, the ape uh ape and
Uh we don't see the first homid about
here, the ape uh ape and the
here, the ape uh ape and the monkeys.
And
And we
And we work
And we work our
And we work our way
And we work our way on
And we work our way on up.
And we work our way on up. And
it's
it's not
And we work our way on up. And
it's not a
it's not a precise
And we work our way on up. And
it's not a precise kind
it's not a precise kind of
And we work our way on up. And
it's not a precise kind of an
it's not a precise kind of an evolution.
We
We said
We said the
We said the heart
We said the heart the
We said the heart the uh
We said the heart the uh the
We said the heart the uh the purr
We said the heart the uh the purr of
We said the heart the uh the purr of the
kitty
kitty is
We said the heart the uh the purr of the
kitty is still
kitty is still at
We said the heart the uh the purr of the
kitty is still at 500.
kitty is still at 500. Kitty's
We said the heart the uh the purr of the
kitty is still at 500. Kitty's purr
kitty is still at 500. Kitty's purr is
500.
500. The
500. The dog
500. The dog wagging
500. The dog wagging tail
500. The dog wagging tail is
500. The dog wagging tail is 500.
500. The dog wagging tail is 500. So
500. The dog wagging tail is 500. So it
isn't
isn't like
500. The dog wagging tail is 500. So it
isn't like the
isn't like the whole
500. The dog wagging tail is 500. So it
isn't like the whole thing
isn't like the whole thing marches
together.
together. The
together. The intellect
together. The intellect certainly
together. The intellect certainly is
together. The intellect certainly is not
the
the same
together. The intellect certainly is not
the same in
the same in the
together. The intellect certainly is not
the same in the kitty.
the same in the kitty. The
together. The intellect certainly is not
the same in the kitty. The intellect
the same in the kitty. The intellect is
not
not the
not the same.
The
The intellect
not the same.
The intellect is
The intellect is not
not the same.
The intellect is not the
The intellect is not the same
not the same.
The intellect is not the same in
The intellect is not the same in the
dinosaur
dinosaur and
dinosaur and bin
dinosaur and bin Laden.
dinosaur and bin Laden. But
dinosaur and bin Laden. But they
dinosaur and bin Laden. But they both
calibrate
calibrate the
dinosaur and bin Laden. But they both
calibrate the same
calibrate the same level.
How
How do
How do they
How do they both
How do they both come
How do they both come out
How do they both come out 70?
How do they both come out 70? One's
scaly
scaly and
How do they both come out 70? One's
scaly and vicious
scaly and vicious with
How do they both come out 70? One's
scaly and vicious with dragon.
One
One is
One is manifesting
One is manifesting in
One is manifesting in physical
One is manifesting in physical form
One is manifesting in physical form what
it
it is.
One is manifesting in physical form what
it is. The
it is. The other
One is manifesting in physical form what
it is. The other has
it is. The other has disguised
One is manifesting in physical form what
it is. The other has disguised itself
within
within a
within a human.
But
But it's
within a human.
But it's the
But it's the same
within a human.
But it's the same energy.
But it's the same energy. Same
within a human.
But it's the same energy. Same energy.
Same
Same energy.
Same energy. It
Same energy. It kills
Same energy. It kills out
Same energy. It kills out of
um
um that
Same energy. It kills out of
um that viciousness
um that viciousness which
Same energy. It kills out of
um that viciousness which is
um that viciousness which is part
Same energy. It kills out of
um that viciousness which is part of
that
that level
that level of
that level of consciousness.
that level of consciousness. So
that level of consciousness. So we
that level of consciousness. So we can't
make
make it
that level of consciousness. So we can't
make it wrong.
make it wrong. We
that level of consciousness. So we can't
make it wrong. We can't
make it wrong. We can't say
that level of consciousness. So we can't
make it wrong. We can't say bin
make it wrong. We can't say bin Ren
that level of consciousness. So we can't
make it wrong. We can't say bin Ren is
wrong.
wrong. Can't
wrong. Can't say
wrong. Can't say the
wrong. Can't say the dinosaur
wrong. Can't say the dinosaur is
wrong. Can't say the dinosaur is wrong.
Can't
Can't say
wrong. Can't say the dinosaur is wrong.
Can't say the
Can't say the Middle
wrong. Can't say the dinosaur is wrong.
Can't say the Middle East
Can't say the Middle East is
wrong. Can't say the dinosaur is wrong.
Can't say the Middle East is wrong.
Can't say the Middle East is wrong. We
just
just notice
just notice that
just notice that life
just notice that life evolves
just notice that life evolves in
just notice that life evolves in that
just notice that life evolves in that in
and
and it
just notice that life evolves in that in
and it evolves
and it evolves in
just notice that life evolves in that in
and it evolves in that
and it evolves in that way.
just notice that life evolves in that in
and it evolves in that way. Uh
so
so first
so first of
so first of all,
so first of all, you
so first of all, you could
so first of all, you could let
so first of all, you could let go
wanting
wanting to
so first of all, you could let go
wanting to change
wanting to change the
so first of all, you could let go
wanting to change the world
and
and you
and you could
and you could surrender
and you could surrender it
and you could surrender it to
and you could surrender it to God.
Even
Even if
and you could surrender it to God.
Even if the
Even if the world
and you could surrender it to God.
Even if the world is
Even if the world is the
and you could surrender it to God.
Even if the world is the way
Even if the world is the way you
and you could surrender it to God.
Even if the world is the way you see
Even if the world is the way you see it,
you
you still
you still have
you still have to
you still have to allow
you still have to allow God
you still have to allow God to
you still have to allow God to be
you still have to allow God to be God.
When
When it's
you still have to allow God to be God.
When it's time
When it's time for
you still have to allow God to be God.
When it's time for you
When it's time for you to
you still have to allow God to be God.
When it's time for you to become
When it's time for you to become savior
of
of the
of the world,
of the world, you'll
of the world, you'll be
of the world, you'll be notified.
But
But the
of the world, you'll be notified.
But the question
But the question brings
of the world, you'll be notified.
But the question brings up
But the question brings up you
of the world, you'll be notified.
But the question brings up you know
But the question brings up you know that
famous
famous teaching
famous teaching of
famous teaching of Ramana
famous teaching of Ramana Maharshi
famous teaching of Ramana Maharshi the
reason
reason I
famous teaching of Ramana Maharshi the
reason I quote
reason I quote Raman
famous teaching of Ramana Maharshi the
reason I quote Raman Harshi
reason I quote Raman Harshi and
famous teaching of Ramana Maharshi the
reason I quote Raman Harshi and Mr.
reason I quote Raman Harshi and Mr. hear
that
that Maharaj
that Maharaj a
that Maharaj a lot
that Maharaj a lot is
that Maharaj a lot is because
that Maharaj a lot is because they
that Maharaj a lot is because they lived
in
in recent
that Maharaj a lot is because they lived
in recent years
in recent years and
that Maharaj a lot is because they lived
in recent years and what
in recent years and what they
that Maharaj a lot is because they lived
in recent years and what they said
in recent years and what they said was
taken
taken down
taken down verbatim.
taken down verbatim. So
taken down verbatim. So we
taken down verbatim. So we know
taken down verbatim. So we know exactly
what
what they
taken down verbatim. So we know exactly
what they said
what they said in
taken down verbatim. So we know exactly
what they said in response
what they said in response to
taken down verbatim. So we know exactly
what they said in response to certain
questions.
questions. When
questions. When you
questions. When you go
questions. When you go back
questions. When you go back to
questions. When you go back to gurus
that
that are
questions. When you go back to gurus
that are 2500
that are 2500 years
questions. When you go back to gurus
that are 2500 years old,
that are 2500 years old, does
questions. When you go back to gurus
that are 2500 years old, does anybody's
guess
guess what
guess what they
guess what they said
guess what they said or
guess what they said or how
guess what they said or how it
guess what they said or how it was
interpreted?
But
But you
But you remember
But you remember Ramana
But you remember Ramana Mahari
But you remember Ramana Mahari said
there's
there's no
But you remember Ramana Mahari said
there's no point
there's no point in
But you remember Ramana Mahari said
there's no point in trying
there's no point in trying to
But you remember Ramana Mahari said
there's no point in trying to save
there's no point in trying to save the
world
world because
world because the
world because the world
world because the world that
world because the world that you
perceive
perceive doesn't
world because the world that you
perceive doesn't even
perceive doesn't even exist.
It's
It's all
It's all a
It's all a projection
It's all a projection of
It's all a projection of your
It's all a projection of your own
perception.
And
And these
And these are
And these are maybe
And these are maybe people
And these are maybe people working
And these are maybe people working out
their
their own
And these are maybe people working out
their own salvation.
their own salvation. And
And these are maybe people working out
their own salvation. And to
their own salvation. And to you
And these are maybe people working out
their own salvation. And to you that
looks
looks like,
looks like, you
looks like, you know,
looks like, you know, I
looks like, you know, I remember
looks like, you know, I remember that
life.
life. I
looks like, you know, I remember that
life. I I've
life. I I've already
looks like, you know, I remember that
life. I I've already cited
life. I I've already cited some
lifetimes
lifetimes to
lifetimes to which
lifetimes to which I
lifetimes to which I learned
lifetimes to which I learned those
lessons
lessons myself.
lifetimes to which I learned those
lessons myself. So
lessons myself. So you
lifetimes to which I learned those
lessons myself. So you don't
lessons myself. So you don't become
lifetimes to which I learned those
lessons myself. So you don't become a
saint,
saint, you
saint, you know,
saint, you know, without
saint, you know, without becoming
without
without being
saint, you know, without becoming
without being a
without being a pirate
saint, you know, without becoming
without being a pirate at
without being a pirate at one
saint, you know, without becoming
without being a pirate at one time
apparently.
And
And uh
apparently.
And uh a
And uh a lot
apparently.
And uh a lot of
And uh a lot of the
apparently.
And uh a lot of the rather
And uh a lot of the rather difficult
apparently.
And uh a lot of the rather difficult pro
lessons
lessons I've
lessons I've learned,
lessons I've learned, you
lessons I've learned, you know,
lessons I've learned, you know, were
were
were lived
lessons I've learned, you know, were
were lived through.
were lived through. So
lessons I've learned, you know, were
were lived through. So perhaps
consciousness
consciousness has
consciousness has to
consciousness has to evolve
consciousness has to evolve through
consciousness has to evolve through the
lower
lower chakras
consciousness has to evolve through the
lower chakras in
lower chakras in order
consciousness has to evolve through the
lower chakras in order to
lower chakras in order to get
consciousness has to evolve through the
lower chakras in order to get to
lower chakras in order to get to the
higher
higher chakra.
higher chakra. I
higher chakra. I don't
higher chakra. I don't know.
higher chakra. I don't know. Um
certainly
certainly the
higher chakra. I don't know. Um
certainly the intention
certainly the intention of
higher chakra. I don't know. Um
certainly the intention of praying
certainly the intention of praying for
the
the world
the world has
the world has a
the world has a collective
the world has a collective benefit
effect.
effect. Let's
the world has a collective benefit
effect. Let's see
effect. Let's see if
the world has a collective benefit
effect. Let's see if that's
effect. Let's see if that's so
the world has a collective benefit
effect. Let's see if that's so this
effect. Let's see if that's so this has
a
a collective
a collective benefit
a collective benefit effect.
a collective benefit effect. It
a collective benefit effect. It does
have
have a
a collective benefit effect. It does
have a collective
have a collective benefit
a collective benefit effect. It does
have a collective benefit effect.
Um
Um but
Um but the
Um but the motivation
Um but the motivation is
Um but the motivation is different.
Um but the motivation is different. The
motivation
u
u to
u to send
u to send one's
u to send one's love
u to send one's love and
u to send one's love and forgiveness
u to send one's love and forgiveness etc
out
out into
u to send one's love and forgiveness etc
out into the
out into the world.
u to send one's love and forgiveness etc
out into the world. You're
out into the world. You're not
u to send one's love and forgiveness etc
out into the world. You're not trying
out into the world. You're not trying to
control
control something
control something you
control something you see.
control something you see. So
control something you see. So the
control something you see. So the ego
control something you see. So the ego is
into
into control
control something you see. So the ego is
into control and
um
um the
um the spiritual
um the spiritual ego
um the spiritual ego is
um the spiritual ego is into
um the spiritual ego is into controlling
people
people for
um the spiritual ego is into controlling
people for pious
people for pious reasons.
But
But it's
But it's still
But it's still control.
If
If you
But it's still control.
If you want
If you want to
But it's still control.
If you want to control
If you want to control people
But it's still control.
If you want to control people for
If you want to control people for their
own
own good,
own good, it's
own good, it's still
own good, it's still wanting
own good, it's still wanting to
own good, it's still wanting to control
them,
them, right?
own good, it's still wanting to control
them, right? Like
them, right? Like you
own good, it's still wanting to control
them, right? Like you want
them, right? Like you want to
own good, it's still wanting to control
them, right? Like you want to you
them, right? Like you want to you want
to
to get
to get them
to get them sober,
to get them sober, right?
to get them sober, right? Well,
to get them sober, right? Well, first
step
step in
to get them sober, right? Well, first
step in Alanon
step in Alanon is
to get them sober, right? Well, first
step in Alanon is to
step in Alanon is to let
to get them sober, right? Well, first
step in Alanon is to let go
step in Alanon is to let go wanting
to get them sober, right? Well, first
step in Alanon is to let go wanting to
control
control that
control that which
control that which is
control that which is out
control that which is out there
control that which is out there because
it
it finds
control that which is out there because
it finds its
it finds its own
control that which is out there because
it finds its own salvation.
it finds its own salvation. You're
control that which is out there because
it finds its own salvation. You're going
to
to deprive
to deprive them
to deprive them of
to deprive them of the
to deprive them of the karmic
to deprive them of the karmic benefit
of
evolving
evolving and
evolving and evolving
evolving and evolving in
evolving and evolving in the
evolving and evolving in the karmic
merit
merit of
evolving and evolving in the karmic
merit of choosing.
merit of choosing. So
evolving and evolving in the karmic
merit of choosing. So if
merit of choosing. So if you
evolving and evolving in the karmic
merit of choosing. So if you force
somebody,
somebody, you
somebody, you rob
somebody, you rob them
somebody, you rob them of
somebody, you rob them of the
somebody, you rob them of the karmic
merit
merit of
somebody, you rob them of the karmic
merit of making
merit of making that
somebody, you rob them of the karmic
merit of making that choice
merit of making that choice because
one's
one's level
one's level of
one's level of consciousness
one's level of consciousness is
determined
determined by
one's level of consciousness is
determined by choice
determined by choice by
one's level of consciousness is
determined by choice by the
determined by choice by the spiritual
free
free will.
So
So if
free will.
So if we
So if we force
free will.
So if we force conditions
So if we force conditions then
free will.
So if we force conditions then in
So if we force conditions then in a
free will.
So if we force conditions then in a way
we
we do
we do a
we do a disservice
we do a disservice spiritually
we do a disservice spiritually because
the
the only
we do a disservice spiritually because
the only reason
the only reason they're
we do a disservice spiritually because
the only reason they're doing
the only reason they're doing that
we do a disservice spiritually because
the only reason they're doing that is
because
because we
because we have
because we have them
because we have them locked
because we have them locked up.
because we have them locked up. That
because we have them locked up. That is
not
not a
because we have them locked up. That is
not a choice
not a choice on
because we have them locked up. That is
not a choice on their
not a choice on their part.
because we have them locked up. That is
not a choice on their part. They
not a choice on their part. They have
not
not hit
not hit bottom
not hit bottom about
not hit bottom about it.
not hit bottom about it. Sooner
not hit bottom about it. Sooner or
later,
later, you
not hit bottom about it. Sooner or
later, you would
later, you would think
not hit bottom about it. Sooner or
later, you would think the
later, you would think the Middle
not hit bottom about it. Sooner or
later, you would think the Middle East
would
would hit
would hit bottom.
Think
Think that's
would hit bottom.
Think that's probably
Think that's probably fellacious.
There's
There's so
There's so much
There's so much gratification
There's so much gratification and
There's so much gratification and fun
There's so much gratification and fun in
all
all this
There's so much gratification and fun in
all this playing
all this playing hero
There's so much gratification and fun in
all this playing hero and
all this playing hero and victim
There's so much gratification and fun in
all this playing hero and victim and
perpetrator
perpetrator that
perpetrator that I
perpetrator that I doubt
perpetrator that I doubt this
perpetrator that I doubt this game
perpetrator that I doubt this game is
going
going to
perpetrator that I doubt this game is
going to quit
going to quit for
perpetrator that I doubt this game is
going to quit for a
going to quit for a long,
perpetrator that I doubt this game is
going to quit for a long, long
going to quit for a long, long time.
Besides,
Besides, with
Besides, with people
Besides, with people who
Besides, with people who have
Besides, with people who have those
lessons
lessons to
Besides, with people who have those
lessons to learn,
lessons to learn, where
Besides, with people who have those
lessons to learn, where else
lessons to learn, where else can
Besides, with people who have those
lessons to learn, where else can they
lessons to learn, where else can they go
on
on the
on the planet
on the planet to
on the planet to learn
on the planet to learn that
you
you can
on the planet to learn that
you can overcome,
you can overcome, you
on the planet to learn that
you can overcome, you can't
you can overcome, you can't overcome
your
your fear
your fear of
your fear of physical
your fear of physical death
your fear of physical death until
your fear of physical death until you
actually
actually walk
your fear of physical death until you
actually walk into
actually walk into bullets.
your fear of physical death until you
actually walk into bullets. You've
actually walk into bullets. You've got
to
to really
to really walk
to really walk into
to really walk into them.
And
And then
to really walk into them.
And then you
And then you pop
to really walk into them.
And then you pop out
And then you pop out a
to really walk into them.
And then you pop out a body
And then you pop out a body and
to really walk into them.
And then you pop out a body and you
realize
one
one time
realize
one time on
one time on a
realize
one time on a slave
one time on a slave ship
realize
one time on a slave ship chained
one time on a slave ship chained to
realize
one time on a slave ship chained to this
ore.
The
The details
ore.
The details are
The details are gory.
ore.
The details are gory. I
The details are gory. I don't
ore.
The details are gory. I don't want
The details are gory. I don't want to
ore.
The details are gory. I don't want to go
into
into it,
into it, but
into it, but there
into it, but there were
into it, but there were no
into it, but there were no latrines
into it, but there were no latrines or
anything
anything else.
into it, but there were no latrines or
anything else. And
anything else. And once
into it, but there were no latrines or
anything else. And once in
anything else. And once in a
into it, but there were no latrines or
anything else. And once in a while
anything else. And once in a while when
the
the beat
the beat the
the beat the guy
the beat the guy that
the beat the guy that led
the beat the guy that led the
the beat the guy that led the beat
couldn't
couldn't stand
the beat the guy that led the beat
couldn't stand it
couldn't stand it anymore.
the beat the guy that led the beat
couldn't stand it anymore. They'd
couldn't stand it anymore. They'd open
all
all the
all the port
all the port holes
all the port holes and
all the port holes and it
all the port holes and it was
all the port holes and it was horrible.
So
So anyway,
this
this torture
this torture and
this torture and torment
this torture and torment and
this torture and torment and being
beaten
beaten up
this torture and torment and being
beaten up and
beaten up and all
this torture and torment and being
beaten up and all the
beaten up and all the rest
this torture and torment and being
beaten up and all the rest and
beaten up and all the rest and finally
reached
reached the
reached the point
reached the point I
reached the point I could
reached the point I could not
reached the point I could not push
myself
myself on
reached the point I could not push
myself on forever
and
and suddenly
and suddenly came
and suddenly came like
and suddenly came like a
and suddenly came like a light.
You're
You're not
and suddenly came like a light.
You're not trapped.
You're not trapped. I
and suddenly came like a light.
You're not trapped. I left
You're not trapped. I left the
and suddenly came like a light.
You're not trapped. I left the body.
You're not trapped. I left the body. The
dead
dead body
dead body lay
dead body lay there.
dead body lay there. I
dead body lay there. I was
dead body lay there. I was free
dead body lay there. I was free as
dead body lay there. I was free as a
bird.
Without
Without enslavement,
Without enslavement, without
Without enslavement, without torture,
without
without the
Without enslavement, without torture,
without the extremity
without the extremity of
Without enslavement, without torture,
without the extremity of the
without the extremity of the situation,
I
I would
I would have
I would have never
I would have never had
I would have never had the
I would have never had the courage
I would have never had the courage to
transcend
transcend it.
I would have never had the courage to
transcend it. Suddenly,
transcend it. Suddenly, like
I would have never had the courage to
transcend it. Suddenly, like a
knowingness
knowingness said,
knowingness said, you
knowingness said, you don't
knowingness said, you don't you're
knowingness said, you don't you're free.
And
And I
knowingness said, you don't you're free.
And I just
And I just let
knowingness said, you don't you're free.
And I just let go,
And I just let go, wanting
knowingness said, you don't you're free.
And I just let go, wanting to
And I just let go, wanting to just
knowingness said, you don't you're free.
And I just let go, wanting to just be
with
with the
with the body,
with the body, and
with the body, and it
with the body, and it croked
with the body, and it croked and
with the body, and it croked and I
with the body, and it croked and I was
free.
free. End
with the body, and it croked and I was
free. End of
free. End of torture,
with the body, and it croked and I was
free. End of torture, end
free. End of torture, end of
with the body, and it croked and I was
free. End of torture, end of torment.
Screw
Screw you.
Up.
Up. Well,
Screw you.
Up. Well, this
Up. Well, this is
Screw you.
Up. Well, this is the
Up. Well, this is the first
Screw you.
Up. Well, this is the first time
Up. Well, this is the first time I
Screw you.
Up. Well, this is the first time I did
the
the finger.
They
They had
the finger.
They had to
They had to haul
the finger.
They had to haul the
They had to haul the dead
the finger.
They had to haul the dead body
They had to haul the dead body out
the finger.
They had to haul the dead body out and
everything.
everything. So
everything. So there,
everything. So there, you
everything. So there, you know.
everything. So there, you know. All
right.
right. So,
everything. So there, you know. All
right. So, you
right. So, you need
everything. So there, you know. All
right. So, you need slave
right. So, you need slave ships
everything. So there, you know. All
right. So, you need slave ships and
galleys
galleys and
galleys and you
galleys and you need
galleys and you need torture
galleys and you need torture chambers.
You
You need
galleys and you need torture chambers.
You need you
You need you hate
galleys and you need torture chambers.
You need you hate to
You need you hate to say
galleys and you need torture chambers.
You need you hate to say that,
You need you hate to say that, but
galleys and you need torture chambers.
You need you hate to say that, but I
don't
don't know
don't know why
don't know why the
don't know why the ego
don't know why the ego is
don't know why the ego is so
don't know why the ego is so resistant.
This
This is
don't know why the ego is so resistant.
This is a
This is a whole
don't know why the ego is so resistant.
This is a whole area
This is a whole area for
don't know why the ego is so resistant.
This is a whole area for research.
This is a whole area for research. Why
people
people have
people have to
people have to hit
people have to hit such
people have to hit such a
people have to hit such a bottom
people have to hit such a bottom before
they
they get
people have to hit such a bottom before
they get a
they get a point?
people have to hit such a bottom before
they get a point? And
they get a point? And sometimes
people have to hit such a bottom before
they get a point? And sometimes the
point
point is
point is so
point is so simple
point is so simple you'd
point is so simple you'd say
point is so simple you'd say how
point is so simple you'd say how nobody
would
would have
point is so simple you'd say how nobody
would have any
would have any trouble
point is so simple you'd say how nobody
would have any trouble admitting
would have any trouble admitting that
about
about themsel
about themsel that
about themsel that they
about themsel that they were
about themsel that they were wrong
about themsel that they were wrong about
some
some simple
about themsel that they were wrong about
some simple little
some simple little thing
about themsel that they were wrong about
some simple little thing and
some simple little thing and people
about themsel that they were wrong about
some simple little thing and people will
practically
practically go
practically go to
practically go to the
practically go to the gallows
practically go to the gallows rather
than
than admit
practically go to the gallows rather
than admit you
than admit you know
practically go to the gallows rather
than admit you know that
than admit you know that they
practically go to the gallows rather
than admit you know that they were
than admit you know that they were you
know
know they
know they left
know they left the
know they left the wrong
know they left the wrong change
know they left the wrong change on
know they left the wrong change on the
counter
counter or
know they left the wrong change on the
counter or something.
counter or something. I
know they left the wrong change on the
counter or something. I mean
counter or something. I mean know
know they left the wrong change on the
counter or something. I mean know this
is
is not
is not a
is not a super
is not a super crisis
is not a super crisis but
is not a super crisis but you've
is not a super crisis but you've seen
that
that in
is not a super crisis but you've seen
that in your
that in your own
is not a super crisis but you've seen
that in your own life
that in your own life haven't
is not a super crisis but you've seen
that in your own life haven't you?
People
People go
People go to
People go to the
People go to the extreme
People go to the extreme over
People go to the extreme over some
triviality.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So there
All right. So there must
All right. So there must be
All right. So there must be some
All right. So there must be some great
karmic
karmic lesson
All right. So there must be some great
karmic lesson to
karmic lesson to be
All right. So there must be some great
karmic lesson to be learned
karmic lesson to be learned in
All right. So there must be some great
karmic lesson to be learned in what
karmic lesson to be learned in what we
witness
witness out
witness out there.
witness out there. So
witness out there. So we
witness out there. So we witness
witness out there. So we witness what
witness out there. So we witness what we
think
think is
witness out there. So we witness what we
think is happening
think is happening out
witness out there. So we witness what we
think is happening out there.
think is happening out there. If
witness out there. So we witness what we
think is happening out there. If these
are
are 78%
are 78% of
are 78% of the
are 78% of the population
are 78% of the population or
are 78% of the population or 85
are 78% of the population or 85 or
whatever
whatever the
are 78% of the population or 85 or
whatever the world
whatever the world it
are 78% of the population or 85 or
whatever the world it is,
whatever the world it is, 78%
are 78% of the population or 85 or
whatever the world it is, 78% now
whatever the world it is, 78% now I
guess
guess these
guess these people
guess these people all
guess these people all have
guess these people all have to
guess these people all have to have
guess these people all have to have a
life.
life. They
guess these people all have to have a
life. They have
life. They have to
guess these people all have to have a
life. They have to live
life. They have to live someplace.
guess these people all have to have a
life. They have to live someplace. They
have
have to
have to have
have to have a
have to have a job.
have to have a job. They
have to have a job. They have
have to have a job. They have to
have to have a job. They have to eat.
They
They have
have to have a job. They have to eat.
They have to
They have to stay
have to have a job. They have to eat.
They have to stay alive.
They have to stay alive. So
have to have a job. They have to eat.
They have to stay alive. So all
They have to stay alive. So all these
people
people are
people are going
people are going to
people are going to lead
people are going to lead these
people are going to lead these kind
people are going to lead these kind of
lifestyles.
If
If you're
If you're driven
If you're driven by
If you're driven by greed
If you're driven by greed in
If you're driven by greed in the
If you're driven by greed in the solar
plexus,
plexus, then
If you're driven by greed in the solar
plexus, then you're
plexus, then you're going
If you're driven by greed in the solar
plexus, then you're going to
plexus, then you're going to become
president
president of
president of a
president of a giant
president of a giant corporation
president of a giant corporation and
milk
milk it
president of a giant corporation and
milk it for
milk it for the
president of a giant corporation and
milk it for the milky
milk it for the milky millions.
president of a giant corporation and
milk it for the milky millions. You
milk it for the milky millions. You got
to
to have
to have someplace
to have someplace to
to have someplace to do
to have someplace to do that.
to have someplace to do that. You
to have someplace to do that. You can't
do
do that
to have someplace to do that. You can't
do that as
do that as a
to have someplace to do that. You can't
do that as a slave
do that as a slave in
to have someplace to do that. You can't
do that as a slave in a
do that as a slave in a galley.
to have someplace to do that. You can't
do that as a slave in a galley. I
do that as a slave in a galley. I mean,
that
that was
that was an
that was an opportunity
that was an opportunity there.
that was an opportunity there. There
that was an opportunity there. There was
not
not an
that was an opportunity there. There was
not an opportunity.
not an opportunity. That
that was an opportunity there. There was
not an opportunity. That was
not an opportunity. That was not
that was an opportunity there. There was
not an opportunity. That was not an
option.
option. So,
option. So, you
option. So, you you
option. So, you you probably
option. So, you you probably um
option. So, you you probably um reinvent
yourself
yourself karmically.
option. So, you you probably um reinvent
yourself karmically. You
yourself karmically. You reinvent
yourself.
yourself. Now,
yourself. Now, somebody
yourself. Now, somebody asked
yourself. Now, somebody asked about
causality
causality and
yourself. Now, somebody asked about
causality and karma.
causality and karma. Karma
yourself. Now, somebody asked about
causality and karma. Karma does
causality and karma. Karma does not
cause
cause anything.
cause anything. You
cause anything. You see,
cause anything. You see, everything
cause anything. You see, everything in
the
the universe
cause anything. You see, everything in
the universe is
the universe is free
cause anything. You see, everything in
the universe is free choice.
the universe is free choice. Everything
in
in the
in the universe
in the universe is
in the universe is free
in the universe is free choice.
in the universe is free choice. You
in the universe is free choice. You have
to
to get
in the universe is free choice. You have
to get off
to get off this
in the universe is free choice. You have
to get off this delusion
to get off this delusion about
causality.
Causality
Causality is
causality.
Causality is a
Causality is a hypothetical
causality.
Causality is a hypothetical operant.
Operant,
Operant, a
Operant, a hypothetical
Operant, a hypothetical operant.
Operant, a hypothetical operant. It
exists
exists only
Operant, a hypothetical operant. It
exists only as
exists only as a
Operant, a hypothetical operant. It
exists only as a hypothesis.
Hypothetical
Hypothetical operant.
Hypothetical operant. It's
Hypothetical operant. It's a
Hypothetical operant. It's a tautology.
It
It has
Hypothetical operant. It's a tautology.
It has no
It has no existence
Hypothetical operant. It's a tautology.
It has no existence in
It has no existence in reality.
Hypothetical operant. It's a tautology.
It has no existence in reality. You
cannot
cannot show
cannot show me
cannot show me any
cannot show me any causality
cannot show me any causality anywhere.
The
The only
cannot show me any causality anywhere.
The only place
The only place causality
cannot show me any causality anywhere.
The only place causality exists
The only place causality exists is
cannot show me any causality anywhere.
The only place causality exists is as
The only place causality exists is as a
thought
thought in
thought in your
thought in your mind.
thought in your mind. You
thought in your mind. You don't
thought in your mind. You don't see
anything
anything causing
thought in your mind. You don't see
anything causing anything
anything causing anything there
thought in your mind. You don't see
anything causing anything there at
anything causing anything there at all.
Nothing's
Nothing's causing
Nothing's causing anything.
Nothing's causing anything. It
Nothing's causing anything. It is
Nothing's causing anything. It is that
way.
way. Everything
Nothing's causing anything. It is that
way. Everything is
way. Everything is what
Nothing's causing anything. It is that
way. Everything is what it
way. Everything is what it is.
Nothing's causing anything. It is that
way. Everything is what it is. If
way. Everything is what it is. If it
Nothing's causing anything. It is that
way. Everything is what it is. If it is
what
what it
what it is,
what it is, it
what it is, it doesn't
what it is, it doesn't have
what it is, it doesn't have to
what it is, it doesn't have to be
caused,
caused, does
what it is, it doesn't have to be
caused, does it?
Existence
Existence is
Existence is sufficient
Existence is sufficient evidence
Existence is sufficient evidence in
Existence is sufficient evidence in and
of
of itself.
Existence is sufficient evidence in and
of itself. It
of itself. It doesn't
Existence is sufficient evidence in and
of itself. It doesn't require
of itself. It doesn't require some
hypothesis
hypothesis outside
hypothesis outside of
hypothesis outside of it
hypothesis outside of it itself
hypothesis outside of it itself because
existence
existence does
hypothesis outside of it itself because
existence does not
existence does not require
hypothesis outside of it itself because
existence does not require an
explanation.
explanation. It
explanation. It is
explanation. It is its
explanation. It is its own
explanation. It is its own explanation
because
because it
explanation. It is its own explanation
because it is
because it is it.
I
I forgot
I forgot what
I forgot what the
I forgot what the question
I forgot what the question was.
That
That question
I forgot what the question was.
That question of
That question of causality
I forgot what the question was.
That question of causality keeps
That question of causality keeps coming
back.
back. No,
back. No, it
back. No, it had
back. No, it had to
back. No, it had to do
back. No, it had to do with
back. No, it had to do with karma
back. No, it had to do with karma and
causality.
causality. that
back. No, it had to do with karma and
causality. that karma
causality. that karma you
back. No, it had to do with karma and
causality. that karma you know
causality. that karma you know the
back. No, it had to do with karma and
causality. that karma you know the way
causality. that karma you know the way I
picture
picture it
picture it in
picture it in my
picture it in my mind
picture it in my mind I
picture it in my mind I don't
picture it in my mind I don't actually
picture
picture it
picture it in my mind I don't actually
picture it in
picture it in my
picture it in my mind I don't actually
picture it in my mind
what
what we
what we how
what we how should
what we how should we
what we how should we read
what we how should we read languages
karma
karma is
what we how should we read languages
karma is like
karma is like the
what we how should we read languages
karma is like the accumulated
karma is like the accumulated energy
field
field like
field like a
field like a computer
field like a computer chip
field like a computer chip that's
field like a computer chip that's part
of
of one's
field like a computer chip that's part
of one's spiritual
of one's spiritual body
field like a computer chip that's part
of one's spiritual body that
of one's spiritual body that follows
field like a computer chip that's part
of one's spiritual body that follows you
along
along around
along around you
along around you can
along around you can reincarnate
along around you can reincarnate because
that
that is
along around you can reincarnate because
that is favorable
that is favorable to
along around you can reincarnate because
that is favorable to c
that is favorable to c certain
along around you can reincarnate because
that is favorable to c certain karmic
resolutions
resolutions or
resolutions or you
resolutions or you may
resolutions or you may not
resolutions or you may not incarnate
resolutions or you may not incarnate you
may
may go
resolutions or you may not incarnate you
may go to
may go to other
resolutions or you may not incarnate you
may go to other domains
may go to other domains and
resolutions or you may not incarnate you
may go to other domains and dimensions
there's
there's an
there's an infinite
there's an infinite number
there's an infinite number number
there's an infinite number number of
dimensions.
Let's
Let's see
Let's see if
Let's see if that's
Let's see if that's so.
There's
There's an
Let's see if that's so.
There's an infinite
There's an infinite number
Let's see if that's so.
There's an infinite number of
There's an infinite number of dimensions
and
and one
and one is
and one is karmically
and one is karmically free
and one is karmically free to
and one is karmically free to choose.
and one is karmically free to choose. Is
it?
it? There's
and one is karmically free to choose. Is
it? There's an
it? There's an infinite
and one is karmically free to choose. Is
it? There's an infinite number
it? There's an infinite number of
dimensions.
dimensions. People
dimensions. People will
dimensions. People will see,
dimensions. People will see, well,
there's
there's the
dimensions. People will see, well,
there's the earth
there's the earth and
dimensions. People will see, well,
there's the earth and then
there's the earth and then there's
heaven
heaven and
heaven and there's
heaven and there's hell.
heaven and there's hell. Oh
heaven and there's hell. Oh my
heaven and there's hell. Oh my god,
there's
there's an
heaven and there's hell. Oh my god,
there's an infinite
there's an infinite number
heaven and there's hell. Oh my god,
there's an infinite number of
there's an infinite number of dimensions
and
and they
and they expand
and they expand at
and they expand at an
and they expand at an infinite
and they expand at an infinite rate.
an
an infinite
and they expand at an infinite rate.
an infinite number
an infinite number of
and they expand at an infinite rate.
an infinite number of dimensions
expanding
expanding at
expanding at an
expanding at an infinite
expanding at an infinite rate
expanding at an infinite rate at
expanding at an infinite rate at the
rate
rate of
expanding at an infinite rate at the
rate of infinity
rate of infinity might
expanding at an infinite rate at the
rate of infinity might say.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So if
All right. So if the
All right. So if the vi
All right. So if the vi let's
All right. So if the vi let's say
All right. So if the vi let's say the
vibrational
vibrational pill
the
the vibrational
the vibrational chip
the
the vibrational
the vibrational chip
the vibrational chip in
the vibrational chip in your
the vibrational chip
the vibrational chip in your spiritual
body
body that
body that would
body that would vibrate
body that would vibrate at
body that would vibrate at a
body that would vibrate at a certain
frequency
frequency and
body that would vibrate at a certain
frequency and it
frequency and it gravitates
body that would vibrate at a certain
frequency and it gravitates towards
frequency and it gravitates towards that
to
to which
to which it
to which it is
to which it is most
to which it is most perfect.
Just
Just like
to which it is most perfect.
Just like a
Just like a dandelion
to which it is most perfect.
Just like a dandelion sea
Just like a dandelion sea floats
to which it is most perfect.
Just like a dandelion sea floats through
the
the air
the air depending
the air depending on
the air depending on the
the air depending on the the
the air depending on the the waves
the air depending on the the waves and
with
with the
the air depending on the the waves and
with the humidity
with the humidity and
the air depending on the the waves and
with the humidity and how
with the humidity and how old
the air depending on the the waves and
with the humidity and how old it
with the humidity and how old it is
the air depending on the the waves and
with the humidity and how old it is and
the
the gravity
the gravity and
the gravity and it
the gravity and it floats
the gravity and it floats into
the gravity and it floats into a
the gravity and it floats into a place
that's
that's just
the gravity and it floats into a place
that's just right
that's just right on
the gravity and it floats into a place
that's just right on top
that's just right on top of
the gravity and it floats into a place
that's just right on top of a
that's just right on top of a cherry
tree
tree leaf,
which
which is
tree leaf,
which is not
which is not right.
tree leaf,
which is not right. If
which is not right. If you
tree leaf,
which is not right. If you want
which is not right. If you want to
tree leaf,
which is not right. If you want to be
which is not right. If you want to be a
dandelion,
you
you can't
dandelion,
you can't grow
you can't grow on
dandelion,
you can't grow on top
you can't grow on top of
dandelion,
you can't grow on top of a
you can't grow on top of a cherry
dandelion,
you can't grow on top of a cherry leaf
tree
tree leaf.
tree leaf. So
tree leaf. So then
tree leaf. So then another
tree leaf. So then another wind
tree leaf. So then another wind comes
along
along and
tree leaf. So then another wind comes
along and oh
along and oh you
tree leaf. So then another wind comes
along and oh you go
along and oh you go off
tree leaf. So then another wind comes
along and oh you go off the
along and oh you go off the cherry
tree leaf. So then another wind comes
along and oh you go off the cherry tree
leaf
leaf and
leaf and now
leaf and now you
leaf and now you land
leaf and now you land down
leaf and now you land down here
leaf and now you land down here and
leaf and now you land down here and you
get
get born
leaf and now you land down here and you
get born in
get born in Milwaukee,
leaf and now you land down here and you
get born in Milwaukee, Wisconsin
and
and learn
and learn German
and learn German in
and learn German in school
and learn German in school cuz
and learn German in school cuz everybody
walks
walks German.
Then
Then you
Then you get
Then you get older
Then you get older and
Then you get older and you
Then you get older and you move
Then you get older and you move away
Then you get older and you move away and
you
you forget
Then you get older and you move away and
you forget your
you forget your German.
Then you get older and you move away and
you forget your German. So
then
then you
then you wish
then you wish you
then you wish you know
then you wish you know how
then you wish you know how to
then you wish you know how to speak
Spanish.
Spanish. Oh
then you wish you know how to speak
Spanish. Oh god.
Um
what
what about
Um
what about the
what about the falling
Um
what about the falling of
what about the falling of people's
calibration?
calibration? We
calibration? We already
calibration? We already mentioned
calibration? We already mentioned that
karmic
karmic choices
calibration? We already mentioned that
karmic choices are
karmic choices are constantly
calibration? We already mentioned that
karmic choices are constantly present.
They're
They're limited.
They're limited. They're
They're limited. They're limited.
They're limited. They're limited. Karmic
choices
choices are
They're limited. They're limited. Karmic
choices are limited
choices are limited by
They're limited. They're limited. Karmic
choices are limited by whatever
choices are limited by whatever domain
you
you happen
you happen to
you happen to be
you happen to be calibrated
you happen to be calibrated in.
you happen to be calibrated in. So
you happen to be calibrated in. So for
that
that reason,
you happen to be calibrated in. So for
that reason, um
that reason, um there's
you happen to be calibrated in. So for
that reason, um there's a
that reason, um there's a limitation
you happen to be calibrated in. So for
that reason, um there's a limitation to
freedom
freedom of
freedom of choice.
freedom of choice. That's
freedom of choice. That's why
freedom of choice. That's why we
freedom of choice. That's why we try
freedom of choice. That's why we try to
pick
pick that
freedom of choice. That's why we try to
pick that which
pick that which is
freedom of choice. That's why we try to
pick that which is appropriate
pick that which is appropriate where
freedom of choice. That's why we try to
pick that which is appropriate where the
conditions
conditions are
conditions are appropriate.
You
You see,
conditions are appropriate.
You see, a
You see, a giraffe
conditions are appropriate.
You see, a giraffe is
You see, a giraffe is not
conditions are appropriate.
You see, a giraffe is not given
You see, a giraffe is not given the
opportunity
opportunity to
opportunity to be
opportunity to be a
opportunity to be a cat.
opportunity to be a cat. You
opportunity to be a cat. You know
opportunity to be a cat. You know what
I'm
I'm saying?
opportunity to be a cat. You know what
I'm saying? It's
I'm saying? It's not
opportunity to be a cat. You know what
I'm saying? It's not within
I'm saying? It's not within his
opportunity to be a cat. You know what
I'm saying? It's not within his choice.
So
So each
So each karmic
So each karmic kernel
So each karmic kernel you
So each karmic kernel you might
So each karmic kernel you might say
So each karmic kernel you might say that
is
is carried
So each karmic kernel you might say that
is carried on
is carried on into
So each karmic kernel you might say that
is carried on into the
is carried on into the next
So each karmic kernel you might say that
is carried on into the next lifetime
determines
determines all
determines all these
determines all these multiple
determines all these multiple things
and
and it
determines all these multiple things
and it does
and it does so
determines all these multiple things
and it does so almost
and it does so almost like
determines all these multiple things
and it does so almost like uh
and it does so almost like uh gravity.
It
It almost
It almost does
It almost does like
wind
wind currents
It almost does like
wind currents on
wind currents on a
seed.
Uh
Uh this
seed.
Uh this is
Uh this is a
seed.
Uh this is a good
Uh this is a good one.
seed.
Uh this is a good one. What
Uh this is a good one. What must
seed.
Uh this is a good one. What must one
Uh this is a good one. What must one be
at
at the
at the depth
at the depth of
at the depth of misery
at the depth of misery in
at the depth of misery in order
at the depth of misery in order to
at the depth of misery in order to fully
surrender?
No.
What
What is
No.
What is the
What is the best
No.
What is the best way
What is the best way to
No.
What is the best way to accomplish
What is the best way to accomplish this?
This
This is
This is a
This is a good
This is a good question.
This is a good question. I've
This is a good question. I've never
asked
asked this
This is a good question. I've never
asked this one.
asked this one. I
This is a good question. I've never
asked this one. I really
asked this one. I really don't
This is a good question. I've never
asked this one. I really don't know
asked this one. I really don't know why
it
it is
it is that
it is that it
it is that it has
it is that it has to
it is that it has to reach
it is that it has to reach such
it is that it has to reach such an
unbearable
unbearable degree.
Maybe
Maybe the
Maybe the more
Maybe the more powerful
Maybe the more powerful the
Maybe the more powerful the ego,
Maybe the more powerful the ego, the
more
more powerful
Maybe the more powerful the ego, the
more powerful the
more powerful the ego,
um,
um, some
um, some people
um, some people have
um, some people have intentionally
powerful
powerful egos.
um, some people have intentionally
powerful egos. Adolf
powerful egos. Adolf Hitler
um, some people have intentionally
powerful egos. Adolf Hitler had
powerful egos. Adolf Hitler had a
um, some people have intentionally
powerful egos. Adolf Hitler had a very
powerful
powerful ego.
powerful ego. He's
powerful ego. He's got,
powerful ego. He's got, first
powerful ego. He's got, first of
powerful ego. He's got, first of all,
powerful ego. He's got, first of all, a
level
level of
powerful ego. He's got, first of all, a
level of consciousness.
level of consciousness. He's
powerful ego. He's got, first of all, a
level of consciousness. He's got
something
something else,
something else, too.
something else, too. He's
something else, too. He's got
something else, too. He's got charisma,
but
but he's
something else, too. He's got charisma,
but he's got
but he's got a
something else, too. He's got charisma,
but he's got a lot
but he's got a lot of
something else, too. He's got charisma,
but he's got a lot of power.
but he's got a lot of power. because
there's
there's a
there's a lot
there's a lot of
there's a lot of egoomaniacs
there's a lot of egoomaniacs with
political
political ambitions
there's a lot of egoomaniacs with
political ambitions out
political ambitions out there
there's a lot of egoomaniacs with
political ambitions out there and
political ambitions out there and they
didn't
didn't succeed
didn't succeed like
didn't succeed like he
didn't succeed like he did
didn't succeed like he did in
didn't succeed like he did in his
didn't succeed like he did in his realm.
So
So there
didn't succeed like he did in his realm.
So there seems
So there seems to
didn't succeed like he did in his realm.
So there seems to be
So there seems to be perhaps
didn't succeed like he did in his realm.
So there seems to be perhaps a
quantitative
quantitative thing
quantitative thing here
quantitative thing here we've
quantitative thing here we've never
looked
looked at.
We're
We're looking
We're looking at
We're looking at a
We're looking at a calibrated
We're looking at a calibrated level
We're looking at a calibrated level but
we're
we're not
We're looking at a calibrated level but
we're not looking
we're not looking at
We're looking at a calibrated level but
we're not looking at quantitative.
So
So okay
So okay let's
So okay let's ask
So okay let's ask we
So okay let's ask we have
So okay let's ask we have permission
So okay let's ask we have permission to
ask
ask resist.
So okay let's ask we have permission to
ask resist. Besides
ask resist. Besides the
So okay let's ask we have permission to
ask resist. Besides the uh
ask resist. Besides the uh calibrated
level
level there
level there is
level there is a
level there is a quantitative
level there is a quantitative uh
level there is a quantitative uh aspect
resist.
resist. Wow.
level there is a quantitative uh aspect
resist. Wow. We
resist. Wow. We never
level there is a quantitative uh aspect
resist. Wow. We never knew
resist. Wow. We never knew that
level there is a quantitative uh aspect
resist. Wow. We never knew that before.
I
I suspected
I suspected it.
I suspected it. I
I suspected it. I suspected
I suspected it. I suspected it.
I suspected it. I suspected it. How
I suspected it. I suspected it. How did
I
I suspect
I suspected it. I suspected it. How did
I suspect it?
Yeah,
Yeah, we
Yeah, we were
Yeah, we were asking
Yeah, we were asking the
Yeah, we were asking the difference
between
between reading
Yeah, we were asking the difference
between reading the
between reading the writings
Yeah, we were asking the difference
between reading the writings of
between reading the writings of a
Yeah, we were asking the difference
between reading the writings of a guru
and
and actually
and actually being
and actually being in
and actually being in their
and actually being in their presence.
And
And we
and actually being in their presence.
And we got
And we got that
and actually being in their presence.
And we got that there
And we got that there was
and actually being in their presence.
And we got that there was a
And we got that there was a difference
not
not on
not on the
not on the calibrated
not on the calibrated level
and
and the
not on the calibrated level
and the speaker
and the speaker at
not on the calibrated level
and the speaker at 620
and the speaker at 620 his
not on the calibrated level
and the speaker at 620 his writing
and the speaker at 620 his writing will
be
be 620.
be 620. But
be 620. But we
be 620. But we got
be 620. But we got that
be 620. But we got that there
be 620. But we got that there was
greater
greater benefit
be 620. But we got that there was
greater benefit and
greater benefit and that
be 620. But we got that there was
greater benefit and that it
greater benefit and that it was
be 620. But we got that there was
greater benefit and that it was not
greater benefit and that it was not a
calibratable
calibratable benefit
calibratable benefit but
calibratable benefit but one
calibratable benefit but one of
quantity.
quantity. Okay.
calibratable benefit but one of
quantity. Okay. So
quantity. Okay. So it
calibratable benefit but one of
quantity. Okay. So it has
quantity. Okay. So it has to
calibratable benefit but one of
quantity. Okay. So it has to do
quantity. Okay. So it has to do with
intensity,
intensity, quantity,
uh
uh availability.
It's
It's so
It's so so
It's so so it'
It's so so it' be
It's so so it' be analogous
It's so so it' be analogous to
It's so so it' be analogous to analogous
to
uh
uh amperage
uh amperage resist.
uh amperage resist. Uhhuh.
uh amperage resist. Uhhuh. So
uh amperage resist. Uhhuh. So the
calibrated
calibrated level
uh amperage resist. Uhhuh. So the
calibrated level would
calibrated level would be
uh amperage resist. Uhhuh. So the
calibrated level would be like
calibrated level would be like the
voltage
and
and but
voltage
and but it's
and but it's still
voltage
and but it's still a
and but it's still a quantitative
amperage.
amperage. Yeah.
amperage. Yeah. It's
amperage. Yeah. It's like
amperage. Yeah. It's like amperage.
Okay.
Okay. So
amperage. Yeah. It's like amperage.
Okay. So what
Okay. So what was
amperage. Yeah. It's like amperage.
Okay. So what was the
Okay. So what was the question?
amperage. Yeah. It's like amperage.
Okay. So what was the question? H
Okay. So what was the question? H yeah,
I
I suppose
I suppose then
I suppose then a
I suppose then a resistance
I suppose then a resistance might
I suppose then a resistance might be
I suppose then a resistance might be the
same
same thing.
I suppose then a resistance might be the
same thing. There
same thing. There could
I suppose then a resistance might be the
same thing. There could be
same thing. There could be willy-nilly
little
little resistances
little resistances where
little resistances where you
little resistances where you let
little resistances where you let it
little resistances where you let it go
or
or there
little resistances where you let it go
or there could
or there could be
little resistances where you let it go
or there could be very
or there could be very very
little resistances where you let it go
or there could be very very powerful
ones
evolved
evolved over
ones
evolved over great
evolved over great eons
ones
evolved over great eons of
evolved over great eons of time
ones
evolved over great eons of time that
evolved over great eons of time that it
takes
takes the
takes the ultimate
takes the ultimate to
takes the ultimate to break
takes the ultimate to break down.
takes the ultimate to break down. Let's
see
see if
takes the ultimate to break down. Let's
see if that's
see if that's so.
That
That is
That is so
That is so is
That is so is it?
That is so is it? Okay.
Now
earthly
earthly life
earthly life is
earthly life is also
earthly life is also an
earthly life is also an opportunity.
earthly life is also an opportunity. We
have
have an
earthly life is also an opportunity. We
have an I
have an I have
earthly life is also an opportunity. We
have an I have a
have an I have a a
earthly life is also an opportunity. We
have an I have a a permission
have an I have a a permission to
earthly life is also an opportunity. We
have an I have a a permission to ask
this
this question
this question here
this question here in
this question here in front
this question here in front of
this question here in front of this
audience.
audience. Resist.
this question here in front of this
audience. Resist. All
audience. Resist. All right.
this question here in front of this
audience. Resist. All right. It's
audience. Resist. All right. It's it's
as
as I
as I am
as I am seeing
as I am seeing it
as I am seeing it in
as I am seeing it in my
as I am seeing it in my mind
as I am seeing it in my mind resist.
All right.
All right. So
as I am seeing it in my mind resist.
All right. So entities
All right. So entities from
as I am seeing it in my mind resist.
All right. So entities from lower
domains
I
I don't
domains
I don't use
I don't use that
domains
I don't use that in
I don't use that in a
domains
I don't use that in a pjorative
I don't use that in a pjorative meaning.
entities
entities from
entities from we
entities from we think
entities from we think life
entities from we think life on
entities from we think life on our
planet's
planet's bad.
entities from we think life on our
planet's bad. There
planet's bad. There are
entities from we think life on our
planet's bad. There are universes
planet's bad. There are universes where
this
this is
this is heaven.
this is heaven. Uh
this is heaven. Uh reincarnate
this is heaven. Uh reincarnate on
this is heaven. Uh reincarnate on this
planet.
planet. So
this is heaven. Uh reincarnate on this
planet. So we
planet. So we get
this is heaven. Uh reincarnate on this
planet. So we get entities
planet. So we get entities from
this is heaven. Uh reincarnate on this
planet. So we get entities from other
realms
realms that
realms that are
realms that are really
realms that are really really
realms that are really really awful.
realms that are really really awful. So
when
when I
realms that are really really awful. So
when I I
when I I think
realms that are really really awful. So
when I I think I
when I I think I said
realms that are really really awful. So
when I I think I said a
when I I think I said a couple
realms that are really really awful. So
when I I think I said a couple of
sessions
sessions ago
sessions ago that
sessions ago that our
sessions ago that our world
sessions ago that our world is
sessions ago that our world is really
purgatorial.
purgatorial. This
sessions ago that our world is really
purgatorial. This is
purgatorial. This is really
sessions ago that our world is really
purgatorial. This is really like
purgatorial
purgatorial where
purgatorial where you
purgatorial where you get
purgatorial where you get to
purgatorial where you get to live
purgatorial where you get to live out
the
the karmic
purgatorial where you get to live out
the karmic set
the karmic set from
purgatorial where you get to live out
the karmic set from previous
the karmic set from previous decisions
and
and where
and where the
and where the gamut
and where the gamut goes
and where the gamut goes from
the
the most
and where the gamut goes from
the most awful
the most awful to
and where the gamut goes from
the most awful to the
the most awful to the highest.
and where the gamut goes from
the most awful to the highest. It
the most awful to the highest. It goes
from
from being
from being loud
from being loud to
from being loud to Jesus
from being loud to Jesus Christ.
You
You see
from being loud to Jesus Christ.
You see the
You see the enormous
range
range of
range of choices
range of choices here.
range of choices here. So
range of choices here. So the
range of choices here. So the freedom
range of choices here. So the freedom of
being
being born
range of choices here. So the freedom of
being born a
being born a human
range of choices here. So the freedom of
being born a human on
being born a human on this
range of choices here. So the freedom of
being born a human on this planet
being born a human on this planet in
this
this millennium
this millennium is
this millennium is the
this millennium is the incredible
multitude
multitude of
this millennium is the incredible
multitude of choices
multitude of choices and
this millennium is the incredible
multitude of choices and I
multitude of choices and I suspect
this millennium is the incredible
multitude of choices and I suspect in
other
other domains
other domains there
other domains there is
other domains there is not
other domains there is not r
other domains there is not r that
other domains there is not r that range
of
of choice
um
um that's
um that's a
um that's a correct
um that's a correct statement
um that's a correct statement is
um that's a correct statement is it
um that's a correct statement is it so
they
they come
um that's a correct statement is it so
they come here
they come here for
um that's a correct statement is it so
they come here for the
they come here for the great
um that's a correct statement is it so
they come here for the great range
they come here for the great range of
freedom
freedom is
freedom is it
freedom is it which
freedom is it which does
freedom is it which does not
freedom is it which does not exist
freedom is it which does not exist in
other
other domains
freedom is it which does not exist in
other domains is
other domains is it
freedom is it which does not exist in
other domains is it yes
other domains is it yes I
freedom is it which does not exist in
other domains is it yes I suspect
other domains is it yes I suspect other
domains
domains are
domains are ruled
domains are ruled by
domains are ruled by powerful
domains are ruled by powerful entities
that
that limit
um
um choice
um choice resist.
um choice resist. Okay,
um choice resist. Okay, thank
um choice resist. Okay, thank you.
>> I
>> I never
um choice resist. Okay, thank you.
>> I never thank
>> I never thank her.
um choice resist. Okay, thank you.
>> I never thank her. I
>> I never thank her. I just
um choice resist. Okay, thank you.
>> I never thank her. I just take
>> I never thank her. I just take her
um choice resist. Okay, thank you.
>> I never thank her. I just take her for
granted.
Just
Just to
granted.
Just to take
Just to take her
granted.
Just to take her for
Just to take her for granted.
granted.
Just to take her for granted. Hey,
Just to take her for granted. Hey, stand
up.
up. Do
up. Do that.
I
I want
up. Do that.
I want a
I want a public
up. Do that.
I want a public acknowledgement
sweet
sweet wife
sweet wife because
sweet wife because she's
sweet wife because she's a
sweet wife because she's a gone
sweet wife because she's a gone through
all
all these
sweet wife because she's a gone through
all these revelations
all these revelations and
sweet wife because she's a gone through
all these revelations and uh
all these revelations and uh you
sweet wife because she's a gone through
all these revelations and uh you know
because
because uh
because uh the
because uh the spiritual
because uh the spiritual research
because uh the spiritual research takes
you
you into
because uh the spiritual research takes
you into realms
you into realms that
because uh the spiritual research takes
you into realms that uh
you into realms that uh you
because uh the spiritual research takes
you into realms that uh you know
you into realms that uh you know we've
had
had to
had to work
had to work our
had to work our way
had to work our way back
had to work our way back out
had to work our way back out of
had to work our way back out of some
had to work our way back out of some of
them
them you
had to work our way back out of some of
them you know
them you know back
had to work our way back out of some of
them you know back up
them you know back up through
had to work our way back out of some of
them you know back up through the
them you know back up through the long
black
black dark
black dark tunnel
black dark tunnel in
black dark tunnel in order
black dark tunnel in order to
black dark tunnel in order to get
black dark tunnel in order to get back
to
to the
black dark tunnel in order to get back
to the light
to the light again.
black dark tunnel in order to get back
to the light again. How
to the light again. How do
black dark tunnel in order to get back
to the light again. How do we
to the light again. How do we get
black dark tunnel in order to get back
to the light again. How do we get off
into
into that
into that universe?
into that universe? I
into that universe? I don't
into that universe? I don't know.
into that universe? I don't know. We
shouldn't
shouldn't have
into that universe? I don't know. We
shouldn't have gone
shouldn't have gone there.
into that universe? I don't know. We
shouldn't have gone there. Okay.
shouldn't have gone there. Okay. Uh
into that universe? I don't know. We
shouldn't have gone there. Okay. Uh now
therefore
it
it could
therefore
it could be
why
why such
why such intolerable
why such intolerable misery?
Why
Why why
why such intolerable misery?
Why why do
Why why do you
why such intolerable misery?
Why why do you suppose
Why why do you suppose some
why such intolerable misery?
Why why do you suppose some people
Why why do you suppose some people must
reach
reach such
reach such an
reach such an incredible
reach such an incredible depth
reach such an incredible depth of
unbelievable
suffering
suffering and
suffering and misery
suffering and misery in
suffering and misery in order
suffering and misery in order to
surrender?
Anybody
Anybody got
Anybody got any
Anybody got any ideas?
>> Huh?
>> Collective
>> Collective sorrow.
>> Collective sorrow. collective.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, we
>> Collective sorrow. collective.
>> Yeah, we feel
>> Yeah, we feel sorrow
>> Collective sorrow. collective.
>> Yeah, we feel sorrow about
>> Yeah, we feel sorrow about it
that
that it
that it should
that it should have
that it should have to
that it should have to be
that it should have to be that
that it should have to be that way.
that it should have to be that way. But
the
the question
that it should have to be that way. But
the question is
the question is really
that it should have to be that way. But
the question is really how
the question is really how come
that it should have to be that way. But
the question is really how come it
the question is really how come it is
that
that way?
that way? I
that way? I don't
that way? I don't know if
that way? I don't know if we're
that way? I don't know if we're probably
allowed
allowed to
that way? I don't know if we're probably
allowed to find
allowed to find the
that way? I don't know if we're probably
allowed to find the answer,
allowed to find the answer, but
that way? I don't know if we're probably
allowed to find the answer, but let's
let's
let's work
let's work on
let's work on it.
let's work on it. What
let's work on it. What do
let's work on it. What do you
let's work on it. What do you think?
>> What
>> What does
let's work on it. What do you think?
>> What does he
>> What does he say?
let's work on it. What do you think?
>> What does he say? Do
>> What does he say? Do you
let's work on it. What do you think?
>> What does he say? Do you hear
>> What does he say? Do you hear him?
>> Realization
>> Realization of
>> Realization of hope.
>> Hopelessness.
They
They have
They have to
They have to conceive.
>> You
>> You have
They have to conceive.
>> You have to
>> You have to reach
They have to conceive.
>> You have to reach hopelessness.
>> You have to reach hopelessness. Is
They have to conceive.
>> You have to reach hopelessness. Is that
what
what he
what he said?
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Why
what he said?
>> Yes. Why does
>> Yes. Why does it
what he said?
>> Yes. Why does it take
>> Yes. Why does it take him
what he said?
>> Yes. Why does it take him so
>> Yes. Why does it take him so long
what he said?
>> Yes. Why does it take him so long to
reach
reach hopelessness?
reach hopelessness? I
reach hopelessness? I mean,
reach hopelessness? I mean, after
reach hopelessness? I mean, after guy's
been
been jail
reach hopelessness? I mean, after guy's
been jail five
been jail five times,
reach hopelessness? I mean, after guy's
been jail five times, his
been jail five times, his wife's
reach hopelessness? I mean, after guy's
been jail five times, his wife's left
him.
him. They've
him. They've taken
him. They've taken off
him. They've taken off his
him. They've taken off his right
him. They've taken off his right leg.
He's
He's blind
him. They've taken off his right leg.
He's blind and
He's blind and going
him. They've taken off his right leg.
He's blind and going deaf.
He's blind and going deaf. And
him. They've taken off his right leg.
He's blind and going deaf. And the
He's blind and going deaf. And the guy
says,
says, "No,
says, "No, I
says, "No, I don't
says, "No, I don't want
says, "No, I don't want to
says, "No, I don't want to give
says, "No, I don't want to give up
drinking
drinking out."
says, "No, I don't want to give up
drinking out." He
drinking out." He think,
says, "No, I don't want to give up
drinking out." He think, "God
drinking out." He think, "God almighty,
he
he wants
he wants to
he wants to take
he wants to take I
he wants to take I have
he wants to take I have to
he wants to take I have to put
he wants to take I have to put a
he wants to take I have to put a put
he wants to take I have to put a put his
head
head in
he wants to take I have to put a put his
head in a
head in a thumb
he wants to take I have to put a put his
head in a thumb screw."
head in a thumb screw." You
he wants to take I have to put a put his
head in a thumb screw." You know,
head in a thumb screw." You know, like
this.
this. I
this. I can
this. I can see
this. I can see why
this. I can see why the
this. I can see why the inquisition
arose.
arose. You
this. I can see why the inquisition
arose. You know
arose. You know what?
this. I can see why the inquisition
arose. You know what? What
arose. You know what? What did
this. I can see why the inquisition
arose. You know what? What did you
arose. You know what? What did you say?
>> The
>> The Lord
the
the magnitude
>> The Lord
the magnitude of
the magnitude of match.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, very
>> Oh, very good.
>> Oh, very good. Very
>> Oh, very good. Very good.
>> I
>> I suspect
>> Oh, very good. Very good.
>> I suspect that
>> I suspect that what
>> Oh, very good. Very good.
>> I suspect that what he's
>> I suspect that what he's saying
>> Oh, very good. Very good.
>> I suspect that what he's saying is
>> I suspect that what he's saying is so
that's
that's the
that's the truth.
that's the truth. Wow.
that's the truth. Wow. Thank
that's the truth. Wow. Thank you.
>> Yes,
>> Yes, that
that's the truth. Wow. Thank you.
>> Yes, that makes
>> Yes, that makes sense,
that's the truth. Wow. Thank you.
>> Yes, that makes sense, right?
>> Yes, that makes sense, right? Doesn't
it?
Uh
Uh the
it?
Uh the desire
Uh the desire to
it?
Uh the desire to let
Uh the desire to let it
it?
Uh the desire to let it go
Uh the desire to let it go must
it?
Uh the desire to let it go must be
Uh the desire to let it go must be equal
to
to that
to that which
to that which created
to that which created in
to that which created in the
to that which created in the first
place.
place. Huh?
That's
That's very
That's very good.
That's very good. Very
That's very good. Very good.
That's very good. Very good. In
That's very good. Very good. In other
words,
words, by
That's very good. Very good. In other
words, by merit.
words, by merit. In
That's very good. Very good. In other
words, by merit. In other
words, by merit. In other words,
That's very good. Very good. In other
words, by merit. In other words, you're
undoing
undoing it
undoing it by
undoing it by merit.
undoing it by merit. In
undoing it by merit. In a
undoing it by merit. In a way,
undoing it by merit. In a way, the
desire
has
has to
has to be
has to be intense.
People
People ask,
has to be intense.
People ask, why
People ask, why do
has to be intense.
People ask, why do some
People ask, why do some people
has to be intense.
People ask, why do some people reach
enlightenment?
enlightenment? They're
enlightenment? They're all
enlightenment? They're all finding
enlightenment? They're all finding the
same
same pathway,
enlightenment? They're all finding the
same pathway, find
same pathway, find the
enlightenment? They're all finding the
same pathway, find the same
same pathway, find the same technique,
same
same asham,
same asham, same
same asham, same meditation.
same asham, same meditation. Why
same asham, same meditation. Why does
some
some rocket
same asham, same meditation. Why does
some rocket ahead
some rocket ahead and
same asham, same meditation. Why does
some rocket ahead and others
some rocket ahead and others don't?
The
The only
The only answer
The only answer I've
The only answer I've ever
The only answer I've ever seen
The only answer I've ever seen or
experienced
experienced was
The only answer I've ever seen or
experienced was the
experienced was the intensity
The only answer I've ever seen or
experienced was the intensity of
experienced was the intensity of the
desire.
desire. It
desire. It has
desire. It has to
desire. It has to be
desire. It has to be voracious,
desire. It has to be voracious, almost
inhuman
inhuman or
desire. It has to be voracious, almost
inhuman or ultrahuman
inhuman or ultrahuman or
desire. It has to be voracious, almost
inhuman or ultrahuman or metahuman.
inhuman or ultrahuman or metahuman. The
intensity
intensity has
intensity has to
intensity has to be
intensity has to be ferocious
intensity has to be ferocious to
intensity has to be ferocious to reach
the
the goal.
intensity has to be ferocious to reach
the goal. And
the goal. And that's
intensity has to be ferocious to reach
the goal. And that's how
the goal. And that's how you
intensity has to be ferocious to reach
the goal. And that's how you break
the goal. And that's how you break the
barrier
barrier in
barrier in any
barrier in any uh
barrier in any uh sport.
barrier in any uh sport. That's
barrier in any uh sport. That's when
barrier in any uh sport. That's when you
hit
hit the
barrier in any uh sport. That's when you
hit the wall
hit the wall that
barrier in any uh sport. That's when you
hit the wall that you
hit the wall that you cannot
barrier in any uh sport. That's when you
hit the wall that you cannot go
hit the wall that you cannot go beyond.
You
You cannot
You cannot accept
You cannot accept that
You cannot accept that limitation
You cannot accept that limitation and
you
you by
You cannot accept that limitation and
you by sheer
you by sheer force
You cannot accept that limitation and
you by sheer force of
you by sheer force of will
and
and you
and you white
and you white knuckle
and you white knuckle it
and you white knuckle it and
and you white knuckle it and grit
and you white knuckle it and grit your
teeth
teeth and
and you white knuckle it and grit your
teeth and by
teeth and by sheer
and you white knuckle it and grit your
teeth and by sheer determination
teeth and by sheer determination you
crash
crash through.
crash through. That's
crash through. That's about
crash through. That's about what
crash through. That's about what it
takes
takes to
crash through. That's about what it
takes to reach
takes to reach the
crash through. That's about what it
takes to reach the higher
takes to reach the higher levels
crash through. That's about what it
takes to reach the higher levels of
enlightenment.
enlightenment. It
enlightenment. It has
enlightenment. It has to
enlightenment. It has to be
tenacious
one-pointedness
one-pointedness of
one-pointedness of mind
one-pointedness of mind with
one-pointedness of mind with a
one-pointedness of mind with a fixity
one-pointedness of mind with a fixity of
goal
goal and
one-pointedness of mind with a fixity of
goal and intensity.