Welcome to Dr. David Hawkins Sedona 2002
series, The Way to God. Lecture 2,
Radical Subjectivity,
the Eye of Self. Originally presented
February 16th, 2002 at the Sedona
Creative Life Center.
Well, today is today. Therefore, I
thought we'd start at the beginning of
today
uh and welcome you all. Thank you very
much for being here. It's my honor to be
able to speak to you all.
As is customary, we calibrate the energy
level of the audience as a whole before
and after the lecture.
So, to document it, today we started at
4:31. All right. Mhm. 431.
Um, let's turn on the projector. Let's
see. Let's just let's just put the
calibrated levels of consciousness on
there and find out where we are.
I feel like an astronaut all wired up
with all these gadgets.
But 431 is a pretty high calibration. As
you can see, 431
uh
actually leaves most of mankind in the
dust, you might say. How about the next
one on the right there? On the right.
Yeah,
the clear one.
Yeah. Let's see.
So, this was a a scale put together
during the last lecture.
by a friend of ours. Stand up. There he
is. Who knows what we'll have by the end
of today's lecture. Anyway, last time we
started to sketch on the board and
before by the time we were done, he had
this done on his computer. So, this is
another way of displaying the data.
uh
as we said 78% of the world we we start
out by sort of giving a a context for
the lecture uh recapitulating sort of
the development of how this all arose
um that we find that um
it was when I wrote power versus force
in 95 that 85% of the world's population
calibrated below 200 200 being the
critical level of integrity.
Below 200, everything makes you go weak
with kinesiology. Above 200, it makes
you go strong. It differentiates truth
from falsehood and various degrees of
really spiritual energy.
Uh you might say the energy field of
divine love is the most uh strong at
this level and diminishes as you go this
way.
uh at that time 85% but now 78% of the
world's population
uh calibrates below 200
they've all joined the Taliban I guess
bin Laden by the way calibrates to 70 so
we that's a different story okay so let
let's this is where we ended up the last
lecture we were and today we'll work on
this graph a little bit more the
audience audience always participates as
we evolve.
The lectures are given by myself,
representative of the Institute for
Advanced Spiritual Research,
a nonprofit charity, and um that
supports publishing the books and doing
the research etc.
Um
and by its title, you can tell it is not
a religious organization, nor is it a
new age kind of an organization. In
fact, it isn't an organization.
It's dedicated to spiritual truth.
People say, you know, what what
religious affiliation do you have? I'd
say, I don't have any I don't have any
religious affiliation.
Uh we experience uh the absolute truth
subjectively which is the really the
subject of today's lecture.
Uh today's lecture is entitled radical
subjectivity
and we'll explain what that means later.
God is both imminent and transcendent.
Religion has to do with God as
transcendent.
spirituality, enlightenment, the way of
Zen and
uh the ancient um mystics is uh through
within the discovery of God imminent
rather than transcendent.
Let's go back then. Let's go to the next
one. We'll show you what we did at home
with your uh what you gave us to work
with. Haha, look at there. There's the
next development in the chart.
Uh what we've added is the feeling that
I mean what causes the levels of
gradation to be there. Well,
as you get to the left, the light is
obscured by the ego.
And as the ego is resolved, transcended
um
the light shines um with greater
intensity. So you might say the ego is
like clouds and as you remove the clouds
the sun shines forth.
Up until recent times 1,000 calibrates
the levels of the great spiritual beings
of history and that has been the limit
of human physiology. Physiology.
The human nervous system until
almost now can only could only handle up
to a thousand. And then with some
difficulty, in fact with great
difficulty. And
then as it goes down, you see what
happens is the clouds begin to obscure
this the sky and therefore that was the
what's indicated by the shading.
Today we'll um try to improve on the
chart even further. So we're starting
with a recapitulation really of the map
of consciousness
because historically that's how it
evolved. It be the work was first
published as a PhD dissertation called
quantitative and qualitative analysis
and calibration of the levels of human
consciousness
complete with the null hypothesis P is
less than 0.001 O1 statistical analysis
and it was uh it was sufficiently
impressive that when presented to the
academic to the faculty who has to all
vote on it uh I presented it during
their vacation time and the dean called
them back from their vacation. Would you
believe the academic community came back
from their vacation to review the
material because they thought it was so
remarkable.
Actually, it's the E= MC² of the
nonlinear domain. So, I guess that
caused excitement.
I say these things from a jacular
viewpoint. You understand? All right.
So, this is as far as we've gotten with
the graph. And we're going to need your
help today. We'll go further if we have
time because to be a little more
accurate, a little more accurate, I have
to get unhooked. I don't I might
strangle myself by the time this is
over. If I turn blue and lay on the
floor, you know it's this thing. Uh,
of course, this looks pretty because
it's a nice graceful graph, etc. Now,
actually, the way it would be would be
we would calibrate we could calibrate
the percentage of the population that
makes up each of these. You see, we got
right now that we made this a little too
dark. It's copy max's fault.
78% we said of the world's population is
below 200. What we could do is ask what
percentage is uh from 500 up or 500
down. What percentage is it 400, 310,
250, 200? We could go all the way down.
You understand? Then we would have more
like a bar graph. You know what I'm
saying? To show what percentage of the
population falls within these various
categories.
In any case, the reason we started
talking about it at all is at 4:31 you
can see uh one is pretty well on their
way to the light. They're pretty much in
the light. That's traditionally the
level of the intellect, the capacity to
reason and think
and uh which is of great benefit.
It's of great benefit.
Whatever is of great benefit to get up
to here then becomes a block to getting
beyond it.
So after struggling your whole life to
perfect your intellect, you now find
that it is the main obstacle.
And we discovered that um what was it?
Um
4% of the world's population
uh it goes from 500 up. So here we go.
Uh 4% of the world's population is from
here over. When you get to 540,
the number of people that reach this is
0.4%. 0.4.
So we dropped from 4% to 0.4%.
The difficulty is that it's very hard to
transcend this level. We should have a
little dotted line there. It's very hard
to transcend the level 499. 499
is the limit of the intellect. Einstein,
Sir Isaac Newton, all the great uh
scientific geniuses
Freud u all calibrated 499.
Uh and if you go back Sir Francis Bacon,
if you all the great intellects,
scientific intellects throughout history
seem to stop at 499.
uh the great books of the western world
which are is everybody familiar with
them? They were done in University of
Chicago I think back in the 30s. Let's
see what the level of the the great
books of the western world
are the greatest philosophic uh insights
and intelligence throughout all of
history.
their permission or resist. It's over
450, 460, 465, 470, 480, 45, 490, 495,
496.
The great books of the western world
calibrated 496.
So, um that's the accumulated wisdom
of the greatest intellects uh in all of
history. Of course, the great books of
the western world exclude um
spirituality.
Uh and so it's as far as philosophy can
take you.
So
today we're talking about radical
subjectivity. So
after that little historical
introduction, we'll get more to the
topic for today.
Spirituality has to do with
discovering a different paradigm of
reality.
Science, the world up to 499, the
Newtonian paradigm has to do with form.
It has to do with content.
Spirituality
has to do with context and not content.
And it is a different paradigm.
Now the difficulty in society is society
is in the linear paradigm
to society
the Newtonian paradigm is what's real.
That is traditional science.
Science is in the low well in the 400s 4
20 uh 425 and up. Medicine is maybe
around 430. psychiatrist maybe five
points higher
and um but it is still within the linear
paradigm which as we know from our own
spiritual research and personal
experience is a very limited paradigm of
reality.
The spiritual dimension has to do with
context and it is first of all
unlimited. It is nonlinear
and it is touched by advanced
theoretical physics
who realizes that no further advance can
be made in understanding the reality of
the universe without understanding the
nature of consciousness itself which
accounts for the conferences on science
and consciousness
which have occurred which I've spoken at
a few in Tuc in
New Mexico.
There were a few. They had a few of them
and maybe three in a row at the
University of Arizona,
but they have stopped. Probably blew
their wires out
because there's quite a war ideologic
war between traditional science and
advanced uh consciousness.
uh and traditional science to some
degree feels greatly threatened by the
nonlinear domain that there is a
dimension beyond the comprehension of
the intellect.
Therefore,
there is the linear domain that is the
realm of the ego. It's the traditional
world of
our civilization. Uh beyond that is the
nonlinear domain. The nonlinear which is
approached via science in the form of
chaos theory. Chaos theory begins to
sense that there's something beyond that
which is countable, calculable,
measurable that can be weighed,
identified and photographed.
that there is another reality and is
that is just where it's pushing forward
to try to comprehend the nonlinear
domain.
Spirituality is the nonlinear domain
which creates context.
Science and the linear domain create
content content. But meaning doesn't
come out of content.
Meaning comes out of context.
Consequently, science is unable to grasp
the meaning of anything
which is a bit of a limitation. Uh got
an atomic uh reaction. What will I do
with it? Do I blow up the world or
create energy or what?
All right. So
the difficulty then is that it is
context is what creates meaning,
significance.
All of human life is lived from the
nonlinear domain.
Although we handle an object here in the
linear,
it's the nonlinear that gives us
significance.
It gives it meaning. All right.
Human life then is lived subjectively
as the experiential
presence of consciousness itself
as it registers the linear domain. It's
not the linear domain but what it means
to you.
What is a million dollars? It's what it
means to you. If I stack a million
dollars here, it's just a bunch of
paper. It's a nuisance. It' be right in
the way, wouldn't it? I'd be moving a
million dollars all the time. She I
can't get to
No, it's what it means to us. What it
means to us.
So the human is run by significance and
meaning which is in the nonlinear
domain.
Significance and meaning are
conveyed by a a flick of the eyebrow.
You're out someplace in public and your
father flicks his eyebrow. Wham! That
totally changed your life right that
instant. Nothing was said.
You get the meaning of that. Keep that
up and you're going to hear about it
when you get home, young man.
So, the significance then, meaning
value, all the things that we live for
and motivate all of life are all in the
nonlinear domain.
They may find expression in the linear
domain. A new um MercedesBenz
is in the linear domain, but it's what
it means to you. So
reality then is
what we have agreed reality is
the linear.
But the linear is always subjectively
experienced by consciousness which is in
the nonlinear.
Therefore, the radical materialist is up
against the absurdity
that if only an objective,
scientifically measurable
kind of a world is objective and true
and verifiable, then by what right does
he say so? Because that is a subjective
conclusion.
So the objective world, it doesn't even
exist except that it is experienced
subjectively.
It is the subjective reality that we're
talking about in spiritual
evolution.
In the book I'm working on now, I try to
track the evolution of consciousness
throughout all of time.
throughout the universe expressing
itself as this universe, this planet,
the evolution of life on this on this
planet from the beginning up till the
present time.
That takes a couple pages already.
Actually, all such things are simple
when you see them.
So, when you see them, they're all quite
simple.
The mystic then the mystic is one who
realizes the presence of God as
the unmanifest becoming manifest is
consciousness awareness
and the radical subjectivity of the
sense of I.
Therefore the book I'm finishing now is
just called I
of the eye was approaching it. eye of
the eye is coming really through the
third third eye of the Buddha body in a
way and
but it's preparing the way so power the
first one the PhD thesis was a
scientific basis I thought most
comprehensible by the academic world
and then pushed it a little bit over to
the nonlinear and used something safe
and familiar to the to the intellect the
academic intellect and that was that
graph, you know, that graph and we used
logarithms and things that people are
comfortable with.
And then we moved on to the eye of the
eye which was uh the evolution of that
to its higher significance and
dimensions
and I hope to conclude with it with the
book that I'm just finishing now.
And what we're tracking that is
subjective experience.
The subjective experience at the left
hand side of the chart is
uh has to do with physicality
and it really emanates from the animal
domain.
When you track what is the ego anyway?
Is it something evil? Is it something to
be fought? Is it something to be ashamed
of? Conquered? You hear all kinds of
approaches to the ego
as a screaming maniac that you have to
quell etc. The wild ox of the Zen ox
hurting pictures.
It arises uh if you track it back uh as
to its ideology, its origin is really
within the animal domain. It's really
within the animal domain. You won't find
anything in your ego that you can't see
at the nearest Monkey Island.
If you go to the zoo and watch Monkey
Island, there is your ego right there.
They're grasping. They're challenging
each other. They're bearing their teeth.
They're trying to grab each other and
mate right on the spot and fight off all
the females fighting for the male. The
male's fighting for the female. So you
see this alpha and male and female
dominance and you see people looking for
favoritism. You see people codependent
with each other
and
and love me cuz I love you. And
you see all of human pathology exhibited
there. Paranoia, possessiveness,
territoriality.
Uh all you see is today's headline.
Well, I didn't see this morning's
headline, but I'm sure it's right from
the latest review from Monkey Island
called This Planet. You have a monkey
called Bin Laden who's out there to be a
king of the hill and kill off everybody
on the way. You get some sick monkeys
that are pretty whackle and u society
tends to isolate them. So in a monkey
colony uh somebody who's sort of insane
gets put off to the side and
uh
so if you look at the ego then let's
what the chart of the ego let's look at
that calibrated map of consciousness
again all we see is really the dominance
of the animal within us of course the
animal the animal within us is still
present anatomically as the animal
brain.
So being a human being is a very
difficult thing. My uh if I was St.
Peter, I'd say, "Are you human?" Yeah,
you pass.
Anybody who survived a total life as a
human being is in a terrible conflict in
the instant you're here. Why? Because
you have an animal body. It's made of
meat and bones and the same thing as a
cow or a horse.
Within the brain, you have adabistic
drives built into your brain. The basic
nuclei in your brain are built into
survival,
hating rivals.
All right. So, here you have an animal
body. Uh you have the remnants of the
old reptilian, not only animal, but
reptilian yet reptilian brain.
and then superimpose the mamlian brain
and then lastly the cerebral
cortex in the frontal region of the
cerebral cortex which is a very late
arrival in the in the human scene couple
hundred thousand years which is you know
practically no time at all. Therefore
it's helpful to realize we're a
primitive race. My view of mankind is a
very primitive race.
um barely out of the animal stage. Why
can we say that? Well, we see that 87%
of the people are not out of the animal
stage yet. You know, the the human the
human the light of humanness uh dimly
dawns on some people.
Uh but it's a late arrival.
It's it's only in n the late 1986 or so
that the consciousness level of mankind
jumped from 190 to 207.
In other words, like yesterday.
Well, consciousness level 200 here is
the difference between that which is
destructive to life, negative to life,
and that which is spiritually aware. So,
you don't really see the beginning of
love till 200.
Love doesn't count in the world of
survival on the battlefield. Forget it.
And you're selling used cars. Forget it.
Random friend of mine who was here last
time sells used cars. I mean, the idea
is to
it has to do with survival.
All right. So this evolution of
consciousness then which you be which
evolved in the beginning
genesis makes makes you go strong
in the beginning out of uh nonform non
anything arose light
then was the energy
of the unmanifest becoming manifest.
The first sign of any divinity in the
universe
so far as we know is light. Let's see if
that's all.
Now first estimation of God as manifest
was of light. It's just right. So
Genesis makes you go strong. Genesis
there's only three books of the Old
Testament that make you go strong.
Genesis is one of them. So
Proverbs is another
and Psalms is another. The rest of them
make you go weak and seem to come out of
sort of a primitive religion primitive
religion in which the view of God has is
in an anthropomorphic projection from
the unconscious of all that is negative
and feared.
All right. So the evolution of
consciousness then takes us through
this energy is coming up through the
animal kingdom. There's a bifurcation in
the animal kingdom, a very strange one.
Um if we go back to the lowest forms of
life, uh we find um that there is no
concern for others. It's rapacious and
it lives by virtue of destroying the
life of another.
This reaches its epitome
uh during the age of the dinosaur. The
dinosaur was probably the epitome
of that energy when it rained upon the
earth.
Rapaceious with no concern for anything
except its own
uh greedy survival.
The maternal instinct had not arisen as
yet. the dinosaur laid an egg and wished
it well.
Good luck.
And um
but then there arose a parallel uh
line of evolution.
The warm-blooded uh herbivore. The
herbivore
does not kill anything in order to eat.
In fact, the herbivore supports life.
The green grass grows. the herbivore
eats it. It represents combination
combining oxygen and chlorophyll
and then refertilizes the earth which
makes for more grass. So the herbivore
doesn't have to kill anything or anybody
in order to survive. So you have that
which survives only by killing and that
which survives without killing.
And the evolution of love as I'm
tracking the evolution of consciousness
um doesn't begin until you it arises on
the planet as maternal love. The m the
mother is caring for the infant is the
first dawning of love on the planet.
until that until mian love or the bird
the bird's mother caring for the egg
loved it really didn't exist. Huh? Does
a dinosaur love another dinosaur? Not
likely.
All right.
You might say the appearance of
spiritual energy then was in the form of
the mother
and much later between man and woman.
Romantic love is a very recent
development. It's only a few hundred
years old. The upper classes didn't pay
attention to love. You married what was
good for the family and they found love
elsewhere.
Um, men and women until very recent
times spent very little time with each
other. The man was out hunting and
fishing and brawling and and doing uh
unmentionable things and the woman was
home taking care of domestic issues and
they spent very little time. There was
very little companionship between man
and woman.
So romantic love was really quite recent
really uh in the late feudal period. Uh
the idea of romance between man and
woman is a pretty modern kind of a
thing. So even romantic love is very
recent on the planet. One would assume
it was always there but if you look back
through history you realize it was
relatively rare.
So
at 410 431 where we are today we're
looking at God as wisdom meaningful.
We he's approachable by reason. He's
capable of un we're capable of
understanding him and the mind at this
point is capable of abstraction.
Well, at the lower levels the mind is
very concrete. It's not capable of
abstraction.
And uh as people evolve and reason
begins to really take hold,
they hear a spiritual truth and a
certain percentage become attracted to
it. that starts the spiritual quest
either through of an emotional hitting
bottom or by the sheer advance of
consciousness and its evolution as it is
expressed as reason.
So 431 is a very high level
surpasses
uh most of mankind
most of mankind right
um
any guy who's watching the TV news will
tell you that the world is so stupid
that's what a guy is supposed to say to
his wife God it's so stupid
he's all upset about politics and she's
not interested in politics are you
interested in politics
No excitement about the late nose. Oh
well. So
radical subjectivity then is the very
essence of experiencing the presence of
God as
that which says I.
That which allows you to be aware of
your own existence
is at all times present,
never absent.
It's the first thing you become aware of
when you wake up in the morning. First
thing that happens before thinking this
even starts is the awareness of your own
existence. Is the awareness of
existence.
There's an awareness
as you wake up
that one exists. You don't even have a
name yet.
If I catch you the very first incident,
you open your eyes, say, "What's your
name?" Then give me a second while I
wake up.
Give me a second. Are you man or woman?
Wait, give me a second till I wake up.
Are you American or European? What are
you? Give me a second to wake up.
So consciousness is there before even
content. Consciousness awakens
then with the awareness of existence.
That which allows you to say I
is presumed as you wake up to be the
personal eye
because reality
seems to have to do with form and facts.
and physicality.
One presumes that
knowing that I am, that I exist, being
aware,
the sense of eye is coming from a
personal eye.
And that's the only illusion we have to
jump.
The sense of eye is not coming from a
personal eye at all. It's coming from an
impersonal eye.
Consciousness is an impersonal quality.
The consciousness which arises as you
awaken is not personal at all. You have
it focused on the personal
but its essence is not personal.
It is because of the infinite eye
that which is not different than
divinity, reality, truth, all the things
that's been called throughout the ages.
It illuminates the awareness
that shines forth as the awareness of
your own existence,
but its source is the infinite eye. Is
that clear?
That which knows that you're here this
second
is not the personal eye. Because
if we ablate the personal eye, you will
still be aware that
one's quality is that of existence.
It was that dilemma that confronted me
at age three. People say they like to
hear personal stories and
the personal story is actually
irrelevant. But it it display it it
gives an example of what we're talking
about. In this lifetime at age three,
out of complete oblivion and
nothingness,
suddenly there was a shock.
This thing here was sitting in a little
wagon
and I realized I exist.
It was the awareness of existence very
with extreme clarity and extremely
shockingly shocking intensity.
Nor was I pleased with it.
There was a shocking awareness of
existence.
Instantly arose a fear. If I had come
into existence, then hypothetically
it might have been that I might not have
come into existence.
So it was really the awareness of
existence as as beingness,
I amness.
At three, there was no verbalization
about any of this, but it was a complete
understanding of it, let me tell you.
And it really set the theme for this
life lifetime for uh many years to come.
That dilemma of reality as existence
versus non-existence
is in an extremely abstract and
extremely high level. It's a spiritual
paradox you don't have to solve until
you get to level 890 or something
which was difficult to handle there for
8 days. So,
Um but the dilemma of existence versus
non-existence was like a silent um
paradox you know that uh hung out in the
back of my mind
uh in the lifelong pursuit of
identifying the radical truth of the
self and who you are.
And um it wasn't verbalized
again for many years.
Uh
uh
but there was the paradox of existence
versus non-existence.
The beautiful thing about realizing the
truth of who you are, the truth of who
you are is not different than
that which subject subjectively is
conscious of your existence.
Nothing needs to be said about it. It
doesn't have to be searched for.
You don't have to study to find it.
It's more an intuitive awareness that
sort of dawns on you that that is the
ultimate reality you've been searching
for.
That ultimate reality
is timeless. And as one becomes aware of
it, one realizes
that that which you really are has
always existed,
will always exist because it is beyond
existence versus non-existence.
It is beyond time.
It is beyond form.
It is the substrate out of which all
experiencing arises.
And that solves all the riddles.
Now religion says such a awareness is
not possible till you after you're dead
and
in heaven or someplace.
So religion looks at God as
transcendent.
The transcendent God uh shows up in
Genesis,
creates the universe,
promptly disappears,
and goes in heaven, moved to heaven, and
you don't get any chance to meet him
till after you're dead if you've been
good.
There is that horrible moment called
judgment day, though. Uh-oh.
So God rolls the dice, says, "Good luck.
You're on your own." Then he hangs out
in heaven waiting for you with a big
stick.
And uh if you didn't do so well, wacko
into the boiling cauldron
out of which he gets great. By the way,
he loves to see people suffer. Anyway,
he picks the good and the bad or he
picks 144,000, whatever.
Where does that come from? 144,000.
>> Revelations.
>> Oh, Revelations. Oh, okay. All right.
Anyway, out of the billions and billions
and billions of souls, he picks this
number. Anyway, anyhow,
so that is the God who is transcendent
to be feared, projected somewhere
elsewhere in time and space
because heaven is up there and you're
down here.
Well, if you're down here and heaven god
is up there,
the chances are not too good you're
going to run into him at the
Walmart.
So, traditional real religion then is a
denial of the reality of the truth of
yourself.
that is
in great contrast to the mystic.
Religion therefore is
extremely limited as compared to
spirituality.
So we differentiate between religion and
A very delicate
but important difference to be made.
The signers of the constitution
understood it perfectly. The
constitution in the United States
calibrates at over 700. That is
spiritual brilliance. That's the level
of the sage, the genius.
It clearly differentiates spiritual
freedom
from the establishment of religion and
clearly saw that if anything, religion
is an enemy of spiritual freedom. Of
course coming out of England and
Protestant Catholic conflicts over the
years etc. they were of course highly
conscious of that but I don't think it
came out of their historical experience.
It came out of really a spiritual
inspiration because the signers of the
Declaration of Independence etc all
calibrated in the high 500s. They were
really extremely gifted men and we were
we are very very fortunate. Constitution
United States calibrates higher than the
constitution of any country on the
planet.
It guarantees spiritual freedom and it
does so by prohibiting religion from
becoming established and simultaneously
it does not prohibit religion. So it was
extremely brilliant and very few people
today really comprehend the difference
between spiritual and religious.
So religion then becomes over time an
institution which has its upside and its
downside.
In another book we're doing right now we
calibrate the level of truth of all the
world's great religions. And you can
track it down through time. You can
track it down from the time of its
origination down through the centuries
and down through the council of Trent,
the council of na all the various things
and see what happened to all the various
world's religions.
Traditionally the mystic has been um
at odds with traditional religion. In
fact, some religions condemn the mystic
and historically mystics were burned at
the stake and declared heretics etc.
Excommunicated
and put in strange places.
In some world's religions actually
um
the the subjective reality of the mystic
is is declared to be formally heretic
heresy. Yeah.
To experience the presence of God within
is actually forbidden
in Islam for instance.
Uh
so the Christian mystic didn't do too
well either.
The only place the mystic has really
prospered in history has been uh in the
area in in India
where the tradition of the mystic is uh
traditional. The vidas
they explain the realization of the
presence of God itself
uh for some thousands of years.
All those by the way do calibrated at a
thousand as does the Buddha
who
cleverly got himself born in India
so that he didn't get crucified for his
teachings. Had he been born elsewhere,
he would not have fared as well. But
there was already um a friendly
knowledge of spiritual truth in that
part of the world of some of great
antiquity.
So what he taught was not at great odds
with their tradition.
And the land of the Buddha, the lands
that are favorable to Buddhism are today
the most favorable to the mystic
when we speak in Korea, let's say, or
the Orient. you know, they come by the
thousands from all over the country
because
all we're saying is that we have sort of
demonstrated in a scientific verifiable
way what their culture has held to be
the truth for thousands of years.
So the prosperity of a religion or a
spiritual teaching depends considerably
then on context on context. Not just on
content.
The religionist tends to emphasize
content
and declare holy wars based on content
thereby negating the context. But it is
the context out of which their spiritual
teaching come is true.
Without context, what they're babbling
is nonsense. any mental hospital
that's full of religious people that can
babble all kinds of religious stuff.
It's the context that gives a spiritual
teaching any kind of validity
because God is the ultimate context.
That which is God deres it infinite
power by the fact that divinity is
infinite context.
Out of infinite context comes infinite
power.
So religion which negates context has
just negated its own validity.
And spiritual seekers are made up
considerably by people who have had
a variety of religious backgrounds
and many have ridden it as far as it can
go and then want to know
where do we go from here.
Some people have had subjective
spiritual experiences were which were
quite
quite powerful
in this lifetime.
uh such things occurred
at age 12 or 14.
A near-death experience which was
transformative totally eliminated the
fear of death
uh for the rest of my life.
And in the late 30s, suddenly
all that the mind had considered myself
in reality
completely disappeared and
was replaced by an infinite context
which was
the presence which
swept away all thought.
So those kind of severe spiritual
experiences then account for some of us
being here.
Other people become interested in
spiritual work because they have a
variety of illnesses and they've heard
that through spiritual investigation
every illness known to mankind has been
known to
become healed and resolved and I myself
have witnessed it.
It is true that with a certain with
intense spiritual work a certain
percentage of spir of physical illnesses
will remit or totally cure. In some
cases they will not.
But to a spiritually evolved person it
no longer matters whether it does or it
doesn't. So the fallacy of criticizing
that spiritual work did not lead to the
healing of something means that the
person did not evolve you know with
great intensity you follow the course of
miracles let's say with great intensity
or even aa even the 12step you take
third step of the 12step groups with
great intensity
you finally reach a state whether
whether whether the physicality survives
or not is totally irrelevant
Because when you totally surrender your
will to God, the cra the craving for
continued physicality disappears.
And whether this physicality survives or
not is frankly of no interest
whatsoever.
So a person who intensely does spiritual
work will either recover from the
physical illness or they will reach such
an advanced state of consciousness that
whether the body survives or not is
really not of any particular interest.
It'll even reach a point where if it
would leave soon that would be fine.
So spiritual endeavor then does
handle any and all physical illnesses.
Anybody who's been around in any of the
consciousness
um
teachings that are prevalent of course
of miracles is the one I was familiar
with. Uh we saw people with every
illness uh on the face of the earth go
into remission and recover.
And that started these attitudinal
healing centers which were based on
uh a group um spiritual approach to
chronic and incurable illnesses. And
Jerry John Paulski started one out in
Tibon
and
he wrote Love is Letting Go of Fear.
And then Jolski brought his whole staff
back east where I had a big clinic. We
started the second attitudinal healing
center in New York.
In New York and there we did also see
every kind of illness known to mankind
remitt.
And this particular body which I was
afflicted with all kinds of disasters
in my in the late 30 my when my 30some
rather was slowly remitted from a whole
lot of these disasters and uh
including uh the ability to see when I
uh grew up. I had thick glasses and uh I
was we call nowadays a nerd no doubt. Um
everybody played stickball. while I sat
there reading Plato.
Does sound kind of nerdy when I look at
it now, but uh
I liked Aristophanes and Plato and
Aristotle, and those are my heroes.
And uh
anyway, so with thick uh bifocals on,
you can't play baseball too good because
it hits you in the nose before you see
it. And uh and uh you're too small and
skinny to play football. And uh so I
tried the swimming team and they said,
"You're way too short."
So Plato was my pale. And uh
but anyway, after this transformation of
consciousness, uh many ailments healed
himself and I still wore thick I was
into triocals then. And uh while in a
course of miracles class, somebody said,
"Why do you still wear them?" And I
thought, huh, I never thought of that uh
as a belief system.
I always thought being a physician in
training uh you know, being a physician
that uh near side of the shore and a
stigmatism all those things were were
physical due to faulty construction of
the eyeball and the lens etc. So I never
thought of it as an illness due to a
belief system. And when she said that I
thought, "Huh, that is interesting.
and put the glasses away in my pocket
and never took them out again. So then I
had to drive blind for six weeks, which
uh
happily I wasn't living in New York City
anymore.
Uh but it was interesting because what I
needed to see I could see. See, when you
surrender every instant, when you stop
trying to control or change every
instant as it arises, as the wave of the
instant arises, you surrender it as it
arises. So, you begin riding the crest
of the instant of now. And as you do
that, I would always be able to see just
what I needed to see, the pedestrian
right before
I ran over it, so I missed it. The stop
sign turning red. It's a I could only
the edge of the cliff driving around
Sedona. I can remember driving around
the edge of the cliff and I could just
see the edge of the cliff. So I was
surrendering fear all the time. S fear
and I would just see the edge of the
cliff because I needed to see it. And
I'd go to make a left turn in the dark
in the rain. And all of a sudden, I
would see the curb that I was supposed
to see because the headlights of some
car would mysteriously arrive in some
place, illuminate the curb, and I'd make
it.
If you look at it through the inlet,
it's hairy. But um so anyway, this six
six weeks I surrendered surrendered my
survival to the presence of God.
And um the infinite president uh guided
everything which it has since 1965.
Anyway, the illusion that the the the
ego sells you the illusion that it's
because of the ego that you survive. But
actually it's because of the self with a
capital S that you survive.
It certainly was not the ego keeping me
alive. So anyway, I thought,
well, I guess you never get to see
anything again. I mean, I couldn't see
this crowd here. No way. I couldn't see
the table. I can't see anything close,
and I can't see anything far.
You can't see either close or far, then
you can't see anything, can you? So, uh,
I knew, you know, so I knew it was light
or dark. But so one day I was standing
in the kitchen of a friend uh and I
think I was course of miracles class in
fact you know anyway we were standing in
the kitchen the friend and talking about
this that or the other thing and
suddenly with no warning everything
became clearly visible. I looked at the
calendar across the room. I could read
the calendar January, February, March,
February, June.
And um so even vision returned with
great clarity. And a number of people
I've told the story uh who heard the
story tried it and had the same
experience. And they all said it took
about six weeks.
So anyway, that's the six weeks program,
folks. And
anybody is willing to drive in traffic
without knowing where you're going until
the last instant. If you're nervous can
take it. Uh so
as as we progress spiritually various
peculiar phenomena do occur. There's uh
physiologic changes.
Uh we'll take a break. We'll take it a
break in a second. There's physiologic
changes which we're going to do
questions and answers later. I want you
all to leave here with questions
satisfied. There's physiologic changes
that happen and they're diff they differ
depending on where you along you are
along the path
and some are exquisite, some are beyond
description.
There's also various psychic paranormal
um what do they call them? so-called
cities arise
um
which spiritual debunkers like to
attack.
There's also there's also paranormal
kinds of things you know paranormal uh
arise.
there is exquisitly pleasurable
sensations
and then as you get higher and higher at
least in this particular case there's
extremely awful kinds of pain and you
get wrecked by all kinds of uh
discomforts.
So we'll try to recontextualize all
these things as
the the nerv physiology of the nervous
system literally changes as you advance
spiritually.
There is shifts in the brain's
neurotransmitters.
there's a shift from adrenaline to to
endorphins as a predominant
uh motif um neurochemically
speaking
there is a diminish and finally
elimination of the
startle reflex
if a shot goes off behind me I don't
react at all when I say by me I'm
talking about this body
if a shot goes off. It's a passing uh
noticed notice, but there's no sense of
alarm that disappeared after the
near-death experience.
And in World War II, there was no fear
of death either. And we'd be facing even
in certain death and and I felt high.
You were throwing up on the deck and I
felt exhilarated. I was in a state of um
happiness. I guess I thought I was
assuming to be with God or something. I
don't know what.
So there's a difference in emotional
reactions
and there are really profound changes
throughout the human body and I think
the healing process which many people
come to Sedona seeking healing for
various things which we explained in the
last lecture and previous ones
the energy field of of love to choose
love.
um then tends to favor uh a healing and
a healthiness of the entire acupuncture
system and a strengthening of the immune
system.
And I think any illness if you um become
interested in intense with spiritual
work and by intense I mean intense
uh you can transcend the level at which
that illness will remit.
There's also karmic uh influences
as u that may prevail.
Uh there's many times when karmic
deterrence to healing become transcended
and the person goes into remission.
There are certain serious karmic
um
limitations perhaps
that uh preclude uh the absolute healing
of certain conditions. You see
so each and every case is researched.
That's why we find kinesiology very fun
and useful.
We find it's very useful in karmic
research because some trait or some
persistence in your life
that's not explicable by logic. You can
find with a little few questions you can
find out where that originated and
sometimes you can even recall it. Oh
yes. Oh yes, I remember that. Huh? You
remember it? Well, it wasn't this
lifetime. No, it wasn't this lifetime.
But you do remember it.
I know why I don't get along with
horses.
I just don't get on with horses. And I
also remember where that all started.
Anyway, we haven't transcended that one
with horses yet, have we? Or have we?
Let's see if we transcended that one
with horses or not.
We have transcended that one with
horses. Resist. Yes, we did.
I was very mean to horses and they were
also very mean to me and we just didn't
get along for a lot of lifetimes.
Uh
in fact I might that might have even
remitted this week. Yes. Yes. There was
a horse out in the corral and uh crying
crying crying. All the other horses had
gone out on the trail and this horse
just cried and cried and was just
carrying on and I couldn't stand it. So
I was at the girls uh ranch where I'm a
chief of staff there. They have 50
adolescent girls.
So I said I have to take care of this. I
couldn't stand this horse crying
obviously with emotional pain and
separation anxiety. So I went out and
comforted stopped everything to go out
and comfort this horse and began talking
to that horse
who realized it was being
compassionately
compassion was paying attention to it.
The horse got that
uh and uh it didn't heal the horse, but
I think the horse did get a message, but
it could be where that remitted anyway.
All right. So,
we'll talk about that a little bit more.
We'll start the second session. We'll
take a break now. We'll take we'll start
the next session with some questions and
go where this audience uh would like to
go. We've covered a great variety of
subjects and any one of them is a
tickoff point from which one question
can keep me going for an hour
which I promise not to do. First we ask
some questions about kinesiology itself.
Uh we don't teach kinesiology. We uh
explain how to do it and then it's up to
you. It's like riding learning how to
ride a bicycle. I can't really run
bicycle riding classes.
Uh but we do give you references where
you can go and u people ask us we have a
sheet that gives references on
kinesiology.
Uh Jerry Templates uh I just happen to
be familiar with he puts out a whole
course called switchtime living in which
demonstrates it in spades.
Um also it's not a technique that
everyone can do you know
uh but you you can find people who are
able to do it and if you have a distinct
question should you kill yourself or not
or go to a movie you can ask them
that's my favorite quotes I couldn't
decide whether to go to a movie this
afternoon or commit suicide so
when two people are calibrating a
thinger event wise they get different
question answers
Um,
as we say, this is a relative scale. If
you really are serious about it, uh,
first of all, you don't have to
calibrate anything. I've already done it
for you. But if you're going to be do it
yourselfish, uh,
if you have to do it yourself, uh, you
can use the single the single ring uh,
technique. If it's an important
question, we suggest you use uh you find
a partner you can work with. For some
people, it comes very rapidly. I when I
first saw it, I got how to do it in an
instant. Uh
so I tend to be impatient with people
that it takes them weeks to to get what
I could see in one instant. So I'm not a
great teacher of it. But um as I say,
Templas has a switched on living. Uh
there's there's a book by a nurse that's
very good. Anyway, if you call the
writer office, we have references on
kinesiology.
Uh John Diamond's book, Your Body
Doesn't Lie, is about as good a
description of the technique as you will
find anywhere, and it has illustrations.
The book is also out as behavioral
kinesiology.
So, John Diamond, MD, um,
your body doesn't lie is a very good
reference and Jerry Templates is an
elaboration of it, uh, with videos and
audios. And so, that's a good way to
learn it.
To really define it for yourself, you
have to say in reference to this scale
of consciousness, you can use any scale.
You can make up your own scale, but in
reference to this scale of
consciousness, you have to give
conscious reference to it.
And I used to say at on a scale of
consciousness from 1 to a,000 where 200
is integrity and 500 is love or where
200 is integrity 600 is enlightenment.
On that scale of consciousness
then the answer to this question is so
and so.
You understand it's an arbitrary scale.
We could have made it from one to 100.
We could make could have made it from
zero to 0.1 and you could have 01 O1 you
know see
anyway this turned out to be
logarithmically so because I asked is
this numeric it said no it's logarithmic
all right all right so it's a
logarithmic rhythmic scale so if you
want accuracy then you have to say in
reference to this scale where 200 is
integrity and 600 is enlightenment
this dog calibrates at so and so and As
I've already told in previous lectures,
a dog's wagging tail calibrates at 500.
And so does a cat's purr.
So who would you rather have in your
kitchen? Bin Lden at 70 or your kitty
purring for dinner.
And Coco Coco, you know the chimpanzeee
calibrates over 200. And there's a gray
parrot famous out of the University of
Arizona. What's the parrot's name? The
gray gray African. And this gray African
can count and tell colors. And she says,
"Get gray cork." He gets the gray cork.
You know, he knows which is gray and he
knows which is cork. And he calibrates
over 200. So you're safer with the
gorilla cocoa than you are with 78% of
the people on the planet who steal your
wallet while they're drinking with you.
So, what percentage of genuine mystics
are alive in the world today?
>> I'm glad they didn't ask how many are
dead in the world today.
What percentage of genuine mystics?
Well, let's see. What is a genuine
mystic?
>> A genuine mystic is uh they mean by this
somebody who calibrates over 600 resist.
Okay.
What percent uh well or when they're
alive in the world today. We can't get
percentage cuz it's less than 0.01 or
something like that. We could get the
number though. The number of people on
the planet today who calibrate over 600
is over 30 32
but it's between 30 and 32.
The number of people who calibrate over
let's see where's that other scale we
had up here. Uh
these were revised periodically because
these changed between 1995 and uh and
two the year 2001.
The number of people up here is um so it
said from here what did we say 31. Yes.
We let's do the rest. You come on over.
We'll do the rest. The number of people
700 or over. That's all right. You're
okay. You have to worry about it. Number
of people over 700 is
uh more than six, more than eight,
more than seven, more than eight. All
right, 700 looks like. No, 800. The
number over 800 is more than two. Three,
three.
The number over 900 is more than two.
Three. The number over 980 is more than
one.
two one one over 980. So you can see
that's why this trails off
because there aren't many there. This is
six billion over here and there's a
couple here.
All right, that's why we we re rever
their insights and their teachings
because uh they're relatively rare.
uh
and how does how does that come about?
It comes about by uh this question here
specifically. How does one go about
surrendering the ego to God?
Um
and then we'll answer another question
at the same time. Can intention alone
change your consciousness? Yes, it's
intention. It's intention
that um that motivates the whole
spiritual
uh effort. It's one's intention that
sets sets the context
and then everything else falls within
that context. So intention
you see the the mind will automatically
prioritize everything.
If your most intense
intention is to reach the conscious
experience of the presence of God then
everything gets subsumed under that.
The mind then automatically discards
things that would be extraneous.
So
I can remember going through medical
school and I put my way through college
and medical school. The financial demand
of getting through medical school and
the intellectual demand of endless hours
of study took priority over everything.
There was no time to read novels. There
was no time to go to movies. There was
no time to every dollar had to count. So
that prioritized everything. And I was a
cab driver.
as my wife well knows. And uh
and every second counted. Every second
was uh money. So the oncoming when the
light turned green and the oncoming
traffic, if they didn't instantly jump
it, I made my left already. You know, by
the time they got the intersection, I
was out.
But consider the heebie-jebies. But I
said, I can't help that because I just
learned it that way because the priority
was such. So the intention then is
uh very determinative
which answers the next question. It says
how do you surrender the ego to God?
Well
the books I'm writing have to do with
understanding the mechanisms of the ego.
In last lecture we talked about
positionality.
We talked about um and we talked about
today that that the ego arose as a
survival
mechanism in the animal world.
It then became elaborated by the
intellect.
The intellect now becomes the instrument
of the animal instinct.
It's still up to the same thing. It's
just more sophisticated.
To be top dog now means the brand of car
you write drive and it's year
and um
or one's position or one's title or
one's income or the story you bought
your clothes or the style.
So the intellect has merely become the
servant of the animal
and expresses itself in more
sophisticated ways. uh it's still up to
being king of the hill and being the
alpha male or the alpha female etc.
If you see that the ego a rose is not
different than the animal and its
motivations are not different than the
animal
then you can stop feeling guilt about it
and stop making it wrong.
There are many spiritual teachings that
tend to make the ego wrong and label it
all its ongoingness as sin. Huh?
Sin is just the persistence of the
animal to give into
biologic drives
at the price of a more evolved kind of
human love. Then that gets labeled sin.
So sin would be that which is still
innate to the animal kingdom
and by being human it is now expected
that you will transcend it and not be
dominated by the animal drive doesn't
mean you don't have the animal drive but
it means you won't be dominated by it
to see there the reason I track the
origin of consciousness as it evolved
throughout evolution is
to disass Assemble the guilt and shame
mechanism which precludes many people
from serious spiritual or religious
endeavor
in the 12step groups. Many people buck
at the fourth step. The fourth step is a
fearless searching moral inventory.
Yeah. A lot of people will go the third
step, but when it gets to the fourth
step, they don't want to go to a anymore
because
they're faced with what looks to them
like an ominous guilt trip.
Well,
the bill the
So, how can you look at the downside of
the ego without succumbing to guilt and
shame and anger, etc.? If you realize
that it's just the persistence of the
animal, you can get off moralizing about
it.
And if you get off moralizing about it,
you can avoid spiritual guilt.
If you've listened to enough
confessions, you will realize that
everybody's ego is the same. The next
penitent in the booth is just going to
tell you the same thing the last 10,000
told you. I lied to my mother. I cheated
on my wife. I'm lusting after my
secretary.
I took pence home from the office. I
stole paper clips. I mean, what does the
ego do? It's inquisitive, huh?
And it's carnal.
and it's lascivious and leiddenous
and it gets hooked on those things. So
the difficulty with addiction is it gets
hooked on it. It gets hooked on it.
All right.
So the first thing we do is try to grasp
the totality of the ego and the best way
is to contextualize how it evolved
throughout all of history which is what
I'm doing in this current book. The
reason I disagree with the textbook, you
know, I like I like the course of
miracles. I think it's a great thing. I
mean it's a it just blows you out when
you read the sentence says, you know, uh
my thoughts don't mean anything.
Whoa. somebody with a college education.
My thoughts don't mean anything. I drove
cab all those years to polish up my
thoughts and now you tell me they don't
mean anything. Well, because spiritually
motivated people are generally in the
400s. Uh I like the course of miracles
because it tends to disassemble the ego
as the great
um thing that we which we genulect. And
uh I mean uh my thoughts don't mean
anything. That's my favorite favorite
from the course of miracles. But I don't
like the textbook because the textbook I
think was it was sourced from a
different somewhat different source than
the workbook because it tends to
polarize one with the ego. And picture
the ego as one's enemy an evil enemy.
Uh the animal isn't evil. It's just
animal. You know it's animal. It's not
evil just animal.
All right. So the willingness to
surrender
uh let's see here let's take the put
that the calibrated levels on again the
willingness to surrender the lesser for
the greater is all that's required. All
right.
Uh the willingness to question the
validity of anything below 200. Let's
say you hate somebody and that hate is
quote justified end quote.
In fact, as a matter of fact, you don't
have to go over and over the fact that
it's justified.
You should grant the ego its wish right
in the beginning and say, "Yes, it is
justified.
It is justified. You ran off with your
wife, ruined your business, burned down
your house, and you peed at him, right?"
That's that old joke. The guy's saying
he got in the street corner, and his
wife has run off, his house is burned
down, he's been fired, and he says, "I
don't know, God. Why me? And he heard
the voice come out of the heavens. I
don't know, George. There's just
something about you pissing me off.
Nothing like a little kad karma to turn
a guy into an atheist, huh? So, how can
the ego be surrendered to God? So, all
right. The first is to become acquainted
what is the ego? It's the persistence
of the animal instinct but now
elaborated through mind the intellect
and given
authenticity
by the mutual agreement of society.
All right. The reason I stay with
current events for many years I ignored
current events. Since I didn't read
newspaper, listen to radio for years and
years.
Somebody did a make wrong about it and I
bought it. I let go of the make wrong
about
paying attention to the world.
That make wrong is a misinterpretation
of the calibrated level of 700 where
let's say Ramano Maharshi says there's
no point in trying to change the world
because the world that you see doesn't
exist which is true within a certain
context.
Within another context, the world is an
extreme is is the drama of the ego. I
find it fascinating because what you see
is every ego mechanism played out on a
grand stage.
So if you want to understand your ego,
what you try to do is comprehend what
goes on in the world and see it in terms
of the ego and you then understand
yourself
and you understand the fallacy of the
many positions that uh pertain and are
popularized in society. You see right
through the fallacy
in a way that is expressible through
languaging
from the nonlinear domain. You see the
idiocy of it. You don't see it as idiocy
but you see beyond it but you can't
explain it. So it takes years to learn
how to read language things in a fluent
way to explain that which is obvious so
that it makes sense to the intellect. So
being a student of the world then
um you're really a student of the ego.
So letting go wanting to change it in
the world comes about as a as a
willingness to want letting letting it
go within yourself and vice versa.
Forgiving
the world and forgiving yourself are one
and the same thing because the world is
just a projection of the ego. You might
say, "Well, it's not my ego." Well, it's
the collective ego. So, you might as
well take on the collective ego and do
everybody a favor, you know?
Well, the people haven't gotten around
discerning their ego. You surrender it
for them. And they get jacks for they
get they jacks are openers. They get
into heaven right off the bat. you did
it for him. Well, we say, you know, we
say that in a jocular fashion, but
that's a fact
that every step you take forward
spiritually benefits all of mankind.
One person that you forgive
already affects the consciousness level
of all of mankind
that's so resistant.
Therefore, everyone is a savior.
Potential savior. Is it? Everyone is a
potential savior. Each and every one of
us as we forgive that one person that we
hated, we could chop them in small
pieces and flush them
because they deserve it. You can't
pretend they didn't deserve it. And you
can't pretend they didn't do it. It's a
fact they did and they probably do
deserve it.
But despite that, you still forgive
them. That's where the jump is. All
right. So that comes out of the
willingness. The intention then to make
these moves comes about from
first of all it comes about through the
heart. I usually don't talk about the
heart because it makes the uh lecture
very short.
Yeah.
And you bring up the heart. Goodbye. Uh
I I sit on the heart.
Uh I also have to sit on the mind. Uh
but the mind is easier to sit on than
the heart. But uh to keep the mind
functioning in turn in languaging
comprehensible to the world took a great
deal of effort. Took me many years
when the heart comes up. So all right.
You see the willingness to make these
steps comes from the heart. It's because
of the innate love of God you're willing
to surrender the hatred. You understand?
You don't do it because you
intellectually understand that it's a
necessary step to reach enlightenment.
Your willingness to surrender everything
to God, including one's justified
hatreds, is strong enough that brings
you to the willingness to surrender
them.
The willingness to surrender all to God
is the all fire in the middle of it all.
It allows you to walk into a hail of
bullets. Literally walk into a hail of
bullets.
For thee, oh God, I do die with joy. And
you walk right into the bullets and you
go into ecstasy. The minute you leave
the body, ecstasy.
Having done it and remembering it
when done for the love of God, the
immediate experience as you go out of
body is ecstasy. You knew you know that
you have passed a great barrier.
And that many have not. And one of the
great values of war is that it does
allow those below 200 to cross over 200.
Because when you face death for the
belief in a higher good, if it's even
the good of mankind or for the love of
God, then you pass a certain level that
those who have not done it cannot pass.
So in a way, war is an opportunity for
which many young men seek to reach that
level because you actually have to face
literal death to do it. You can't just
do it in your imagination.
So that's one of the
side benefits of war. Not that I
recommended this the best way possible,
but it beats Harry Kerry, I'll tell you,
because Harry Kerry was not too great
either.
All right. the willingness to surrender
one's all. That that's the and as I've
said in previous lectures, the integrity
of the kamicazi pilot, you know, and a
lot of these uh Islamic zealots when you
calibrate them, they actually literally
believe they're doing it for God. And as
such, they are over 200 as they may be
in error. But u those who manipulate
such people on the other hand calibrate
70.
That was a lie to them.
Yeah. We said last time when they get
there and find that there's 72 virgins,
what they don't know is they're over 900
years old.
That's the part the guru doesn't tell
him. You know, you get 72 verses. All
right.
And they are really bad too. But anyway,
all right. So spiritual integrity,
spiritual integrity means one does what
one does
out of the innate love for God. Now that
love for God may not swell up as an
outpouringness of emotion.
It can be a profound commitment
out of the willingness.
So ascending the ladder, if you want to
call it the ladder then is based on
willingness. the willingness to
surrender anything because it stands in
the way of your experiencing the
presence of God.
So it comes out of a profound commitment
and not an not an emotionality.
The emotionality
is a substitute for what is really a
greater insight. The greater insight is
the intuitive understanding of the
essence of your own existence
and the willingness then to commit to a
greater understanding of that reality.
Willing to surrender everything to God
is the machinery behind all this. It
allows you to do
Now as you take the the nature of the
ego apart you the work becomes more
specific.
We said religion is one thing
enlightenment is another.
Jesus Christ died for the salvation of
the world. The Buddha taught
enlightenment.
Christ taught the way to heaven.
He doesn't talk.
He only there's only one quote we still
have and that is that heaven is within
you that God is both transcendent and
imminent.
But the stress of Christianity is
primarily on God as transcendent
although it is the way of the heart.
The Buddha is aimed in a different
direction. the realization of the
presence of God as the Buddha nature as
the reality of the self
and that branch of Buddhism called lotus
land coincides with Christianity in
which the Buddha of the lotus land is
the savior.
All right. So the aim of Christianity is
to reach 540.
The ultimate
saintthood, the ideal of Christianity
is unconditional love. 540.
Where can you find 540 in today's
society? There are spiritual teachers
above 540.
There are spiritual groups 540 and over.
The best known being Alcoholics
Anonymous.
Yeah. Aa, curiously enough, calibrates
at 540. Unconditional love.
unconditional love, which is shocking to
people who are not familiar with
unconditional love because the guy has a
slip, he goes out, shoots three people,
runs over five children, and burns down
his house. And when he comes back to a
meeting, they say, "Gee, we're glad
you're back, Joe.
You sure need to be here."
You may not think you got a problem, but
we know you do. So,
all right. That's unconditional love in
practice as a reality, not as a not as a
religious ideal to be memorized, but as
an actual way of the heart.
And Jesus really says that if you get up
to 540, you really don't have to worry.
In fact, he says if you get to up to
500, you don't have to worry. The ideal
of to love your neighbor as yourself is
what?
Love your neighbor as yourself. Is it is
over 500? Resist. It's over 540.
Reserve. Uhoh. It's unconditional love,
folks. Hate to tell you, but it's
unconditional love.
Oh, gee. Wiz that darn neighbor. We got
to Oh.
I was holding off on him.
Yes. still be uh at that. Well, maybe
after today's lecture, we'll get around
to it.
Okay, we'll well Okay.
Well, okay. Where does the willingness
come from? As justified as it is,
you realize what it's costing you. You
say, "Do I love Jesus? Do I love Christ?
Do I love God? Am I willing to sacrifice
the ego for enlightenment?" however you
want to phrase it,
more than I want to dislike this person.
And of course, the answer comes no
because otherwise you're giving your
ultimate spiritual destiny to some
stranger, your ex-mother-in-law or
something.
You understand?
So the willingness to surrender then
comes out of the willingness
to give all to God.
Raman Maharshi is well known because he
only died died in the 1958 and the
advantage of the more recent gurus who
calibrated in the 700
700s Mr. Soda Maharaj and Ramano
Maharshi both around 700
is because they live so relatively
recently that we at least have forbatim
some explanation of teachings which were
already there in more cryptic form
uh hundreds of years or even a thousand
years ago but they were so cryptic as to
be unintelligible
unless you're already enlightened.
Many of the things that are said, let's
say,
by Hang Poe are absolutely right on,
but to realize they're right on, you got
to be at like 800 to get it,
which isn't too helpful when you're
still trying to figure out how to
forgive your ex-mother-in-law.
So, practically speaking, we want to
start with a teacher to to whom we can
relate.
Having a pe teacher of very high
calibration is not necessarily of any
great benefit. I think the the aura of
the great teacher is a great benefit,
but the specifics of what is being
taught may not correlate with where
you're at at the time. If you're still
having trouble getting forgiving your
ex-mother-in-law, you don't need a
teacher 800 to tell you that you got to
let that go.
The course of miracles is extremely good
at that because uh the in in what the
course of miracles says is you cannot
let it you cannot forgive it as you
presently see it. Isn't that a great
brilliant observation on the nature of
the ego
the way you see it now? No, you can't
honestly legitimately let it go. You can
only pretend to have let it go. You can
only suppress the anger. You can only
suppress the judgmentalism.
It says that your your problem is not
that you hate it or you're angry or
something. The problem is that reality
has been distorted by the perceptual
apparatus of the ego
and now you're seeing it out of context.
And when you place it back in context,
it's automatically resolved. There's
nothing to forgive.
Every uh negative feeling then is a
consequence of taking something out of
context.
taking it out of context and coloring it
with an emotionality.
All right. So, how do you surrender to
specific surrendering the ego is first
to contextualize what ego really is that
it's not evil and
that it's the persistence of the animal
but the persistence of the animal deters
one's spiritual evolution and therefore
the object is to transcend it.
The best way to transcend it and the
reason for these lectures is to describe
in some detail the actual mechanisms of
the ego
in the course of miracles
that is done to a considerable extent.
There's a considerable explanation as
you go through the workbook of the
mechanisms of the ego. Um but then it's
really up to the Holy Spirit when you
surrender it to God. You're asking God
to recontextualize it and so that you
see it differently. And now that you see
it differently, there's nothing to
forgive and the whole thing is resolved.
In these lectures, we try to be more
specific about how does that how does
that perceptual distortion occur in the
first place?
It occurs in the first place because of
the ego's propensity
for positionality
in positionality meaning the creation of
the opposites by an arbitrary point of
view
to pick on a scale of temperature and
say well above this it's hot and below
this is cold. Well, you could have gone
down here and said above this it's hot
and below this it's cold. Or you could
have gone up and here and say above this
it's hot and below here it's cold. The
important thing to see is that the the
scale is really only of one measurement.
It's not two.
It's not either or. It's not good versus
bad
to see that what the mind considers to
be opposites are merely gradations all
on the same scale.
All right.
Let's take what could be conceived of by
the ego as a duality in this very scale
of consciousness. We could say, well,
there's a duality between that which is
above 200 and makes you go strong with
kinesiology and that which is below 200,
it makes you go weak.
Like temperature, temperature measures
the presence of heat, doesn't measure
the presence of cold.
There's only one variable called heat.
If heat is present, we call it warm. As
less and less heat is present, we call
it cold. So cold is nothing but the the
absence of heat, right? There is no such
thing as coldness. I mean, we can do the
same thing with light. Light and
darkness are not opposites. There is
only one variable.
What is that? Algebra.
where you study how the relationship of
var variables, there's only one variable
and that's called light. Light is either
present or not.
Light is either intensely present, less
and less light. We begin to say it's
getting dimmer. Now we can say it's semi
dark. And now we can say it's dark. Now
we can say it's pitch black. There's
only one variable, light. There's not
two variables called light and darkness.
Therein lies the resolution of the
problems of the ego. To realize that one
thing, there is only one variable.
It's present to varying degrees. That's
all or experiencable by varying degrees.
So on this scale of consciousness then
the light which shines forth first
described in gen Genesis the unmanifest
becomes manifest in the nonlinear world
of nonform
as the energy field of light
representing the infinite potentiality
of that which becomes the universe.
All right. So as the infinite
potentiality,
the radiance of God shines forth as
creation,
it does so first in the nonlinear
domain. Only weighed down the whole
process does it begin to appear in form
and materiality.
That's weighed along the process.
By the time it reaches physicality,
then the light interacts with
physicality
and life originates and then evolves
from the bottom up.
So, as we said last time, there's no
conflict between evolution
and creation because evolution is
creation.
Evolution is creation. Sorry. So as the
hand of God unfolds,
perception witnesses it as a sequence in
what it thinks is time.
But all we're seeing is the unfoldment
of creation. And therefore, creation is
what is responsible for what is
happening this instant because the
unfoldingness of creation is what we
call now. Huh? All right. So all we see
then is the infinite potentiality, the
power of God
manifesting
not only as this universe but as an
infinite sequence of universes because
the essence of God includes as a quality
creation, creativity
that which is created by God then has
the essence of God within it and
consequently also has the power of
creation.
So as one uni, as we speak of it
linguistically,
out of the universe arises an infinite
universe of infinite universes of
infinite universes which
every instant faster than the speed of
light are creating further universes
which because they are innately creative
are creating other universes.
You understand what I'm saying? Right?
out of power like that then we have to
have a we have to scale down the power
so that it's compatible with
protoplasmic life
this kind of this kind of energy then
would fry an ordinary piece of
protoplasm wouldn't it
even boils uh solid lava into solid rock
into lava anyway so infinite power has
it gets scaled down and we call
uh the love of God. So this is a scale
of of love at the top is infinite
unconditional love
and
this represents less and less love. When
we get down to the level of the
dinosaur, love is sorely absent. One
dinosaur does not really care about
another as he gobbles him up, right?
You see maybe the most advanced
dinosaur. She lays an egg and maybe cast
back a longing glance at it. That's the
beginning. But she goes on because
there's other things to do. All right.
So
we see consciousness then can be
calibrated as to the presence of love.
This denotes the absence of love. Huh?
As we note the absence of love, we
notice that instead of love, we have
egocentricity.
We have a narcissistic
megalomaniac self agrandisment
in which
the self with a small s of the ego
becomes God.
And out of that to maintain that
illusion
that which is really God has to be
refused.
And that's where the lower astral realm
arises.
Lower astral realm.
Then it's constituted by the those that
consciousness which refuses the divinity
of God as creator and says no.
I am Elizabeth
am greater than all of mankind
and the international tribunal and is
that goes this way and the international
tribunal has no right to question my
actions nor do these judges have any
authority nor does this court have any
of this authority
because I am greater than all of mankind
right
>> I can therefore with impunity slaughter
34 million people and it's my business
not yours my b is not yours right it
allows Hitler to say that Germany does
not Germans don't deserve to live
because they've lost the war and he
wanted all Germany destroyed right he
wanted all of Paris destroyed so
throughout history
that which is the totally devoid of
divine love and refuses it then presents
itself on the planet
as a I haven't tracked it out
completely. Let me see if I'm right.
Let me see. Am I right? Yeah. Yep. I'm
going to do a step on it again. Uh
yes, what I'm thinking is correct. Is it
It's okay to say it is. Okay. So,
I don't like to shock people out of
their shoes, but uh the dinosaurs, as
much as they're cute and we give them
away with hamburgers and all, are the
ultimate of.
And so that that lineage then evolves as
Mosovich as Hitler as uh as Nero as the
great um torturers and killers of
mankind.
Um the opposite way of the herbivore
which
uh see love appears uh within evolution
as first as maternal love. That's its
first breakthrough.
Uh so the evolution into love choosing
either love choosing God or choosing to
negate God and choosing the energy of
the dinosaur is like two alternate ways
to go. Okay. All right. So there there
the degree to which love is present then
and the unconditionality of it the
willingness to totally surrender
anything and everything to God is the
one variable uh on that scale. It does
not mean that anybody is better than
anybody else. That's why I like the
other scale. Let's put up the other
scale. Let's put up the
the nice clear one.
All right. So, this the clear one is
mathematically uh correct. U
but it doesn't infer what we're saying.
Let's have the shaded one, which is the
next one in revolution.
shaded one. So this graphically tries to
display the same concept. The presence
of God is infinite potentiality
as the reality of the self
unfolding.
All right? So this is the persistence
you might say of the animal world. The
persistence of the animal domain.
Persistence of
not the opposite but the other. So
there's two ways to go. The way of
hatred and the dinosaur
um where your survival is always at the
cost of the life of someone else or the
way of the herbivore
in which life is sustained in the
mamalian world by love.
So you choose either love or non-love.
The freedom of our own nature as we are
created is to to choose choose God or
not.
I spent many years as an atheist and I
mean I was a devout atheist. I didn't
fool around with it as an intellectual
position
because it was cute and stylish. No, it
was not intellectualism.
You know, in college you get sophomore
work and you know uh no it wasn't that
kind. was uh I think as I've spoken
before I was walking in the woods one
day and I was a devout u in fact a
scrupulous uh Christian I was a boy
soprano and um I still uh adore uh
church and uh great cathedrals
and I don't speak in great cathedrals
because then I walk in I break out in
tears at the incredible beauty of it.
Anyway, one day I was uh the downside of
religion was scrupulosity and uh anyway
I had a very good Christian background.
So one day I'm walking through the woods
and all of a sudden the totality of
man's suffering
was revealed.
It was almost like the opposite side of
the infinite light that came to me when
I was like 37 or whatever. It was almost
like the opposite of it.
the in the the totality of the suffering
of all mankind throughout all of time.
I can't explain to you how I knew it but
it was
in that instant I became an atheist.
I hated any god that could allow
the sheer dimension is as well as
qualities of what I saw.
And I became a rabid atheist.
I mean I went to Jesuit universities and
boy when we hit the bar on Friday night
I mean I could beat them beat their
socks off with theology. I got a
straight A in theology and thought it
was all BS.
And so here's this atheist getting
straight A's in theology. I can tell you
everything that's wrong with
Thomas Aquinas's proofs for the
existence of God as primary cause. In
fact, I'll tell you today if I remember.
And uh it was always worth a free beer.
But
those are drinking days in college.
uh because I held
a a confusion which the ego commonly
makes. It holds God responsible for that
which is the consequence of the ego. The
totality of human suffering is the
consequence of all those ego positions.
It's not a consequence of God. God
doesn't create any
create anything like that. But the ego
which
uh does create it. So I held God
responsible for that which is really the
consequence of the functioning of the
ego
but I was uh integrously
uh atheist.
Let's see what happens to the atheist
calibration wise at the level of the
atheist the integrity was over 200 210
280 300.
All right. So the atheist can be
integrous. Huh? Integris.
uh if it's not an inellectual position
of pridefulness and vanity and ego,
but if one's commitment to truth is
profound
and you're a religionist, there's going
to be a moment when you're going to go
through a violent convulsion because the
lot of
what one holds dear is going to run
smack up against the commitment to
absolute truth. And that's what that was
me anyway. So
at the time I was a psychoan
psychoanalysis and uh Lionel Oloy who
was a professor at Columbia University
and he was an atheist too. So we we were
took a dim view of religion.
He called it foxhole fear and I said
you're right.
Foxhole fear. Yeah right. You regress
the childhood and you want daddy God to
save you. Oh boy. Wasn't that infantile?
We were both ridiculous. So that's as
good as the in intellect can do with
God. So because the presence of God is a
direct and profound experience and all
that went out the window many years
later when I hit bottom and uh and the
ego stopped functioning altogether
went into a funk.
So the willingness to surrender every
positionality to God then requires
understanding the nature of the ego. We
said every the ego works on the basis of
positionalities of either ors. It takes
that which is unitary and see and tries
to dissolve it into a duality.
So the problem of the ego is that
positionality creates duality.
Therefore, the strict definition of the
pathway
which I represent would be most closely
historically advida.
The pathway of
understanding the presence of God by
understanding the nature and the source
of the mind itself
which takes you as you go through it
beyond mind to no mind. And then the
question is how do you explain
no mind in language?
That took 30 years.
How do you explain no mind via the mind?
Right.
All right. So the surrendering of the
willingness to surrender positionalities
then is really done the power behind it
is really the heart. the willingness to
surrender the way you see it and ask God
uh to show it to you as it is in truth.
The willingness to let go right and
wrong. And
you see what keeps these positions
and this part is important. The rest of
it was just talking. What keeps these
positions in place is the satisfaction,
the feed, the feedback we get out of it,
the juice we get out of it.
The ego can juice any situation
and just suck all kinds of continuing
energy to survive out of it.
Channel 15 News at 5:30, that'll really
put you on
There you'll see sentimentality, the
tragic squeezed, all the babies drowning
in the bathtubs and the little tikes
getting run over by this
taxi cabs. Never a child, it's always a
tikeke, nor a tot.
Because tot squeezes that bit of cheapo
sentimentality out of you. You know what
I mean? All right. That's what the ego
does all the time. You watch people as
they get on TV. This is a the generation
of complainers. Everybody gets complain.
Everybody has a position, a political
correct
springboard from which to get some time
and attention.
You'll see how they juice it. I mean,
the ego delights in every one of its
positions. So, it isn't that it hates,
it's that it enjoys hating. It isn't
that it gets revenge, it digs getting
revenge. turning that and knifing that
son of a I'm making him pay.
When a cop does that to a culprit, we
punish him, don't we? He's doing just
what you want to do. Beat the crap out
of that robber.
Last night we're watching on TV some guy
the railroad robber or something to
killer. I don't know. He killed like 30,
40 people all over the country.
Butchered them, sexually molested them,
chopped them into small pieces, sexually
molested the pieces. I mean, you know,
and uh at the end you can be sure
somebody's worried about this guy's
civil rights, right?
Yeah. Right. I worry about his civil
rights.
Uh yes. So that's an mislication of a
positionality. It's correct. But what
invalidates it is context.
The the ethics of war is not the same as
the ethics of peace. the ethics of
uh the street is not the ethics of the
university
and uh we behave differently at Harvard
than we do on the streets of New York
City when we're dealing crack. You know
what I mean? You got a different set of
standards. So context then is very
important to truth. Truth is cannot be
stated without defining context.
And the attempt to define truth as
content only is the downfall of science.
Currently, science is belittling itself.
Right now, the buzz word in science is
what's called um
um I forget it. It's so horrible. I'm
going to forget it.