Welcome
Welcome to
Welcome to Dr.
Welcome to Dr. David
Welcome to Dr. David Hawkins
Welcome to Dr. David Hawkins Sedona
Welcome to Dr. David Hawkins Sedona 2002
series,
series, The
Welcome to Dr. David Hawkins Sedona 2002
series, The Way
series, The Way to
Welcome to Dr. David Hawkins Sedona 2002
series, The Way to God.
series, The Way to God. Lecture
Welcome to Dr. David Hawkins Sedona 2002
series, The Way to God. Lecture 1,
Causality:
Causality: The
Causality: The Ego's
Causality: The Ego's Foundation.
Originally
Originally presented
Causality: The Ego's Foundation.
Originally presented January
Originally presented January 19th,
Causality: The Ego's Foundation.
Originally presented January 19th, 2002
at
at the
at the Sedona
at the Sedona Creative
at the Sedona Creative Life
at the Sedona Creative Life Center.
So
So I'm
at the Sedona Creative Life Center.
So I'm very
So I'm very pleased
at the Sedona Creative Life Center.
So I'm very pleased to
So I'm very pleased to start
at the Sedona Creative Life Center.
So I'm very pleased to start with
So I'm very pleased to start with you
at the Sedona Creative Life Center.
So I'm very pleased to start with you a
series
series of
series of 12
series of 12 lectures.
series of 12 lectures. The
series of 12 lectures. The last
series of 12 lectures. The last time
series of 12 lectures. The last time I
did
did 12
series of 12 lectures. The last time I
did 12 lectures
did 12 lectures was
series of 12 lectures. The last time I
did 12 lectures was back
did 12 lectures was back in
series of 12 lectures. The last time I
did 12 lectures was back in the
did 12 lectures was back in the early
80s.
80s. And
80s. And those
80s. And those were
80s. And those were 12
80s. And those were 12 uh
80s. And those were 12 uh 12
80s. And those were 12 uh 12 visits
80s. And those were 12 uh 12 visits with
the
the good
80s. And those were 12 uh 12 visits with
the good doctor
the good doctor is
80s. And those were 12 uh 12 visits with
the good doctor is what
the good doctor is what they
80s. And those were 12 uh 12 visits with
the good doctor is what they the
the good doctor is what they the way
they
they titled
they titled them.
they titled them. And
they titled them. And the
they titled them. And the that
they titled them. And the that had
they titled them. And the that had to
they titled them. And the that had to do
with
with the
they titled them. And the that had to do
with the application
with the application of
they titled them. And the that had to do
with the application of our
with the application of our research
they titled them. And the that had to do
with the application of our research on
the
the nature
the nature of
the nature of consciousness
the nature of consciousness as
the nature of consciousness as it
applied
applied to
the nature of consciousness as it
applied to various
applied to various illnesses.
the nature of consciousness as it
applied to various illnesses. So
applied to various illnesses. So each
the nature of consciousness as it
applied to various illnesses. So each of
those
those 12
those 12 tapes
those 12 tapes applied
those 12 tapes applied to
those 12 tapes applied to a
those 12 tapes applied to a different
thing
thing such
those 12 tapes applied to a different
thing such as
thing such as heart
those 12 tapes applied to a different
thing such as heart disease
thing such as heart disease or
depression
depression or
depression or anxiety.
This
This series
depression or anxiety.
This series um
This series um the
depression or anxiety.
This series um the research
This series um the research has
considerably
considerably advanced
considerably advanced over
considerably advanced over the
considerably advanced over the last
considerably advanced over the last 20
years.
uh
uh power
uh power versus
uh power versus force
uh power versus force was
uh power versus force was preceded
uh power versus force was preceded by
good
good 10
uh power versus force was preceded by
good 10 years
good 10 years of
uh power versus force was preceded by
good 10 years of research
good 10 years of research and
uh power versus force was preceded by
good 10 years of research and um
um
um to
make
make sure
um to
make sure that
make sure that it
um to
make sure that it met
make sure that it met the
um to
make sure that it met the scientific
criteria
criteria of
criteria of today's
criteria of today's world
criteria of today's world I
criteria of today's world I went
criteria of today's world I went to
criteria of today's world I went to the
bother
bother of
criteria of today's world I went to the
bother of getting
bother of getting a
criteria of today's world I went to the
bother of getting a PhD
so
so as
so as to
so as to give
so as to give it
so as to give it greater
so as to give it greater academic
credence.
And
And so
And so I
And so I got
And so I got a
And so I got a PhD
And so I got a PhD at
And so I got a PhD at age
And so I got a PhD at age 65
and
and however
and however my
and however my PhD
and however my PhD didn't
and however my PhD didn't come
and however my PhD didn't come out
and however my PhD didn't come out till
about
about a
and however my PhD didn't come out till
about a month
about a month after
and however my PhD didn't come out till
about a month after the
about a month after the book
and however my PhD didn't come out till
about a month after the book was
published.
published. So
published. So they
published. So they said
published. So they said so
published. So they said so we
published. So they said so we put
published. So they said so we put the
PhD
PhD on
published. So they said so we put the
PhD on the
PhD on the front.
published. So they said so we put the
PhD on the front. I
PhD on the front. I says
published. So they said so we put the
PhD on the front. I says no
PhD on the front. I says no you
published. So they said so we put the
PhD on the front. I says no you better
wait
wait until
wait until I
wait until I get
wait until I get it.
So
So the
wait until I get it.
So the first
So the first edition
wait until I get it.
So the first edition of
So the first edition of power
wait until I get it.
So the first edition of power versus
just
just said
just said MD
just said MD and
just said MD and then
just said MD and then a
just said MD and then a month
just said MD and then a month later
just said MD and then a month later I
got
got the
just said MD and then a month later I
got the PhD.
got the PhD. So
just said MD and then a month later I
got the PhD. So now
got the PhD. So now it
just said MD and then a month later I
got the PhD. So now it says
got the PhD. So now it says MD/PhD
just said MD and then a month later I
got the PhD. So now it says MD/PhD which
I
I thought
I thought would
I thought would impress
I thought would impress the
I thought would impress the world
I thought would impress the world and
give
give it
I thought would impress the world and
give it greater
give it greater firepower
because
because at
because at that
because at that time
because at that time I
because at that time I thought
because at that time I thought the
because at that time I thought the first
significant
significant review
because at that time I thought the first
significant review of
significant review of the
because at that time I thought the first
significant review of the work
significant review of the work would
because at that time I thought the first
significant review of the work would be
in
in brainmind
in brainmind bulletin
in brainmind bulletin and
in brainmind bulletin and which
in brainmind bulletin and which it
in brainmind bulletin and which it was
and
and it
in brainmind bulletin and which it was
and it got
and it got a
in brainmind bulletin and which it was
and it got a very
and it got a very positive
in brainmind bulletin and which it was
and it got a very positive review
and it got a very positive review and
resulted
resulted in
resulted in it
resulted in it being
resulted in it being published
resulted in it being published in
resulted in it being published in other
countries.
So
So the
So the research
So the research is
So the research is of
So the research is of course
So the research is of course has
So the research is of course has gone
considerably
considerably further.
So the research is of course has gone
considerably further. The
considerably further. The purpose
So the research is of course has gone
considerably further. The purpose of
power
power versus
power versus force
power versus force was
power versus force was to
power versus force was to go
power versus force was to go from
power versus force was to go from the
familiar
familiar linear
power versus force was to go from the
familiar linear world
and
and provide
and provide a
and provide a context
and provide a context in
and provide a context in which
and provide a context in which you
and provide a context in which you could
move
move into
and provide a context in which you could
move into the
move into the less
and provide a context in which you could
move into the less familiar
move into the less familiar nonlinear
with
with some
with some degree
with some degree of
with some degree of comfort
with some degree of comfort that
with some degree of comfort that you're
not
not moving
with some degree of comfort that you're
not moving into
not moving into the
with some degree of comfort that you're
not moving into the purely
not moving into the purely mystical
imaginary.
So
So I
imaginary.
So I was
So I was presenting
imaginary.
So I was presenting it
So I was presenting it from
imaginary.
So I was presenting it from the
viewpoint
viewpoint of
viewpoint of what
viewpoint of what I
viewpoint of what I considered
viewpoint of what I considered the
average
average intelligent
viewpoint of what I considered the
average intelligent reader
average intelligent reader who's
viewpoint of what I considered the
average intelligent reader who's also
interested
interested in
interested in spirituality.
and
and who
interested in spirituality.
and who is
and who is focused
interested in spirituality.
and who is focused on
and who is focused on the
parameter
parameter the
parameter the leading
parameter the leading edge
parameter the leading edge of
parameter the leading edge of advanced
theoretical
theoretical physics
parameter the leading edge of advanced
theoretical physics which
theoretical physics which is
parameter the leading edge of advanced
theoretical physics which is stuck
theoretical physics which is stuck right
now
now because
now because it
now because it can't
now because it can't get
now because it can't get beyond
now because it can't get beyond the
now because it can't get beyond the this
block
block between
now because it can't get beyond the this
block between the
block between the linear
now because it can't get beyond the this
block between the linear and
block between the linear and the
nonlinear
nonlinear domain.
nonlinear domain. It's
nonlinear domain. It's gone
nonlinear domain. It's gone about
nonlinear domain. It's gone about as
nonlinear domain. It's gone about as far
as
as it
nonlinear domain. It's gone about as far
as it can
as it can go
nonlinear domain. It's gone about as far
as it can go in
as it can go in the
nonlinear domain. It's gone about as far
as it can go in the linear
as it can go in the linear domain.
Um
Um so
Um so I
Um so I helped
Um so I helped I
Um so I helped I was
Um so I helped I was hoping
Um so I helped I was hoping to
Um so I helped I was hoping to enlarge
the
the paradigm
Um so I helped I was hoping to enlarge
the paradigm of
the paradigm of reality
Um so I helped I was hoping to enlarge
the paradigm of reality of
the paradigm of reality of science
so
so that
so that the
so that the intelligent
so that the intelligent reader
you
you know
so that the intelligent reader
you know could
you know could comprehend
so that the intelligent reader
you know could comprehend the
you know could comprehend the work
so that the intelligent reader
you know could comprehend the work and
say
say ha
say ha there
say ha there must
say ha there must be
say ha there must be something
say ha there must be something uh
say ha there must be something uh in
say ha there must be something uh in the
nonlinear
nonlinear domain
say ha there must be something uh in the
nonlinear domain that
nonlinear domain that we
say ha there must be something uh in the
nonlinear domain that we should
nonlinear domain that we should be
looking
looking at.
looking at. So
looking at. So that
looking at. So that was
looking at. So that was that
looking at. So that was that purpose.
The
The purpose
looking at. So that was that purpose.
The purpose of
The purpose of power
looking at. So that was that purpose.
The purpose of power versus
was
was to
was to take
was to take us
was to take us from
was to take us from the
was to take us from the familiar
um
um the
was to take us from the familiar
um the Newtonian
um the Newtonian paradigm
was to take us from the familiar
um the Newtonian paradigm of
um the Newtonian paradigm of reality
and
and prepare
and prepare us
and prepare us that
and prepare us that there
and prepare us that there is
and prepare us that there is evidence
evidence
evidence of
and prepare us that there is evidence
evidence of the
evidence of the reality
and prepare us that there is evidence
evidence of the reality of
evidence of the reality of the
and prepare us that there is evidence
evidence of the reality of the nonlinear
because
because that's
because that's the
because that's the great
because that's the great learning
because that's the great learning block.
the
the uh
because that's the great learning block.
the uh intellectuals
the uh intellectuals uh
because that's the great learning block.
the uh intellectuals uh at
the uh intellectuals uh at the
because that's the great learning block.
the uh intellectuals uh at the present
time
time the
time the sort
time the sort of
time the sort of this
time the sort of this almost
time the sort of this almost like
time the sort of this almost like a
political
political shift
time the sort of this almost like a
political shift in
political shift in psychiatry
time the sort of this almost like a
political shift in psychiatry for
instance
instance in
instance in which
instance in which they
instance in which they constantly
instance in which they constantly use
the
the word
instance in which they constantly use
the word evidence-based
the word evidence-based evidence-based
so
so is
so is anything
so is anything having
so is anything having to
so is anything having to do
so is anything having to do with
so is anything having to do with the
nature
nature of
so is anything having to do with the
nature of man
nature of man is
so is anything having to do with the
nature of man is dead
nature of man is dead now
so is anything having to do with the
nature of man is dead now and
nature of man is dead now and we
so is anything having to do with the
nature of man is dead now and we only
talk
talk about
talk about white
talk about white mice
talk about white mice levers
talk about white mice levers and
talk about white mice levers and doses
of
of meds
talk about white mice levers and doses
of meds and
of meds and neurotransmitters
talk about white mice levers and doses
of meds and neurotransmitters there's
of meds and neurotransmitters there's no
human
human attached
human attached anymore
human attached anymore no
human attached anymore no mention
anything
anything human
human attached anymore no mention
anything human is
anything human is law
human attached anymore no mention
anything human is law because
anything human is law because it
human attached anymore no mention
anything human is law because it has
anything human is law because it has to
be
be evidence-based.
Well,
Well, the
be evidence-based.
Well, the purpose
Well, the purpose of
be evidence-based.
Well, the purpose of power
Well, the purpose of power versus
be evidence-based.
Well, the purpose of power versus force
was
was evidence-based.
was evidence-based. Evidence-based.
So,
So, as
was evidence-based. Evidence-based.
So, as you
So, as you see
was evidence-based. Evidence-based.
So, as you see that
So, as you see that scale
was evidence-based. Evidence-based.
So, as you see that scale of
consciousness
consciousness which
consciousness which has
consciousness which has become
relatively
relatively well
consciousness which has become
relatively well known
relatively well known and
consciousness which has become
relatively well known and has
relatively well known and has been
reprinted
reprinted in
reprinted in many
reprinted in many many
reprinted in many many other
reprinted in many many other books
reprinted in many many other books and
cited
cited in
reprinted in many many other books and
cited in many
cited in many references
reprinted in many many other books and
cited in many references and
cited in many references and is
relatively
relatively well
relatively well known.
relatively well known. What
relatively well known. What I
relatively well known. What I tried
relatively well known. What I tried to
do
do was
relatively well known. What I tried to
do was present
do was present evidence-based
documentation
documentation of
documentation of the
documentation of the reality
documentation of the reality of
documentation of the reality of the
nonlinear
nonlinear domain
documentation of the reality of the
nonlinear domain and
nonlinear domain and provide
documentation of the reality of the
nonlinear domain and provide some
nonlinear domain and provide some kind
of
of signpost
of signpost so
of signpost so that
of signpost so that the
of signpost so that the unfamiliar
of signpost so that the unfamiliar could
be
be approached
of signpost so that the unfamiliar could
be approached without
be approached without undue
of signpost so that the unfamiliar could
be approached without undue anxiety.
People
People who
People who think
People who think the
People who think the only
People who think the only world
People who think the only world is
People who think the only world is the
intellectual
intellectual world
People who think the only world is the
intellectual world of
intellectual world of logic
People who think the only world is the
intellectual world of logic or
intellectual world of logic or the
material
material world
material world are
material world are rather
material world are rather frightened
material world are rather frightened of
anything
anything that
material world are rather frightened of
anything that that
anything that that goes
material world are rather frightened of
anything that that goes beyond
anything that that goes beyond that
material world are rather frightened of
anything that that goes beyond that par
their
their paradigm.
their paradigm. It
their paradigm. It has
their paradigm. It has to
their paradigm. It has to do
their paradigm. It has to do with
paradigm
paradigm anxiety.
their paradigm. It has to do with
paradigm anxiety. That
paradigm anxiety. That there's
their paradigm. It has to do with
paradigm anxiety. That there's anything
real
real that
real that is
real that is beyond
real that is beyond the
real that is beyond the science's
capacity
capacity to
real that is beyond the science's
capacity to measure
capacity to measure is
real that is beyond the science's
capacity to measure is rather
capacity to measure is rather scary
real that is beyond the science's
capacity to measure is rather scary to
many
many people.
many people. And
many people. And it
many people. And it uh
many people. And it uh and
many people. And it uh and they
viferously
viferously get
many people. And it uh and they
viferously get on
viferously get on television.
many people. And it uh and they
viferously get on television. You'll
viferously get on television. You'll see
them
them at
them at night,
them at night, you
them at night, you know,
them at night, you know, trying
them at night, you know, trying to
them at night, you know, trying to uh
prove
prove that
them at night, you know, trying to uh
prove that near-death
prove that near-death experiences
them at night, you know, trying to uh
prove that near-death experiences are
all
all due
all due to
all due to brain
all due to brain physiology
all due to brain physiology and
all due to brain physiology and God
all due to brain physiology and God is
probably
probably just
all due to brain physiology and God is
probably just a
probably just a nucleus
all due to brain physiology and God is
probably just a nucleus and
hypothalammus
hypothalammus somewhere
trying
trying to
hypothalammus somewhere
trying to keep
trying to keep keep
hypothalammus somewhere
trying to keep keep reality
trying to keep keep reality confined
into
into this
into this box
into this box of
into this box of the
into this box of the logical
uncomfortable
uh
uh and
uh and there
uh and there are
uh and there are there's
uh and there are there's some
uh and there are there's some people
whose
whose life
uh and there are there's some people
whose life is
whose life is uh
uh and there are there's some people
whose life is uh devoted
whose life is uh devoted to
uh and there are there's some people
whose life is uh devoted to knocking
whose life is uh devoted to knocking you
know
know knocking
know knocking anything
know knocking anything beyond
know knocking anything beyond the
ordinary
ordinary paradigm.
So
So power
So power versus
So power versus force
So power versus force was
So power versus force was then
So power versus force was then the
introduction
introduction to
So power versus force was then the
introduction to the
introduction to the material
So power versus force was then the
introduction to the material and
introduction to the material and uh
So power versus force was then the
introduction to the material and uh the
thing
thing that
thing that was
thing that was interesting
thing that was interesting about
thing that was interesting about it
thing that was interesting about it is
that
that we
thing that was interesting about it is
that we learned
that we learned that
uh
uh you
uh you can't
uh you can't use
uh you can't use ordinary
uh you can't use ordinary mechanical
instruments
instruments when
uh you can't use ordinary mechanical
instruments when you're
instruments when you're dealing
uh you can't use ordinary mechanical
instruments when you're dealing with
instruments when you're dealing with a
nonlinear.
nonlinear. The
nonlinear. The nonlinear
nonlinear. The nonlinear has
nonlinear. The nonlinear has to
nonlinear. The nonlinear has to do
nonlinear. The nonlinear has to do with
with
with life
nonlinear. The nonlinear has to do with
with life itself
with life itself constantly.
Consequently,
Consequently, it
Consequently, it would
Consequently, it would seem
Consequently, it would seem obvious
Consequently, it would seem obvious that
the
the measuring
Consequently, it would seem obvious that
the measuring instrument
the measuring instrument of
Consequently, it would seem obvious that
the measuring instrument of that
the measuring instrument of that domain
would
would be
would be a
would be a living
would be a living thing.
would be a living thing. In
would be a living thing. In this
would be a living thing. In this case,
would be a living thing. In this case, a
human
human being
would be a living thing. In this case, a
human being and
human being and the
would be a living thing. In this case, a
human being and the response
human being and the response of
would be a living thing. In this case, a
human being and the response of that
human
human being
human being to
human being to the
human being to the field
human being to the field of
consciousness.
Once
Once in
Once in a
Once in a while
Once in a while I
Once in a while I get
Once in a while I get a
Once in a while I get a letter
Once in a while I get a letter from
readers
readers says,
Once in a while I get a letter from
readers says, can't
readers says, can't you
Once in a while I get a letter from
readers says, can't you somehow
readers says, can't you somehow do
Once in a while I get a letter from
readers says, can't you somehow do this
electronically?
That's
That's missing
electronically?
That's missing the
That's missing the point
electronically?
That's missing the point altogether.
That's missing the point altogether. No,
you
you cannot
you cannot do
you cannot do that
you cannot do that electronically.
Nor
Nor would
you cannot do that electronically.
Nor would I
Nor would I have
you cannot do that electronically.
Nor would I have any
Nor would I have any interest
you cannot do that electronically.
Nor would I have any interest in
Nor would I have any interest in doing
it
it because
it because that
it because that is
it because that is a
it because that is a different
it because that is a different world.
The
The electronically
it because that is a different world.
The electronically recordable
The electronically recordable world
it because that is a different world.
The electronically recordable world is
the
the Newtonian
the Newtonian paradigm
the Newtonian paradigm of
the Newtonian paradigm of reality
the Newtonian paradigm of reality which
according
according to
the Newtonian paradigm of reality which
according to our
according to our calibrated
the Newtonian paradigm of reality which
according to our calibrated levels
according to our calibrated levels of
consciousness
consciousness stops
consciousness stops at
consciousness stops at 499.
So
So we
consciousness stops at 499.
So we can
So we can follow
consciousness stops at 499.
So we can follow the
So we can follow the greatest
consciousness stops at 499.
So we can follow the greatest scientific
minds
minds in
minds in history,
minds in history, Newton
minds in history, Newton and
minds in history, Newton and uh
minds in history, Newton and uh Freud
and
and Einstein
and we
push
push the
and we
push the limits
push the limits of
and we
push the limits of the
push the limits of the scientific
logical
logical mind.
logical mind. And
logical mind. And on
logical mind. And on our
logical mind. And on our scale
logical mind. And on our scale of
consciousness
consciousness of
logical mind. And on our scale of
consciousness of which
consciousness of which most
logical mind. And on our scale of
consciousness of which most people
they're
they're familiar
they're familiar the
they're familiar the 499
they're familiar the 499 is
they're familiar the 499 is is
they're familiar the 499 is is pretty
much
much the
they're familiar the 499 is is pretty
much the edge
much the edge of
uh
uh the
uh the Newtonian
uh the Newtonian paradigm
uh the Newtonian paradigm and
uh the Newtonian paradigm and you'll
find
find a
uh the Newtonian paradigm and you'll
find a lot
find a lot of
uh the Newtonian paradigm and you'll
find a lot of very
find a lot of very advanced
uh the Newtonian paradigm and you'll
find a lot of very advanced theor
find a lot of very advanced theor uh
scientific
scientific thesis
scientific thesis etc
scientific thesis etc doctrines
scientific thesis etc doctrines and
scientific thesis etc doctrines and uh
bodies
bodies of
scientific thesis etc doctrines and uh
bodies of knowledge
bodies of knowledge stop
scientific thesis etc doctrines and uh
bodies of knowledge stop at
bodies of knowledge stop at 499.
It's
It's amazing
It's amazing how
It's amazing how over
It's amazing how over the
It's amazing how over the centuries
It's amazing how over the centuries so
many
many Sir
It's amazing how over the centuries so
many Sir Francis
many Sir Francis Bacon
It's amazing how over the centuries so
many Sir Francis Bacon so
many Sir Francis Bacon so many
It's amazing how over the centuries so
many Sir Francis Bacon so many of
many Sir Francis Bacon so many of them
stop
stop at
stop at $499.
stop at $499. First
stop at $499. First I
stop at $499. First I thought
stop at $499. First I thought I'm
stop at $499. First I thought I'm making
a
a mistake
stop at $499. First I thought I'm making
a mistake here.
a mistake here. And
stop at $499. First I thought I'm making
a mistake here. And how
a mistake here. And how can
stop at $499. First I thought I'm making
a mistake here. And how can they
a mistake here. And how can they all
stop at $499. First I thought I'm making
a mistake here. And how can they all be
$4.99
and
and there's
$4.99
and there's some
and there's some I
$4.99
and there's some I couldn't
and there's some I couldn't believe
$4.99
and there's some I couldn't believe were
$4.99.
$4.99. Like
$4.99. Like Einstein
$4.99. Like Einstein I
$4.99. Like Einstein I said
$4.99. Like Einstein I said no
$4.99. Like Einstein I said no he's
$4.99. Like Einstein I said no he's got
to
to be
$4.99. Like Einstein I said no he's got
to be more
to be more than
$4.99. Like Einstein I said no he's got
to be more than 54.99.
Uh
Uh but
Uh but no
Uh but no it
Uh but no it was
Uh but no it was $4.99.
Uh but no it was $4.99. So
Uh but no it was $4.99. So that's
Uh but no it was $4.99. So that's pretty
much
much the
Uh but no it was $4.99. So that's pretty
much the level
much the level at
Uh but no it was $4.99. So that's pretty
much the level at which
much the level at which we
Uh but no it was $4.99. So that's pretty
much the level at which we begin
much the level at which we begin to
merge
merge emerge
merge emerge into
merge emerge into a
merge emerge into a different
merge emerge into a different paradigm
of
of reality.
power
power versus
power versus force
power versus force took
power versus force took us
power versus force took us then
power versus force took us then from
power versus force took us then from the
Newtonian
Newtonian into
power versus force took us then from the
Newtonian into the
Newtonian into the nonlinear
power versus force took us then from the
Newtonian into the nonlinear from
Newtonian into the nonlinear from the
linear
linear domain
linear domain to
linear domain to the
linear domain to the nonlinear.
You
You see
linear domain to the nonlinear.
You see if
You see if we
linear domain to the nonlinear.
You see if we use
You see if we use language
linear domain to the nonlinear.
You see if we use language that
You see if we use language that is
linear domain to the nonlinear.
You see if we use language that is not
religiously
religiously historically
religiously historically loaded
religiously historically loaded uh
religiously historically loaded uh you
get
get a
religiously historically loaded uh you
get a wider
get a wider audience
religiously historically loaded uh you
get a wider audience people
get a wider audience people who
religiously historically loaded uh you
get a wider audience people who don't
have
have you
have you know
have you know if
have you know if you
have you know if you mention
have you know if you mention it
spiritual
spiritual or
have you know if you mention it
spiritual or religious
spiritual or religious terms
have you know if you mention it
spiritual or religious terms if
spiritual or religious terms if you
start
start dealing
start dealing in
start dealing in Sanskrit
start dealing in Sanskrit terms
start dealing in Sanskrit terms a
start dealing in Sanskrit terms a number
of
of people
start dealing in Sanskrit terms a number
of people will
of people will leave
start dealing in Sanskrit terms a number
of people will leave the
of people will leave the audience
because
because for
because for one
because for one reason
because for one reason or
because for one reason or another
because for one reason or another so
because for one reason or another so I
have
have tried
because for one reason or another so I
have tried to
have tried to stick
because for one reason or another so I
have tried to stick with
have tried to stick with primarily
common
common wording
common wording and
common wording and uh
common wording and uh So
common wording and uh So the
common wording and uh So the world
common wording and uh So the world of
familiarity,
familiarity, America
common wording and uh So the world of
familiarity, America calibrates
familiarity, America calibrates right
now
now at
now at 421.
now at 421. 421.
That's
That's the
now at 421. 421.
That's the intellect.
That's the intellect. The
now at 421. 421.
That's the intellect. The 400s
That's the intellect. The 400s are
now at 421. 421.
That's the intellect. The 400s are the
intellect.
So
So anybody
intellect.
So anybody who's
So anybody who's reasonably
intellectually
intellectually curious
intellectually curious would
intellectually curious would find
intellectually curious would find the
work
work interesting
intellectually curious would find the
work interesting and
work interesting and it
intellectually curious would find the
work interesting and it would
work interesting and it would lead
intellectually curious would find the
work interesting and it would lead them
to
to the
to the door
to the door of
to the door of a
to the door of a new
to the door of a new discovery.
right
right in
to the door of a new discovery.
right in the
right in the beginning
to the door of a new discovery.
right in the beginning I
right in the beginning I want
to the door of a new discovery.
right in the beginning I want to
right in the beginning I want to correct
sort
sort of
sort of a
sort of a misconception
sort of a misconception that
sort of a misconception that may
sort of a misconception that may have
arisen
arisen and
sort of a misconception that may have
arisen and um
arisen and um and
sort of a misconception that may have
arisen and um and it
arisen and um and it also
sort of a misconception that may have
arisen and um and it also has
arisen and um and it also has to
sort of a misconception that may have
arisen and um and it also has to do
arisen and um and it also has to do with
the
the um
the um advancement
the um advancement of
the um advancement of my
the um advancement of my own
consciousness
consciousness and
the um advancement of my own
consciousness and understanding.
consciousness and understanding. Um
the um advancement of my own
consciousness and understanding. Um we
sort
sort of
sort of developed
sort of developed a
sort of developed a a
sort of developed a a calibrated
sort of developed a a calibrated map
sort of developed a a calibrated map of
consciousness
consciousness at
sort of developed a a calibrated map of
consciousness at which
consciousness at which 200
sort of developed a a calibrated map of
consciousness at which 200 was
consciousness at which 200 was a
critical
critical level.
We
We said
critical level.
We said that
We said that everything
critical level.
We said that everything above,
We said that everything above, we
critical level.
We said that everything above, we found
that
that everything
that everything above
that everything above 200,
that everything above 200, everything
that's
that's true,
that everything above 200, everything
that's true, everything
that's true, everything that's
that everything above 200, everything
that's true, everything that's valid,
everything
everything that's
everything that's pro-life,
everything
everything that's
everything that's pro-life,
everything that's spiritually
everything that's spiritually um
everything that's pro-life,
everything that's spiritually um whole
goes
goes from
goes from 200
goes from 200 up
goes from 200 up and
goes from 200 up and makes
goes from 200 up and makes you
goes from 200 up and makes you go
strong.
strong. Everything
goes from 200 up and makes you go
strong. Everything below
strong. Everything below 200
goes from 200 up and makes you go
strong. Everything below 200 makes
strong. Everything below 200 makes you
go
go weak.
Um,
Um, and
go weak.
Um, and it
Um, and it goes
go weak.
Um, and it goes all
Um, and it goes all the
go weak.
Um, and it goes all the way
Um, and it goes all the way down
go weak.
Um, and it goes all the way down to
Um, and it goes all the way down to the
bottom.
bottom. So
bottom. So the
bottom. So the scale
bottom. So the scale of
bottom. So the scale of consciousness
was
was the
bottom. So the scale of consciousness
was the very
was the very top
bottom. So the scale of consciousness
was the very top was
was the very top was the
bottom. So the scale of consciousness
was the very top was the thousand
was the very top was the thousand Jesus
Christ,
Christ, Krishna,
Christ, Krishna, Buddha,
Christ, Krishna, Buddha, the
Christ, Krishna, Buddha, the great
avatars
avatars that
Christ, Krishna, Buddha, the great
avatars that have
avatars that have set
Christ, Krishna, Buddha, the great
avatars that have set the
avatars that have set the paradigm
Christ, Krishna, Buddha, the great
avatars that have set the paradigm of
spiritual
spiritual reality
spiritual reality for
spiritual reality for thousands
spiritual reality for thousands of
spiritual reality for thousands of years
calibrated
calibrated at
spiritual reality for thousands of years
calibrated at a
calibrated at a thousand.
spiritual reality for thousands of years
calibrated at a thousand. And
calibrated at a thousand. And at
spiritual reality for thousands of years
calibrated at a thousand. And at that
time
time we
time we discovered
time we discovered by
time we discovered by asking
time we discovered by asking that
time we discovered by asking that the
human
human nervous
time we discovered by asking that the
human nervous system
human nervous system cannot
time we discovered by asking that the
human nervous system cannot tolerate
human nervous system cannot tolerate an
energy
energy a
energy a spiritual
energy a spiritual energy
energy a spiritual energy beyond
energy a spiritual energy beyond a
thousand.
thousand. And
energy a spiritual energy beyond a
thousand. And those
thousand. And those of
energy a spiritual energy beyond a
thousand. And those of you
thousand. And those of you who've
energy a spiritual energy beyond a
thousand. And those of you who've gone
into
into very
into very advanced
into very advanced states
into very advanced states of
consciousness
consciousness will
into very advanced states of
consciousness will remember
consciousness will remember up
into very advanced states of
consciousness will remember up to
consciousness will remember up to 600
into very advanced states of
consciousness will remember up to 600 is
extremely
extremely pleasant.
extremely pleasant. In
extremely pleasant. In the
extremely pleasant. In the high
extremely pleasant. In the high 500s
extremely pleasant. In the high 500s is
it
it gets
extremely pleasant. In the high 500s is
it gets ecstatic.
Uh
Uh everything
Uh everything is
Uh everything is incredibly
Uh everything is incredibly beautiful.
Sound
Sound is
Uh everything is incredibly beautiful.
Sound is crystalline
Sound is crystalline and
Uh everything is incredibly beautiful.
Sound is crystalline and pure.
Sound is crystalline and pure. Uh
there's
there's a
there's a total
there's a total oneness
there's a total oneness to
there's a total oneness to everything.
Everything
Everything happens
there's a total oneness to everything.
Everything happens by
Everything happens by um
there's a total oneness to everything.
Everything happens by um synchronicity.
If
If you
If you think
If you think salt,
If you think salt, somebody
If you think salt, somebody says,
If you think salt, somebody says, "Would
you
you like
If you think salt, somebody says, "Would
you like some
you like some salt?"
It's
It's a
It's a marvelous
It's a marvelous world.
It's a marvelous world. You
It's a marvelous world. You can
It's a marvelous world. You can leave
It's a marvelous world. You can leave in
the
the high
It's a marvelous world. You can leave in
the high 500s.
the high 500s. You
It's a marvelous world. You can leave in
the high 500s. You can
the high 500s. You can walk
It's a marvelous world. You can leave in
the high 500s. You can walk out
the high 500s. You can walk out the
It's a marvelous world. You can leave in
the high 500s. You can walk out the door
without
without a
without a nickel
without a nickel in
without a nickel in your
without a nickel in your pocket
without a nickel in your pocket and
without a nickel in your pocket and no
food
food and
without a nickel in your pocket and no
food and everything
food and everything will
without a nickel in your pocket and no
food and everything will be
food and everything will be provided.
And
And I've
And I've done
And I've done it.
And I've done it. I
And I've done it. I walked
And I've done it. I walked out
And I've done it. I walked out without
anything.
And
And uh
And uh just
And uh just as
And uh just as you
And uh just as you think,
And uh just as you think, gosh,
And uh just as you think, gosh, I
And uh just as you think, gosh, I can
show
show you
And uh just as you think, gosh, I can
show you a
show you a snack.
And uh just as you think, gosh, I can
show you a snack. A
show you a snack. A friend
And uh just as you think, gosh, I can
show you a snack. A friend of
show you a snack. A friend of yours
says,
says, I'm
says, I'm going
says, I'm going for
says, I'm going for breakfast.
says, I'm going for breakfast. Got
says, I'm going for breakfast. Got to
take
take you
says, I'm going for breakfast. Got to
take you after
take you after breakfast.
says, I'm going for breakfast. Got to
take you after breakfast. It
take you after breakfast. It just
happens
happens that
happens that way.
happens that way. And
happens that way. And you
happens that way. And you can
happens that way. And you can go
happens that way. And you can go for
months
months without
happens that way. And you can go for
months without anything
months without anything at
happens that way. And you can go for
months without anything at all.
months without anything at all. So
happens that way. And you can go for
months without anything at all. So the
high
high 500s
high 500s are
high 500s are the
high 500s are the world
high 500s are the world of
high 500s are the world of the
synchronous,
synchronous, miraculous,
high 500s are the world of the
synchronous, miraculous, harmonious.
It's
It's an
It's an exquisite
It's an exquisite world.
uh
uh many
It's an exquisite world.
uh many gurus
uh many gurus uh
It's an exquisite world.
uh many gurus uh I
uh many gurus uh I would
It's an exquisite world.
uh many gurus uh I would say
uh many gurus uh I would say the
majority
majority that
majority that the
majority that the world
majority that the world considers
majority that the world considers to
majority that the world considers to be
gurus
gurus are
majority that the world considers to be
gurus are in
gurus are in the
majority that the world considers to be
gurus are in the mid
gurus are in the mid to
majority that the world considers to be
gurus are in the mid to high
gurus are in the mid to high 500s
um
um over
um over 540
um over 540 as
um over 540 as you
um over 540 as you remember
um over 540 as you remember is
um over 540 as you remember is uh
unconditional
unconditional love.
So
So a
So a true
So a true guru
So a true guru people
So a true guru people say
So a true guru people say what's
So a true guru people say what's a
So a true guru people say what's a true
guru
guru a
So a true guru people say what's a true
guru a true
guru a true guru
So a true guru people say what's a true
guru a true guru we
guru a true guru we and
So a true guru people say what's a true
guru a true guru we and we
guru a true guru we and we asked
kinesiology
kinesiology is
kinesiology is what
kinesiology is what has
kinesiology is what has to
kinesiology is what has to calibrate
over
over 540
kinesiology is what has to calibrate
over 540 unconditional
over 540 unconditional love.
kinesiology is what has to calibrate
over 540 unconditional love. Um
so
so that
so that brings
so that brings us
so that brings us up
so that brings us up to
so that brings us up to 600.
so that brings us up to 600. At
so that brings us up to 600. At 600
so that brings us up to 600. At 600 the
the
the ride
so that brings us up to 600. At 600 the
the ride up
the ride up to
so that brings us up to 600. At 600 the
the ride up to 600
the ride up to 600 is
so that brings us up to 600. At 600 the
the ride up to 600 is hard
the ride up to 600 is hard work
so that brings us up to 600. At 600 the
the ride up to 600 is hard work in
the ride up to 600 is hard work in the
beginning
beginning but
beginning but after
beginning but after a
beginning but after a while
beginning but after a while it
beginning but after a while it becomes
uh
uh in
beginning but after a while it becomes
uh in intensely
uh in intensely inspired
beginning but after a while it becomes
uh in intensely inspired and
uh in intensely inspired and it
beginning but after a while it becomes
uh in intensely inspired and it takes
uh in intensely inspired and it takes on
an
an energy
an energy of
an energy of its
an energy of its own.
an energy of its own. Um
and
and the
an energy of its own. Um
and the movement
and the movement the
an energy of its own. Um
and the movement the spiritual
and the movement the spiritual movement
continues
continues of
continues of its
continues of its own
continues of its own valition
continues of its own valition you
continues of its own valition you might
say.
say. It's
continues of its own valition you might
say. It's like
say. It's like the
continues of its own valition you might
say. It's like the spiritual
say. It's like the spiritual energy
continues of its own valition you might
say. It's like the spiritual energy gets
is
is so
is so strong
is so strong that
is so strong that it
is so strong that it now
is so strong that it now takes
is so strong that it now takes over
is so strong that it now takes over the
whole
whole process.
and
and you
and you become
and you become more
and you become more of
and you become more of a
and you become more of a witness
and you become more of a witness of
and you become more of a witness of it.
And
And at
and you become more of a witness of it.
And at 600
um
um one
um one reaches
um one reaches a
um one reaches a state
um one reaches a state that
um one reaches a state that the
um one reaches a state that the world
calls
calls enlightened
um one reaches a state that the world
calls enlightened in
calls enlightened in which
um
um you
um you may
um you may or
um you may or may
um you may or may not
um you may or may not stay
um you may or may not stay in
um you may or may not stay in the
um you may or may not stay in the world.
Uh
Uh you
um you may or may not stay in the world.
Uh you may
Uh you may or
um you may or may not stay in the world.
Uh you may or may
Uh you may or may not
um you may or may not stay in the world.
Uh you may or may not stay
Uh you may or may not stay in
um you may or may not stay in the world.
Uh you may or may not stay in the
Uh you may or may not stay in the world.
At
At 600
At 600 um
At 600 um everything
At 600 um everything sort
At 600 um everything sort of
At 600 um everything sort of goes
At 600 um everything sort of goes into
At 600 um everything sort of goes into a
state
state of
At 600 um everything sort of goes into a
state of exquisite
state of exquisite bliss
At 600 um everything sort of goes into a
state of exquisite bliss and
state of exquisite bliss and it's
At 600 um everything sort of goes into a
state of exquisite bliss and it's very
difficult
difficult to
difficult to function.
It's
It's uh
difficult to function.
It's uh questionable
It's uh questionable whether
difficult to function.
It's uh questionable whether or
It's uh questionable whether or not
difficult to function.
It's uh questionable whether or not to
even
even breathe.
even breathe. Uh
um
um a
even breathe. Uh
um a number
um a number of
even breathe. Uh
um a number of times
um a number of times breathing
even breathe. Uh
um a number of times breathing only
resumed
resumed because
resumed because somebody
resumed because somebody insisted
resumed because somebody insisted on
resumed because somebody insisted on it.
So
So but
resumed because somebody insisted on it.
So but you
So but you didn't
resumed because somebody insisted on it.
So but you didn't need
So but you didn't need to
resumed because somebody insisted on it.
So but you didn't need to breathe
So but you didn't need to breathe and
that
that state
that state was
that state was perfect.
that state was perfect. The
that state was perfect. The body
disappears
disappears as
that state was perfect. The body
disappears as a
disappears as a reality
that state was perfect. The body
disappears as a reality and
disappears as a reality and there
that state was perfect. The body
disappears as a reality and there is
disappears as a reality and there is no
really
really no
really no reason
really no reason to
really no reason to continue.
However,
However, there's
really no reason to continue.
However, there's probably
However, there's probably a
really no reason to continue.
However, there's probably a karmic
propensity
propensity momentum
propensity momentum that
propensity momentum that carries
propensity momentum that carries one
along.
along. Uh,
propensity momentum that carries one
along. Uh, in
along. Uh, in each
propensity momentum that carries one
along. Uh, in each instant
along. Uh, in each instant that
propensity momentum that carries one
along. Uh, in each instant that that
happened,
happened, it
happened, it was
happened, it was love
happened, it was love that
happened, it was love that uh,
happened, it was love that uh, it
happened, it was love that uh, it got
the
the body
happened, it was love that uh, it got
the body to
the body to breathe
happened, it was love that uh, it got
the body to breathe again.
the body to breathe again. So,
happened, it was love that uh, it got
the body to breathe again. So, love
the body to breathe again. So, love for
someone
someone who
someone who would
someone who would have
someone who would have been
someone who would have been concerned
someone who would have been concerned if
the
the body
someone who would have been concerned if
the body stopped
the body stopped breathing.
someone who would have been concerned if
the body stopped breathing. The
the body stopped breathing. The world
considers
considers that
considers that death
considers that death and
considers that death and goes
considers that death and goes into
greater
greater reaction
considers that death and goes into
greater reaction about
greater reaction about that.
considers that death and goes into
greater reaction about that. So,
somebody
somebody that
somebody that you
somebody that you care
somebody that you care about,
somebody that you care about, you
somebody that you care about, you looked
at
at him,
somebody that you care about, you looked
at him, you
at him, you realize
somebody that you care about, you looked
at him, you realize he
at him, you realize he believes
somebody that you care about, you looked
at him, you realize he believes in
at him, you realize he believes in death
and
and he
and he thinks
and he thinks you're
and he thinks you're going
and he thinks you're going to
and he thinks you're going to be
and he thinks you're going to be he
thinks
thinks you're
and he thinks you're going to be he
thinks you're dead
thinks you're dead and
and he thinks you're going to be he
thinks you're dead and he
thinks you're dead and he will
and he thinks you're going to be he
thinks you're dead and he will now
thinks you're dead and he will now feel
very
very bad
very bad about
very bad about that.
very bad about that. So
very bad about that. So you
very bad about that. So you breathe.
That's
That's the
very bad about that. So you breathe.
That's the only
That's the only reason
very bad about that. So you breathe.
That's the only reason you
That's the only reason you breathe
very bad about that. So you breathe.
That's the only reason you breathe but
because
because you
because you really
because you really don't
because you really don't have
because you really don't have to.
Uh
Uh so
because you really don't have to.
Uh so at
Uh so at that
because you really don't have to.
Uh so at that point
Uh so at that point one
because you really don't have to.
Uh so at that point one has
Uh so at that point one has really
entered
entered the
entered the nonlinear
entered the nonlinear domain.
entered the nonlinear domain. Uh
entered the nonlinear domain. Uh at
entered the nonlinear domain. Uh at um
it's
it's 700.
entered the nonlinear domain. Uh at um
it's 700. We're
it's 700. We're going
entered the nonlinear domain. Uh at um
it's 700. We're going to
it's 700. We're going to recalibrate.
We're
We're going
We're going to
We're going to do
We're going to do redo
We're going to do redo a
We're going to do redo a few
We're going to do redo a few things
today.
today. Uh
We're going to do redo a few things
today. Uh we
today. Uh we don't
We're going to do redo a few things
today. Uh we don't have
today. Uh we don't have anything
We're going to do redo a few things
today. Uh we don't have anything from
700 to
700 to a,000.
700 to a,000. Uh
700 to a,000. Uh except
700 to a,000. Uh except it
700 to a,000. Uh except it just
700 to a,000. Uh except it just says
enlightenment.
enlightenment. Actually
700 to a,000. Uh except it just says
enlightenment. Actually enlightenment
starts
starts at
starts at 600
starts at 600 and
starts at 600 and then
starts at 600 and then at
starts at 600 and then at 700
starts at 600 and then at 700 uh
starts at 600 and then at 700 uh the
reality
reality of
starts at 600 and then at 700 uh the
reality of the
reality of the self
starts at 600 and then at 700 uh the
reality of the self with
reality of the self with a
starts at 600 and then at 700 uh the
reality of the self with a capital
reality of the self with a capital S
starts at 600 and then at 700 uh the
reality of the self with a capital S is
all
all that
all that is
all that is those
all that is those are
all that is those are the
all that is those are the levels
all that is those are the levels of
Ramana
Ramana Maharshi
all that is those are the levels of
Ramana Maharshi Nisser
Ramana Maharshi Nisser Gada
all that is those are the levels of
Ramana Maharshi Nisser Gada Maharaj
uh
uh uh
uh uh Swami's
uh uh Swami's number
uh uh Swami's number of
uh uh Swami's number of them
uh uh Swami's number of them uh
uh uh Swami's number of them uh 800
uh uh Swami's number of them uh 800 is
quite
quite a
uh uh Swami's number of them uh 800 is
quite a high higher
quite a high higher level
uh uh Swami's number of them uh 800 is
quite a high higher level and
quite a high higher level and up
uh uh Swami's number of them uh 800 is
quite a high higher level and up to
quite a high higher level and up to 600
is
is blissful
maybe
maybe even
is blissful
maybe even close
maybe even close to
is blissful
maybe even close to 700
maybe even close to 700 but
is blissful
maybe even close to 700 but beyond
maybe even close to 700 but beyond that
if
if the
if the the
if the the trip
if the the trip the
if the the trip the trip
if the the trip the trip at least
if the the trip the trip at least in
this
this case
if the the trip the trip at least in
this case was
this case was extremely
if the the trip the trip at least in
this case was extremely painful.
The
The slightest
The slightest thing
The slightest thing that's
The slightest thing that's out
The slightest thing that's out brings
The slightest thing that's out brings a
racking
racking pain
The slightest thing that's out brings a
racking pain through
racking pain through the
The slightest thing that's out brings a
racking pain through the whole
racking pain through the whole nervous
system
system and
system and it
system and it was
system and it was horrific
system and it was horrific at
system and it was horrific at times
system and it was horrific at times and
um
um by
system and it was horrific at times and
um by meditation
um by meditation and
system and it was horrific at times and
um by meditation and prayer
um by meditation and prayer one
system and it was horrific at times and
um by meditation and prayer one gets
what
what what
what what the
what what the paradox
what what the paradox is
what what the paradox is that's
what what the paradox is that's blocking
you.
you. So
what what the paradox is that's blocking
you. So you
you. So you learn
what what the paradox is that's blocking
you. So you learn that
you. So you learn that what
what what the paradox is that's blocking
you. So you learn that what the
you. So you learn that what the world
considers
considers to
considers to be
considers to be the
considers to be the state
considers to be the state uh
considers to be the state uh is
considers to be the state uh is one
considers to be the state uh is one of
considers to be the state uh is one of a
series
series of
considers to be the state uh is one of a
series of states.
Although
Although it's
Although it's true
Although it's true enlightenment
Although it's true enlightenment is
Although it's true enlightenment is at
600 when
600 when most
Although it's true enlightenment is at
600 when most people
600 when most people at
Although it's true enlightenment is at
600 when most people at 600
600 when most people at 600 don't
Although it's true enlightenment is at
600 when most people at 600 don't move
any
any further
any further half
any further half of
any further half of them
any further half of them leave
any further half of them leave the
any further half of them leave the world
and
and don't
any further half of them leave the world
and don't return
uh
uh go
uh go into
uh go into retirement
uh go into retirement uh
uh go into retirement uh withdraw
uh go into retirement uh withdraw from
the
the world
uh go into retirement uh withdraw from
the world or
the world or I
uh go into retirement uh withdraw from
the world or I suppose
the world or I suppose they
uh go into retirement uh withdraw from
the world or I suppose they just
the world or I suppose they just there
was
was nobody
was nobody around
was nobody around to
was nobody around to cajol
was nobody around to cajol them
was nobody around to cajol them into
breathing
breathing so
was nobody around to cajol them into
breathing so they
breathing so they didn't
uh
seldom
seldom do
uh
seldom do they
seldom do they move
uh
seldom do they move beyond
seldom do they move beyond that
uh
seldom do they move beyond that um
seldom do they move beyond that um uh
uh
seldom do they move beyond that um uh uh
first
first of
first of all
first of all the
first of all the state
first of all the state is
first of all the state is so
first of all the state is so complete
and
and total
first of all the state is so complete
and total and
and total and satisfying
first of all the state is so complete
and total and satisfying that
and total and satisfying that it
first of all the state is so complete
and total and satisfying that it would
Not
Not there
Not there would
Not there would be
Not there would be no
Not there would be no thought
Not there would be no thought to
Not there would be no thought to move
beyond.
beyond. There
Not there would be no thought to move
beyond. There is
beyond. There is no
Not there would be no thought to move
beyond. There is no beyond.
beyond. There is no beyond. You
Not there would be no thought to move
beyond. There is no beyond. You are
already
already at
already at the
already at the ultimate
already at the ultimate state.
already at the ultimate state. 600
already at the ultimate state. 600 is
already at the ultimate state. 600 is al
already
already an
already at the ultimate state. 600 is al
already an ultimate
already an ultimate state.
already at the ultimate state. 600 is al
already an ultimate state. So
already an ultimate state. So there's
nowhere
nowhere to
nowhere to move
nowhere to move beyond
nowhere to move beyond nor
nowhere to move beyond nor is
nowhere to move beyond nor is there
nowhere to move beyond nor is there any
reason
reason to
nowhere to move beyond nor is there any
reason to do
reason to do so.
Once
Once in
Once in a
Once in a great
Once in a great while
Once in a great while peculiarly
uh
uh that
Once in a great while peculiarly
uh that state
uh that state will
Once in a great while peculiarly
uh that state will begin
uh that state will begin to
Once in a great while peculiarly
uh that state will begin to move
uh that state will begin to move of
Once in a great while peculiarly
uh that state will begin to move of its
own.
own. that
own. that uh
own. that uh inner
um
um what
own. that uh inner
um what would
um what would you
own. that uh inner
um what would you call
um what would you call it?
own. that uh inner
um what would you call it? Drive
um what would you call it? Drive of
own. that uh inner
um what would you call it? Drive of the
self
self within
uh
an
an aspect
an aspect of
an aspect of consciousness
an aspect of consciousness itself
uh
uh presents
an aspect of consciousness itself
uh presents a
uh presents a paradox
because
because 600
because 600 isn't
because 600 isn't the
because 600 isn't the solution
because 600 isn't the solution of
because 600 isn't the solution of every
paradox
paradox that's
because 600 isn't the solution of every
paradox that's possible.
Um
Um and
Um and a
Um and a paradox
Um and a paradox will
Um and a paradox will appear
Um and a paradox will appear and
Um and a paradox will appear and with
Um and a paradox will appear and with it
this
this racking
Um and a paradox will appear and with it
this racking physical
this racking physical pain.
uh
uh one
uh one then
uh one then intuitits
uh one then intuitits what
uh one then intuitits what the
uh one then intuitits what the paradox
is
is or
uh one then intuitits what the paradox
is or it
is or it just
uh one then intuitits what the paradox
is or it just comes
is or it just comes to
uh one then intuitits what the paradox
is or it just comes to you
is or it just comes to you as
uh one then intuitits what the paradox
is or it just comes to you as you're
driving
driving along
and
and these
driving along
and these are
and these are dualities
driving along
and these are dualities uh
and these are dualities uh which
driving along
and these are dualities uh which are
extremely
extremely abstract
extremely abstract and
extremely abstract and which
extremely abstract and which are
extremely abstract and which are not
really
really worth
extremely abstract and which are not
really worth bothering
really worth bothering bothering
extremely abstract and which are not
really worth bothering bothering with
for
for the
for the average
for the average person.
Those
Those of
for the average person.
Those of you
Those of you know
for the average person.
Those of you know know
Those of you know know my
for the average person.
Those of you know know my personal
Those of you know know my personal story
know
know that
which
which I
know that
which I recounted
which I recounted in
know that
which I recounted in the
which I recounted in the back
know that
which I recounted in the back of
which I recounted in the back of power
versus
versus force
uh
uh and
versus force
uh and I
uh and I think
versus force
uh and I think in
uh and I think in the
versus force
uh and I think in the beginning
uh and I think in the beginning of
versus force
uh and I think in the beginning of ID
the
the eye
the eye um
the eye um this
the eye um this particular
the eye um this particular sojurnn
spiritual
spiritual sojurn
the eye um this particular sojurnn
spiritual sojurn standing
spiritual sojurn standing here
the eye um this particular sojurnn
spiritual sojurn standing here talking
to
to you
to you began
to you began at
to you began at age
to you began at age three
to you began at age three went
to you began at age three went out
to you began at age three went out as
complete
complete nothingness
to you began at age three went out as
complete nothingness suddenly
there
there was
there was a
there was a shocking
there was a shocking awareness
there was a shocking awareness of
existence
not
not pleasing
not pleasing either
suddenly
suddenly where
not pleasing either
suddenly where there
suddenly where there was
not pleasing either
suddenly where there was a
suddenly where there was a shock
shocking
shocking awareness
shocking awareness of
shocking awareness of existence
had
had returned
shocking awareness of existence
had returned into
had returned into actual
shocking awareness of existence
had returned into actual existence.
Uh
Uh the
Uh the paradox
Uh the paradox then
Uh the paradox then that
Uh the paradox then that arose
Uh the paradox then that arose at
Uh the paradox then that arose at age
three
three there
Uh the paradox then that arose at age
three there was
three there was no
Uh the paradox then that arose at age
three there was no mentation
three there was no mentation but
Uh the paradox then that arose at age
three there was no mentation but there
was
was a
was a complete
was a complete and
was a complete and total
was a complete and total understanding
of
of the
was a complete and total understanding
of the paradox.
There
There came
There came the
There came the fear
There came the fear of
There came the fear of non-existence
to
to exist
There came the fear of non-existence
to exist brings
to exist brings up
There came the fear of non-existence
to exist brings up its
to exist brings up its polar
There came the fear of non-existence
to exist brings up its polar opposite
to exist brings up its polar opposite of
non-existence
non-existence and
non-existence and the
non-existence and the fear
non-existence and the fear came
non-existence and the fear came up.
non-existence and the fear came up. If
non-existence and the fear came up. If I
had
had come
non-existence and the fear came up. If I
had come into
had come into existence
non-existence and the fear came up. If I
had come into existence then
had come into existence then it
non-existence and the fear came up. If I
had come into existence then it might
have
have been
have been that
have been that I
have been that I would
have been that I would not
have been that I would not have
have been that I would not have come
into
into existence.
have been that I would not have come
into existence. So
into existence. So the
have been that I would not have come
into existence. So the paradox
into existence. So the paradox to
have been that I would not have come
into existence. So the paradox to be
solved
solved in
solved in this
solved in this lifetime
solved in this lifetime which
solved in this lifetime which only
solved in this lifetime which only took
another
another 50
solved in this lifetime which only took
another 50 years
another 50 years to
solved in this lifetime which only took
another 50 years to solve
another 50 years to solve or
solved in this lifetime which only took
another 50 years to solve or something
uh
uh or
uh or 60
uh or 60 years
uh or 60 years whatever
uh or 60 years whatever uh
uh or 60 years whatever uh was
uh or 60 years whatever uh was existence
versus
versus non-existence.
That
That paradox
That paradox to
That paradox to solve
That paradox to solve that
That paradox to solve that paradox
That paradox to solve that paradox takes
you
you beyond
That paradox to solve that paradox takes
you beyond what
you beyond what let's
That paradox to solve that paradox takes
you beyond what let's see
you beyond what let's see what
That paradox to solve that paradox takes
you beyond what let's see what what
existence
existence versus
existence versus non-existence
existence versus non-existence is.
Existence
Existence versus
existence versus non-existence is.
Existence versus non-existence
Existence versus non-existence comes
existence versus non-existence is.
Existence versus non-existence comes up
uh
uh as
uh as a
uh as a blockade
uh as a blockade at
uh as a blockade at 800,
uh as a blockade at 800, 810,
uh as a blockade at 800, 810, 840,
8:30,
8:30, 8:35.
uh as a blockade at 800, 810, 840,
8:30, 8:35. It
8:30, 8:35. It comes
uh as a blockade at 800, 810, 840,
8:30, 8:35. It comes up
8:30, 8:35. It comes up at
uh as a blockade at 800, 810, 840,
8:30, 8:35. It comes up at 8:35.
8:30, 8:35. It comes up at 8:35. So
uh as a blockade at 800, 810, 840,
8:30, 8:35. It comes up at 8:35. So a
conscious
conscious level
conscious level 835
comes
comes up
conscious level 835
comes up this
comes up this in
conscious level 835
comes up this in incredible
comes up this in incredible pain.
conscious level 835
comes up this in incredible pain. And
that
that paradox
that paradox of
that paradox of existence
that paradox of existence versus
non-existence,
non-existence, it's
that paradox of existence versus
non-existence, it's really
the
the question
the question is
the question is really
the question is really is
the question is really is there
the question is really is there an
opposite
opposite to
the question is really is there an
opposite to God?
opposite to God? And
the question is really is there an
opposite to God? And the
opposite to God? And the answer
the question is really is there an
opposite to God? And the answer is
opposite to God? And the answer is no.
Is
Is there
Is there an
Is there an opposite
Is there an opposite to
Is there an opposite to existence?
Is there an opposite to existence? No.
So
So it's
Is there an opposite to existence? No.
So it's a
So it's a very
Is there an opposite to existence? No.
So it's a very high
So it's a very high paradox.
Is there an opposite to existence? No.
So it's a very high paradox. But
So it's a very high paradox. But you
don't
don't have
don't have to
don't have to worry
don't have to worry about
don't have to worry about it
don't have to worry about it until
don't have to worry about it until then.
That's
That's the
don't have to worry about it until then.
That's the good
That's the good news.
don't have to worry about it until then.
That's the good news. But
That's the good news. But um
don't have to worry about it until then.
That's the good news. But um the
That's the good news. But um the bad
news
news is
news is if
news is if you
news is if you have
news is if you have the
uh
uh karmic
news is if you have the
uh karmic uh
uh karmic uh momentum
news is if you have the
uh karmic uh momentum to
uh karmic uh momentum to continue
news is if you have the
uh karmic uh momentum to continue on
after
after having
after having reached
after having reached such
after having reached such a
after having reached such a blissful
state,
state, you
after having reached such a blissful
state, you go
state, you go through
after having reached such a blissful
state, you go through some
state, you go through some agonizing
states.
states. We
states. We were
states. We were in
states. We were in Korea
states. We were in Korea and
states. We were in Korea and uh
states. We were in Korea and uh I
states. We were in Korea and uh I was
states. We were in Korea and uh I was in
such
such an
states. We were in Korea and uh I was in
such an agonizing
such an agonizing state.
states. We were in Korea and uh I was in
such an agonizing state. I
such an agonizing state. I forget
states. We were in Korea and uh I was in
such an agonizing state. I forget what
that
that polarity
that polarity was.
that polarity was. U
you
you see
that polarity was. U
you see consciousness
you see consciousness is
that polarity was. U
you see consciousness is is
you see consciousness is is blocked
that polarity was. U
you see consciousness is is blocked all
the
the time
the time by
the time by a
the time by a positionality
the time by a positionality which
the time by a positionality which we'll
get
get into.
the time by a positionality which we'll
get into. Positionality
get into. Positionality creates
the time by a positionality which we'll
get into. Positionality creates a
duality.
duality. Well,
duality. Well, there's
duality. Well, there's dualities
duality. Well, there's dualities within
the
the ordinary
duality. Well, there's dualities within
the ordinary domain,
the ordinary domain, love
duality. Well, there's dualities within
the ordinary domain, love and
the ordinary domain, love and hate
duality. Well, there's dualities within
the ordinary domain, love and hate and
all
all that
all that which
all that which everybody's
all that which everybody's familiar
with.
with. But
all that which everybody's familiar
with. But there
with. But there are
all that which everybody's familiar
with. But there are paradoxical
seeming
seeming dualities
at
at much
seeming dualities
at much higher
at much higher levels.
seeming dualities
at much higher levels. But
at much higher levels. But you
seeming dualities
at much higher levels. But you don't
have
have to
have to really
have to really bother
have to really bother with
have to really bother with them
have to really bother with them until
you
you get
have to really bother with them until
you get there.
So
So anyway,
So anyway, I
So anyway, I was
So anyway, I was racked
So anyway, I was racked with
So anyway, I was racked with pain
So anyway, I was racked with pain and
So anyway, I was racked with pain and uh
I
I was
So anyway, I was racked with pain and uh
I was intuiting
I was intuiting what
So anyway, I was racked with pain and uh
I was intuiting what it
I was intuiting what it was
So anyway, I was racked with pain and uh
I was intuiting what it was and
I was intuiting what it was and sort
So anyway, I was racked with pain and uh
I was intuiting what it was and sort of
meditating
meditating and
meditating and then
meditating and then suddenly
meditating and then suddenly I
meditating and then suddenly I sort
meditating and then suddenly I sort of
saw
saw it.
meditating and then suddenly I sort of
saw it. And
saw it. And but
meditating and then suddenly I sort of
saw it. And but anyway,
saw it. And but anyway, it
meditating and then suddenly I sort of
saw it. And but anyway, it was
saw it. And but anyway, it was extremely
painful.
painful. It's
painful. It's like
painful. It's like it's
painful. It's like it's like
painful. It's like it's like your
painful. It's like it's like your whole
body's
body's on
painful. It's like it's like your whole
body's on fire.
body's on fire. It's
painful. It's like it's like your whole
body's on fire. It's like
body's on fire. It's like your
painful. It's like it's like your whole
body's on fire. It's like your nervous
system
system is
system is made
system is made up
system is made up of
system is made up of barbed
system is made up of barbed wire
system is made up of barbed wire and
system is made up of barbed wire and the
barbed
barbed wire
system is made up of barbed wire and the
barbed wire has
barbed wire has now
system is made up of barbed wire and the
barbed wire has now has
barbed wire has now has electricity
running
running through
running through it
running through it and
running through it and it's
running through it and it's a
running through it and it's a racked
pain.
pain. It's
running through it and it's a racked
pain. It's really
pain. It's really within
running through it and it's a racked
pain. It's really within the
pain. It's really within the whole
running through it and it's a racked
pain. It's really within the whole aura.
You
You can't
You can't get
You can't get away
You can't get away from
You can't get away from it
You can't get away from it because
You can't get away from it because it's
the
the aura
You can't get away from it because it's
the aura that
the aura that does
You can't get away from it because it's
the aura that does that.
the aura that does that. So
You can't get away from it because it's
the aura that does that. So this
the aura that does that. So this demand,
in
in other
in other words,
in other words, it
in other words, it demands
in other words, it demands attention.
So
So uh
I
I was
I was questioning
I was questioning why
I was questioning why that
I was questioning why that is
I was questioning why that is or
something.
something. And
I was questioning why that is or
something. And uh
something. And uh Susan
I was questioning why that is or
something. And uh Susan uh
something. And uh Susan uh was
I was questioning why that is or
something. And uh Susan uh was reading
something
something out
something out of
something out of there
something out of there was
something out of there was a
something out of there was a Buddhist
something out of there was a Buddhist uh
Bible
Bible in
something out of there was a Buddhist uh
Bible in Korea
Bible in Korea in
something out of there was a Buddhist uh
Bible in Korea in in
Bible in Korea in in in
something out of there was a Buddhist uh
Bible in Korea in in in a
Bible in Korea in in in a hotel
something out of there was a Buddhist uh
Bible in Korea in in in a hotel room.
There
There isn't
There isn't a
There isn't a Bible
There isn't a Bible there.
There isn't a Bible there. Well,
There isn't a Bible there. Well, they
they
they do
There isn't a Bible there. Well, they
they do have
they do have a
There isn't a Bible there. Well, they
they do have a Bible,
they do have a Bible, but
There isn't a Bible there. Well, they
they do have a Bible, but there's
they do have a Bible, but there's also
There isn't a Bible there. Well, they
they do have a Bible, but there's also a
Buddhist
Buddhist Bible
Buddhist Bible sort
Buddhist Bible sort of
Buddhist Bible sort of thing.
Buddhist Bible sort of thing. So
Buddhist Bible sort of thing. So uh
Buddhist Bible sort of thing. So uh in
it
it she
Buddhist Bible sort of thing. So uh in
it she was
it she was reading
Buddhist Bible sort of thing. So uh in
it she was reading that
it she was reading that the
Buddhist Bible sort of thing. So uh in
it she was reading that the Buddha
it she was reading that the Buddha was
racked
racked with
racked with pain
racked with pain as
racked with pain as though
racked with pain as though his
racked with pain as though his bones
were
were broken
racked with pain as though his bones
were broken and
were broken and he
racked with pain as though his bones
were broken and he was
were broken and he was attacked
racked with pain as though his bones
were broken and he was attacked by
demons.
demons. And
demons. And she
demons. And she read
demons. And she read that
demons. And she read that to
demons. And she read that to me
demons. And she read that to me and
demons. And she read that to me and inly
I
I felt
demons. And she read that to me and inly
I felt better.
It's
It's okay
It's okay to
It's okay to be
It's okay to be wrecked
It's okay to be wrecked by
It's okay to be wrecked by demons
It's okay to be wrecked by demons and
It's okay to be wrecked by demons and uh
feel
feel like
It's okay to be wrecked by demons and uh
feel like all
feel like all your
It's okay to be wrecked by demons and uh
feel like all your bones
feel like all your bones are
It's okay to be wrecked by demons and uh
feel like all your bones are broken.
feel like all your bones are broken. So
those
those are
those are just
those are just adventure
those are just adventure stories
those are just adventure stories neither
here
here nor
those are just adventure stories neither
here nor there.
What
What I
What I was
What I was really
What I was really driving
What I was really driving at
What I was really driving at is
out
out of
What I was really driving at is
out of power
out of power versus
What I was really driving at is
out of power versus force,
out of power versus force, there
What I was really driving at is
out of power versus force, there seemed
to
to arise,
to arise, and
to arise, and it
to arise, and it bothered
to arise, and it bothered me
to arise, and it bothered me at
to arise, and it bothered me at the
time,
time, a
to arise, and it bothered me at the
time, a seeming
time, a seeming duality,
to arise, and it bothered me at the
time, a seeming duality, or
time, a seeming duality, or at least
to arise, and it bothered me at the
time, a seeming duality, or at least one
could
could draw
could draw sort
could draw sort of
could draw sort of a
could draw sort of a political
could draw sort of a political uh
position
position about
could draw sort of a political uh
position about it.
position about it. Um,
could draw sort of a political uh
position about it. Um, above
position about it. Um, above 200
could draw sort of a political uh
position about it. Um, above 200 is
position about it. Um, above 200 is that
which
which is
which is pro-life,
which is pro-life, supports
which is pro-life, supports life,
which is pro-life, supports life, and
that
that which
which is pro-life, supports life, and
that which is
that which is true.
which is pro-life, supports life, and
that which is true. Below
that which is true. Below 200
which is pro-life, supports life, and
that which is true. Below 200 is
that which is true. Below 200 is that
which
which is
which is not
which is not true,
which is not true, does
which is not true, does not
which is not true, does not support
life.
life. Everything
which is not true, does not support
life. Everything that
life. Everything that is
which is not true, does not support
life. Everything that is venomous,
hateful,
hateful, selfish,
hateful, selfish, greedy,
hateful, selfish, greedy, destructive
hateful, selfish, greedy, destructive to
others,
it
it that
it that seemed
it that seemed to
it that seemed to create
it that seemed to create a
it that seemed to create a certain
polarity.
polarity. So
it that seemed to create a certain
polarity. So here
polarity. So here is
it that seemed to create a certain
polarity. So here is a
polarity. So here is a work
it that seemed to create a certain
polarity. So here is a work devoted
polarity. So here is a work devoted to
transcending
transcending polarities.
transcending polarities. And
transcending polarities. And the
transcending polarities. And the work
itself
itself seems
transcending polarities. And the work
itself seems to
itself seems to be
transcending polarities. And the work
itself seems to be bringing
itself seems to be bringing up
transcending polarities. And the work
itself seems to be bringing up a
polarity.
Uh
Uh you
polarity.
Uh you know,
Uh you know, similar
polarity.
Uh you know, similar to
Uh you know, similar to good
polarity.
Uh you know, similar to good and
Uh you know, similar to good and evil,
there's
there's above
there's above 200
there's above 200 and
there's above 200 and below
there's above 200 and below 200.
there's above 200 and below 200. And
below
below 200,
there's above 200 and below 200. And
below 200, keep
below 200, keep away
there's above 200 and below 200. And
below 200, keep away from.
below 200, keep away from. Don't
there's above 200 and below 200. And
below 200, keep away from. Don't go
below 200, keep away from. Don't go out
and
and play
and play with
and play with those
and play with those kids
and play with those kids that
and play with those kids that are
and play with those kids that are below
200,
200, Jimmy.
They
They have
They have wicked
They have wicked greedy
They have wicked greedy thoughts
They have wicked greedy thoughts and
They have wicked greedy thoughts and uh
and
and are
They have wicked greedy thoughts and uh
and are out
and are out to
They have wicked greedy thoughts and uh
and are out to drag
and are out to drag you
They have wicked greedy thoughts and uh
and are out to drag you down
and are out to drag you down into
They have wicked greedy thoughts and uh
and are out to drag you down into a
street
street gang
street gang and
street gang and get
street gang and get you
street gang and get you tattooed
street gang and get you tattooed and
drugged
drugged up
street gang and get you tattooed and
drugged up and
drugged up and hooked
street gang and get you tattooed and
drugged up and hooked on
drugged up and hooked on heroin
street gang and get you tattooed and
drugged up and hooked on heroin or
something
something and
something and uh
something and uh and
something and uh and they
something and uh and they lure
something and uh and they lure you
something and uh and they lure you into
crime
crime or
something and uh and they lure you into
crime or evil
crime or evil or
something and uh and they lure you into
crime or evil or something.
crime or evil or something. So
something and uh and they lure you into
crime or evil or something. So uh
crime or evil or something. So uh it
seemed
seemed to
seemed to create
seemed to create that
seemed to create that and
seemed to create that and that
seemed to create that and that bothered
me
me and
seemed to create that and that bothered
me and yet
me and yet we
seemed to create that and that bothered
me and yet we went
me and yet we went back
seemed to create that and that bothered
me and yet we went back over
me and yet we went back over it
seemed to create that and that bothered
me and yet we went back over it and
me and yet we went back over it and over
again
again and
again and of
again and of course
again and of course those
again and of course those of
again and of course those of you
again and of course those of you who
again and of course those of you who are
familiar
familiar with
again and of course those of you who are
familiar with the
familiar with the work
again and of course those of you who are
familiar with the work of
familiar with the work of Dinesiology
yourself
yourself know
yourself know it
yourself know it is
yourself know it is it
yourself know it is it is
yourself know it is it is extremely
definite.
definite. There
yourself know it is it is extremely
definite. There is
definite. There is nothing
yourself know it is it is extremely
definite. There is nothing imaginary.
If
If if
If if science
If if science wants
If if science wants evidence-based
If if science wants evidence-based um
work,
work, kinesiology
If if science wants evidence-based um
work, kinesiology is
work, kinesiology is truly
evidence-based.
evidence-based. Your
evidence-based. Your arm
evidence-based. Your arm either
evidence-based. Your arm either goes
strong
strong or
evidence-based. Your arm either goes
strong or goes
strong or goes weak.
evidence-based. Your arm either goes
strong or goes weak. And
strong or goes weak. And there's
evidence-based. Your arm either goes
strong or goes weak. And there's no
strong or goes weak. And there's no if
and
and or
and or but
and or but about
and or but about it.
and or but about it. And
and or but about it. And it
and or but about it. And it always
and or but about it. And it always gives
you
you the
and or but about it. And it always gives
you the same
you the same answer.
And
And then
And then it
And then it sort
And then it sort of
And then it sort of dawned
And then it sort of dawned on
And then it sort of dawned on me
And then it sort of dawned on me uh
And then it sort of dawned on me uh sort
of
of dawned
And then it sort of dawned on me uh sort
of dawned on
of dawned on me
And then it sort of dawned on me uh sort
of dawned on me that
of dawned on me that that
And then it sort of dawned on me uh sort
of dawned on me that that that
of dawned on me that that that first
And then it sort of dawned on me uh sort
of dawned on me that that that first of
all
all this
all this scale
all this scale is
all this scale is drawn
all this scale is drawn a
all this scale is drawn a little
incorrectly.
incorrectly. And
all this scale is drawn a little
incorrectly. And I
incorrectly. And I want
all this scale is drawn a little
incorrectly. And I want to
incorrectly. And I want to redraw
all this scale is drawn a little
incorrectly. And I want to redraw it
today.
today. So
uh
uh the
today. So
uh the other
uh the other thing
today. So
uh the other thing is
uh the other thing is that
today. So
uh the other thing is that it's
uh the other thing is that it's not
really
really two
really two different
really two different worlds.
really two different worlds. What
really two different worlds. What what
happens
happens is
really two different worlds. What what
happens is this.
Near
Near the
Near the top
Near the top of
Near the top of the
Near the top of the scale
Near the top of the scale at
Near the top of the scale at 1,00
Near the top of the scale at 1,00 you
have
have the
Near the top of the scale at 1,00 you
have the great
have the great avatars.
Near the top of the scale at 1,00 you
have the great avatars. So
there's
there's the
there's the universal
there's the universal presence.
there's the universal presence. There's
the
the unmanifest
which
which becomes
which becomes manifest
which becomes manifest as
which becomes manifest as creation.
Creation
Creation is
which becomes manifest as creation.
Creation is continuous.
Consciousness
Consciousness as
Consciousness as it
Consciousness as it interacts
Consciousness as it interacts with
matter.
evolves
evolves as
evolves as life
evolves as life and
evolves as life and then
evolves as life and then life
evolves as life and then life evolves
evolves as life and then life evolves up
into
into higher
evolves as life and then life evolves up
into higher and
into higher and higher
evolves as life and then life evolves up
into higher and higher capacities
through
through evolution.
Therefore,
Therefore, creation
through evolution.
Therefore, creation and
Therefore, creation and evolution
through evolution.
Therefore, creation and evolution are
one
one in
one in the
one in the same
one in the same thing.
one in the same thing. What
one in the same thing. What science
calls
calls evolution
one in the same thing. What science
calls evolution is
calls evolution is nothing
one in the same thing. What science
calls evolution is nothing but
calls evolution is nothing but the
unfolding
unfolding of
unfolding of creation.
unfolding of creation. As
unfolding of creation. As creation
unfolds,
unfolds, sequentially
unfolding of creation. As creation
unfolds, sequentially perception
unfolds, sequentially perception thinks
it
it sees
it sees something
it sees something happening.
it sees something happening. It's
it sees something happening. It's only
the
the unfolding
it sees something happening. It's only
the unfolding of
the unfolding of evolution.
So
So evolution
So evolution is
So evolution is nothing
So evolution is nothing but
So evolution is nothing but a
demonstration
demonstration of
So evolution is nothing but a
demonstration of the
demonstration of the fact
So evolution is nothing but a
demonstration of the fact that
demonstration of the fact that creation
is
is continuous
which
which gets
is continuous
which gets us
which gets us away
is continuous
which gets us away from
which gets us away from the
is continuous
which gets us away from the view
which gets us away from the view of
is continuous
which gets us away from the view of that
God
God was
God was uh
God was uh God
God was uh God was
God was uh God was around
God was uh God was around at
God was uh God was around at the
God was uh God was around at the time
God was uh God was around at the time of
Genesis.
He
He um
He um created
He um created uh
He um created uh the
He um created uh the world
He um created uh the world and
He um created uh the world and took
He um created uh the world and took off
and
and you
He um created uh the world and took off
and you don't
and you don't see
He um created uh the world and took off
and you don't see him
and you don't see him again
He um created uh the world and took off
and you don't see him again till
and you don't see him again till you
He um created uh the world and took off
and you don't see him again till you get
to
to heaven.
So
So God
to heaven.
So God is
So God is elsewhere
to heaven.
So God is elsewhere in
So God is elsewhere in time,
to heaven.
So God is elsewhere in time, way
So God is elsewhere in time, way back
to heaven.
So God is elsewhere in time, way back in
their
their early
their early early
their early early beginnings,
prehistoric,
prehistoric, and
their early early beginnings,
prehistoric, and you're
prehistoric, and you're not
their early early beginnings,
prehistoric, and you're not going
prehistoric, and you're not going to
their early early beginnings,
prehistoric, and you're not going to see
him
him unless
him unless you've
him unless you've been
him unless you've been very,
him unless you've been very, very
him unless you've been very, very good,
and
and you
him unless you've been very, very good,
and you go
and you go to
him unless you've been very, very good,
and you go to a
and you go to a heavenly
him unless you've been very, very good,
and you go to a heavenly place
and you go to a heavenly place where
him unless you've been very, very good,
and you go to a heavenly place where he
sits
sits waiting
sits waiting in
sits waiting in judgment.
sits waiting in judgment. Oh
sits waiting in judgment. Oh my
sits waiting in judgment. Oh my god,
what
what a
sits waiting in judgment. Oh my god,
what a scary
what a scary paradigm
sits waiting in judgment. Oh my god,
what a scary paradigm of
what a scary paradigm of reality.
sits waiting in judgment. Oh my god,
what a scary paradigm of reality. In
what a scary paradigm of reality. In the
meantime,
meantime, you're
meantime, you're on
meantime, you're on your
meantime, you're on your own,
meantime, you're on your own, folks.
meantime, you're on your own, folks. And
um
um once
meantime, you're on your own, folks. And
um once in
um once in a
meantime, you're on your own, folks. And
um once in a while
um once in a while he
meantime, you're on your own, folks. And
um once in a while he says
um once in a while he says strange
things
things to
things to people
things to people who
things to people who sometimes
things to people who sometimes get
things to people who sometimes get put
in
in mental
things to people who sometimes get put
in mental hospitals
in mental hospitals for
things to people who sometimes get put
in mental hospitals for what
in mental hospitals for what he
things to people who sometimes get put
in mental hospitals for what he says
or
or he
or he speaks
or he speaks through
or he speaks through prophets
or he speaks through prophets and
various
various bizarre
or he speaks through prophets and
various bizarre pronounce
pronouncements.
pronouncements. So
pronouncements. So it's
pronouncements. So it's a
pronouncements. So it's a strange
pronouncements. So it's a strange world.
Um
and
and of
and of course
and of course it
and of course it it
and of course it it explains
and of course it it explains why
and of course it it explains why a
and of course it it explains why a lot
of
of people
and of course it it explains why a lot
of people never
of people never find
and of course it it explains why a lot
of people never find God.
of people never find God. Uh
and of course it it explains why a lot
of people never find God. Uh if
of people never find God. Uh if he
and of course it it explains why a lot
of people never find God. Uh if he was
in
in prehistoric
in prehistoric times
in prehistoric times and
in prehistoric times and doesn't
in prehistoric times and doesn't exist
until
until you
in prehistoric times and doesn't exist
until you get
until you get to
in prehistoric times and doesn't exist
until you get to heaven,
until you get to heaven, you're
in prehistoric times and doesn't exist
until you get to heaven, you're pretty
much
much on
much on your
much on your own.
Uh
Uh but
much on your own.
Uh but the
Uh but the reality
much on your own.
Uh but the reality of
Uh but the reality of it
much on your own.
Uh but the reality of it is
Uh but the reality of it is um
that
that that
that that which
that that which shines
that that which shines forth
that that which shines forth uh
that that which shines forth uh as
divinity
is
is the
is the pure
is the pure essence
is the pure essence out
is the pure essence out of
is the pure essence out of which
is the pure essence out of which arises
love.
love. And
is the pure essence out of which arises
love. And this
love. And this love
is the pure essence out of which arises
love. And this love then
love. And this love then does
is the pure essence out of which arises
love. And this love then does radiate
down
down throughout
down throughout creation
much
much like
down throughout creation
much like the
much like the proverbial
down throughout creation
much like the proverbial step
much like the proverbial step down
transformers.
And
And if
transformers.
And if you
And if you calibrate
transformers.
And if you calibrate the
And if you calibrate the level
transformers.
And if you calibrate the level of
And if you calibrate the level of an
archangel,
let's
let's just
archangel,
let's just do
let's just do it
archangel,
let's just do it for
let's just do it for the
archangel,
let's just do it for the fun.
let's just do it for the fun. Uh
archangel,
let's just do it for the fun. Uh an
archangel, we
archangel, we have
archangel, we have permission.
archangel, we have permission. Resist.
Uh
Uh runs
archangel, we have permission. Resist.
Uh runs 500,000
Uh runs 500,000 and
archangel, we have permission. Resist.
Uh runs 500,000 and over
Uh runs 500,000 and over resist.
archangel, we have permission. Resist.
Uh runs 500,000 and over resist. Okay.
Now,
Now, this
Now, this is
Now, this is a
Now, this is a logarithmic
Now, this is a logarithmic scale,
Now, this is a logarithmic scale, folks.
And
And every
Now, this is a logarithmic scale, folks.
And every step
And every step as
Now, this is a logarithmic scale, folks.
And every step as you
And every step as you get
Now, this is a logarithmic scale, folks.
And every step as you get higher
And every step as you get higher and
higher
higher is
higher is an
higher is an enormous
higher is an enormous increase
higher is an enormous increase in
energy.
And
And uh
And uh an
And uh an archangel
And uh an archangel runs
And uh an archangel runs 500,000
And uh an archangel runs 500,000 and
And uh an archangel runs 500,000 and and
up
up and
And uh an archangel runs 500,000 and and
up and up.
So
So we're
So we're talking
So we're talking about
So we're talking about power
So we're talking about power of
So we're talking about power of such
immensity.
Uh
Uh we're
Uh we're talking
Uh we're talking about
Uh we're talking about when
Uh we're talking about when I
Uh we're talking about when I first
witnessed
witnessed it
Uh we're talking about when I first
witnessed it went
witnessed it went into
Uh we're talking about when I first
witnessed it went into that
witnessed it went into that state.
The
The power
The power that
The power that holds
The power that holds rock
The power that holds rock together,
steel
steel together,
The power that holds rock together,
steel together, holds
steel together, holds the
The power that holds rock together,
steel together, holds the planet
together,
together, holds
together, holds the
together, holds the universe
together, holds the universe together
together, holds the universe together is
the
the infinite
together, holds the universe together is
the infinite power
the infinite power of
together, holds the universe together is
the infinite power of God
which
which we
which we think
which we think is
which we think is physical.
which we think is physical. Uh
which we think is physical. Uh it's
which we think is physical. Uh it's we
witness
witness it
which we think is physical. Uh it's we
witness it as
witness it as physical.
uh
uh that
uh that is
uh that is the
uh that is the power
uh that is the power of
uh that is the power of God
uh that is the power of God that
uh that is the power of God that the
cohesion
cohesion between
uh that is the power of God that the
cohesion between atoms
cohesion between atoms and
uh that is the power of God that the
cohesion between atoms and what
cohesion between atoms and what makes
cement
cement hard
cement hard is
cement hard is the
cement hard is the the
cement hard is the the infinite
cement hard is the the infinite power
cement hard is the the infinite power of
God
God is
manifesting
manifesting in
manifesting in that
manifesting in that domain.
manifesting in that domain. So
this
this enormous
manifesting in that domain. So
this enormous power
this enormous power then
manifesting in that domain. So
this enormous power then the
this enormous power then the light.
manifesting in that domain. So
this enormous power then the light. So
Genesis
Genesis calibrates
Genesis calibrates positive.
Genesis calibrates positive. There's
only
only three
Genesis calibrates positive. There's
only three books
only three books in
Genesis calibrates positive. There's
only three books in the
only three books in the Old
Genesis calibrates positive. There's
only three books in the Old Testament.
Genesis
Genesis is
Genesis is one
Genesis is one of
Genesis is one of them
Genesis is one of them that
Genesis is one of them that calibrates
positive.
positive. The
Genesis is one of them that calibrates
positive. The Old
positive. The Old Testament
Genesis is one of them that calibrates
positive. The Old Testament you
positive. The Old Testament you have
uh
uh Psalms,
Proverbs
Proverbs and
uh Psalms,
Proverbs and Genesis.
Proverbs and Genesis. All
uh Psalms,
Proverbs and Genesis. All you
Proverbs and Genesis. All you have
uh Psalms,
Proverbs and Genesis. All you have three
books
books of
books of the
books of the Old
books of the Old Testament
books of the Old Testament test
positive.
So
So this
So this infinite
So this infinite power
So this infinite power then
So this infinite power then radiates
forth
forth as
So this infinite power then radiates
forth as the
forth as the light
So this infinite power then radiates
forth as the light of
forth as the light of love.
So this infinite power then radiates
forth as the light of love. Huh?
forth as the light of love. Huh? So
here's
here's what
here's what we're
here's what we're actually
here's what we're actually seeing.
Here's
Here's what
here's what we're actually seeing.
Here's what we're
Here's what we're actually
here's what we're actually seeing.
Here's what we're actually seeing
Here's what we're actually seeing is
that
that the
that the top
that the top the
that the top the the
that the top the the amount
that the top the the amount of
that the top the the amount of love
that the top the the amount of love is
high
high at
that the top the the amount of love is
high at the
high at the top
that the top the the amount of love is
high at the top of
high at the top of the
that the top the the amount of love is
high at the top of the scale
high at the top of the scale and
that the top the the amount of love is
high at the top of the scale and becomes
less
less and
less and less.
So
So if
less and less.
So if this
So if this picture
less and less.
So if this picture was
So if this picture was drawn
less and less.
So if this picture was drawn correctly,
the
the lower
the lower half
the lower half of
the lower half of the
the lower half of the scale
the lower half of the scale as
the lower half of the scale as we
the lower half of the scale as we get
below
below 200,
the lower half of the scale as we get
below 200, the
below 200, the top
the lower half of the scale as we get
below 200, the top would
below 200, the top would be
the lower half of the scale as we get
below 200, the top would be very
below 200, the top would be very bright
and
and then
and then it
and then it darkens
and then it darkens as
and then it darkens as we
and then it darkens as we go
and then it darkens as we go down.
and then it darkens as we go down. And
as
as we
and then it darkens as we go down. And
as we go
as we go below
and then it darkens as we go down. And
as we go below 200,
as we go below 200, it
and then it darkens as we go down. And
as we go below 200, it gets
as we go below 200, it gets darker
and then it darkens as we go down. And
as we go below 200, it gets darker and
darker
darker and
darker and by
darker and by the
darker and by the bottom
darker and by the bottom of
darker and by the bottom of the
darker and by the bottom of the scale,
it's
it's pretty
darker and by the bottom of the scale,
it's pretty black.
I'm
I'm going
I'm going to
I'm going to draw
I'm going to draw you
I'm going to draw you a
I'm going to draw you a new
I'm going to draw you a new map
I'm going to draw you a new map of
consciousness
today.
today. If
today. If any
today. If any graphic
today. If any graphic artist,
today. If any graphic artist, I'm
today. If any graphic artist, I'm sure
somebody
somebody will
today. If any graphic artist, I'm sure
somebody will figure
somebody will figure out
today. If any graphic artist, I'm sure
somebody will figure out how
somebody will figure out how to
today. If any graphic artist, I'm sure
somebody will figure out how to do
somebody will figure out how to do this
so
so it's
so it's doesn't
so it's doesn't look
so it's doesn't look like
so it's doesn't look like kindergarten.
But
But anyway,
so
so what
so what we're
so what we're seeing
so what we're seeing then
so what we're seeing then is
so what we're seeing then is not
so what we're seeing then is not good
and
and evil.
so what we're seeing then is not good
and evil. This
and evil. This is
so what we're seeing then is not good
and evil. This is not
and evil. This is not not
so what we're seeing then is not good
and evil. This is not not two
contrasting
contrasting either
contrasting either ors.
contrasting either ors. You're
contrasting either ors. You're seeing
contrasting either ors. You're seeing a
great
great deal
contrasting either ors. You're seeing a
great deal of
great deal of love,
contrasting either ors. You're seeing a
great deal of love, less
great deal of love, less and
contrasting either ors. You're seeing a
great deal of love, less and less
great deal of love, less and less and
less
less love
less love and
less love and it
less love and it diminishes.
less love and it diminishes. You're
looking
looking more
less love and it diminishes. You're
looking more like
looking more like at
less love and it diminishes. You're
looking more like at a
looking more like at a thermometer.
less love and it diminishes. You're
looking more like at a thermometer. You
see
see though
see though there's
see though there's only
see though there's only one
see though there's only one variable.
Don't
Don't forget
see though there's only one variable.
Don't forget to
Don't forget to get
see though there's only one variable.
Don't forget to get beyond
Don't forget to get beyond dualities.
You
You have
You have to
You have to realize
You have to realize the
You have to realize the error
You have to realize the error is
assuming
assuming that
You have to realize the error is
assuming that there's
assuming that there's two
You have to realize the error is
assuming that there's two variables.
There's
There's only
There's only one
There's only one variable.
There's only one variable. We'll
There's only one variable. We'll explain
that
that there's
There's only one variable. We'll explain
that there's either
that there's either light.
There's only one variable. We'll explain
that there's either light. The
that there's either light. The only
variable
variable between
variable between light
variable between light and
variable between light and darkness
variable between light and darkness is
there's
there's only
variable between light and darkness is
there's only light.
there's only light. There
variable between light and darkness is
there's only light. There isn't
there's only light. There isn't two
things
things such
things such as
things such as light
things such as light and
things such as light and darkness.
There's
There's only
things such as light and darkness.
There's only light.
There's only light. Light
things such as light and darkness.
There's only light. Light is
There's only light. Light is either
there
there or
there or it's
there or it's not
there or it's not there.
there or it's not there. And
there or it's not there. And the
there or it's not there. And the light
can
can be
there or it's not there. And the light
can be very
can be very very
there or it's not there. And the light
can be very very bright
can be very very bright or
there or it's not there. And the light
can be very very bright or it
can be very very bright or it can
there or it's not there. And the light
can be very very bright or it can be
very
very very
very very dim.
very very dim. When
very very dim. When it
very very dim. When it gets
very very dim. When it gets very
very very dim. When it gets very very
dim,
dim, we
very very dim. When it gets very very
dim, we say
dim, we say it's
very very dim. When it gets very very
dim, we say it's darkness.
dim, we say it's darkness. Darkness
very very dim. When it gets very very
dim, we say it's darkness. Darkness is
not
not a
not a thing.
not a thing. You
not a thing. You can't
not a thing. You can't shine
not a thing. You can't shine darkness
into
into a
not a thing. You can't shine darkness
into a closet.
into a closet. Shine
not a thing. You can't shine darkness
into a closet. Shine me
into a closet. Shine me some
not a thing. You can't shine darkness
into a closet. Shine me some darkness.
It
It does
It does no
It does no reality.
It does no reality. The
It does no reality. The absence
It does no reality. The absence of
light.
light. So
It does no reality. The absence of
light. So there's
light. So there's only
It does no reality. The absence of
light. So there's only one
light. So there's only one variable
that's
that's light.
And
And in
that's light.
And in the
And in the scale
that's light.
And in the scale of
And in the scale of consciousness
that's light.
And in the scale of consciousness then
there's
there's only
there's only one
there's only one variable
there's only one variable and
there's only one variable and that's
love.
Infinite
Infinite love
Infinite love makes
Infinite love makes you
Infinite love makes you infinitely
powerful.
The
The moment
The moment of
The moment of enlightenment
The moment of enlightenment which
The moment of enlightenment which was
January
January 1065
The moment of enlightenment which was
January 1065 or
January 1065 or not
The moment of enlightenment which was
January 1065 or not the
January 1065 or not the moment
The moment of enlightenment which was
January 1065 or not the moment but
whatever
whatever space
whatever space it
whatever space it was
was
was uh
whatever space it was
was uh left
was uh left me
whatever space it was
was uh left me jarred
was uh left me jarred and
whatever space it was
was uh left me jarred and thoughtless
for
for many
for many years.
Let's
Let's just
for many years.
Let's just we
Let's just we recently
for many years.
Let's just we recently out
Let's just we recently out of
for many years.
Let's just we recently out of curiosity
I
I was
I was almost
I was almost scared
I was almost scared to
I was almost scared to ask
I was almost scared to ask that
I was almost scared to ask that that
I was almost scared to ask that that was
the
the one
I was almost scared to ask that that was
the one that
the one that had
I was almost scared to ask that that was
the one that had 500,000
the one that had 500,000 resist.
I was almost scared to ask that that was
the one that had 500,000 resist. It
the one that had 500,000 resist. It was
a
a thought
a thought from
a thought from the
a thought from the one
a thought from the one at
a thought from the one at 500,000
resistance.
resistance. A
a thought from the one at 500,000
resistance. A thought
resistance. A thought out
a thought from the one at 500,000
resistance. A thought out of
resistance. A thought out of enormous
prayer
prayer and
prayer and archangel
prayer and archangel merely
prayer and archangel merely gives
prayer and archangel merely gives you
prayer and archangel merely gives you a
thought
instant
instant took
instant took me
instant took me right
instant took me right out
instant took me right out of
instant took me right out of the
right
right out
instant took me right out of the
right out of
right out of the
instant took me right out of the
right out of the world
right out of the world of
instant took me right out of the
right out of the world of what
right out of the world of what the
instant took me right out of the
right out of the world of what the world
calls
calls reality
calls reality into
calls reality into a
calls reality into a different
calls reality into a different total
reality.
The
The therefore
analogous
analogous to
The therefore
analogous to light
analogous to light then
The therefore
analogous to light then the
analogous to light then the top
The therefore
analogous to light then the top of
analogous to light then the top of the
scale
scale at
scale at 1,00
is
is about
scale at 1,00
is about as
is about as much
scale at 1,00
is about as much light
is about as much light as
scale at 1,00
is about as much light as protoplasm
is about as much light as protoplasm can
handle
handle without
handle without frying
and
and it
handle without frying
and it fries
and it fries even
handle without frying
and it fries even there.
and it fries even there. But
uh
so
so this
uh
so this light
so this light is
uh
so this light is very
so this light is very intense
uh
so this light is very intense and
so this light is very intense and the
ordinary
ordinary protoplasm
ordinary protoplasm really
ordinary protoplasm really cannot
ordinary protoplasm really cannot handle
it.
it. It
ordinary protoplasm really cannot handle
it. It gets
it. It gets it
ordinary protoplasm really cannot handle
it. It gets it scales
it. It gets it scales down
ordinary protoplasm really cannot handle
it. It gets it scales down then
it. It gets it scales down then and
ordinary protoplasm really cannot handle
it. It gets it scales down then and we
notice
notice that
notice that at
notice that at what
notice that at what we
notice that at what we calibrate
notice that at what we calibrate at
notice that at what we calibrate at 200
what
what has
notice that at what we calibrate at 200
what has happened
what has happened here
notice that at what we calibrate at 200
what has happened here is
what has happened here is that
notice that at what we calibrate at 200
what has happened here is that you
haven't
haven't gone
haven't gone from
haven't gone from love
haven't gone from love to
haven't gone from love to not
haven't gone from love to not love.
What's
What's happened
haven't gone from love to not love.
What's happened is
What's happened is that
haven't gone from love to not love.
What's happened is that it
What's happened is that it changes
quality.
Now
Now in
quality.
Now in any
Now in any progression
quality.
Now in any progression of
Now in any progression of comparisons
you'll
you'll notice
you'll notice the
you'll notice the logical
you'll notice the logical error
you'll notice the logical error was
you'll notice the logical error was made
by
by Aristotle
you'll notice the logical error was made
by Aristotle is
by Aristotle is made
you'll notice the logical error was made
by Aristotle is made by
by Aristotle is made by all
you'll notice the logical error was made
by Aristotle is made by all the
by Aristotle is made by all the great
thinkers
thinkers of
thinkers of all
thinkers of all time.
uh
uh in
thinkers of all time.
uh in looking
uh in looking for
thinkers of all time.
uh in looking for the
uh in looking for the primary
thinkers of all time.
uh in looking for the primary cause
let's
let's say
let's say um
Sir
Sir Thomas
let's say um
Sir Thomas Aquinus's
Sir Thomas Aquinus's uh
let's say um
Sir Thomas Aquinus's uh arguments
Sir Thomas Aquinus's uh arguments for
the
the existence
the existence of
the existence of God
the existence of God uh
the existence of God uh there
the existence of God uh there is
the existence of God uh there is the
classic
classic argument
the existence of God uh there is the
classic argument of
classic argument of uh
the existence of God uh there is the
classic argument of uh first
classic argument of uh first cause
the existence of God uh there is the
classic argument of uh first cause uh
and
and today's
and today's lecture
and today's lecture we're
and today's lecture we're going
and today's lecture we're going to
and today's lecture we're going to try
and
and get
and today's lecture we're going to try
and get rid
and get rid of
and today's lecture we're going to try
and get rid of cause
and get rid of cause it's
and today's lecture we're going to try
and get rid of cause it's a
and get rid of cause it's a great
impediment
impediment somebody
impediment somebody write
impediment somebody write down
impediment somebody write down cause
impediment somebody write down cause we
must
must don't
impediment somebody write down cause we
must don't forget
must don't forget we
impediment somebody write down cause we
must don't forget we have
must don't forget we have to
impediment somebody write down cause we
must don't forget we have to eliminate
cause
cause from
cause from our
cause from our thinking
cause from our thinking anyway
cause from our thinking anyway it
cause from our thinking anyway it gets
down
down to
cause from our thinking anyway it gets
down to first
down to first cause
cause from our thinking anyway it gets
down to first cause the
down to first cause the difficulty
cause from our thinking anyway it gets
down to first cause the difficulty with
that
that kind
uh
uh thinking
that kind
uh thinking this
uh thinking this is
that kind
uh thinking this is that
uh thinking this is that it
that kind
uh thinking this is that it doesn't
realize
realize that
realize that many
realize that many sequences
realize that many sequences there's
realize that many sequences there's a
change
change of
realize that many sequences there's a
change of quality
change of quality along
realize that many sequences there's a
change of quality along the
change of quality along the way
realize that many sequences there's a
change of quality along the way which
they
they don't
they don't take
they don't take into
they don't take into account
the
the change
they don't take into account
the change of
the change of quality
as
as you
as you look
as you look through
as you look through a
as you look through a sequence
as you look through a sequence of
as you look through a sequence of what
the
the world
as you look through a sequence of what
the world calls
the world calls cause
as you look through a sequence of what
the world calls cause is
the world calls cause is you're
expecting
expecting to
expecting to find
expecting to find something
expecting to find something very
expecting to find something very very
similar
similar as
expecting to find something very very
similar as cause
similar as cause number
expecting to find something very very
similar as cause number uno
similar as cause number uno no
expecting to find something very very
similar as cause number uno no cause
number
number uno
number uno is
number uno is of
number uno is of a
number uno is of a different
number uno is of a different quality
number uno is of a different quality see
the
the same
number uno is of a different quality see
the same thing
the same thing you'll
number uno is of a different quality see
the same thing you'll understand
the same thing you'll understand as
number uno is of a different quality see
the same thing you'll understand as soon
as
as I
as I tell
as I tell you
as I tell you this,
as I tell you this, if
as I tell you this, if we
as I tell you this, if we take
as I tell you this, if we take a
thermometer,
let's
let's say
let's say above
let's say above a
let's say above a th00and
let's say above a th00and the
let's say above a th00and the water
turns
turns into
let's say above a th00and the water
turns into steam.
turns into steam. When
let's say above a th00and the water
turns into steam. When you
turns into steam. When you get
let's say above a th00and the water
turns into steam. When you get down
turns into steam. When you get down to
calibration
calibration level
calibration level 200,
calibration level 200, it
calibration level 200, it turns
calibration level 200, it turns to
calibration level 200, it turns to ice.
It's
It's still
calibration level 200, it turns to ice.
It's still only
It's still only H2O.
calibration level 200, it turns to ice.
It's still only H2O. But
It's still only H2O. But wo,
calibration level 200, it turns to ice.
It's still only H2O. But wo, what
It's still only H2O. But wo, what a
change
change of
change of quality.
change of quality. So
change of quality. So what
change of quality. So what we
change of quality. So what we have
change of quality. So what we have at
200 is
200 is not
change of quality. So what we have at
200 is not a
200 is not a duality
change of quality. So what we have at
200 is not a duality of
200 is not a duality of water
change of quality. So what we have at
200 is not a duality of water versus
nonwater.
nonwater. We
nonwater. We just
nonwater. We just have
nonwater. We just have at
nonwater. We just have at this
nonwater. We just have at this end
nonwater. We just have at this end hot
water,
water, Jesus
nonwater. We just have at this end hot
water, Jesus and
water, Jesus and and
nonwater. We just have at this end hot
water, Jesus and and Krishna
water, Jesus and and Krishna and
nonwater. We just have at this end hot
water, Jesus and and Krishna and all
those
those people.
those people. And
those people. And then
those people. And then at
those people. And then at 200
those people. And then at 200 this
those people. And then at 200 this water
turns
turns into
those people. And then at 200 this water
turns into ice.
turns into ice. It's
those people. And then at 200 this water
turns into ice. It's still
turns into ice. It's still just
those people. And then at 200 this water
turns into ice. It's still just water.
It's
It's not
It's not a
It's not a duality
It's not a duality of
It's not a duality of water
It's not a duality of water versus
nonwater.
nonwater. Okay,
It's not a duality of water versus
nonwater. Okay, that
nonwater. Okay, that will
It's not a duality of water versus
nonwater. Okay, that will help
nonwater. Okay, that will help a
It's not a duality of water versus
nonwater. Okay, that will help a lot
nonwater. Okay, that will help a lot of
people.
people. You
people. You see,
people. You see, when
people. You see, when you
people. You see, when you get
people. You see, when you get caught
people. You see, when you get caught by
the
the dualities
people. You see, when you get caught by
the dualities which
the dualities which is
people. You see, when you get caught by
the dualities which is created
the dualities which is created by
people. You see, when you get caught by
the dualities which is created by some
positionality,
the
the way
positionality,
the way you
the way you transcend
positionality,
the way you transcend perception
the way you transcend perception is
positionality,
the way you transcend perception is you
have
have to
have to find
have to find the
have to find the positionality
have to find the positionality that's
creating
creating that
have to find the positionality that's
creating that duality
creating that duality and
have to find the positionality that's
creating that duality and remove
creating that duality and remove that
positionality
positionality and
positionality and the
positionality and the duality
positionality and the duality then
collap
collap collapses.
positionality and the duality then
collap collapses. And
collap collapses. And what
positionality and the duality then
collap collapses. And what you
collap collapses. And what you see
positionality and the duality then
collap collapses. And what you see is
that
that it's
that it's not
that it's not a
that it's not a duality.
that it's not a duality. It's
that it's not a duality. It's a
gradation.
gradation. Let's
that it's not a duality. It's a
gradation. Let's say
gradation. Let's say good
that it's not a duality. It's a
gradation. Let's say good and
gradation. Let's say good and evil.
that it's not a duality. It's a
gradation. Let's say good and evil. So
you
you could
you could start
you could start with
you could start with good
you could start with good at
you could start with good at the
you could start with good at the top,
right?
right? And
you could start with good at the top,
right? And then
right? And then remove
you could start with good at the top,
right? And then remove more
right? And then remove more more
you could start with good at the top,
right? And then remove more more good.
And
And at
And at and
And at and at
And at and at a
And at and at a certain
And at and at a certain point,
And at and at a certain point, depending
on
on what
And at and at a certain point, depending
on what your
on what your positionality
And at and at a certain point, depending
on what your positionality is,
on what your positionality is, you
And at and at a certain point, depending
on what your positionality is, you would
say,
say, well,
say, well, that's
say, well, that's evil.
say, well, that's evil. Well,
say, well, that's evil. Well, people
would
would be
say, well, that's evil. Well, people
would be in
would be in different
say, well, that's evil. Well, people
would be in different places.
would be in different places. A
say, well, that's evil. Well, people
would be in different places. A street
kid
kid from
kid from I
kid from I treat
kid from I treat a
kid from I treat a lot
kid from I treat a lot of
kid from I treat a lot of street
kid from I treat a lot of street kids.
You
You know,
kid from I treat a lot of street kids.
You know, I
You know, I I'm
kid from I treat a lot of street kids.
You know, I I'm in
You know, I I'm in a
kid from I treat a lot of street kids.
You know, I I'm in a girls
You know, I I'm in a girls ranch.
kid from I treat a lot of street kids.
You know, I I'm in a girls ranch. We
have
have lots
have lots of
have lots of juvenile
have lots of juvenile adolescents
have lots of juvenile adolescents there
and
and their
have lots of juvenile adolescents there
and their their
and their their scale
have lots of juvenile adolescents there
and their their scale of
and their their scale of what's
have lots of juvenile adolescents there
and their their scale of what's okay
and their their scale of what's okay and
what's
what's not
what's not okay
what's not okay is
what's not okay is quite
what's not okay is quite a
what's not okay is quite a bit
what's not okay is quite a bit different
than
than what
what's not okay is quite a bit different
than what goes
than what goes on
what's not okay is quite a bit different
than what goes on at
than what goes on at Harvard
or
or what
or what goes
or what goes in
or what goes in the
or what goes in the Lower
or what goes in the Lower East
or what goes in the Lower East Side
or what goes in the Lower East Side in
New
New York
or what goes in the Lower East Side in
New York City.
New York City. You
or what goes in the Lower East Side in
New York City. You know
New York City. You know what
or what goes in the Lower East Side in
New York City. You know what I
New York City. You know what I see?
or what goes in the Lower East Side in
New York City. You know what I see? So,
uh
uh anyway,
uh anyway, to
uh anyway, to them
uh anyway, to them what
uh anyway, to them what we
uh anyway, to them what we would
consider
really
really malevolent
really malevolent to
really malevolent to them
really malevolent to them would
really malevolent to them would just
really malevolent to them would just be
a
a kick.
really malevolent to them would just be
a kick. Not
a kick. Not only
really malevolent to them would just be
a kick. Not only that,
a kick. Not only that, but
really malevolent to them would just be
a kick. Not only that, but they
a kick. Not only that, but they have
really malevolent to them would just be
a kick. Not only that, but they have a
rationale
rationale that
rationale that they
rationale that they asked
rationale that they asked for
rationale that they asked for it.
Their
Their position
rationale that they asked for it.
Their position is
Their position is if
rationale that they asked for it.
Their position is if your
Their position is if your purse
rationale that they asked for it.
Their position is if your purse gets
stolen,
stolen, well,
stolen, well, she
stolen, well, she asked
stolen, well, she asked for
stolen, well, she asked for it.
stolen, well, she asked for it. She
stolen, well, she asked for it. She left
it
it on
stolen, well, she asked for it. She left
it on the
it on the back
stolen, well, she asked for it. She left
it on the back of
it on the back of her
stolen, well, she asked for it. She left
it on the back of her chair
it on the back of her chair in
stolen, well, she asked for it. She left
it on the back of her chair in the
store.
store. I
store. I mean,
store. I mean, what
store. I mean, what do
store. I mean, what do you
store. I mean, what do you expect?
store. I mean, what do you expect? So,
that's
that's their
store. I mean, what do you expect? So,
that's their idea
that's their idea of
store. I mean, what do you expect? So,
that's their idea of good
that's their idea of good and
store. I mean, what do you expect? So,
that's their idea of good and evil.
It's
It's her
It's her fault
It's her fault cuz
It's her fault cuz she
It's her fault cuz she left
It's her fault cuz she left the
It's her fault cuz she left the purse
sitting
sitting there.
It's her fault cuz she left the purse
sitting there. That's
sitting there. That's they
It's her fault cuz she left the purse
sitting there. That's they believe
sitting there. That's they believe that.
That's
That's true.
That's true. Isn't
That's true. Isn't that
That's true. Isn't that wrong
That's true. Isn't that wrong to
That's true. Isn't that wrong to steal?
She
She left
That's true. Isn't that wrong to steal?
She left her
She left her purse
That's true. Isn't that wrong to steal?
She left her purse right
She left her purse right there.
That's true. Isn't that wrong to steal?
She left her purse right there. Oh,
She left her purse right there. Oh, I
punched
punched her.
punched her. Well,
punched her. Well, she
punched her. Well, she snotted
punched her. Well, she snotted off
punched her. Well, she snotted off to
me,
me, so
punched her. Well, she snotted off to
me, so I
me, so I punched
punched her. Well, she snotted off to
me, so I punched her
me, so I punched her one
punched her. Well, she snotted off to
me, so I punched her one right
me, so I punched her one right in
punched her. Well, she snotted off to
me, so I punched her one right in the
face.
She
She deserved
face.
She deserved it.
She deserved it. She
face.
She deserved it. She asked
She deserved it. She asked for
face.
She deserved it. She asked for it.
She deserved it. She asked for it. That
that's
that's their
that's their right.
that's their right. Like
that's their right. Like Bin
that's their right. Like Bin Laden.
that's their right. Like Bin Laden. I
mean,
mean, they're
that's their right. Like Bin Laden. I
mean, they're all
mean, they're all rich
that's their right. Like Bin Laden. I
mean, they're all rich and
mean, they're all rich and successful
and
and so
and so they
and so they deserve
and so they deserve to
and so they deserve to get
and so they deserve to get bombed,
right?
right? No
and so they deserve to get bombed,
right? No problem.
So,
I
I mean,
So,
I mean, they
I mean, they work
So,
I mean, they work their
I mean, they work their butt
So,
I mean, they work their butt off
I mean, they work their butt off and
drive
drive theel
drive theel to
drive theel to deprive
drive theel to deprive themselves
drive theel to deprive themselves of
things
things to
drive theel to deprive themselves of
things to go
things to go to
drive theel to deprive themselves of
things to go to school
things to go to school and
drive theel to deprive themselves of
things to go to school and drive
things to go to school and drive a
drive theel to deprive themselves of
things to go to school and drive a cab
to
to all
to all hours
to all hours a
to all hours a night.
to all hours a night. I
to all hours a night. I had
to all hours a night. I had about
to all hours a night. I had about four
jobs
jobs just
to all hours a night. I had about four
jobs just to
jobs just to get
to all hours a night. I had about four
jobs just to get through
jobs just to get through college.
to all hours a night. I had about four
jobs just to get through college. And
now
now that
now that you
now that you you've
now that you you've you've
now that you you've you've gotten
through
through medical
now that you you've you've gotten
through medical school
through medical school and
now that you you've you've gotten
through medical school and all
through medical school and all in
now that you you've you've gotten
through medical school and all in the
world
world say
world say you're
world say you're successful.
world say you're successful. Now
world say you're successful. Now they
hate
hate you
world say you're successful. Now they
hate you because
hate you because you
world say you're successful. Now they
hate you because you worked
hate you because you worked your
world say you're successful. Now they
hate you because you worked your butt
off.
Only
Only a
off.
Only a quarter
Only a quarter of
off.
Only a quarter of the
Only a quarter of the men
off.
Only a quarter of the men over
Only a quarter of the men over there
off.
Only a quarter of the men over there in
that
that country
that country know
that country know how
that country know how to
that country know how to read.
that country know how to read. So
that country know how to read. So I
that country know how to read. So I mean
they
they could
that country know how to read. So I mean
they could at least
they could at least get
that country know how to read. So I mean
they could at least get their
they could at least get their yourself
off
off their
off their butt
off their butt and
off their butt and learn
off their butt and learn how
off their butt and learn how to
off their butt and learn how to read,
you
you know,
off their butt and learn how to read,
you know, so
you know, so at
off their butt and learn how to read,
you know, so at least
you know, so at least they
off their butt and learn how to read,
you know, so at least they have
something
something to
something to complain
something to complain about.
Anyway,
Anyway, they're
something to complain about.
Anyway, they're too
Anyway, they're too busy
something to complain about.
Anyway, they're too busy blaming
Anyway, they're too busy blaming us.
something to complain about.
Anyway, they're too busy blaming us. So
anyway,
anyway, you
anyway, you see
anyway, you see good
anyway, you see good and
anyway, you see good and evil
anyway, you see good and evil then
anyway, you see good and evil then is
anyway, you see good and evil then is in
the
the as
anyway, you see good and evil then is in
the as good
the as good Jesus
anyway, you see good and evil then is in
the as good Jesus said
the as good Jesus said in
anyway, you see good and evil then is in
the as good Jesus said in the
the as good Jesus said in the eye
anyway, you see good and evil then is in
the as good Jesus said in the eye of
the as good Jesus said in the eye of the
beholder.
beholder. But
beholder. But I
beholder. But I want
beholder. But I want to
beholder. But I want to just
beholder. But I want to just clear
beholder. But I want to just clear up
beholder. But I want to just clear up uh
that
that there
beholder. But I want to just clear up uh
that there is
that there is not
beholder. But I want to just clear up uh
that there is not here
that there is not here good
beholder. But I want to just clear up uh
that there is not here good and
that there is not here good and evil.
There
There is
There is not
There is not here
There is not here a
There is not here a duality.
There is not here a duality. There
There is not here a duality. There is
There is not here a duality. There is a
change
change of
There is not here a duality. There is a
change of character
change of character in
There is not here a duality. There is a
change of character in consciousness.
At
At 1,00
At 1,00 it
At 1,00 it inspires
At 1,00 it inspires the
At 1,00 it inspires the world
either
either consciously
At 1,00 it inspires the world
either consciously or
either consciously or unconsciously.
The
The energy
The energy field
The energy field created
The energy field created by
The energy field created by the
The energy field created by the great
avatars
avatars uplifts
The energy field created by the great
avatars uplifts and
avatars uplifts and holds
The energy field created by the great
avatars uplifts and holds this
avatars uplifts and holds this world
this
this very
this very instant.
this very instant. The
this very instant. The energy
this very instant. The energy field
this very instant. The energy field of
everybody
everybody in
this very instant. The energy field of
everybody in this
everybody in this room
this very instant. The energy field of
everybody in this room is
everybody in this room is upholding
this very instant. The energy field of
everybody in this room is upholding this
world.
world. This
world. This very
world. This very instant
that
that which
world. This very instant
that which we
that which we are
world. This very instant
that which we are this
that which we are this moment
world. This very instant
that which we are this moment upholds
and
and lifts
and lifts the
and lifts the world.
and lifts the world. You
and lifts the world. You see
that
that grandiosity
and lifts the world. You see
that grandiosity or
that grandiosity or a
and lifts the world. You see
that grandiosity or a fact?
that grandiosity or a fact? Is
and lifts the world. You see
that grandiosity or a fact? Is that
grandiosity?
grandiosity? Right.
grandiosity? Right. Okay.
grandiosity? Right. Okay. Uh
grandiosity? Right. Okay. Uh that
grandiosity? Right. Okay. Uh that is
grandiosity? Right. Okay. Uh that is a
fact
fact which
grandiosity? Right. Okay. Uh that is a
fact which we
fact which we just
grandiosity? Right. Okay. Uh that is a
fact which we just stated
fact which we just stated resist.
grandiosity? Right. Okay. Uh that is a
fact which we just stated resist. That's
a
a fact.
a fact. Okay.
a fact. Okay. So
a fact. Okay. So periodically
a fact. Okay. So periodically we
a fact. Okay. So periodically we do
kinesiology
kinesiology just
a fact. Okay. So periodically we do
kinesiology just to
kinesiology just to verify
a fact. Okay. So periodically we do
kinesiology just to verify something
that
that the
that the ego
that the ego may
that the ego may have
that the ego may have a
that the ego may have a doubt
that the ego may have a doubt about.
All right.
All right. So
that the ego may have a doubt about.
All right. So I
All right. So I I
that the ego may have a doubt about.
All right. So I I hope
All right. So I I hope to
that the ego may have a doubt about.
All right. So I I hope to clarify
All right. So I I hope to clarify then
that
that scale
that scale consciousness
that scale consciousness we're
that scale consciousness we're not
talking
talking about
that scale consciousness we're not
talking about a
talking about a duality
that scale consciousness we're not
talking about a duality of
talking about a duality of good
that scale consciousness we're not
talking about a duality of good and
evil.
evil. We're
evil. We're talking
evil. We're talking about
evil. We're talking about gradations
evil. We're talking about gradations of
love.
love. Um
evil. We're talking about gradations of
love. Um that
love. Um that which
evil. We're talking about gradations of
love. Um that which we
love. Um that which we call
evil. We're talking about gradations of
love. Um that which we call evil
love. Um that which we call evil is
merely
merely totally
merely totally unloving.
merely totally unloving. Unloving.
merely totally unloving. Unloving. I'm
researching
researching the
merely totally unloving. Unloving. I'm
researching the level
researching the level of
merely totally unloving. Unloving. I'm
researching the level of non-lo.
I
I don't
I don't advise
I don't advise people
I don't advise people to
I don't advise people to do
I don't advise people to do that.
I don't advise people to do that. I'll
do
do it
I don't advise people to do that. I'll
do it at
do it at the
I don't advise people to do that. I'll
do it at the bottom.
And
And I'm
And I'm discovering
And I'm discovering non-love.
And I'm discovering non-love. uh
And I'm discovering non-love. uh in
doing
doing this
And I'm discovering non-love. uh in
doing this I'm
doing this I'm writing
And I'm discovering non-love. uh in
doing this I'm writing I'm
doing this I'm writing I'm finishing
And I'm discovering non-love. uh in
doing this I'm writing I'm finishing a
book
book now
book now called
book now called I
in
in which
book now called I
in which we
in which we try
book now called I
in which we try to
in which we try to trace
book now called I
in which we try to trace the
in which we try to trace the evolution
of
of consciousness
of consciousness as
of consciousness as it
of consciousness as it appeared
of consciousness as it appeared within
the
the created
of consciousness as it appeared within
the created universe
the created universe and
of consciousness as it appeared within
the created universe and track
the created universe and track its
evolution
evolution over
evolution over time
evolution over time and
evolution over time and its
evolution over time and its evolution
all
all the
evolution over time and its evolution
all the way
all the way up
evolution over time and its evolution
all the way up the
all the way up the scale
evolution over time and its evolution
all the way up the scale of
all the way up the scale of life
evolution over time and its evolution
all the way up the scale of life through
all
all the
all the various
all the various life
all the various life forms
uh
uh throughout
all the various life forms
uh throughout the
uh throughout the eons
all the various life forms
uh throughout the eons and
uh throughout the eons and as
all the various life forms
uh throughout the eons and as it
manifests
manifests up
manifests up to
manifests up to the
manifests up to the very
manifests up to the very highest
possible
As
As we
As we do
As we do that,
As we do that, we
As we do that, we notice
As we do that, we notice that
As we do that, we notice that life
As we do that, we notice that life seems
to
to come
As we do that, we notice that life seems
to come up
to come up two
As we do that, we notice that life seems
to come up two different
to come up two different tracks.
One
One track
One track sort
One track sort of
One track sort of reaches
One track sort of reaches its
One track sort of reaches its greatest
uh
uh perfection
One track sort of reaches its greatest
uh perfection in
uh perfection in the
One track sort of reaches its greatest
uh perfection in the age
uh perfection in the age of
One track sort of reaches its greatest
uh perfection in the age of the
dinosaurs
in
in which
dinosaurs
in which life
the
the life
the life of
the life of the
the life of the individual
is
is at
the life of the individual
is at the
is at the price
the life of the individual
is at the price at
is at the price at the
the life of the individual
is at the price at the cost
is at the price at the cost of
the life of the individual
is at the price at the cost of the
is at the price at the cost of the life
of
of another
of another individual.
So
So the
of another individual.
So the great
So the great reptiles,
of another individual.
So the great reptiles, the
So the great reptiles, the great
dinosaurs
dinosaurs lived
dinosaurs lived by
dinosaurs lived by the
dinosaurs lived by the death
dinosaurs lived by the death of
dinosaurs lived by the death of others.
So
So we
dinosaurs lived by the death of others.
So we see
So we see one
dinosaurs lived by the death of others.
So we see one energy
So we see one energy in
dinosaurs lived by the death of others.
So we see one energy in the
So we see one energy in the world.
dinosaurs lived by the death of others.
So we see one energy in the world. It
lives
lives by
lives by the
lives by the death
lives by the death of
lives by the death of others.
It
It is
lives by the death of others.
It is therefore
It is therefore the
lives by the death of others.
It is therefore the extreme
It is therefore the extreme of
narcissism.
If
If we
narcissism.
If we were
If we were going
narcissism.
If we were going to
If we were going to define
narcissism.
If we were going to define evil,
If we were going to define evil, we
would
would see
would see we
would see we would
would see we would we
would see we would we would
would see we would we would say
would see we would we would say it
would see we would we would say it is
the
the extreme
would see we would we would say it is
the extreme of
the extreme of selfishness.
would see we would we would say it is
the extreme of selfishness. I
the extreme of selfishness. I wish
would see we would we would say it is
the extreme of selfishness. I wish to
live
live therefore
live therefore you
live therefore you will
live therefore you will have
live therefore you will have to
live therefore you will have to die.
Mr.
Mr. Ben
live therefore you will have to die.
Mr. Ben Louden
Mr. Ben Louden says,
live therefore you will have to die.
Mr. Ben Louden says, "I
Mr. Ben Louden says, "I wish
live therefore you will have to die.
Mr. Ben Louden says, "I wish to
Mr. Ben Louden says, "I wish to express
my
my feelings."
He
He must
my feelings."
He must have
He must have grown
my feelings."
He must have grown up
He must have grown up in
my feelings."
He must have grown up in grown
He must have grown up in grown up
my feelings."
He must have grown up in grown up in
He must have grown up in grown up in the
let
let it
let it all
let it all hang
let it all hang out
let it all hang out era.
let it all hang out era. Remember
let it all hang out era. Remember when
we
we were
let it all hang out era. Remember when
we were that
we were that was
let it all hang out era. Remember when
we were that was about
we were that was about in
let it all hang out era. Remember when
we were that was about in the
we were that was about in the 60s
let it all hang out era. Remember when
we were that was about in the 60s or
we were that was about in the 60s or so
in
in which
in which you
in which you express
in which you express yourself
in which you express yourself and
in which you express yourself and don't
repress
repress your
in which you express yourself and don't
repress your feelings.
So
So there
So there was
So there was the
So there was the maximum
So there was the maximum of
self-indulgence,
self-indulgence, his
So there was the maximum of
self-indulgence, his feeling
self-indulgence, his feeling at
So there was the maximum of
self-indulgence, his feeling at the
price
price of
price of 3,000
price of 3,000 other
price of 3,000 other lies.
So
So the
price of 3,000 other lies.
So the other
So the other life
price of 3,000 other lies.
So the other life is
So the other life is immaterial.
Uh
at
at the
Uh
at the very
at the very bottom
Uh
at the very bottom of
at the very bottom of the
Uh
at the very bottom of the of
at the very bottom of the of that
Uh
at the very bottom of the of that scale,
you
you might
you might say,
you might say, we
you might say, we find
you might say, we find the
you might say, we find the venomous.
you might say, we find the venomous. So
I'm
I'm writing
you might say, we find the venomous. So
I'm writing a
I'm writing a chapter
you might say, we find the venomous. So
I'm writing a chapter on
I'm writing a chapter on the
you might say, we find the venomous. So
I'm writing a chapter on the venomous.
And
And the
And the venomous,
And the venomous, one
And the venomous, one bite
And the venomous, one bite from
And the venomous, one bite from the
venomous
venomous and
And the venomous, one bite from the
venomous and you're
venomous and you're dead.
And the venomous, one bite from the
venomous and you're dead. Um
venomous and you're dead. Um the
commoded
commoded dragon
commoded dragon uh
commoded dragon uh is
commoded dragon uh is a
commoded dragon uh is a living
commoded dragon uh is a living example,
sort
sort of
commoded dragon uh is a living example,
sort of anistic.
sort of anistic. Um,
but
but the
but the truly
but the truly venomous
but the truly venomous are
but the truly venomous are much
but the truly venomous are much more
basic
basic than
but the truly venomous are much more
basic than that.
The
The uh
The uh box
The uh box jellyfish
The uh box jellyfish has
The uh box jellyfish has something
The uh box jellyfish has something like
26 fatal
26 fatal enzymes,
The uh box jellyfish has something like
26 fatal enzymes, fatal
26 fatal enzymes, fatal poisons,
The uh box jellyfish has something like
26 fatal enzymes, fatal poisons, 26
fatal
fatal venoms.
fatal venoms. It
fatal venoms. It not
fatal venoms. It not only
fatal venoms. It not only kills
fatal venoms. It not only kills you
once,
once, it
fatal venoms. It not only kills you
once, it kills
once, it kills you
fatal venoms. It not only kills you
once, it kills you 26
once, it kills you 26 different
fatal venoms. It not only kills you
once, it kills you 26 different times
and
and weights.
Wow.
Wow. Was
and weights.
Wow. Was that
Wow. Was that necessary?
and weights.
Wow. Was that necessary? I
Wow. Was that necessary? I mean,
and weights.
Wow. Was that necessary? I mean, one
Wow. Was that necessary? I mean, one one
poison
poison do
poison do it.
The
The black
poison do it.
The black mamba
The black mamba who
poison do it.
The black mamba who calibrates
The black mamba who calibrates I
poison do it.
The black mamba who calibrates I think
at
at 35
at 35 or
at 35 or something
also
also has
at 35 or something
also has all
also has all these
at 35 or something
also has all these neurotoxins
also has all these neurotoxins and
however
however I
however I found
however I found that
however I found that the
however I found that the ultimate
culprit
culprit is
however I found that the ultimate
culprit is a
culprit is a little
however I found that the ultimate
culprit is a little mollisk
culprit is a little mollisk that
however I found that the ultimate
culprit is a little mollisk that lives
at
at the
at the bottom
at the bottom of
at the bottom of the
at the bottom of the sea
at the bottom of the sea who
at the bottom of the sea who has
at the bottom of the sea who has a
at the bottom of the sea who has a long
Latin
Latin name
at the bottom of the sea who has a long
Latin name which
Latin name which I
at the bottom of the sea who has a long
Latin name which I can't
Latin name which I can't remember
at the bottom of the sea who has a long
Latin name which I can't remember but
Latin name which I can't remember but he
apparently
apparently burrows
apparently burrows through
apparently burrows through the
apparently burrows through the shell
apparently burrows through the shell of
his
his prey
apparently burrows through the shell of
his prey and
his prey and injects
apparently burrows through the shell of
his prey and injects a
his prey and injects a magnificent
cocktail
cocktail of
cocktail of 40
cocktail of 40 fatal
cocktail of 40 fatal enzymes.
cocktail of 40 fatal enzymes. 40
poisons.
One's
One's enough
One's enough to
One's enough to kill
One's enough to kill you
One's enough to kill you and
One's enough to kill you and then
One's enough to kill you and then they
did
did it
One's enough to kill you and then they
did it again
did it again and
One's enough to kill you and then they
did it again and then
did it again and then they
One's enough to kill you and then they
did it again and then they did
did it again and then they did it
One's enough to kill you and then they
did it again and then they did it again.
Each
Each one
Each one a
Each one a different
Each one a different enzyme
Each one a different enzyme system.
That
That doesn't
Each one a different enzyme system.
That doesn't occur
That doesn't occur just
Each one a different enzyme system.
That doesn't occur just spontaneously,
does
does it?
does it? You
does it? You can't
does it? You can't just
does it? You can't just say,
does it? You can't just say, well,
does it? You can't just say, well, out
of
of the
does it? You can't just say, well, out
of the accidental
of the accidental playing
does it? You can't just say, well, out
of the accidental playing around
of the accidental playing around of
evolution,
evolution, this
evolution, this worked
evolution, this worked pretty
evolution, this worked pretty good.
evolution, this worked pretty good. So,
it
it no,
evolution, this worked pretty good. So,
it no, you
it no, you begin
evolution, this worked pretty good. So,
it no, you begin to
it no, you begin to see
evolution, this worked pretty good. So,
it no, you begin to see there's
intelligence
intelligence behind
intelligence behind all
intelligence behind all in
intelligence behind all in this
universe.
universe. So
the
the ultimate
the ultimate venom
the ultimate venom then
the ultimate venom then is
the ultimate venom then is so
the ultimate venom then is so potent
that
that it
the ultimate venom then is so potent
that it is
that it is 40
the ultimate venom then is so potent
that it is 40 times
that it is 40 times what
the ultimate venom then is so potent
that it is 40 times what it's
that it is 40 times what it's needed
the ultimate venom then is so potent
that it is 40 times what it's needed to
be.
be. 40
be. 40 different
be. 40 different possible
be. 40 different possible enzymes.
We
We come
be. 40 different possible enzymes.
We come up
We come up through
be. 40 different possible enzymes.
We come up through the
We come up through the web
be. 40 different possible enzymes.
We come up through the web spider
We come up through the web spider which
is
is also
is also the
is also the most
is also the most v
is also the most v vicious
is also the most v vicious creature
is also the most v vicious creature on
the
the planet.
is also the most v vicious creature on
the planet. The
the planet. The web
is also the most v vicious creature on
the planet. The web spider
the planet. The web spider funnel
is also the most v vicious creature on
the planet. The web spider funnel funnel
web
web spider
web spider also
web spider also is
web spider also is loaded
web spider also is loaded with
web spider also is loaded with enough
poisons
poisons to
web spider also is loaded with enough
poisons to kill
poisons to kill a
web spider also is loaded with enough
poisons to kill a whole
poisons to kill a whole army
web spider also is loaded with enough
poisons to kill a whole army of
poisons to kill a whole army of people.
Why
Why the
Why the over
Why the over why
Why the over why the
Why the over why the overdoneness
Why the over why the overdoneness of
Why the over why the overdoneness of the
fatal?
fatal? Huh?
Why the over why the overdoneness of the
fatal? Huh? Why
fatal? Huh? Why the
Why the over why the overdoneness of the
fatal? Huh? Why the overdoneness?
fatal? Huh? Why the overdoneness? Why
the
the extreme
the extreme of
the extreme of it?
the extreme of it? So
the extreme of it? So that
the extreme of it? So that line
the extreme of it? So that line of
evolution
evolution comes
the extreme of it? So that line of
evolution comes up.
And
And I
And I I
And I I say
And I I say I
And I I say I think
And I I say I think I
And I I say I think I think
And I I say I think I think it
And I I say I think I think it it
And I I say I think I think it it its
mastery
mastery was
And I I say I think I think it it its
mastery was at
mastery was at the
And I I say I think I think it it its
mastery was at the age
mastery was at the age of
And I I say I think I think it it its
mastery was at the age of the
mastery was at the age of the dinosaur.
Uh
happily
happily the
Uh
happily the dinosaur
happily the dinosaur got
Uh
happily the dinosaur got wiped
happily the dinosaur got wiped out
Uh
happily the dinosaur got wiped out or
none
none of
none of us
none of us would
none of us would be
none of us would be here.
none of us would be here. We'd
none of us would be here. We'd all
none of us would be here. We'd all be
eaten
eaten years
none of us would be here. We'd all be
eaten years ago.
Anyway,
Anyway, at
Anyway, at the
Anyway, at the same
Anyway, at the same time
Anyway, at the same time though
Anyway, at the same time though of
Anyway, at the same time though of the
venomous,
venomous, you
Anyway, at the same time though of the
venomous, you see
venomous, you see the
Anyway, at the same time though of the
venomous, you see the benign,
venomous, you see the benign, you
Anyway, at the same time though of the
venomous, you see the benign, you see
the
the you
the you see
the you see the
the you see the mammal,
the you see the mammal, you
the you see the mammal, you see
the you see the mammal, you see the
domestic
domestic animal.
the you see the mammal, you see the
domestic animal. The
domestic animal. The deer
the you see the mammal, you see the
domestic animal. The deer isn't
domestic animal. The deer isn't killing
anybody.
anybody. It's
anybody. It's it's
anybody. It's it's living
anybody. It's it's living off
anybody. It's it's living off the
chlorophyll,
chlorophyll, the
anybody. It's it's living off the
chlorophyll, the the
chlorophyll, the the oxygen,
anybody. It's it's living off the
chlorophyll, the the oxygen, the
chlorophyll, the the oxygen, the energy
of
of the
of the sun
of the sun and
of the sun and it
of the sun and it kills
of the sun and it kills nobody.
of the sun and it kills nobody. It
of the sun and it kills nobody. It eats
the
the top
of the sun and it kills nobody. It eats
the top off
the top off the
of the sun and it kills nobody. It eats
the top off the grass.
the top off the grass. The
of the sun and it kills nobody. It eats
the top off the grass. The grass
the top off the grass. The grass roots
remain.
remain. He
remain. He walks
remain. He walks around
remain. He walks around and
remain. He walks around and he
remain. He walks around and he does
remain. He walks around and he does his
elimination
elimination which
remain. He walks around and he does his
elimination which fertilizes
elimination which fertilizes more
remain. He walks around and he does his
elimination which fertilizes more grass.
So
So more
So more grass,
So more grass, more
So more grass, more rain,
So more grass, more rain, more
So more grass, more rain, more oxygen,
more
more chlorophyll.
So
So it's
So it's like
So it's like one,
So it's like one, the
So it's like one, the herbiviverous
So it's like one, the herbiviverous then
supports
supports life.
So it's like one, the herbiviverous then
supports life. It
supports life. It doesn't
So it's like one, the herbiviverous then
supports life. It doesn't Nobody
supports life. It doesn't Nobody has
So it's like one, the herbiviverous then
supports life. It doesn't Nobody has to
die
die for
die for a
die for a mule
die for a mule to
die for a mule to keep
die for a mule to keep on
die for a mule to keep on living.
die for a mule to keep on living. Nobody
has
has to
die for a mule to keep on living. Nobody
has to die
has to die for
die for a mule to keep on living. Nobody
has to die for a
has to die for a cow
die for a mule to keep on living. Nobody
has to die for a cow or
has to die for a cow or a
die for a mule to keep on living. Nobody
has to die for a cow or a lamb,
has to die for a cow or a lamb, a
die for a mule to keep on living. Nobody
has to die for a cow or a lamb, a sheep.
It's
It's as
It's as though
It's as though there's
It's as though there's two
It's as though there's two different
lines
lines of
It's as though there's two different
lines of evolution
lines of evolution going
It's as though there's two different
lines of evolution going on.
All
All right.
Today
Today we
All right.
Today we wanted
Today we wanted to
All right.
Today we wanted to talk.
Today we wanted to talk. We
All right.
Today we wanted to talk. We people
always
always ask,
always ask, "What
always ask, "What title
always ask, "What title are
always ask, "What title are you
always ask, "What title are you going
always ask, "What title are you going to
speak
speak about?"
always ask, "What title are you going to
speak about?" Well,
speak about?" Well, I
always ask, "What title are you going to
speak about?" Well, I never
speak about?" Well, I never really
always ask, "What title are you going to
speak about?" Well, I never really know
until
until I
until I get
until I get here.
until I get here. But
until I get here. But anyway,
until I get here. But anyway, today
until I get here. But anyway, today to
make
make them
until I get here. But anyway, today to
make them happy,
make them happy, I
until I get here. But anyway, today to
make them happy, I told
make them happy, I told them
until I get here. But anyway, today to
make them happy, I told them we're
make them happy, I told them we're going
to
to talk
to talk about
to talk about um
to talk about um what
to talk about um what was
to talk about um what was going
to talk about um what was going to
to talk about um what was going to talk
about.
What
What was
What was the
What was the name
What was the name of
What was the name of the
What was the name of the title?
What was the name of the title? Oh,
causality,
causality, right?
What was the name of the title? Oh,
causality, right? Causality.
What?
Oh,
Oh, he's
What?
Oh, he's turning
Oh, he's turning the
What?
Oh, he's turning the machine
Oh, he's turning the machine over.
Great.
uh
we
we want
we want to
we want to talk
we want to talk about
we want to talk about causality
we want to talk about causality because
eventually
eventually spiritual
we want to talk about causality because
eventually spiritual awareness
eventually spiritual awareness has
we want to talk about causality because
eventually spiritual awareness has to
eventually spiritual awareness has to do
with
with understanding
with understanding the
with understanding the nature
with understanding the nature of
creation,
creation, the
with understanding the nature of
creation, the nature
creation, the nature of
with understanding the nature of
creation, the nature of God
creation, the nature of God because
they're
they're they
they're they go
they're they go hand
they're they go hand in
they're they go hand in hand
they're they go hand in hand in
they're they go hand in hand in a
they're they go hand in hand in a way
and
and one
they're they go hand in hand in a way
and one of
and one of the
they're they go hand in hand in a way
and one of the major
and one of the major blocks
they're they go hand in hand in a way
and one of the major blocks uh
and one of the major blocks uh that
keeps
keeps people
keeps people in
keeps people in the
keeps people in the 400s
keeps people in the 400s and
keeps people in the 400s and and
keeps people in the 400s and and keeps
them
them from
keeps people in the 400s and and keeps
them from evolving
them from evolving is
keeps people in the 400s and and keeps
them from evolving is a
them from evolving is a misunderstanding
of
of the
of the word
of the word uh
of the word uh the
of the word uh the concept
of the word uh the concept concept
of the word uh the concept concept of
causality.
I
I think
I think I
I think I did
I think I did uh
I think I did uh speak
I think I did uh speak about
I think I did uh speak about it
I think I did uh speak about it in
I think I did uh speak about it in uh
power
power versus
I think I did uh speak about it in uh
power versus force
power versus force but
I think I did uh speak about it in uh
power versus force but I
power versus force but I want
I think I did uh speak about it in uh
power versus force but I want to
power versus force but I want to go
I think I did uh speak about it in uh
power versus force but I want to go into
it
it a
it a little
it a little more
it a little more differently.
it a little more differently. There
it a little more differently. There are
many
many ways
it a little more differently. There are
many ways for
many ways for spiritual
it a little more differently. There are
many ways for spiritual evolution.
I'm
I'm also
I'm also working
I'm also working on
I'm also working on another
I'm also working on another one
I'm also working on another one book
called
called radical
I'm also working on another one book
called radical reality
called radical reality all
I'm also working on another one book
called radical reality all stands
revealed
revealed in
revealed in which
revealed in which we
revealed in which we do
revealed in which we do like
revealed in which we do like a
revealed in which we do like a thousand
calibrations
calibrations of
revealed in which we do like a thousand
calibrations of everybody
calibrations of everybody of
revealed in which we do like a thousand
calibrations of everybody of any
significance
significance that
significance that ever
significance that ever lived
significance that ever lived and
significance that ever lived and and
current
current trends
significance that ever lived and and
current trends in
current trends in society
significance that ever lived and and
current trends in society rock
current trends in society rock music
significance that ever lived and and
current trends in society rock music all
the
the way
the way from
the way from Aristotle
the way from Aristotle to
current
current living
the way from Aristotle to
current living uh
current living uh creatures
the way from Aristotle to
current living uh creatures and
current living uh creatures and places
and
and it
and it creates
and it creates an
and it creates an understanding
and it creates an understanding of
and it creates an understanding of the
nature
nature of
and it creates an understanding of the
nature of consciousness
nature of consciousness and
and it creates an understanding of the
nature of consciousness and how
nature of consciousness and how it
evolved
evolved and
evolved and expressed
evolved and expressed itself
evolved and expressed itself in
evolved and expressed itself in mankind
over
over time
and
and in
and in doing
and in doing that
and in doing that we
and in doing that we also
and in doing that we also calibrated
various
various spiritual
and in doing that we also calibrated
various spiritual techniques,
various spiritual techniques, practices,
mantras,
teachers,
teachers, writings
uh
uh to
uh to get
uh to get an
uh to get an understanding
uh to get an understanding of
uh to get an understanding of how
uh to get an understanding of how does
spiritual
spiritual knowledge
uh to get an understanding of how does
spiritual knowledge evolve?
spiritual knowledge evolve? How
uh to get an understanding of how does
spiritual knowledge evolve? How does
spiritual knowledge evolve? How does it
express
express itself?
express itself? How
express itself? How is
express itself? How is it
express itself? How is it utilized
express itself? How is it utilized by
people?
people? There
express itself? How is it utilized by
people? There are
people? There are very
express itself? How is it utilized by
people? There are very significant
spiritual
spiritual teachers
spiritual teachers who
spiritual teachers who calibrated
spiritual teachers who calibrated in
spiritual teachers who calibrated in the
200s.
Well,
Well, the
Well, the most
Well, the most significant
Well, the most significant thing
Well, the most significant thing we
Well, the most significant thing we need
to
to know
Well, the most significant thing we need
to know about
to know about a
Well, the most significant thing we need
to know about a spiritual
to know about a spiritual teacher
Well, the most significant thing we need
to know about a spiritual teacher is
whether
whether they're
whether they're over
whether they're over 200.
whether they're over 200. That's
whether they're over 200. That's all
whether they're over 200. That's all I
care
care about.
whether they're over 200. That's all I
care about. If
care about. If they're
whether they're over 200. That's all I
care about. If they're over
care about. If they're over 200,
whether they're over 200. That's all I
care about. If they're over 200, they're
integrous.
integrous. If
integrous. If they're
integrous. If they're under
integrous. If they're under 200,
integrous. If they're under 200, which
there
there are
integrous. If they're under 200, which
there are some
there are some very
integrous. If they're under 200, which
there are some very famous
there are some very famous gurus
integrous. If they're under 200, which
there are some very famous gurus in
there are some very famous gurus in the
world
world that
world that are
world that are under
world that are under 200,
the
the most
world that are under 200,
the most significant
the most significant thing
world that are under 200,
the most significant thing is
the most significant thing is that
they're
they're over
they're over 200.
they're over 200. Now,
they're over 200. Now, various
understandings
understandings of
they're over 200. Now, various
understandings of of
understandings of of how
they're over 200. Now, various
understandings of of how to
understandings of of how to progress
have
have come
have come along
have come along historically,
some
some by
have come along historically,
some by religious
some by religious tradition.
have come along historically,
some by religious tradition. the
pathway
pathway to
pathway to enlightenment,
pathway to enlightenment, the
the
the pathway
pathway to enlightenment, the
the pathway to
the pathway to the
pathway to enlightenment, the
the pathway to the realization
the pathway to the realization of
pathway to enlightenment, the
the pathway to the realization of the
presence
presence of
presence of God
about
about which
presence of God
about which I
about which I speak
presence of God
about which I speak and
about which I speak and about
presence of God
about which I speak and about which
about which I speak and about which this
research
research is
research is concerned
research is concerned is
research is concerned is the
research is concerned is the pathway
research is concerned is the pathway way
through
through consciousness
research is concerned is the pathway way
through consciousness itself
through consciousness itself the
research is concerned is the pathway way
through consciousness itself the most
direct
probably
probably is
direct
probably is closest
it
it would
it would be
it would be closest
it would be closest to
it would be closest to adva
it would be closest to adva be
it would be closest to adva be closest
to
to Zen
it would be closest to adva be closest
to Zen perhaps.
uh
uh on
uh on the
uh on the other
uh on the other hand
uh on the other hand it
uh on the other hand it also
uh on the other hand it also includes
uh on the other hand it also includes an
intensity
intensity of
uh on the other hand it also includes an
intensity of devotion.
There
There are
There are ways
There are ways that
There are ways that take
There are ways that take many
There are ways that take many lifetimes
um
um and
There are ways that take many lifetimes
um and the
um and the progression
There are ways that take many lifetimes
um and the progression is
um and the progression is slow
There are ways that take many lifetimes
um and the progression is slow much
arduous
arduous work
arduous work and
arduous work and very
arduous work and very slow
arduous work and very slow progress.
A
A mantra
arduous work and very slow progress.
A mantra can
A mantra can go
arduous work and very slow progress.
A mantra can go all
A mantra can go all the
arduous work and very slow progress.
A mantra can go all the way
A mantra can go all the way from
some
some mantras
some mantras make
some mantras make you
some mantras make you go
some mantras make you go weak.
some mantras make you go weak. It's
some mantras make you go weak. It's good
to
to to
some mantras make you go weak. It's good
to to know
to to know about
some mantras make you go weak. It's good
to to know about that.
And
And uh
And uh some
And uh some are
And uh some are very
And uh some are very good.
And uh some are very good. There's
And uh some are very good. There's a
we'll
we'll just
And uh some are very good. There's a
we'll just use
we'll just use an
And uh some are very good. There's a
we'll just use an example.
we'll just use an example. The
difference
difference between
difference between and
difference between and au
difference between and au m
depending
depending on
difference between and au m
depending on which
depending on which group
difference between and au m
depending on which group you
depending on which group you go
difference between and au m
depending on which group you go to.
depending on which group you go to. One
will
will say
will say another
will say another say
will say another say right
will say another say right quite
will say another say right quite a
difference.
difference. Let's
will say another say right quite a
difference. Let's see
difference. Let's see what
will say another say right quite a
difference. Let's see what the
difference
difference is.
Is
Is over
difference is.
Is over 400.
Is
Is over
Is over 500.
M
M is
Is over 500.
M is over
M is over 600.
Is over 500.
M is over 600. Oh
M is over 600. Oh is
Is over 500.
M is over 600. Oh is 699.
Oh
Oh is
Oh is over
Oh is over 700.
Oh is over 700. Oh
Oh is over 700. Oh is
Oh is over 700. Oh is over
Oh is over 700. Oh is over 740.
Oh is over 700. Oh is over 740. Ohm
Oh is over 700. Oh is over 740. Ohm is
780.
780. Oh
Oh is over 700. Oh is over 740. Ohm is
780. Oh is
780. Oh is 900
Oh is over 700. Oh is over 740. Ohm is
780. Oh is 900 ohm
780. Oh is 900 ohm is
Oh is over 700. Oh is over 740. Ohm is
780. Oh is 900 ohm is 999.
Oh
Oh is
Oh is very
Oh is very high.
Oh is very high. Let's
Oh is very high. Let's do
Oh is very high. Let's do aum.
Is
Is over
Oh is very high. Let's do aum.
Is over 200.
Thank
Thank you.
Thank you. Some
Thank you. Some spiritual
Thank you. Some spiritual groups
Thank you. Some spiritual groups have
been
been doing
Thank you. Some spiritual groups have
been doing for
been doing for centuries
Thank you. Some spiritual groups have
been doing for centuries and
been doing for centuries and tell
Thank you. Some spiritual groups have
been doing for centuries and tell you
where
where the
where the truth
where the truth they
where the truth they get
where the truth they get nowhere.
probably
probably been
where the truth they get nowhere.
probably been loud
probably been loud and
where the truth they get nowhere.
probably been loud and joined
probably been loud and joined them
where the truth they get nowhere.
probably been loud and joined them or
somebody
there.
there. So
somebody
there. So there's
there. So there's very
somebody
there. So there's very serious
there. So there's very serious spiritual
er
er errors
er errors in
er errors in the
er errors in the works
er errors in the works of
er errors in the works of uh
er errors in the works of uh really
er errors in the works of uh really high
highly
highly esteemed
er errors in the works of uh really high
highly esteemed uh
highly esteemed uh teachers.
er errors in the works of uh really high
highly esteemed uh teachers. That
highly esteemed uh teachers. That error
is
is uh
is uh written
is uh written up.
is uh written up. I
is uh written up. I just
is uh written up. I just read
is uh written up. I just read it
is uh written up. I just read it uh
reviewed
reviewed it
is uh written up. I just read it uh
reviewed it the
reviewed it the other
is uh written up. I just read it uh
reviewed it the other day.
reviewed it the other day. Panali's
is uh written up. I just read it uh
reviewed it the other day. Panali's um
sutras
sutras uh
sutras uh yoga
sutras uh yoga sutras
sutras uh yoga sutras uh
sutras uh yoga sutras uh said
sutras uh yoga sutras uh said translated
by
h
h I
h I know
h I know who
h I know who he
h I know who he is.
h I know who he is. Um
h I know who he is. Um anyway
h I know who he is. Um anyway translated
by
by somebody
uh
uh it's
uh it's called
uh it's called intergalled
uh it's called intergalled yoga
uh it's called intergalled yoga but
uh it's called intergalled yoga but that
error
error is
uh it's called intergalled yoga but that
error is right
error is right in
uh it's called intergalled yoga but that
error is right in that
error is right in that book.
uh it's called intergalled yoga but that
error is right in that book. So
error is right in that book. So you
uh it's called intergalled yoga but that
error is right in that book. So you know
you're
you're a
you're a devote
you're a devote and
you're a devote and you
you're a devote and you read
you're a devote and you read this
you're a devote and you read this it's
by
by Sacha
you're a devote and you read this it's
by Sacha Danda
by Sacha Danda translation
you're a devote and you read this it's
by Sacha Danda translation of
by Sacha Danda translation of Pangali
you
you say
you say this
you say this has
you say this has got
you say this has got to
you say this has got to be
you say this has got to be the
you say this has got to be the truth
don't
don't believe
you say this has got to be the truth
don't believe it
don't believe it don't
you say this has got to be the truth
don't believe it don't believe
don't believe it don't believe anything
unless
unless you
unless you check
unless you check it
unless you check it out
unless you check it out yourself
unless you check it out yourself or
unless you check it out yourself or have
somebody
somebody who
unless you check it out yourself or have
somebody who understands
somebody who understands how
unless you check it out yourself or have
somebody who understands how to
somebody who understands how to check
things
things out
things out check
things out check it
things out check it out
things out check it out for
things out check it out for you
things out check it out for you which
things out check it out for you which is
one
one reason
things out check it out for you which is
one reason I'm
one reason I'm working
things out check it out for you which is
one reason I'm working on
one reason I'm working on the
things out check it out for you which is
one reason I'm working on the current
book
book which
book which will
book which will give
book which will give a
book which will give a thousand
calibrations
calibrations because
book which will give a thousand
calibrations because a
calibrations because a lot
book which will give a thousand
calibrations because a lot of
calibrations because a lot of people
don't
don't have
don't have the
don't have the time
don't have the time the
don't have the time the energy
don't have the time the energy and
they're
they're not
don't have the time the energy and
they're not really
they're not really interested
don't have the time the energy and
they're not really interested in
they're not really interested in in
kinesiology
kinesiology I
kinesiology I myself
kinesiology I myself I'm
kinesiology I myself I'm not
kinesiology I myself I'm not really
interested
interested in
kinesiology I myself I'm not really
interested in kinesiology
interested in kinesiology any
kinesiology I myself I'm not really
interested in kinesiology any more
interested in kinesiology any more than
Galileo's
Galileo's interested
Galileo's interested in
Galileo's interested in telescopes.
Galileo's interested in telescopes. He
thought
thought telescopes
Galileo's interested in telescopes. He
thought telescopes were
thought telescopes were very
Galileo's interested in telescopes. He
thought telescopes were very boring,
thought telescopes were very boring, but
they
they revealed
they revealed a
they revealed a staggeringly
they revealed a staggeringly interesting
universe,
universe, which
they revealed a staggeringly interesting
universe, which is
universe, which is what
they revealed a staggeringly interesting
universe, which is what kinesiology
universe, which is what kinesiology is
to
to me.
to me. It's
to me. It's rather
to me. It's rather tedious,
to me. It's rather tedious, but
to me. It's rather tedious, but it
reveals
reveals uh
to me. It's rather tedious, but it
reveals uh information
reveals uh information you
to me. It's rather tedious, but it
reveals uh information you can't
reveals uh information you can't get
to me. It's rather tedious, but it
reveals uh information you can't get in
any
any other
any other way.
Certain
Certain information
any other way.
Certain information is
Certain information is of
any other way.
Certain information is of itself
Certain information is of itself just
any other way.
Certain information is of itself just to
know
know it
know it uh
know it uh can
know it uh can save
know it uh can save many
know it uh can save many a
know it uh can save many a lifetime
know it uh can save many a lifetime of
spiritual
spiritual endeavor.
some
some some
some some things
some some things the
some some things the information
some some things the information itself
is
is so
some some things the information itself
is so staggering
is so staggering that
some some things the information itself
is so staggering that it
is so staggering that it instantly
some some things the information itself
is so staggering that it instantly jumps
your
your consciousness
your consciousness ahead
your consciousness ahead of
your consciousness ahead of time.
your consciousness ahead of time. I
forgot
forgot something
your consciousness ahead of time. I
forgot something to
forgot something to start
your consciousness ahead of time. I
forgot something to start on
forgot something to start on this.
your consciousness ahead of time. I
forgot something to start on this. Uh
forgot something to start on this. Uh I
have
have permission
have permission resist
have permission resist to
have permission resist to go
have permission resist to go back
have permission resist to go back to
have permission resist to go back to the
beginning
beginning it
have permission resist to go back to the
beginning it uh
beginning it uh the
have permission resist to go back to the
beginning it uh the conscious
beginning it uh the conscious level
have permission resist to go back to the
beginning it uh the conscious level of
the
the audience
the audience is
the audience is over
the audience is over 400
the audience is over 400 410
the audience is over 400 410 412
level
level is
the audience is over 400 410 412
level is 410
level is 410 411
the audience is over 400 410 412
level is 410 411 410
level is 410 411 410 to
the audience is over 400 410 412
level is 410 411 410 to 411.
level is 410 411 410 to 411. Okay,
the audience is over 400 410 412
level is 410 411 410 to 411. Okay, we
just
just remember
just remember that
just remember that for
just remember that for later.
just remember that for later. We
just remember that for later. We usually
calibrate
calibrate the
just remember that for later. We usually
calibrate the conscious
calibrate the conscious level
just remember that for later. We usually
calibrate the conscious level of
calibrate the conscious level of the
audience
audience before
audience before we
audience before we give
audience before we give the
audience before we give the lecture
audience before we give the lecture and
then
then after.
If
If it
If it goes
If it goes down,
they
they were
If it goes down,
they were okay
they were okay till
If it goes down,
they were okay till they
they were okay till they got
If it goes down,
they were okay till they got here.
Certain
Certain bits
Certain bits of
Certain bits of information
Certain bits of information um
Certain bits of information um have
Certain bits of information um have a
have
have a
Certain bits of information um have a
have a great
have a great value.
Certain bits of information um have a
have a great value. just
have a great value. just just
Certain bits of information um have a
have a great value. just just to
have a great value. just just to just
Certain bits of information um have a
have a great value. just just to just to
have
have heard
have heard it
have heard it to
have heard it to get
have heard it to get it
have heard it to get it jumps
have heard it to get it jumps you
have heard it to get it jumps you ahead
enormously.
enormously. So
have heard it to get it jumps you ahead
enormously. So usually
enormously. So usually you
have heard it to get it jumps you ahead
enormously. So usually you wait
enormously. So usually you wait till
have heard it to get it jumps you ahead
enormously. So usually you wait till the
students
students are
students are very
students are very advanced
students are very advanced and
students are very advanced and then
students are very advanced and then you
present
present these
students are very advanced and then you
present these concepts.
present these concepts. I
students are very advanced and then you
present these concepts. I say
present these concepts. I say heck
students are very advanced and then you
present these concepts. I say heck let's
put
put them
put them right
put them right in
put them right in the
put them right in the beginning
put them right in the beginning because
the
the information
put them right in the beginning because
the information itself
the information itself already
put them right in the beginning because
the information itself already is
transformative.
All
All right.
transformative.
All right. So
All right. So we
transformative.
All right. So we want
All right. So we want to
transformative.
All right. So we want to look
All right. So we want to look through
the
the illusion
the illusion of
the illusion of causality
because
because causality
the illusion of causality
because causality blocks
because causality blocks creates
the illusion of causality
because causality blocks creates a
perceptual
perceptual block
perceptual block that
perceptual block that you
perceptual block that you cannot
perceptual block that you cannot see
what
what is
perceptual block that you cannot see
what is actually
what is actually going
perceptual block that you cannot see
what is actually going on
what is actually going on and
perceptual block that you cannot see
what is actually going on and you
what is actually going on and you cannot
really
really experience
really experience the
really experience the presence
really experience the presence of
really experience the presence of God
really experience the presence of God in
a
a way.
really experience the presence of God in
a way. It's
a way. It's a
really experience the presence of God in
a way. It's a great
a way. It's a great blockade.
The
The new
The new Newtonian
The new Newtonian paradigm,
The new Newtonian paradigm, the
The new Newtonian paradigm, the world
The new Newtonian paradigm, the world of
the
the ego,
The new Newtonian paradigm, the world of
the ego, the
the ego, the world
The new Newtonian paradigm, the world of
the ego, the world of
the ego, the world of the
The new Newtonian paradigm, the world of
the ego, the world of the intellect,
the ego, the world of the intellect, the
way
way the
way the ego
way the ego is
way the ego is structured,
way the ego is structured, sees
way the ego is structured, sees a
way the ego is structured, sees a this
causing
causing a
way the ego is structured, sees a this
causing a that.
The
The whole
The whole paradigm
of
of our
The whole paradigm
of our society
of our society is
The whole paradigm
of our society is based
of our society is based on
The whole paradigm
of our society is based on a
of our society is based on a this
The whole paradigm
of our society is based on a this causes
of
of that.
of that. The
of that. The Supreme
of that. The Supreme Court
of that. The Supreme Court upholds
of that. The Supreme Court upholds it.
Scientists
Scientists verify
of that. The Supreme Court upholds it.
Scientists verify it.
Scientists verify it. It's
of that. The Supreme Court upholds it.
Scientists verify it. It's built
Scientists verify it. It's built into
the
the language.
the language. The
the language. The newspaper
the language. The newspaper headlines
say
say it.
the language. The newspaper headlines
say it. The
say it. The movies
the language. The newspaper headlines
say it. The movies reveal
say it. The movies reveal it.
the language. The newspaper headlines
say it. The movies reveal it. it
say it. The movies reveal it. it it's
all
all prevailing
all prevailing in
all prevailing in our
all prevailing in our society.
Consequently,
Consequently, becoming
all prevailing in our society.
Consequently, becoming enlightened
Consequently, becoming enlightened in
this
this world
this world is
this world is difficult
because
the
the mind,
the mind, the
the mind, the ego,
the mind, the ego, feelings,
you're
you're bared
the mind, the ego, feelings,
you're bared continuously
you're bared continuously round
the mind, the ego, feelings,
you're bared continuously round the
clock
by
by a
clock
by a paradigm
by a paradigm of
clock
by a paradigm of reality
by a paradigm of reality which
clock
by a paradigm of reality which is
by a paradigm of reality which is based
on
on duality.
on duality. There's
on duality. There's always
on duality. There's always a
on duality. There's always a this
causing
causing a
on duality. There's always a this
causing a that.
The
The whole
The whole judicial
The whole judicial system.
I
I was
The whole judicial system.
I was standing
I was standing on
The whole judicial system.
I was standing on a
I was standing on a street
The whole judicial system.
I was standing on a street corner
I was standing on a street corner and
there
there was
there was an
there was an accident
there was an accident and
there was an accident and that
there was an accident and that gave
there was an accident and that gave me
there was an accident and that gave me a
heart
heart attack,
right?
The
The court
right?
The court agrees
The court agrees pays
right?
The court agrees pays half
The court agrees pays half a
right?
The court agrees pays half a million
dollars.
dollars. Insurance
dollars. Insurance company
dollars. Insurance company pays.
dollars. Insurance company pays. We
dollars. Insurance company pays. We all
pick
pick up.
dollars. Insurance company pays. We all
pick up. So
pick up. So this
dollars. Insurance company pays. We all
pick up. So this paradigm
pick up. So this paradigm of
dollars. Insurance company pays. We all
pick up. So this paradigm of causality
the
the courts
the courts have
the courts have now
the courts have now spread
the courts have now spread so
the courts have now spread so extreme.
If
If I
the courts have now spread so extreme.
If I walk
If I walk down
the courts have now spread so extreme.
If I walk down the
If I walk down the sidewalk
the courts have now spread so extreme.
If I walk down the sidewalk out
If I walk down the sidewalk out there
and
and trip
and trip and
and trip and fall
and trip and fall and
and trip and fall and then
and trip and fall and then I
and trip and fall and then I can
and trip and fall and then I can sue
this
this place
and trip and fall and then I can sue
this place here
this place here that
and trip and fall and then I can sue
this place here that the
this place here that the sidewalk
and trip and fall and then I can sue
this place here that the sidewalk was
crooked
crooked or
crooked or too
crooked or too rough
crooked or too rough or
crooked or too rough or too
crooked or too rough or too smooth
crooked or too rough or too smooth or
there
there should
crooked or too rough or too smooth or
there should have
there should have been
crooked or too rough or too smooth or
there should have been a
there should have been a warning
crooked or too rough or too smooth or
there should have been a warning sign
there
there or
there or if
there or if there
there or if there if
there or if there if there's
there or if there if there's a
there or if there if there's a warning
sign
sign there
there or if there if there's a warning
sign there and
sign there and it's
there or if there if there's a warning
sign there and it's lit
sign there and it's lit up
there or if there if there's a warning
sign there and it's lit up it's
sign there and it's lit up it's only
there or if there if there's a warning
sign there and it's lit up it's only in
English.
English. You
English. You understand?
It's
It's not
English. You understand?
It's not in
It's not in foreign
English. You understand?
It's not in foreign languages.
It's not in foreign languages. So,
I
I mean,
I mean, I've
I mean, I've testified
I mean, I've testified in
I mean, I've testified in front
I mean, I've testified in front of
juries
juries that
I mean, I've testified in front of
juries that would
juries that would have
I mean, I've testified in front of
juries that would have agreed.
Caution,
Caution, wet
Caution, wet floor,
Caution, wet floor, but
Caution, wet floor, but it
Caution, wet floor, but it wasn't
Caution, wet floor, but it wasn't in
Spanish.
Spanish. Well,
Caution, wet floor, but it wasn't in
Spanish. Well, okay,
Spanish. Well, okay, there
Caution, wet floor, but it wasn't in
Spanish. Well, okay, there you
Spanish. Well, okay, there you go.
Caution, wet floor, but it wasn't in
Spanish. Well, okay, there you go. What
about
about if
about if I'm
about if I'm from
about if I'm from Russia?
about if I'm from Russia? Some
about if I'm from Russia? Some of
about if I'm from Russia? Some of you
got
got to
about if I'm from Russia? Some of you
got to guess
got to guess here
about if I'm from Russia? Some of you
got to guess here from
got to guess here from Russia.
about if I'm from Russia? Some of you
got to guess here from Russia. He
got to guess here from Russia. He says,
"Not
"Not in
"Not in Russian.
"Not in Russian. I'm
"Not in Russian. I'm suing."
"Not in Russian. I'm suing." So,
"Not in Russian. I'm suing." So, you'd
have
have to
"Not in Russian. I'm suing." So, you'd
have to have
have to have it
"Not in Russian. I'm suing." So, you'd
have to have it in
have to have it in every
"Not in Russian. I'm suing." So, you'd
have to have it in every language
have to have it in every language on
"Not in Russian. I'm suing." So, you'd
have to have it in every language on the
planet.
planet. Then
planet. Then he'd
planet. Then he'd say,
planet. Then he'd say, "Well,
planet. Then he'd say, "Well, I
planet. Then he'd say, "Well, I didn't
see
see it."
planet. Then he'd say, "Well, I didn't
see it." Well,
see it." Well, it
planet. Then he'd say, "Well, I didn't
see it." Well, it wasn't
see it." Well, it wasn't lit
planet. Then he'd say, "Well, I didn't
see it." Well, it wasn't lit up.
see it." Well, it wasn't lit up. Oh,
planet. Then he'd say, "Well, I didn't
see it." Well, it wasn't lit up. Oh, it
wasn't
wasn't lit
wasn't lit up.
wasn't lit up. Well,
wasn't lit up. Well, we'll
wasn't lit up. Well, we'll have
wasn't lit up. Well, we'll have to
wasn't lit up. Well, we'll have to give
him
him an
wasn't lit up. Well, we'll have to give
him an award,
him an award, right?
wasn't lit up. Well, we'll have to give
him an award, right? Wasn't
him an award, right? Wasn't lit
wasn't lit up. Well, we'll have to give
him an award, right? Wasn't lit up.
him an award, right? Wasn't lit up. It
wasn't
wasn't in
wasn't in every
wasn't in every foreign
wasn't in every foreign language.
wasn't in every foreign language. How
about
about the
wasn't in every foreign language. How
about the size?
about the size? The
wasn't in every foreign language. How
about the size? The letters
about the size? The letters are
wasn't in every foreign language. How
about the size? The letters are only
this
this big
this big and
this big and I
this big and I had
this big and I had trouble
this big and I had trouble seeing
this big and I had trouble seeing it.
The
The letter
this big and I had trouble seeing it.
The letter should
The letter should be
this big and I had trouble seeing it.
The letter should be this
The letter should be this big.
this big and I had trouble seeing it.
The letter should be this big. The
The letter should be this big. The court
jury.
jury. So
jury. So you
jury. So you see
jury. So you see the
jury. So you see the how
jury. So you see the how bizarre.
jury. So you see the how bizarre. So
jury. So you see the how bizarre. So our
society
society becomes
jury. So you see the how bizarre. So our
society becomes so
society becomes so bizarre
jury. So you see the how bizarre. So our
society becomes so bizarre because
everything
everything is
everything is assumed
everything is assumed to
everything is assumed to be
everything is assumed to be a
everything is assumed to be a cause.
everything is assumed to be a cause. The
minute
minute you
everything is assumed to be a cause. The
minute you say
minute you say something
everything is assumed to be a cause. The
minute you say something is
minute you say something is a
everything is assumed to be a cause. The
minute you say something is a cause,
minute you say something is a cause, you
imply
imply that
imply that it's
imply that it's a
imply that it's a fault.
imply that it's a fault. It's
imply that it's a fault. It's a
imply that it's a fault. It's a fault.
It's
It's a
imply that it's a fault. It's a fault.
It's a fault.
It's a fault. If
imply that it's a fault. It's a fault.
It's a fault. If the
It's a fault. If the earth
imply that it's a fault. It's a fault.
It's a fault. If the earth is
It's a fault. If the earth is warming,
it's
it's somebody's
it's somebody's fault.
it's somebody's fault. Let's
it's somebody's fault. Let's get
it's somebody's fault. Let's get rid
it's somebody's fault. Let's get rid of
the
the earth
it's somebody's fault. Let's get rid of
the earth is
the earth is warming
it's somebody's fault. Let's get rid of
the earth is warming right
the earth is warming right now.
it's somebody's fault. Let's get rid of
the earth is warming right now. Okay.
Uh,
Uh, the
Uh, the proposition
Uh, the proposition that
Uh, the proposition that the
Uh, the proposition that the globe
Uh, the proposition that the globe is
warming
warming up
Uh, the proposition that the globe is
warming up is
warming up is correct.
Uh, the proposition that the globe is
warming up is correct. Is
warming up is correct. Is it?
Uh, the proposition that the globe is
warming up is correct. Is it? Thank
warming up is correct. Is it? Thank you.
It's
It's all
It's all BS.
It's all BS. It's
It's all BS. It's all
It's all BS. It's all political
It's all BS. It's all political crap.
The
The Institute
It's all BS. It's all political crap.
The Institute for
The Institute for Science
It's all BS. It's all political crap.
The Institute for Science and
The Institute for Science and the
It's all BS. It's all political crap.
The Institute for Science and the Public
Interest
Interest is
Interest is wacko.
Interest is wacko. And
Interest is wacko. And they
Interest is wacko. And they deal
Interest is wacko. And they deal in
hysteria.
hysteria. You
Interest is wacko. And they deal in
hysteria. You know,
hysteria. You know, smoke
Interest is wacko. And they deal in
hysteria. You know, smoke a
hysteria. You know, smoke a cigarette,
you're
you're going
you're going to
you're going to die.
you're going to die. Oh
you're going to die. Oh my
you're going to die. Oh my god,
you're going to die. Oh my god, the
public
public hysteria.
you're going to die. Oh my god, the
public hysteria. Let's
public hysteria. Let's just
you're going to die. Oh my god, the
public hysteria. Let's just ask
public hysteria. Let's just ask about
that.
There's
There's more
that.
There's more hydrocarbons
There's more hydrocarbons and
that.
There's more hydrocarbons and noxious
gases
gases coming
gases coming from
gases coming from the
gases coming from the exhaust
gases coming from the exhaust of
gases coming from the exhaust of the
ordinary
ordinary car
gases coming from the exhaust of the
ordinary car than
ordinary car than a
gases coming from the exhaust of the
ordinary car than a whole
ordinary car than a whole box
gases coming from the exhaust of the
ordinary car than a whole box of
ordinary car than a whole box of Cuban
cigars.
cigars. Resist.
Why
Why worry
cigars. Resist.
Why worry about
Why worry about smoking?
cigars. Resist.
Why worry about smoking? You
Why worry about smoking? You get
cigars. Resist.
Why worry about smoking? You get in
Why worry about smoking? You get in your
car
car and
car and you're
car and you're exposing
car and you're exposing yourself
car and you're exposing yourself to
car and you're exposing yourself to more
hydrocarbons.
hydrocarbons. If
car and you're exposing yourself to more
hydrocarbons. If you
hydrocarbons. If you smoke
car and you're exposing yourself to more
hydrocarbons. If you smoke the
hydrocarbons. If you smoke the you
car and you're exposing yourself to more
hydrocarbons. If you smoke the you might
as
as well
as well smoke
as well smoke a
as well smoke a box
as well smoke a box of
as well smoke a box of car
as well smoke a box of car Cuban
as well smoke a box of car Cuban cigars
because
because either
as well smoke a box of car Cuban cigars
because either that
because either that or
as well smoke a box of car Cuban cigars
because either that or take
because either that or take an
as well smoke a box of car Cuban cigars
because either that or take an electric
bus.
And
And people
bus.
And people live
And people live next
bus.
And people live next to
And people live next to the
bus.
And people live next to the parkway.
They
They might
They might as
They might as well
They might as well chain
They might as well chain smoke
They might as well chain smoke cigars
all
all the
They might as well chain smoke cigars
all the way
all the way around
They might as well chain smoke cigars
all the way around because
all the way around because just
breathing
breathing in
breathing in and
breathing in and out.
breathing in and out. But
breathing in and out. But all
breathing in and out. But all the
hysteria
hysteria is
breathing in and out. But all the
hysteria is about
hysteria is about smoking
breathing in and out. But all the
hysteria is about smoking and
hysteria is about smoking and you
breathing in and out. But all the
hysteria is about smoking and you don't
hear
hear any
hear any hysteria
hear any hysteria about
hear any hysteria about the
hear any hysteria about the emission.
It's
It's automobiles
hear any hysteria about the emission.
It's automobiles in
It's automobiles in the
hear any hysteria about the emission.
It's automobiles in the United
It's automobiles in the United States
that
that are
that are causing
that are causing all
that are causing all lung
that are causing all lung cancer.
that are causing all lung cancer. I
that are causing all lung cancer. I mean
it's
it's so
that are causing all lung cancer. I mean
it's so obvious
it's so obvious it's
that are causing all lung cancer. I mean
it's so obvious it's you
it's so obvious it's you know
that are causing all lung cancer. I mean
it's so obvious it's you know it's
it's so obvious it's you know it's like
seeing
seeing this
seeing this here.
All right.
So
So now
So now causality
So now causality is
So now causality is a
So now causality is a very
So now causality is a very uh
So now causality is a very uh important
roadblock.
roadblock. It's
So now causality is a very uh important
roadblock. It's a
roadblock. It's a major
So now causality is a very uh important
roadblock. It's a major roadblock.
roadblock. It's a major roadblock. It's
practically
practically nobody
practically nobody gets
practically nobody gets beyond
practically nobody gets beyond the
practically nobody gets beyond the 400s
in
in our
practically nobody gets beyond the 400s
in our society.
What
What percent
What percent get
What percent get beyond
What percent get beyond the
What percent get beyond the 400s?
What percent get beyond the 400s? H
What percent get beyond the 400s? H in
our
our society,
What percent get beyond the 400s? H in
our society, current
our society, current society,
uh
uh over
uh over 1%
uh over 1% of
uh over 1% of the
uh over 1% of the population
uh over 1% of the population gets
uh over 1% of the population gets beyond
400s,
400s, 2%.
It's
It's a
It's a very
It's a very rare
It's a very rare to
It's a very rare to get
It's a very rare to get beyond
It's a very rare to get beyond the
It's a very rare to get beyond the 400s.
Even
Even uh
It's a very rare to get beyond the 400s.
Even uh Freud
Even uh Freud didn't
It's a very rare to get beyond the 400s.
Even uh Freud didn't make
Even uh Freud didn't make it,
It's a very rare to get beyond the 400s.
Even uh Freud didn't make it, Einstein,
Sir
Sir Isaac
Sir Isaac Newton,
Sir Isaac Newton, Bacon,
Sir Isaac Newton, Bacon, all
Sir Isaac Newton, Bacon, all the
Sir Isaac Newton, Bacon, all the great
minds.
490.
490. The
490. The intellect
490. The intellect is
490. The intellect is the
490. The intellect is the great
490. The intellect is the great block.
And
And the
490. The intellect is the great block.
And the reason
And the reason it's
490. The intellect is the great block.
And the reason it's such
And the reason it's such a
490. The intellect is the great block.
And the reason it's such a great
And the reason it's such a great block,
it
it it
it it it's
it it it's structured.
it it it's structured. It's
it it it's structured. It's whole
it it it's structured. It's whole its
whole
whole basis
it it it's structured. It's whole its
whole basis is
whole basis is causality.
There's
There's always
There's always a
There's always a this
There's always a this causing
There's always a this causing a
There's always a this causing a that.
That's
That's a
There's always a this causing a that.
That's a dualistic
That's a dualistic perception.
There's always a this causing a that.
That's a dualistic perception. That's
called
called dualism.
called dualism. A
called dualism. A this
called dualism. A this and
called dualism. A this and a
called dualism. A this and a that.
That's
That's why
called dualism. A this and a that.
That's why we
That's why we tried
called dualism. A this and a that.
That's why we tried to
That's why we tried to wipe
called dualism. A this and a that.
That's why we tried to wipe out
That's why we tried to wipe out duality
when
when it
when it comes
when it comes to
when it comes to the
when it comes to the map
when it comes to the map of
consciousness.
consciousness. There's
when it comes to the map of
consciousness. There's no
consciousness. There's no good
when it comes to the map of
consciousness. There's no good and
consciousness. There's no good and evil
there.
there. It's
there. It's all
there. It's all a
there. It's all a gradation.
there. It's all a gradation. There's
there. It's all a gradation. There's no
opposites.
There's
There's a
There's a this
There's a this causing
There's a this causing a
There's a this causing a that.
What
What we
There's a this causing a that.
What we did
What we did in
There's a this causing a that.
What we did in explaining
What we did in explaining how
There's a this causing a that.
What we did in explaining how we
What we did in explaining how we were
going
going to
going to prove
going to prove the
going to prove the map
going to prove the map of
going to prove the map of consciousness
is
is applicable
going to prove the map of consciousness
is applicable to
is applicable to all
going to prove the map of consciousness
is applicable to all seeming
is applicable to all seeming dualities.
In
In a
In a duality,
In a duality, there's
In a duality, there's only
In a duality, there's only one
In a duality, there's only one variable.
And
it
it goes
it goes like
it goes like this.
it goes like this. From
it goes like this. From intense
it goes like this. From intense to
it goes like this. From intense to less
intense.
intense. There
it goes like this. From intense to less
intense. There are
intense. There are not
it goes like this. From intense to less
intense. There are not two
intense. There are not two variables.
There
There is
There is not
There is not two
There is not two variables.
There is not two variables. Good
There is not two variables. Good versus
evil.
Hot
Hot versus
Hot versus cold.
Hot versus cold. Cold
Hot versus cold. Cold is
Hot versus cold. Cold is not
Hot versus cold. Cold is not the
opposite
opposite of
Hot versus cold. Cold is not the
opposite of hot.
Hot
Hot has
Hot has no
Hot has no opposite.
Hot has no opposite. Heat
Hot has no opposite. Heat is
Hot has no opposite. Heat is either
there
there or
Hot has no opposite. Heat is either
there or not
there or not there.
Hot has no opposite. Heat is either
there or not there. But
there or not there. But that
Hot has no opposite. Heat is either
there or not there. But that doesn't
make
make it
make it its
make it its opposite.
Electricity
Electricity is
make it its opposite.
Electricity is either
Electricity is either in
make it its opposite.
Electricity is either in the
Electricity is either in the wire
make it its opposite.
Electricity is either in the wire or
Electricity is either in the wire or it
is
is not
is not in
is not in the
is not in the wire.
is not in the wire. Electricity
is not in the wire. Electricity doesn't
have
have an
is not in the wire. Electricity doesn't
have an opposite
have an opposite called
no
no electric.
You
You can't
no electric.
You can't send
You can't send no
no electric.
You can't send no electricity
You can't send no electricity down
no electric.
You can't send no electricity down a
wire.
wire. You
wire. You can
wire. You can only
wire. You can only send
wire. You can only send electricity.
This
This is
wire. You can only send electricity.
This is the
This is the whole
wire. You can only send electricity.
This is the whole key.
This is the whole key. If
wire. You can only send electricity.
This is the whole key. If you
This is the whole key. If you just
wire. You can only send electricity.
This is the whole key. If you just get
what
what I'm
what I'm saying
what I'm saying today,
what I'm saying today, it
what I'm saying today, it advances
what I'm saying today, it advances your
consciousness
consciousness enormously.
Things
Things are
Things are more
Things are more or
Things are more or less
Things are more or less one
Things are more or less one variable.
There
There are
Things are more or less one variable.
There are not
There are not two
Things are more or less one variable.
There are not two variables.
How
How much
How much absence
How much absence of
How much absence of love
must
must there
How much absence of love
must there be
must there be before
How much absence of love
must there be before your
must there be before your perception
would
would say,
would say, "Well,
would say, "Well, that's
would say, "Well, that's evil."
would say, "Well, that's evil." That
depends,
depends, right?
would say, "Well, that's evil." That
depends, right? Most
depends, right? Most of
would say, "Well, that's evil." That
depends, right? Most of the
depends, right? Most of the world
would say, "Well, that's evil." That
depends, right? Most of the world right
now
now would
now would say
now would say they've
now would say they've been
now would say they've been loud
now would say they've been loud as
now would say they've been loud as evil.
But
But I'm
now would say they've been loud as evil.
But I'm sure
But I'm sure there's
now would say they've been loud as evil.
But I'm sure there's a
But I'm sure there's a lot
now would say they've been loud as evil.
But I'm sure there's a lot of
But I'm sure there's a lot of Islamic
zealots
zealots that
zealots that consider
zealots that consider him
zealots that consider him a
zealots that consider him a hero,
zealots that consider him a hero, right?
So,
So, you're
zealots that consider him a hero, right?
So, you're always
So, you're always dealing
zealots that consider him a hero, right?
So, you're always dealing with
So, you're always dealing with only
zealots that consider him a hero, right?
So, you're always dealing with only a
arbitrary
arbitrary perception.
arbitrary perception. So
arbitrary perception. So the
arbitrary perception. So the world
arbitrary perception. So the world of
duality
duality then
arbitrary perception. So the world of
duality then is
duality then is the
arbitrary perception. So the world of
duality then is the product
duality then is the product of
arbitrary perception. So the world of
duality then is the product of an
arbitrary
arbitrary positionality.
An
An arbitrary
arbitrary positionality.
An arbitrary positionality.
There
There is
There is no
There is no this
There is no this causing
There is no this causing that.
There is no this causing that. That
There is no this causing that. That is
all
all a
There is no this causing that. That is
all a bizarre
all a bizarre illusion.
There is no this causing that. That is
all a bizarre illusion. There
all a bizarre illusion. There is
There is no this causing that. That is
all a bizarre illusion. There is the
unfoldment
unfoldment of
unfoldment of the
unfoldment of the universe
unfoldment of the universe as
unfoldment of the universe as it
proceeds
proceeds thusly.
If
If we
If we look
If we look for
If we look for a
If we look for a cause,
If we look for a cause, let's
If we look for a cause, let's take
If we look for a cause, let's take cause
as
as far
If we look for a cause, let's take cause
as far as
as far as we
If we look for a cause, let's take cause
as far as we can
as far as we can in
If we look for a cause, let's take cause
as far as we can in the
as far as we can in the logical
If we look for a cause, let's take cause
as far as we can in the logical world.
For
For a
For a speck
For a speck of
For a speck of dust
For a speck of dust to
For a speck of dust to be
For a speck of dust to be right
For a speck of dust to be right where
For a speck of dust to be right where it
is.
is. There
For a speck of dust to be right where it
is. There it
is. There it is
For a speck of dust to be right where it
is. There it is right
is. There it is right there.
For a speck of dust to be right where it
is. There it is right there. See
is. There it is right there. See that
speck
speck of
speck of dust?
speck of dust? Anyway,
speck of dust? Anyway, that
speck of dust? Anyway, that that
speck of dust? Anyway, that that speck
of
of dust.
It's
It's all
It's all in
It's all in your
It's all in your head.
It's all in your head. There's
It's all in your head. There's no
It's all in your head. There's no speck
of
of dust
for
for this
for this speck
for this speck of
for this speck of dust.
for this speck of dust. What
for this speck of dust. What causes
for this speck of dust. What causes this
p?
p? This
for this speck of dust. What causes this
p? This thing
p? This thing is
for this speck of dust. What causes this
p? This thing is something
p? This thing is something simple.
for this speck of dust. What causes this
p? This thing is something simple. Speck
of
of dust.
of dust. We're
of dust. We're not
of dust. We're not talking
of dust. We're not talking about
of dust. We're not talking about a
of dust. We're not talking about a whole
industrial
industrial complex
of dust. We're not talking about a whole
industrial complex or
industrial complex or the
of dust. We're not talking about a whole
industrial complex or the political
structure
structure United
structure United States
structure United States or
structure United States or something.
We're
We're just
structure United States or something.
We're just talking
We're just talking about
structure United States or something.
We're just talking about one
We're just talking about one little
lousy
lousy piece
lousy piece of
lousy piece of dust.
lousy piece of dust. For
lousy piece of dust. For this
lousy piece of dust. For this little
piece
piece of
lousy piece of dust. For this little
piece of dust
piece of dust to
lousy piece of dust. For this little
piece of dust to be
piece of dust to be here,
lousy piece of dust. For this little
piece of dust to be here, what
piece of dust to be here, what is
lousy piece of dust. For this little
piece of dust to be here, what is the
cause?
cause? Well,
cause? Well, the
cause? Well, the cause
cause? Well, the cause would,
cause? Well, the cause would, you
cause? Well, the cause would, you know,
it
it would
cause? Well, the cause would, you know,
it would depend
it would depend on
cause? Well, the cause would, you know,
it would depend on the
it would depend on the barometric
pressure
pressure today.
pressure today. It
pressure today. It would
pressure today. It would depend
pressure today. It would depend on
pressure today. It would depend on the
movement
movement of
pressure today. It would depend on the
movement of the
movement of the air
pressure today. It would depend on the
movement of the air in
movement of the air in this
pressure today. It would depend on the
movement of the air in this room,
movement of the air in this room, which
would
would depend
would depend on
would depend on the
would depend on the temperature,
would depend on the temperature, which
would
would depend
would depend on the temperature, which
would depend on
would depend on how
would depend on the temperature, which
would depend on how many
would depend on how many people
would depend on the temperature, which
would depend on how many people are
here,
here, and
here, and the
here, and the dimensions
here, and the dimensions of
here, and the dimensions of the
here, and the dimensions of the room.
here, and the dimensions of the room. It
also
also depend
here, and the dimensions of the room. It
also depend for
also depend for a
here, and the dimensions of the room. It
also depend for a room
also depend for a room to
here, and the dimensions of the room. It
also depend for a room to be
also depend for a room to be here.
here, and the dimensions of the room. It
also depend for a room to be here. There
has
has to
has to be
has to be a
has to be a land.
has to be a land. There
has to be a land. There has
has to be a land. There has to
has to be a land. There has to be a
state
state for
has to be a land. There has to be a
state for a
state for a county
has to be a land. There has to be a
state for a county to
state for a county to be
has to be a land. There has to be a
state for a county to be in.
state for a county to be in. There
has to be a land. There has to be a
state for a county to be in. There has
to
to be
to be a
to be a planet
to be a planet for
to be a planet for that
to be a planet for that to
to be a planet for that to be
to be a planet for that to be on.
to be a planet for that to be on. That
planet
planet is
to be a planet for that to be on. That
planet is not
planet is not alone.
to be a planet for that to be on. That
planet is not alone. The
planet is not alone. The universe
to be a planet for that to be on. That
planet is not alone. The universe has
got
got to
got to be
got to be whirling
got to be whirling around
got to be whirling around with
got to be whirling around with other
universes.
universes. And
got to be whirling around with other
universes. And for
universes. And for the
got to be whirling around with other
universes. And for the planet
universes. And for the planet to
got to be whirling around with other
universes. And for the planet to be
where
where it
where it is
where it is so
where it is so that
where it is so that this
where it is so that this state
where it is so that this state can
where it is so that this state can be
where
where this
where it is so that this state can be
where this county
where this county is,
where it is so that this state can be
where this county is, where
where this county is, where this
building
building is,
building is, where
building is, where these
building is, where these air
building is, where these air currents
are,
are, and
building is, where these air currents
are, and all
are, and all these
building is, where these air currents
are, and all these people
are, and all these people are.
building is, where these air currents
are, and all these people are. And
are, and all these people are. And this
speaker
speaker here
speaker here pointing
speaker here pointing his
speaker here pointing his finger
speaker here pointing his finger up
speaker here pointing his finger up in
the
the air.
That's
That's all
That's all the
That's all the due
That's all the due to
That's all the due to the
That's all the due to the evolution
That's all the due to the evolution of
all
all of
That's all the due to the evolution of
all of preceding
all of preceding time,
That's all the due to the evolution of
all of preceding time, is
all of preceding time, is it
That's all the due to the evolution of
all of preceding time, is it not?
all of preceding time, is it not? All
That's all the due to the evolution of
all of preceding time, is it not? All of
preceding
preceding time
preceding time had
preceding time had to
preceding time had to evolve
preceding time had to evolve for
preceding time had to evolve for all
preceding time had to evolve for all the
planets
planets to
preceding time had to evolve for all the
planets to be
planets to be where
preceding time had to evolve for all the
planets to be where they
planets to be where they are.
preceding time had to evolve for all the
planets to be where they are. For
planets to be where they are. For the
universe
universe to
universe to be
universe to be where
universe to be where it
universe to be where it is.
universe to be where it is. So
universe to be where it is. So that
universe to be where it is. So that this
state
state can
universe to be where it is. So that this
state can be
state can be this
universe to be where it is. So that this
state can be this place
state can be this place on
universe to be where it is. So that this
state can be this place on the
state can be this place on the globe
universe to be where it is. So that this
state can be this place on the globe at
this
this point
this point in
this point in time
this point in time where
this point in time where this
this point in time where this barometric
pressure
pressure and
this point in time where this barometric
pressure and the
pressure and the atmospheric
this point in time where this barometric
pressure and the atmospheric pressure
and
and these
and these temperatures
and these temperatures and
and these temperatures and gradations
and
and this
and these temperatures and gradations
and this light
and this light coming
and these temperatures and gradations
and this light coming down
and this light coming down and
and these temperatures and gradations
and this light coming down and making
little
little air
little air currents
little air currents and
little air currents and the
little air currents and the breath
little air currents and the breath from
my
my speaking
little air currents and the breath from
my speaking voice.
my speaking voice. There's
little air currents and the breath from
my speaking voice. There's an
my speaking voice. There's an infinite
number
number of
number of finite
number of finite causes
acting
acting in
number of finite causes
acting in concert
acting in concert throughout
number of finite causes
acting in concert throughout all
acting in concert throughout all of
time.
time. All
time. All of
time. All of time
time. All of time has
time. All of time has to
time. All of time has to have
time. All of time has to have occurred
up
up to
time. All of time has to have occurred
up to the
up to the moment
time. All of time has to have occurred
up to the moment for
up to the moment for this
time. All of time has to have occurred
up to the moment for this little
up to the moment for this little speck.
Now
Now you
Now you go
Now you go to
Now you go to court
Now you go to court and
Now you go to court and tell
Now you go to court and tell me
Now you go to court and tell me who
Now you go to court and tell me who are
you
you going
Now you go to court and tell me who are
you going to
you going to sue.
This
This idiot
This idiot had
This idiot had to
This idiot had to eat
This idiot had to eat a
This idiot had to eat a lousy
This idiot had to eat a lousy diet
This idiot had to eat a lousy diet for
This idiot had to eat a lousy diet for a
lot
lot of
This idiot had to eat a lousy diet for a
lot of years
lot of years to
This idiot had to eat a lousy diet for a
lot of years to be
lot of years to be standing
This idiot had to eat a lousy diet for a
lot of years to be standing there
lot of years to be standing there in
This idiot had to eat a lousy diet for a
lot of years to be standing there in the
street
street corn
street corn getting
street corn getting knocked
street corn getting knocked over
street corn getting knocked over by
street corn getting knocked over by just
a
a loud
street corn getting knocked over by just
a loud noise
a loud noise of
street corn getting knocked over by just
a loud noise of an
a loud noise of an accident.
street corn getting knocked over by just
a loud noise of an accident. You
what
what I
what I mean?
what I mean? What
what I mean? What about
what I mean? What about what's
what I mean? What about what's he
what I mean? What about what's he been
eating
eating for
what I mean? What about what's he been
eating for 66
eating for 66 years
what I mean? What about what's he been
eating for 66 years that
eating for 66 years that he's
what I mean? What about what's he been
eating for 66 years that he's loaded
with
with so
with so much
with so much cholesterol
with so much cholesterol and
with so much cholesterol and why
with so much cholesterol and why does
with so much cholesterol and why does he
overreact
overreact with
with so much cholesterol and why does he
overreact with all
overreact with all that
with so much cholesterol and why does he
overreact with all that adrenaline?
overreact with all that adrenaline? I
mean,
mean, when
mean, when something
mean, when something a
mean, when something a loud
mean, when something a loud noise
mean, when something a loud noise goes
off
off near
mean, when something a loud noise goes
off near me,
off near me, I
mean, when something a loud noise goes
off near me, I don't
off near me, I don't even
mean, when something a loud noise goes
off near me, I don't even respond
off near me, I don't even respond to
mean, when something a loud noise goes
off near me, I don't even respond to it.
That
That happens
That happens at
That happens at about
That happens at about 600.
That happens at about 600. You
That happens at about 600. You suddenly
stop
stop responding
That happens at about 600. You suddenly
stop responding to
stop responding to loud
That happens at about 600. You suddenly
stop responding to loud noises.
stop responding to loud noises. I
know
know why.
know why. They're
know why. They're just
know why. They're just in
know why. They're just in the
know why. They're just in the periphery.
Anyway,
Anyway, they
know why. They're just in the periphery.
Anyway, they don't
Anyway, they don't affect
know why. They're just in the periphery.
Anyway, they don't affect you
Anyway, they don't affect you because
you
you is
you is everywhere
you is everywhere that
you is everywhere that is.
you is everywhere that is. So,
you is everywhere that is. So, it's
you is everywhere that is. So, it's not
a
a threat.
you is everywhere that is. So, it's not
a threat. Oh,
a threat. Oh, I
you is everywhere that is. So, it's not
a threat. Oh, I see
a threat. Oh, I see why.
you is everywhere that is. So, it's not
a threat. Oh, I see why. Because
a threat. Oh, I see why. Because Okay.
You're
You're not
You're not in
You're not in a
You're not in a specific
You're not in a specific place.
You're not in a specific place. So
therefore,
therefore, yeah,
You're not in a specific place. So
therefore, yeah, you're
therefore, yeah, you're under
You're not in a specific place. So
therefore, yeah, you're under attack.
Yeah.
Yeah. Anyhow,
Yeah. Anyhow, we
Yeah. Anyhow, we want
Yeah. Anyhow, we want to
Yeah. Anyhow, we want to get
Yeah. Anyhow, we want to get rid
Yeah. Anyhow, we want to get rid of
causality.
The
The cause
The cause even
The cause even within
The cause even within the
The cause even within the linear
The cause even within the linear domain
of
of anything
The cause even within the linear domain
of anything is
of anything is the
The cause even within the linear domain
of anything is the totality
of anything is the totality of
The cause even within the linear domain
of anything is the totality of all
of anything is the totality of all that
is
is throughout
is throughout all
is throughout all of
is throughout all of time.
That
That is
is throughout all of time.
That is the
That is the cause
is throughout all of time.
That is the cause of
That is the cause of anything.
is throughout all of time.
That is the cause of anything. The
speaker
speaker is
speaker is getting
speaker is getting impatient
speaker is getting impatient because
speaker is getting impatient because uh
he's
he's afraid
speaker is getting impatient because uh
he's afraid his
he's afraid his battery's
speaker is getting impatient because uh
he's afraid his battery's running
he's afraid his battery's running out.
I
I think
I think I
I think I have
I think I have all
I think I have all these
I think I have all these switches
I think I have all these switches on
I think I have all these switches on and
I'm
I'm ready
I think I have all these switches on and
I'm ready to
I'm ready to go.
>> All
>> All right,
>> All right, let's
>> All right, let's go.
>> Well,
>> Well, we
>> All right, let's go.
>> Well, we had
>> Well, we had a
>> All right, let's go.
>> Well, we had a couple
>> Well, we had a couple of
>> All right, let's go.
>> Well, we had a couple of questions
coming
coming up
coming up during
coming up during the
coming up during the intermission
coming up during the intermission that
uh
uh we
uh we we
uh we we most
uh we we most of
uh we we most of these
uh we we most of these questions
uh we we most of these questions that
you
you have
uh we we most of these questions that
you have in
you have in mind
uh we we most of these questions that
you have in mind will
you have in mind will be
uh we we most of these questions that
you have in mind will be answered.
I
I forgot
I forgot to
I forgot to tell
I forgot to tell you
I forgot to tell you what
I forgot to tell you what our
I forgot to tell you what our format
I forgot to tell you what our format was
going
going to
I forgot to tell you what our format was
going to be
going to be this
I forgot to tell you what our format was
going to be this morning.
going to be this morning. We
I forgot to tell you what our format was
going to be this morning. We would
going to be this morning. We would start
with
with a
with a lecture
with a lecture then
with a lecture then we'll
with a lecture then we'll have
with a lecture then we'll have a
with a lecture then we'll have a break
then
then we'll
with a lecture then we'll have a break
then we'll have
then we'll have um
with a lecture then we'll have a break
then we'll have um resumption
then we'll have um resumption of
with a lecture then we'll have a break
then we'll have um resumption of lecture
and
and then
and then later
and then later today
uh
uh we'll
and then later today
uh we'll have
uh we'll have questions
and then later today
uh we'll have questions and
uh we'll have questions and answers
and then later today
uh we'll have questions and answers uh
we'll
we'll end
we'll end up
we'll end up with
we'll end up with sort
we'll end up with sort of
we'll end up with sort of a
we'll end up with sort of a workshop
from
from 4
we'll end up with sort of a workshop
from 4 to
from 4 to 5
we'll end up with sort of a workshop
from 4 to 5 of
from 4 to 5 of uh
we'll end up with sort of a workshop
from 4 to 5 of uh people
from 4 to 5 of uh people who
we'll end up with sort of a workshop
from 4 to 5 of uh people who want
from 4 to 5 of uh people who want to
review
review kinesiology
review kinesiology people
review kinesiology people have
review kinesiology people have specific
questions
and
and um
and um everybody
and um everybody who
and um everybody who wants
and um everybody who wants to
and um everybody who wants to um
and um everybody who wants to um say
hello
hello to
and um everybody who wants to um say
hello to me
hello to me and
and um everybody who wants to um say
hello to me and we
hello to me and we will
and um everybody who wants to um say
hello to me and we will hand
hello to me and we will hand out
and um everybody who wants to um say
hello to me and we will hand out maybe
some
some personal
some personal messages
some personal messages we'll
We'll
We'll we'll
some personal messages we'll
We'll we'll talk
We'll we'll talk to
some personal messages we'll
We'll we'll talk to everyone.
We'll we'll talk to everyone. The
some personal messages we'll
We'll we'll talk to everyone. The reason
the
the reason
the reason for
the reason for these
the reason for these uh
the reason for these uh uh
the reason for these uh uh gettogethers
is
is because
the reason for these uh uh gettogethers
is because uh
is because uh over
the reason for these uh uh gettogethers
is because uh over the
is because uh over the years
the reason for these uh uh gettogethers
is because uh over the years we've
gotten
gotten innumerable
gotten innumerable requests
gotten innumerable requests for
workshops
and
and I
and I don't
and I don't do
and I don't do workshops.
and I don't do workshops. Um
so
so we've
and I don't do workshops. Um
so we've had
so we've had many
and I don't do workshops. Um
so we've had many individual
so we've had many individual visitors
but
but the
but the requests
but the requests are
but the requests are so
but the requests are so numerous
uh
uh they
but the requests are so numerous
uh they can't
uh they can't we
but the requests are so numerous
uh they can't we can't
uh they can't we can't possibly
but the requests are so numerous
uh they can't we can't possibly meet
them
them all.
them all. So
them all. So um
them all. So um we
them all. So um we thought
them all. So um we thought if
them all. So um we thought if we
them all. So um we thought if we have
them all. So um we thought if we have a
regularly
regularly scheduled
them all. So um we thought if we have a
regularly scheduled once
regularly scheduled once a
them all. So um we thought if we have a
regularly scheduled once a month
regularly scheduled once a month for
them all. So um we thought if we have a
regularly scheduled once a month for a
year
year that
year that would
year that would give
year that would give most
year that would give most people
year that would give most people an
opportunity
opportunity uh
year that would give most people an
opportunity uh and
opportunity uh and those
year that would give most people an
opportunity uh and those who
opportunity uh and those who miss
certain
certain lectures
certain lectures we'd
certain lectures we'd have
certain lectures we'd have it
certain lectures we'd have it on
certain lectures we'd have it on audio
and
and video
uh
uh so
uh so we'll
uh so we'll do
uh so we'll do one
uh so we'll do one series
uh so we'll do one series once
uh so we'll do one series once a
uh so we'll do one series once a month
for
for a
uh so we'll do one series once a month
for a year
for a year uh
uh so we'll do one series once a month
for a year uh and
for a year uh and then
uh so we'll do one series once a month
for a year uh and then after
for a year uh and then after that
uh so we'll do one series once a month
for a year uh and then after that I
don't
don't know
don't know what
don't know what we'll
don't know what we'll do.
don't know what we'll do. Uh
don't know what we'll do. Uh the
don't know what we'll do. Uh the work
don't know what we'll do. Uh the work uh
first
first of
don't know what we'll do. Uh the work uh
first of all
first of all uh
don't know what we'll do. Uh the work uh
first of all uh is
first of all uh is continuous.
The
The uh
The uh we
The uh we discover
The uh we discover things
The uh we discover things all
The uh we discover things all the
The uh we discover things all the time
that
that boggle
The uh we discover things all the time
that boggle that
that boggle that are
The uh we discover things all the time
that boggle that are mindboggling.
Uh
Uh since
Uh since we
Uh since we wrote
Uh since we wrote power
Uh since we wrote power versus
Uh since we wrote power versus force
many
many things
Uh since we wrote power versus force
many things we
many things we said
Uh since we wrote power versus force
many things we said in
many things we said in there
Uh since we wrote power versus force
many things we said in there have
already
already shifted
already shifted and
already shifted and changed.
already shifted and changed. So
consciousness
consciousness that
already shifted and changed. So
consciousness that means
consciousness that means consciousness
is
is evolving.
The
The spiritual
is evolving.
The spiritual research
The spiritual research in
is evolving.
The spiritual research in the
The spiritual research in the past
didn't
didn't exist.
didn't exist. Could
didn't exist. Could be
didn't exist. Could be I
didn't exist. Could be I invented
didn't exist. Could be I invented it.
The
The man
didn't exist. Could be I invented it.
The man who
The man who invented
didn't exist. Could be I invented it.
The man who invented spiritual
The man who invented spiritual research,
right?
right? Uh
right? Uh you
right? Uh you know
right? Uh you know usually
right? Uh you know usually talking
right? Uh you know usually talking about
archaeology,
archaeology, you
right? Uh you know usually talking about
archaeology, you know,
archaeology, you know, where
right? Uh you know usually talking about
archaeology, you know, where St.
archaeology, you know, where St. Sm's
bones
bones are
bones are someplace
bones are someplace and
bones are someplace and you
bones are someplace and you watch
bones are someplace and you watch that
on
on TV.
It
It has
It has to
It has to do
It has to do with
It has to do with history
It has to do with history and
It has to do with history and geography.
Has
Has nothing
It has to do with history and geography.
Has nothing to
Has nothing to do
It has to do with history and geography.
Has nothing to do with
Has nothing to do with religion
It has to do with history and geography.
Has nothing to do with religion or
spirituality
spirituality really.
um
um consciousness
spirituality really.
um consciousness research
um consciousness research is
spirituality really.
um consciousness research is the
um consciousness research is the only
spirituality really.
um consciousness research is the only uh
approach
approach that
approach that I
approach that I know
approach that I know to
approach that I know to really
investigate
investigate the
approach that I know to really
investigate the reality
investigate the reality behind
approach that I know to really
investigate the reality behind the
world's
world's teachings.
world's teachings. Some
world's teachings. Some of
world's teachings. Some of them
world's teachings. Some of them as
world's teachings. Some of them as we
just
just demonstrated
world's teachings. Some of them as we
just demonstrated this
just demonstrated this morning
world's teachings. Some of them as we
just demonstrated this morning that
interesting
interesting um
interesting um and
interesting um and a
interesting um and a is
interesting um and a is quite
interesting um and a is quite amazingly
different.
different. So
interesting um and a is quite amazingly
different. So many
different. So many errors
interesting um and a is quite amazingly
different. So many errors are
different. So many errors are very
important
important to
important to discover
important to discover and
important to discover and the
important to discover and the reason
that
that enlightenment
important to discover and the reason
that enlightenment is
that enlightenment is so
important to discover and the reason
that enlightenment is so so
that enlightenment is so so extremely
rare.
rare. It's
rare. It's first
rare. It's first of
rare. It's first of all
rare. It's first of all few
rare. It's first of all few people
rare. It's first of all few people are
motivated.
Not
Not too
Not too many
Not too many people
Not too many people have
Not too many people have much
Not too many people have much karmic
momentum
momentum by
Not too many people have much karmic
momentum by the
momentum by the time
Not too many people have much karmic
momentum by the time they
momentum by the time they get
Not too many people have much karmic
momentum by the time they get through
momentum by the time they get through a
lifetime
lifetime on
lifetime on this
lifetime on this planet
lifetime on this planet and
lifetime on this planet and uh
lifetime on this planet and uh but
lifetime on this planet and uh but it's
uh
uh life
lifetime on this planet and uh but it's
uh life is
uh life is pretty
lifetime on this planet and uh but it's
uh life is pretty much
uh life is pretty much set
lifetime on this planet and uh but it's
uh life is pretty much set against
uh life is pretty much set against it.
The
The chances
The chances of
The chances of becoming
The chances of becoming lightning
The chances of becoming lightning are
very
very slim
statistically
statistically at least.
statistically at least. It's
statistically at least. It's we
statistically at least. It's we were
talking
talking before
statistically at least. It's we were
talking before about
talking before about the
statistically at least. It's we were
talking before about the structure
talking before about the structure of
the
the ego
the ego and
the ego and how
the ego and how prevails
the ego and how prevails in
the ego and how prevails in society.
But
But the
the ego and how prevails in society.
But the other
But the other thing
the ego and how prevails in society.
But the other thing that
But the other thing that that
the ego and how prevails in society.
But the other thing that that prevails
and
and about
and about which
and about which I
and about which I write
and about which I write quite
and about which I write quite a
and about which I write quite a bit
and about which I write quite a bit uh
somewhat
somewhat in
and about which I write quite a bit uh
somewhat in eye
somewhat in eye of
and about which I write quite a bit uh
somewhat in eye of the
somewhat in eye of the eye
and about which I write quite a bit uh
somewhat in eye of the eye and
somewhat in eye of the eye and more
powerfully
powerfully in
powerfully in the
powerfully in the in
powerfully in the in the
powerfully in the in the book
powerfully in the in the book I'm
finishing
finishing now
powerfully in the in the book I'm
finishing now called
finishing now called I
powerfully in the in the book I'm
finishing now called I is
finishing now called I is spiritual
error
error has
error has also
error has also prevailed
error has also prevailed immensely.
error has also prevailed immensely. Not
only
only do
error has also prevailed immensely. Not
only do you
only do you have
error has also prevailed immensely. Not
only do you have the
only do you have the world
error has also prevailed immensely. Not
only do you have the world of
only do you have the world of the
error has also prevailed immensely. Not
only do you have the world of the ego
which
which you
which you have
which you have to
which you have to deal
which you have to deal with
which you have to deal with which
which you have to deal with which you
incorporated
incorporated as
which you have to deal with which you
incorporated as yourself
but
but religious
but religious error
but religious error prevails.
Many
Many um
but religious error prevails.
Many um common
Many um common spiritual
but religious error prevails.
Many um common spiritual sayings
Many um common spiritual sayings are
absolutely
absolutely baloney.
absolutely baloney. People
absolutely baloney. People spend
absolutely baloney. People spend their
whole
whole lives.
Spiritual
Spiritual communities
Spiritual communities babble
Spiritual communities babble these
Spiritual communities babble these uh
sayings
sayings uh
Spiritual communities babble these uh
sayings uh and
sayings uh and uh
Spiritual communities babble these uh
sayings uh and uh you
sayings uh and uh you know
Spiritual communities babble these uh
sayings uh and uh you know and
sayings uh and uh you know and they
Spiritual communities babble these uh
sayings uh and uh you know and they just
accept
accept them
accept them at
accept them at face
accept them at face value.
accept them at face value. They're
accept them at face value. They're not
only
only facious,
accept them at face value. They're not
only facious, they're
only facious, they're they're
accept them at face value. They're not
only facious, they're they're actually
erroneous.
erroneous. They're
erroneous. They're completely
erroneous. They're completely erroneous.
All
All things
erroneous. They're completely erroneous.
All things are
All things are possible
erroneous. They're completely erroneous.
All things are possible to
All things are possible to God.
erroneous. They're completely erroneous.
All things are possible to God. There's
one
one you
one you hear
one you hear all
one you hear all the
one you hear all the time,
one you hear all the time, you
one you hear all the time, you know.
one you hear all the time, you know. No,
I'll
I'll tell
one you hear all the time, you know. No,
I'll tell you
I'll tell you what's
one you hear all the time, you know. No,
I'll tell you what's not
I'll tell you what's not possible
one you hear all the time, you know. No,
I'll tell you what's not possible to
God.
God. is
God. is not
God. is not godness.
God. is not godness. Not
God. is not godness. Not godness
God. is not godness. Not godness is
God. is not godness. Not godness is not
possible
possible to
God. is not godness. Not godness is not
possible to go.
possible to go. You
God. is not godness. Not godness is not
possible to go. You know
possible to go. You know what
God. is not godness. Not godness is not
possible to go. You know what I'm
saying?
All
All things
saying?
All things are
All things are possible
saying?
All things are possible to
All things are possible to go.
saying?
All things are possible to go. I
All things are possible to go. I mean,
you
you hear
you hear these
you hear these ridiculous
you hear these ridiculous statements.
But
But all right,
you hear these ridiculous statements.
But all right, we're
But all right, we're going
you hear these ridiculous statements.
But all right, we're going to
But all right, we're going to go
you hear these ridiculous statements.
But all right, we're going to go back
But all right, we're going to go back to
causality
causality and
causality and try
causality and try to
causality and try to remove
causality and try to remove that
causality and try to remove that as
causality and try to remove that as a
major
major roadblock
causality and try to remove that as a
major roadblock because
major roadblock because it
causality and try to remove that as a
major roadblock because it it
major roadblock because it it blocks
causality and try to remove that as a
major roadblock because it it blocks the
awareness
awareness of
awareness of karma,
awareness of karma, blocks
awareness of karma, blocks the
awareness of karma, blocks the awareness
of
of the
awareness of karma, blocks the awareness
of the presence
of the presence of
awareness of karma, blocks the awareness
of the presence of God.
of the presence of God. And
awareness of karma, blocks the awareness
of the presence of God. And the
of the presence of God. And the purpose
of
of consciousness
of consciousness work
of consciousness work is
of consciousness work is to
of consciousness work is to discover
of consciousness work is to discover the
presence
presence of
of consciousness work is to discover the
presence of God
presence of God within.
Religion
Religion is
Religion is concerned
Religion is concerned with
Religion is concerned with the
Religion is concerned with the presence
of
of God
Religion is concerned with the presence
of God without.
of God without. God
Religion is concerned with the presence
of God without. God is
of God without. God is transcendent.
Elsewhere
Elsewhere in
Elsewhere in time
Elsewhere in time and
Elsewhere in time and place,
even
even Christianity,
you
you lead
you lead a
you lead a good
you lead a good life,
you lead a good life, you
you lead a good life, you go
you lead a good life, you go to
you lead a good life, you go to heaven,
and
and there's
you lead a good life, you go to heaven,
and there's where
and there's where God
you lead a good life, you go to heaven,
and there's where God is.
and there's where God is. God
you lead a good life, you go to heaven,
and there's where God is. God is
and there's where God is. God is in
heaven.
heaven. Although
heaven. Although Jesus
heaven. Although Jesus did
heaven. Although Jesus did counter
heaven. Although Jesus did counter that
with
with heaven
heaven. Although Jesus did counter that
with heaven is
with heaven is within
heaven. Although Jesus did counter that
with heaven is within you.
with heaven is within you. Thank
goodness
goodness he
goodness he did
goodness he did say
goodness he did say that.
goodness he did say that. So
goodness he did say that. So God
goodness he did say that. So God is
goodness he did say that. So God is both
imminent
imminent and
goodness he did say that. So God is both
imminent and transcendent.
That
That which
That which is
That which is all
That which is all prevailing
That which is all prevailing could
hardly
hardly just
That which is all prevailing could
hardly just come
hardly just come right
That which is all prevailing could
hardly just come right up
hardly just come right up to
That which is all prevailing could
hardly just come right up to the
periphery
periphery of
periphery of you
periphery of you and
periphery of you and stop
periphery of you and stop there.
periphery of you and stop there. Just
logic
logic tells
periphery of you and stop there. Just
logic tells you
logic tells you if
periphery of you and stop there. Just
logic tells you if God
logic tells you if God is
periphery of you and stop there. Just
logic tells you if God is everywhere
logic tells you if God is everywhere in
the
the universe
the universe then
the universe then that
the universe then that with
the universe then that with within
the universe then that with within you
the
the source
the universe then that with within you
the source of
the source of life
obviously
obviously is
obviously is within
obviously is within yourself.
obviously is within yourself. How
obviously is within yourself. How to
obviously is within yourself. How to p
how
how to
obviously is within yourself. How to p
how to come
how to come to
obviously is within yourself. How to p
how to come to the
how to come to the knowingness
obviously is within yourself. How to p
how to come to the knowingness of
how to come to the knowingness of that
and
and the
and the conscious
and the conscious awareness
and the conscious awareness of
and the conscious awareness of the
presence
presence of
and the conscious awareness of the
presence of God
presence of God is
and the conscious awareness of the
presence of God is the
presence of God is the purpose
and the conscious awareness of the
presence of God is the purpose of
presence of God is the purpose of these
lectures
lectures and
lectures and the
lectures and the purpose
lectures and the purpose of
lectures and the purpose of the
spiritual
spiritual research
which
which brings
which brings us
which brings us back
which brings us back then
which brings us back then to
which brings us back then to the
which brings us back then to the great
block
block of
which brings us back then to the great
block of causality.
Causality
Causality in
Causality in constantly
Causality in constantly reinforces
perception
perception which
Causality in constantly reinforces
perception which is
perception which is dualistic
Causality in constantly reinforces
perception which is dualistic and
there's
there's a
there's a this
there's a this and
there's a this and a
there's a this and a that.
there's a this and a that. It
there's a this and a that. It presumes
separation.
In
In the
In the world
In the world of
In the world of duality,
In the world of duality, in
In the world of duality, in the
In the world of duality, in the world
In the world of duality, in the world of
the
the ego,
In the world of duality, in the world of
the ego, it
the ego, it makes
In the world of duality, in the world of
the ego, it makes sense
the ego, it makes sense that
In the world of duality, in the world of
the ego, it makes sense that you're
the ego, it makes sense that you're here
and
and God
and God is
and God is there.
All
All the
and God is there.
All the religion,
All the religion, every
and God is there.
All the religion, every every
All the religion, every every sermon,
every
every Sunday
every Sunday morning
every Sunday morning is
every Sunday morning is about
every Sunday morning is about the
every Sunday morning is about the fact
that
that you're
every Sunday morning is about the fact
that you're here
that you're here and
every Sunday morning is about the fact
that you're here and God's
that you're here and God's there.
every Sunday morning is about the fact
that you're here and God's there. Yeah.
So,
So, how
So, how you
So, how you going
So, how you going to
So, how you going to experience
So, how you going to experience the
presence
presence of
So, how you going to experience the
presence of God
presence of God who
So, how you going to experience the
presence of God who disappeared
presence of God who disappeared after
chapter
chapter one
chapter one of
chapter one of Genesis?
chapter one of Genesis? And
chapter one of Genesis? And you're
chapter one of Genesis? And you're not
gonna
gonna see
chapter one of Genesis? And you're not
gonna see him
gonna see him again
chapter one of Genesis? And you're not
gonna see him again till
gonna see him again till heaven
chapter one of Genesis? And you're not
gonna see him again till heaven if
you've
you've been
you've been a
you've been a good
you've been a good girl
you've been a good girl or
you've been a good girl or boy,
you've been a good girl or boy, you
know.
H
H God.
So
traditionally
traditionally the
traditionally the enlightened
traditionally the enlightened um
traditionally the enlightened um the
person
person who
traditionally the enlightened um the
person who comes
person who comes into
traditionally the enlightened um the
person who comes into enlightenment
person who comes into enlightenment by
virtue
virtue of
virtue of one
virtue of one reason
virtue of one reason or
virtue of one reason or another
uh
uh has
virtue of one reason or another
uh has been
uh has been uh
virtue of one reason or another
uh has been uh called
uh has been uh called a
virtue of one reason or another
uh has been uh called a mystic.
uh has been uh called a mystic. The
mystic
mystic is
mystic is one
mystic is one whose
mystic is one whose experience
mystic is one whose experience of
mystic is one whose experience of God
mystic is one whose experience of God is
in
in the
mystic is one whose experience of God is
in the immediate
in the immediate presence
mystic is one whose experience of God is
in the immediate presence and
in the immediate presence and as
mystic is one whose experience of God is
in the immediate presence and as all
prevailing
prevailing and
prevailing and the
prevailing and the source
prevailing and the source of
prevailing and the source of the
prevailing and the source of the self,
the
the source
prevailing and the source of the self,
the source of
the source of one's
prevailing and the source of the self,
the source of one's own
the source of one's own life.
prevailing and the source of the self,
the source of one's own life. The
speakingness
speakingness and
speakingness and the
speakingness and the inspiration
speakingness and the inspiration out
speakingness and the inspiration out of
which
which the
speakingness and the inspiration out of
which the voice
which the voice is
speakingness and the inspiration out of
which the voice is talking
which the voice is talking because
speakingness and the inspiration out of
which the voice is talking because the
personal
personal ego
personal ego died
personal ego died in
personal ego died in January
personal ego died in January 1065.
personal ego died in January 1065. It's
never
never returned.
personal ego died in January 1065. It's
never returned. The
never returned. The speakingness
personal ego died in January 1065. It's
never returned. The speakingness happens
of
of its
of its own.
of its own. It's
of its own. It's not
of its own. It's not caused
of its own. It's not caused by
of its own. It's not caused by anything.
There's
There's no
of its own. It's not caused by anything.
There's no cause
There's no cause for
of its own. It's not caused by anything.
There's no cause for the
There's no cause for the speakingness.
There's
There's no
There's no cause.
There's no cause. You
There's no cause. You understand?
There's no cause. You understand? It
There's no cause. You understand? It is
the
the manifestation
There's no cause. You understand? It is
the manifestation of
the manifestation of that
There's no cause. You understand? It is
the manifestation of that which
the manifestation of that which is
There's no cause. You understand? It is
the manifestation of that which is as
the manifestation of that which is as it
spreads
spreads out.
spreads out. There's
spreads out. There's no
spreads out. There's no cause
spreads out. There's no cause to
spreads out. There's no cause to this
speakingness
speakingness here.
spreads out. There's no cause to this
speakingness here. This
speakingness here. This speakingness
spreads out. There's no cause to this
speakingness here. This speakingness is
happening
happening of
happening of its
happening of its own.
You
You understand
happening of its own.
You understand that?
Nothing
Nothing is
Nothing is causing
Nothing is causing this
Nothing is causing this speaking
Nothing is causing this speaking to
Nothing is causing this speaking to to
speak.
speak. Nothing
except
except the
except the presence
except the presence of
except the presence of God.
except the presence of God. The
except the presence of God. The only
source
source of
except the presence of God. The only
source of anything
source of anything happening
except the presence of God. The only
source of anything happening is
source of anything happening is the
evolution
evolution of
evolution of the
evolution of the presence
evolution of the presence of
evolution of the presence of God
evolution of the presence of God as
evolving
evolving in
evolution of the presence of God as
evolving in this
evolving in this moment.
All
All right.
All right. Um
All right. Um there
All right. Um there is
All right. Um there is no
All right. Um there is no this
All right. Um there is no this causing
All right. Um there is no this causing a
that
that that
All right. Um there is no this causing a
that that is
that that is an
All right. Um there is no this causing a
that that is an artifact
that that is an artifact of
All right. Um there is no this causing a
that that is an artifact of perception.
How
How does
How does movement
How does movement and
How does movement and change
How does movement and change come
How does movement and change come about?
So
So let's
How does movement and change come about?
So let's talk
So let's talk about
How does movement and change come about?
So let's talk about what
So let's talk about what is
How does movement and change come about?
So let's talk about what is the
So let's talk about what is the nature
of
of God
of God because
of God because it's
of God because it's helpful
of God because it's helpful to
of God because it's helpful to know
where
where you're
of God because it's helpful to know
where you're going
where you're going before
of God because it's helpful to know
where you're going before you
where you're going before you take
of God because it's helpful to know
where you're going before you take an
arduous
arduous trip
arduous trip to
arduous trip to get
arduous trip to get there.
arduous trip to get there. You
understand?
Nobody
Nobody thinks
Nobody thinks of
Nobody thinks of that.
Nobody thinks of that. H
the
the Old
Nobody thinks of that. H
the Old Testament
the Old Testament God
Nobody thinks of that. H
the Old Testament God is
the Old Testament God is sort
Nobody thinks of that. H
the Old Testament God is sort of
the Old Testament God is sort of ill
Nobody thinks of that. H
the Old Testament God is sort of ill and
psychotic
psychotic and
psychotic and bizarre,
psychotic and bizarre, very
psychotic and bizarre, very arbitrary.
psychotic and bizarre, very arbitrary. I
mean,
mean, you
psychotic and bizarre, very arbitrary. I
mean, you wouldn't
mean, you wouldn't even
psychotic and bizarre, very arbitrary. I
mean, you wouldn't even take
mean, you wouldn't even take him
psychotic and bizarre, very arbitrary. I
mean, you wouldn't even take him in
mean, you wouldn't even take him in your
spiritual
spiritual class.
spiritual class. Anybody
spiritual class. Anybody lived
spiritual class. Anybody lived and
thought
thought that
spiritual class. Anybody lived and
thought that way.
thought that way. We're
spiritual class. Anybody lived and
thought that way. We're going to
thought that way. We're going to get
even
even with
even with them,
even with them, trash
even with them, trash those
even with them, trash those people
even with them, trash those people out,
kill
kill them,
even with them, trash those people out,
kill them, and
kill them, and I
even with them, trash those people out,
kill them, and I got
kill them, and I got my
even with them, trash those people out,
kill them, and I got my favorite
kill them, and I got my favorite few.
And
And I
And I mean,
And I mean, you
And I mean, you know,
And I mean, you know, you'd
And I mean, you know, you'd say,
And I mean, you know, you'd say, "This
guy's
guy's a
And I mean, you know, you'd say, "This
guy's a guru."
guy's a guru." You
And I mean, you know, you'd say, "This
guy's a guru." You know,
guy's a guru." You know, he
And I mean, you know, you'd say, "This
guy's a guru." You know, he wouldn't
even
even make
even make it
even make it to
even make it to guru.
All right.
All right. So,
even make it to guru.
All right. So, in
All right. So, in the
even make it to guru.
All right. So, in the midst
All right. So, in the midst of
even make it to guru.
All right. So, in the midst of that,
Christ
Christ comes
Christ comes with
Christ comes with a
Christ comes with a new
Christ comes with a new message
Christ comes with a new message where
Christ comes with a new message where it
was
was quite
Christ comes with a new message where it
was quite unwelcome.
was quite unwelcome. Christ
Christ comes with a new message where it
was quite unwelcome. Christ was
was quite unwelcome. Christ was put
Christ comes with a new message where it
was quite unwelcome. Christ was put to
death
death for
death for revealing
death for revealing the
death for revealing the truth.
as
as was
death for revealing the truth.
as was John
as was John the
death for revealing the truth.
as was John the Baptist.
If
If there's
If there's no
If there's no this
If there's no this causing
If there's no this causing it
If there's no this causing it that,
how
how does
If there's no this causing it that,
how does what
how does what we
If there's no this causing it that,
how does what we witness
how does what we witness come
If there's no this causing it that,
how does what we witness come about?
how does what we witness come about? All
right,
right, let's
right, let's say
right, let's say that
God
God being
right, let's say that
God being all
God being all prevailing
right, let's say that
God being all prevailing and
God being all prevailing and infinitely
powerful
is
is like
powerful
is like a
is like a giant
powerful
is like a giant electromagnetic
is like a giant electromagnetic field.
Now
Now the
Now the interesting
Now the interesting power
Now the interesting power in
Now the interesting power in force
Now the interesting power in force is
force
force goes
Now the interesting power in force is
force goes from
force goes from here
Now the interesting power in force is
force goes from here to
force goes from here to there
Now the interesting power in force is
force goes from here to there and
force goes from here to there and in
doing
doing that
doing that it
doing that it expends
doing that it expends its
doing that it expends its energy.
Force
Force goes
doing that it expends its energy.
Force goes like
Force goes like this
doing that it expends its energy.
Force goes like this and
Force goes like this and now
doing that it expends its energy.
Force goes like this and now gets
Force goes like this and now gets worn
out
out and
out and it
out and it collapses.
All
All empires
out and it collapses.
All empires come
All empires come to
out and it collapses.
All empires come to an
All empires come to an end.
out and it collapses.
All empires come to an end. All
All empires come to an end. All wars
come
come to
come to an
come to an end.
come to an end. All
come to an end. All force
come to an end. All force exhausts
itself
itself because
come to an end. All force exhausts
itself because force
itself because force has
come to an end. All force exhausts
itself because force has to
itself because force has to be
come to an end. All force exhausts
itself because force has to be fed
energy
energy from
energy from elsewhere.
It's
It's limited.
energy from elsewhere.
It's limited. Force
It's limited. Force results
energy from elsewhere.
It's limited. Force results in
counterforce.
When
When I
counterforce.
When I consult
When I consult with
counterforce.
When I consult with foreign
When I consult with foreign governments,
I
I tell
I tell them,
I tell them, "If
I tell them, "If you
I tell them, "If you exert
I tell them, "If you exert force,
I tell them, "If you exert force, they
will
will come
I tell them, "If you exert force, they
will come back
will come back with
I tell them, "If you exert force, they
will come back with counterforce.
will come back with counterforce. You
better
better make
better make sure
better make sure you
better make sure you got
better make sure you got more
better make sure you got more force
better make sure you got more force than
they
they got."
I'd
I'd say
I'd say the
I'd say the better
I'd say the better way
I'd say the better way is
I'd say the better way is to
I'd say the better way is to support
I'd say the better way is to support and
love
love the
I'd say the better way is to support and
love the head
love the head of
I'd say the better way is to support and
love the head of the
love the head of the other
I'd say the better way is to support and
love the head of the other government
love the head of the other government in
return
return for
return for which
return for which he
return for which he will
return for which he will drop
return for which he will drop his
return for which he will drop his force.
He
He doesn't
return for which he will drop his force.
He doesn't need
He doesn't need it
return for which he will drop his force.
He doesn't need it anymore.
He doesn't need it anymore. And
return for which he will drop his force.
He doesn't need it anymore. And now
he'll
he'll be
he'll be your
he'll be your friend.
Headline
Headline said
he'll be your friend.
Headline said that
Headline said that worked.
he'll be your friend.
Headline said that worked. Yeah.
All
All right.
Power
Power stands
All right.
Power stands there,
affects
affects all
affects all within
affects all within its
affects all within its radiation,
requires
requires no
affects all within its radiation,
requires no expenditure
requires no expenditure of
affects all within its radiation,
requires no expenditure of energy,
requires no expenditure of energy, does
not
not expend
not expend energy.
It
It sustains.
not expend energy.
It sustains. It
It sustains. It is
not expend energy.
It sustains. It is what
It sustains. It is what it
not expend energy.
It sustains. It is what it is.
It sustains. It is what it is. And
not expend energy.
It sustains. It is what it is. And its
power
power radiates
power radiates forth
power radiates forth with
power radiates forth with no
power radiates forth with no dimensions.
Huh?
Gravity,
Gravity, it
Gravity, it just
Gravity, it just stands
Gravity, it just stands there.
Gravity, it just stands there. Gravity
doesn't
doesn't go
Gravity, it just stands there. Gravity
doesn't go from
doesn't go from here
Gravity, it just stands there. Gravity
doesn't go from here to
doesn't go from here to there.
Gravity, it just stands there. Gravity
doesn't go from here to there. The
doesn't go from here to there. The power
of
of God
of God does
of God does not
of God does not move
of God does not move from
of God does not move from here
of God does not move from here to
of God does not move from here to there.
It
It is
of God does not move from here to there.
It is a
It is a standing
of God does not move from here to there.
It is a standing field
It is a standing field out
of God does not move from here to there.
It is a standing field out of
It is a standing field out of which
of God does not move from here to there.
It is a standing field out of which all
of
of life
of life evolves.
How
How does
of life evolves.
How does what
How does what appears
of life evolves.
How does what appears to
How does what appears to be
of life evolves.
How does what appears to be happenings
occur?
occur? See
occur? See there
occur? See there is
occur? See there is no
occur? See there is no happenings
occur? See there is no happenings in
occur? See there is no happenings in the
world.
world. Happening
occur? See there is no happenings in the
world. Happening is
world. Happening is an
occur? See there is no happenings in the
world. Happening is an arbitrary
world. Happening is an arbitrary point
of
of view
of view of
of view of the
of view of the ego.
of view of the ego. You
of view of the ego. You start,
of view of the ego. You start, you
of view of the ego. You start, you say
start,
start, that's
of view of the ego. You start, you say
start, that's a
start, that's a happening.
of view of the ego. You start, you say
start, that's a happening. Stop.
start, that's a happening. Stop. That's
it.
it. That's
it. That's a
it. That's a happening
it. That's a happening between
it. That's a happening between start
it. That's a happening between start and
stop.
stop. But
it. That's a happening between start and
stop. But you
stop. But you could
it. That's a happening between start and
stop. But you could have
stop. But you could have said
it. That's a happening between start and
stop. But you could have said start
here.
here. You
here. You could
here. You could have
here. You could have said
here. You could have said stop
here. You could have said stop there.
You
You know what
here. You could have said stop there.
You know what I
You know what I mean?
here. You could have said stop there.
You know what I mean? There's
You know what I mean? There's nothing
happening.
happening. This
happening. This is
happening. This is an
happening. This is an illusion
happening. This is an illusion of
perception.
Therefore,
Therefore, you
Therefore, you don't
Therefore, you don't have
Therefore, you don't have to
Therefore, you don't have to explain
Therefore, you don't have to explain any
happenings
happenings because
Therefore, you don't have to explain any
happenings because there
happenings because there are
Therefore, you don't have to explain any
happenings because there are none.
happenings because there are none. So
that
that saves
that saves you
that saves you a
that saves you a lot
that saves you a lot of
that saves you a lot of work.
How
How do
that saves you a lot of work.
How do things
How do things h
that saves you a lot of work.
How do things h come
How do things h come about
that saves you a lot of work.
How do things h come about in
How do things h come about in the
universe?
In
In the
universe?
In the beginning
In the beginning there
universe?
In the beginning there was
In the beginning there was the
universe?
In the beginning there was the light
In the beginning there was the light and
the
the light
the light shone
the light shone forth
the light shone forth and
the light shone forth and represents
the light shone forth and represents the
expression
expression of
the light shone forth and represents the
expression of God
expression of God as
the light shone forth and represents the
expression of God as the
expression of God as the universe
continuous
continuous everpresent
continuous everpresent without
continuous everpresent without beginning
and
and without
continuous everpresent without beginning
and without end.
Out
Out of
Out of this
Out of this infinite
Out of this infinite potentiality,
the
the nature
Out of this infinite potentiality,
the nature of
the nature of God
Out of this infinite potentiality,
the nature of God is
the nature of God is unmanifest
Out of this infinite potentiality,
the nature of God is unmanifest as
infinite
infinite potentiality
even
even within
infinite potentiality
even within the
even within the physical
infinite potentiality
even within the physical domain.
One
One cubic
inch
inch of
One cubic
inch of empty
inch of empty space
One cubic
inch of empty space has
inch of empty space has more
One cubic
inch of empty space has more power
inch of empty space has more power than
is
is represented
is represented by
is represented by the
is represented by the total
is represented by the total weight
is represented by the total weight of
the
the entire
is represented by the total weight of
the entire universe.
That's
That's even
That's even within
advanced
advanced theoretical
That's even within
advanced theoretical physics.
In
In the
In the nonlinear
In the nonlinear domain
In the nonlinear domain even
In the nonlinear domain even that
In the nonlinear domain even that is
minuscule.
minuscule. There
In the nonlinear domain even that is
minuscule. There is
minuscule. There is no
In the nonlinear domain even that is
minuscule. There is no limit
minuscule. There is no limit to
In the nonlinear domain even that is
minuscule. There is no limit to the
power
power potential
power potential power
power potential power in
power potential power in any
infinitely
infinitely small
power potential power in any
infinitely small point
infinitely small point in
power potential power in any
infinitely small point in space.
And
And we'll
And we'll explain
And we'll explain why
And we'll explain why that
And we'll explain why that is
And we'll explain why that is so.
All
All that
And we'll explain why that is so.
All that all
All that all that
And we'll explain why that is so.
All that all that exists
All that all that exists exists.
The
The source
The source of
The source of all
The source of all that
The source of all that exists
The source of all that exists then
The source of all that exists then is
the
the unmanifest.
The source of all that exists then is
the unmanifest. The
the unmanifest. The source
The source of all that exists then is
the unmanifest. The source of
the unmanifest. The source of all
The source of all that exists then is
the unmanifest. The source of all that
exists
is
is God
manifesting
manifesting what
manifesting what seems
manifesting what seems to
manifesting what seems to exist
manifesting what seems to exist as
creation.
creation. It
manifesting what seems to exist as
creation. It appears
creation. It appears sequential
manifesting what seems to exist as
creation. It appears sequential because
the
the unfoldment
the unfoldment of
the unfoldment of the
the unfoldment of the universe
the unfoldment of the universe is
perceived
perceived by
the unfoldment of the universe is
perceived by perception
perceived by perception as
the unfoldment of the universe is
perceived by perception as evolving
perceived by perception as evolving in
time
time which
time which is
time which is just
time which is just an
time which is just an illusion
time which is just an illusion of
time which is just an illusion of ego.
There
There is
time which is just an illusion of ego.
There is no
There is no such
time which is just an illusion of ego.
There is no such thing
There is no such thing as
time which is just an illusion of ego.
There is no such thing as time
There is no such thing as time nor
time which is just an illusion of ego.
There is no such thing as time nor is
there
there space.
there space. Anyway,
there space. Anyway, what
there space. Anyway, what seems
there space. Anyway, what seems to
there space. Anyway, what seems to be
happening?
happening? How
there space. Anyway, what seems to be
happening? How does
happening? How does it
there space. Anyway, what seems to be
happening? How does it come
happening? How does it come about?
there space. Anyway, what seems to be
happening? How does it come about? And
we
we this
we this will
we this will explain
we this will explain karma
we this will explain karma and
take
take care
we this will explain karma and
take care of
take care of what
we this will explain karma and
take care of what happens
take care of what happens to
we this will explain karma and
take care of what happens to you
take care of what happens to you after
you
you leave
you leave the
you leave the body
you leave the body etc.
The
The spirit
you leave the body etc.
The spirit then
The spirit then is
you leave the body etc.
The spirit then is like
The spirit then is like this
you leave the body etc.
The spirit then is like this you
The spirit then is like this you or
you leave the body etc.
The spirit then is like this you or your
spirit
spirit or
spirit or what
spirit or what do
spirit or what do you
spirit or what do you want
spirit or what do you want to
spirit or what do you want to call
yourself
yourself entity
spirit or what do you want to call
yourself entity is
yourself entity is a
spirit or what do you want to call
yourself entity is a speck
yourself entity is a speck of
spirit or what do you want to call
yourself entity is a speck of dust.
yourself entity is a speck of dust. See
now
now the
now the movement
now the movement of
now the movement of every
now the movement of every speck
now the movement of every speck of
now the movement of every speck of dust
then
then depends
now the movement of every speck of dust
then depends on
then depends on the
now the movement of every speck of dust
then depends on the power
then depends on the power of
now the movement of every speck of dust
then depends on the power of the
then depends on the power of the field
of
of gravity
of gravity which
of gravity which dominates
of gravity which dominates everything
within
within this
of gravity which dominates everything
within this room.
The
The field
The field of
The field of gravity
The field of gravity doesn't
The field of gravity doesn't move,
but
but everything
The field of gravity doesn't move,
but everything within
but everything within it,
The field of gravity doesn't move,
but everything within it, if
but everything within it, if it's
The field of gravity doesn't move,
but everything within it, if it's a
giant
giant electromagnetic
giant electromagnetic field,
giant electromagnetic field, moves
depending
depending on
giant electromagnetic field, moves
depending on the
depending on the charge
giant electromagnetic field, moves
depending on the charge on
depending on the charge on the
giant electromagnetic field, moves
depending on the charge on the particle
and
and its
and its polarity
and its polarity and
and its polarity and its
and its polarity and its size
and its polarity and its size and
and its polarity and its size and its
position
position amongst
and its polarity and its size and its
position amongst all
position amongst all the
and its polarity and its size and its
position amongst all the other
particles.
Karma
Karma then
particles.
Karma then is
Karma then is the
particles.
Karma then is the charge
Karma then is the charge on
particles.
Karma then is the charge on your
particle.
The
The spirit
particle.
The spirit within
The spirit within you,
the
the spirit
the spirit within
the spirit within you
then
then by
the spirit within you
then by virtue
then by virtue of
the spirit within you
then by virtue of the
then by virtue of the various
the spirit within you
then by virtue of the various choices
and
and decisions
develops
develops you
and decisions
develops you might
develops you might say
and decisions
develops you might say analogous
analogous
analogous to
analogous to a
analogous to a certain
analogous to a certain polarity
a
a certain
analogous to a certain polarity
a certain position
a certain position within
analogous to a certain polarity
a certain position within in
relationship
relationship to
relationship to every
relationship to every other
relationship to every other particle.
relationship to every other particle. So
everything
everything in
relationship to every other particle. So
everything in the
everything in the universe
relationship to every other particle. So
everything in the universe is
everything in the universe is absolutely
perfectly
perfectly aligned
perfectly aligned with
perfectly aligned with where
perfectly aligned with where it
perfectly aligned with where it is
because
because of
perfectly aligned with where it is
because of what
because of what it
perfectly aligned with where it is
because of what it is.
because of what it is. Because
perfectly aligned with where it is
because of what it is. Because of
because of what it is. Because of what
it
it is.
Everything
Everything merely
it is.
Everything merely is
Everything merely is what
it is.
Everything merely is what it
Everything merely is what it is.
it is.
Everything merely is what it is. And
Everything merely is what it is. And as
a
a result
a result of
a result of being
a result of being what
a result of being what it
a result of being what it is,
a result of being what it is, its
a result of being what it is, its fate
is
is sealed.
a result of being what it is, its fate
is sealed. Right?
Unless
Unless bin
Unless bin Laden
Unless bin Laden changes
Unless bin Laden changes his
Unless bin Laden changes his mind
completely
completely as
Unless bin Laden changes his mind
completely as he
completely as he leaves
Unless bin Laden changes his mind
completely as he leaves the
completely as he leaves the body,
Unless bin Laden changes his mind
completely as he leaves the body, he
will
will be
will be gravitate
will be gravitate to
will be gravitate to where
that
that kind
will be gravitate to where
that kind of
that kind of spirit
will be gravitate to where
that kind of spirit is
that kind of spirit is attracted.
will be gravitate to where
that kind of spirit is attracted. Huh?
The
The heavens,
The heavens, the
The heavens, the hells,
The heavens, the hells, the
The heavens, the hells, the purgatories
are
are nothing
The heavens, the hells, the purgatories
are nothing but
are nothing but the
The heavens, the hells, the purgatories
are nothing but the non-physical
extension
because
because life
extension
because life is
because life is continuous.
Because
Because of
Because of the
Because of the non-duality
Because of the non-duality of
Because of the non-duality of reality,
there
there is
Because of the non-duality of reality,
there is only
there is only life.
Because of the non-duality of reality,
there is only life. There
there is only life. There is
Because of the non-duality of reality,
there is only life. There is no
there is only life. There is no such
thing
thing as
thing as not
thing as not life.
thing as not life. And
thing as not life. And if
thing as not life. And if you
thing as not life. And if you have
thing as not life. And if you have life
now,
now, you
thing as not life. And if you have life
now, you cannot
now, you cannot become
thing as not life. And if you have life
now, you cannot become not
now, you cannot become not life.
God
God cannot
God cannot become
God cannot become not
God cannot become not God.
God cannot become not God. That
God cannot become not God. That which
God cannot become not God. That which is
cannot
cannot become
God cannot become not God. That which is
cannot become non-ess.
Consequently,
that
that which
Consequently,
that which is
that which is the
Consequently,
that which is the spirit
that which is the spirit that
Consequently,
that which is the spirit that as
that which is the spirit that as it
leaves
leaves the
leaves the body
leaves the body merely
leaves the body merely gravitates
leaves the body merely gravitates to
leaves the body merely gravitates to its
own
own gravitational
harmony.
harmony. Huh?
It's
It's obvious
those
those of
those of you
those of you have
those of you have been
those of you have been out
those of you have been out of
those of you have been out of the
those of you have been out of the body.
How
How many
those of you have been out of the body.
How many people
How many people here
those of you have been out of the body.
How many people here have been
How many people here have been out
those of you have been out of the body.
How many people here have been out of
the
the body?
the body? Yeah,
the body? Yeah, a
the body? Yeah, a lot
the body? Yeah, a lot of
the body? Yeah, a lot of people.
the body? Yeah, a lot of people. The
first
first thing
the body? Yeah, a lot of people. The
first thing you
first thing you realize
the body? Yeah, a lot of people. The
first thing you realize as
first thing you realize as you
the body? Yeah, a lot of people. The
first thing you realize as you go
first thing you realize as you go out
the body? Yeah, a lot of people. The
first thing you realize as you go out of
body
body is
body is that
body is that the
body is that the you
body is that the you is
body is that the you is out
body is that the you is out is
body is that the you is out is now
body is that the you is out is now up
here.
you
you you
you you know
you you know it
you you know it happened
you you know it happened to
you you know it happened to me
you you know it happened to me before
you you know it happened to me before it
was
was a
you you know it happened to me before it
was a popular
was a popular subject
you you know it happened to me before it
was a popular subject there
was a popular subject there wasn't
you you know it happened to me before it
was a popular subject there wasn't any
TV
TV programs
TV programs on
TV programs on about
TV programs on about body
TV programs on about body I
TV programs on about body I was
TV programs on about body I was in
psychoanalysis
psychoanalysis with
TV programs on about body I was in
psychoanalysis with a
psychoanalysis with a an
TV programs on about body I was in
psychoanalysis with a an atheistic
psychoanalysis with a an atheistic uh
psychoanalyst
psychoanalyst he
psychoanalyst he was
psychoanalyst he was professor
psychoanalyst he was professor of
psychiatry
and
and psychoanalysis
and psychoanalysis at
and psychoanalysis at Columbia
University
University was
and psychoanalysis at Columbia
University was a
University was a prize
and psychoanalysis at Columbia
University was a prize catch
University was a prize catch as
and psychoanalysis at Columbia
University was a prize catch as an
analyst
analyst in
analyst in those
analyst in those days
analyst in those days you
analyst in those days you were
analyst in those days you were who
analyst in those days you were who your
analyst
analyst was
analyst in those days you were who your
analyst was the
analyst was the best
analyst in those days you were who your
analyst was the best analysts
analyst was the best analysts are
analyst in those days you were who your
analyst was the best analysts are hard
to
to get
to get man
to get man and
to get man and if
to get man and if You
to get man and if You got
to get man and if You got so
to get man and if You got so and
to get man and if You got so and so's
analogy.
analogy. Boy,
to get man and if You got so and so's
analogy. Boy, I
analogy. Boy, I mean
to get man and if You got so and so's
analogy. Boy, I mean you
analogy. Boy, I mean you walked
to get man and if You got so and so's
analogy. Boy, I mean you walked on
water.
I
I had
water.
I had Lionovacy.
I had Lionovacy. He
water.
I had Lionovacy. He was
I had Lionovacy. He was full
water.
I had Lionovacy. He was full professor
at
at Columbia
at Columbia and
at Columbia and training
at Columbia and training analyst
at Columbia and training analyst at
at Columbia and training analyst at the
Columbia
Columbia psychic
at Columbia and training analyst at the
Columbia psychic analytic.
Columbia psychic analytic. So
at Columbia and training analyst at the
Columbia psychic analytic. So when
Columbia psychic analytic. So when I
at Columbia and training analyst at the
Columbia psychic analytic. So when I got
him
him as
him as an
him as an analyst
him as an analyst boy
him as an analyst boy and
him as an analyst boy and I'll
him as an analyst boy and I'll tell
him as an analyst boy and I'll tell you
at
at the
him as an analyst boy and I'll tell you
at the time
at the time I
him as an analyst boy and I'll tell you
at the time I was
at the time I was an
him as an analyst boy and I'll tell you
at the time I was an atheist
at the time I was an atheist and
him as an analyst boy and I'll tell you
at the time I was an atheist and he
at the time I was an atheist and he was
an
an atheist.
an atheist. We
an atheist. We both
an atheist. We both took
an atheist. We both took a
an atheist. We both took a very
an atheist. We both took a very dim
an atheist. We both took a very dim view
of
of religion.
Nobody
Nobody ever
Nobody ever heard
Nobody ever heard of
Nobody ever heard of out
Nobody ever heard of out of
Nobody ever heard of out of body
experience.
experience. And
Nobody ever heard of out of body
experience. And uh
experience. And uh we
Nobody ever heard of out of body
experience. And uh we both
experience. And uh we both agreed
Nobody ever heard of out of body
experience. And uh we both agreed with
Freud
Freud that
Freud that it
Freud that it was
Freud that it was God
Freud that it was God was
Freud that it was God was a
Freud that it was God was a projection
from
from the
Freud that it was God was a projection
from the unconscious,
from the unconscious, a
Freud that it was God was a projection
from the unconscious, a father
from the unconscious, a father figure
about
about which
about which everybody
about which everybody was
about which everybody was ambivalent.
You
You feared
about which everybody was ambivalent.
You feared God
You feared God and
about which everybody was ambivalent.
You feared God and you
You feared God and you hated
about which everybody was ambivalent.
You feared God and you hated him
You feared God and you hated him at
about which everybody was ambivalent.
You feared God and you hated him at the
same
same time
same time etc.
same time etc. So
same time etc. So uh
same time etc. So uh in
same time etc. So uh in the
same time etc. So uh in the middle
same time etc. So uh in the middle of
all
all this
same time etc. So uh in the middle of
all this I
all this I got
same time etc. So uh in the middle of
all this I got very
all this I got very sick
same time etc. So uh in the middle of
all this I got very sick one
all this I got very sick one time
same time etc. So uh in the middle of
all this I got very sick one time and
all this I got very sick one time and I
was
was in
was in this
was in this hospital
was in this hospital bed
was in this hospital bed and
was in this hospital bed and um
was in this hospital bed and um next
thing
thing I
was in this hospital bed and um next
thing I know
thing I know I
was in this hospital bed and um next
thing I know I was
thing I know I was six
was in this hospital bed and um next
thing I know I was six feet
thing I know I was six feet over
was in this hospital bed and um next
thing I know I was six feet over the
bed.
bed. Holy
bed. Holy catfish.
bed. Holy catfish. I
bed. Holy catfish. I never
bed. Holy catfish. I never heard
bed. Holy catfish. I never heard out
about
about experience.
bed. Holy catfish. I never heard out
about experience. Here
about experience. Here I
bed. Holy catfish. I never heard out
about experience. Here I am,
about experience. Here I am, invisible,
uh,
uh, no
uh, no weight,
uh, no weight, uh,
uh, no weight, uh, suspended
uh, no weight, uh, suspended in
uh, no weight, uh, suspended in time
uh, no weight, uh, suspended in time and
space,
space, you
uh, no weight, uh, suspended in time and
space, you might
space, you might say.
uh, no weight, uh, suspended in time and
space, you might say. Painless.
space, you might say. Painless. It
uh, no weight, uh, suspended in time and
space, you might say. Painless. It was
wonderful.
wonderful. Why
wonderful. Why ever
wonderful. Why ever went
wonderful. Why ever went back?
wonderful. Why ever went back? What
wonderful. Why ever went back? What an
idiot.
idiot. Anyway,
and
and a
and a mere
and a mere thought
and a mere thought would
and a mere thought would move
and a mere thought would move you
and a mere thought would move you over.
I
I mean,
and a mere thought would move you over.
I mean, it
I mean, it was.
and a mere thought would move you over.
I mean, it was. And
I mean, it was. And I
and a mere thought would move you over.
I mean, it was. And I looked
I mean, it was. And I looked down,
there's
there's Dave
there's Dave laying
there's Dave laying in
there's Dave laying in the
there's Dave laying in the bed.
there's Dave laying in the bed. I
there's Dave laying in the bed. I mean,
he
he was
there's Dave laying in the bed. I mean,
he was a
he was a mess.
there's Dave laying in the bed. I mean,
he was a mess. I'll
he was a mess. I'll tell
there's Dave laying in the bed. I mean,
he was a mess. I'll tell you
he was a mess. I'll tell you how
there's Dave laying in the bed. I mean,
he was a mess. I'll tell you how that
Yeah,
Yeah, he's
Yeah, he's not
Yeah, he's not long
Yeah, he's not long for
Yeah, he's not long for this
Yeah, he's not long for this world.
And
And he
Yeah, he's not long for this world.
And he looked
And he looked rather
Yeah, he's not long for this world.
And he looked rather poorly,
And he looked rather poorly, but
Yeah, he's not long for this world.
And he looked rather poorly, but I
And he looked rather poorly, but I could
hear,
hear, think,
hear, think, feel,
hear, think, feel, and
hear, think, feel, and the
hear, think, feel, and the sense
hear, think, feel, and the sense of
self,
self, the
hear, think, feel, and the sense of
self, the presence
self, the presence of
hear, think, feel, and the sense of
self, the presence of who
self, the presence of who am
hear, think, feel, and the sense of
self, the presence of who am I?
self, the presence of who am I? The
hear, think, feel, and the sense of
self, the presence of who am I? The eye
was
was up
was up here.
was up here. The
was up here. The eye
was up here. The eye was
was up here. The eye was definitely
was up here. The eye was definitely not
there.
there. Not
was up here. The eye was definitely not
there. Not only
there. Not only that,
was up here. The eye was definitely not
there. Not only that, but
there. Not only that, but although
was up here. The eye was definitely not
there. Not only that, but although it
sounds
sounds alarming
sounds alarming to
sounds alarming to people
sounds alarming to people who
sounds alarming to people who never
heard
heard of
sounds alarming to people who never
heard of it,
heard of it, the
sounds alarming to people who never
heard of it, the capacities,
heard of it, the capacities, the
sounds alarming to people who never
heard of it, the capacities, the senses
exist
exist in
exist in the
exist in the atheric
exist in the atheric body,
exist in the atheric body, not
exist in the atheric body, not in
exist in the atheric body, not in the
physical
physical body.
exist in the atheric body, not in the
physical body. So
physical body. So although
exist in the atheric body, not in the
physical body. So although the
physical body. So although the ears
exist in the atheric body, not in the
physical body. So although the ears and
the
the eyes
the eyes and
the eyes and all
the eyes and all that
the eyes and all that were
the eyes and all that were laying
the eyes and all that were laying in
the eyes and all that were laying in the
bed
bed in
the eyes and all that were laying in the
bed in that
bed in that body
the eyes and all that were laying in the
bed in that body there,
bed in that body there, I
the eyes and all that were laying in the
bed in that body there, I could
bed in that body there, I could see
the eyes and all that were laying in the
bed in that body there, I could see and
hear
hear and
hear and feel
hear and feel and
hear and feel and remember
hear and feel and remember and
hear and feel and remember and see
hear and feel and remember and see and
do
do everything
hear and feel and remember and see and
do everything fine.
do everything fine. Didn't
hear and feel and remember and see and
do everything fine. Didn't need
do everything fine. Didn't need that
phys
phys physicality
phys physicality at
phys physicality at all.
uh
uh h
later
later went
later went back
later went back in
later went back in it,
later went back in it, but
later went back in it, but um
later went back in it, but um I
later went back in it, but um I forget
how
how I
later went back in it, but um I forget
how I went
how I went back
later went back in it, but um I forget
how I went back in
how I went back in it.
later went back in it, but um I forget
how I went back in it. Sort
how I went back in it. Sort of
later went back in it, but um I forget
how I went back in it. Sort of snap.
how I went back in it. Sort of snap. I
think
think when
think when I
think when I told
think when I told my
think when I told my analyst
think when I told my analyst about
think when I told my analyst about that,
we
we both
think when I told my analyst about that,
we both agreed
we both agreed that
think when I told my analyst about that,
we both agreed that it
we both agreed that it was
think when I told my analyst about that,
we both agreed that it was probably
we both agreed that it was probably due
to
to the
to the infection,
to the infection, a
to the infection, a toxic
to the infection, a toxic psychosis
to the infection, a toxic psychosis of
some
some kind
to the infection, a toxic psychosis of
some kind in
some kind in which
to the infection, a toxic psychosis of
some kind in which we
some kind in which we had
to the infection, a toxic psychosis of
some kind in which we had created
some kind in which we had created a
to the infection, a toxic psychosis of
some kind in which we had created a dual
physicality
physicality and
physicality and projected
physicality and projected it
physicality and projected it somehow.
Anyway,
Anyway, we
physicality and projected it somehow.
Anyway, we were
Anyway, we were both
physicality and projected it somehow.
Anyway, we were both happy
Anyway, we were both happy with
physicality and projected it somehow.
Anyway, we were both happy with that.
I
I never
I never told
I never told anybody
I never told anybody about
I never told anybody about it
I never told anybody about it anyway.
uh
uh the
I never told anybody about it anyway.
uh the same
uh the same as
I never told anybody about it anyway.
uh the same as uh
uh the same as uh uh
I never told anybody about it anyway.
uh the same as uh uh the
uh the same as uh uh the near-death
experience
experience that
experience that I'd
experience that I'd had
experience that I'd had early
experience that I'd had early in
experience that I'd had early in life.
experience that I'd had early in life. I
never
never tell
experience that I'd had early in life. I
never tell anybody
never tell anybody about
experience that I'd had early in life. I
never tell anybody about that
never tell anybody about that at
experience that I'd had early in life. I
never tell anybody about that at all.
never tell anybody about that at all. I
never
never did
never did until
never did until 1995.
Uh
Uh such
never did until 1995.
Uh such things
Uh such things were
never did until 1995.
Uh such things were not
Uh such things were not heard
never did until 1995.
Uh such things were not heard about
heard
heard of.
heard of. By
heard of. By the
heard of. By the way,
heard of. By the way, the
heard of. By the way, the in
heard of. By the way, the in the
heard of. By the way, the in the TV
they're
they're always
heard of. By the way, the in the TV
they're always confusing
they're always confusing near
heard of. By the way, the in the TV
they're always confusing near death
they're always confusing near death and
out
out of
out of body.
out of body. You
out of body. You know,
out of body. You know, they
out of body. You know, they think
they're
they're the
out of body. You know, they think
they're the same
they're the same thing.
out of body. You know, they think
they're the same thing. They're
they're the same thing. They're so
naive.
naive. You
naive. You know,
naive. You know, they're
naive. You know, they're two
naive. You know, they're two totally
different
different things.
naive. You know, they're two totally
different things. If
different things. If you
naive. You know, they're two totally
different things. If you calibrate
different things. If you calibrate the
level
level of
level of an
level of an out-of-
level of an out-of- body
level of an out-of- body experience,
level of an out-of- body experience, uh
you're
you're pretty
level of an out-of- body experience, uh
you're pretty much
you're pretty much the
level of an out-of- body experience, uh
you're pretty much the same
you're pretty much the same person
level of an out-of- body experience, uh
you're pretty much the same person that
you
you were
you were before.
you were before. uh
you were before. uh smarter
you were before. uh smarter uh
you were before. uh smarter uh you
you were before. uh smarter uh you know
that
that you're
you were before. uh smarter uh you know
that you're not
that you're not just
you were before. uh smarter uh you know
that you're not just a
that you're not just a physical
you were before. uh smarter uh you know
that you're not just a physical body.
that you're not just a physical body. So
there
there is
there is a
there is a spiritual
there is a spiritual advance.
there is a spiritual advance. Uh
there is a spiritual advance. Uh but
there is a spiritual advance. Uh but a
near-death
near-death experience
there is a spiritual advance. Uh but a
near-death experience you
near-death experience you see
there is a spiritual advance. Uh but a
near-death experience you see a
transformation.
transformation. There's
transformation. There's a
transformation. There's a huge
transformation. There's a huge leap
transformation. There's a huge leap in
level
level of
transformation. There's a huge leap in
level of consciousness.
Uh
Uh so
Uh so anyway
Uh so anyway the
Uh so anyway the the
Uh so anyway the the not
Uh so anyway the the not the
Uh so anyway the the not the same
Uh so anyway the the not the same thing
at
at all.
Uh so anyway the the not the same thing
at all. Anyway,
at all. Anyway, we're
Uh so anyway the the not the same thing
at all. Anyway, we're getting
at all. Anyway, we're getting back
Uh so anyway the the not the same thing
at all. Anyway, we're getting back to
causality.
causality. So
causality. So the
causality. So the nature
causality. So the nature of
causality. So the nature of God
causality. So the nature of God then
causality. So the nature of God then is
infinite
infinite power
causality. So the nature of God then is
infinite power of
infinite power of such
causality. So the nature of God then is
infinite power of such an
infinite power of such an immense
causality. So the nature of God then is
infinite power of such an immense degree
in
in 65
in 65 or
in 65 or and
in 65 or and then
in 65 or and then again
in 65 or and then again consciousness
kept
kept advancing
in 65 or and then again consciousness
kept advancing over
kept advancing over the
in 65 or and then again consciousness
kept advancing over the years.
kept advancing over the years. There
would
would be
would be a
would be a new
would be a new condition
would be a new condition in
would be a new condition in which
would be a new condition in which the
power
power of
would be a new condition in which the
power of God
power of God became
would be a new condition in which the
power of God became even
power of God became even more
would be a new condition in which the
power of God became even more revealed.
Staggering.
Staggering. Staggering.
This
This power
Staggering. Staggering.
This power is
This power is absolute.
There's
There's nothing
There's nothing that
There's nothing that can
There's nothing that can oppose
There's nothing that can oppose the
power
power of
There's nothing that can oppose the
power of God.
power of God. There
There's nothing that can oppose the
power of God. There is
power of God. There is no
There's nothing that can oppose the
power of God. There is no opposite
power of God. There is no opposite to
the
the power
the power of
the power of God.
the power of God. Nothing
the power of God. Nothing is
the power of God. Nothing is possible
anymore.
anymore. The
the power of God. Nothing is possible
anymore. The non-godness
anymore. The non-godness is
the power of God. Nothing is possible
anymore. The non-godness is possible.
That
That which
That which is
That which is all
That which is all that
That which is all that is
That which is all that is as
That which is all that is as infinite
power.
power. When
That which is all that is as infinite
power. When I
power. When I first
That which is all that is as infinite
power. When I first saw
power. When I first saw that
That which is all that is as infinite
power. When I first saw that power,
power. When I first saw that power, I
was
was just
the
the mind
was just
the mind disappeared.
the mind disappeared. All
was just
the mind disappeared. All thoughts
stopped
stopped and
stopped and the
stopped and the body
stopped and the body moved
stopped and the body moved of
stopped and the body moved of its
stopped and the body moved of its own,
which
which it
stopped and the body moved of its own,
which it does
which it does to
stopped and the body moved of its own,
which it does to this
which it does to this day.
stopped and the body moved of its own,
which it does to this day. It's
which it does to this day. It's always
doing
doing surprising.
doing surprising. Look
doing surprising. Look what
doing surprising. Look what it's
doing surprising. Look what it's doing
now.
now. I
doing surprising. Look what it's doing
now. I mean,
now. I mean, it
doing surprising. Look what it's doing
now. I mean, it just
now. I mean, it just does
doing surprising. Look what it's doing
now. I mean, it just does all
now. I mean, it just does all kinds
doing surprising. Look what it's doing
now. I mean, it just does all kinds of
things.
things. It
things. It does
things. It does it
things. It does it all
things. It does it all by
things. It does it all by itself.
things. It does it all by itself. See,
people
people say,
things. It does it all by itself. See,
people say, "Why
people say, "Why do
things. It does it all by itself. See,
people say, "Why do you
people say, "Why do you do
things. It does it all by itself. See,
people say, "Why do you do that?"
people say, "Why do you do that?" You
see
see the
see the duality?
see the duality? There's
see the duality? There's a
see the duality? There's a me
see the duality? There's a me and
see the duality? There's a me and then
see the duality? There's a me and then a
body.
body. It
see the duality? There's a me and then a
body. It just
body. It just does
see the duality? There's a me and then a
body. It just does what
body. It just does what it
see the duality? There's a me and then a
body. It just does what it does
body. It just does what it does by
see the duality? There's a me and then a
body. It just does what it does by its
lonesome.
lonesome. I
lonesome. I mean,
lonesome. I mean, it's
lonesome. I mean, it's amusing
lonesome. I mean, it's amusing and
lonesome. I mean, it's amusing and it's
a
a lot
lonesome. I mean, it's amusing and it's
a lot of
a lot of fun,
but
but it's
but it's got
but it's got nothing
but it's got nothing to
but it's got nothing to do
but it's got nothing to do at
but it's got nothing to do at all
but it's got nothing to do at all with
who
who I
but it's got nothing to do at all with
who I am.
who I am. And
but it's got nothing to do at all with
who I am. And I
who I am. And I often
but it's got nothing to do at all with
who I am. And I often look
who I am. And I often look at
but it's got nothing to do at all with
who I am. And I often look at it
who I am. And I often look at it and
but it's got nothing to do at all with
who I am. And I often look at it and I
can't
can't believe
can't believe it's
can't believe it's even
can't believe it's even there.
can't believe it's even there. I
can't believe it's even there. I see.
However,
it
it took
it took many
it took many years
it took many years to
it took many years to get
it took many years to get used
it took many years to get used to
running
running it.
it took many years to get used to
running it. It's
running it. It's like
it took many years to get used to
running it. It's like running
running it. It's like running things
it took many years to get used to
running it. It's like running things by
remote
remote control.
remote control. The
remote control. The U
remote control. The U is
remote control. The U is over
remote control. The U is over there
remote control. The U is over there and
everybody's
everybody's talking
remote control. The U is over there and
everybody's talking to
everybody's talking to the
remote control. The U is over there and
everybody's talking to the U.
everybody's talking to the U. And
remote control. The U is over there and
everybody's talking to the U. And you
wonder
wonder who
wonder who they're
wonder who they're talking
wonder who they're talking to.
There
There isn't
wonder who they're talking to.
There isn't any
There isn't any me
wonder who they're talking to.
There isn't any me there
There isn't any me there at
wonder who they're talking to.
There isn't any me there at all.
There isn't any me there at all. You
know,
know, they're
know, they're talking
know, they're talking to
know, they're talking to that
physicality.
We're
We're going
We're going to
We're going to back
We're going to back get
We're going to back get back
We're going to back get back to
causality.
causality. So
We're going to back get back to
causality. So here
causality. So here is
We're going to back get back to
causality. So here is everything
causality. So here is everything within
the
the universe
being
being what
the universe
being what it
being what it is.
the universe
being what it is. That's
being what it is. That's all
the universe
being what it is. That's all it
being what it is. That's all it can
the universe
being what it is. That's all it can do.
There
There is
There is no
There is no this
There is no this that
There is no this that does
There is no this that does it
There is no this that does it that.
Everything
Everything is
There is no this that does it that.
Everything is every
Everything is every instant
There is no this that does it that.
Everything is every instant the
Everything is every instant the perfect
expression
expression of
expression of that
expression of that which
expression of that which it
expression of that which it is
expression of that which it is at
expression of that which it is at this
instant.
instant. As
expression of that which it is at this
instant. As a
instant. As a consequence,
expression of that which it is at this
instant. As a consequence, it's
instant. As a consequence, it's being
what
what it
what it is
what it is at
what it is at this
what it is at this instant.
what it is at this instant. Instant
being
being a
what it is at this instant. Instant
being a point
being a point of
what it is at this instant. Instant
being a point of perception
being a point of perception and
what it is at this instant. Instant
being a point of perception and no
being a point of perception and no such
thing
thing as
thing as an
thing as an instant
thing as an instant actually
thing as an instant actually existing.
But
at
at this
at this particular
at this particular instant,
at this particular instant, its
polarity,
polarity, its
at this particular instant, its
polarity, its choices,
polarity, its choices, its
at this particular instant, its
polarity, its choices, its wisdoms,
polarity, its choices, its wisdoms, its
life
life experiences
are
are held
life experiences
are held within
are held within this
life experiences
are held within this enormous
are held within this enormous grav
gravitational
gravitational field.
gravitational field. You
gravitational field. You see
gravitational field. You see how
gravitational field. You see how it's
automatic.
You
You see
You see why
You see why the
You see why the justice
You see why the justice of
You see why the justice of God
You see why the justice of God is
absolute.
absolute. The
You see why the justice of God is
absolute. The idea
absolute. The idea of
You see why the justice of God is
absolute. The idea of an
absolute. The idea of an arbitrary
You see why the justice of God is
absolute. The idea of an arbitrary God
who
who judges
who judges you
who judges you at
who judges you at death
who judges you at death is
who judges you at death is idiotic
beyond
beyond belief.
That
That which
That which you
That which you are
That which you are automatically
That which you are automatically goes
That which you are automatically goes to
that
that which
That which you are automatically goes to
that which it
that which it is.
That which you are automatically goes to
that which it is. It
that which it is. It has
That which you are automatically goes to
that which it is. It has no
that which it is. It has no choice
That which you are automatically goes to
that which it is. It has no choice in
the
the matter,
the matter, does
the matter, does it?
That
That which
the matter, does it?
That which you
That which you are
the matter, does it?
That which you are automatically
gravitates
gravitates to
gravitates to that
gravitates to that which
gravitates to that which it
gravitates to that which it is.
You
You can
gravitates to that which it is.
You can take
You can take an
gravitates to that which it is.
You can take an old
You can take an old bar
gravitates to that which it is.
You can take an old bar and
You can take an old bar and grill,
gravitates to that which it is.
You can take an old bar and grill, new
buyer
buyer buys
buyer buys it,
buyer buys it, cleans
buyer buys it, cleans it
buyer buys it, cleans it up,
buyer buys it, cleans it up, puts
drapes,
drapes, curtains,
buyer buys it, cleans it up, puts
drapes, curtains, new
drapes, curtains, new carpets.
buyer buys it, cleans it up, puts
drapes, curtains, new carpets. It's
drapes, curtains, new carpets. It's all
glossied
glossied up.
glossied up. Does
glossied up. Does the
glossied up. Does the old
glossied up. Does the old crew
glossied up. Does the old crew come
glossied up. Does the old crew come back
to
to the
glossied up. Does the old crew come back
to the bar
to the bar and
glossied up. Does the old crew come back
to the bar and grill
to the bar and grill and
glossied up. Does the old crew come back
to the bar and grill and say,
to the bar and grill and say, "Gee,
Henry,
Henry, this
Henry, this place
Henry, this place looks
Henry, this place looks great
Henry, this place looks great now."
Henry, this place looks great now." And
they
they don't
Henry, this place looks great now." And
they don't go
they don't go there
Henry, this place looks great now." And
they don't go there anymore.
It
It doesn't
It doesn't appeal
It doesn't appeal to
It doesn't appeal to them
It doesn't appeal to them at
It doesn't appeal to them at all.
Waterfront
Waterfront dive
It doesn't appeal to them at all.
Waterfront dive is
Waterfront dive is a
It doesn't appeal to them at all.
Waterfront dive is a waterfront
Waterfront dive is a waterfront dive.
You
You clean
You clean it
You clean it up,
You clean it up, put
You clean it up, put new
You clean it up, put new drapes,
You clean it up, put new drapes, and
You clean it up, put new drapes, and all
it
it stinks.
You clean it up, put new drapes, and all
it stinks. Who
it stinks. Who the
You clean it up, put new drapes, and all
it stinks. Who the hell
it stinks. Who the hell wants
You clean it up, put new drapes, and all
it stinks. Who the hell wants to
it stinks. Who the hell wants to go
there?
Nobody
Nobody wants
there?
Nobody wants to
Nobody wants to go
there?
Nobody wants to go there.
Nobody wants to go there. Bunch
there?
Nobody wants to go there. Bunch of
foots
foots go
foots go there.
foots go there. You
foots go there. You know what
foots go there. You know what I
foots go there. You know what I mean?
Get
Get drunk
foots go there. You know what I mean?
Get drunk and
Get drunk and throw
foots go there. You know what I mean?
Get drunk and throw up
Get drunk and throw up on
foots go there. You know what I mean?
Get drunk and throw up on the
Get drunk and throw up on the floor.
They
They they
They they get
They they get all
They they get all excited
They they get all excited about
They they get all excited about that.
You
You know what
They they get all excited about that.
You know what I
You know what I mean?
They they get all excited about that.
You know what I mean? Who
You know what I mean? Who wants
They they get all excited about that.
You know what I mean? Who wants to
You know what I mean? Who wants to hang
out
out there?
Get
Get in
out there?
Get in a
Get in a brawl,
out there?
Get in a brawl, they
Get in a brawl, they call
out there?
Get in a brawl, they call the
Get in a brawl, they call the cops.
out there?
Get in a brawl, they call the cops. I
mean,
mean, geez.
mean, geez. All right.
mean, geez. All right. You
mean, geez. All right. You lift
mean, geez. All right. You lift a
mean, geez. All right. You lift a few
bucks
bucks from
mean, geez. All right. You lift a few
bucks from some
bucks from some other
mean, geez. All right. You lift a few
bucks from some other guy,
bucks from some other guy, they
mean, geez. All right. You lift a few
bucks from some other guy, they turn
bucks from some other guy, they turn you
in.
in. I
in. I mean,
in. I mean, nutsville,
in. I mean, nutsville, man.
in. I mean, nutsville, man. Who
in. I mean, nutsville, man. Who wants
in. I mean, nutsville, man. Who wants to
hang
hang out
in. I mean, nutsville, man. Who wants to
hang out in
hang out in a
in. I mean, nutsville, man. Who wants to
hang out in a joint
hang out in a joint like
in. I mean, nutsville, man. Who wants to
hang out in a joint like that?
Where
Where does
Where does a
Where does a guy
Where does a guy from
Where does a guy from Waterfront
Where does a guy from Waterfront Dive
Where does a guy from Waterfront Dive go
when
when they
Where does a guy from Waterfront Dive go
when they clean
when they clean up
Where does a guy from Waterfront Dive go
when they clean up his
when they clean up his whole
Where does a guy from Waterfront Dive go
when they clean up his whole hangout?
when they clean up his whole hangout? He
goes
goes to
goes to another
goes to another waterfront
goes to another waterfront dive.
goes to another waterfront dive. That's
where
where he
goes to another waterfront dive. That's
where he goes.
where he goes. He's
goes to another waterfront dive. That's
where he goes. He's attracted
where he goes. He's attracted to
goes to another waterfront dive. That's
where he goes. He's attracted to that
which
which he
which he is.
which he is. You
which he is. You understand?
which he is. You understand? He
which he is. You understand? He is
which he is. You understand? He is not
attracted.
attracted. He
which he is. You understand? He is not
attracted. He is
attracted. He is not
which he is. You understand? He is not
attracted. He is not attracted.
attracted. He is not attracted. If
which he is. You understand? He is not
attracted. He is not attracted. If I
say,
say, "Here's
say, "Here's a
say, "Here's a free
say, "Here's a free ticket
say, "Here's a free ticket that'll
say, "Here's a free ticket that'll take
you
you to
say, "Here's a free ticket that'll take
you to see
you to see the
say, "Here's a free ticket that'll take
you to see the PA,
you to see the PA, they
say, "Here's a free ticket that'll take
you to see the PA, they can
you to see the PA, they can I
say, "Here's a free ticket that'll take
you to see the PA, they can I sell
you to see the PA, they can I sell it?
How
How much
How much is
How much is it
How much is it worth?
Oh
Oh well.
How much is it worth?
Oh well. So
that
that which
that which is
that which is attracted
that which is attracted to
that which is attracted to that.
that which is attracted to that. So
that which is attracted to that. So one
automatically
automatically gravitates
now
now to
now to that
now to that which
now to that which one
now to that which one is
now to that which one is you
now to that which one is you might
now to that which one is you might say
to
to that
now to that which one is you might say
to that which
to that which you
now to that which one is you might say
to that which you already
to that which you already are.
now to that which one is you might say
to that which you already are. Some
people
people are
people are attracted
people are attracted to
people are attracted to beauty.
people are attracted to beauty. The
great
great cathedrals
people are attracted to beauty. The
great cathedrals of
great cathedrals of Europe.
people are attracted to beauty. The
great cathedrals of Europe. When
great cathedrals of Europe. When I
traveled
traveled Europe
traveled Europe I
traveled Europe I went
traveled Europe I went from
traveled Europe I went from one
cathedral
cathedral to
traveled Europe I went from one
cathedral to another.
cathedral to another. The
traveled Europe I went from one
cathedral to another. The attraction
cathedral to another. The attraction was
to
to experience
to experience chart
to experience chart the
to experience chart the blue
to experience chart the blue window
to experience chart the blue window in
chart
and
and or
and or I
and or I spoke
and or I spoke one
and or I spoke one time
and or I spoke one time at
and or I spoke one time at what's
and or I spoke one time at what's the
great
great place
and or I spoke one time at what's the
great place in
great place in London
and or I spoke one time at what's the
great place in London um
great place in London um Westminster
Abby
Abby around
Abby around Westminster
Abby around Westminster Abby.
Uh
Uh the
Abby around Westminster Abby.
Uh the things
Uh the things that
Abby around Westminster Abby.
Uh the things that inspire
Uh the things that inspire and
Abby around Westminster Abby.
Uh the things that inspire and attract
you
you then
you then reflect
you then reflect that
you then reflect that which
you then reflect that which you
you then reflect that which you are.
you then reflect that which you are. So
even
even be
you then reflect that which you are. So
even be before
even be before I
you then reflect that which you are. So
even be before I became
even be before I became that
you then reflect that which you are. So
even be before I became that which
even be before I became that which I
you then reflect that which you are. So
even be before I became that which I am,
I
I was
I was already
I was already that
I was already that which
I was already that which I
I was already that which I am,
I was already that which I am, but
I was already that which I am, but it
seemed
seemed to
I was already that which I am, but it
seemed to be
seemed to be that
I was already that which I am, but it
seemed to be that which
seemed to be that which I
I was already that which I am, but it
seemed to be that which I was
seemed to be that which I was at
I was already that which I am, but it
seemed to be that which I was at the
time,
time, which
time, which was
time, which was already
time, which was already attracted
time, which was already attracted to
what
what I
time, which was already attracted to
what I really
what I really was,
time, which was already attracted to
what I really was, which
what I really was, which was
time, which was already attracted to
what I really was, which was the
what I really was, which was the great
cathedrals,
cathedrals, you
cathedrals, you know.
Anyway,
Anyway, I
cathedrals, you know.
Anyway, I calibrated
Anyway, I calibrated the
cathedrals, you know.
Anyway, I calibrated the great
cathedrals
cathedrals there
cathedrals there at
cathedrals there at 700
cathedrals there at 700 700
cathedrals there at 700 700 Westminster
Abby.
Abby. The
cathedrals there at 700 700 Westminster
Abby. The great
Abby. The great cathedrals
cathedrals there at 700 700 Westminster
Abby. The great cathedrals Notredam.
Ah,
Ah, they're
Ah, they're stunning.
Pardon
Pardon me.
Ah, they're stunning.
Pardon me. Great
Pardon me. Great beauty
Ah, they're stunning.
Pardon me. Great beauty always
Pardon me. Great beauty always makes
Ah, they're stunning.
Pardon me. Great beauty always makes you
cry.
cry. I
cry. I avoid
cry. I avoid it
cry. I avoid it because
cry. I avoid it because uh
cry. I avoid it because uh I
cry. I avoid it because uh I become
totally
totally incapacitated
just
just the
just the memory
just the memory of
just the memory of uh
just the memory of uh the
just the memory of uh the cathedrals.
The
The sacrifice
just the memory of uh the cathedrals.
The sacrifice of
The sacrifice of all
just the memory of uh the cathedrals.
The sacrifice of all the
The sacrifice of all the people
just the memory of uh the cathedrals.
The sacrifice of all the people over
hundreds
hundreds of
hundreds of years
hundreds of years uh
hundreds of years uh spending
hundreds of years uh spending a
hundreds of years uh spending a whole
lifetime
lifetime just
hundreds of years uh spending a whole
lifetime just to
lifetime just to carve
hundreds of years uh spending a whole
lifetime just to carve one
lifetime just to carve one pulpit.
hundreds of years uh spending a whole
lifetime just to carve one pulpit. I
mean
mean just
mean just the
mean just the enormity
mean just the enormity of
mean just the enormity of the
which
which is
mean just the enormity of the
which is the
which is the second
mean just the enormity of the
which is the second way
which is the second way to
mean just the enormity of the
which is the second way to god
which is the second way to god which
mean just the enormity of the
which is the second way to god which I
don't
don't talk
don't talk about
don't talk about because
don't talk about because it
don't talk about because it cannot
don't talk about because it cannot be
talked
talked about
the
the way
the way I
the way I the
the way I the pathway
the way I the pathway to
the way I the pathway to god
the way I the pathway to god I
the way I the pathway to god I speak
about
about is
the way I the pathway to god I speak
about is probably
about is probably most
the way I the pathway to god I speak
about is probably most closely
about is probably most closely alied
the way I the pathway to god I speak
about is probably most closely alied as
I
I said
I said with
I said with zenerva
it's
it's rather
I said with zenerva
it's rather radical
it's rather radical reality
I said with zenerva
it's rather radical reality radical
truth
truth And
truth And you
truth And you can
truth And you can talk
truth And you can talk about
truth And you can talk about it.
truth And you can talk about it. The
truth And you can talk about it. The way
through
through the
truth And you can talk about it. The way
through the heart
through the heart cannot
truth And you can talk about it. The way
through the heart cannot be
through the heart cannot be talked
about.
about. So
as
as you
about. So
as you remove
as you remove the
about. So
as you remove the barriers
as you remove the barriers uh
about. So
as you remove the barriers uh the
as you remove the barriers uh the way
through
through the
through the heart
through the heart becomes
uh
uh more
through the heart becomes
uh more powerful.
The
The classic
The classic yoga
The classic yoga are
The classic yoga are through
The classic yoga are through the
The classic yoga are through the mind
and
and through
The classic yoga are through the mind
and through the
and through the heart.
uh
uh the
uh the Greek
uh the Greek cathedral
uh
uh brings
uh the Greek cathedral
uh brings forth
uh brings forth enormous
overwhelming
overwhelming the
overwhelming the experience
overwhelming the experience of
overwhelming the experience of divine
love
love and
overwhelming the experience of divine
love and the
love and the presence
overwhelming the experience of divine
love and the presence of
love and the presence of divine
overwhelming the experience of divine
love and the presence of divine love
love and the presence of divine love as
the
the self
and
and that
the self
and that incapacitates
and that incapacitates you.
So
So I
So I try
So I try to
So I try to stay
So I try to stay away
So I try to stay away from
So I try to stay away from love
So I try to stay away from love uh
because
that
that brings
that brings everything
that brings everything to
that brings everything to a
that brings everything to a halt.
when
when I
that brings everything to a halt.
when I finish
when I finish the
that brings everything to a halt.
when I finish the lectures
when I finish the lectures maybe
that brings everything to a halt.
when I finish the lectures maybe then
we'll
we'll we'll
we'll we'll let
we'll we'll let that
we'll we'll let that run.
Um
so
so everything
so everything is
so everything is merely
so everything is merely being
so everything is merely being what
so everything is merely being what it
so everything is merely being what it is
as
as a
so everything is merely being what it is
as a result
as a result of
so everything is merely being what it is
as a result of the
as a result of the nature
so everything is merely being what it is
as a result of the nature of
as a result of the nature of creation
itself
itself whose
itself whose capacity
itself whose capacity is
itself whose capacity is infinite
itself whose capacity is infinite whose
presence
presence is
itself whose capacity is infinite whose
presence is always
presence is always present
itself whose capacity is infinite whose
presence is always present and
presence is always present and who
sustains
sustains your
sustains your life.
sustains your life. The
sustains your life. The evidence
sustains your life. The evidence of
sustains your life. The evidence of the
presence
presence of
sustains your life. The evidence of the
presence of God
presence of God within
sustains your life. The evidence of the
presence of God within you
presence of God within you is
sustains your life. The evidence of the
presence of God within you is your
existence.
that
that one
existence.
that one exists
that one exists is
the
the demonstration
the demonstration and
the demonstration and the
the demonstration and the proof
the demonstration and the proof of
the demonstration and the proof of the
existence
existence of
the demonstration and the proof of the
existence of God.
That
That which
That which the
That which the ordinary
That which the ordinary mind
That which the ordinary mind takes
That which the ordinary mind takes for
granted
granted is
That which the ordinary mind takes for
granted is the
granted is the very
That which the ordinary mind takes for
granted is the very source
granted is the very source of
That which the ordinary mind takes for
granted is the very source of the
awareness
awareness of
awareness of the
awareness of the presence
awareness of the presence of
awareness of the presence of divinity
awareness of the presence of divinity as
existence.
What
What is
What is the
What is the source
What is the source of
What is the source of existence
What is the source of existence if
What is the source of existence if it
What is the source of existence if it is
not
not causality?
If
If one's
If one's existence
If one's existence is
If one's existence is not
If one's existence is not the
If one's existence is not the end
If one's existence is not the end of
If one's existence is not the end of a
bunch
bunch of
If one's existence is not the end of a
bunch of whole
bunch of whole billiard
If one's existence is not the end of a
bunch of whole billiard balls
bunch of whole billiard balls going
through
through time
through time and
through time and coming
through time and coming out
through time and coming out as
through time and coming out as one
labeled
labeled you,
then
then how
then how does
then how does one
then how does one come
then how does one come into
manifestation?
manifestation? Huh?
The
The only
The only source
The only source of
The only source of existence,
The only source of existence, the
capacity
capacity for
The only source of existence, the
capacity for existence
capacity for existence is
The only source of existence, the
capacity for existence is divinity.
Nothing
Nothing in
Nothing in the
Nothing in the universe
Nothing in the universe has
Nothing in the universe has the
Nothing in the universe has the power
Nothing in the universe has the power to
create
create existence.
Nothing in the universe has the power to
create existence. Nothing.
in
in causality
in causality is
in causality is the
in causality is the thinnest
in causality is the thinnest of
in causality is the thinnest of flimsy
attempts
attempts to
in causality is the thinnest of flimsy
attempts to rationalize
attempts to rationalize how
in causality is the thinnest of flimsy
attempts to rationalize how it
attempts to rationalize how it could
otherwise
otherwise come
otherwise come about
uh
uh by
otherwise come about
uh by that
uh by that which
otherwise come about
uh by that which does
uh by that which does not
otherwise come about
uh by that which does not wish
uh by that which does not wish to
acknowledge
acknowledge its
acknowledge its source
acknowledge its source as
acknowledge its source as God
which
which is
acknowledge its source as God
which is how
which is how you
acknowledge its source as God
which is how you get
which is how you get to
acknowledge its source as God
which is how you get to the
which is how you get to the lower
acknowledge its source as God
which is how you get to the lower astral
lower
lower astral
lower astral is
lower astral is the
lower astral is the s
lower astral is the s is
the
the place
lower astral is the s is
the place where
the place where those
lower astral is the s is
the place where those who
the place where those who deny
lower astral is the s is
the place where those who deny God
it's
it's a
it's a different
it's a different dimension
it's a different dimension than
it's a different dimension than This
it's a different dimension than This is
a
a different
it's a different dimension than This is
a different dimension.
There's
There's an
There's an infinite
There's an infinite number
There's an infinite number of
There's an infinite number of dimensions
of
of which
There's an infinite number of dimensions
of which this
of which this is
There's an infinite number of dimensions
of which this is only
of which this is only one
There's an infinite number of dimensions
of which this is only one of
of which this is only one of an
There's an infinite number of dimensions
of which this is only one of an infinite
number.
There's
There's an
number.
There's an infinite
There's an infinite number
number.
There's an infinite number of
dimensions.
Each
Each one
dimensions.
Each one evolving
in
in infinite
in infinite directions.
There's
There's an
in infinite directions.
There's an infinite
There's an infinite number
in infinite directions.
There's an infinite number of
dimensions.
This
This is
dimensions.
This is only
This is only one
dimensions.
This is only one of
This is only one of an
dimensions.
This is only one of an infinite
This is only one of an infinite number
of
of dimensions.
of dimensions. How
of dimensions. How can
of dimensions. How can it
of dimensions. How can it be
of dimensions. How can it be infinite
and
and ever
of dimensions. How can it be infinite
and ever expanding
and ever expanding and
of dimensions. How can it be infinite
and ever expanding and and
and ever expanding and and never
stopping?
stopping? Because
stopping? Because the
stopping? Because the energy
stopping? Because the energy of
creation,
creation, the
stopping? Because the energy of
creation, the presence
creation, the presence of
stopping? Because the energy of
creation, the presence of God,
creation, the presence of God, the
innate
innate one
innate one innate
innate one innate quality,
innate one innate quality, the
innate one innate quality, the presence
of
of God
innate one innate quality, the presence
of God is
of God is creation.
Therefore,
Therefore, that
Therefore, that which
Therefore, that which is
Therefore, that which is created
Therefore, that which is created has
within
within it
Therefore, that which is created has
within it the
within it the energy
Therefore, that which is created has
within it the energy of
within it the energy of God,
Therefore, that which is created has
within it the energy of God, which
continues
continues to
continues to create,
continues to create, which
continues to create, which continues
continues to create, which continues to
create,
create, and
continues to create, which continues to
create, and that
create, and that which
continues to create, which continues to
create, and that which is
create, and that which is created
continues
continues to
continues to create.
continues to create. Therefore,
continues to create. Therefore, out
continues to create. Therefore, out of
one
one dimension
continues to create. Therefore, out of
one dimension evolves
one dimension evolves an
continues to create. Therefore, out of
one dimension evolves an infinite
one dimension evolves an infinite number
of
of dimensions.
of dimensions. Out
of dimensions. Out of
of dimensions. Out of each
of dimensions. Out of each of
of dimensions. Out of each of the
infinite
infinite number
of dimensions. Out of each of the
infinite number of
infinite number of dimensions
of dimensions. Out of each of the
infinite number of dimensions evolve
infinite number of dimensions evolve an
infinite
infinite number
infinite number of
infinite number of dimensions.
infinite number of dimensions. You
understand
understand the
infinite number of dimensions. You
understand the expanse
understand the expanse of
infinite number of dimensions. You
understand the expanse of the
understand the expanse of the universe,
right?
Um
Um the
right?
Um the awareness
Um the awareness that
right?
Um the awareness that the
Um the awareness that the self
is
is the
is the source
is the source of
is the source of an
is the source of an infinite
is the source of an infinite series
is the source of an infinite series of
an
an infinite
is the source of an infinite series of
an infinite series
an infinite series of
is the source of an infinite series of
an infinite series of an
an infinite series of an infinite
is the source of an infinite series of
an infinite series of an infinite series
of
of dimensions
of dimensions calibrates
of dimensions calibrates over
of dimensions calibrates over what?
Calibrates
Calibrates over
of dimensions calibrates over what?
Calibrates over a,000
Calibrates over a,000 1100
of dimensions calibrates over what?
Calibrates over a,000 1100 1200
Calibrates over a,000 1100 1200 1250
1280 1290
1280 1290 1290
1280 1290 1290 first
1280 1290 1290 first time
1280 1290 1290 first time in
1280 1290 1290 first time in history.
Okay.
Uh
that
that which
Uh
that which is
that which is the
Uh
that which is the source
that which is the source oneself
is
is also
is also the
is also the source
is also the source of
is also the source of all
is also the source of all the
dimensions.
You're
You're not
You're not limited
You're not limited to
You're not limited to just
You're not limited to just this
dimension.
dimension. You're
You're not limited to just this
dimension. You're only
dimension. You're only expressing
yourself
yourself as
yourself as this
yourself as this dimension.
All right?
All right? That's
yourself as this dimension.
All right? That's just
All right? That's just a
yourself as this dimension.
All right? That's just a recent
discovery.
um
to
to understand
to understand then
to understand then your
to understand then your relationship
to understand then your relationship to
God
God and
to understand then your relationship to
God and karma.
Karma
Karma is
Karma is merely
Karma is merely what
Karma is merely what one
Karma is merely what one has
Karma is merely what one has become
throughout
throughout the
Karma is merely what one has become
throughout the various
we
we call
we call them
we call them lifetimes.
At
At 600
we call them lifetimes.
At 600 you
At 600 you see
we call them lifetimes.
At 600 you see there's
At 600 you see there's only
we call them lifetimes.
At 600 you see there's only one
lifetime.
You
You see
lifetime.
You see the
You see the the
lifetime.
You see the the infinite
You see the the infinite not
lifetime.
You see the the infinite not infinite
number
number but
number but quite
number but quite a
number but quite a few
number but quite a few incarnations.
Uh
Uh there's
number but quite a few incarnations.
Uh there's a
Uh there's a it's
number but quite a few incarnations.
Uh there's a it's just
Uh there's a it's just a
number but quite a few incarnations.
Uh there's a it's just a recall
Uh there's a it's just a recall of
number but quite a few incarnations.
Uh there's a it's just a recall of one
life.
life. It's
life. It's this
life. It's this life
life. It's this life one
life. It's this life one remembers
life. It's this life one remembers being
a
a pickpocket
life. It's this life one remembers being
a pickpocket in
a pickpocket in Paris
life. It's this life one remembers being
a pickpocket in Paris and
a pickpocket in Paris and various
life. It's this life one remembers being
a pickpocket in Paris and various things
like
like that.
It's
It's uh
like that.
It's uh it's
It's uh it's only
like that.
It's uh it's only just
It's uh it's only just within
like that.
It's uh it's only just within memory.
It's
It's just
It's just who
It's just who you
It's just who you are
It's just who you are or
It's just who you are or have
It's just who you are or have been
It's just who you are or have been and
and
and what
It's just who you are or have been and
and what was
and what was learned
It's just who you are or have been and
and what was learned there.
Uh
we
we shouldn't
Uh
we shouldn't say
we shouldn't say this
Uh
we shouldn't say this thing
we shouldn't say this thing on
Uh
we shouldn't say this thing on tape
we shouldn't say this thing on tape at
all,
all, but
all, but I
all, but I remember
all, but I remember one
all, but I remember one time
all, but I remember one time as
all, but I remember one time as a
pirate.
pirate. The
all, but I remember one time as a
pirate. The trouble
pirate. The trouble with
all, but I remember one time as a
pirate. The trouble with being
pirate. The trouble with being a
all, but I remember one time as a
pirate. The trouble with being a pirate
was
was not
was not what
was not what people
was not what people think
was not what people think pirates
was not what people think pirates are.
In
In fact,
was not what people think pirates are.
In fact, the
In fact, the booty
was not what people think pirates are.
In fact, the booty that
In fact, the booty that I
was not what people think pirates are.
In fact, the booty that I picked
In fact, the booty that I picked up
was not what people think pirates are.
In fact, the booty that I picked up in
that
that lifetime,
that lifetime, I
that lifetime, I still
that lifetime, I still know
that lifetime, I still know where
that lifetime, I still know where it
that lifetime, I still know where it is.
And
And I
that lifetime, I still know where it is.
And I can
And I can calibrate
that lifetime, I still know where it is.
And I can calibrate you
And I can calibrate you and
that lifetime, I still know where it is.
And I can calibrate you and tell
And I can calibrate you and tell you
exactly
exactly where
exactly where it
exactly where it is.
exactly where it is. Is
exactly where it is. Is I
exactly where it is. Is I hit
exactly where it is. Is I hit all
exactly where it is. Is I hit all that
gold
gold in
exactly where it is. Is I hit all that
gold in the
gold in the Caribbean.
exactly where it is. Is I hit all that
gold in the Caribbean. Anyway,
gold in the Caribbean. Anyway, in
exactly where it is. Is I hit all that
gold in the Caribbean. Anyway, in that
lifetime,
lifetime, the
lifetime, the problem
lifetime, the problem was
lifetime, the problem was not
lifetime, the problem was not a
lifetime, the problem was not a satanic
energy
energy of
lifetime, the problem was not a satanic
energy of killing
energy of killing off
lifetime, the problem was not a satanic
energy of killing off people.
energy of killing off people. That
lifetime, the problem was not a satanic
energy of killing off people. That was
not
not a
not a vicious
not a vicious fire
not a vicious fire at
not a vicious fire at all.
not a vicious fire at all. It
not a vicious fire at all. It was
not a vicious fire at all. It was greed.
I
I remember
not a vicious fire at all. It was greed.
I remember one
I remember one time
not a vicious fire at all. It was greed.
I remember one time I
I remember one time I had
not a vicious fire at all. It was greed.
I remember one time I had a
I remember one time I had a shipload
not a vicious fire at all. It was greed.
I remember one time I had a shipload of
captives,
captives, slaves,
captives, slaves, etc.
No,
No, they
captives, slaves, etc.
No, they were
No, they were captives.
captives, slaves, etc.
No, they were captives. Yeah,
No, they were captives. Yeah, captives.
I
I remember
I remember now.
I remember now. I
I remember now. I read.
I remember now. I read. Uh
I remember now. I read. Uh anyway,
I remember now. I read. Uh anyway, I
I remember now. I read. Uh anyway, I got
the
the crew
I remember now. I read. Uh anyway, I got
the crew off
the crew off the
I remember now. I read. Uh anyway, I got
the crew off the ship.
the crew off the ship. I
I remember now. I read. Uh anyway, I got
the crew off the ship. I got
the crew off the ship. I got the
I remember now. I read. Uh anyway, I got
the crew off the ship. I got the gold
and
and now
and now I'm
and now I'm stuck
and now I'm stuck with
and now I'm stuck with the
and now I'm stuck with the captives.
What
What the
and now I'm stuck with the captives.
What the hell
What the hell are
and now I'm stuck with the captives.
What the hell are you
What the hell are you going
and now I'm stuck with the captives.
What the hell are you going to
What the hell are you going to do
and now I'm stuck with the captives.
What the hell are you going to do with
them?
them? Well,
them? Well, I
them? Well, I was
them? Well, I was not
them? Well, I was not satanic.
them? Well, I was not satanic. In
them? Well, I was not satanic. In other
words,
words, I
them? Well, I was not satanic. In other
words, I wasn't
words, I wasn't going
them? Well, I was not satanic. In other
words, I wasn't going to
words, I wasn't going to beat
them? Well, I was not satanic. In other
words, I wasn't going to beat them
words, I wasn't going to beat them and
kill
kill them
kill them and
kill them and all,
kill them and all, but
kill them and all, but I
kill them and all, but I was
kill them and all, but I was very
kill them and all, but I was very very
greedy
greedy in
kill them and all, but I was very very
greedy in the
greedy in the thought
kill them and all, but I was very very
greedy in the thought the
greedy in the thought the cost
kill them and all, but I was very very
greedy in the thought the cost of
feeding
feeding these
feeding these feeding
feeding these feeding these
feeding these feeding these people
feeding these feeding these people and
giving
giving them
feeding these feeding these people and
giving them water
giving them water all
feeding these feeding these people and
giving them water all the
giving them water all the way
feeding these feeding these people and
giving them water all the way back
giving them water all the way back to
land.
land. So,
land. So, I
land. So, I sent
land. So, I sent them
land. So, I sent them all
land. So, I sent them all overboard.
Not
Not out
land. So, I sent them all overboard.
Not out of
Not out of cruelty,
land. So, I sent them all overboard.
Not out of cruelty, out
Not out of cruelty, out of
land. So, I sent them all overboard.
Not out of cruelty, out of greed.
Not out of cruelty, out of greed. I
didn't
didn't want
didn't want to
didn't want to spend
didn't want to spend the
didn't want to spend the money
didn't want to spend the money to
didn't want to spend the money to keep
them
them all
didn't want to spend the money to keep
them all alive.
Is
Is that
Is that a
Is that a fact?
Is
Is that
Is that a fact?
Is that a
Is that a fact? That
Is that a fact?
Is that a fact? That was
Is that a fact? That was a
Is that a fact?
Is that a fact? That was a fact.
Is that a fact? That was a fact. The
fact.
fact. Yeah,
fact. Yeah, that
fact. Yeah, that was
fact. Yeah, that was that
fact. Yeah, that was that lifetime.
Yeah.
Yeah. I
fact. Yeah, that was that lifetime.
Yeah. I mean,
Yeah. I mean, I
fact. Yeah, that was that lifetime.
Yeah. I mean, I remember
Yeah. I mean, I remember it
fact. Yeah, that was that lifetime.
Yeah. I mean, I remember it going
through.
through. Anyway,
through. Anyway, I
through. Anyway, I was
through. Anyway, I was cold-hearted.
Cold-hearted.
Cold-hearted. Not
through. Anyway, I was cold-hearted.
Cold-hearted. Not a
Cold-hearted. Not a savage.
through. Anyway, I was cold-hearted.
Cold-hearted. Not a savage. Not
Cold-hearted. Not a savage. Not a
killer.
killer. Not
killer. Not one
killer. Not one of
killer. Not one of these
just
just greed,
killer. Not one of these
just greed, I
just greed, I guess.
killer. Not one of these
just greed, I guess. Like
just greed, I guess. Like Scrooge.
Uh,
Uh, I
Uh, I know
Uh, I know where
Uh, I know where the
Uh, I know where the gold
Uh, I know where the gold is.
Uh, I know where the gold is. So,
Uh, I know where the gold is. So, from
that
that lifetime.
Uh, I know where the gold is. So, from
that lifetime. So,
that lifetime. So, let's
Uh, I know where the gold is. So, from
that lifetime. So, let's just
that lifetime. So, let's just do
Uh, I know where the gold is. So, from
that lifetime. So, let's just do it
that lifetime. So, let's just do it for
the
the fun
the fun of
the fun of the
the fun of the audience
the fun of the audience because
questions
questions of
the fun of the audience because
questions of Karma
questions of Karma came
the fun of the audience because
questions of Karma came up.
questions of Karma came up. That
the fun of the audience because
questions of Karma came up. That is
questions of Karma came up. That is a
fact.
fact. Resist.
fact. Resist. The
fact. Resist. The gold
fact. Resist. The gold is
fact. Resist. The gold is still
fact. Resist. The gold is still there.
Resist.
Resist. Uh
fact. Resist. The gold is still there.
Resist. Uh I
Resist. Uh I can
fact. Resist. The gold is still there.
Resist. Uh I can easily
Resist. Uh I can easily find
fact. Resist. The gold is still there.
Resist. Uh I can easily find it.
Resist. Uh I can easily find it. Resist.
I
I know
I know where
I know where it
I know where it is.
I know where it is. Uh
I know where it is. Uh it's
I know where it is. Uh it's uh
I know where it is. Uh it's uh advisable
for
for me
I know where it is. Uh it's uh advisable
for me to
for me to go
I know where it is. Uh it's uh advisable
for me to go get
for me to go get it.
I know where it is. Uh it's uh advisable
for me to go get it. Resist.
So
So I
So I I
So I I I
So I I I just
So I I I just had
So I I I just had to
So I I I just had to forget
So I I I just had to forget about
So I I I just had to forget about being
a
a multi-millionaire
So I I I just had to forget about being
a multi-millionaire in
a multi-millionaire in this
So I I I just had to forget about being
a multi-millionaire in this life
a multi-millionaire in this life and
So I I I just had to forget about being
a multi-millionaire in this life and uh
sell
sell newspapers,
sell newspapers, be
sell newspapers, be a
sell newspapers, be a bartender,
sell newspapers, be a bartender, drive
cabs,
cabs, and
sell newspapers, be a bartender, drive
cabs, and all
cabs, and all the
sell newspapers, be a bartender, drive
cabs, and all the things
cabs, and all the things I
sell newspapers, be a bartender, drive
cabs, and all the things I did
cabs, and all the things I did to
sell newspapers, be a bartender, drive
cabs, and all the things I did to make
cabs, and all the things I did to make a
few
few dollars
few dollars and
few dollars and survive.
few dollars and survive. And
few dollars and survive. And here's
multi-millions
multi-millions of
few dollars and survive. And here's
multi-millions of dollars
multi-millions of dollars gold
few dollars and survive. And here's
multi-millions of dollars gold sit
multi-millions of dollars gold sit down
there
there Caribbean
there Caribbean and
there Caribbean and God
there Caribbean and God says
there Caribbean and God says no.
there Caribbean and God says no. Well,
okay.
okay. No
there Caribbean and God says no. Well,
okay. No is
okay. No is no.
there Caribbean and God says no. Well,
okay. No is no. Might
okay. No is no. Might have
there Caribbean and God says no. Well,
okay. No is no. Might have to
okay. No is no. Might have to pay
there Caribbean and God says no. Well,
okay. No is no. Might have to pay tax
okay. No is no. Might have to pay tax on
it.
it. I
it. I don't
it. I don't know
it. I don't know what
it. I don't know what it
it. I don't know what it is.
Uh
Uh you
it. I don't know what it is.
Uh you pick
Uh you pick up
it. I don't know what it is.
Uh you pick up the
Uh you pick up the karma
it. I don't know what it is.
Uh you pick up the karma of
Uh you pick up the karma of that
it. I don't know what it is.
Uh you pick up the karma of that greed.
So
So uh
So uh therefore
So uh therefore what
So uh therefore what you've
So uh therefore what you've become
automatically
uh
uh goes
uh goes as
uh goes as a
uh goes as a continuum.
uh goes as a continuum. It's
uh goes as a continuum. It's just
uh goes as a continuum. It's just one
life
life you
uh goes as a continuum. It's just one
life you have.
life you have. There's
uh goes as a continuum. It's just one
life you have. There's only
life you have. There's only one
uh goes as a continuum. It's just one
life you have. There's only one life.
There's
There's not
There's not multiple
There's not multiple lives.
There's not multiple lives. Uh
There's not multiple lives. Uh there's
no
no such
There's not multiple lives. Uh there's
no such thing
no such thing as
There's not multiple lives. Uh there's
no such thing as going
no such thing as going from
There's not multiple lives. Uh there's
no such thing as going from life
no such thing as going from life to
non-life
non-life and
non-life and then
non-life and then back
non-life and then back to
non-life and then back to life
non-life and then back to life and
non-life and then back to life and then
incarnating
incarnating and
non-life and then back to life and then
incarnating and all.
incarnating and all. There's
non-life and then back to life and then
incarnating and all. There's only
incarnating and all. There's only one
life.
life. And
life. And so
life. And so long
life. And so long as
life. And so long as you
life. And so long as you identify
life. And so long as you identify with
the
the body,
life. And so long as you identify with
the body, you
the body, you limit
life. And so long as you identify with
the body, you limit the
the body, you limit the memory
life. And so long as you identify with
the body, you limit the memory to
the body, you limit the memory to this
body's
body's life.
body's life. As
body's life. As you
body's life. As you no
body's life. As you no longer
body's life. As you no longer identify
me
me or
body's life. As you no longer identify
me or the
me or the self
body's life. As you no longer identify
me or the self as
me or the self as this
body's life. As you no longer identify
me or the self as this physicality,
then
then the
then the memory
then the memory of
then the memory of all
then the memory of all the
then the memory of all the other
lifetimes
lifetimes comes
then the memory of all the other
lifetimes comes back.
lifetimes comes back. Many
then the memory of all the other
lifetimes comes back. Many people
lifetimes comes back. Many people have
memory
memory of
memory of previous
memory of previous lifetimes
memory of previous lifetimes when
memory of previous lifetimes when they
go
go out
memory of previous lifetimes when they
go out of
go out of body.
memory of previous lifetimes when they
go out of body. Once
go out of body. Once they've
memory of previous lifetimes when they
go out of body. Once they've escaped
this
this body
this body uh
this body uh they
this body uh they can
this body uh they can see
this body uh they can see all
this body uh they can see all the
this body uh they can see all the life
all
all the
this body uh they can see all the life
all the bodies.
all the bodies. Uh
this body uh they can see all the life
all the bodies. Uh so
all the bodies. Uh so karma
this body uh they can see all the life
all the bodies. Uh so karma then
all the bodies. Uh so karma then is
merely
merely the
merely the accumulated
merely the accumulated energy.
merely the accumulated energy. So
merely the accumulated energy. So every
action
action affects
merely the accumulated energy. So every
action affects your
action affects your calibrated
merely the accumulated energy. So every
action affects your calibrated level
action affects your calibrated level of
consciousness.
So
So the
consciousness.
So the spirit
So the spirit body
consciousness.
So the spirit body which
So the spirit body which has
consciousness.
So the spirit body which has a
So the spirit body which has a classic
name.
name. There's
name. There's a
name. There's a book
name. There's a book by
name. There's a book by a
name. There's a book by a Korean
name. There's a book by a Korean called
Omni
Omni Omniology
name. There's a book by a Korean called
Omni Omniology Professor
Omni Omniology Professor something
name. There's a book by a Korean called
Omni Omniology Professor something other
there's
there's a
there's a name
there's a name to
there's a name to that
there's a name to that aspect
there's a name to that aspect of
there's a name to that aspect of the
spirit
spirit body
there's a name to that aspect of the
spirit body which
spirit body which sort
there's a name to that aspect of the
spirit body which sort of
spirit body which sort of is
there's a name to that aspect of the
spirit body which sort of is like
spirit body which sort of is like a
little
little computer.
little computer. So
little computer. So your
little computer. So your spirit
little computer. So your spirit body
little computer. So your spirit body has
a
a little
little computer. So your spirit body has
a little spirit
a little spirit computer
little computer. So your spirit body has
a little spirit computer in
a little spirit computer in it
keeps
keeps track
keeps track of
keeps track of where
keeps track of where you
keeps track of where you are
keeps track of where you are in
keeps track of where you are in time
space
space and
keeps track of where you are in time
space and all
space and all your
keeps track of where you are in time
space and all your merits
space and all your merits demerits
keeps track of where you are in time
space and all your merits demerits and
uh
uh etc.
uh etc. Uh
uh etc. Uh so
that
that brings
uh etc. Uh so
that brings us
that brings us to
uh etc. Uh so
that brings us to a
that brings us to a recalibration
uh etc. Uh so
that brings us to a recalibration and
this
this is
this is a
this is a great
this is a great moment
this is a great moment in
this is a great moment in time
this is a great moment in time when
this is a great moment in time when the
we're
we're going
this is a great moment in time when the
we're going to
we're going to change
this is a great moment in time when the
we're going to change this
we're going to change this calibrated
levels
levels of
levels of consciousness.
levels of consciousness. Can
levels of consciousness. Can I
levels of consciousness. Can I just
bother
bother with
levels of consciousness. Can I just
bother with you?
bother with you? Uh
you
you see
you see this
you see this implies
you see this implies that
you see this implies that the
you see this implies that the top
you see this implies that the top is
better
better than.
you see this implies that the top is
better than. It's
better than. It's not
you see this implies that the top is
better than. It's not a
better than. It's not a matter
you see this implies that the top is
better than. It's not a matter of
better than. It's not a matter of better
than.
than. It's
than. It's different
than. It's different than
than. It's different than but
than. It's different than but not
than. It's different than but not better
than.
than. Uh
than. It's different than but not better
than. Uh you
than. Uh you don't
than. It's different than but not better
than. Uh you don't want
than. Uh you don't want somebody
than. It's different than but not better
than. Uh you don't want somebody in
than. Uh you don't want somebody in the
700s
700s as
700s as president
700s as president of
700s as president of the
700s as president of the United
700s as president of the United States.
Just
Just won't
700s as president of the United States.
Just won't work.
Just won't work. they
700s as president of the United States.
Just won't work. they wouldn't
Just won't work. they wouldn't have
700s as president of the United States.
Just won't work. they wouldn't have any
interest
interest at
interest at all.
interest at all. Uh
interest at all. Uh we
interest at all. Uh we found
interest at all. Uh we found that
interest at all. Uh we found that great
leaders
leaders of
interest at all. Uh we found that great
leaders of great
leaders of great religions
should
should be
should be around
should be around 570.
You
You cannot
should be around 570.
You cannot run
You cannot run a
should be around 570.
You cannot run a huge
You cannot run a huge organization
should be around 570.
You cannot run a huge organization like
the
the Catholic
the Catholic Church
the Catholic Church over
the Catholic Church over 600.
the Catholic Church over 600. It
wouldn't
wouldn't make
the Catholic Church over 600. It
wouldn't make any
wouldn't make any sense
the Catholic Church over 600. It
wouldn't make any sense at
wouldn't make any sense at all.
the Catholic Church over 600. It
wouldn't make any sense at all. And
wouldn't make any sense at all. And you
don't
don't have
don't have enough
don't have enough power,
don't have enough power, spiritual
don't have enough power, spiritual power
in
in the
don't have enough power, spiritual power
in the 400s.
570,
570, our
570, our current
570, our current pope
570, our current pope is
570, our current pope is a
570, our current pope is a wonderful
pope.
pope. I
570, our current pope is a wonderful
pope. I consider
pope. I consider him
570, our current pope is a wonderful
pope. I consider him great.
He
He tries
He tries to
He tries to heal.
He tries to heal. He
He tries to heal. He goes
He tries to heal. He goes 570
He tries to heal. He goes 570 is
unconditional
unconditional love.
He tries to heal. He goes 570 is
unconditional love. He
unconditional love. He tries
He tries to heal. He goes 570 is
unconditional love. He tries to
unconditional love. He tries to bring
everybody
everybody together
everybody together and
everybody together and heal
everybody together and heal up
everybody together and heal up the
everybody together and heal up the past
as
as best
everybody together and heal up the past
as best he
as best he can.
Uh
Uh the
Uh the Buddhist
Uh the Buddhist um
Uh the Buddhist um political
Uh the Buddhist um political leader,
what's
what's his
Uh the Buddhist um political leader,
what's his name?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yes.
>> Yeah. Yes. Runs
>> Yeah. Yes. Runs around
>> Yeah. Yes. Runs around 570.
>> Yeah. Yes. Runs around 570. If
>> Yeah. Yes. Runs around 570. If you're
going
going to
>> Yeah. Yes. Runs around 570. If you're
going to be
going to be the
>> Yeah. Yes. Runs around 570. If you're
going to be the great
going to be the great leader
>> Yeah. Yes. Runs around 570. If you're
going to be the great leader of
going to be the great leader of a
>> Yeah. Yes. Runs around 570. If you're
going to be the great leader of a great
world
world church,
world church, you
world church, you ought
world church, you ought to
world church, you ought to be
world church, you ought to be around
around
around the
world church, you ought to be around
around the ideal
around the ideal is
world church, you ought to be around
around the ideal is 570.
around the ideal is 570. If
world church, you ought to be around
around the ideal is 570. If you
around the ideal is 570. If you want
world church, you ought to be around
around the ideal is 570. If you want to
be
be president
be president of
be president of the
be president of the United
be president of the United States,
be president of the United States, you
better
better be
be president of the United States, you
better be around
better be around 450.
be president of the United States, you
better be around 450. All
better be around 450. All the
be president of the United States, you
better be around 450. All the great
presidents
presidents are
presidents are really
presidents are really around
presidents are really around 450.
presidents are really around 450. The
signers
signers of
presidents are really around 450. The
signers of the
signers of the instit
presidents are really around 450. The
signers of the instit constitution
uh
uh declaration
uh declaration of
uh declaration of independence
uh declaration of independence were
uh declaration of independence were more
in
in the
uh declaration of independence were more
in the 500s
in the 500s in
uh declaration of independence were more
in the 500s in the
in the 500s in the constitution
uh declaration of independence were more
in the 500s in the constitution United
States
States calibrates
States calibrates at
States calibrates at 700
higher
higher than
States calibrates at 700
higher than any
higher than any country
States calibrates at 700
higher than any country I
higher than any country I know
States calibrates at 700
higher than any country I know of.
higher than any country I know of. But
to
to be
to be a
to be a president
to be a president you
to be a president you better
to be a president you better be
to be a president you better be smart
around
around 450.
And
And u
And u the
And u the great
And u the great commentators
O'Reilly
O'Reilly and
And u the great commentators
O'Reilly and all
O'Reilly and all those
And u the great commentators
O'Reilly and all those people
O'Reilly and all those people they're
all
all around
all around 450.
all around 450. a
all around 450. a great
all around 450. a great uh
all around 450. a great uh so
all around 450. a great uh so 450
all around 450. a great uh so 450 is
all around 450. a great uh so 450 is the
intellect,
intellect, the
all around 450. a great uh so 450 is the
intellect, the capacity
intellect, the capacity to
all around 450. a great uh so 450 is the
intellect, the capacity to really
intellect, the capacity to really handle
this
this world.
this world. And
this world. And if
this world. And if you're
this world. And if you're going
this world. And if you're going to
this world. And if you're going to be
this world. And if you're going to be a
great
great political
this world. And if you're going to be a
great political reader
great political reader leader,
this world. And if you're going to be a
great political reader leader, you
better
better be
better be around
better be around 450
better be around 450 or
better be around 450 or you're
better be around 450 or you're going
better be around 450 or you're going to
get
get your
better be around 450 or you're going to
get your socks
get your socks beat
better be around 450 or you're going to
get your socks beat off.
get your socks beat off. Uh
better be around 450 or you're going to
get your socks beat off. Uh 500
get your socks beat off. Uh 500 and
better be around 450 or you're going to
get your socks beat off. Uh 500 and up,
one
one isn't
one isn't interested
one isn't interested in
one isn't interested in that
one isn't interested in that anymore.
Worldly
Worldly power
one isn't interested in that anymore.
Worldly power is
Worldly power is uninteresting
one isn't interested in that anymore.
Worldly power is uninteresting and
Worldly power is uninteresting and u
politics
politics are
politics are only
politics are only interesting
politics are only interesting to
politics are only interesting to the
degree
degree that
politics are only interesting to the
degree that they
degree that they reflect
politics are only interesting to the
degree that they reflect a
degree that they reflect a certain
spiritual
spiritual truth.
spiritual truth. So,
spiritual truth. So, what
spiritual truth. So, what I
spiritual truth. So, what I wanted
spiritual truth. So, what I wanted to
spiritual truth. So, what I wanted to do
is
is say
spiritual truth. So, what I wanted to do
is say that
is say that one
spiritual truth. So, what I wanted to do
is say that one is
is say that one is not
spiritual truth. So, what I wanted to do
is say that one is not better
is say that one is not better than
spiritual truth. So, what I wanted to do
is say that one is not better than the
other.
other. Uh,
other. Uh, and
other. Uh, and many
other. Uh, and many of
other. Uh, and many of my
other. Uh, and many of my favorite
other. Uh, and many of my favorite my
favorite
favorite people
other. Uh, and many of my favorite my
favorite people that
favorite people that that
other. Uh, and many of my favorite my
favorite people that that Sus
favorite people that that Sus and
other. Uh, and many of my favorite my
favorite people that that Sus and I
favorite people that that Sus and I both
love
love very
love very much
love very much are
love very much are in
love very much are in in
love very much are in in the
love very much are in in the 300s.
They're
They're very
love very much are in in the 300s.
They're very willing.
Um,
Um, we've
Um, we've got
Um, we've got carpenters
Um, we've got carpenters working
Um, we've got carpenters working for
Um, we've got carpenters working for us
now
now who
Um, we've got carpenters working for us
now who are
now who are really
Um, we've got carpenters working for us
now who are really great
now who are really great people.
Um, we've got carpenters working for us
now who are really great people. 310
now who are really great people. 310 is
willingness.
willingness. Yeah,
willingness. Yeah, let
willingness. Yeah, let me
willingness. Yeah, let me do
willingness. Yeah, let me do it.
willingness. Yeah, let me do it. Let
willingness. Yeah, let me do it. Let me
help.
help. Let
willingness. Yeah, let me do it. Let me
help. Let me
help. Let me They're
willingness. Yeah, let me do it. Let me
help. Let me They're great
help. Let me They're great people
willingness. Yeah, let me do it. Let me
help. Let me They're great people to
help. Let me They're great people to be
with.
with. They
with. They build
with. They build the
with. They build the whole
with. They build the whole world.
with. They build the whole world. The
whole
whole world
with. They build the whole world. The
whole world is
whole world is built
with. They build the whole world. The
whole world is built by
whole world is built by people
with. They build the whole world. The
whole world is built by people in
whole world is built by people in the
300s.
300s. Uh,
and
and uh,
300s. Uh,
and uh, this
and uh, this we
300s. Uh,
and uh, this we have
and uh, this we have a
300s. Uh,
and uh, this we have a crew
and uh, this we have a crew working
300s. Uh,
and uh, this we have a crew working for
us
us right
us right now
us right now that
us right now that has
us right now that has a
us right now that has a little
us right now that has a little white
dog.
dog. And
us right now that has a little white
dog. And this
dog. And this little
us right now that has a little white
dog. And this little white
dog. And this little white dog
us right now that has a little white
dog. And this little white dog uh,
dog. And this little white dog uh, who
us right now that has a little white
dog. And this little white dog uh, who I
never
never met
never met before.
never met before. Here's
never met before. Here's this
never met before. Here's this workman.
He's
He's a
never met before. Here's this workman.
He's a one
He's a one dog
never met before. Here's this workman.
He's a one dog contractor.
He's a one dog contractor. You
never met before. Here's this workman.
He's a one dog contractor. You know,
they
they come
they come one
they come one dog,
they come one dog, two
they come one dog, two dog,
one
one dog
they come one dog, two dog,
one dog contractor.
one dog contractor. And
they come one dog, two dog,
one dog contractor. And this
one dog contractor. And this little
they come one dog, two dog,
one dog contractor. And this little dog
goes
goes everywhere
goes everywhere with
goes everywhere with him,
goes everywhere with him, you
goes everywhere with him, you know,
loyal
loyal as
goes everywhere with him, you know,
loyal as can
loyal as can be.
goes everywhere with him, you know,
loyal as can be. So,
loyal as can be. So, here's
goes everywhere with him, you know,
loyal as can be. So, here's this
loyal as can be. So, here's this white
dog
dog who
dog who I'd
dog who I'd never
dog who I'd never met
dog who I'd never met before.
dog who I'd never met before. He
dog who I'd never met before. He never
met
met me.
dog who I'd never met before. He never
met me. And
met me. And this
dog who I'd never met before. He never
met me. And this dog
met me. And this dog comes
dog who I'd never met before. He never
met me. And this dog comes right
met me. And this dog comes right over
just
just instantly
just instantly loving
just instantly loving him.
just instantly loving him. instantly
loving
loving you.
just instantly loving him. instantly
loving you. Just
loving you. Just glad
just instantly loving him. instantly
loving you. Just glad to
loving you. Just glad to see
just instantly loving him. instantly
loving you. Just glad to see you.
loving you. Just glad to see you. And
gosh,
gosh, let's
gosh, let's be
gosh, let's be friends.
gosh, let's be friends. And
gosh, let's be friends. And boy,
instantly
instantly we
gosh, let's be friends. And boy,
instantly we were
instantly we were like
gosh, let's be friends. And boy,
instantly we were like intimate
instantly we were like intimate loving
pals.
pals. Instant
pals. Instant love.
pals. Instant love. Huh?
pals. Instant love. Huh? We
pals. Instant love. Huh? We calibrated
that
that dog.
pals. Instant love. Huh? We calibrated
that dog. Let's
that dog. Let's do
pals. Instant love. Huh? We calibrated
that dog. Let's do that
that dog. Let's do that dog.
That
That dog
That dog uh
That dog uh who
That dog uh who was
That dog uh who was up
That dog uh who was up in
That dog uh who was up in the
That dog uh who was up in the White
That dog uh who was up in the White M
right
right now.
That dog uh who was up in the White M
right now. Uh
right now. Uh that
That dog uh who was up in the White M
right now. Uh that dog,
right now. Uh that dog, we
That dog uh who was up in the White M
right now. Uh that dog, we have
permission,
permission, right?
permission, right? He's
permission, right? He's over
permission, right? He's over I'm
permission, right? He's over I'm just
permission, right? He's over I'm just my
guess.
guess. He's
permission, right? He's over I'm just my
guess. He's 500.
guess. He's 500. He's
permission, right? He's over I'm just my
guess. He's 500. He's over
guess. He's 500. He's over five.
permission, right? He's over I'm just my
guess. He's 500. He's over five. 501
guess. He's 500. He's over five. 501 502
504 505
504 505 506
504 505 506 507
504 505 506 507 58
about
about 505
504 505 506 507 58
about 505 508
pure
pure love
pure love first
pure love first time
pure love first time I
pure love first time I calibrated
pure love first time I calibrated a
dog's
dog's wagging
pure love first time I calibrated a
dog's wagging tail
dog's wagging tail and
pure love first time I calibrated a
dog's wagging tail and got
dog's wagging tail and got 500
pure love first time I calibrated a
dog's wagging tail and got 500 I
dog's wagging tail and got 500 I said
whoa
whoa half
whoa half the
whoa half the people
whoa half the people on
whoa half the people on the
whoa half the people on the planet
whoa half the people on the planet don't
we
we calibrated
whoa half the people on the planet don't
we calibrated our
we calibrated our our
whoa half the people on the planet don't
we calibrated our our cat's
we calibrated our our cat's purr
whoa half the people on the planet don't
we calibrated our our cat's purr let's
get
get kitty's
get kitty's purr
get kitty's purr oh
get kitty's purr oh I
get kitty's purr oh I love
get kitty's purr oh I love that
get kitty's purr oh I love that kitty
kitty's
kitty's purr
get kitty's purr oh I love that kitty
kitty's purr is
kitty's purr is over
get kitty's purr oh I love that kitty
kitty's purr is over 500
kitty's purr is over 500 is
get kitty's purr oh I love that kitty
kitty's purr is over 500 is it
kitty's purr is over 500 is it 502
get kitty's purr oh I love that kitty
kitty's purr is over 500 is it 502 2
kitty's purr is over 500 is it 502 2 504
kitty's
kitty's purr
kitty's purr kitty
kitty's purr kitty just
kitty's purr kitty just sits
kitty's purr kitty just sits there
kitty's purr kitty just sits there just
radiating
radiating pure
radiating pure love.
So
So here
radiating pure love.
So here love
So here love comes
radiating pure love.
So here love comes through
So here love comes through the
radiating pure love.
So here love comes through the animal
kingdom
kingdom without
kingdom without intellect.
kingdom without intellect. People
kingdom without intellect. People look
down
down on
kingdom without intellect. People look
down on on
down on on the
kingdom without intellect. People look
down on on the animal
down on on the animal because
kingdom without intellect. People look
down on on the animal because it
down on on the animal because it doesn't
have
have an
have an intellect.
have an intellect. See
have an intellect. See that's
have an intellect. See that's the
have an intellect. See that's the ego.
They
They say
have an intellect. See that's the ego.
They say the
They say the animal
have an intellect. See that's the ego.
They say the animal don't
They say the animal don't have
have an intellect. See that's the ego.
They say the animal don't have an
They say the animal don't have an ego.
Can't
Can't get
Can't get screwed
Can't get screwed up
Can't get screwed up like
Can't get screwed up like humans.
This
This dog
Can't get screwed up like humans.
This dog just
This dog just comes
Can't get screwed up like humans.
This dog just comes over
This dog just comes over and
Can't get screwed up like humans.
This dog just comes over and loves
This dog just comes over and loves you
like
like that.
like that. Isn't
like that. Isn't that
like that. Isn't that great?
like that. Isn't that great? No
like that. Isn't that great? No wonder
people
people love
like that. Isn't that great? No wonder
people love their
people love their animals.
like that. Isn't that great? No wonder
people love their animals. And
people love their animals. And we,
like that. Isn't that great? No wonder
people love their animals. And we, we
know,
know, people
know, people say,
know, people say, "Well,
know, people say, "Well, he's
know, people say, "Well, he's sick.
know, people say, "Well, he's sick. You
know,
know, he
know, people say, "Well, he's sick. You
know, he thinks
know, he thinks more
know, people say, "Well, he's sick. You
know, he thinks more about
know, he thinks more about his
know, people say, "Well, he's sick. You
know, he thinks more about his dog
know, he thinks more about his dog than
he
he does
he does other
he does other people."
he does other people." Well,
he does other people." Well, the
he does other people." Well, the people
around
around him
he does other people." Well, the people
around him calibrate
around him calibrate about
he does other people." Well, the people
around him calibrate about 190
around him calibrate about 190 and
he does other people." Well, the people
around him calibrate about 190 and his
dog
dog calibrates
dog calibrates at
dog calibrates at 500.
Love
Love goes
dog calibrates at 500.
Love goes to
Love goes to love,
dog calibrates at 500.
Love goes to love, right?
Oh,
Oh, I
Oh, I just
Oh, I just love
Oh, I just love So,
Oh, I just love So, I
Oh, I just love So, I instantly
Oh, I just love So, I instantly love
that
that dog
Oh, I just love So, I instantly love
that dog and
that dog and I
Oh, I just love So, I instantly love
that dog and I instantly
that dog and I instantly love
Oh, I just love So, I instantly love
that dog and I instantly love the
that dog and I instantly love the kitty.
So,
So, isn't
So, isn't that
So, isn't that strange,
So, isn't that strange, huh?
So, isn't that strange, huh? That
So, isn't that strange, huh? That love
comes
comes up
So, isn't that strange, huh? That love
comes up then.
comes up then. So
So, isn't that strange, huh? That love
comes up then. So we
comes up then. So we were
So, isn't that strange, huh? That love
comes up then. So we were saying
comes up then. So we were saying this
morning
morning there's
morning there's like
morning there's like two
morning there's like two channels.
morning there's like two channels. One
there's
there's a
morning there's like two channels. One
there's a channel
there's a channel of
morning there's like two channels. One
there's a channel of that
there's a channel of that which
morning there's like two channels. One
there's a channel of that which is
venomous,
venomous, poisonous
venomous, poisonous hatred
venomous, poisonous hatred and
venomous, poisonous hatred and brings
about
about death.
venomous, poisonous hatred and brings
about death. Then
about death. Then there's
venomous, poisonous hatred and brings
about death. Then there's that
about death. Then there's that which
venomous, poisonous hatred and brings
about death. Then there's that which is
nurturing,
nurturing, benign,
nurturing, benign, peaceful
nurturing, benign, peaceful and
nurturing, benign, peaceful and serves
as
as an
nurturing, benign, peaceful and serves
as an avenue
as an avenue for
nurturing, benign, peaceful and serves
as an avenue for love.
In
In my
In my view
In my view it
In my view it love
In my view it love manifested
In my view it love manifested within
In my view it love manifested within the
physical
physical domain
uh
uh by
uh by motherhood.
uh by motherhood. There
uh by motherhood. There was
uh by motherhood. There was no
uh by motherhood. There was no love.
Dinosaur
Dinosaur doesn't
uh by motherhood. There was no love.
Dinosaur doesn't love
Dinosaur doesn't love its
uh by motherhood. There was no love.
Dinosaur doesn't love its eggs.
Dinosaur doesn't love its eggs. He
uh by motherhood. There was no love.
Dinosaur doesn't love its eggs. He just
lays
lays an
lays an egg
lays an egg and
lays an egg and goes
lays an egg and goes off,
lays an egg and goes off, right?
lays an egg and goes off, right? It's
the
the maternal.
lays an egg and goes off, right? It's
the maternal. The
the maternal. The maternal,
lays an egg and goes off, right? It's
the maternal. The maternal, the
the maternal. The maternal, the mother
who
who cares
who cares about
who cares about the
who cares about the child.
who cares about the child. That's
who cares about the child. That's the
beginning.
beginning. That's
who cares about the child. That's the
beginning. That's when
beginning. That's when love
who cares about the child. That's the
beginning. That's when love began
beginning. That's when love began to
shine
shine on
shine on the
shine on the earth.
shine on the earth. There
shine on the earth. There was
shine on the earth. There was no
shine on the earth. There was no love
shine on the earth. There was no love in
the
the world
shine on the earth. There was no love in
the world of
the world of dinosaurs.
shine on the earth. There was no love in
the world of dinosaurs. Show
the world of dinosaurs. Show me
shine on the earth. There was no love in
the world of dinosaurs. Show me some
love
love in
love in the
love in the world
love in the world of
love in the world of dinosaurs.
love in the world of dinosaurs. It
doesn't
doesn't exist
love in the world of dinosaurs. It
doesn't exist there.
doesn't exist there. Everything
love in the world of dinosaurs. It
doesn't exist there. Everything eats
everything
everything else.