Oh is something else
and the sound of M is inherent in all
sound and it can be heard by anybody who
attunes to it and you can hear it within
your own mind and it's the sound of the
universe
is there at all times. S
is there at all times.
We know that the
practice of Dr. Diamond where you go,
you're all familiar with that, right? to
get you out of a negative feeling uh or
a negative space. You know, you pound
the thymus gland and you go, "Haha,
and you think of someone you love and
that instantly raises your energy and
your vibration."
And if you were in an energy field, it
now puts you in a positive one. And it
has an effect on the immune system and
of course on the acupuncture system and
on the kinesiologic response.
So now we we've tried to create a
context of rationality unnecessarily but
because the ego is a doubting Thomas and
that the ego is built on nothing but
doubt
because of his doubt. Um we tried to
build a logical premise upon which
one can approach spiritual
reality and at the same time be logical,
scientific, modern, advanced and
educated.
Anybody argues about you say you don't
know much about quantum mechanics do
you?
The mere belief that prayer prayer is
effective is sufficient to make prayer
effective. Is it not? Even if prayer
wasn't effective, the fact we all
believe it's effective, it now is
effective. I'll tell you. So that
quantum potentiality then has no
limitation. And therefore the the degree
of one's faith
then empowers it empowers it. This
gripure is enormously powerful. What it
holds in mind rings out throughout all
of human consciousness.
It takes only a few people very advanced
only a few consciousnesses very advanced
to negate all of all of Ethiopia and
Bafra and god knows what else goes on
because the power of that is so enormous
that it counterbalances all of that. So
we all serve all of life through all of
our spiritual endeavors, everything that
we surrender to God. Um the good of all,
every advance, every forgiveness that we
personally do,
every time we let go of feeling sad and
unhappy,
every negativity we let go benefits all
of mankind. Consequently, anybody who's
in spiritual endeavor is of service
of service to man at all times just by
their intention.
So meditation then is really
changing the context of one's life that
one's life becomes a meditation
in that it's it's lived in the in form
but in the context of the awareness that
the divinity is the unmanifest out of
which the manifest is arising and you're
merely witnessing
creation unfolding in the world of form
as it appears to perception.
Well, we had some questions this
morning.
Shall we do a few questions?
Anybody got any questions they'd like to
bring up? If not, we'll read these.
There was something we were going to
explain today and I forgot what it was.
Um
so people um ask you know how can they
advance their consciousness? In a way I
I wish I'd never calibrated the levels
of consciousness because
people miss the point of it. The point
of it is merely to show where one is on
a pathway.
Consciousness is evolving. Where is it
at a certain point? Well, of course it
is amazingly instructive to calibrate a
great many things. and a book we're
working on now. We're going to do a
thousand calibrations. We've got 998
down. I guess we'll do two for lunch and
there we got it.
It gives you a comprehension of the
evolution of consciousness
from the beginning of time as it first
manifests on this planet
uh in the forms of creation as it
evolves up through
the expressions of life.
How it evolves through
the primate and into takes expression in
the form of the human brain.
Homo erectus now homo sapien. And in the
book we announce the birth of a new
genus of man homo spiritus.
The nature of man has actually shifted
in the late 1980s when the consciousness
level of mankind went from 190 which is
non-integrous and non- integrous and
non-truth
and it jumped to 207.
That was the beginning of a new
paradigm. A new paradigm of what it
means to be human.
One could be as a siten, as a hun, one
could be called human
calibrating at 110,
slaughtering everybody. The only thing
that criminative men thought about was
slaughtering others and then looting and
raping and then slaughtering some more.
And if they had nobody to slaughter,
they got bored and they sailed around
looking for somebody to slaughter.
That's all they did. Europe era after
era, wasn't it? Century after century
was this horde from here or this horde
from here? I mean, these people had
nothing to do. What' they do? Just sit
around. Hey, let's let's go raid
somebody.
So we call that human. Well, it's really
sort of prehuman, isn't it? It's it it's
human in a anatomical kind of
definition.
Uh it's not human in what we mean by
human.
Human by what we mean is human. To be
human means to be aware of the impact of
what you're doing on others. It's the
beginning of spiritual awareness.
We can't really call bin Laden human.
He's humanoid. Sort of humanoid. Looks
human. Talks human.
But without that inner essence that we
identify with humanness. Humanness. I
mean it's in, you know, it's not really
human yet.
Calibrates at 90. That's not really
That's uh the savage horde, the
barbarian.
Then in the late 80s suddenly we see the
conscious level of man jump to 207
in which spiritual awareness, spiritual
integrity,
spiritual awareness as an innate human
quality comes into full recognition.
You see in the evolutionary tree of the
primate
uh Neanderthal man doesn't evolve to
homo erectus and homo sapien. What
happens is on the homminid tree
this branch goes off becomes
that and this branch breaks off. It's a
it's a new branch. It's not the
evolution. Neanderthal doesn't become
President Bush.
Neanderthal
goes this far and then Neanderthal then
Carl Magdan comes out. See? And then uh
oh you know the names of all they're
always finding some fossil somewhere
creep down man or something no pilt down
man or chromagnet man or so the thing
evolutionary wise that's interesting is
that they are different branches off the
tree it is not the original branch
the mouse does not become the lion no
mouse goes off this way then the wreck
comes off this way and then our supio
goes off this way
so I think What's happened is now is
that the human the evolution of the
human consciousness is such that the
human nervous system can now handle the
energy required for spiritual awareness.
I don't think Lord entities I don't
think their nervous system is able to
handle it.
We never asked these things before.
Let's ask those just for fun. the the
the nervous system of the nervous system
of u Neanderthal man
uh
is equipped to handle spiritual
awareness resist he can't handle it
um so what's happening now is actually
through evolution through evolution the
nervous system is able to handle
spiritual energy resistance
in this lifetime it's been extremely
agonizingly painful resist has been
extremely agonizingly painful
because each
sudden sometimes extremely major advance
in consciousness was also accompanied by
a severe burning painful sensation
throughout the human body. That's what
went on the other day. Resist. Yeah. It
just never stops. So it's like the
nervous system is evolving to handle
the spiritual energy is quite demanding.
Jesus Christ sweat blood. You know the
Buddha was tormented by agonies of his
like his bones were all broken
beset by
negative energies and energy descent.
But he said his bones are all broken.
And we read that in Korea and instantly
it was okay that that pain and agony
would come and go.
Okay for the Buddha, it's okay for me.
So what's happening then is that the
nervous system is evolving to be able to
handle higher spiritual energies. If
they're not that well evolved yet,
they're painful. They're painful. The
ender man would have been had would have
been horrible. he would have been
miserable.
Let's just I wanted to ask personalize
it because the witness of personal
experiences
um
uh let's see how we can ask this.
All right. So for mankind to evolve more
spiritually his nervous system actually
has to evolve to be able to handle
resist
actual nervous system. Huh?
>> Let's see. Is it the neurons? It's the
neurons themselves that have to evolve,
resist. Huh.
It's still not clear to me what causes
the actual pain of it. But anyway, all
right. So then what's going on is that
through evolution then evolution is is
is the way creation appears on the
planet. The nervous system of mankind is
evolving
so as to be able to handle the enormous
power of a higher spiritual energy.
If you're not ready for it, it's really
quite painful. It really is quite
agonizing. And uh when you clear up some
spiritual dilemma, at least in my
experience, some major spiritual
dilemma, there would be a whole period
of like feeling like all your nerves are
on fire. I mean, it's just horrible
really.
But the realization of what's the cause
of it makes it bearable. So it means to
me that evolution now is that mankind's
consciousness level is rising. His
nervous system has to rise in order to
be able to handle it. He he has to
evolve in order to be able to handle a
higher spiritual energy.
Um
yeah, we share our spiritual strength
and hope with each other because through
that mutuality we create a field and the
field itself tends to support the
advancement of consciousness.
The teacher the energy field of the
teacher is one of context.
One of context. Out of the context
arises content which the audience finds
interesting but it's really the context
that gives the content
its meaningfulness its
comprehensibleness
its impact.
Um
it helps people
accept things that they find
unacceptable.
Uh
there there's always questions about the
technique of kinesiology and I can't
really go into it. Um
we've done it many many times. I'm going
to we'll go through it one more time.
We'll do we'll do it one more time. The
basics of what you need to know. Susie
and I come on over here in the light.
Susie, you see the two people have to be
integrous. You've got a calibrator with
200. It means your intention has to be
that you're interested in truth for the
sake of truth. You know what I'm saying?
Um it's like an innate curiosity about
what is the truth of this. You know what
is the what is the truth of something.
So you have an innate curiosity about
what is the truth of the thing. Not for
some reward, not for sensation.
Uh not because you can win in the stock
market, you know, you have to really
really want to know what is the truth of
this matter. So the two people are
integrous.
They don't have any background noise.
They don't have any music. They don't
have any distractions. Their intention
is to come together to discern the
truth. We've found an experience which
one of us serves as the best. I'm good
with questioning, she's good at
answering. So you find a person you can
work with. Now the the question itself,
the intention of the question has to be
integrous.
Uh so two integrous people come
together. They want to know for the sake
of truth and the pursuit of truth what
you know what are the facts about the
case and they then simply ask with two
fingers and they press down and I say
resist that's all she does to resist you
know you don't have to be a rocket
scientist to do kinesiology some people
make it so difficult they write me a
long letter what
this audience here calibrates over 400
resist
okay got it that's All there is to the
test. That's all there is to it. Just
yes or no. All right. Now, there's a
comparative difference of the strength.
I don't bear down as hard as I can to
see if I can break her arm down. I'm
just going to push down like with a
couple of feathers, you know? Couple of
feathers. Okay. Um,
what I'm holding in mind is true. Is it
okay? Okay. See, I can do it with one
finger.
So, she resists to the degree that it
takes to resist one finger.
All right. Now, if I ask another
question and the same amount of
resistance doesn't hold her, then she
goes down.
So, when she resists, she resists with
the same amount of strength. Let's say,
how much strength does it take to resist
one finger?
All right. Next time I ask a question,
she's going to resist to that extent
because we want to compare the two. You
understand? We're trying to compare two
states of strength.
So if this time she resists lightly and
the next time she resists mightily,
she's going to throw off the answer.
So the person if you use common sense,
what you're trying to do is just you're
trying to get a comparison between the
two states.
All right? That's all we have to do. And
so it's very very simple. It's yes or
no. So when I used to do it in front of
large audiences, we had a thousand
people. We'd divide up into 500 group
pairs of doctor and patient and I would
hold up an apple and I'd say, "Okay,
everybody in the audience, doctors, get
ready. I'll get test the patient. Okay,
now look at this apple up here. Okay,
now resist."
And then I say, "All right, now look at
this apple." Then they would resist.
Resist. Okay. They would look at this
apple, but on that apple they would all
go weak. This is a thousand people. I've
never met I never I don't know any
500 couples of doctor and patient. When
they looked at this apple, they all went
weak. When they looked at this apple,
they all went strong. One had pesticide
in it. The other didn't. That's all
there was. We repeated the same thing in
Korea. Dr. Moon handed us two bags with
green leaves in it. We didn't know what
it was even about. She said, "Test these
out." One made everybody go weak, one
made everybody go strong. Then she
opened up later and said, "Oh, one had a
pesticide in it." All right.
So, that's all there is to the
kinesiologic test is not really
difficult.
If people get different answers, there's
a number of reasons. One is the shift of
intention. You could have background
music. You can have things throwing you
off.
Um
we sometimes find that husbands and
wives don't work well together.
I don't know why but not not
infrequently. Uh we'll get a married
couple say well you know for some reason
we can't seem to work with each other. I
suppose if we spend enough time with
kinesiologic research we could find why
that is so in that specific pair. We did
find the reason something about uh G
energy. Oh yes. Then we found that some
people really couldn't do kinesiology.
It had to do with somehow with the
balance of the chi energy in their
acupuncture system. The energy system,
wasn't that right? Yeah. We we never did
really find out why a lot of people
can't do it other than non integrity.
Some people are not really capable of it
because of the balance, the cheat
balance in their energy field resist.
Yeah, we got a yes to that. Um, of the
people in this room, for instance, what
percent would have that problem? Can we
we we have permission to ask that
resist? More than 5% might have that
problem. More than 4% might have that
problem. In this Oh, that's because of
the people in this room. Oh. Oh, yeah.
In the public. In the public. But in the
public, more than 5%. 10%. 15%.
>> Yeah. So, in the public, just in the
public at large, there's probably 10% of
the people just there's something about
the imbalance of their chi energy.
They're not suitable
in a more spiritually committed group
like this. the energies are more. All
right. So, I thought just I just wanted
to answer the that question about
kinesiology because you can't go into
the details.
Um, and you have to find somebody that
you can work with.
Um,
we were talking about how to forgive
yourself out in the courtyard before
and um and we were joking around. If
you're rotten to no good.
So you're rotten to no good.
So
what's to forgive yourself for?
That you're wicked and bad. Of course
you're wicked and bad. We're all wicked
and bad, man. We wouldn't be here,
right? You're rotten. No good. And it
was a terrible and awful thing to do.
You're right. That's a fact.
You see, so we unplug the guilt because
guilt is it, like we were saying before,
guilt is its own payoff.
If it's okay to feel guilty and okay to
be wrong and okay, then there's no
payoff and that disappears it. How long
can you hang on guily guilt? if it's
okay to be rotten and no good.
Everybody here's rotten and no good,
right?
What would a lifetime be if you weren't
rotten and no good? You wouldn't have to
be here. I mean, a whole lifetime is
spent overcoming being rotten no good,
worthless,
wrong, stupid.
And if not, uh, our endeavor is to prove
that the other guy is.
If we're not, then he is. So, uh, that's
the game, huh?
Well, they asked me some teachers here.
I don't know. We're going to do a lot of
teachers in the book. Um,
some of these teachers, I don't know.
People find obscure writers elsewhere
that I've never heard of. I don't know.
All the all the truth has ever been
needed has already been written. You
know, you don't have to look through the
back stacks in the bookstore to find
hocus pocus that lived in 1412 what he
said. I mean, it's interesting what he
said and it may or may not be true. And
I can understand
that one would want to know, but we can
ask this one. I don't know who he is,
but it probably wouldn't be valid. No, I
don't think it'd be valid because I
don't know who this is. Uh
I want to finish these questions before
noon. Each question we only have a few
minutes. Each question brings up a whole
different principle and a whole
different area for discussion. You know
any one of these questions could we
could spend the entire morning um
tracing it through to its ultimate
meaning.
Is discovering the unmanifest a function
of exact focusing or peripheral focus?
It says, "Please don't say both." Well,
I was going to say both.
Oh, well. Uh, no.
Seeing the unmanifest, seeing that which
is nonform and form is far, it is far
more advanced. You start out by
realizing that that which you are is the
context out of which all of life and all
of its expressions, both subjective and
supposedly objective, is arising.
That you are the field out of which that
is all arising.
It starts out visual field that all
that's hap happening within this room is
happening within an infinite space of
silence and nonform.
um out of which arises sound and all
those things. Is there such a thing as
individual identity?
Um there is as far as imagination goes,
as far as the ego goes, that which is
karmically inheritable from one thing to
the next is the degree to which one
holds one's identity of self with the
ego.
It's a illusion. It's transitory. It
lasts of course for hundreds of millions
or thousands of years.
So it'll do till it wears out. But
the thought that I am this or I am that
within form then creates a karmic
consequence
creates a karmic consequence.
The thought that I am an individual
separate from God that um that I am that
which is born and dies
that I am that which calls itself me.
This physicality and its history yes
that'll have karmic consequences.
That's what the Buddha meant when the
Buddha said, "If you don't want to keep
reincarnating, then you've got to become
enlightened and transcend and realize
that you are that out of which
you are that out of which that
formulation arises. You are not the
formulation.
You're you're that out of which the
formulation arises.
You're not the thought. You're that out
of which the thought arises.
Huh?
You're not the emotion. You're the
source out of which that emotion arises
to realize that you are a priority to
mind. So in meditation then one
witnesses the procession
and by what one pointedness of mind one
all of a sudden in one instant gets that
I am that
out of which thought arises. Huh.
You realize that mind the that mind in
speaking generically
is that which which is present just
prior to thought.
The field the field here you don't know
thought until you you you hear it from
me. What was there right prior to my
saying that
you understand
there is a readiness a uh a presence
the capacity for awareness the capacity
of hearingness the capacity for
comprehensionness
is already here it's already in
existence before I just said that
got it right before I said it you're
you're what you are before I say
How do I know what it's going to do? It
just jumps across the stage and does
anything wants to.
It does anything it wants to. Thank
goodness it obeys the law would get
arrested.
Thank goodness he's been trained
to at least have a have a radar unit in
the car.
Ah, yes. That radar unit tells you
what's coming up ahead of time. Huh?
Little anticipatory preparation.
And that's what the mind is doing. You
see, like a little radar unit. It isn't
there on your screen yet. So you're the
screen that has the capacity to register
the thought as it's said.
It's very simple to realize that you're
the unmanifest out of which the manifest
arises. Right? Everybody here knows that
already. Correct.
Isn't that so?
>> Oh, thank you God. Jeez.
The Buddha told me that. I said, "I'll
be sure and tell him when I go back."
You know,
he said, "We didn't have the printing
press in those." Dave, Dave, when you go
back, I want you to bring this up.
Buddha, don't feel guilty about it.
Never mind. I will see to it that it
gets said. Let's see if the Buddha wants
me to say that.
>> Oh, the pressure's on.
We have permission to ask. This is the
intention of the Buddha resistance. All
right. Thank you. The transition of the
Buddha is
out of the unmanifest the potentiality
to realize that you are the source of
the manifest. Out of which comes
existence,
out of which comes beingness, I amness.
The book I'm finishing now is called I.
Not I amness. Amnness is already late in
the game. I want you to understand I is
prior to amnest prior to existence that
which I was prior to this little body
suddenly appearing in this wagon
trauma day.
The infinite potentiality for that
consciousness to arise and then presume
existence. Yeah. because it identified
with the physicality then went into
shock about existence versus
non-existence.
The unmanifest is prior to beingness,
prior to existence, prior to isness,
prior to amness,
prior to amnness, prior to isness, prior
to existence, prior to consciousness
itself.
Mr.
said that, didn't he?
He was right.
First time I read that, I thought, what
the hell does that mean?
It's just that it's so obvious that,
as you can see, it's extremely obvious.
There you go.
Just know that you are the field out of
which arises the content of the field.
Because how do you know there's anything
in the field? You can only know it by
knowing it. That which has the capacity
of knowingness has the capacity for
recognition. See, see we point this out
here. Recognition.
You say, you see, it goes back then
through this. That's what meditation is.
So contemplation then is walking about
in the world in a meditative state in
which one's focus is is on the source
out of which the entire phenomena is
arising
outside of time outside of
conceptualization outside of wording
this out of outside of adding giving it
names. Huh?
There's no there's awareness of
awareness, but there's no awareness of
an I being aware. That's a mentation
that you'll add on top of it.
Okay. Is there any more questions?
Because I think we have to stop
in exactly two minutes.
>> If anybody has a question that's
absolutely silent and wordless, I'm
right here.
>> Let's start from the Yes. You want to
calibrate the level of the audience
before and after.
>> We we we decided we do it a little bit
differently. This time we're going to do
what the change is at the end. Let's
let's do what the change is already.
You think there's a change already from
prior to now. Is this more than four
points? Five points. Six points. It's
eight points. Wow. More than seven
points. More than eight points.
Okay.
matter a couple hours um conscious level
of a group of the group you know jump
seven or eight points just like that
that's an enormous jump you see you
don't think that's much that's enormous
it's enormous it takes a whole lifetime
of all that you learn just to go up a
couple of points
uh
and and and all that we've said is is is
seinal in that it starts a process going
you know when we were talking about the
infinite infinite quantum of
potentiality
to just hear certain things already
starts a process going. You see, nobody
in this room is the same as they were
when they walked in.
Is that a fact?
Nobody in this room, nobody in this room
better dare. Nobody in this room is the
same as when they walked in resist.
That's correct. Nobody in this room is
has escaped the field. Why? Because the
field is what lifts us all.
The field is what lifts this be entity
here. See, it's the field. So one's
surrender to God then is merely
surrendering to buoyancy.
Buoyancy.
If you just don't interfere, you
automatically begin to rise. So this
afternoon we're going to speak about
renunciation. Renunciation is one of the
traditional pathways to God. It's very
often associated with the med med
meditation as a formal discipline. One
renounces the world
um joins a monastery
uh lives a certain kind of a life and a
lot of spiritual seekers sort of feel
guilty that they're not doing that.
Anybody here feel guilty that they're
not a monk somewhere in a Yeah. Right. I
you know periodically you think you know
if I was really spiritually committed I
wouldn't be driving on the way to work
here. I'd be, you know, eating rice and
beating on gongs and meditating and
shave my head and sitting still and and
not fooling around here in the world. So
a lot of us go through that period of
feeling guilty that we have not you know
reached the maximum extreme of re
renunciation.
So this afternoon I want to talk about
renunciation. What is the essence of
renunciation?
Because in a in a way all spiritual work
is renunciation. For one thing you're
renunciating you're renouncing the
negative for the positive. So all
spiritual work is in essence
renunciation.
Okay. We'll meet again. What time?
>> 1:00.
Thank you.
Let's ask about the calibration the
level of consciousness of mankind. We
have permission to ask that the
consciousness level of mankind all of it
world population is over 207 208
it's at 207
208 no it's still 207
consciousness level of mankind doesn't
move for long centuries
I don't know why uh
it stood at 190 for many many centuries.
If you go back to the 1500s, 1400s,
it stood at 20 190 many many centuries
and then suddenly quickly jumped to 207
and now because somebody asked as it
moved uh it's still at 207 as of today
anyway.
Uh 207
what does that mean?
means whatever you want it to mean.
Nothing in and of itself has any
meaning. You understand that? All
meaning is a projection, an
interpretation, a superimposition.
If you look at a at a sunset,
what does it mean?
It doesn't mean anything. It is what it
is as the expression of its the divinity
of its it the expression of its essence.
Nothing means anything. Therefore,
nothing has a why to it. Why is a
sunset? Why is a sunset? You know, uh it
just is. Huh?
The mind is not happy with that. It
wants an explanation for things because
it wants to propagate itself.
If it can formulate a question, then it
justifies
um another large research grant for one
thing.
It does it just is that way, you know?
It just is that way. Like that fuzzy
little thing on the microphone. I mean,
it just is what it is. You know what I'm
saying? Not sure people have
explanations for it, but whatever it
was, I thought it was adorable.
I sort of miss it now, actually.
So,
we wanted to sort of add to the
discussion of meditation some commentary
on attachment and renunciation.
What the mind has trouble letting go of
are its attachments.
We we talked about that this morning.
One attachment is the emotional payoff.
Another attachment to thoughts is the
narcissistic investment.
The thought that I created those
thoughts. They're mine. They're
precious.
Um
the overvaluation of thoughts because of
our own of the narcissism that is innate
to
uh the ego
as we mentioned before how the ego
arises
its origination
in this domain in this dimension.
on this planet, you know, it rose as a
as an evolutionary outgrowth of uh
animal the animal nature. You said
there's no point in feeling guilty about
your ego and how it operates. It grew
over the millennia,
millions of years of evolution.
The animal has to know here from there
and
it it presumes the reality of a here and
there and for survival. Therefore,
the ego is based on a duality of this
versus that.
Good to eat, not good to eat. Friend,
foe gets into dualities of opposites.
And in the animal world, that's very
useful. You better know what's to eat or
what's going to eat you. You better know
the difference.
And if you're gonna jump on an on a
mouse, you better know that you are here
and the mouse is there so that you can
estimate the jump. So the whole ego then
is based on the animal consciousness of
survival.
So it's basically dualistic by virtue of
its structure.
because it's structured that way.
There's no point of feeling guilty about
it because you didn't create it that
way.
It think it thinks in terms of good,
bad, right, wrong, um, etc.
With the development of the forebrain,
the intellect, now
the style of animal instinctual
expression
um takes on far more elaborate form,
far more elaborate
elaborations now. So that what we're
limited to the physical reach of the
animal is can now be extended out
globally and via the internet.
Uh what was once limited limited to u
the edge of the woods is now can now
threaten the whole univer the whole
world the human world. So we see that
the inlick then extended the animal
motivations and contextualizations of B
reality
and have spread them out into much more
sophisticated extensions. Intrinsically
however they are still the same thing.
Um
the animal in order to survive then
valued certain things and there arose
attachment
and attachment really begins you might
say
noticeably in the mamlian world
the infant's attachment to the mother is
essential and critical to survival
emotional attachment. We see the
beginning then of that which is
nurturing in the evolution of the animal
world that wasn't there with the
dinosaur.
It shows up in the bird. The mother bird
hangs around, waits for the little
birdies and feeds them. And then we see
the development really through the
maternal bond of the development of love
which later develops into romantic love
between male and female. But love really
first emerges within the animal kingdom
as maternal nurturance.
So attachment then comes in very early.
The infant is obviously quite attached.
It gets attached to the mother.
It's actually the mother's lovingness
that to which the infant owes its
survival.
The mother's lovingness is a nonlinear
reality.
The mother's physicality
is linear.
The infant doesn't differentiate the
two. It gets that love and survival is
coming from from this and gets attached
to that physicality and that form.
It isn't this that's ensuring the
infant's happiness and survival but the
lovingness which is
not physical. So its physical survival
is really based on the nonlinear.
Its linear survival is really coming as
a result of the nonlinear because love
which calibrates at 500 and
unconditional love at 540.
Love and lovingness is what is the
source of the infant's survival which
then takes expression through the
mother's nurturance.
Anyway, attachment then becomes a habit.
Attachment
is also because we identify with what we
consider to be our own narcissistic
creations, our own thoughts and feelings
and all become overvalued.
Traditionally, one could renounce the
world and join a spiritual
organization
uh that is timehonored. It is recognized
throughout society to join the
monastery, to join a nunnery, to
renounce the world
is a traditional pathway to God in which
one acts out you know in the external
world
and makes an absolute statement
and leaves the world. So traditionally
at one time most spir serious spiritual
seekers or many were actually
renunciates.
One could become a hermit, one could
become
solitary, one could join a small group
or one could join a large organization
and become a formal renunciate.
The usual renunciation was of the
materiality of the world, acquisition,
ownership and therefore the
historical attributes of the renunciate
was poverty
um patience
um
sexual abstinence
um and devoting one's life to service.
service uh for others
in the meditative tradition. Then it
allowed for a great deal of time and
energy to be devoted to the meditative
practice itself. Meditative practice
itself works out well. At the same time
I noticed where experientially with u
manual work
uh one meditates to the point of u
almost non-reality of the physical body
and you forget to eat and all that and
uh you stay sort of grounded they call
it by uh doing physical work. There
doesn't seem to be any conflict between
physical work and meditation.
one can continue right on with with
physical manual labor and not interrupt
the meditation at all. You can go right
on digging a ditch and doesn't seem to
interfere with anything. So that
tradition of the monastic life of u
prayer and meditation and and simple
manual labor uh which is traditional uh
seems to work out quite well.
traditional
um let's say meditative practice and
intellectualism
uh dealing in the worm world of form and
commerce
um is much more difficult to to
um to do. It's not that it's impossible,
but it's
difficult to look over a corporation's
u corporate accounts and at the same
time
at the same same time being in a really
cool state.
All right. So there there is gross
renunciation as a lifestyle as a as a
major commitment
and many people here have done it in
previous lifetimes and some will
probably do it in future lifetimes and
in many people it is a part-time thing.
For many people in the room here who
have semi-normal lives there's periods
where you go on retreat. Um and there
are many you know hours during the week
that you spend on meditation. So you try
to do a balance between
uh handling the world at the same time
progressing spiritually.
The progression spiritual spiritually
through meditation
has classically been likened to
renunciation.
In this case the renunciation is mental
rather than a social lifestyle.
So that all all spiritual work in a way
is a renunciation.
First of all, we've talked in previous
talks about transcending the opposites.
The polarity of the opposites is an
illusion.
And one doesn't have to choose between
opposites. One merely sees the opposite,
what seems like in the opposite
direction as an alternate.
One then refuses the alternate and
merely chooses the positive. So you
don't have to be against
what is seen to be the negative. You
don't have to hate sin and get out there
and fight sin.
You just choose virtue, right? Choose.
So you choose the positive rather than
attacking the negative so as to avoid
getting polarized between the good and
bad, good and evil, up and down and all
those illusions
in a way. What? So renunciation in its
essence then not as a lifestyle but as
an essence is is the essence of all
spiritual work because you're at all
times renouncing it as an attachment,
renouncing it as a value, renouncing it
as as a way that you choose to go. So by
choosing the positive in a way you're
always renouncing the negative. you know
to renounce allowing a certain thing to
dominate your consciousness. What does
it say? Somebody says here
how do you handle anger? You see
that will bring up then
what is the anger about and
you'll see to let it go will require a
relinquishment.
So the relinquishment could be
semantically referred to as a
renunciation.
The anger then is about a positionality.
The willingness to let the positionality
go
is a renunciation.
It's a renunciation of the payoff of the
emotionality that goes with it. For one
thing,
those that have done the course of
miracles remember, you know that
anger would come from perception.
Perception comes from illusion.
And by the willingness to surrender it
to the Holy Spirit, you're asking God to
recontextualize how you're seeing it
through place perception with spiritual
vision. And what does that mean? It
means to see it minus a dualistic
uh illusion.
The pathway to God we we sort of
represent in all the lectures, you know,
is really uh the pathway of um it well
we'll get to devotion. Devotion is
underneath it, but it seems to be the
pathway through mind. It's really
actually the pathway through no mind.
When we talked about the unmanifest as
the ultimate, we're talking about no
mind, right?
Because once you start talking about
mind, you're talking about form.
So all forms of meditation and spiritual
work are in in essence a renunciation.
It's a rejection of a what seems to be a
this direction for this direction. And
it's choosing the positive rather than
anything else.
And that always means letting go of the
attachment. And the attachment then
means the imaginary value.
So anger would be then hanging on to the
imaginary value of a certain
positionality.
Renunciation would be the willingness to
let go that seeming benefit. Then what
happens is
the field of consciousness itself
recontextualizes
and you see it differently. And now
because you see it differently, there's
nothing to be angry about.
Does that answer the anger problem?
Anybody have any questions on anger?
Because that was one that has come up
several times. But it represents
how in meditation one looks at one
dissects and disassembles the
construction that leads to the anger.
So meditation in a way is a constantly a
constant deepening.
It's a deconstruction of the formulation
of what appeared to be a problem. And it
in its
in as you take it apart it disappears as
an illusion.
And there's nothing to handle because it
has no reality.
We answered these questions and I want
to answer the last question. Yes.
What is the um free will in a divinely
unfolding universe? Yes. Right. Uh the
question of free will is a whole another
question.
We said that hap everything is happening
of its own including the appearance of
the human ego.
As we saw, the ego arises out of the
evolution of consciousness, beginning in
the animal native world and evolving up
to humanness
in which conflict doesn't even begin to
arise in any kind of a serious manner
until the physical consciousness, the
consciousness of physicality
begins to meet
spiritual reality.
That's where homo spiritis gets born.
Huh? The animal doesn't have any
conflict,
does it? It doesn't have like a
spiritual nature. It has to balance
against its animal nature.
In fact, up to level 200,
somebody was asking me about that. Up to
level 200,
uh, it's not a real problem.
No, it's not a real problem. Below that,
you just hate people and you enjoy
hating them and you don't have any
problem about that.
The Americans say you kill them. What's
the problem?
Let's ask about that. Where were we
going to ask about it? Somebody asked
me. Oh yes, during the break. Uh it's
sort of uh how come people who calibrate
below 200 are not able to do
kinesiology?
And I've never asked the question.
We have the permission to ask the
question. Resist.
Let's see. Below 200 is below integrity.
Resist. Below 200 is below integrity.
Resist.
That which is in Oh, that which is non
integrous is denied the power of truth.
Resist. Oh, I see. So you see, as you go
up the levels of consciousness, power
increases.
So you don't give gunpowder to children,
right? Understand?
It's it's only as you become purified
now
that you're given a new tool that's
enormously powerful.
You realize that be able the capacity to
be able to tell the the truth from
falsehood about anything anywhere in
time or the universe
has never existed in human history. Just
got born.
Just got born.
Oh, that's homos spirit is getting born,
isn't it? Well,
that's part of homospiritis getting
born. Wow. Homospheris really began
about late 1980s through this. Wow. See,
we find out things all the time. They
come to your mind. You'll say, I just
got to know that.
If you want to know how kinesiology
works, that's how it works. You see, and
if you've got time, the two of us can
get into it, you know, when you start
researching a thing. And that brings up
the next question. That brings up the
next question. Oh, yeah. So, homositis
is so is newly born
marked by the what I call the antecedent
of the second coming of Christ. Okay.
Christ said that let's see the second
coming of Christ would really be
preceded by
resist. Yeah. That began the late 1980s.
Resist.
That meant 207.
That's the second coming of Christ. See,
like the dawn arising, you know, you
just don't go from black to suddenly
Jesus Christ is standing there blasting
everybody away and they're all going,
"Wow." It's like the energy begins to
arise so that he would make sense to
you.
Would make sense to you. Does Jesus
Christ make sense to the
monkey island at the zoo? No. He could
stand there and preach all day. with me
anything, right?
Consciousness has to so it's like a
preparatory advancing of consciousness
that's able to handle the truth. First
of all, we said this morning the human
nervous system has to evolve to handle
it. Human nervous system has to evolve
to be able to handle it.
So the evolution of consciousness then
um means that the stage is being set.
The progression of consciousness
is evolving. It evolves and as it
evolves
now it's crossed over to a different
paradigm of reality.
It was interesting. I was calibrating uh
Walmart. You know Walmart recently
couple weeks ago or a month ago
uh was the was has re has become the
largest corporation in the world.
largest corporation in the world
back in 95 94 or so when I did research
on on Walmart and I corresponded with
Sam Walton and and I I uh uh admired his
integrity and he was a man who was he
was a man who was putting integrity into
the business place. I mean you know that
was revolutionary
and uh what would come of that? Well in
those days Walmart calibrated in the
high 300s. It still does.
Um so that which is integrous then which
is integrous uh tends to um is now the
biggest corporation in the world. So
integrity resulted in the biggest cor in
and it's becoming the greatest
corporation in the world. I think that's
just an interesting phenomena because
here we are in an era where
consciousness is for the first time in
human history jumping from non-integrity
to integrity
and then we have a demonstration of it
in the marketplace. Well, in spiritual
terminology is not meaningful to large
numbers of the population. Certainly the
bottom line of the biggest corporation
in the world is very meaningful to a lot
of people.
And uh the Wall Street Journal called me
up a couple months ago and wanted to
know uh how real is that? How real is it
that if you put spiritual reality into
the into the business world that it
literally shows up in the bottom line?
>> Well, I think Walmart answered that
question, didn't it? just like Enron
or Wcom answered in the other direction
that um for things to survive now it
seems to me they will have to become
integrous
in a non-integrous world integrity is
not required to survive
at all. You can succeed in a
non-integous world by stealing everybody
else's blind
and threatening them with guns and
invasion. In a more integist world, this
doesn't work anymore. In a more
integrous world, bombing the trade world
trade center doesn't win you a lot of
Islamic converts.
That might have worked. I think they're
a couple hundred years out of date with
that move. and one of our first people
back in the 1500s. You know, in today's
world, they look sort of idiotic. You
know what I mean? You killed off 3,000
Americans. You've only got 300 million
to go. So, you better get busy
if you want to kill off Americans.
You got 300 million to go. So,
what we're seeing, I think, is a new
dimension of
um the prevalence of human
consciousness. It's its energy level
rises and with it it lifts it lifts all
of mankind
and what was okay before is now what was
okay before because it was ab above the
line is now below the line. So as the
water rose, that which was above the
water is now below the water. And I
think what will be acceptable and what
will prevail in mankind
uh is going to shift as a result of a
the consequence of the energy field
itself. So we saw this morning how the
energy field itself lifts and sustains
in an impersonal
nonlinear way just by the nature of its
gravity.
So the human then is like a quark in the
field of consciousness.
And what accounts for the evolution of
one's individual consciousness is
letting go of ballast. As you let go of
ballast, your cork automatically rises.
The field doesn't run. The field doesn't
move. Although we said the prevailing
field on the planet now at 207 is quite
a bit different than 190. They are two
different dimensions of existence
altogether.
All right, I think we've answered those
questions.
We see that renunciation then is a
lifestyle.
Renunciation that can be best expressed
as its corlary,
not its opposite but its correlary which
is the choosing of the positive.
It's not necessary to renounce the
negative, but only to choose the
positive and bypass the polarization.
By bypass getting stuck in a
positionality.
All right. Now, we wanted to spend time
this afternoon answering questions. We
said we wouldn't lecture the whole day.
We did it all morning and we've done it
somewhat this afternoon. And uh now we'd
like to discuss anything you would like
to discuss. And um people asked if we
could do the M again.
>> Yes.
>> So where does emotion fit in spiritual
growth or living out your spiritual
values? It seems to have
>> you'll have to come over.
>> Yeah.
>> Repeat the question.
>> You'll have to come over. So I don't
understand the question. I'll repeat it
though for the mic.
>> Go ahead.
>> What was the question? Where does
emotions fit in spiritual growth or
spiritual values? I mean, as it seems
every time they're spoken of, they
they're not serving the spiritual life
well.
>> Well, the emotions you see on we she's
asking what is the value of emotion in
spiritual work. We see on the scale of
consciousness. Maybe we should put that
skill back up. That uh the emotion
depends on the level of integrity
and that emotion itself is not
necessarily
uh a detrimental. We were talking about
negative emotions which calibrate below
200. Hatred, anger, self-pity, guilt,
remorse. But as you get over 200, now
emotion becomes a positive asset.
uh integrity, the commitment to
integrity is is a certain emotionality.
It's not emotionality the way most
people think of it, but it's uh it's a
certain space of commitment. Um you can
do it when you clean up the kitchen in
the morning, you can commit to getting
this place absolutely clean the way I
want it. Um
eventually you see as as the emotion
goes up it calibrates higher and higher.
Probably the most important emotion and
we will get to that in a later lecture
uh in spiritual work is that of love but
beyond that devotion.
Devotion.
What makes any spiritual understanding
comprehensible and work is that one is
one's devotion to the truth.
So the pathway of heart and the pathway
of mind are one and the same. They end
up one and the same because the pathway
of
Adva let's say the adva
pathway of no mind the pathway of Zen
is really based on a profound and
intense dedication pointedness of mind
is the expression of an intense
dedication
a a love that is not in the world of
ordinary emotionality.
Um the love um the devotion to
achieve one-pointedness of mind is
extreme and intense to leave everything
in the world. Fixate only on that which
is straight ahead of you with no
deviance.
Takes an intense dedication and that is
devotion.
There is a very simple way to meditate.
Um, and and one that I teach people most
generally is to merely sit and close
your eyes. If you sit and close your
eyes and look straight ahead, if you sit
and close your eyes and look straight
ahead, you'll see little cord pusles. If
we all, if we all look ahead, close your
eyes, look ahead, you see all little
dancing cord pusles, right? Those are
the little blood core pusles
uh going through the
capillaries uh in the retina.
And you just look straight ahead.
If you look straight ahead, you see
there's no real form there. There's all
these little dancing
uh little particulates of light. They've
got a some kind of a name. I forgotten
what the name is. um little little
illuminations like if you look straight
ahead then you see this sort of a
semilank field of uh little dancing
minuscule tiny dotlets of light and one
can just look at them observationally
without comment or anything and at the
same time be aware of one's breathing
not to alter just be aware of the
breathing so within oneself you're
watching watching the breathing and
you're looking straight ahead
and you just profoundly relax
and let that take you wherever it takes
you.
As you do the sense of being
me here begins to disappear.
this sense of infinite space because one
gets the feeling that it that it's
almost like space looking at space like
there's not an individual person looking
at the back of the eyelids.
It's like it's beginning to it happens
of its own. The breathingness also
one becomes aware is happening of its
own. There is no breather doing the
breathing.
There is no thinker doing the thinking.
There is no seer doing the seeing,
no thinker behind the thoughts,
no doer behind the actions,
no looker even. All this is just
happening of its own spontaneously.
Where does free will come in? Free will
comes in then
in choosing to go in the direction of
God. Choosing to go in the direction of
spiritual truth as one understands it at
this point of the evolution of one's own
consciousness.
Free will then is the innate capacity
for choice. But that choice is limited.
It's karmically determined. The choices
of the past have already determined the
possible choices of the present present.
A zebra cannot choose to be a kangaroo.
So the karmic evolution of consciousness
throughout all of the evolution of human
consciousness and and and its
expression in in one's own particular
karmic development then results in a
certain range a certain range of karmic
possibilities
within that range free will operates to
the degree that one energizes it,
chooses it, wishes it.
Free will doesn't mean that a camel can
decide to be a kangaroo. No, free will
will means that within the range of what
is possible due to my own karmic
inheritance,
what is within that range of
possibility, one can make the choice.
However, the minute that choice is made,
this is already it already shifts the
future choices.
So free will then makes a choice from
moment to moment. Each choice then
instantly changes
the potentiality.
It either enlarges the choice or
decreases the choice.
We saw that on our chart of
of
quantum mechanics.
Uh every choice then becomes you might
say in chaos theory a bifurcation.
So free will is like an endless series
of bifurcations. Because I choose this
now these possibilities open up. And
again if I choose this there thereby
this whole basket of opportunities open
up. Now if I choose to be part of the
field rather than the particular I've
immensely opened my potentialities.
When you choose the field rather than
the content of the field now you're
choosing an infinite potentiality.
So a group like like us here today
by commitment have chosen
to realize the truth of one's reality as
context.
So habitually the members of the group
here in their own spiritual practice are
constantly bypassing content and
constantly opening the avenue for the
conscious awareness of context as their
ultimate reality by saying I am not this
I am not that the pathway of negation or
by saying I am this and I am that
one is already changing one's karmic
potentiality
to be to go to go out of this body and
come back in another. Then one starts
with
the basket of infinite potentialities
that you left off with the last time
because you frankly wore out the last
body.
Why can't you keep one body for 100,000
years? Well, until you're done with
evolution is because it doesn't work out
that way. And uh I can't know what it is
to be black if I got a white body. I
don't know what it's like to be a woman
if I've got a male body. I mean, I'm
stuck with the limitation. You
understand? So, you may choose to come
back as as everybody sort of sort of the
everythingness
of potentiality.
Um,
the only way you can know a thing is to
be it.
That's why
you can't know it by reading about it. I
don't know what it is to be a woman
unless I am one. I can read about it.
It's interesting. It's intriguing
and I can become very very
about it but I don't know what it is to
be it unless I am it. So one thing that
karmic evolution
uh one one of its great values is you
get to understand and know things by
virtue of being them. Wow.
H that's a fact. Eh,
that's a fact. Is it? Wow.
Well, so the last those two lifetimes I
realized why I I did them. Yeah. You
have to actually be that to get it to
know what that is.
Wow. There's some rough lifetimes, but
uh that's the only way you got to know
it, you know. Oh, so
what it is to feel like uh I mean you
got to get chopped up by somebody to
find out what it's like to feel like to
get chopped up and then it's lifetime
you you're merciful and you don't chop
up people. Wow, I see what it is like
you know first your arm goes and this
leg goes and you watch your head go
flying off and you walk through the
world fly upside down before the blood
leaves your brain and you you think God
that's what I did to people now you got
it. Okay. Yeah. It's like it takes so
much to get a thing, right? We'd all
have one kind of one lifetime otherwise.
You know, we'd read a good book, uh,
read about God and Jesus, and there you
are in heaven. Done.
I don't know.
Universe seems to be that you
practically got to live through all of
it to transcend it.
Wonder if that's so. All these things
come up. I don't know where they come
from.
That's soul resist. Whoa. H.
So karma isn't a bad thing. Karma is not
a bad thing. Let's get that across.
Karma is not a bad thing. Karma is a
exciting and wonderful thing. Resist.
Let's not put down karma, folks. I mean,
you don't get to go to the circus unless
you go to the circus, you know.
I don't really want to know what it's
like to go through child birth to tell
you the truth.
But
my heart is certainly with the
experience.
Do I know what it's like to go through
child? I know what it's like to go
through child birth through the previous
lifetimes. Resist. Oh, I do. Huh? I
guess I blotted it out, folks.
>> Forget about it.
Uh
now as those lifetimes come back to you
there they're multitudinous they're a
lot you know I think the Buddhist said
there were thousands and um
anyway
we get to understand it by being it see
the mind cannot know anything it can
only know about um something that's a
very important it sounds like a fine
distinction but it's crucial
The mind can only know about a thing.
The only way to know a thing is to be
it. To be it
to be the context out of which all
seeming reality arises is the way you
realize that's what's called
self-realization. Oh, right.
You realize it by being it. Huh?
Then so realization is just that
recognition that you are it is it. So
yeah I always thought it was simple
right? Uh
the realization that one does realize
the realization of what is real is uh
realization.
>> Ah that's a good example. You see what
I'm saying?
The only way to realize what it is to be
a human being is to be one and then you
get what it is. It's very difficult.
It's very complex. It's very
challenging.
Uh I think anybody who has lived the
human life deserves to go to heaven.
If I was St. Peter, I'd say you live the
human life, pass.
Because its challenge is exquisite. It's
you know the complexity of the human
mind itself its enormous identifications
as consciousness evolved throughout time
its enormous capacity for identification
and then losing the reality of who it is
in that identification.
It loses the touch with that which which
it really is. It loses the fact that
it's context and it begins to believe
that it's content. That that's all
that's happening. That's all that's
happening is that it loses,
you know, like um who was um the god
that can imagine what it's like to be a
cow. Oh, Krishna and Mu was like a cow
and he became one and he forgot that
he'd wled it and some other god had to
come and rescue him to remind him that
he'd forgotten that he that he willed
himself to be a cow to see what it's
like to be a cow. Of course it was a
cow. He couldn't remember that he had
willed it because now he was a cow.
Indra Indra came and helped rescue him
and said
helped rescue him that he'd wished
himself to see what it's what it's like
to be a cow. So we've done that as
humans, haven't we? We've all been
curious what it's like to be a human and
what it is to um be here and we found
out
u
all right so renunciation then is re to
renounce the false for the true to see
that truth has no opposite there is no
opposite to truth just as there is no
opposite to God
only the true is true and only That
which exists has reality.
Uh only only the allness of God has any
reality. That takes care of existence
versus non-existence.
Allness versus nothingness.
How any you know how those karmic things
uh persist in lifetime. One time
somebody went to a lecture that I gave
back in uh Sedona Villa that was I don't
know back in the 80s late '7s somewhere.
Anyway, somebody heard a lecture on
consciousness. I was talking about the
calibrated levels of consciousness in
those days and the part that pays in
sobriety and in the middle of it this
guy just went into a really great state
and u after years of succumbing to
alcohol he suddenly he was beyond it and
u in fact I calibrated him one time he
went up 150 points
so he came out of the pits and went into
a state of like unconditional love and
joy so um anyway
couple months later I here, knock at the
door, and here he is. This guy's a
workman, and he's a very good carpenter,
excellent carpenter,
uh, cabinet maker, actually. And, uh, he
backed up with a trailer. And here was
this incredible,
uh, table made from a slab of wood this
thick from the top of Mingus Mountain
hit by lightning in 1956. And he saved
this incredible slab of wood and he'd
made this incredible he thought it was a
bench, but I use it as a table. It
weighs a couple hundred pounds. Anyway,
he made this thing. He spent six weeks
making it out of appreciation for the
his recovery. And he backed up with this
thing and somehow we got it into the
house. And there engraved on the top in
Sanskrit is nothingness versus allness.
He'd never heard me. I never said
anything about it. There at age three,
nothingness versus allness. And there it
was inscribed and beautiful carved all
the sources nothingness. So you can see
how karmically a thing like that
prevails in the field of consciousness
emerges then as as getting reborn in
another lifetime to transcend that
illusion.
Somebody picks it up you know in Sedona
we call it on the inner.
Somebody picks up on the inner that
that's prevailing in your consciousness.
And at the time he he uh brought that it
was as yet unresolved. It was allness
versus nothingness was as yet not
evolved in this consciousness. It was a
sometime after that. So how did his
psyche pick that up as the central theme
of this lifetime? Because I didn't give
lectures like I am now. I never
mentioned anything about personal
experience. I just talked about the
calibrated levels of consciousness and
all. So somehow his psyche had picked up
the the c the central focus of that.
So that's our karmic you might say our
karmic unfoldment from lifetime to
lifetime. Um
and the choices we make then are the
exercise of free will
for for some reason the kinesiology as a
tool is is not uh suitable for somebody
who calibrates below 200. In the
beginning when I discovered the capacity
of kinesiology to tell truth from
falsehood
uh I didn't know what to do with it for
years and I didn't know what to write
about it because at that time I thought
it could be used for you know extremely
nefarious ends sort of like discovering
gunpowder you know dynamite
u should you share that with the world
or not discovering nuclear power any of
those things yeah you know sort of a
moral dilemma. So I I I really puzzled
over it for years. Should should this be
shared with the world or not shared with
the world? You know what I'm saying?
At that time I didn't realize that um to
to make it work, you yourself have to be
integrous. So it couldn't be used for
non- integrity. But for years I did not
publish it or write about it because
um I thought I thought at the time it
was a two-edged sword and that it could
be used to destroy mankind.
And so I didn't want to share it. And it
was only later that I got that it was
sharable and that it was safe and that
if your intention is less than 200 or
the people are less than 200. In other
words, it'd be like non-intigorous
people can make it might go off. So I
was delighted to find that. I only found
that out after I wrote power versus
force and then I had to revise the new
edition. uh because in originally I
thought anybody could use kinesiology
and get the truth about anything
and then later on I saw
now I know what resolved it I saw that
the only way you could get ahead uh
would be be by becoming more integrous
the only way you can let's say compete
on the world of integrity
is be by becoming more integrous the
only way you can become more powerful is
to become more loving
and therefore it couldn't be used in a
destructive way. And that allowed that
that understanding allowed me to publish
power versus force. But it was only
after the first edition that I s we we
only lately discovered that unless
you're over 200. And we didn't discover
it until we started getting letters that
people said didn't work. Well, I'd used
it for years in all kinds of groups and
uh kinesiologists and holistic health
practitioners. It always worked. It
always worked. never saw that it didn't
work. So I thought where is this coming
from? We tried it and it doesn't work.
What do you mean it doesn't work?
Uh and then we discovered that uh that
it had these limitations. Integrity of
motive, integrity of intention,
integrity of the two people. So there
was a built-in safe safeguard because
certainly to have the capacity to
discern the truth or falsehood of
anything gives you in a way uh an
incredible degree of power more more
power than any any human actually the
average person today certainly anybody
who attends these conferences has more
power than anybody ever existed really
in a way um Caesar didn't have the way
to tell truth from falsehood or you know
what I'm saying is that that's true I
mean they The average spiritually
educated person now has more power than
all the potentates who ever lived. He's
just he got more power than Caesar ever
had. Caesar couldn't tell there's truth
or falsehood. You know, he could only go
out there
and if you won, you you were right. And
if you lost, you lost.
And uh so it's a gift that mankind has
now. It's a gift like a gift came out of
that advancement of consciousness.
So we were like given a gift to be the
gift of discernment.
It was throughout time. Discernment was
when the third eye opened up in the
Buddha body and it didn't happen until
you're quite evolved spiritually to be
able to look at a thing and see whether
it's integrous or nonintigorous. The
truth and the false is a very advanced
level of spiritual maturity
which one which many people don't make
otherwise all the false gurus and a lot
of the new age nonsense and circus
circus uh acts would have no attraction.
Um
when a person is very spiritually
evolved they see the essence of what a
thing is just by glancing or just
hearing about it. you know, I can pick
up a letter and I can tell you just by
the feel of the letter what
what what it's all about, what its
energy is. And um but that only comes at
a certain point. Up to that up to that
time, you're you know, you're easily
easily bamboozled by all kinds of uh
smoke and incense and sandals and long
hair and oo and a's and mantras and
chants and music and bongs and bells and
crap. You know that's the astral circus
in a way you know and card readings and
psychics and readings and master this
that and the other on the other side
that tells you to sell your Chevy and
buy a Ford. Okay.
He says to sell your Chevy and buy a
Ford. Okay. All right.
So the way to spiritual advancement is
difficult. You have to evolve through
the whole difficulty of being a human
being which in itself is is quite a trip
is it not? Just to be a human being and
survive is already u an enormous
confrontation
and it means always it means in certain
way a constant renunciation because the
child its first thing is to learn how to
renounce this for that. We call it good
and bad. So the way the child the normal
child works is
it's egocentricity is surrendered
because in return it gets approval and
love from the mother. If you let go of
this impulsivity and this greediness and
this desiraability
you get rewarded by approval from the
mother. So the evolution of healthy
human consciousness
then really depends on adequate
parenting, adequate parenting. If
there's nobody there to reward you for
letting go of your selfishness, then you
end up a psychopath. You end up a
sociopath.
You just do what you want to do. If you
want it, you steal it. If you take it,
you feel like punching somebody, you
punch them.
Uh so the chronicity the civotism of
criminality
is because at that critical level of
human consciousness
uh there wasn't the letting go of the
narcissistic core of the ego which
persists in the psychopath.
There's really no point to incarceration
you know as punishment is sort of
idiotic. The reason it doesn't work is
it has no reality to it at all. You
know, because if this defect is a
chronic illness and which it is, it
shows up by age 1 or two or three. The
inability to delay gratification and
then it shows itself as a pattern of
behaviors which always ignore the rights
or the feelings of others. It's just
total egocentricity from the word go.
This becomes a lifestyle. So putting
somebody in prison for 18 years, it's
not surprising that within 24 hours of
letting them out, they do exactly the
same thing to put them in prison the
first time.
It's because it's like an illness due to
a defect. Whether the defect is genetic
or
experiential because the lack of
adequate mothering and parenting and
childhood.
But in dealing with myself
professionally, it seems to be an
illness. Criminalism. Criminalism is an
illness. Criminalism is an illness and u
there's no treatment for it uh except to
protect society from it. You know when
you want to protect if it's a ravenous
predator and you're not going to change
its ways. There's no point of punishing
the wolf for being a wolf. The wolf is a
wolf. It's a predator. So you can
isolate yourself from the predator to
protect society. So you can put them in
compounds where you know there's a fence
down the middle and predators on this
side and non-predators on this side.
That's what we do. We put the sheep on
this sides and we put fence between the
a fence between the the wolf and the
sheep. Yeah. You don't punish the wolf
for being a wolf. See bad wolf. You ate
sheep. Boom. Boom. Boom. We'll give you
18 years. At the end of 18 years, what
is the wolf going to do? It's going to
eat a sheep the first day out. After 18
years of not eating sheep, man, you are
really hungry for sheep.
You know, the most horrendous case of
rape I've ever heard of. I don't want to
even mention the details. It's so awful.
But this guy would did something was so
butchered and so horrible. It's to be
unbelievable. And after 26 years in
prison for doing this horrendous thing,
do you know within 24 hours, he did the
same thing all over again to another
woman. You know, chopped her arms off.
Uh
so when you see that one of this
receivists are about to be released, you
know that the next crime is going to
happen in the next 24 hours. And what
are you going to do, George, after 26
years in prison? I'm going to write the
first woman I see. That's what I'm going
do. That's the truth of it.
So we see that criminalism then is a
failure of this maturation process where
you surrender the selfish egoentricity
of the ego in return for love.
That devotion that is developed later as
a spirit, the spiritually committed
person has that has that to a high
degree. Has that to a high degree that
um sense of uh
of the absolute um sovereignty of love
as
a central focus of one's life is what uh
brings people to spirituality.
the intuitive awareness that that which
is infinitely loving is just beyond
one's conscious grasp and at the same
time is innate within one's presence as
the reality of your own existence.
Traditionally of course religion has
divided um spirit you know God into
imminent and transcendent and the mystic
the mystic is the one in whom spiritual
reality is comes from within
to be faced with existence versus
non-existence does not come from without
it stems from the presence of God within
you almost demanding recognition about
its truth and its reality.
The mis the mystic then is um it's the
one who knows God as imminent as the
self. God imminent as the self. Um in
some religions this is considered uh
heresy understand. At one time I would
have been burned at the stake. Was I
ever burned at the stake? Probably.
Anyway, I don't remember being burned
steak. I I think I do. Yeah. Oh yes. Oh
anyway. Being a mystic was not a good
thing centuries ago in Europe. It would
get you burned at the stake.
That which is uh was said.
Yeah, that's okay. Yeah, I know. Anyway,
the mystic did not fare too well in many
civilizations and uh it is today in uh
today considered a heresy in many uh
contexts in um Islam. uh for instance uh
the mystic uh is considered a heretic.
See Islam considers um talks about yoga
yoga a union with God. It's like there
there's a me and then there's a God. See
and then the two become
uh like a unity. Well, in as much as
there is only the sun shining, removing
the clouds, the cloud doesn't join the
sun. You see what I'm saying?
That which is not real evaporates,
leaving only that which is real. So
there is no union of the unreal with the
real. The ego doesn't join and be in a
yoga and a union with God. Right?
So
the mystic is a heretic in the views of
Islam and in certain traditional
branches of Christianity is not
considered
radical in
in the Hindu or the Buddhists but
they're more sophisticated.
So
God is transcendent then means God as as
otherness.
You get that the person looking for
transcendent God through religion is
looking for an otherness called God.
It's an other. That's why the Buddha
didn't talk about God. Because the
minute you talk about God, you're
looking for something other than what
you are. There's me, wicked worm here,
worthless worm. And then there's God.
You see how separated that is?
So the more you insist on the reality of
a transcendent God, the more you divine,
the more you deny your own spiritual
reality.
If the only God that's a real God is
transcendent,
then your chances are nil, folks,
because his quality is different than
yours.
The difficulties with um the
intellectual approaches to God is that
let's say let's take um the arguments of
Thomas Aquinus
when you go back through an endless
series of causes to the prime cause the
epistemologic error there is the failure
to realize that the initial cause is a
different quality than the rest of the
billiard balls in an endless series of
billiard balls does not start with one
super billiard ball. It starts with one
non-billiard ball. A ho,
it changes its quality. As you go back
to source,
then you find a different quality than
what you're looking for. You have to
have something of a greater dimension.
It's now in a different category of
logic.
You don't find the source of an endless
series of billyard balls in one billiard
ball. You find it in a non-billyard
ball. Huh?
So most spiritual groups are made up of
people who have gone a certain direction
in religion. I've loved religion and I
to this day adore it. I adore going to
church. I adore the music. I endure the
preaching. I enjoy I love ministers and
all that goes with the church, you know.
I love it. Except
that's
one direction to go and enlightenment is
another.
You understand?
Salvation is one thing, enlightenment is
another.
Christ came
for purposes salvation.
The Buddha came to teach enlightenment.
Two different things.
>> Salvation what?
salvation from the illusion of
of your own reality.
You know, karmically we said that the
universe is the the universe is one
karmic reality. The total universe is
one karmic
unity.
In that karmic unity,
there are the various levels and
dimensions.
And Christ said if you do if you do
things that are below calibrate below
200, you will end up next lifetime in
very miserable places. So did the
Buddhist say that. So did Krishna say
that. Every light being that's ever
existed says there's a multistrata
multistrata in within the realm of
consciousness going from the lowest
hells to the higher hills to the
purgatories the lower heavens to the
higher heavens to enlightenment itself
to go beyond all positionalities.
They said don't go there. Woe to those
who abuse the innocence of the child
because where they are going when they
leave the body is not a pleasant place
to go. So Christ wasn't threatening you
with hell, but he was telling you it's a
fact that
the karmic weight, the u the karmic
calibration of one's um karmic body,
let's say, like a quirk in in the water
will rise or sink to various levels. And
all it's saying is that the lower levels
are
incredibly awful. Having been there, I
will guarantee you, I will tell you that
hell is far worse than you can imagine.
You can imagine the worst incredible
hell that your imagination. And you're
not even scratching it. It goes far
beyond that. Goes beyond the dreadful,
beyond the terrible, beyond the
unescribable
to realms of nonform.
In the realms of nonform, hell takes on
dimensions that you can't even imagine.
And so Jesus Christ out of his love for
mankind, he came down from heaven. He
never had any previous lifetimes.
He came down from heaven to tell you
that that is the case. That if you
choose below 200. So all Jesus said was
choose below. Don't choose that which is
below 200. That's all he said. If it
makes you weak with kinesiology, bypass
it. That's all Jesus said.
Renounce that which is below 200. And uh
that's all the Buddha said. That's all
anybody's ever said. We all know that
the horrific leads us to intense inner
psych psychic suffering. You don't have
to be dead to discover hell. We've all
done things that we've laying awake
squirming with inner pain about
sometimes for months or years even.
So you don't have to be dead to
experience the consequence. So
everything has its own karmic karmic
corollary. Not necessarily a consequence
as though it's a punishment or
something.
But if you choose to walk within certain
dimensions, you're going to be exposed
to certain temperatures, barometric
pressures, light radiations. The hells
are very bad places to go. That's all
Jesus says. Woe to those who do this,
that, or the other because you're going
to experience hellish places. Well, most
people because they identify with the
body don't remember the hells they're
in.
enlightened person remembers it all.
He'll tell you not because he read in a
book because it's it's a recent
experience.
It's a recent experience in this
lifetime. It's a very recent experience.
I will tell you that hell is one hell
one hell of of valid place. It's
possible to exist in a place of such
spiritual pain and agony.
One wish wishes that one had never come
into existence at all.
So Jesus Christ told the truth. That was
his purpose. The Buddha when we
calibrate when we ask about the Buddha
we get he had many many lifetimes and
many many lifetimes and he said that the
way out the event the way out of it all
together is to transcend all
identification with temporality and form
and then you will not be subject subject
to reincarnated lifetimes which may or
may not be agonizing.
All right. Does that take care of heaven
and hell? I thought we threw in heaven
and hell by a quarter after three.
Any questions? And then we'll take we'll
take a break and then after that anybody
wants to talk to me personally, I'll be
up here and we'll just I'll just meet
with people and say hi to them and and
speak whatever I can say. Yes sir.
>> Will you talk about prayer?
>> Prayer
>> and how you can help. Yes, we said that
prayer when we talking about quantum
mechanics,
we're trying to give the science of
prayer that um
prayer then presents opens an a
potentiality opens a potentiality in the
infinite reality and uh is effective
again its effectiveness has to do with
the calibrated level of the prayer
itself. the calibrated level of the
person praying that person's karma and
the karmic conditions of the world. You
can pray for all Arabs to drop dead
tomorrow, but they're not going to. See?
Uh so how integrous is the prayer? Most
prayers are like children's prayer. I
can remember running for my violin
lesson, praying up a storm. My mother
said, "I'm left this little country
school. I got to go one mile down Dean
Road
uh and catch the bus. The buses were
like every two hours, you know. I mean,
not a bus every 10 minutes, you know.
So, it was the bus that would get you to
your violin lesson. And I'm carrying
this violin case and I'm tearing down
here one mile going like hell and
praying up a storm the whole mile that
God would hold up the bus till I got
there cuz I left five minutes late.
Bus took off.
No wonder I became an atheist for years.
Right?
So that's self-interest. Self-interest.
So it's what what is your expectation of
prayer that if you are presenting it as
a gift to uh the universe in that
quantum potentiality then you're
influencing the likelihood. We said the
quantum mechanics has to do with
likelihoods and potentialities.
you know, the
the um whatchamacallit. Uh we were
looking on television last night. Um
anyway, the likelihood of your finding a
thing where you saw it last time is
already changed. The Heisenberg
principle, I'm sorry. The Heisenberg
principle is that having looked at a
thing, the likelihood is not going to be
there the second time because you looked
at it the first time. you've already
changed the potential reality. So prayer
changes the I think potentiality.
I think a thousand people praying for a
certain thing increases the likelihood
of that. It doesn't cause it though
because reality is beyond cause. But it
does increase likelihood. What I think
it does is change the buoyancy of the
cork. So the cork is more likely to rise
up within the karmic reality of the sea.
That's what I think prayer does. you
know increases likelihood. It also
creates form. It also creates form. Uh
certainly how did that carpenter know
allness versus nothingness and do it in
Sanskrit? I mean how did he know that it
was he picked it up somewhere in form?
You know
any other question then we'll we'll take
a break and then we'll just spend the
rest of day chatting. Yes. related to
the prayer question. I know there are a
lot of new spiritual masters that are
when you ask them about praying, they
say that that reinforces your delusion
that you are separate from God. Can you
talk about that and intention and how
that
>> Well, those are very there's various
different levels at which the question
can be understood and answered.
the on a certain level no prayer is
necessary nor is it answerable nor does
it have it any real have any reality
but that's one level that isn't the
level that's meant by people when people
say you know how effective is how good
is prayer
uh I think prayer is as effective as
when it's karmically limited to at the
at the at the at the time within a
universe being what it is at the time
it certainly is A declaration of
intention certainly is a statement of
intention
to say that prayer
is saying that you're separate from from
God. You know what is it that's praying?
Your ego is what's praying. Your spirit
doesn't need to pray. The ultimate
reality of that which you're already is
is already there. It has no no need to
pray. So it's the ego that's praying in
the first place.
Your ego is not one and the same as God
or you wouldn't be a spiritual seeker.
You would be a guru. You know, you'd be
enlightened. You'd be a Christ.
Um so those are ways of constructing
things.
Any question can be addressed from
different levels. So one of the values
of the scale of consciousness is to gall
cal you can tell at what level are you
do you want an answer at what because
anything you can say about anything is
only an appearance
it's only a style uh anomalization it's
um
everything is depending on what you're
from what position you're viewing it
everything is a is is a product of point
of view and the answer you can get is
only an artificial construction coming
out of a point of view. That's the whole
basis of quantum mechanics. You find
what you look for. If you're looking for
dots and zeros, you'll find lots of dots
and zeros. If you're looking for
triangles and whistles, you'll find lots
of triangles and whistles.
That consciousness is of such a nature
that it
It it it has an illusion. It think it
thinks there's a this finding of that.
Actually, by asking this, it's already
defined the thatness.
The question itself has already defined
the answer.
Therefore, there isn't a this finding of
that. Is only consciousness
coming to the obvious conclusion that
whatever you ask about is what you're
going to find. And certainly quantum
mechanics is a beautiful scientific way
of of saying that the Heisenberg
principle is you will discover what
you're looking for. So the advancing
edge of physics is up against the fact
that until it knows more about
consciousness, it can't really make any
further advance. Is it a thisness
finding an objective out thatness? Or is
it only discovering how the human mind
works projected out into an apparent
universe which an illusory thinks is is
a that being looked at by a this. No,
it's all of this being looked at by a
this. That's what we know from here.
There's only a this finding a this. And
what it finds is so if you're looking
for little blue pebbles, you then you
will find the little blue pebbles. If
you find looking for little green ones,
you'll find little green ones because
that's what you're looking for. So, you
can only discover that which you're
seeking.
>> Uhhuh.
>> We were talking about the uh
consciousness level of people in the
room rising as a result of being here.
I'm wondering does that persist when we
leave this day? You know, does that does
that
>> Oh, does it hang with you?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. No, it goes with you.
>> It goes with the ticket. You know, you
get to take it you get to take it home.
anything left on the plate, you get to
take the sandwiches, cookies home with
you.
>> That sort of brings up the question that
if you come to all the lectures that how
far do you uh get
>> you want to ask?
>> But they own they own it. What you own
you own. Yeah.
>> Uh it only goes up because you've owned
it because you've said yes to it.
Because you've incorporated and made it
part of yours. Otherwise the calibrated
level doesn't go up. I give the same
lecture to another audience. They start
at uh 182 and at the end lecture it's
182. Nobody got anything or took it into
themselves. Then they got absorbed or
moved as a result. But you know a group
like this is very easy to talk to
because they they're like a sponge. You
know they can't pick up anything and go
with it.
Okay. So we'll take a break again.