Let's go on to Mr. Chiron. Can we have
permission to do Mr. Chiron in this
group at this time?
God help us all. Mr. Chiron is over 200.
He says, "Uhuh. Mr. Chiron is over 175,
180, 185, 190." Oh. Oh. So, thank you.
So, that's a little bit of a reversal
over what it used to be. I think Chiron
used to be high and came down and Arafat
was barely down and has come up. That's
fact.
Okay. Chiron was once higher resistance
and has now come down resist. And Arafat
was once lower and has now come up
resistance. Yeah, you've got a oddball
crisscross there
in which u
one has come down in order to win and
the other one is coming up in order to
survive. I think in Arafat realizes
unless he owns integrity, he's a dead
duck. And I think he realizes that it's
not Palestine or or himself his
political self that's at risk. It's
integrity itself. I think it's
intuitively dawning on him that unless
he owns the power of integrity, he's a
goner.
That's a fact. Yeah. By God, he is
getting it. So all the people praying
for it, it's working. [laughter]
Somebody's hearing it. You know, the
first one that really regains integrity
is going to win and win the respect of
the world and the backing of the world.
Whichever one finally comes out with
integrity is going to win. Okay.
So that's Arafat and Chin Yogananda. We
had calibrated him before was at 550.
He would therefore be the perfect
spiritual teacher. Let's say all
spiritual teachers are good for wherever
you're at. See if this guy tells you
it's wrong to chap up infidels. That's a
danger advance. So he's a very good guru
till there. You understand what I'm
saying?
550 is the classical guru in our in our
world. Um, these are people that are
unconditionally loving. What would we
say he was 550? Yeah. 550. 540 is
unconditional love.
Anything that runs 540 and and up is
certainly
uh worthy of great respect. And
uh as we said, the 12step groups are
540.
They represent the pure essence of
spirituality.
Uh that which has no opinion on external
issues tells you right away that it's
not corruptible. There's no no opinions
on outside issues.
Anything that has no opinions on outside
issues can't be bought or sold, can it?
Because there's no lever out there to
grab them by. [laughter]
They don't care what you think of them.
They don't need your post. They don't
need your money. They can just be who
they are. Yes.
Does your man still fight with you?
>> Um, that I'm not going to ask because
you're asking the fate of the karmic
fate of his spirit. I don't know.
As of being here on the planet, he
calibrated 550. I presume his writings
are 550.
I presume that's correct.
As I said before, sometimes there's a
disparity between the writings of a
teacher and their current calibration.
It's because as you evolve, don't forget
a test of that comes up all the time and
you can buy its opposite. Um
the uh power over others. I remember
being presented with that one and uh I
forget what that level was. We
calibrated it later.
Uh but it was really infinite. I mean
enormous power unlimited by any
limitation.
And it was offered. All you had to do
was say yes to it. And u so the
in the book I'm finishing now I feel
responsible as a spiritual educator
teacher or whatever you want to call it
to forewarn people that as you grow up
that which is luciferic is waiting for
you.
Uh it's waiting for you and when you get
there then it heads for you. It's like
the media doesn't bite you until you
become a celebrity. You know what I
mean?
You're not you're not influencing enough
people. But when you start getting up
there now, the sniper's bullet starts
getting aimed at you. So um I feel it's
a responsibility to educate student
about that that as you evolve that which
would deny the reality of what you have
uh realized as truth becomes challenged
and it's done cleverly. I think I wrote
it rather specifically in the book I'm
finishing now. I remember it at
at about 8:50 or so comes in
the realization out of nowhere. It's not
via a person. No spiritual truth comes
from other beings. You don't you know
you don't know what you know cuz that
told me or some spirit ascended
spiritual master told you that it's a
realization of that which you are. So
then suddenly in the purity of that
incredible space
comes the
knowingness. It comes out of like a
nonverbal realization.
Now that you are beyond personal karma
and there is no arbitrary god
to punish you in as much as there is no
payment and no no consequences to
anything you do, think or say, you are
free to have absolute power over others.
And that is the ultimate luciferic. And
of course that's one is apparently
brought down a number of teachers.
The other defect that the luciferic
offers on the way up is um to see love
as a trap.
Now remember that that's a very specific
one that as you go up higher and higher
lucifer will come to you either in the
form of a person a teacher or an entity
coming through somebody you're talking
to will say don't you see that love is
just a trap
and they will sometimes use the Buddha's
description of the ultimate reality is
void to verify it and back it up.
No, it's not love that's a limitation to
the realization of the infinite reality.
It's the attachment to it.
None of these things have any power
within themsself. All the things we're
scared about and thought about through
all spiritual and religious instruction.
It isn't the thing themselves. It's our
attachment to it. Is money and sex a
great limitation to spiritual evolution?
Well, Ramach Krishna said so. and young
men. It's such a problem that he forbid
it. You weren't allowed to even touch
money. Money and sex were the two traps
within a certain limited context. That's
so in a broader context. No, it's the
attachment to them. A free being can go
to the casino, win or lose, and walk
away untouched. Huh?
Untouched.
Because the reality is not involved in
it. No, it's the attachment to love and
money. It's the attachment to power. So
I saw the luciferic. What the luciferic
is is the temptation
to own the power of God and but not the
love of God.
You see because the love of God that
which divinity is both power and
and love.
If you negate the reality of the love
then you have nothing but power over
others.
And the next question to the luciferic,
they haven't tried it since because I
beat him beat his ass.
[laughter]
The next thing to the luciferic is that
what what is your attachment to power,
buddy? [laughter]
Now that you have no karmic consequences
to pay, now that there's no arbitrary
God waiting up there from the Old
Testament to beat the chops off you, you
know, why don't you just do whatever
you're going to do? Forget about
conscience. There's no payment can be
extracted by anyone.
All power is yours. That's what it's
said.
Jesus got the same deal in the garden of
these seminary.
Jesus got the same presentation, didn't
he? He work kneel down and worship me
all powers.
So the answer to that luciferic demon
because you'll get him if you're moving
towards enlightenment. He waiting for
you
and teachers have failed to prepare
their students with what the what the
answer is to the naive mind. It sounds
very convincing. It comes from very high
feeling authority. This amazing
realization and You have no
consequences. There's nothing unknown to
be answerable to for.
You're beyond human karma.
All power is yours.
And if you stop at that point, you
become a prince in the luciferic realm.
And the question to that demon is this.
Of
what good is your power? Of what use?
Are you still attached to power?
What do you want with power?
I remember one time somebody hated me
very intensely
which I picked up on the
inner. It was reported via dream from
somebody else that this energy hated me.
And uh this is when I was a celebrity in
a different realm, you know, in New
York. I had the biggest practice in the
world, in the country and all this. This
guy hated me and I said, "What does he
hate me for?" He envious your power. I
power? What power?
I treat lots and lots of sick people.
What What is he talking about?
A projection from his own unconscious, I
guess. Because if you contextualize
things in terms of power, then you see
that as power.
If a million people go, does that give
you power?
It doesn't change who you are one iota.
You know what we were talking about
women before.
You see what is
what is
is the magnificence of the woman is the
divinity within her womanhood. It's not
her womanhood per se, but the divinity
expressing itself in this particular
case as femininity. And when we get to
father's day, [laughter]
expressing itself as masculinity. You
see, those are just the world of form.
It's only how it looks from a viewpoint
of perception. The viewpoint of
perception.
And as consciousness evolves, it
transcends gender. You know that which
you are has no limitations such as
gender anyway.
All right. So you've already got the
answer to the ultimate. The one is the
challenge to love to sacrifice love for
gain and power over others and
manipulation sexual satisfaction or
whatever.
The other great temptation
is the luc luciferica.
The teaching that love is an attachment
and a limitation and a block to
enlightenment
is a major error.
We have permission to ask that is a
statement of fact. Is it that is a
statement of fact and you see the
authority background of it is the
misinterpretation of the Buddha teaching
of u the ultimate reality as void.
Void is nothingness.
What the Buddha meant was no thingness.
Nothingness beyond form. What the Buddha
said was that the ultimate truth is the
unmanifest.
Beyond form
is just beyond form.
That's different.
If the void was the absolute reality,
there'd be nobody to tell you about it,
wouldn't there? [laughter]
First of all, they'd have nothing to say
and there'd be no one there to say it.
The ego will create a feeling of
oblivion and you go into oblivion
because oblivion is not the same as the
ultimate reality. You can't stay there
and you come out of oblivion and you
find yourself three years old in a
little cart. [laughter]
Shocked to discover that you have a body
again.
People ask me about the various
religions in the world. So far the the
Buddhists have uh
maintained the strictest purest. The m
the Buddhists have maintained the
highest teaching. People ask what's the
highest teaching? I think uh classic
Buddhism
the highest teaching is classic Buddhism
is yeah classic Buddhism is pretty much
it hasn't sold out for u political gain
control political power see what
happened with Christianity is it got
sold out uh peace me all doled out to
the various rulers and emperors and
various things
so far Buddhism has avoided God I don't
know where Hinduism is currently. Let's
just see where the world is at
currently.
Uh well, of course, you have to be quite
definite how you express this.
Uh current Protest Protestantism as it
is practiced in America. Protestantism
in a as a general is over 485, 490, 495,
500, 505.
Let me write this down. Protestantism
505 as of today.
Um
Protestantism
consciousness level of it is falling
resist
rising resist
it's becoming secularized progressive.
Oh I see it's destroyed by
secularization here. All right. So what
happens is as a religion gets older is
it begins to get secularized by the
civilization
uh uh by the civilization in which it
finds itself.
Um you know financial considerations it
takes money to build churches and you
got to build a congregation and
everything costs money. You got to have
insurance. You know what I mean?
Especially if you're a prison.
Imagine the malpractice insurance.
talking about doctors. Yeah. Jeez.
Uh
so of the world's current religion let's
say well let's ask for current we ask we
can ask about Hinduism is Hinduism is
practiced um in its most pristine level
in India currently is over 500 is 560
by 80 580 Hinduism ism at its best in
current India comes out of 575. Hope
somebody's writing this down because
afterwards I don't remember any of this.
Um
Hinduism you were going to ask about
Islam. Islam
uh as currently practiced in the Arabic
world uh calibrates over 200 resist. No
Islam has just been destroyed.
Destroyed.
uh Christianity, Catholicism. Okay.
Catholicism in the current world
exclusive of
priestly events is over 500 510.
Catholicism
at its best, at its pristine best in
current America is over 510.
It's over 509. It's about 510. 50 it's
over 505 506
it's loving it's loving but it has lost
its pristine don't forget in the
beginning it was a thousand
uh at the time of Christ Christianity
was a thousand so it's come down
considerably
Islam has come down considerably
Hinduism still maintains it what do we
say 575 that's very high 575
and
It's close to enlightenment at 600. Wow.
And Buddhism has declined the least.
Let's see what Buddhism is at currently.
>> Let's see.
>> Yeah, I'll have to.
>> Yes, I'll define classically.
Um, okay.
Uh, the vehicle uh Henana,
we have permission to ask about Henana.
Hinana calibrates over 800 850. Sorry.
Hana Buddhism is practiced today
calibrates over 850
860 870 870 Okay, we got 870. Somebody
put that down. Uh
Mahana,
which includes Zen calibrates over 850,
860, 865.
Did we get 860 for both of them?
>> Somebody's writing it down. Huh?
>> 870. Let's do it again. Hinana and
Mahayana are almost identical as far as
calibrated level consciousness
resistance. Yeah, they're almost
identical. One is the lesser vehicle,
one is the greater vehicle.
Uh
lotus land Buddhism is something else.
Let's do lotus land. Lotus land is the
closest to Christianity. We have
permission to do lotus land in front of
this audience. Resist lotus land. We
have permission in front of this
audience. Resist.
Uh, it's over 550, 580, 590, 600.
Lotus land is right at 600. Resist.
Yeah, I would suspect so.
Lotus land is right at 600.
Lotus land is the Buddha of salvation in
which the Buddha becomes the savior.
It's the equivalent of Christianity.
The rad the radical
spiritual the spiritual realist you
might say
[laughter]
this the spiritual teacher has been
kicked around throughout the centuries
realizes
that in this world which calibrated less
than 190 over the many centuries
that the best you could hope for was to
reach unconditional love
don't forget in a world that's dominated
by hatred love I mean hatred anger
Starvation, war, killing, rape, suicide.
500 is almost astronomical.
Almost astronomical.
So in a way Jesus Christ
the lotus land Buddhist the Buddha of
salvation
uh the great savior is saying aim for
500 or 540 and from there on you don't
have to worry let's see if that's true
you get to 540 you won't have to worry
[laughter]
you get the unconditional love you won't
have to worry
>> speak
Native American
>> I did uh the Native American. See the
Native American was a monotheist. Said
it said the history of religion will
tell you the first monotheists were in
ancient Egypt. U the sun god a kenan
wasn't it? EA econom econ somebody
was the for was the launching of
monotheism for the first time about 500
BC
or 5,000 BC somewhere around there
[laughter]
[sighs and gasps]
somewhere around there. What was her
question?
>> What was their question?
>> Oh, a Native American. Yes. All right.
So the great accomplishment there was
the pagan tribes
uh
and the reason ancient Egypt rejected
that particular
uh ruler is he brought in monotheism
just like in
uh later Roman culture there were many
gods numerous gods. So we say primitive
religion tended to have numerous gods, a
pantheon of gods which still exist to
this day uh in Hinduism. Each one you
might say are subdivisions of deity
divided into various representations.
What was the question?
>> Oh, Native American. Yes. All right. So
the Native American, you see, was into
monotheism.
Of course, we don't know how far back
their history is, what their teachings
were back that far. Ancient Egypt, we
still have, you know, actually the
writings from those days, but the Native
American believed in uh the great spirit
was already a monotheist
actually was a monotheist. And I think
we we calibrated Chief Detroit who's
very famous. Anybody here familiar with
the
his recitations of Chief Detroit are
quite profound. All right. Chief Detroit
who is an airquay uh calibrated over 700
resists 710 720 730 730 that's higher
than Muhammad Muhammad came in at 731
so that capacity to realize the presence
of an infinite
infinite oneness the infinite divinity
out of which all of creation manifests
See, the Native American could see the
expression of divinity in all things
that live. Brother elk, brother Rabbit,
apologizing to
u the fact I've got to knock you out of
body.
See, the animal doesn't die when you
knock it out of body. It just gets
knocked out of body. Let's see. That's a
fact. It's just Yeah, it hardly
sometimes hardly animal hardly even
notices it. The animal doesn't really
notice it most of the time. He's just
doesn't notice it most of the time. It's
flying around in a little flies body.
Swat. Now it's flying around in his
little atheric body. It doesn't even
really notice. It comes back in through
another egg and it's flying and it's got
amnesia. It's got amnesia for that. It
doesn't even remember that it was and
then wasn't. That doesn't worry worry
about not being because it doesn't
remember that it wasn't.
[laughter]
So the Native American already knew that
the actually the animal doesn't actually
die. It sacrifices this
physical manifestation. Now I has to go
around the other side and wait to come
back again. And so he says, "Thank you,
brother, for giving up your physicality
for the maintenance of my physicality.
And uh don't take this personally, but I
got to eat you." [laughter]
[laughter]
All right. So the inlect puts that down
as what is it? Pantheism
and Catholicism. It's a it's a it's an
error to see divinity in all of nature
and all that exists because traditional
religion tends to be uh seeing God as
transcendent.
You see the probably the reason Buddhism
comes up so high is because the Buddha
taught that the realization of the
absolute truth
by whatever you call it divinity or the
ultimate or reality.
He called it the Buddha nature is merely
to realize that which we talked about
this morning that which you really are
that instant right before mind gets in
and interrupts your awareness of who you
are.
So the Buddha said God is is imminent
imminent not. So the ultimate divine
divinity is both imminent within as the
self with a capital S and transcendent
as the supreme. When Krishna writes of
the supreme
he really it's really meant to be not
only the supreme transcendent but the
the supreme imminent as the self
as that the essence of that which you
are. So the Native American then was
quite evolved, quite evolved
and um happily didn't know he was
evolved or he would have made a thing
out of it, [laughter]
chopped it to pieces. You know what I'm
saying? Uh
addiction is a whole story in itself. I
don't know if we have time to do
addiction. We'll do addiction then we'll
break again. Uh I did a you know
probably one of the first lectures on
consciousness and was on addiction back
in the early 80s.
I did it in California at a conference
on consciousness and addiction.
My understanding of addiction at that
time was that you see all this stuff
from here down is painful.
Uh
painful as compared to it's not being
there.
Drugs drugs block out your experiencing
of all this here.
A drug itself only calibrates around 75
or 80.
Alcohol calibrates around 75.
Drug calibrate around 75 to 80. See, as
chemicals, these chemicals just
calibrate around 75 or 80.
Uh
the awareness of the presence of
God within is blocked by
the conversation and the energy fields
of the ego.
It's like the clouds in the sky block
off the radiance of the sun.
What the drugs do is silence these
energy fields.
Anesthetize them. Therefore, you only
feel the radiance of the higher
vibrations. Now, all these vibrations
are going on at once. Let's say light
comes through a spectrum. You see the
radiance. If I block all these off now
you experience this is who I am. Huh?
The experience even if experienced once
is like a near-death experience. The
first time you get high, you already got
it.
First time you feel that lovely,
gorgeous, I love everybody. Isn't life
grand?
Whoa.
You got it right now. Right that moment.
Anybody who doesn't keep repeating that
must be stupid. [laughter]
I say I'm going to go back to here, go
to the office, and be poed at my boss
and worry about my What's the matter
with that idiot? Why didn't he just
block it off and stay there? Stay stoned
and live there. You know what I'm
saying?
That's what the voice within says. Why
should I live this miserable, horrible
life? Have a few beers on the way to
work. Not hurting anybody. It's my
money, right?
[laughter]
Well,
so that euphoria then is not so the drug
it doesn't have the capacity to create a
high. The point is it is not the drug
that creates this feeling of euphoria.
The feeling of euphoria is the radiance
of the self.
Is this all right? So if we block off
the negative energies, then what's left
is the radiance of the self. You feel
high, you feel fantastic, you feel
great.
The only problem is you didn't really
transcend the lower sense of the ego.
You only temporarily blocked it off. You
found a shortcut.
Somehow that creates some kind of a
karmic debt. Some kind of a karmic debt,
right? Uh somehow that creates some kind
of a karmic debt. You know, somehow it's
as though the money that you stole you
now owe back later with with interest.
Anybody has gone through withdrawal from
drugs or alcohol knows I think you pay
it and with interest all that you stole
you might say uh in an artificial manner
uh
now you're not allowed to touch it if
you're going to recover one day at a
time you don't have you can't touch any
of it. So then what happens is the way
back legitimately is discovered. So the
12 steps is nothing but how to come from
an artificially induced euphoria
back into a lovingness which you have
actually become. Now because you have
become it, you own it. It's no longer
vulnerable. Nobody can take it away from
you
because lovingness is a condition. It's
a way of being. It's a way of being. And
as members of this group know, because
there's a great deal of lovingness here
as you walk through Walmarts,
your lovingness goes with you. And
people intuit it. That's why they smile
at you and and they're open and very
vulnerable with you. You see, what love
is is an openness and a vulnerability.
Lady, I bump into her basket and she was
just wide open, totally vulnerable to
me. You know, I could have snatched a
person running. [laughter]
She probably would have said thank you.
How can we help you? [laughter]
Would you like another person? All
right.
Trust. Part of love is trust. The more
loving we are, the more capable we are
of trust. So,
all right. That's the way we get out of
uh the negative. Um
so, that's the story on addiction pretty
much. You get addicted. What you're
addicted to is this state. Once you
experience this state, nothing less than
that is going to ever do. Tell you
near-death experience. How many people
here had near-death experiences? Right?
Nothing nothing in this world comes near
it. Uh the longing to return to that
state of awareness, that condition, that
presence hangs with you. And that's what
the addict has to get off of. And that's
why recovery is slow, difficult and
statistically
uh
these levels are not necessarily
progressive. You know, it's not like
grade school and then third grade,
fourth grade. You can make great leaps
hitting bottom. You know, the story of
addiction is to me addiction is the fast
way to God. You either die or you get
it. [laughter]
Either guy or you did it. So, it's like
la last gaspers, you know, you've been
63 times on this planet and you're
getting pretty desperate.
Uh, the fastest way either makes or
breaks you is addiction. You either die
in sanity and agony and horrible death
or you transcend it. So, you can go all
the way from down here suicidal suicidal
right here and suddenly go into
a presence infinite state.
Incredible state. Incredible state.
Like the presence of God. From the
depths of hell, one can call forth.
If there is a God, I ask him to help me.
Then remember nothing and suddenly stand
in the infinite presence.
So that's from the lower depths of hell
to
what was the level of that day? The
level of that day was over 750, 800,
850, 890, 900.
It was the ultimate from the depths of
hell to the presence of the infinite.
So can you jump levels? You bet you can.
As we said, you can go from grief, stop
seeing it as loss, feeling sorry for
yourself and juicing it out of self-pity
and seeing it as freedom. Where is
freedom up here? 200 and something.
Where is freedom? What happened to our
freedom? Somebody's stolen our freedom.
[laughter]
I want my freedom back. Please, where's
my freedom?
>> [laughter]
>> I know what I can grieve. I can grieve.
I've lost my freedom. [laughter]
Oh, I'm safe with attachment again. Oh,
you see, [laughter]
if you get attached to freedom, then it
becomes a compulsion. You see them out
there. You see them out there on
motorcycles all day long. Tattoos, hair
flying, I'm free.
[laughter]
I mean, they're hooked on it. You know
what I mean? They're like addicted to
it. You take away his Harley and he
thinks suicide.
We told you last time, nobody ever
shoots a Harley-Davidson by mistake. You
know, children, family members,
ex-wives, mother-in-laws shot all the
time by accident, but never
Harley-Davidson. [laughter]
So, you can get addicted to even
freedom, right? It's a compulsion to
never get a job, never put a tie on. You
get like hooked on it. You know what I'm
saying? You got run by it.
All right. So, we can bypass levels.
There is a a relic around. Let's ask if
we can ask about this relic. I don't
know anything about this relic. I only
heard that there is a relic around.
There is a relic around. Resist. This is
a genuine relic resist. You have
permission to ask about this relic
resist.
This is a genuine real relic. It is. It
has the vibration
within it of its original owner. It is
okay. Oh, I get what it is. Okay. It's
over 800, 850, 860, 870, 890.
It's energy of this. The only energy
within this relic is over 890, 900, 920.
Okay, this uh there's a relic somewhere.
I don't know where it is.
Well, I'm going to go visit that. I
don't know about you, but [laughter]
I just want to touch my little toe to
that 920 and
photograph it, maybe.
All right. So, that's something I've
never asked before. H
the spiritual energy can persist in the
physical body even after physical death
resist. It only does so in evolved
enlightened beings resist it does so in
the average human being resist.
Oh and the enlightened being the remains
are special. Huh.
That's strange isn't it? Realize that.
>> I'm going to stuff you.
[laughter]
There's karmic merit in uh visiting a
relic. Is it the karmic merit
arises from
the reverence from the presence within
resist?
Oh, I see. The karmic merit arises from
really the reverence for God is
represented by the energy of the relic
resistance. Okay. The karmic
benefit arises from the energy of the
relic itself as a physicality
resistance.
They both
there's a value to visiting relics
folks. Hate to tell you that
[laughter]
I mean travel restrictions being what
they are today. Uh going through you
know you getting one your bag saying we
got to check you out for relics boy.
[laughter]
He's carrying a relic in his pocket.
Bring it take him aside for his
[laughter]
the date of death we said before is is
already set at the time of the time of
birth. The date of death is already set.
Uh the question was is that date like in
written in cement resist is that date
like equivalent of written in cement
resist
do we have other options resist
no you don't really oh you think you did
well I don't have to feel bad about that
one anymore now
[laughter]
I had the opportunity didn't take it
after year years after I said what an
idiot you were man you There you were in
that infinite presence one one with the
infinite lovingness of the universe and
you said I'm going back in the body.
What a stupid idiot.
I thought we'd resume because we do have
sort of a special
occasion in Sedona today that might bear
considering the questions we asked
before.
Uh
we got that the relics did uh let's re
let's redo it
the relics that are spoken of are
genuine resist it's worthwhile for us to
visit them resist wow there's a karmic
merit in so doing resist huh
the there is an energy that radiates
from them resist
which is over 800 900 950 960 16.
>> Wow. Ah. All right. We get we get that
this is a rather unique occasion. These
Krishna
sorry these relics which are present in
Sedona uh will only be visitable for the
rest of the day. I thought what we might
do is break early. I'll tell you how to
get there. And those of you who wish to,
we might visit the the relics because
the alternative is to spend 14 hours
flying over to Asia [laughter] to visit
which I have done. I'll tell you from
here to Korea is a long way.
>> I miss going this year. Um, all right.
So we have these uh uh it says that they
are genuine
um
that it is of karmic merit to merely
visit them that they do create benefit
beneficience of their own
and of course the willingness to
acknowledge
what would we say uh the value of
divinity and whatever its expression is
a karmic merit that comes from within
your own spiritual
self. Um, and so we thought we might
break early and go visit the u the
relics.
They're on display until 5:00. Then at
5:00, the Buddhist community here, which
is represented by our wonderful uh
videographer,
and there's a strong Buddhist community
here. Uh anyway, they have
somehow gotten these assembled relics
here. Anything Calvary is that high is
worth a visit. So I thought we might
break early. I'll tell you where it is.
You go out West Sedona.
But I thought it might be fun. We just
go visit these relics. Uh using
kinesiology, we can calibrate the merit,
the worthwhile, the impact it would have
on our own spiritual growth or
worthwhileness of it. and we'll take a
democratic vote. We'll go. There
[laughter] you go.
[cheering]
There's true democracy for you.
>> My votes are all and yours are none.
Okay.
>> What' you say?
>> The directions.
>> Oh, yes.
>> Uh it's a rare opportunity and of course
it's in it's aligned with our purpose.
Our purpose is to evolve spiritually.
And when we get on the other side,
we'll say to him, "And we did visit your
relics." [laughter]
Yeah. Again, he's at the door. He said,
"Did you visit my relics when you had an
opportunity?" No.
Never turned down a relic. I've never
visited a relic before, and I never gave
it serious consideration until we
calibrated it. And uh now the integrity
of this um
oh and therefore the intent it's
integrity. All right. So the integrity
see the integrity is in the intention
but what is the intention to acknowledge
divinity in whatever its representative
form. We did it this morning using women
as an example. We didn't mean to use it
as women visav men. You see the ego
tends to see that as a separation.
You're just naming mankind by that name.
Uh mankind is uh also by the name of
man. It's w man. Woman man woman. Man is
part of woman. Right. [laughter]
Or is woman in addition on the man? He
stuck a wool in front of men
[laughter]
and got women.
All right. So anyway, that's all
political boiling
to to see the divinity within all that
exists. Well, the divinity,
the existence of divinity within certain
aspects of life or certain gurus, pieces
of consciousness that speak to you, etc.
It's just that they're more
recognizable. You see that same divinity
is within all that exists. It is not
possible for anything to exist unless it
comes out of creation. All that comes
out of creation
then
has within it the essence of divinity or
it could not be
anything to be.
So
in deciding to go over and visit the
relic then we take take advantage of a
rare opportunity.
Uh we give thanks to the Buddhist
community for making it available to us
and we give recognition to the value of
the our own research methods to discern
the true from the false. I'm sure
there's all kinds of false relics all
over the world.
And if you go to South America, many of
these things are for sale. You know,
pre-Colombian stuff is for sale
everywhere on every street corner. You
as soon as you get off the airplane,
pre-colian art. [laughter]
And uh it makes your arm go weak. That's
the only difference.
Pre-colian art that makes your arm go
strong costs a lot more than that which
makes you go weak. I'll tell you.
All right. So, we've got some
interesting questions. I want to finish
them. So, if their exhibit is until 5,
if we leave here at 4:00, that would
give us plenty of time and pretty things
are pretty much cleaned up. I just
thought it'd be fun to move us as a
group, you know, to a different uh
context and um acknowledge uh the
Buddhist community here, which in itself
is a a good thing to do. Huh. We saw
that Buddhism had declined the least of
all the world's religions. very
interestingly
uh because it stuck to its own
spirituality rather than getting
involved in local politics. What
happened to most religions I think is
that they got invaded by the local
politics to get the church to align
itself with this regime versus the house
of Hapsburg versus the house of
something or other of course is what
costed a lot of its uh
uh believability. So, I think we've
answered most of the most of the
questions that we had on top of the
list. I want to make sure
um we're often asked about Joel
Goldsmith and we've done him many times.
You see, there's many spiritual teachers
that are in the high 400s. Joel
Goldsmith is in the high 400s, 490, 495,
500. Bill Goldmith's writings are over
495.
His writings are over 500. His writings
are about 495 results. Okay, that so
he's taking you as far as the intellect
can take you in the understanding of of
truth. The teachers in the high 400s are
often very excellent because they have
mastered
mastered the knowledge and of course
spiritual
searchers very are very often in the
400s and the air addition that comes in
the high 400s is what springs you into
the 500s. How do you get out of the
400s? Because you learn within the 400s
the world of the intellect
that the intellect is not going to give
you the answer.
So the greatest fruit that the intellect
can give you is I ain't what you're
looking for. Whoa. [laughter]
Because all society thinks all you got
to do is read another book and take
another course and you'll get there.
uh Nissa Gada Maharaj's level
consciousness on the earth was over 700
conscious the book I am that I think is
uh
other books really are in the high 400s.
Um somebody asked me what love is. Well,
okay.
Um,
as as commonly understood, love is an
emotion and this emotion goes from here
to there.
Love is something you give, something is
love is something you get. Consequently,
love is something you can lose.
Uh,
therefore, love is valitional.
It's conditional.
Uh
there's a famous cowboy song. I just
don't love you anymore. [laughter]
Sorry babe, but [laughter]
just ain't got that old feeling for you
the way I used to.
Love is also something that's deserved.
You have to earn love. You have to pay
for love.
It's like a commodity, a very pleasant
one and highly regarded.
uh but it's lossable.
It goes from here to there and therefore
it's subject to dissolution
and vulnerable to attack
is something that people fear the loss
of etc.
>> So what is love actually? Well,
as those of you who've gone into really
high spaces know that love,
the love they're talking about is really
about up here. Love is a way of being.
It's a way, it's a way of being with the
world.
The condition of lovingness prevails
as a permanency because it's what and
it's what you are. It's what you become.
The willingness to be friendly in
Walmarts is because you're a loving
being. It's coming from your lovingness.
Doesn't depend on whether this lady with
her basket smiles you or appreciates it.
It's just who you are. And it's who you
are in all
times, places, and conditions. It
doesn't change. Uh it's not given. It's
not lost. It's not taken away. It's not
something you earn. It's what you've
become. Similar to generosity.
Generosity is a way of being in the
world. It doesn't have to do with money.
Generosity has to do with the
willingness to be open and share what
you are with life for
what? For the good of life itself only
because of that's what you are. It's
because that's where you become. You
automatically
you automatically
uh appreciate life and all its
expressions.
You know what I mean? You drive along a
country road. The place I go to the
girls ranch three mornings a week where
I'm chief of staff. Got 55 girls there
and all conditions of disarray. I'll
tell you. Anyway, on the way there,
there's a bunch of periodically there's
a bunch of cows, you know, bunch of
cattle there and you can't help but stop
and love and the cows look at you like
this. [laughter]
I mean, I say this morning, I'm not
going to stop with the cows at 8:00
already. But then the cow's standing
there and she looks at me like that and
you just have to be with the cow because
she's life expressing itself
uh in that beautiful way that a cow is.
You know, a cow just a beautiful
creature being what it is. You know what
I'm saying? And there's the little
calves there being what they are. And of
course, you know, they're going to get
eaten someday.
[laughter]
You can even say, "I'm going to love
eating you sometime, baby." You know
[laughter]
why is the cow there?
Well, if you didn't eat meat, there
wouldn't be any cows. Do you realize
that?
If everybody gives up eating meat, cows
will disappear. Who's going to raise
them? Who's going to feed them? Who's
going to go to all that work for what?
Right?
The eating of cows then means that
millions of cows come into experiencing
life.
When they get put to sleep, they
instantly disappear on the other side.
They come back as another cow again.
[laughter]
It's all the same cow. Let's see if
that's true.
Generically speaking, it's all the same
cow. It's all the same cow.
[laughter]
Why do we say that? Because the
consciousness of We did it on our orange
kitty.
All orange kitties are the same orange
Yes,
we said that evolution as it appears in
physicality is the reflection of that
which has occurred on the level of
consciousness. It's on the level of
consciousness that form evolves into the
forms that we see as life on earth.
The form can then be optionally
energized by energies on the other side.
You might would say for speech on the
other side can opt to be the life energy
within that form.
That form has a central you remember in
power versus force we talked about
attractor fields in the nonlinear domain
of what appears as chaos. what appears
as chaos. Multiple orange kitties all
over the planet. There is a central
attractor field of orange kittiness.
We could even draw if we had a computer.
There's an attractor field.
Nature draws attractor fields for you
all the time. All you have to do is fly
in a plane and look at the formation of
the earth below you and the vegetation.
But as you watch um the there's a
beautiful series of uh videos on right
now or TVs on now called the Deep Blue.
What is it? Deep Blue. Yeah.
Underwater. A magnificent series on the
History Channel. I think it's a
Discovery Channel. Anyway, incredible be
the incredible beauty at the depth of
the sea. Stunning creatures.
So stunningly beautiful. You just suck
in your breath. You go. That's existing
5,000 ft down in the dark. Woo! Gorgeous
radiance. Beautiful. But you see the
schools of fish feeling as though
they're worn like this.
You see the whole tens of thousands of
fish all in the design like this. You
see the same thing with the birds taking
off. They all like this. Well, the
presumption of the ego which believes in
causality is that this bird is flying
like like a squadron of fighters this
many feet from this one. It thinks that
these birds are following this birds
and being causing these. So actually
what's happening these birds are not
following each other at all. These birds
are being controlled by an attractor
field in the visible domain.
Each bird is uniquely controlled by the
same attractor field and that's why they
line up. They're not following each
other at all.
So when you see the birds feeling like
that, that's the demonstration of the
attractor field which is in the
invisible domain becoming manifest in a
flock of birds in flight.
[clears throat]
That's stunningly obvious in this
series. is the deep blue. You see um 5
million minnows all turning as one and
the shine of light as they swing. They
swing like one one being one being and
thousands and thousands of bodies
simultaneously. That's the attractive
field.
The animal gods of the Native Americans,
the many gods of the Hindu pantheon
all represent to me
um symbolic
those are the attractor fields. In other
words,
there is central to all orange kittiness
the essence of that which makes orange
kittiness and it radiates out what looks
to perception as individual separate
orange kitties. But there's only one
orange kittiness that's radiating out.
You understand what I'm saying?
So the essence of each genus and species
then exists on the invisible domain and
actualizes within the physical.
What I what I said is true is
there is one orange kitty. Is there is
one orange kitty.
The reason I know this is I've had a
whole series of orange kitties and it's
always the same kitty. [laughter]
I mean, in orange kitty's nature is the
same. You ever notice that? Doberman
pinchers. They're all the same, you
know. So we love each species and and
genus because it represents in
physicality
certain characteristics that we've come
to love and appreciate.
>> That goes for the animal kingdom. But
does that go with the human?
>> Oh, you would ask such a question,
wouldn't you?
[laughter]
Oh my goodness. I don't know.
Turn out the lights.
>> [laughter]
>> Uh this is a valid question resist.
It's an answerable question resist. It's
not an answerable question. [laughter]
I think because of individual karma in
the condition of the human we have
individual karma resist. Yeah. So we
don't represent a
>> uh a group uh the manifestation of
otherwise there would be like one human
being and we would all radiate out the
sameness the sameness
but what we radiate mainly is difference
right there's the sameness to our
essence but a difference
um
could be the different races maybe
represent do perhaps different races
represent sort sort of a coalition of
energies resist. No, they don't even. So
humanness is an individual karma resist.
>> Orange kittiness is a group karma
resist. Well, that's there's certain
spiritual teachings that animals share a
group karma whereas mankind share has
individual karmas. So the orange kitties
then have a group orange kittiness
karma. [laughter]
They have a pretty good pretty good
karma.
>> We have permission to ask that humans
have the capacity to reincarnate in
subhuman forms. He says no. I've asked
that before. We always get no. So you
don't have to worry about coming back as
a frog.
Only a frog gets to come back as a frog.
[laughter]
All right.
What was the reason we got out of this?
Anyway,
[laughter]
this asks the purpose of enlightenment.
Well, is the highest level of
enlightenment the desire to help others
become enlightened? Um you might say so
if that but that that again is a program
that is rejected on the condition. The
condition only is what it is.
Uh
it is what it is to the world because
because it is that it's similar to the
question about uh loving lovingness.
You see you don't you're not loving in
in order to anything.
You understand what I'm saying? You're
not once a person becomes loving there
is no purpose to that lovingness. It's
just what they are. They become that.
So you're not that lovingness doesn't
like present itself in Walmarts in order
to make other shoppers happy or for any
other reason. It's just who you are. And
who you are turns some people on and
probably makes other people hate you.
[laughter]
Lots of people hate love. is there were
countries in the world in which it was
illegal. You know, Cambodia was one of
them. Remember Paul taught you put to
death if you display affection and
lovingness in public. It's suitable for
execution. So,
a Japanese warrior and then king who
showed lovingness towards his captive,
I'm sure would may have been gotten
himself bayoneted on the spot for
for insubordination.
Nikki What's the Is there a correlation
between intelligence and consciousness?
>> I never asked that before. You mean like
IQ?
>> IQ.
>> Yeah, there is some correlation,
meaningful correlation between IQ and
consciousness resist. No,
you can be have an IQ and be very
stupid.
You can be very stupid and be very
beneficial to the world, you know.
So, no, apparently not. It's just some
people are built more muscular. Somebody
came up today and he to me he was the
perfect misamore. You know what I mean?
He had like muscles and bone. You
probably lift 100 pounds like, you know,
[laughter]
I was born
an ectomorph. You know,
lifting anything over 50 pounds has
always been a struggle my whole life.
Uh, and I always tell people people are
born sematypes, endomorph. This is off
the subject. Endomorph, misamorph, and
ectomorph.
And endomorph tends to be chunky.
Tends to be very family oriented. Got to
have family around you.
Values family, homelessness,
domestic domesticity,
and dieting probably isn't going to do
any good at all. [laughter]
If you look at a candy bar, you gain a
half a pound. So,
uh, they have a wonderful digestive
tract. The misamomorph tends to be more
muscular and, um, capable of sports.
And the, uh, the misomorph, as they get
older, if they sit in front of the TV
and drink beer, they're going to put it
on. But if the misamomorph cuts down
their diet and exercises, they will lose
weight. So the misomorph can either gain
or lose weight. The endomorph is going
to stay on diet pills, but they aren't
going to really take much of the weight
off. Not going to change your lifestyle
anyway. The ectomorph is skinny and
neurotic and [laughter]
who's that that actor that's that
typifies the
>> Woody typifies the ectomorph. Yeah. thin
and wiry and somewhat nervous and
neurotic and prone to nervous breakdowns
and [laughter]
never going to gain weight. And uh
eating too much just makes him throw up.
He doesn't gain weight. [laughter]
So we sort of accept our fate, you might
say. If you're an endomorph, quit
struggling with it. Become the happy,
jolly, fat person everybody loves.
If you're a misamorph, be sure and diet
and exercise to gain weight. And if
you're an ectomorph, you're too neurotic
to worry about it anyway. So [laughter]
now [clears throat]
you can't you can't rate anything. You
can't rate anything up and down the
scale. You can only know where it is.
Many of the world's best spiritual
teachers are in the four high 400s.
They are more capable of expressing,
verbalizing, making comprehensible and
understandable
the word spiritual truth than people in
the 800s. Let's say
most people in the 800s are totally
unintelligible.
[laughter]
Most of them stay home. You never see
them in public.
First of all, there's nothing to say.
[laughter]
That's quite a roadblock to begin with.
Take you 20, 30 years to figure what
you're going to say about all this.
There's nothing to say about it.
Most spiritual teachers of a very
advanced enlightenment are not
necessarily good teachers any more than
Padreski was a great piano teacher.
Najinski was probably a very lousy
ballet teacher. You know what I'm
saying? The fact that you're a great
musician doesn't make you a great
teacher.
The best teachers of good musicians are
themselves, not genius musicians.
Otherwise, they'd be on the road.
[laughter]
I
in childhood the great spirit artistic
merit was greatly appreciated by the
family. We traveled endless miles to see
Jinsky or
any of the great performers of the day
and my grandfather on my mother's side
knew a lot of them personally and uh
many of them were great virtuosos but as
teachers forget it make one mistake get
out of here I can't stand it you stupid
idiot
lousy teachers all right so a great
teacher very often the high 400s these
these are often the most aryodite
teachers. They are the most erodite
teachers. They uh can compare the
world's literature, cite all the
references that reinforce and confirm
each other.
So they are great clarifiers, great
clarifiers of sphere of the truth. So
you can't say that a teacher at 540 is
better than a teacher at 480. They're
different. They're teaching different
things. The higher one goes up the
scale, the more it is that the presence
of that which you are itself has the
transformative effect rather than
verbatim the wording the wording.
So
there are some beings in whose presence
one feels an elevation of consciousness
but they're writing
verbal fluency. They're not great
writers and there's great writers who
have the data down pat.
Um they're interesting but you don't
exactly go into a state of somat in the
presency.
So one is not better than the other.
They serve different purposes.
Very often when you go with the way of
the heart which we'll talk more about at
a later date you can bypass and shoot
all the way up
because love bypasses the intellect
altogether. You understand? Love takes
you to 500 and it's beyond reason. It's
beyond reason. Somebody says why do you
love that person thing but
you can't give any reason why can't give
any reason
certain music instantly tr you instantly
transcend who's who's that newest tape
we have right right now CD
>> let me just calibrate what he's at the
music I'm thinking of now calibrates
over 500 520 530 540 550 560 570 My god,
he's way up there. What's his name? The
music I'm thinking about calibrates at
560.
>> Andrea Andrea.
>> Andre Belli. Right. Correct. All right.
So, you see what the space you go into
as you listen to that music.
If the way of the pathway of the heart
is open in you tends to bring tears.
That's why it's not good to drive
[laughter] to.
[laughter]
It's bad music to drive to because you
lose all interest in going anywhere for
anything about anything.
I mean, everything is totally incomplete
right now. Where is there to go for
what? You know what I mean? [laughter]
That's his name. Five. What was he
>> way up there? Okay. So, artistic the
that that which is great beauty. The
great cathedrals of the world, you know,
calibrate around 700 chart.
Uh you go into a cathedral like chart,
you can't stop crying. It's just just
overwhelming. And
some of the great cathedrals I've been
in, uh, they just overwhelm you. All
thought stops. The joy of beauty comes
up and
you can't function in that state. I've
noticed there's no graffiti in the great
cathedrals of the world. Isn't that
interesting? Because that which hates
beauty is the source of graffiti.
Graffiti usually uh desecrates that
which is let's see what does it
desecrate it usually desecrates that
which is below 200 resist desecrates
that which is about 190 resist
graffiti is usually used to desecrate
that which is above 190 192 195
okay so anything calibrates around 195
tends to pull forth graffiti to face it.
Huh?
At 500, even the weirdest
even the weirdest person
doesn't have what it takes.
So great beauty then overwhelms people,
sets them back into the reality of the
self out of which such thinkingness does
not arise. With the exception of extreme
madness,
I see you being right now. Okay. Uh,
we have permission to ask about the PA
resist.
Uh, PA calibrates over 550, 580, 590. PA
calibrates at 590.
Now desecrated the PA. We have
permission to calibrate it. Is this its
level was over 60.
level was over 40 45
that which desecrated the piet. Remember
when the piet was attacked the entity
was 4 40 says 45. Oh boy. Still walking
in two feet though. [laughter] 45
uh infuriated probably by the
perfection. What did we say the piano
calibrated at? I forget.
>> Anyway, way up there. [clears throat]
So that which is incredible beauty
uh has a tendency to
has a tendency to throw you back into
the self
to walk into the world's great
cathedrals that have been there for a
thousand years.
The incredible music, the incense, the
beauty shining forth through the stained
glass windows. Even if it's not your
religion, the reverence,
the collective reverence, the worship of
God expressing itself as such incredible
beauty
um has an uplifting experience.
One then ascribes that experience to the
out there of the cathedral. No, the
cathedral
lifts you to the experience of that
which is present at all times within
yourself. But you only allow yourself to
experience under these conditions. That
which you're experiencing is the
presence of the divine within.
Incredible beauty then unleashes
the dam in which
that which is love, that which is sacred
shines forth. And that radiance is what
makes you feel like crying. You know,
incredible beauty brings a lump in your
throat.
Incredible beauty as it rises
makes the hair in the back of your head
stand up and then as it gets even
higher, you can't stop crying. Huh? Is
that so? Those of you who gone into
incredibly beautiful spaces, you know
that you can't stop crying at a certain
level. At a certain level, you can't
even witness anything has to do with
love. It just breaks you up. [laughter]
Little puppy walking down the street,
you break out in tears.
I mean it's adorableness is lovableness
and you can see what it means to the
owner. You know the whole space of all
that lovingness is just too much. It
just knocks you out. So there's a
difficult time there.
A difficult time of weeping and crying
over
the presence of divinity as beauty and
love.
It says is consciousness a byproduct of
spirit entering
dense matter? No. No, it is not.
Uh, consciousness arises prior to
matter.
Genesis is pretty pretty correct
according to our own research that out
of what appeared as chaos chaos to
perception
which is really nonform
arose light as consciousness.
The power of consciousness is such that
it can Power of consciousness is such
that it can initiate life when it
touches matter
and that matter then evolves from below
up. So creation is from above down
and then we see the evolution of life
forms from the bottom up from the ooze
to us. [laughter]
Then we can look down on the worms. I'm
getting somebody to look that up.
What is the nursing mind and
consciousness? Consciousness is the
field
which supports the phenomena called
mind. Consciousness itself is without
form.
Without form
just before you think a thought, what
you're experiencing is awareness which
is radiating out of it's an aspect of
consciousness.
If you want to, you can watch and see
right before every thought you have an
opportunity.
That opportunity presents itself
continuously.
It lasts about 110,000th of a second.
You got to be quick.
That space is 110,000 of a second
approximately. It's just it's more than
that. It's just No, it's not more than
that. Darn it. It's always been like
110,000th of a second. When we say that,
it sounds very very minimal. And and who
the heck's going to make it through the
crack in 110,000 of a second?
That's an only temporal physical time.
That doesn't sound like much. But in
that space of that 110,000th of a
second, you're looking at eternity,
which is outside of time. So you have
a window open to that which is beyond
time, the infinite
one 10,000 of a second. What does that
mean? What does that mean? It means then
you become aware of your thoughts as
sort of a thingness thing. It's sort of
like your thought is a thing. See, right
prior to this thing occupying the space
of your attention
is a space. If there wasn't an empty
space, the thought would have no place
to present itself.
You know what I'm saying?
Without a blank screen, there's nothing
for a thought project itself upon.
with a little self-reflection. The best
place to become enlightened is driving,
riding in a taxi cab, any place,
[laughter]
waiting in the line at the waiting in
the line of the supermarket.
One's thoughts go by nonchalantly and
suddenly one sees
one instant right before the thought.
That's who you are. And you pull back
into that nothinkingness
prior to thought.
It's there all the time. It's there all
the time. So it's said that the entryway
into enlightenment is in the instant of
now.
That now is always present.
It's all it only takes a curiosity
really.
You don't have to
fast and join a monastery or a nunnery.
Beat drums and gongs and
channel lake.
to beat yourself, deprive yourself.
Every possible instant of now is forever
present.
Outside of time, forever is this moment.
So you really in a way have forever to
notice this. Out of sheer curiosity,
forget about enlightenment, forget about
God, all that.
Just out of sheer curiosity watch and
see
that each thought arises in an empty
space
be with the empty space
and as the next thought arises the empty
space is there again the empty space
presents itself continuously
and then one sees
I'm the space and not the thought it's
simple huh
Any more questions? I want to make sure
they're all answered and then maybe
we'll take off for the relics, which
will be a fun thing to do. Yes.
>> What did you say?
>> Oh, yes, indeed. Right. Oh, yeah. I hope
someone remembers what we were. We were
433,
I think.
>> Okay. We have permission to calibrate
the energy of the group. So, we're 433.
434 435 436 437 438 439 440 Wow 441 Holy
went up seven points 700 points
as a group.
As a group, as we said, the average
consciousness advances five points in a
lifetime. We went up seven points in a
matter of hours, you know.
So what does that mean? It just means
there's a willingness to hold belief in
suspension
and allow a different energy to
recontextualize what you already know.
I probably didn't say anything you
haven't heard before today. A few unique
things perhaps,
but the way in which that is held, the
readiness of the field.
So to become enlightened is to see that
one is the field and not the content of
the field. That's the only difference.
You're the field in which the thought
presents itself
and you'll catch it one/10enth onto the
second. You don't think that's possible?
Yep. Because if you're watching for it,
if you're watching for it, that tends to
potentiate its appearance. The one the
minute you get curious about what is
there prior to thought, prior to mind,
the minute you get curious about it,
that fires off the quantum potential for
that to present itself as a reality. You
understand what I'm saying?
To merely be interested, curious about
it,
to hold that in mind tends to increase
potentiality, the likelihood of it
manifesting as a experiential reality.
Yes.
>> Question
is perfect.
changing then
>> if everything is perfect what's the
point of perfecting anything because it
is perfect already that the essence
Everything is perfect as it is.
What does that mean?
Nothing can be
other than the perfection of that which
it is. That has to do with the
a thing that's very hard to explain.
Uh the radical identity of self of that
which it is with that which it is
in which there is no
absence of information that has to be
projected onto it by the observer.
What you're asking is easy to see,
difficult to answer in a verbal form.
The formula lies a piece of plastic.
It's absolutely perfect.
It's perfectly
It's perfectly exactly that which it is.
The perfection is in that it fulfills
its karmic destiny at all times.
Absolutely.
It has no destiny to be a camel. It' be
an imperfect camel.
But it is not an imperfect piece of
plastic.
It would be imperfect in the eye of the
groundskeeper
who feels it should be swept away.
But that's trying to impose in trying to
impose form on what is.
What it is is the absolute perfect
expression of all that it take
throughout the evolution of
all of time through the invention of
plastic through the all of us being here
through the gravity through the
barometric pressure for the for this
building to be here for Sedona to be
founded etc. It took all of that for
this divine piece of plastic to be where
it is. [laughter]
You You remember that movie? It was one
of the funniest movies I ever saw which
a Coke bottle falls from a plane into
What was the name of that movie?
>> Huh?
>> What was the name of that?
>> The gods must be crazy.
>> The gods must be crazy. Right.
>> [laughter]
>> The gods must be crazy is one of the a
wonderful movie for spiritual seekers,
you know. See, because you see how we
project onto a thing what we think it
is, which has nothing to do with what it
is, you know, is its value became when
two people wanted the one Coke bottle.
That was the beginning of the breakdown
of their society. [laughter]
One person had a Coke bottle and only
one. Uh oh, now everybody else wanted
the Coke bottle and the fight started.
Of course, that's a very comical. So
perfection is then what you see it as.
There are different levels of perfection
because they're really all a definition.
You see, in the absolute,
the word perfection would be
meaningless.
Just like the word beauty is meaningless
when you stand there looking at a
sunset.
Incredible. All words you could use
would be
uh irrelevant.
Everything is perfectly
what it is at every moment because there
is no other possibility.
Any other possibility is an intellectual
positionality.
with no that does not reflect any
reality.
Nothing can be anything except that
which it is. To be that which it is, it
already has to be perfectly that which
it is, or it couldn't exist at all.
For the evolution of consciousness to
take the forms that it takes. So, as
consciousness evolves, it takes these
forms. Here's the Middle East right
here. He's here's a a Neanderthal man.
Here's uh
it gets to here from there.
So you can't make it wrong for being in
the process of getting here. It isn't
here yet.
That which was what it was. As evolution
became more and more conscious. Homo
u spiritus is just born.
five minutes ago.
[laughter]
Spirit is is just barely the latest
evolutionary tree of mankind.
It doesn't value the physical and the
material anymore. It doesn't value
wealth. It doesn't value the ego come
comes out of the evolution of animal
consciousness and survival.
Homo spirit is doesn't even value that
anymore.
You can give me $10 million to do
something non-integrous and it would
sound like a joke, wouldn't it? You can
sell your soul for what? That would be
ridiculous
to to to someone who's not to that
level, it would be a major temptation.
You understand? So, we've become a
different kind of an entity.
If I say to you, visiting a relic will
have its spiritual advantage, we all
say, hey, let's go.
If it does not have a spiritual
advantage, we wouldn't leave, would we?
So we are brought together by
by spiritual intention
that which sets our karma. So as a group
we share a common karma. people
dedicated to spiritual intention that is
what becomes paramount surrounds other
objectives
makes people travel long distances etc.
So the same drive that brings us here
today would give us the spiritual
curiosity. What is it like to visit uh a
genuine ancient spiritual relic? I don't
know. I've never visited one.
[laughter]
So spiritual curiosity then
is
charged up by our spiritual commitment.
Will we all see God as we visit the
relic? I don't know. Will we all get a
great buzz? No. I think we all get a
great satisfaction that somehow as a
group we acknowledge the presence of God
as it radiates forth into this world at
a consciousness level of over 900 which
is a very rare opportunity.
So out of reverence for God, we say
thanks for the opportunity and avail
oursel of probably once in a lifetime
experience. How many here before have
had a chance to visit a great relic?
Couple.
All right. So we'll quit here for today.
I've tried to answer all the questions I
could.
It's been my great pleasure. It's been
my pleasure.
>> [applause]