Keep
The
The music
Keep
The music is
so
so incredible.
so incredible. I
so incredible. I can't
so incredible. I can't function
so incredible. I can't function on
so incredible. I can't function on its
own.
Beauty
Beauty just
Beauty just wipes
Beauty just wipes you
Beauty just wipes you out.
Beauty just wipes you out. You
Beauty just wipes you out. You have
Beauty just wipes you out. You have to
avoid
avoid beauty
Beauty just wipes you out. You have to
avoid beauty if
avoid beauty if you're
Beauty just wipes you out. You have to
avoid beauty if you're going
avoid beauty if you're going to
Beauty just wipes you out. You have to
avoid beauty if you're going to stay
avoid beauty if you're going to stay in
the
the world.
I
I try
the world.
I try to
I try to avoid
the world.
I try to avoid beauty
I try to avoid beauty as
the world.
I try to avoid beauty as much
I try to avoid beauty as much as
the world.
I try to avoid beauty as much as I
I try to avoid beauty as much as I can.
Then
Then I
Then I notice
Then I notice how
Then I notice how beautiful
Then I notice how beautiful my
Then I notice how beautiful my fingers
are.
It's
It's true.
It's true. Uh
It's true. Uh that
It's true. Uh that calibrates
It's true. Uh that calibrates at
It's true. Uh that calibrates at 750.
Exquisite
Exquisite beauty
It's true. Uh that calibrates at 750.
Exquisite beauty takes
Exquisite beauty takes you
It's true. Uh that calibrates at 750.
Exquisite beauty takes you beyond
what
what the
what the nervous
what the nervous system
what the nervous system can
what the nervous system can handle.
So
So I
what the nervous system can handle.
So I said
So I said in
what the nervous system can handle.
So I said in the
So I said in the book
what the nervous system can handle.
So I said in the book I'm
So I said in the book I'm finishing
what the nervous system can handle.
So I said in the book I'm finishing now
or
or the
or the one
or the one I
or the one I just
or the one I just finished,
or the one I just finished, I
or the one I just finished, I don't
remember
remember which,
that
that when
that when people
that when people get
that when people get to
that when people get to a
that when people get to a certain
that when people get to a certain level
of
of consciousness,
there
there is
there is a
there is a tendency
there is a tendency to
there is a tendency to leave
there is a tendency to leave the
there is a tendency to leave the world
because
because one
there is a tendency to leave the world
because one gets
because one gets sort
there is a tendency to leave the world
because one gets sort of
because one gets sort of removed
there is a tendency to leave the world
because one gets sort of removed by
because one gets sort of removed by it.
And
And uh
you
you can
And uh
you can see
you can see how
And uh
you can see how hard
you can see how hard it
And uh
you can see how hard it is
you can see how hard it is to
And uh
you can see how hard it is to function
at
at 7:50,
to
to be
at 7:50,
to be in
to be in the
at 7:50,
to be in the condition
to be in the condition that
at 7:50,
to be in the condition that that
to be in the condition that that music
takes
takes you
takes you to
and
and take
takes you to
and take the
and take the subway
takes you to
and take the subway and
and take the subway and get
takes you to
and take the subway and get to
and take the subway and get to work
takes you to
and take the subway and get to work on
time,
would
would feel
time,
would feel a
would feel a little
time,
would feel a little difficult.
would feel a little difficult. So
time,
would feel a little difficult. So the
tendency
tendency is
tendency is to
tendency is to withdraw
from
from the
tendency is to withdraw
from the world
and
and rebalance.
and rebalance. uh
and rebalance. uh if
and rebalance. uh if it's
and rebalance. uh if it's possible
and rebalance. uh if it's possible to
rebalance
and
and to
and to see
what
what one's
and to see
what one's remaining
what one's remaining capacities
and to see
what one's remaining capacities may
what one's remaining capacities may be.
Yeah.
Today
Today we're
Yeah.
Today we're going
Today we're going to
Yeah.
Today we're going to be
Today we're going to be talking
Yeah.
Today we're going to be talking about
Today we're going to be talking about u
karma,
karma, a
karma, a subject
karma, a subject which
karma, a subject which is
karma, a subject which is familiar
karma, a subject which is familiar to
those
those of
karma, a subject which is familiar to
those of an
those of an eastern
karma, a subject which is familiar to
those of an eastern background
those of an eastern background and
karma, a subject which is familiar to
those of an eastern background and not
all
all that
all that familiar
all that familiar to
all that familiar to people
all that familiar to people with
all that familiar to people with a
western
western background.
However,
However, you
However, you know,
However, you know, familiar
However, you know, familiar to
However, you know, familiar to uh
spiritual
spiritual students
and
and um
and um so
and um so I
and um so I thought
and um so I thought I
and um so I thought I would
and um so I thought I would uh
and um so I thought I would uh focus
today
today on
and um so I thought I would uh focus
today on its
today on its implications,
and um so I thought I would uh focus
today on its implications, its
today on its implications, its real
significance,
um
its
its complexity
its complexity and
its complexity and at
its complexity and at the
its complexity and at the same
its complexity and at the same time
simplicity
and
and um
and um what
and um what it
and um what it really
and um what it really means.
We
We said
and um what it really means.
We said that
We said that um
the
the entire
universe
universe is
universe is one
universe is one karmic
universe is one karmic unity.
There
There is
universe is one karmic unity.
There is one
There is one all-encompassing
karmic
karmic totality
karmic totality to
karmic totality to the
karmic totality to the allness
karmic totality to the allness of
karmic totality to the allness of all
karmic totality to the allness of all of
creation
in
in which
in which everything
in which everything is
in which everything is in
in which everything is in from
in which everything is in from moment
in which everything is in from moment to
moment
moment incredible
in which everything is in from moment to
moment incredible and
moment incredible and perfect
in which everything is in from moment to
moment incredible and perfect balance
with
with everything
with everything else.
harmonic
harmonic perfection.
Part
Part of
Part of that
perfection,
perfection, harmonic
Part of that
perfection, harmonic perfection,
is
what
what appears
is
what appears to
what appears to be
is
what appears to be chaotic.
And
And that
And that which
And that which seems
And that which seems to
And that which seems to be
And that which seems to be chaotic
And that which seems to be chaotic and
rule
rule against
And that which seems to be chaotic and
rule against the
rule against the harmonic
And that which seems to be chaotic and
rule against the harmonic balance
rule against the harmonic balance of
And that which seems to be chaotic and
rule against the harmonic balance of the
universe
is
is only
universe
is only so
is only so because
universe
is only so because of
is only so because of it
universe
is only so because of it being
is only so because of it being perceived
in
in that
in that way.
That
That harmony
in that way.
That harmony includes
That harmony includes the
in that way.
That harmony includes the capacity.
You
You might
You might say
You might say the
You might say the quantum
You might say the quantum potentiality
to
to suddenly
You might say the quantum potentiality
to suddenly become
to suddenly become its
You might say the quantum potentiality
to suddenly become its opposite.
gentle,
gentle, gentle
gentle, gentle children,
gentle, gentle children, listen
gentle, gentle children, listen to
gentle, gentle children, listen to me,
I'll
I'll kill
gentle, gentle children, listen to me,
I'll kill you.
People
People say,
People say, "Where
People say, "Where did
People say, "Where did that
People say, "Where did that come
People say, "Where did that come from?"
Adolf
Adolf Hitler
People say, "Where did that come from?"
Adolf Hitler had
Adolf Hitler had been
People say, "Where did that come from?"
Adolf Hitler had been loud
Adolf Hitler had been loud and
People say, "Where did that come from?"
Adolf Hitler had been loud and bang,
man.
man. And
man. And we
man. And we were
man. And we were praying
man. And we were praying and
man. And we were praying and singing
man. And we were praying and singing and
enjoying
enjoying the
man. And we were praying and singing and
enjoying the incense
enjoying the incense and
man. And we were praying and singing and
enjoying the incense and all
enjoying the incense and all of
man. And we were praying and singing and
enjoying the incense and all of a
enjoying the incense and all of a sudden
a
a bomb
a bomb came
a bomb came out
a bomb came out of
a bomb came out of someplace.
a bomb came out of someplace. How
a bomb came out of someplace. How can
that
that be?
a bomb came out of someplace. How can
that be? Doesn't
that be? Doesn't that
a bomb came out of someplace. How can
that be? Doesn't that disprove
that be? Doesn't that disprove the
existence
existence of
existence of God?
Well,
God's
God's hard
God's hard to
God's hard to get
God's hard to get rid
God's hard to get rid of.
God
God just
God's hard to get rid of.
God just won
God just won the
God's hard to get rid of.
God just won the vote
back
back into
back into existence
back into existence again.
back into existence again. I
back into existence again. I was
back into existence again. I was so
relieved.
relieved. I
back into existence again. I was so
relieved. I thought
relieved. I thought they
back into existence again. I was so
relieved. I thought they were
relieved. I thought they were going
back into existence again. I was so
relieved. I thought they were going to
vote
vote God
vote God out
vote God out of
vote God out of existence,
vote God out of existence, out
vote God out of existence, out of
vote God out of existence, out of the
money,
money, out
vote God out of existence, out of the
money, out of
money, out of the
vote God out of existence, out of the
money, out of the constitution.
They're
They're going
They're going to
They're going to take
They're going to take it
They're going to take it and
They're going to take it and God
They're going to take it and God we
trust
trust and
They're going to take it and God we
trust and eliminate
trust and eliminate it.
They're going to take it and God we
trust and eliminate it. Boy,
trust and eliminate it. Boy, I
They're going to take it and God we
trust and eliminate it. Boy, I was
scared.
But
But God
scared.
But God made
But God made it
scared.
But God made it just
But God made it just made
scared.
But God made it just made it
But God made it just made it through
scared.
But God made it just made it through by
three
three votes
three votes or
three votes or something
three votes or something or
three votes or something or five
three votes or something or five volts.
I
I understand
three votes or something or five volts.
I understand there
I understand there were
three votes or something or five volts.
I understand there were five
I understand there were five idiots
three votes or something or five volts.
I understand there were five idiots that
voted
voted against
voted against it.
Remember
Remember uh
voted against it.
Remember uh what
Remember uh what was
voted against it.
Remember uh what was her
Remember uh what was her name?
voted against it.
Remember uh what was her name? Maline
Murray
Murray O'Hare.
Speaking
Speaking of
Murray O'Hare.
Speaking of karma,
I
I remember
I remember this
I remember this guy
I remember this guy on
I remember this guy on TV
I remember this guy on TV trying
I remember this guy on TV trying to
unite
unite God
I remember this guy on TV trying to
unite God from
unite God from every
I remember this guy on TV trying to
unite God from every from
unite God from every from our
I remember this guy on TV trying to
unite God from every from our society.
And
And I
And I thought,
And I thought, Jesus,
And I thought, Jesus, doesn't
And I thought, Jesus, doesn't he
And I thought, Jesus, doesn't he ever
read
read the
And I thought, Jesus, doesn't he ever
read the story
read the story of
And I thought, Jesus, doesn't he ever
read the story of me?
read the story of me? Well,
And I thought, Jesus, doesn't he ever
read the story of me? Well, you
read the story of me? Well, you never
heard
heard of
heard of karma.
Karma
Karma is
heard of karma.
Karma is uh
Karma is uh interesting.
Oh
Oh boy,
Oh boy, I'm
Oh boy, I'm back
Oh boy, I'm back in
Oh boy, I'm back in the
Oh boy, I'm back in the intellect
Oh boy, I'm back in the intellect again.
Thank
Thank you.
Oh boy, I'm back in the intellect again.
Thank you. Lord,
back
back into
back into reason
back into reason and
back into reason and logic.
back into reason and logic. That
back into reason and logic. That was
scary.
Sometimes
Sometimes I
Sometimes I think
Sometimes I think I'm
Sometimes I think I'm going
Sometimes I think I'm going to
disappear.
disappear. I
Sometimes I think I'm going to
disappear. I was
disappear. I was talking
Sometimes I think I'm going to
disappear. I was talking to
disappear. I was talking to my
Sometimes I think I'm going to
disappear. I was talking to my friend
here
here this
here this morning.
here this morning. I
here this morning. I said,
here this morning. I said, "Are
here this morning. I said, "Are you
getting
getting smaller?"
here this morning. I said, "Are you
getting smaller?" You
getting smaller?" You get
here this morning. I said, "Are you
getting smaller?" You get He
getting smaller?" You get He seems
here this morning. I said, "Are you
getting smaller?" You get He seems to
getting
getting smaller
getting smaller every
getting smaller every time
getting smaller every time I
getting smaller every time I see
getting smaller every time I see him.
My
My clothes
getting smaller every time I see him.
My clothes keep
My clothes keep getting
getting smaller every time I see him.
My clothes keep getting bigger
My clothes keep getting bigger and
getting smaller every time I see him.
My clothes keep getting bigger and as
time
time goes
time goes on,
time goes on, you
time goes on, you get
time goes on, you get smaller
time goes on, you get smaller and
smaller.
smaller. Pretty
time goes on, you get smaller and
smaller. Pretty soon
smaller. Pretty soon you
time goes on, you get smaller and
smaller. Pretty soon you you're
smaller. Pretty soon you you're looking
up
up to
up to see
up to see yourself
up to see yourself in
up to see yourself in the
up to see yourself in the mirror.
Eventually,
Eventually, you
up to see yourself in the mirror.
Eventually, you disappear,
Eventually, you disappear, I
up to see yourself in the mirror.
Eventually, you disappear, I guess.
Well,
Well, the
Well, the karma
karma
karma is
Well, the karma
karma is really
karma is really an
Well, the karma
karma is really an incredibly
karma is really an incredibly great
story.
story. You
story. You can
story. You can also
story. You can also skip
story. You can also skip it
story. You can also skip it all
together.
At
At any
At any one
At any one instant,
At any one instant, you
At any one instant, you can
At any one instant, you can just
completely
completely and
At any one instant, you can just
completely and totally
completely and totally surrender
At any one instant, you can just
completely and totally surrender all
that
that you
that you think
that you think you
that you think you are
that you think you are to
that you think you are to God.
that you think you are to God. And
that you think you are to God. And um
of
of course
that you think you are to God. And um
of course that
of course that could
that you think you are to God. And um
of course that could be
of course that could be a
that you think you are to God. And um
of course that could be a karmically
determined
determined event.
What
What is
determined event.
What is the
What is the significance
determined event.
What is the significance of
What is the significance of karma?
determined event.
What is the significance of karma? In
What is the significance of karma? In in
some
some instances,
some instances, it's
some instances, it's a
some instances, it's a profound
significance.
significance. It
some instances, it's a profound
significance. It also
significance. It also makes
has
has has
has has the
has has the capacity
has has the capacity to
has has the capacity to light
has has the capacity to light up
has has the capacity to light up areas
of
of your
has has the capacity to light up areas
of your own
of your own life.
has has the capacity to light up areas
of your own life. so
of your own life. so that
has has the capacity to light up areas
of your own life. so that they
of your own life. so that they make
sense.
Without
Without understanding
sense.
Without understanding karma
as
as is
as is done
as is done in
as is done in the
as is done in the west,
it
it leaves
as is done in the west,
it leaves one
it leaves one with
as is done in the west,
it leaves one with really
it leaves one with really one
as is done in the west,
it leaves one with really one only
it leaves one with really one only one
tool
tool to
tool to approach
tool to approach God
tool to approach God and
tool to approach God and that's
tool to approach God and that's faith.
Because
Because nothing
tool to approach God and that's faith.
Because nothing in
Because nothing in life
tool to approach God and that's faith.
Because nothing in life makes
Because nothing in life makes sense.
Why
Why are
Why are some
Why are some children
Why are some children born
Why are some children born crippled
Why are some children born crippled and
blind?
blind? Born
Why are some children born crippled and
blind? Born with
blind? Born with AIDS,
Why are some children born crippled and
blind? Born with AIDS, born
blind? Born with AIDS, born from
Why are some children born crippled and
blind? Born with AIDS, born from cocaine
addicted
addicted mothers
addicted mothers with
addicted mothers with brain
addicted mothers with brain damage.
We
We noted
addicted mothers with brain damage.
We noted in
We noted in earlier
addicted mothers with brain damage.
We noted in earlier lectures
We noted in earlier lectures that
addicted mothers with brain damage.
We noted in earlier lectures that at
We noted in earlier lectures that at the
moment
moment of
moment of birth,
moment of birth, everybody
moment of birth, everybody already
moment of birth, everybody already has
moment of birth, everybody already has a
calibrated
calibrated level
moment of birth, everybody already has a
calibrated level of
calibrated level of consciousness.
At
At the
At the moment
At the moment of
At the moment of birth,
instantly
instantly you
At the moment of birth,
instantly you enter
instantly you enter this
At the moment of birth,
instantly you enter this domain
instantly you enter this domain at
At the moment of birth,
instantly you enter this domain at a
calibrated
calibrated level
calibrated level of
calibrated level of consciousness.
Now
Now we
calibrated level of consciousness.
Now we could
Now we could explain
calibrated level of consciousness.
Now we could explain physical
differences
differences genetically.
differences genetically. We
differences genetically. We could
differences genetically. We could say,
well,
well, that
differences genetically. We could say,
well, that genetic
well, that genetic pot
differences genetically. We could say,
well, that genetic pot pour
um
um the
um the game
um the game of
um the game of chance
um the game of chance of
um the game of chance of genes
um the game of chance of genes and
sperms
sperms and
um the game of chance of genes and
sperms and all
sperms and all that
um the game of chance of genes and
sperms and all that stuff
would
would explain
would explain why
this
this child
would explain why
this child is
this child is crippled,
would explain why
this child is crippled, this
this child is crippled, this child
would explain why
this child is crippled, this child is
blind,
blind, this
blind, this child
blind, this child is
blind, this child is deaf,
blind, this child is deaf, and
blind, this child is deaf, and this
child
child is
blind, this child is deaf, and this
child is a
child is a genius,
blind, this child is deaf, and this
child is a genius, and
child is a genius, and this
blind, this child is deaf, and this
child is a genius, and this child
child is a genius, and this child writes
symphonies
symphonies at
symphonies at age
symphonies at age four.
That
That would
symphonies at age four.
That would be
That would be the
symphonies at age four.
That would be the mechanistic
reductionistic
uh
uh scientific
reductionistic
uh scientific explanation.
It's
It's just
It's just genetic
It's just genetic chance,
combinations
combinations and
It's just genetic chance,
combinations and permutations
combinations and permutations of
It's just genetic chance,
combinations and permutations of all
those
those genes
those genes and
those genes and chromosomes.
And
And so
those genes and chromosomes.
And so that
And so that would
those genes and chromosomes.
And so that would be
And so that would be fine
except
except that
except that when
except that when we
except that when we calibrate
except that when we calibrate their
levels
levels of
except that when we calibrate their
levels of consciousness,
levels of consciousness, we
except that when we calibrate their
levels of consciousness, we find
levels of consciousness, we find that
the
the calibrated
the calibrated level
the calibrated level of
the calibrated level of consciousness
the calibrated level of consciousness is
completely
completely different.
the calibrated level of consciousness is
completely different. That
completely different. That is
the calibrated level of consciousness is
completely different. That is not
genetically
genetically determined.
genetically determined. It's
genetically determined. It's not
determined
determined by
genetically determined. It's not
determined by chromosomes.
determined by chromosomes. In
genetically determined. It's not
determined by chromosomes. In fact,
determined by chromosomes. In fact, it's
the
the other
the other way
the other way around.
the other way around. Because
the other way around. Because of
the other way around. Because of karmic
inheritance,
one
one automatically
one automatically comes
one automatically comes into
one automatically comes into certain
genetic
genetic and
one automatically comes into certain
genetic and chromosomeal
uh
uh patterns
uh patterns which
uh patterns which then
uh patterns which then become
uh patterns which then become the
mechanism
mechanism by
uh patterns which then become the
mechanism by which
mechanism by which that
uh patterns which then become the
mechanism by which that karmic
propensity
propensity expresses
propensity expresses itself.
What
What we
propensity expresses itself.
What we see
What we see in
propensity expresses itself.
What we see in the
visible
visible domain,
the
the discernable
visible domain,
the discernable domain
the discernable domain is
visible domain,
the discernable domain is consequences
and
and not
and not causes.
The
The fastest
and not causes.
The fastest spiritual
The fastest spiritual advance
and not causes.
The fastest spiritual advance is
The fastest spiritual advance is to
and not causes.
The fastest spiritual advance is to jump
beyond
beyond the
beyond the mind's
beyond the mind's belief
beyond the mind's belief in
beyond the mind's belief in causality.
There
There is
beyond the mind's belief in causality.
There is no
There is no causality
beyond the mind's belief in causality.
There is no causality anywhere
There is no causality anywhere in
beyond the mind's belief in causality.
There is no causality anywhere in this
domain.
domain. There's
domain. There's nothing
domain. There's nothing causing
anything.
All
All is
All is becoming
All is becoming that
All is becoming that which
All is becoming that which it
All is becoming that which it is
All is becoming that which it is out
All is becoming that which it is out of
its
its own
All is becoming that which it is out of
its own karmic
its own karmic potentiality
All is becoming that which it is out of
its own karmic potentiality and
fulfillment.
fulfillment. Because
fulfillment. Because creation
reveals
reveals itself.
And
And as
And as it
And as it reveals
And as it reveals itself,
And as it reveals itself, perception
sees
sees it
And as it reveals itself, perception
sees it as
sees it as progressive
And as it reveals itself, perception
sees it as progressive and
sees it as progressive and calls
And as it reveals itself, perception
sees it as progressive and calls it
evolution.
evolution. Yeah.
So
So from
evolution. Yeah.
So from the
So from the moment
evolution. Yeah.
So from the moment of
So from the moment of birth
evolution. Yeah.
So from the moment of birth there
So from the moment of birth there is
already
let's
let's say
already
let's say a
let's say a quality
already
let's say a quality of
let's say a quality of karma
already
let's say a quality of karma that
let's say a quality of karma that we
already
let's say a quality of karma that we can
calibrate
calibrate as
calibrate as a
calibrate as a level
calibrate as a level of
calibrate as a level of consciousness.
We
We use
calibrate as a level of consciousness.
We use this
We use this little
calibrate as a level of consciousness.
We use this little pattern
We use this little pattern here
just
just sort
just sort of
just sort of like
just sort of like a
just sort of like a homing
just sort of like a homing base,
just sort of like a homing base, you
know,
know, so
just sort of like a homing base, you
know, so I
know, so I remember
just sort of like a homing base, you
know, so I remember where
know, so I remember where I
just sort of like a homing base, you
know, so I remember where I am
know, so I remember where I am here
just sort of like a homing base, you
know, so I remember where I am here in
the
the world.
the world. Oh,
the world. Oh, yes.
Well,
Well, most
the world. Oh, yes.
Well, most of the
Well, most of the people
the world. Oh, yes.
Well, most of the people I'm
Well, most of the people I'm talking
about
about aren't
about aren't even
about aren't even on
about aren't even on here.
They
They didn't
about aren't even on here.
They didn't make
They didn't make it
about aren't even on here.
They didn't make it that
They didn't make it that far.
So
So this
domain
domain seems
So this
domain seems to
domain seems to be
So this
domain seems to be purgatorial
domain seems to be purgatorial in
So this
domain seems to be purgatorial in in
domain seems to be purgatorial in in its
qualities.
Let's
Let's ask
qualities.
Let's ask if
Let's ask if we
qualities.
Let's ask if we got
Let's ask if we got permission
qualities.
Let's ask if we got permission to
Let's ask if we got permission to ask
that.
that. We
that. We have
that. We have permission
that. We have permission to
that. We have permission to ask
that. We have permission to ask that
here.
This
This is
This is um
um
um a
This is um
um a um
um a um a
This is um
um a um a purgatorial
um a um a purgatorial type
This is um
um a um a purgatorial type domain
um a um a purgatorial type domain that
in
in which
uh
uh all
in which
uh all opportunities
uh all opportunities exist
in which
uh all opportunities exist both
uh all opportunities exist both high
in which
uh all opportunities exist both high and
low.
One
One can
low.
One can rise
One can rise or
low.
One can rise or fall.
One
One gets
One gets a
One gets a chance
One gets a chance to
One gets a chance to undo
One gets a chance to undo the
One gets a chance to undo the negative
karma
karma and
One gets a chance to undo the negative
karma and acquire
karma and acquire positive
One gets a chance to undo the negative
karma and acquire positive karma.
right?
right? So
right? So this
right? So this is
right? So this is a
right? So this is a formative
right? So this is a formative domain
purgatorial.
You
You can
You can tell
You can tell it's
You can tell it's purgatorial
You can tell it's purgatorial because
You can tell it's purgatorial because it
goes
goes from
You can tell it's purgatorial because it
goes from the
goes from the very
You can tell it's purgatorial because it
goes from the very ugliest
goes from the very ugliest and
You can tell it's purgatorial because it
goes from the very ugliest and worst
goes from the very ugliest and worst and
most
most horrific
to
to the
most horrific
to the most
to the most uh
most horrific
to the most uh divine.
The
The slums
The slums of
The slums of some
The slums of some of
The slums of some of the
The slums of some of the poorest
countries
countries in
The slums of some of the poorest
countries in the
countries in the world
The slums of some of the poorest
countries in the world where
countries in the world where I've
The slums of some of the poorest
countries in the world where I've been.
The
The slums
The slums are
The slums are unbelievable.
To
To somebody
The slums are unbelievable.
To somebody who've
To somebody who've grown
The slums are unbelievable.
To somebody who've grown up
To somebody who've grown up in
The slums are unbelievable.
To somebody who've grown up in the
western
western world
western world in
western world in America,
to
to walk
western world in America,
to walk through
to walk through those
western world in America,
to walk through those slums
to walk through those slums and
western world in America,
to walk through those slums and see
to walk through those slums and see the
style
style of
style of life
style of life is
style of life is like
style of life is like shocking.
style of life is like shocking. You
don't
don't even
style of life is like shocking. You
don't even believe
don't even believe it.
style of life is like shocking. You
don't even believe it. It's
don't even believe it. It's not
style of life is like shocking. You
don't even believe it. It's not even
possible
that
that that
possible
that that which
that that which calls
possible
that that which calls itself
that that which calls itself human
possible
that that which calls itself human could
survive
survive in
survive in these
survive in these conditions.
eating
eating bugs,
um
um bitten
um bitten by
um bitten by rats,
uh
uh using
um bitten by rats,
uh using his
uh using his building
um bitten by rats,
uh using his building materials,
pieces
pieces of
pieces of scrap
pieces of scrap and
pieces of scrap and cardboard
pieces of scrap and cardboard all
pieces of scrap and cardboard all pasted
together
outside
outside of
outside of uh
outside of uh what's
outside of uh what's it
capital
capital of
outside of uh what's it
capital of Brazil?
>> Rio
>> Rio di
>> Rio di Janeiro.
Well,
Well, anyway,
>> Rio di Janeiro.
Well, anyway, not
Well, anyway, not Brasilia,
>> Rio di Janeiro.
Well, anyway, not Brasilia, but
Well, anyway, not Brasilia, but uh
>> Rio di Janeiro.
Well, anyway, not Brasilia, but uh the
old
old city
old city was
old city was on
old city was on the
old city was on the side
old city was on the side of
old city was on the side of the
old city was on the side of the mountain
there.
there. They
old city was on the side of the mountain
there. They call
there. They call them,
old city was on the side of the mountain
there. They call them, I
there. They call them, I forget
old city was on the side of the mountain
there. They call them, I forget the
there. They call them, I forget the name
of
of the
of the world,
of the world, the
of the world, the words,
of the world, the words, but
of the world, the words, but uh
of the world, the words, but uh they
live
live in
of the world, the words, but uh they
live in pieces
live in pieces of
of the world, the words, but uh they
live in pieces of cardboard
live in pieces of cardboard boxes
of the world, the words, but uh they
live in pieces of cardboard boxes and
live in pieces of cardboard boxes and uh
maybe
maybe a
maybe a family
maybe a family of
maybe a family of 12
maybe a family of 12 lives
maybe a family of 12 lives on
maybe a family of 12 lives on there
maybe a family of 12 lives on there and
they
they take
maybe a family of 12 lives on there and
they take turns
they take turns sleeping
maybe a family of 12 lives on there and
they take turns sleeping in
they take turns sleeping in there.
Oh,
Oh, anyway,
Oh, anyway, it's
Oh, anyway, it's incredible.
Oh, anyway, it's incredible. And
everybody
everybody begs
Oh, anyway, it's incredible. And
everybody begs for
everybody begs for a
Oh, anyway, it's incredible. And
everybody begs for a living.
The
The biggest
The biggest mistake
The biggest mistake is
The biggest mistake is to
The biggest mistake is to give
The biggest mistake is to give a
The biggest mistake is to give a begging
child
child a
The biggest mistake is to give a begging
child a penny.
Then
Then they're
Then they're then
Then they're then over
Then they're then over you
Then they're then over you like
Then they're then over you like a
Then they're then over you like a swarm
of
of army
Then they're then over you like a swarm
of army ants
and
and you
and you realize
and you realize that
and you realize that you're
and you realize that you're not
and you realize that you're not going
and you realize that you're not going to
be
be able
and you realize that you're not going to
be able to
be able to hold
and you realize that you're not going to
be able to hold back
be able to hold back this
and you realize that you're not going to
be able to hold back this flood.
You
You can
You can hand
You can hand out
You can hand out money
You can hand out money to
You can hand out money to the
You can hand out money to the children
coming
coming up
You can hand out money to the children
coming up to
coming up to you
You can hand out money to the children
coming up to you and
coming up to you and it's
You can hand out money to the children
coming up to you and it's not
coming up to you and it's not going
You can hand out money to the children
coming up to you and it's not going to
alter
alter anything
alter anything because
alter anything because there's
alter anything because there's floods
alter anything because there's floods of
them.
them. As
alter anything because there's floods of
them. As you
them. As you go
alter anything because there's floods of
them. As you go out
them. As you go out handfuls
alter anything because there's floods of
them. As you go out handfuls of
them. As you go out handfuls of pennies,
more
more and
more and more
more and more and
more and more and more
more and more and more come
more and more and more come and
more and more and more come and more
more and more and more come and more and
more
more and
more and more and more come and more and
more and more
more and more come.
more and more and more come and more and
more and more come. They
more and more come. They would
more and more and more come and more and
more and more come. They would come
more and more come. They would come from
miles
miles and
miles and miles
miles and miles and
miles and miles and miles
and
and you
miles and miles and miles
and you see
and you see that
miles and miles and miles
and you see that it's
and you see that it's not
miles and miles and miles
and you see that it's not going
and you see that it's not going to
change
change anything
change anything at
change anything at all
trying
trying to
change anything at all
trying to change
trying to change the
change anything at all
trying to change the circumstance
because
because what
because what you're
because what you're seeing
because what you're seeing is
because what you're seeing is is
because what you're seeing is is the
effect.
effect. You're
because what you're seeing is is the
effect. You're seeing
effect. You're seeing the
because what you're seeing is is the
effect. You're seeing the effect.
effect. You're seeing the effect. You're
not
not seeing
not seeing the
not seeing the cause.
Certain
Certain neighborhoods
not seeing the cause.
Certain neighborhoods pull
Certain neighborhoods pull to
not seeing the cause.
Certain neighborhoods pull to them
that
that which
that which is
that which is negative.
that which is negative. The
that which is negative. The broken
window
window theory
that which is negative. The broken
window theory in
window theory in sociology.
The
The first
The first broken
The first broken factory
The first broken factory window,
The first broken factory window, if
The first broken factory window, if you
don't
don't repair
The first broken factory window, if you
don't repair it,
don't repair it, brings
The first broken factory window, if you
don't repair it, brings graffiti.
don't repair it, brings graffiti. The
graffiti
graffiti brings
graffiti brings the
graffiti brings the crime.
graffiti brings the crime. That
graffiti brings the crime. That brings
the
the rape.
graffiti brings the crime. That brings
the rape. That
the rape. That brings
graffiti brings the crime. That brings
the rape. That brings the
the rape. That brings the robbery.
graffiti brings the crime. That brings
the rape. That brings the robbery. That
brings
brings the
brings the drugs.
brings the drugs. That
brings the drugs. That brings
brings the drugs. That brings the
brings the drugs. That brings the arson.
That
That brings
brings the drugs. That brings the arson.
That brings the
That brings the murder.
The
The negative
The negative energy
The negative energy field
The negative energy field then
The negative energy field then pulls
The negative energy field then pulls to
it
it all
The negative energy field then pulls to
it all that
it all that which
The negative energy field then pulls to
it all that which is
it all that which is aligned
The negative energy field then pulls to
it all that which is aligned with
it all that which is aligned with that
field.
People
People say
field.
People say I
People say I don't
field.
People say I don't believe
People say I don't believe in
field.
People say I don't believe in karma.
People say I don't believe in karma. I
don't
don't want
don't want anybody
don't want anybody to
don't want anybody to believe
don't want anybody to believe in
don't want anybody to believe in karma
because
because what
don't want anybody to believe in karma
because what one
because what one is
don't want anybody to believe in karma
because what one is at
because what one is at any
don't want anybody to believe in karma
because what one is at any instant
is
is the
is the karmic
is the karmic conclusion
is the karmic conclusion of
is the karmic conclusion of all
is the karmic conclusion of all that
is the karmic conclusion of all that is
preceded.
You
You know
You know we
You know we the
You know we the main
You know we the main reason
You know we the main reason it's
You know we the main reason it's not
well
well understood
You know we the main reason it's not
well understood in
well understood in the
You know we the main reason it's not
well understood in the west
well understood in the west is
You know we the main reason it's not
well understood in the west is Jesus
well understood in the west is Jesus did
not
not get
not get into
not get into it
not get into it in
not get into it in any
not get into it in any great
not get into it in any great depth.
not get into it in any great depth. He
only
only mentioned
not get into it in any great depth. He
only mentioned it
only mentioned it briefly
as
as a
as a subject.
as a subject. Uh
but
but the
as a subject. Uh
but the teachings
but the teachings of
as a subject. Uh
but the teachings of Christianity
are
that
that all
are
that all actions
have
have a
have a consequence,
a
a spiritual
have a consequence,
a spiritual consequence
in
in in
in in another
in in another domain
in in another domain that
in in another domain that it
in in another domain that it has
in in another domain that it has to
in in another domain that it has to do
with
with the
in in another domain that it has to do
with the fact
with the fact that
in in another domain that it has to do
with the fact that every
with the fact that every action
in in another domain that it has to do
with the fact that every action then
with the fact that every action then has
some
some kind
some kind of
some kind of a
some kind of a registering
some kind of a registering in
some kind of a registering in the
some kind of a registering in the soul.
Some
Some kind
some kind of a registering in the soul.
Some kind of
Some kind of aspect
some kind of a registering in the soul.
Some kind of aspect of
Some kind of aspect of the
some kind of a registering in the soul.
Some kind of aspect of the soul
registers
for
for all
registers
for all time.
every
every action
every action and
every action and decision
every action and decision and
every action and decision and this
every action and decision and this will
determine
determine your
every action and decision and this will
determine your fate
determine your fate in
every action and decision and this will
determine your fate in later
other
other dimensions.
Heavens,
Heavens, hells
other dimensions.
Heavens, hells and
Heavens, hells and purgatories
are
are pretty
are pretty much
are pretty much accepted
are pretty much accepted by
are pretty much accepted by all
are pretty much accepted by all the
world's
world's religions
are pretty much accepted by all the
world's religions as
world's religions as a
are pretty much accepted by all the
world's religions as a reality.
Sometimes
Sometimes people
Sometimes people resist
Sometimes people resist karma
Sometimes people resist karma because
they
they have
Sometimes people resist karma because
they have it
they have it cons
Sometimes people resist karma because
they have it cons confused
they have it cons confused with
reincarnation.
reincarnation. They
reincarnation. They are
reincarnation. They are two
reincarnation. They are two different
things.
things. Reincarnation
reincarnation. They are two different
things. Reincarnation is
things. Reincarnation is one
reincarnation. They are two different
things. Reincarnation is one thing,
karma
karma is
karma is another.
All
All religions
karma is another.
All religions teach
All religions teach karma
karma is another.
All religions teach karma but
All religions teach karma but they
karma is another.
All religions teach karma but they don't
use
use that
use that term.
use that term. That
use that term. That is
use that term. That is what
use that term. That is what a
use that term. That is what a Sanskrit
term
term karma
use that term. That is what a Sanskrit
term karma I
term karma I suppose.
use that term. That is what a Sanskrit
term karma I suppose. Yeah.
They
They don't
They don't use
They don't use the
They don't use the terminology
because
because life
They don't use the terminology
because life seems
because life seems unfair
They don't use the terminology
because life seems unfair to
because life seems unfair to yourself
and
and to
and to others.
and to others. As
and to others. As you
and to others. As you look
and to others. As you look around
there's
there's a
and to others. As you look around
there's a bitterness
there's a bitterness towards
and to others. As you look around
there's a bitterness towards God
there's a bitterness towards God and
eventually
eventually even
eventually even a
eventually even a hatred
eventually even a hatred of
eventually even a hatred of God
comes
comes out
eventually even a hatred of God
comes out of
comes out of the
eventually even a hatred of God
comes out of the lack
comes out of the lack of
eventually even a hatred of God
comes out of the lack of karma
understanding
understanding karma.
understanding karma. Therefore,
understanding karma. Therefore, I
understanding karma. Therefore, I think
it's
it's beneficial
beneficial
beneficial to
beneficial to one's
beneficial to one's faith
beneficial to one's faith and
understanding
to
to understand
to understand that
to understand that what
to understand that what you
to understand that what you see
to understand that what you see are
consequences
consequences consequences
of
of things
consequences consequences
of things that
of things that have
consequences consequences
of things that have been
of things that have been brought
consequences consequences
of things that have been brought over
brought
brought in
brought in to
brought in to one's
brought in to one's life
brought in to one's life over
brought in to one's life over long
expanses
expanses of
brought in to one's life over long
expanses of time
with
with no
with no understanding
with no understanding of
with no understanding of karma.
with no understanding of karma. God
with no understanding of karma. God then
appears
appears unfair
with no understanding of karma. God then
appears unfair unfair.
Why
Why is
Why is how
Why is how does
Why is how does God
Why is how does God allow
Why is how does God allow this
Why is how does God allow this crippled
child
child to
Why is how does God allow this crippled
child to be
child to be born?
Why is how does God allow this crippled
child to be born? You
child to be born? You hear
Why is how does God allow this crippled
child to be born? You hear that
child to be born? You hear that all
Why is how does God allow this crippled
child to be born? You hear that all the
time.
Therefore,
Therefore, I
time.
Therefore, I don't
Therefore, I don't believe
time.
Therefore, I don't believe in
Therefore, I don't believe in God.
time.
Therefore, I don't believe in God. So,
failure
failure to
failure to comprehend
failure to comprehend karma,
failure to comprehend karma, I
failure to comprehend karma, I think,
leads
leads to
failure to comprehend karma, I think,
leads to a
leads to a lot
failure to comprehend karma, I think,
leads to a lot of
leads to a lot of atheism
failure to comprehend karma, I think,
leads to a lot of atheism and
agnosticism
and
and even
agnosticism
and even eventually
and even eventually rage
agnosticism
and even eventually rage and
and even eventually rage and hatred
agnosticism
and even eventually rage and hatred of
God
because
because it
God
because it doesn't
because it doesn't accept
responsibility.
responsibility. You
responsibility. You see
responsibility. You see with
responsibility. You see with karma
responsibility. You see with karma you
accept
accept the
responsibility. You see with karma you
accept the responsibility
accept the responsibility that
responsibility. You see with karma you
accept the responsibility that one's
accept the responsibility that one's own
decisions
and
and prior
decisions
and prior existences
are
are what
are what have
are what have determined
are what have determined the
are what have determined the situation.
Otherwise
Otherwise it
are what have determined the situation.
Otherwise it looks
Otherwise it looks like
are what have determined the situation.
Otherwise it looks like an
Otherwise it looks like an arbitrary
are what have determined the situation.
Otherwise it looks like an arbitrary god
just
just um
just um didn't
just um didn't give
just um didn't give a
just um didn't give a rap
just um didn't give a rap about
just um didn't give a rap about this
just um didn't give a rap about this kid
and
and favored
just um didn't give a rap about this kid
and favored this
and favored this one
just um didn't give a rap about this kid
and favored this one or
and favored this one or what?
just um didn't give a rap about this kid
and favored this one or what? How
and favored this one or what? How do
just um didn't give a rap about this kid
and favored this one or what? How do you
explain
explain God?
H
one
one of
one of the
one of the best
one of the best uses
one of the best uses of
one of the best uses of kinesiology
one of the best uses of kinesiology is
as
as a
one of the best uses of kinesiology is
as a research
as a research tool.
Within
Within 3
Within 3 minutes
Within 3 minutes flat,
Within 3 minutes flat, you
Within 3 minutes flat, you can
Within 3 minutes flat, you can satisfy
all
all your
Within 3 minutes flat, you can satisfy
all your questions
all your questions about
Within 3 minutes flat, you can satisfy
all your questions about karma.
That's
That's if
That's if you're
That's if you're slow.
Within
Within about
That's if you're slow.
Within about one
Within about one minute
That's if you're slow.
Within about one minute flat,
Within about one minute flat, you
That's if you're slow.
Within about one minute flat, you can
discover
the
the likelihoods
discover
the likelihoods of
the likelihoods of why
discover
the likelihoods of why your
the likelihoods of why your life
discover
the likelihoods of why your life is
the likelihoods of why your life is the
way
way it
way it is.
way it is. and
way it is. and certain
way it is. and certain things
way it is. and certain things have
recurred.
recurred. And
way it is. and certain things have
recurred. And as
recurred. And as people
way it is. and certain things have
recurred. And as people get
recurred. And as people get into
spiritual
spiritual study,
spiritual study, they
spiritual study, they begin
spiritual study, they begin to
spiritual study, they begin to sort
spiritual study, they begin to sort of
intuitively
intuitively get,
spiritual study, they begin to sort of
intuitively get, you
intuitively get, you know,
spiritual study, they begin to sort of
intuitively get, you know, I
intuitively get, you know, I must
spiritual study, they begin to sort of
intuitively get, you know, I must have
done
done something
done something in
done something in some
done something in some lifetime
done something in some lifetime to
explain
explain why
done something in some lifetime to
explain why this
explain why this is
done something in some lifetime to
explain why this is the
explain why this is the 14th
done something in some lifetime to
explain why this is the 14th time
explain why this is the 14th time a
white
white truck
white truck has
white truck has run
white truck has run into
white truck has run into the
white truck has run into the back
white truck has run into the back of
white truck has run into the back of my
car.
14 times,
14 times, 14
14 times, 14 different
14 times, 14 different cities.
14 times, 14 different cities. There's
got
got to
14 times, 14 different cities. There's
got to be
got to be something
14 times, 14 different cities. There's
got to be something there.
You
You know,
You know, we
You know, we we've
You know, we we've all
You know, we we've all had
You know, we we've all had things
recurrent
recurrent patterns
You know, we we've all had things
recurrent patterns in
recurrent patterns in our
You know, we we've all had things
recurrent patterns in our life
recurrent patterns in our life that
You know, we we've all had things
recurrent patterns in our life that are
beyond
beyond explanation
that
that you
beyond explanation
that you can
that you can consult
beyond explanation
that you can consult all
that you can consult all the
beyond explanation
that you can consult all the wise
that you can consult all the wise ones
of
of the
of the world
of the world and
of the world and frankly
of the world and frankly they
of the world and frankly they don't
of the world and frankly they don't know
them.
them. They
of the world and frankly they don't know
them. They don't
them. They don't know
of the world and frankly they don't know
them. They don't know the
them. They don't know the answers
unless
you're
you're aware
unless
you're aware of
you're aware of the
unless
you're aware of the reality
you're aware of the reality of
unless
you're aware of the reality of the
spiritual
spiritual domain
and
and that
spiritual domain
and that it
and that it overrules
spiritual domain
and that it overrules the
and that it overrules the physical.
It
It overrules
It overrules the
It overrules the physical.
It's
It's only
It overrules the physical.
It's only when
It's only when a
It overrules the physical.
It's only when a you
It's only when a you identify
It overrules the physical.
It's only when a you identify a
It's only when a you identify a certain
pattern
pattern and
pattern and then
pattern and then you
pattern and then you say
pattern and then you say you
pattern and then you say you know
pattern and then you say you know it's
very
very likely
pattern and then you say you know it's
very likely that
very likely that such
pattern and then you say you know it's
very likely that such and
very likely that such and such
pattern and then you say you know it's
very likely that such and such happened
and
and you'll
and you'll find
and you'll find yes
and you'll find yes it
and you'll find yes it did
and you'll find yes it did in
and you'll find yes it did in fact
and you'll find yes it did in fact such
and
and such
and you'll find yes it did in fact such
and such happened
for
for all
for all this
for all this sequence
for all this sequence of
for all this sequence of events
for all this sequence of events that
have
have happened
for all this sequence of events that
have happened let's
have happened let's say
for all this sequence of events that
have happened let's say in
have happened let's say in relationships
I
I must
I must have
I must have been
I must have been an
I must have been an so
I must have been an so at
I must have been an so at one
I must have been an so at one in
I must have been an so at one in some
lifetime
that's
that's the
that's the only
that's the only explanation
that's the only explanation is
that's the only explanation is it
that's the only explanation is it why
why
why ship.
that's the only explanation is it why
why ship. Everybody
why ship. Everybody beat
that's the only explanation is it why
why ship. Everybody beat up
why ship. Everybody beat up on
that's the only explanation is it why
why ship. Everybody beat up on you
why ship. Everybody beat up on you and
give
give you
give you a
give you a hard
give you a hard time
give you a hard time in
give you a hard time in relationships
give you a hard time in relationships in
this
this lifetime.
Well,
Well, they're
Well, they're waiting
Well, they're waiting for
Well, they're waiting for you,
Well, they're waiting for you, folks.
That's
That's generally
uh
uh the
uh the truth
uh the truth of
uh the truth of it.
All
All right.
uh the truth of it.
All right. So,
All right. So, you
uh the truth of it.
All right. So, you don't
All right. So, you don't have
uh the truth of it.
All right. So, you don't have to
All right. So, you don't have to be
uh the truth of it.
All right. So, you don't have to be a
rocket
rocket scientist
rocket scientist to
rocket scientist to get
rocket scientist to get what
rocket scientist to get what it's
rocket scientist to get what it's all
about.
about. that
rocket scientist to get what it's all
about. that it
about. that it seems
rocket scientist to get what it's all
about. that it seems rather
about. that it seems rather obvious
rocket scientist to get what it's all
about. that it seems rather obvious that
every
every decision
then
then sets
every decision
then sets up
then sets up a
every decision
then sets up a vibrational
then sets up a vibrational pattern
somewhere
somewhere in
somewhere in the
somewhere in the soul
somewhere in the soul body
which
which exists
somewhere in the soul body
which exists over
which exists over time
and
and thus
and thus we
and thus we see
and thus we see in
and thus we see in this
and thus we see in this lifetime
the
the externalization
and thus we see in this lifetime
the externalization the
the externalization the physicality
and thus we see in this lifetime
the externalization the physicality the
expression
expression of
expression of that
expression of that which
expression of that which we
expression of that which we have
expression of that which we have become
I
I always
expression of that which we have become
I always thought
I always thought Jesus
expression of that which we have become
I always thought Jesus Christ
I always thought Jesus Christ didn't
talk
talk too
talk too much
talk too much about
talk too much about karma
talk too much about karma for
talk too much about karma for a
talk too much about karma for a couple
of
of reasons.
talk too much about karma for a couple
of reasons. First
of reasons. First of
talk too much about karma for a couple
of reasons. First of all,
of reasons. First of all, it
talk too much about karma for a couple
of reasons. First of all, it would
of reasons. First of all, it would have
made
made him
made him unpopular
made him unpopular in
made him unpopular in the
made him unpopular in the society
made him unpopular in the society in
which
which he
made him unpopular in the society in
which he was
which he was living.
It
It wasn't
It wasn't in
It wasn't in India,
It wasn't in India, you
It wasn't in India, you know,
It wasn't in India, you know, it
It wasn't in India, you know, it wasn't
far
far east
It wasn't in India, you know, it wasn't
far east where
far east where it
It wasn't in India, you know, it wasn't
far east where it would
far east where it would have
It wasn't in India, you know, it wasn't
far east where it would have been
far east where it would have been so
what?
what? No,
what? No, it
what? No, it was
what? No, it was cuz
what? No, it was cuz such
what? No, it was cuz such things
what? No, it was cuz such things were
known
known for
what? No, it was cuz such things were
known for thousand
known for thousand years
what? No, it was cuz such things were
known for thousand years before
known for thousand years before the
birth
birth of
birth of Christ
birth of Christ in
birth of Christ in the
birth of Christ in the far
birth of Christ in the far east.
birth of Christ in the far east. But
where
where he
birth of Christ in the far east. But
where he grew
where he grew up,
birth of Christ in the far east. But
where he grew up, they
where he grew up, they were
birth of Christ in the far east. But
where he grew up, they were pretty
rudimentary.
rudimentary. The
rudimentary. The calibrated
rudimentary. The calibrated level
rudimentary. The calibrated level of
consciousness
consciousness at
rudimentary. The calibrated level of
consciousness at the
consciousness at the time
rudimentary. The calibrated level of
consciousness at the time of
consciousness at the time of Jesus
rudimentary. The calibrated level of
consciousness at the time of Jesus was
100.
At
At the
100.
At the time
At the time of
100.
At the time of the
At the time of the birth
100.
At the time of the birth of
At the time of the birth of Buddha
100.
At the time of the birth of Buddha was
90.
500 years
500 years later
90.
500 years later at
500 years later at the
90.
500 years later at the time
500 years later at the time of
90.
500 years later at the time of birth
500 years later at the time of birth of
Christ
Christ it
Christ it was
Christ it was 100.
Christ it was 100. So
Christ it was 100. So he's
Christ it was 100. So he's talking
Christ it was 100. So he's talking to
people
people with a
Christ it was 100. So he's talking to
people with a consciousness
people with a consciousness level
Christ it was 100. So he's talking to
people with a consciousness level of
100.
100. You
100. You know
and
and his
100. You know
and his teachings
and his teachings were
100. You know
and his teachings were unpopular
and his teachings were unpopular at
100. You know
and his teachings were unpopular at the
time
to
to put
time
to put it
to put it mildly.
time
to put it mildly. Yeah.
to put it mildly. Yeah. He
time
to put it mildly. Yeah. He was
to put it mildly. Yeah. He was not
exactly
exactly a
exactly a popular
exactly a popular teacher
exactly a popular teacher around
exactly a popular teacher around town
and
and um
exactly a popular teacher around town
and um to
and um to the
exactly a popular teacher around town
and um to the powers
and um to the powers that
exactly a popular teacher around town
and um to the powers that be.
and um to the powers that be. So
exactly a popular teacher around town
and um to the powers that be. So I
and um to the powers that be. So I also
thought
thought in
thought in the
thought in the height
thought in the height of
thought in the height of wisdom
thought in the height of wisdom he
thought in the height of wisdom he just
didn't
didn't bring
thought in the height of wisdom he just
didn't bring it
didn't bring it up
thought in the height of wisdom he just
didn't bring it up as
didn't bring it up as a
thought in the height of wisdom he just
didn't bring it up as a specific
didn't bring it up as a specific topic
per
per se.
He
He he
per se.
He he said
He he said it
per se.
He he said it that
He he said it that all
per se.
He he said it that all your
He he said it that all your actions
per se.
He he said it that all your actions will
have
have consequences
have consequences in
have consequences in a
have consequences in a later
have consequences in a later life.
He
He did
have consequences in a later life.
He did mention
He did mention once
have consequences in a later life.
He did mention once in
He did mention once in Matthew
have consequences in a later life.
He did mention once in Matthew something
about
about Isaiah
about Isaiah has
about Isaiah has come
about Isaiah has come back
about Isaiah has come back to
about Isaiah has come back to us
about Isaiah has come back to us as
about Isaiah has come back to us as John
the
the Baptist
about Isaiah has come back to us as John
the Baptist in
the Baptist in Matthew.
about Isaiah has come back to us as John
the Baptist in Matthew. That's
the Baptist in Matthew. That's the
about Isaiah has come back to us as John
the Baptist in Matthew. That's the only
that's
that's the
that's the only
that's the only quote
that's the only quote making
that's the only quote making a
that's the only quote making a direct
reference.
reference. Huh.
on
on such
on such an
on such an advanced
on such an advanced level
on such an advanced level of
consciousness.
It's
It's obvious
It's obvious that
It's obvious that what
It's obvious that what you
It's obvious that what you are
that
that the
It's obvious that what you are
that the ego
that the ego and
It's obvious that what you are
that the ego and your
that the ego and your karma
It's obvious that what you are
that the ego and your karma and
that the ego and your karma and that
which
which you
which you are
which you are are
which you are are all
which you are are all one
which you are are all one the
which you are are all one the same
thing.
thing. You
which you are are all one the same
thing. You don't
thing. You don't have
which you are are all one the same
thing. You don't have to
thing. You don't have to worry
which you are are all one the same
thing. You don't have to worry about
karma.
karma. Just
karma. Just work
karma. Just work on
karma. Just work on what
karma. Just work on what your
karma. Just work on what your problems
are
are in
karma. Just work on what your problems
are in the
are in the present
karma. Just work on what your problems
are in the present because
are in the present because they
karma. Just work on what your problems
are in the present because they are
are in the present because they are the
consequence
of
of karma.
consequence
of karma. So
of karma. So you
consequence
of karma. So you don't
of karma. So you don't have
consequence
of karma. So you don't have to
of karma. So you don't have to really
study
study and
study and teach
study and teach karma.
study and teach karma. So
study and teach karma. So I
study and teach karma. So I thought
study and teach karma. So I thought he
just
just bypassed
study and teach karma. So I thought he
just bypassed it
just bypassed it as
study and teach karma. So I thought he
just bypassed it as as
just bypassed it as as unnecessary.
He
He gave
He gave the
He gave the folks
He gave the folks enough
He gave the folks enough to
He gave the folks enough to think
He gave the folks enough to think about
it
it anyway.
A
A more
A more sophisticated
A more sophisticated group.
A more sophisticated group. I
A more sophisticated group. I think
A more sophisticated group. I think if
he
he was
A more sophisticated group. I think if
he was speaking
he was speaking to
A more sophisticated group. I think if
he was speaking to people
he was speaking to people of
A more sophisticated group. I think if
he was speaking to people of a
he was speaking to people of a more
advanced
advanced consciousness,
there
there might
advanced consciousness,
there might have
there might have been
advanced consciousness,
there might have been greater
explanation.
As
As we've
explanation.
As we've said
As we've said in
explanation.
As we've said in previous
As we've said in previous lectures,
explanation.
As we've said in previous lectures, the
purpose
purpose of
purpose of uh
purpose of uh the
purpose of uh the life
purpose of uh the life of
purpose of uh the life of Jesus
purpose of uh the life of Jesus Christ
was
was salvation.
purpose of uh the life of Jesus Christ
was salvation. That
was salvation. That he
purpose of uh the life of Jesus Christ
was salvation. That he did
was salvation. That he did come
purpose of uh the life of Jesus Christ
was salvation. That he did come down
directly
directly from
directly from heaven
directly from heaven as
directly from heaven as a
directly from heaven as a manifestation
directly
directly from
directly from heaven as a manifestation
directly from heaven
directly from heaven and
directly from heaven as a manifestation
directly from heaven and had
directly from heaven and had no
directly from heaven as a manifestation
directly from heaven and had no prior
lifetimes,
no
no human
lifetimes,
no human lifetimes.
That's
That's correct,
That's correct, is
That's correct, is it?
So
he
he wasn't
he wasn't really
he wasn't really gung-ho
he wasn't really gung-ho on
he wasn't really gung-ho on the
he wasn't really gung-ho on the subject
to
to begin
he wasn't really gung-ho on the subject
to begin with.
to begin with. Having
not
not had
not had a
not had a lot
not had a lot of
not had a lot of previous
not had a lot of previous lifetimes,
his
his familiarities
not had a lot of previous lifetimes,
his familiarities was
his familiarities was with
not had a lot of previous lifetimes,
his familiarities was with heaven
his familiarities was with heaven and
the
the nature
the nature of
the nature of heaven
the nature of heaven and
the nature of heaven and how
the nature of heaven and how one
the nature of heaven and how one gets
there
and
and how
and how one
and how one avoids
and how one avoids the
and how one avoids the other
and how one avoids the other direction.
The
The Buddha
and how one avoids the other direction.
The Buddha on
The Buddha on the
and how one avoids the other direction.
The Buddha on the other
The Buddha on the other hand
and how one avoids the other direction.
The Buddha on the other hand had
The Buddha on the other hand had many
many
many previous
many previous lifetimes
and
and therefore
many previous lifetimes
and therefore spoke
and therefore spoke freely
many previous lifetimes
and therefore spoke freely of
and therefore spoke freely of it.
many previous lifetimes
and therefore spoke freely of it. Let's
see
see the
see the Buddha
see the Buddha did
see the Buddha did indeed
see the Buddha did indeed in
see the Buddha did indeed in fact
see the Buddha did indeed in fact have
many
many previous
see the Buddha did indeed in fact have
many previous human
many previous human lifetimes
see the Buddha did indeed in fact have
many previous human lifetimes with
many previous human lifetimes with it.
Okay.
Okay. So
two
two different
Okay. So
two different ways
two different ways of
Okay. So
two different ways of approaching
two different ways of approaching the
subject.
If
If what
subject.
If what your
If what your spiritual
subject.
If what your spiritual difficulties
If what your spiritual difficulties are
now
now is
now is the
now is the real
now is the real of
now is the real of your
now is the real of your karmic
inheritance
inheritance from
now is the real of your karmic
inheritance from prior
inheritance from prior lifetimes,
now is the real of your karmic
inheritance from prior lifetimes, it
doesn't
doesn't really
doesn't really change
doesn't really change it.
doesn't really change it. What
doesn't really change it. What it
doesn't really change it. What it does
do
do is
doesn't really change it. What it does
do is make
do is make it
doesn't really change it. What it does
do is make it more
do is make it more acceptable.
If
If buses
If buses keep
If buses keep running
If buses keep running into
If buses keep running into the
If buses keep running into the back
If buses keep running into the back of
your
your car
If buses keep running into the back of
your car and
your car and then
If buses keep running into the back of
your car and then you
your car and then you find
If buses keep running into the back of
your car and then you find in
your car and then you find in some
lifetime
lifetime you
lifetime you drove
lifetime you drove your
lifetime you drove your oxen
lifetime you drove your oxen over
lifetime you drove your oxen over your
neighbors
gardens
gardens periodically
gardens periodically out
gardens periodically out of
gardens periodically out of paranoia
gardens periodically out of paranoia or
whatever.
whatever. It
gardens periodically out of paranoia or
whatever. It wouldn't
whatever. It wouldn't make
gardens periodically out of paranoia or
whatever. It wouldn't make sense,
whatever. It wouldn't make sense, huh?
So,
a
a little
So,
a little karmic
a little karmic research
So,
a little karmic research into
a little karmic research into your
So,
a little karmic research into your own
particular
particular grievances
gets
gets rid
particular grievances
gets rid of
gets rid of self-pity.
gets
gets rid
gets rid of
gets rid of self-pity,
indignant
indignant rage,
resentment.
How
How could
resentment.
How could God
How could God be
resentment.
How could God be so
How could God be so unfair?
When
When I
When I was
When I was a
When I was a kid,
When I was a kid, all
When I was a kid, all everybody's
When I was a kid, all everybody's going
out
out for
When I was a kid, all everybody's going
out for football.
out for football. Football.
When I was a kid, all everybody's going
out for football. Football. Christ,
out for football. Football. Christ, I
weighed
weighed 62
weighed 62 lbs.
So,
So, I
weighed 62 lbs.
So, I used
So, I used to
weighed 62 lbs.
So, I used to hang
So, I used to hang like
weighed 62 lbs.
So, I used to hang like this
So, I used to hang like this every
weighed 62 lbs.
So, I used to hang like this every day
cuz
cuz I
cuz I thought
cuz I thought I'd
cuz I thought I'd get
cuz I thought I'd get I
cuz I thought I'd get I could
cuz I thought I'd get I could stretch
myself
myself out
cuz I thought I'd get I could stretch
myself out and
myself out and get
cuz I thought I'd get I could stretch
myself out and get taller.
And
And I
And I ate
And I ate a
And I ate a lot,
And I ate a lot, but
And I ate a lot, but you
And I ate a lot, but you I
And I ate a lot, but you I couldn't
And I ate a lot, but you I couldn't get
fatter
fatter or
And I ate a lot, but you I couldn't get
fatter or taller.
fatter or taller. So,
uh
uh you
uh you see,
uh you see, it's
uh you see, it's like
uh you see, it's like unfair,
uh you see, it's like unfair, isn't
uh you see, it's like unfair, isn't it?
I
I mean,
uh you see, it's like unfair, isn't it?
I mean, the
I mean, the other
uh you see, it's like unfair, isn't it?
I mean, the other kids
I mean, the other kids are
uh you see, it's like unfair, isn't it?
I mean, the other kids are misorous.
They
They get
They get out
They get out there
They get out there and
They get out there and knock
They get out there and knock people
They get out there and knock people over
and
and wrestle
They get out there and knock people over
and wrestle with
and wrestle with each
They get out there and knock people over
and wrestle with each other
and wrestle with each other and
They get out there and knock people over
and wrestle with each other and all
kinds
kinds of
kinds of wild
kinds of wild things.
And
And I'm
kinds of wild things.
And I'm reading
And I'm reading a
kinds of wild things.
And I'm reading a book,
And I'm reading a book, so
karmic
karmic propensity
karmic propensity then
so
so many
karmic propensity then
so many people
so many people then
karmic propensity then
so many people then have
so many people then have many
resentments
resentments about
resentments about many
resentments about many things
resentments about many things in
resentments about many things in their
life
life and
resentments about many things in their
life and if
life and if you
resentments about many things in their
life and if you check
life and if you check back
resentments about many things in their
life and if you check back on
life and if you check back on them
you'll
you'll see
you'll see that
you'll see that they
you'll see that they were
you'll see that they were earned
you'll see that they were earned they
were
were earned
you'll see that they were earned they
were earned deserved
were earned deserved and
you'll see that they were earned they
were earned deserved and now
were earned deserved and now you're
thankful
thankful for
thankful for them
thankful for them because
thankful for them because you
thankful for them because you say
thankful for them because you say well
if
if I
thankful for them because you say well
if I was
if I was an
thankful for them because you say well
if I was an so
if I was an so in
thankful for them because you say well
if I was an so in past
if I was an so in past lifetimes
thankful for them because you say well
if I was an so in past lifetimes and
cruel
cruel and
cruel and selfish
cruel and selfish and
beat
beat my
cruel and selfish and
beat my wife
beat my wife every
cruel and selfish and
beat my wife every day
beat my wife every day like
cruel and selfish and
beat my wife every day like they
beat my wife every day like they do
cruel and selfish and
beat my wife every day like they do in
other
other parts
other parts of
other parts of the
other parts of the world.
other parts of the world. It's
other parts of the world. It's your
other parts of the world. It's your duty
to
to beat
other parts of the world. It's your duty
to beat your
to beat your wife
other parts of the world. It's your duty
to beat your wife every
to beat your wife every day
other parts of the world. It's your duty
to beat your wife every day in
to beat your wife every day in certain
parts
parts of
parts of the
parts of the world.
parts of the world. Maybe
parts of the world. Maybe they
parts of the world. Maybe they have
parts of the world. Maybe they have to
come
come back
parts of the world. Maybe they have to
come back and
come back and get
parts of the world. Maybe they have to
come back and get beaten
come back and get beaten because
parts of the world. Maybe they have to
come back and get beaten because they
fail
fail to
fail to beat
fail to beat their
fail to beat their wife
fail to beat their wife every
fail to beat their wife every day.
fail to beat their wife every day. And
so
so it
fail to beat their wife every day. And
so it puts
so it puts it
fail to beat their wife every day. And
so it puts it into
so it puts it into proportion.
fail to beat their wife every day. And
so it puts it into proportion. So
so it puts it into proportion. So some
understanding
understanding of
understanding of karma
understanding of karma then
understanding of karma then gets
understanding of karma then gets you
understanding of karma then gets you out
of
of self-pity,
understanding of karma then gets you out
of self-pity, resentment,
of self-pity, resentment, hatred,
understanding of karma then gets you out
of self-pity, resentment, hatred, hatred
of
of God,
cursing
cursing God
of God,
cursing God for
cursing God for being
of God,
cursing God for being unfair.
and
and putting
and putting you
and putting you here
and putting you here with
and putting you here with whatever
limitations
limitations you
and putting you here with whatever
limitations you have.
limitations you have. And
and putting you here with whatever
limitations you have. And everyone
limitations you have. And everyone has
limitations
because
because all
limitations
because all of
because all of creation
limitations
because all of creation is
because all of creation is one
limitations
because all of creation is one karmic
unity.
Then
Then we
unity.
Then we represent
Then we represent not
unity.
Then we represent not only
Then we represent not only personal
karma
karma but
karma but we
karma but we represent
karma but we represent the
karma but we represent the karmic
pattern
pattern the
karma but we represent the karmic
pattern the karmic
pattern the karmic the
karma but we represent the karmic
pattern the karmic the evolution
pattern the karmic the evolution of
consciousness
on
on this
consciousness
on this planet
uh
uh and
uh and to
uh and to where
uh and to where it
uh and to where it has
uh and to where it has evolved
uh and to where it has evolved in
uh and to where it has evolved in the
evolution
evolution of
uh and to where it has evolved in the
evolution of mankind.
So
So we're
So we're stuck
So we're stuck with
So we're stuck with the
So we're stuck with the karma
So we're stuck with the karma of
So we're stuck with the karma of mankind
itself.
Homo
Homo sapienism,
a
a bad
Homo sapienism,
a bad disease.
a bad disease. Homo
Homo sapienism,
a bad disease. Homo sapienism
which
which can
which can give
which can give you
which can give you everything.
Arthritis,
Arthritis, blindness,
which can give you everything.
Arthritis, blindness, stiffness,
convulsions,
a
a lot
convulsions,
a lot goes
a lot goes with
convulsions,
a lot goes with it.
a lot goes with it. Huh?
Having
Having to
Having to work
Having to work for
Having to work for a
Having to work for a living.
Having to work for a living. Yeah.
And
And all
Having to work for a living. Yeah.
And all those
And all those unfairnesses.
It's
It's okay
It's okay to
It's okay to talk
It's okay to talk about
It's okay to talk about the
It's okay to talk about the daisies
It's okay to talk about the daisies in
the
the field.
It's okay to talk about the daisies in
the field. Neither
the field. Neither do
It's okay to talk about the daisies in
the field. Neither do they
the field. Neither do they labor
It's okay to talk about the daisies in
the field. Neither do they labor to.
the field. Neither do they labor to. It
wasn't
wasn't a
wasn't a human
wasn't a human being
wasn't a human being out
wasn't a human being out there
wasn't a human being out there in
wasn't a human being out there in the
field.
field. They
wasn't a human being out there in the
field. They wouldn't
field. They wouldn't be
wasn't a human being out there in the
field. They wouldn't be just
field. They wouldn't be just sitting
there
looking
looking beautiful
there
looking beautiful waving
looking beautiful waving in
there
looking beautiful waving in the
looking beautiful waving in the wind.
You'd
You'd be
You'd be going
You'd be going to
You'd be going to work.
Get
Get a
You'd be going to work.
Get a shovel,
Get a shovel, Daisy.
You'd be going to work.
Get a shovel, Daisy. And
Get a shovel, Daisy. And let's
You'd be going to work.
Get a shovel, Daisy. And let's see
Get a shovel, Daisy. And let's see how
good
good you
good you think
good you think about
good you think about it.
Fred
Fred Fred
good you think about it.
Fred Fred was
Fred Fred was over
good you think about it.
Fred Fred was over at
Fred Fred was over at our
good you think about it.
Fred Fred was over at our house
Fred Fred was over at our house for
good you think about it.
Fred Fred was over at our house for the
weekend
weekend and
weekend and and
weekend and and was
weekend and and was shoveling
weekend and and was shoveling dirt.
weekend and and was shoveling dirt. You
see,
she
she was
she was a
she was a daisy.
she was a daisy. He
she was a daisy. He wouldn't
she was a daisy. He wouldn't have
she was a daisy. He wouldn't have to
shovel
shovel dirt.
she was a daisy. He wouldn't have to
shovel dirt. You
shovel dirt. You could
she was a daisy. He wouldn't have to
shovel dirt. You could just
shovel dirt. You could just sit
she was a daisy. He wouldn't have to
shovel dirt. You could just sit there
and
and look
and look pretty.
helped
helped us
and look pretty.
helped us out
helped us out with
and look pretty.
helped us out with a
helped us out with a greenhouse
and look pretty.
helped us out with a greenhouse which
had
had fallen
had fallen down.
had fallen down. Its
had fallen down. Its karmic
had fallen down. Its karmic propensity
was
was to
had fallen down. Its karmic propensity
was to decay
was to decay over
had fallen down. Its karmic propensity
was to decay over time
was to decay over time with
had fallen down. Its karmic propensity
was to decay over time with dry
was to decay over time with dry rot.
An
An understanding
An understanding of
An understanding of karma
An understanding of karma then
An understanding of karma then is
important
important to
An understanding of karma then is
important to look
important to look at
An understanding of karma then is
important to look at it
important to look at it that
An understanding of karma then is
important to look at it that you
important to look at it that you didn't
just
just arrive
just arrive spontaneously
just arrive spontaneously out
just arrive spontaneously out of
just arrive spontaneously out of nowhere
as
as you
just arrive spontaneously out of nowhere
as you are
as you are at
just arrive spontaneously out of nowhere
as you are at this
as you are at this moment.
just arrive spontaneously out of nowhere
as you are at this moment. that
as you are at this moment. that somehow
out
out of
out of the
out of the evolution
out of the evolution of
out of the evolution of consciousness.
Now
Now life
out of the evolution of consciousness.
Now life and
Now life and consciousness
out of the evolution of consciousness.
Now life and consciousness are
Now life and consciousness are one
out of the evolution of consciousness.
Now life and consciousness are one and
the
the same.
Um
Um we
the same.
Um we went
Um we went back
the same.
Um we went back into
um
prior
prior to
um
prior to the
prior to the universe
um
prior to the universe this
prior to the universe this morning
Susan
Susan and
Susan and I
Susan and I I
Susan and I I said
Susan and I I said let's
Susan and I I said let's go
Susan and I I said let's go back
priority.
priority. Yes.
We
We got
We got out
We got out of
We got out of the
We got out of the man
We got out of the man unmanifest
We got out of the man unmanifest comes
the
the manifest.
Out
Out of
Out of the
Out of the unmanifest
Out of the unmanifest comes
Out of the unmanifest comes the
manifest.
But
But consciousness,
But consciousness, consciousness
But consciousness, consciousness and
life
life are
But consciousness, consciousness and
life are one
life are one and
But consciousness, consciousness and
life are one and the
life are one and the same.
And
And they
And they don't
And they don't appear
And they don't appear until
existence,
until
until the
until the manifest
until the manifest expresses
until the manifest expresses itself
until the manifest expresses itself as
existence.
That
That which
That which has
That which has no
That which has no existence
That which has no existence is
That which has no existence is beyond
consciousness.
Resist.
Out
Out of
Resist.
Out of the
Out of the unmanifest
Resist.
Out of the unmanifest arises
Out of the unmanifest arises the
manifest.
manifest. Resist.
manifest. Resist. The
manifest. Resist. The manifest
manifest. Resist. The manifest is
manifest. Resist. The manifest is the
void
void of
manifest. Resist. The manifest is the
void of life
void of life or
manifest. Resist. The manifest is the
void of life or consciousness.
void of life or consciousness. Resist.
Out
Out of
Out of the
Out of the manifest
Out of the manifest arises
Out of the manifest arises existence.
Resist.
Innate
Innate to
Innate to existence
Innate to existence is
Innate to existence is consciousness.
And
And consciousness
Innate to existence is consciousness.
And consciousness and
And consciousness and life
Innate to existence is consciousness.
And consciousness and life are
And consciousness and life are one
Innate to existence is consciousness.
And consciousness and life are one and
the
the same.
Wow.
So
So that's
So that's enough
So that's enough before
So that's enough before breakfast.
to
to know
So that's enough before breakfast.
to know that
to know that consciousness
So that's enough before breakfast.
to know that consciousness and
to know that consciousness and life
are
are cannot
are cannot be
are cannot be extinguished.
are cannot be extinguished. H
are cannot be extinguished. H let's
are cannot be extinguished. H let's see
if
if that's
are cannot be extinguished. H let's see
if that's so
life
life cannot
life cannot be
life cannot be extinguished.
life cannot be extinguished. Resist.
Consciousness
Consciousness cannot
life cannot be extinguished. Resist.
Consciousness cannot be
Consciousness cannot be extinguished.
Resist.
Wow.
Wow. What
Resist.
Wow. What does
Wow. What does that
Resist.
Wow. What does that mean?
Wow. What does that mean? That
Resist.
Wow. What does that mean? That means
death
death is
death is impossible.
That
That which
death is impossible.
That which has
That which has life
death is impossible.
That which has life has
That which has life has life
death is impossible.
That which has life has life eternally.
That
That which
That which is
That which is conscious.
You
You can
That which is conscious.
You can swat
You can swat the
That which is conscious.
You can swat the fly,
You can swat the fly, but
That which is conscious.
You can swat the fly, but you
You can swat the fly, but you can't
That which is conscious.
You can swat the fly, but you can't kill
its
its life
its life energy
its life energy because
its life energy because it
its life energy because it flits
its life energy because it flits around
in
in the
its life energy because it flits around
in the astral
in the astral and
its life energy because it flits around
in the astral and comes
in the astral and comes right
its life energy because it flits around
in the astral and comes right back
in the astral and comes right back as
another
another fly.
You
You can't
another fly.
You can't extinguish
You can't extinguish life
another fly.
You can't extinguish life or
consciousness.
consciousness. When
consciousness. When I
consciousness. When I was
consciousness. When I was a
consciousness. When I was a kid,
consciousness. When I was a kid, it
consciousness. When I was a kid, it was
okay
okay to
consciousness. When I was a kid, it was
okay to have
okay to have mercury.
consciousness. When I was a kid, it was
okay to have mercury. My
okay to have mercury. My father
consciousness. When I was a kid, it was
okay to have mercury. My father would
bring
bring home
bring home mercury
which
which they
bring home mercury
which they took
which they took out
bring home mercury
which they took out a
which they took out a filling
bring home mercury
which they took out a filling stations
or
or something
or something and
or something and and
or something and and we
or something and and we had
or something and and we had a
or something and and we had a wonderful
collection
collection of
or something and and we had a wonderful
collection of mercury.
collection of mercury. Bum
or something and and we had a wonderful
collection of mercury. Bum b
collection of mercury. Bum b was
or something and and we had a wonderful
collection of mercury. Bum b was real
heavy
heavy go.
heavy go. Now
heavy go. Now it'
heavy go. Now it' be
heavy go. Now it' be illegal
heavy go. Now it' be illegal I
heavy go. Now it' be illegal I guess
because
because mercury
heavy go. Now it' be illegal I guess
because mercury vapor
because mercury vapor poisoning
heavy go. Now it' be illegal I guess
because mercury vapor poisoning would
send
send everybody
send everybody into
send everybody into paranoid
send everybody into paranoid fits
send everybody into paranoid fits and
you'd
you'd have
send everybody into paranoid fits and
you'd have the
you'd have the EPA
send everybody into paranoid fits and
you'd have the EPA knocking
you'd have the EPA knocking at
send everybody into paranoid fits and
you'd have the EPA knocking at your
door.
door. But
door. But in
door. But in those
door. But in those days
door. But in those days we
door. But in those days we lived
door. But in those days we lived in
door. But in those days we lived in a
more
more simple
door. But in those days we lived in a
more simple world
more simple world of
door. But in those days we lived in a
more simple world of ignorance.
more simple world of ignorance. So
door. But in those days we lived in a
more simple world of ignorance. So we
would
would put
would put it
would put it in
would put it in a
we
we put
would put it in a
we put it
we put it in
would put it in a
we put it in a
we put it in a bowl.
would put it in a
we put it in a bowl. Well,
we put it in a bowl. Well, to
would put it in a
we put it in a bowl. Well, to amuse
we put it in a bowl. Well, to amuse me,
my
my father
my father would
my father would pour
my father would pour some
my father would pour some mercury
my father would pour some mercury in
this
this thing
my father would pour some mercury in
this thing and
this thing and I
my father would pour some mercury in
this thing and I of
this thing and I of course
my father would pour some mercury in
this thing and I of course try
this thing and I of course try to
my father would pour some mercury in
this thing and I of course try to pick
it
it up.
it up. You
it up. You know,
it up. You know, maybe
it up. You know, maybe for
it up. You know, maybe for then
it up. You know, maybe for then I
it up. You know, maybe for then I try
and
and pick
it up. You know, maybe for then I try
and pick up
and pick up the
it up. You know, maybe for then I try
and pick up the mercury
and pick up the mercury and
it up. You know, maybe for then I try
and pick up the mercury and it
and pick up the mercury and it would
just
just go
just go that
just go that way.
just go that way. You
just go that way. You pick
just go that way. You pick up
just go that way. You pick up that
just go that way. You pick up that one,
it
it would
just go that way. You pick up that one,
it would go
it would go that
just go that way. You pick up that one,
it would go that way.
it would go that way. No matter
just go that way. You pick up that one,
it would go that way. No matter what
it would go that way. No matter what you
did,
did, you
did, you can't
did, you can't pick
did, you can't pick up
did, you can't pick up the
did, you can't pick up the mercury.
did, you can't pick up the mercury. It
just
just moves
did, you can't pick up the mercury. It
just moves around
just moves around someplace
did, you can't pick up the mercury. It
just moves around someplace else.
Which
Which is
Which is the
Which is the way
Which is the way life
Which is the way life then
Which is the way life then is.
Which is the way life then is. Cannot
Which is the way life then is. Cannot be
extinguished.
So,
So, we
So, we have
So, we have to
So, we have to give
So, we have to give up
So, we have to give up fearing
So, we have to give up fearing death
because
because it's
So, we have to give up fearing death
because it's it's
because it's it's not
So, we have to give up fearing death
because it's it's not going
because it's it's not going to
So, we have to give up fearing death
because it's it's not going to be
because it's it's not going to be an
escape
escape hatch.
escape hatch. No,
escape hatch. No, you're
escape hatch. No, you're not
escape hatch. No, you're not going
escape hatch. No, you're not going to
get
get out
escape hatch. No, you're not going to
get out of
get out of the
escape hatch. No, you're not going to
get out of the deal
get out of the deal with
escape hatch. No, you're not going to
get out of the deal with death.
Everybody
Everybody grieves
Everybody grieves death
Everybody grieves death and
Everybody grieves death and oh,
Everybody grieves death and oh, I
Everybody grieves death and oh, I fear
death.
death. Come
Everybody grieves death and oh, I fear
death. Come on.
death. Come on. I
Everybody grieves death and oh, I fear
death. Come on. I know.
death. Come on. I know. On
Everybody grieves death and oh, I fear
death. Come on. I know. On the
death. Come on. I know. On the other
side
side of
side of your
side of your consciousness,
it's
it's your
side of your consciousness,
it's your big
it's your big cop
side of your consciousness,
it's your big cop out.
Oh,
Oh, I'll
Oh, I'll die
Oh, I'll die and
Oh, I'll die and get
Oh, I'll die and get away
Oh, I'll die and get away from
Oh, I'll die and get away from it
Oh, I'll die and get away from it all.
Well,
Well, it
Oh, I'll die and get away from it all.
Well, it should
Well, it should be
Oh, I'll die and get away from it all.
Well, it should be that
Well, it should be that easy,
Oh, I'll die and get away from it all.
Well, it should be that easy, huh?
No,
No, it
No, it seems
No, it seems the
No, it seems the karmic
No, it seems the karmic propensities
then
then prevail
in
in and
in and out
in and out weaving
in and out weaving through.
It
It could
in and out weaving through.
It could be
It could be an
in and out weaving through.
It could be an infinite
It could be an infinite number
in and out weaving through.
It could be an infinite number of
lifetimes.
It
It can
lifetimes.
It can be
It can be an
lifetimes.
It can be an infinite
It can be an infinite number
lifetimes.
It can be an infinite number of
It can be an infinite number of human
lifetimes.
I
I never
lifetimes.
I never asked
I never asked that
lifetimes.
I never asked that before.
It's
It's possible
It's possible to
It's possible to have
It's possible to have an
It's possible to have an infinite
It's possible to have an infinite number
of
of human
It's possible to have an infinite number
of human lifetime
of human lifetime resistance.
So,
ain't
ain't that
So,
ain't that neat?
I
I mean,
I mean, you
I mean, you never
I mean, you never want
I mean, you never want to
I mean, you never want to go
I mean, you never want to go to
I mean, you never want to go to heaven.
You
You never
I mean, you never want to go to heaven.
You never want
You never want to
I mean, you never want to go to heaven.
You never want to go
You never want to go to
I mean, you never want to go to heaven.
You never want to go to hell.
You never want to go to hell. You
I mean, you never want to go to heaven.
You never want to go to hell. You just
want
want to
want to go
want to go to
want to go to work
want to go to work every
want to go to work every day,
>> propagate,
>> propagate, have
want to go to work every day,
>> propagate, have sex,
eat
eat up
eat up a
eat up a storm.
eat up a storm. You
eat up a storm. You can
eat up a storm. You can keep
eat up a storm. You can keep doing
eat up a storm. You can keep doing it.
Wow,
what
what a
what a relief.
Oh,
Oh, mint
what a relief.
Oh, mint chocolate
Oh, mint chocolate chip
what a relief.
Oh, mint chocolate chip ice
Oh, mint chocolate chip ice cream.
what a relief.
Oh, mint chocolate chip ice cream. I
Oh, mint chocolate chip ice cream. I do
not
not have
not have to
not have to leave
not have to leave thee.
I'll
I'll get
not have to leave thee.
I'll get old,
I'll get old, toddler
not have to leave thee.
I'll get old, toddler over,
I'll get old, toddler over, come
not have to leave thee.
I'll get old, toddler over, come back
I'll get old, toddler over, come back as
another
another little
another little kid,
another little kid, and
another little kid, and have
another little kid, and have my
chocolate
chocolate chip
another little kid, and have my
chocolate chip and
chocolate chip and ice
another little kid, and have my
chocolate chip and ice cream
chocolate chip and ice cream again.
another little kid, and have my
chocolate chip and ice cream again. No
end.
end. Endless.
You
You never
end. Endless.
You never have
You never have to
end. Endless.
You never have to return
You never have to return to
end. Endless.
You never have to return to God.
You never have to return to God. Is
end. Endless.
You never have to return to God. Is that
a
a fact?
You
You never
a fact?
You never have
You never have to
a fact?
You never have to return
You never have to return to
a fact?
You never have to return to God
You never have to return to God and
resist.
resist. You
resist. You never
resist. You never have
resist. You never have to
resist. You never have to become
enlightened.
enlightened. Resist.
resist. You never have to become
enlightened. Resist. You
enlightened. Resist. You can
resist. You never have to become
enlightened. Resist. You can just
enlightened. Resist. You can just keep
going
going like
going like this
going like this forever.
>> Whoa.
So
So man,
So man, some
So man, some people
So man, some people that's
So man, some people that's going
So man, some people that's going to
So man, some people that's going to be
relief
other
other people
it
it means
other people
it means unless
it means unless you
other people
it means unless you do
it means unless you do some
other people
it means unless you do some kind
it means unless you do some kind of
progressive
progressive spiritual
progressive spiritual work
progressive spiritual work you're
progressive spiritual work you're going
to
to keep
progressive spiritual work you're going
to keep reincarnating
to keep reincarnating as
progressive spiritual work you're going
to keep reincarnating as a
to keep reincarnating as a physical
progressive spiritual work you're going
to keep reincarnating as a physical as
to keep reincarnating as a physical as a
human
human being.
human being. Um
human being. Um that's
human being. Um that's soul
human being. Um that's soul resist
human being. Um that's soul resist you
you
you have
human being. Um that's soul resist you
you have choice
you have choice to
human being. Um that's soul resist you
you have choice to reincarnate
you have choice to reincarnate resist
from
from the
from the astral
from the astral domains
from the astral domains resist.
from the astral domains resist. So
from the astral domains resist. So being
here
here is
from the astral domains resist. So being
here is a
here is a choice.
from the astral domains resist. So being
here is a choice. A
here is a choice. A choice
from the astral domains resist. So being
here is a choice. A choice because
here is a choice. A choice because it's
a
a place
a place to
a place to evolve.
a place to evolve. Resist.
The
The reason
a place to evolve. Resist.
The reason um
we
we have
we have permission
we have permission to
we have permission to ask
we have permission to ask about
we have permission to ask about what
we have permission to ask about what I'm
thinking
thinking about
we have permission to ask about what I'm
thinking about resist
um
that
that which
um
that which is
that which is is
um
that which is is most
that which is is most um
there
there are
there are domains
there are domains where
um
um people
there are domains where
um people go
um people go who
there are domains where
um people go who refu
um people go who refu refuse
there are domains where
um people go who refu refuse God
um people go who refu refuse God resist.
So
So you
So you don't
So you don't have
So you don't have to
So you don't have to go
So you don't have to go to
So you don't have to go to God
So you don't have to go to God in
So you don't have to go to God in a
number
number of
So you don't have to go to God in a
number of ways.
It's
It's not
It's not necessary.
It's not necessary. You
It's not necessary. You can
It's not necessary. You can just
It's not necessary. You can just keep
recycling.
You
You can
You can keep
You can keep recycling
You can keep recycling until
You can keep recycling until inspiration
comes
comes to
You can keep recycling until inspiration
comes to move
comes to move on
You can keep recycling until inspiration
comes to move on ahead.
Now
Now the
Now the Buddha
Now the Buddha apparently
Now the Buddha apparently didn't
Now the Buddha apparently didn't like
physical
physical reincarnations
Now the Buddha apparently didn't like
physical reincarnations cuz
physical reincarnations cuz he
Now the Buddha apparently didn't like
physical reincarnations cuz he didn't
speak
speak too
speak too highly
speak too highly of
speak too highly of it.
He
He said,
speak too highly of it.
He said, "Unless
He said, "Unless you
speak too highly of it.
He said, "Unless you become
He said, "Unless you become enlightened,
you're
you're you're
you're you're going
you're you're going to
you're you're going to have
you're you're going to have to
you're you're going to have to get
you're you're going to have to get re
refysicalized
refysicalized periodically
you're you're going to have to get re
refysicalized periodically or
reincarnate."
Um,
and
and of
and of course
and of course he
and of course he was
and of course he was looking
and of course he was looking at
and of course he was looking at the
downside
downside of
and of course he was looking at the
downside of human
downside of human life.
and of course he was looking at the
downside of human life. He
downside of human life. He was
and of course he was looking at the
downside of human life. He was looking
at
old
old age,
at
old age, sorrow,
old age, sorrow, poverty,
at
old age, sorrow, poverty, and
old age, sorrow, poverty, and death.
that
that those
that those things
that those things he
that those things he thought
that those things he thought were
inevitable,
inevitable, inevitable.
And
And that
And that the
And that the way
And that the way beyond
And that the way beyond it
And that the way beyond it was
And that the way beyond it was to
transcend
transcend karma
by
by becoming
by becoming enlightened,
by becoming enlightened, meaning
by becoming enlightened, meaning to
transcend
transcend one's
by becoming enlightened, meaning to
transcend one's identification
transcend one's identification with
by becoming enlightened, meaning to
transcend one's identification with the
ego,
its
its origin,
ego,
its origin, its
its origin, its function,
ego,
its origin, its function, and
its origin, its function, and its
structure.
And
And to
structure.
And to realize
And to realize the
structure.
And to realize the self,
And to realize the self, to
structure.
And to realize the self, to realize
one's
one's Buddha
one's Buddha nature.
Christianity
Christianity does
one's Buddha nature.
Christianity does does
Christianity does does not
one's Buddha nature.
Christianity does does not emphasize
enlightenment
enlightenment at
enlightenment at all.
There
There is
enlightenment at all.
There is in
Catholicism
a
a condition
Catholicism
a condition or
a condition or one
I
I forgot
I forgot the
I forgot the formal
I forgot the formal ecclesiastic
I forgot the formal ecclesiastic name
for
for it.
It
It signifies
It signifies a
It signifies a high
It signifies a high level
It signifies a high level of
consciousness
as
as a
as a lifestyle.
Christianity
Christianity recognizes
as a lifestyle.
Christianity recognizes saintthood
and
and generally
and generally is
and generally is talking
and generally is talking about
and generally is talking about the
and generally is talking about the 500s,
high
high 500s
like
like Father
like Father Peel
at
at 590,
like Father Peel
at 590, the
at 590, the pope
like Father Peel
at 590, the pope at
at 590, the pope at 570.
like Father Peel
at 590, the pope at 570. the
at 590, the pope at 570. the Pope
like Father Peel
at 590, the pope at 570. the Pope to
at 590, the pope at 570. the Pope to me
is
is saying
is saying like
um
but
but that's
but that's just
but that's just my
but that's just my perception.
but that's just my perception. I
but that's just my perception. I can
tell
tell by
but that's just my perception. I can
tell by the
tell by the way
but that's just my perception. I can
tell by the way he
tell by the way he walks.
He's
He's gotten
He's gotten higher
He's gotten higher as
He's gotten higher as he
He's gotten higher as he got
He's gotten higher as he got older.
He's gotten higher as he got older. So
it
it gets
He's gotten higher as he got older. So
it gets you
it gets you slow
He's gotten higher as he got older. So
it gets you slow down
it gets you slow down as
He's gotten higher as he got older. So
it gets you slow down as the
it gets you slow down as the level
He's gotten higher as he got older. So
it gets you slow down as the level of
consciousness
consciousness goes
consciousness goes up.
You
You have
consciousness goes up.
You have to
You have to forcibly
consciousness goes up.
You have to forcibly stay
You have to forcibly stay out
consciousness goes up.
You have to forcibly stay out of
You have to forcibly stay out of that
certain
certain level
certain level of
certain level of consciousness
certain level of consciousness or
certain level of consciousness or it's
not
not possible
certain level of consciousness or it's
not possible to
not possible to function
certain level of consciousness or it's
not possible to function very
not possible to function very well.
So
So I
So I see
So I see he
So I see he sort
So I see he sort of
So I see he sort of fights
So I see he sort of fights with
So I see he sort of fights with it.
Therefore,
Therefore, whatever
So I see he sort of fights with it.
Therefore, whatever goes
Therefore, whatever goes on
So I see he sort of fights with it.
Therefore, whatever goes on in
Therefore, whatever goes on in our
So I see he sort of fights with it.
Therefore, whatever goes on in our life
currently
currently is
currently is really
currently is really the
currently is really the consequence
currently is really the consequence of
the
the totality
currently is really the consequence of
the totality of
the totality of all
currently is really the consequence of
the totality of all that
the totality of all that has
currently is really the consequence of
the totality of all that has gone
the totality of all that has gone before
as
as it
as it is
as it is expressing
as it is expressing itself
as it is expressing itself under
as it is expressing itself under current
conditions.
It's
It's not
It's not causing
It's not causing the
It's not causing the current
It's not causing the current conditions.
It's
It's expressing
It's not causing the current conditions.
It's expressing itself
It's expressing itself in
It's not causing the current conditions.
It's expressing itself in this
It's expressing itself in this way.
It
It has
It has the
It has the potentiality
It has the potentiality to
It has the potentiality to express
itself
itself and
It has the potentiality to express
itself and under
itself and under these
It has the potentiality to express
itself and under these conditions
itself and under these conditions that
potentiality
potentiality will
potentiality will express
potentiality will express itself
potentiality will express itself this
way
way and
potentiality will express itself this
way and under
way and under these
potentiality will express itself this
way and under these conditions
way and under these conditions that
potentiality
potentiality will
potentiality will express
potentiality will express itself
potentiality will express itself this
way.
So
So nothing
So nothing is
nothing
nothing is
So nothing is
nothing is uh
nothing is uh a
So nothing is
nothing is uh a rigid
nothing is uh a rigid causality
So nothing is
nothing is uh a rigid causality an
inflexible
inflexible causality.
On
On the
inflexible causality.
On the contrary,
On the contrary, closer
inflexible causality.
On the contrary, closer to
On the contrary, closer to truth
inflexible causality.
On the contrary, closer to truth is
On the contrary, closer to truth is the
whole
whole concept
whole concept of
whole concept of quantum
whole concept of quantum potentiality
in
in which
whole concept of quantum potentiality
in which the
in which the prior
whole concept of quantum potentiality
in which the prior what
in which the prior what has
whole concept of quantum potentiality
in which the prior what has gone
in which the prior what has gone before
is
is influencing
is influencing not
is influencing not just
is influencing not just specifically
is influencing not just specifically the
content
content of
is influencing not just specifically the
content of consciousness,
it's
influencing
influencing the
it's
influencing the whole
influencing the whole context.
So
So the
So the whole
So the whole context
So the whole context then
So the whole context then is
So the whole context then is what
increases
the
the likelihood
the likelihood of
the likelihood of certain
the likelihood of certain potentialities
uh
uh coming
the likelihood of certain potentialities
uh coming into
uh coming into expression
in
in spiritual
in spiritual work.
in spiritual work. We
in spiritual work. We in
in spiritual work. We in the
in spiritual work. We in the beginning
focus
focus on
uh
uh content
uh content of
uh content of consciousness.
How
How could
uh content of consciousness.
How could I
How could I have
uh content of consciousness.
How could I have been
How could I have been so
uh content of consciousness.
How could I have been so mean
How could I have been so mean to
uh content of consciousness.
How could I have been so mean to my
stepmother?
stepmother? How
stepmother? How could
stepmother? How could I
stepmother? How could I have
stepmother? How could I have been
stepmother? How could I have been so
this
this and
stepmother? How could I have been so
this and that
this and that to
stepmother? How could I have been so
this and that to my
this and that to my mother-in-law?
stepmother? How could I have been so
this and that to my mother-in-law? And
you
you feel
you feel guilty
you feel guilty how
you feel guilty how you
you feel guilty how you were
you feel guilty how you were selfish
you feel guilty how you were selfish and
stole
stole your
you feel guilty how you were selfish and
stole your sister's
stole your sister's cookie
you feel guilty how you were selfish and
stole your sister's cookie the
stole your sister's cookie the last
cookie
cookie on
cookie on her
cookie on her birthday.
cookie on her birthday. You've
cookie on her birthday. You've been
really
really guilty
cookie on her birthday. You've been
really guilty about
really guilty about that
cookie on her birthday. You've been
really guilty about that for
really guilty about that for 45
cookie on her birthday. You've been
really guilty about that for 45 years.
And
And that
And that she
And that she was
And that she was some
And that she was some little
And that she was some little dinky
And that she was some little dinky thing
way
way back
And that she was some little dinky thing
way back there.
way back there. And
And that she was some little dinky thing
way back there. And you
way back there. And you somehow
And that she was some little dinky thing
way back there. And you somehow you
can't
can't get
can't get it
can't get it out
can't get it out of
can't get it out of your
can't get it out of your head.
You
You took
can't get it out of your head.
You took the
You took the last
can't get it out of your head.
You took the last cookie
You took the last cookie from
can't get it out of your head.
You took the last cookie from your
You took the last cookie from your on
your
your sister's
your sister's birthday.
Oh,
Oh, that
your sister's birthday.
Oh, that selfishness,
Oh, that selfishness, that
your sister's birthday.
Oh, that selfishness, that greediness,
that
that horribleness.
You
You hate
that horribleness.
You hate yourself
You hate yourself for
that horribleness.
You hate yourself for it.
You hate yourself for it. It's
that horribleness.
You hate yourself for it. It's horrible.
50 years
50 years later,
50 years later, you're
50 years later, you're still
50 years later, you're still at
50 years later, you're still at it.
Probably
Probably on
50 years later, you're still at it.
Probably on death's
Probably on death's door,
50 years later, you're still at it.
Probably on death's door, you're
Probably on death's door, you're going
to
to say,
to say, "God,
to say, "God, I
to say, "God, I I
to say, "God, I I stole
to say, "God, I I stole my
to say, "God, I I stole my sister's
cookie.
cookie. Please
let
let me
let me off
let me off the
let me off the hook."
Guilt
Guilt just
let me off the hook."
Guilt just looks
Guilt just looks for
let me off the hook."
Guilt just looks for uh
Guilt just looks for uh something
let me off the hook."
Guilt just looks for uh something to
anchor
anchor itself
anchor itself into.
anchor itself into. It
anchor itself into. It isn't
anchor itself into. It isn't just
anchor itself into. It isn't just the
guilt
guilt about
anchor itself into. It isn't just the
guilt about your
guilt about your sister's
anchor itself into. It isn't just the
guilt about your sister's cookie.
guilt about your sister's cookie. It's
all
all the
all the accumulated
all the accumulated guilt
uh
uh about
all the accumulated guilt
uh about everything
uh about everything throughout
all the accumulated guilt
uh about everything throughout all
uh about everything throughout all of
lifetimes
lifetimes anchoring
lifetimes anchoring itself
lifetimes anchoring itself into
lifetimes anchoring itself into this
particular
particular expression.
Some
Some comprehension
Some comprehension of
Some comprehension of the
Some comprehension of the nature
Some comprehension of the nature of
karma
karma and
Some comprehension of the nature of
karma and maybe
karma and maybe how
Some comprehension of the nature of
karma and maybe how it
karma and maybe how it came
Some comprehension of the nature of
karma and maybe how it came about
karma and maybe how it came about in
your
your own
your own lifetime
your own lifetime can
your own lifetime can facilitate
your own lifetime can facilitate certain
difficult
difficult things
your own lifetime can facilitate certain
difficult things to
difficult things to transcend.
your own lifetime can facilitate certain
difficult things to transcend. Make
difficult things to transcend. Make them
easier.
Make
Make them
easier.
Make them easier
Make them easier to
easier.
Make them easier to transcend.
Make them easier to transcend. here.
I've
I've shared
I've shared some
I've shared some some
I've shared some some things
I've shared some some things from
I've shared some some things from other
lifetimes
lifetimes with
I've shared some some things from other
lifetimes with you,
lifetimes with you, you
I've shared some some things from other
lifetimes with you, you know,
lifetimes with you, you know, and
I've shared some some things from other
lifetimes with you, you know, and we've
had
had sort
had sort of
had sort of fun
had sort of fun with
had sort of fun with it.
had sort of fun with it. We
had sort of fun with it. We have
had sort of fun with it. We have fun
with
with it
had sort of fun with it. We have fun
with it because
with it because now
had sort of fun with it. We have fun
with it because now in
with it because now in this
had sort of fun with it. We have fun
with it because now in this time
with it because now in this time I
had sort of fun with it. We have fun
with it because now in this time I can
look
look back
look back and
look back and now
look back and now I
look back and now I feel
look back and now I feel light
look back and now I feel light about
look back and now I feel light about it.
I'm
I'm sure
look back and now I feel light about it.
I'm sure at
I'm sure at the
look back and now I feel light about it.
I'm sure at the time
I'm sure at the time I
look back and now I feel light about it.
I'm sure at the time I didn't
I'm sure at the time I didn't feel
look back and now I feel light about it.
I'm sure at the time I didn't feel all
that
that light
that light about
that light about it.
It's
It's because
that light about it.
It's because we
It's because we recontextualize
that light about it.
It's because we recontextualize it.
It's because we recontextualize it. So
sometimes
sometimes if
sometimes if you're
sometimes if you're stuck
sometimes if you're stuck in
sometimes if you're stuck in something,
you
you can
sometimes if you're stuck in something,
you can ask,
you can ask, is
sometimes if you're stuck in something,
you can ask, is this
you can ask, is this a
sometimes if you're stuck in something,
you can ask, is this a karmic
propensity?
propensity? Yeah.
propensity? Yeah. Uh
propensity? Yeah. Uh has
propensity? Yeah. Uh has this
propensity? Yeah. Uh has this was
propensity? Yeah. Uh has this was this
propensity? Yeah. Uh has this was this a
bad?
bad? Usually
propensity? Yeah. Uh has this was this a
bad? Usually what
bad? Usually what you
propensity? Yeah. Uh has this was this a
bad? Usually what you look
bad? Usually what you look for
propensity? Yeah. Uh has this was this a
bad? Usually what you look for is
bad? Usually what you look for is the
opposite.
opposite. You
opposite. You you
opposite. You you look
opposite. You you look for
opposite. You you look for the
opposite. You you look for the opposite.
What's
What's happening
opposite. You you look for the opposite.
What's happening to
What's happening to you?
opposite. You you look for the opposite.
What's happening to you? You
What's happening to you? You ask,
was
was that
was that what
was that what I
was that what I did
was that what I did to
was that what I did to others
was that what I did to others in
was that what I did to others in my
was that what I did to others in my past
life?
life? And
was that what I did to others in my past
life? And now
life? And now I
was that what I did to others in my past
life? And now I see
life? And now I see what
was that what I did to others in my past
life? And now I see what it's
life? And now I see what it's like.
was that what I did to others in my past
life? And now I see what it's like. And
the
the only
the only way,
the only way, so
the only way, so one
the only way, so one of
the only way, so one of the
the only way, so one of the ways
the only way, so one of the ways mind
undoes
undoes its
the only way, so one of the ways mind
undoes its guilt
undoes its guilt is
the only way, so one of the ways mind
undoes its guilt is to
undoes its guilt is to undo
the only way, so one of the ways mind
undoes its guilt is to undo it
undoes its guilt is to undo it by
the only way, so one of the ways mind
undoes its guilt is to undo it by living
it
it through
it through and
it through and living
it through and living living
it through and living living the
it through and living living the side
it through and living living the side of
the
the victim.
it through and living living the side of
the victim. So
the victim. So in
it through and living living the side of
the victim. So in the
the victim. So in the prior
it through and living living the side of
the victim. So in the prior lifetime
the victim. So in the prior lifetime you
where
where you
where you were
where you were the
where you were the perpetrator,
where you were the perpetrator, you
where you were the perpetrator, you now
have
have the
where you were the perpetrator, you now
have the responsibility
have the responsibility in
where you were the perpetrator, you now
have the responsibility in this
have the responsibility in this lifetime
to
to undo
to undo that
to undo that either
to undo that either by
to undo that either by good
to undo that either by good works
um
um or
to undo that either by good works
um or by
um or by experiencing
to undo that either by good works
um or by experiencing it
um or by experiencing it out
to undo that either by good works
um or by experiencing it out and
um or by experiencing it out and um
forgiving
forgiving everything
forgiving everything and
forgiving everything and everyone
including
including yourself.
forgiving everything and everyone
including yourself. So
including yourself. So the
forgiving everything and everyone
including yourself. So the tool
including yourself. So the tool that
helps
helps you
helps you through
helps you through all
helps you through all of
helps you through all of this
helps you through all of this is
helps you through all of this is first
of
of all
helps you through all of this is first
of all the
of all the comprehension
helps you through all of this is first
of all the comprehension does
of all the comprehension does make
helps you through all of this is first
of all the comprehension does make many
things
things easier
things easier to
things easier to accept
that
that if
things easier to accept
that if you
that if you can
things easier to accept
that if you can go
that if you can go back
things easier to accept
that if you can go back with
that if you can go back with kinesiology
and
and saying
and saying such
and saying such and
and saying such and in
and saying such and in some
and saying such and in some lifetime
and saying such and in some lifetime did
I
I do
and saying such and in some lifetime did
I do such
I do such and
and saying such and in some lifetime did
I do such and such
I do such and such or
and saying such and in some lifetime did
I do such and such or did
I do such and such or did such
and saying such and in some lifetime did
I do such and such or did such and
I do such and such or did such and such
thing
thing happen
and
and then
thing happen
and then you
and then you can
thing happen
and then you can get
and then you can get sort
thing happen
and then you can get sort of
and then you can get sort of an
thing happen
and then you can get sort of an aha
and then you can get sort of an aha well
I
I guess
I guess it's
I guess it's I
I guess it's I guess
I guess it's I guess it
I guess it's I guess it makes
I guess it's I guess it makes sense
I guess it's I guess it makes sense then
and
and early
I guess it's I guess it makes sense then
and early in
and early in life
I guess it's I guess it makes sense then
and early in life I
and early in life I never
I guess it's I guess it makes sense then
and early in life I never heard
and early in life I never heard of
I guess it's I guess it makes sense then
and early in life I never heard of karma
But
But I
But I would
But I would always
But I would always say,
But I would always say, you
But I would always say, you know,
But I would always say, you know, I
But I would always say, you know, I must
have
have done
But I would always say, you know, I must
have done something
have done something something
But I would always say, you know, I must
have done something something to
somebody
somebody in
somebody in some
somebody in some lifetime
somebody in some lifetime to
somebody in some lifetime to deserve
that.
that. You
somebody in some lifetime to deserve
that. You know
that. You know what
somebody in some lifetime to deserve
that. You know what I'm
that. You know what I'm saying?
It
It just
It just sort
It just sort of
It just sort of made
It just sort of made sense
It just sort of made sense that
otherwise
otherwise there
It just sort of made sense that
otherwise there would
otherwise there would be
It just sort of made sense that
otherwise there would be no
otherwise there would be no explanation
about
about for
about for it
about for it except
about for it except that
about for it except that God
about for it except that God is
arbitrary
arbitrary anatist.
There
There are
There are many
There are many atheists
There are many atheists in
There are many atheists in the
There are many atheists in the world
There are many atheists in the world and
uh
uh they're
There are many atheists in the world and
uh they're not
uh they're not all
There are many atheists in the world and
uh they're not all stupid.
uh they're not all stupid. You
There are many atheists in the world and
uh they're not all stupid. You know,
many
many of
many of them
many of them are
many of them are quite
many of them are quite brilliant.
And
And when
many of them are quite brilliant.
And when they
And when they look
many of them are quite brilliant.
And when they look at
And when they look at the
many of them are quite brilliant.
And when they look at the world
And when they look at the world through
the
the Newtonian
the Newtonian paradigm
the Newtonian paradigm of
the Newtonian paradigm of reality,
um
um the
the Newtonian paradigm of reality,
um the idea
um the idea that
the Newtonian paradigm of reality,
um the idea that there's
um the idea that there's an
the Newtonian paradigm of reality,
um the idea that there's an infinite
benevolent
benevolent God
benevolent God who
benevolent God who is
benevolent God who is not
benevolent God who is not different
benevolent God who is not different than
love
love is
benevolent God who is not different than
love is idiotic.
You
You understand?
You understand? Logic,
You understand? Logic, reason
You understand? Logic, reason at
You understand? Logic, reason at a
certain
certain point
You understand? Logic, reason at a
certain point will
certain point will not
You understand? Logic, reason at a
certain point will not take
certain point will not take you
You understand? Logic, reason at a
certain point will not take you to
certain point will not take you to God.
It'll
It'll take
It'll take you
It'll take you to
It'll take you to atheism.
At
At one
It'll take you to atheism.
At one one
At one one level
It'll take you to atheism.
At one one level of
At one one level of consciousness,
It'll take you to atheism.
At one one level of consciousness, if
you're
you're not
you're not an
you're not an atheist,
you're not an atheist, I
you're not an atheist, I think
you're not an atheist, I think you're
stupid.
I
I was
I was a
I was a devout
I was a devout atheist
I was a devout atheist for
I was a devout atheist for years
I was a devout atheist for years and
I was a devout atheist for years and I
looked
looked at
I was a devout atheist for years and I
looked at anybody
looked at anybody who
I was a devout atheist for years and I
looked at anybody who believed
looked at anybody who believed that
I was a devout atheist for years and I
looked at anybody who believed that God
is
is an
is an absolute
is an absolute idiot.
You
You look
is an absolute idiot.
You look at
You look at the
is an absolute idiot.
You look at the disaster
You look at the disaster of
is an absolute idiot.
You look at the disaster of mankind
You look at the disaster of mankind and
say
God
God is
say
God is the
God is the source
say
God is the source of
God is the source of all
say
God is the source of all this
or
or you
or you can
or you can keep
or you can keep him.
So
that
that was
that was when
that was when I
that was when I held
that was when I held God
that was when I held God as
that was when I held God as the
that was when I held God as the source
no
no the
that was when I held God as the source
no the cause
of
of the
of the human
of the human karmic
of the human karmic dilemma.
What
What we
of the human karmic dilemma.
What we see
What we see then
of the human karmic dilemma.
What we see then as
What we see then as human
of the human karmic dilemma.
What we see then as human tragedy
What we see then as human tragedy is
of the human karmic dilemma.
What we see then as human tragedy is the
effect
effect of
effect of the
effect of the ego
uncaused
uncaused by
effect of the ego
uncaused by God.
uncaused by God. So
it's
it's as
it's as though
the
the capacity
it's as though
the capacity for
the capacity for existence
it's as though
the capacity for existence and
the capacity for existence and life
it's as though
the capacity for existence and life and
consciousness
consciousness is
consciousness is a
consciousness is a given
consciousness is a given and
consciousness is a given and then
consciousness is a given and then what
is
is done
consciousness is a given and then what
is done with
is done with it
consciousness is a given and then what
is done with it becomes
is done with it becomes one's
consciousness is a given and then what
is done with it becomes one's own
is done with it becomes one's own karmic
responsibility
the
the consequences
responsibility
the consequences of
the consequences of which
responsibility
the consequences of which we
the consequences of which we see
collectively
collectively as
collectively as society.
collectively as society. Huh?
But
But when
collectively as society. Huh?
But when I
But when I became
collectively as society. Huh?
But when I became an
But when I became an atheist,
collectively as society. Huh?
But when I became an atheist, it
But when I became an atheist, it was
because
because the
because the totality
because the totality of
because the totality of the
because the totality of the suffering
because the totality of the suffering of
all
all of
because the totality of the suffering of
all of mankind
opened
opened up
opened up as
opened up as a
opened up as a revelation.
opened up as a revelation. It
opened up as a revelation. It was
staggering.
I
I was
I was a
I was a devout
I was a devout religionist
at
at the
I was a devout religionist
at the time
at the time and
scrupulous
scrupulous in
scrupulous in fact
scrupulous in fact scrupulous.
scrupulous in fact scrupulous. And
scrupulous in fact scrupulous. And I
told
told you
scrupulous in fact scrupulous. And I
told you I
told you I used
scrupulous in fact scrupulous. And I
told you I used to
told you I used to dread
scrupulous in fact scrupulous. And I
told you I used to dread Saturday
afternoon.
afternoon. you
afternoon. you went
afternoon. you went to
afternoon. you went to confession
afternoon. you went to confession that
you
you wouldn't
afternoon. you went to confession that
you wouldn't sin
you wouldn't sin someplace
afternoon. you went to confession that
you wouldn't sin someplace before
you wouldn't sin someplace before you
went
went to
went to church
went to church on
went to church on Sunday
went to church on Sunday morning
went to church on Sunday morning and
went to church on Sunday morning and had
communion.
Anyway,
Anyway, I
Anyway, I was
Anyway, I was out
Anyway, I was out in
Anyway, I was out in the
Anyway, I was out in the woods
Anyway, I was out in the woods and
suddenly
suddenly the
Anyway, I was out in the woods and
suddenly the totality
suddenly the totality of
Anyway, I was out in the woods and
suddenly the totality of the
suddenly the totality of the suffering
of
of all
of all mankind
of all mankind throughout
of all mankind throughout all
of all mankind throughout all of
of all mankind throughout all of time
opened
opened up
of all mankind throughout all of time
opened up in
opened up in the
of all mankind throughout all of time
opened up in the most
opened up in the most staggering
revelation
on
on God
revelation
on God on
on God on beyond
revelation
on God on beyond the
on God on beyond the capacity
revelation
on God on beyond the capacity of
ordinary
ordinary human
ordinary human thinkingness
ordinary human thinkingness to
comprehend.
staggering.
In
In that
staggering.
In that instant,
In that instant, I
staggering.
In that instant, I became
In that instant, I became an
staggering.
In that instant, I became an atheist.
God
God went
God went out
God went out that
God went out that fast.
Can't
Can't believe
God went out that fast.
Can't believe in
Can't believe in a
God went out that fast.
Can't believe in a god
Can't believe in a god that
God went out that fast.
Can't believe in a god that allows
Can't believe in a god that allows that
because
because when
because when you
because when you look
because when you look at
because when you look at the
because when you look at the totality
because when you look at the totality of
human
human suffering,
one
one has
one has to
one has to be
one has to be of
one has to be of sizable
one has to be of sizable dimension
one has to be of sizable dimension to
even
even glance
one has to be of sizable dimension to
even glance at
even glance at it.
one has to be of sizable dimension to
even glance at it. Just
even glance at it. Just blows
one has to be of sizable dimension to
even glance at it. Just blows you
even glance at it. Just blows you away.
In
In clinical
In clinical practice,
In clinical practice, you
In clinical practice, you know,
In clinical practice, you know, you
In clinical practice, you know, you see
it
it peacemeal.
In clinical practice, you know, you see
it peacemeal. You
it peacemeal. You see
In clinical practice, you know, you see
it peacemeal. You see it
it peacemeal. You see it peace
In clinical practice, you know, you see
it peacemeal. You see it peace meal
it peacemeal. You see it peace meal in
the
the ER.
In
In war,
the ER.
In war, you
In war, you see
the ER.
In war, you see it
In war, you see it peace
the ER.
In war, you see it peace meal,
In war, you see it peace meal, but
the ER.
In war, you see it peace meal, but this
came
came on.
came on. Not
came on. Not peace
came on. Not peace meal,
came on. Not peace meal, but
came on. Not peace meal, but all
came on. Not peace meal, but all of
came on. Not peace meal, but all of it.
So,
So, was
came on. Not peace meal, but all of it.
So, was I
So, was I ever
came on. Not peace meal, but all of it.
So, was I ever a
So, was I ever a devout
came on. Not peace meal, but all of it.
So, was I ever a devout atheist?
So, was I ever a devout atheist? And
came on. Not peace meal, but all of it.
So, was I ever a devout atheist? And it
took
took Catholicism
took Catholicism apart,
took Catholicism apart, Protestantism
apart,
apart, the
took Catholicism apart, Protestantism
apart, the Reformation
apart, the Reformation apart,
took Catholicism apart, Protestantism
apart, the Reformation apart, the
apart, the Reformation apart, the Bible
idiotic.
Thomas
Thomas Aquinus.
Good
Good God,
Good God, give
Good God, give me
Good God, give me a
Good God, give me a break.
I
I got
Good God, give me a break.
I got straight
I got straight A
Good God, give me a break.
I got straight A in
I got straight A in theology.
And
And a
And a Jesuit
And a Jesuit university.
And a Jesuit university. Straight
And a Jesuit university. Straight A
And a Jesuit university. Straight A in
ethics,
ethics, straight
And a Jesuit university. Straight A in
ethics, straight A
ethics, straight A in
And a Jesuit university. Straight A in
ethics, straight A in logic,
ethics, straight A in logic, straight
And a Jesuit university. Straight A in
ethics, straight A in logic, straight A
in
in theology.
Um
Um because
in theology.
Um because if
Um because if you're
in theology.
Um because if you're going
Um because if you're going to
in theology.
Um because if you're going to be
Um because if you're going to be against
something,
something, you
something, you better
something, you better know
something, you better know a
something, you better know a lot
something, you better know a lot about
it.
So,
So, Friday
So, Friday afternoon
So, Friday afternoon outside
So, Friday afternoon outside of
Marquette
Marquette University
So, Friday afternoon outside of
Marquette University in
Marquette University in the
So, Friday afternoon outside of
Marquette University in the news
Marquette University in the news bar,
uh,
uh, real
uh, real our
uh, real our names
uh, real our names on
uh, real our names on our
uh, real our names on our mugs
uh, real our names on our mugs was
uh, real our names on our mugs was take
on
on all.
uh, real our names on our mugs was take
on all. I
on all. I sat
uh, real our names on our mugs was take
on all. I sat in
on all. I sat in the
uh, real our names on our mugs was take
on all. I sat in the corner
on all. I sat in the corner and
uh, real our names on our mugs was take
on all. I sat in the corner and I
on all. I sat in the corner and I took
on
on all
on all comers
on all comers or
on all comers or the
on all comers or the religionist
on all comers or the religionist and
on all comers or the religionist and I
would
would knock
on all comers or the religionist and I
would knock them
would knock them out
on all comers or the religionist and I
would knock them out of
would knock them out of the
on all comers or the religionist and I
would knock them out of the box
would knock them out of the box one
after
after another.
Never
Never lost
after another.
Never lost around.
Never lost around. It's
after another.
Never lost around. It's a
Never lost around. It's a fact.
after another.
Never lost around. It's a fact. Never
lost
lost around.
All
All right?
lost around.
All right? Because
within
within the
within the Newtonian
within the Newtonian paradigm
within the Newtonian paradigm of
reality,
uh,
uh, nothing
uh, nothing about
uh, nothing about God
uh, nothing about God is
uh, nothing about God is really
provable.
provable. You
uh, nothing about God is really
provable. You have
provable. You have to
uh, nothing about God is really
provable. You have to go
provable. You have to go to
uh, nothing about God is really
provable. You have to go to the
nonlinear
where
where you're
nonlinear
where you're beyond
where you're beyond causality.
nonlinear
where you're beyond causality. You're
beyond
beyond logic.
You're
You're beyond
beyond logic.
You're beyond uh
You're beyond uh literalism
and
and concrete.
Um,
Um, and
and concrete.
Um, and you
Um, and you get
and concrete.
Um, and you get to
Um, and you get to greater
and concrete.
Um, and you get to greater dimensions.
Um
so
so it
Um
so it takes
so it takes the
Um
so it takes the greater
so it takes the greater dimensions
Um
so it takes the greater dimensions to
heal
heal the
heal the negativities
heal the negativities that
heal the negativities that have
heal the negativities that have arisen
out
out of
heal the negativities that have arisen
out of karma.
The
The whatever
The whatever one
The whatever one has
The whatever one has inherited
The whatever one has inherited in
The whatever one has inherited in one
way
way or
The whatever one has inherited in one
way or another
way or another or
The whatever one has inherited in one
way or another or come
way or another or come into
The whatever one has inherited in one
way or another or come into because
way or another or come into because you
come
come into
come into it
come into it just
come into it just by
come into it just by being
come into it just by being human.
come into it just by being human. You
share
share in
come into it just by being human. You
share in human
share in human consciousness.
come into it just by being human. You
share in human consciousness. The
totality
totality of
totality of human
totality of human consciousness
is
is something
totality of human consciousness
is something which
is something which dominates
totality of human consciousness
is something which dominates individual
consciousness.
The
The reason
consciousness.
The reason you
The reason you can
consciousness.
The reason you can light
The reason you can light up
consciousness.
The reason you can light up a
The reason you can light up a whole
crowd
crowd of
crowd of enthusiasts
crowd of enthusiasts about
crowd of enthusiasts about something
crowd of enthusiasts about something is
because
because that
crowd of enthusiasts about something is
because that consciousness
because that consciousness level
crowd of enthusiasts about something is
because that consciousness level is
available
available to
available to the
available to the whole
available to the whole crowd.
Uh
Uh you
available to the whole crowd.
Uh you know
Uh you know Fitler
available to the whole crowd.
Uh you know Fitler knew
Uh you know Fitler knew how
available to the whole crowd.
Uh you know Fitler knew how to
Uh you know Fitler knew how to play
available to the whole crowd.
Uh you know Fitler knew how to play that
like
like a
like a you
like a you know
like a you know he
like a you know he would
like a you know he would play
like a you know he would play 10,000
people
people shouting
like a you know he would play 10,000
people shouting sigh
people shouting sigh at
like a you know he would play 10,000
people shouting sigh at the
people shouting sigh at the same
like a you know he would play 10,000
people shouting sigh at the same time
and
and it
and it was
and it was hypnotic
and it was hypnotic you
and it was hypnotic you know.
If
If you
and it was hypnotic you know.
If you weren't
If you weren't a
and it was hypnotic you know.
If you weren't a Nazi
If you weren't a Nazi in
and it was hypnotic you know.
If you weren't a Nazi in those
If you weren't a Nazi in those years
and it was hypnotic you know.
If you weren't a Nazi in those years in
Germany,
Germany, you
Germany, you must
Germany, you must have
Germany, you must have been
Germany, you must have been brain
Germany, you must have been brain dead
because
it
it was
it was persuasive.
it was persuasive. It
it was persuasive. It was
all-encompassing.
all-encompassing. It
it was persuasive. It was
all-encompassing. It was
all-encompassing. It was powerful.
it was persuasive. It was
all-encompassing. It was powerful. It
was
was patriotic.
was patriotic. It
was patriotic. It was
was patriotic. It was military.
was patriotic. It was military. It
was patriotic. It was military. It was
it
it was
was patriotic. It was military. It was
it was grand.
The
The fact
The fact that
The fact that it
The fact that it was
The fact that it was somewhat
The fact that it was somewhat an
The fact that it was somewhat an error
did
did not
The fact that it was somewhat an error
did not show
did not show up
The fact that it was somewhat an error
did not show up till
did not show up till later.
The fact that it was somewhat an error
did not show up till later. But
did not show up till later. But at
The fact that it was somewhat an error
did not show up till later. But at the
time
time it
time it was,
time it was, you
time it was, you know,
time it was, you know, any
time it was, you know, any normal
time it was, you know, any normal kid
would
would want
time it was, you know, any normal kid
would want to
would want to go
time it was, you know, any normal kid
would want to go to
would want to go to one
time it was, you know, any normal kid
would want to go to one of
would want to go to one of the
time it was, you know, any normal kid
would want to go to one of the boys
camps
camps and
camps and learn
camps and learn how
camps and learn how to
camps and learn how to become
camps and learn how to become a
camps and learn how to become a member
of
of the
camps and learn how to become a member
of the Hitler
of the Hitler Youth.
camps and learn how to become a member
of the Hitler Youth. You
of the Hitler Youth. You it'
camps and learn how to become a member
of the Hitler Youth. You it' have
of the Hitler Youth. You it' have to
camps and learn how to become a member
of the Hitler Youth. You it' have to be
something
something wrong
something wrong with
something wrong with you
something wrong with you not
something wrong with you not to
something wrong with you not to want
something wrong with you not to want to
because
because it
something wrong with you not to want to
because it was
because it was so
something wrong with you not to want to
because it was so prevailing
because it was so prevailing in
something wrong with you not to want to
because it was so prevailing in society.
So
So we
So we see
So we see how
So we see how these
So we see how these dominant
So we see how these dominant levels
So we see how these dominant levels of
consciousness
consciousness then
So we see how these dominant levels of
consciousness then have
consciousness then have resonate
So we see how these dominant levels of
consciousness then have resonate in
consciousness then have resonate in the
human
human condition
human condition because
human condition because everybody
human condition because everybody in
that
that crowd
human condition because everybody in
that crowd is
that crowd is a
human condition because everybody in
that crowd is a captive
that crowd is a captive of
human condition because everybody in
that crowd is a captive of the
that crowd is a captive of the human
condition.
They're
They're all
condition.
They're all born
They're all born with
condition.
They're all born with the
They're all born with the capacity
condition.
They're all born with the capacity for
loyalty,
loyalty, nationalism,
loyalty, nationalism, enthusiasm,
macho
macho masculinity,
militarism,
militarism, all
militarism, all those
militarism, all those things.
militarism, all those things. You
inherit
inherit that
militarism, all those things. You
inherit that as
inherit that as part
militarism, all those things. You
inherit that as part of
inherit that as part of being
militarism, all those things. You
inherit that as part of being a
inherit that as part of being a human.
So,
but
but the
So,
but the worst
but the worst thing
So,
but the worst thing you
but the worst thing you see
So,
but the worst thing you see go
but the worst thing you see go on
So,
but the worst thing you see go on in
but the worst thing you see go on in the
world
world historically
world historically or
world historically or currently
world historically or currently is
really
really the
world historically or currently is
really the consequence
really the consequence of
world historically or currently is
really the consequence of being
really the consequence of being human.
To
To be
To be human
To be human being
to
to be
To be human being
to be to
to be to begin
To be human being
to be to begin with
to be to begin with a
To be human being
to be to begin with a human
to be to begin with a human being
To be human being
to be to begin with a human being can't
tell
tell truth
tell truth from
tell truth from falsehood
a
a walkling
tell truth from falsehood
a walkling stumbling
a walkling stumbling idiot.
How
How did
How did we
How did we ever
How did we ever get
How did we ever get this
How did we ever get this far?
How did we ever get this far? I
How did we ever get this far? I don't
know.
It
It boggles
It boggles me
It boggles me that
It boggles me that we
It boggles me that we even
It boggles me that we even got
It boggles me that we even got here.
Can
Can you
It boggles me that we even got here.
Can you imagine
Can you imagine a
It boggles me that we even got here.
Can you imagine a species
Can you imagine a species that
It boggles me that we even got here.
Can you imagine a species that doesn't
know
know truth
know truth from
know truth from falsehood?
know truth from falsehood? If
know truth from falsehood? If you
know truth from falsehood? If you don't
know
know truth
know truth from falsehood? If you don't
know truth from
know truth from falsehood,
know truth from falsehood? If you don't
know truth from falsehood, that
know truth from falsehood, that pretty
much
much puts
much puts you
much puts you back
much puts you back in
much puts you back in the
much puts you back in the animal
much puts you back in the animal kingdom
where
where your
much puts you back in the animal kingdom
where your instinctual
where your instinctual stimulus
much puts you back in the animal kingdom
where your instinctual stimulus and
response.
Of
Of course,
response.
Of course, this
Of course, this became
response.
Of course, this became more
Of course, this became more elaborate
response.
Of course, this became more elaborate in
the
the homminid
became
became more
the homminid
became more elaborate
became more elaborate in
the homminid
became more elaborate in Neanderthal
manorus.
It
It became
manorus.
It became more
It became more elaborate,
manorus.
It became more elaborate, but
It became more elaborate, but still
manorus.
It became more elaborate, but still its
innate
innate nature
innate nature didn't
innate nature didn't change
innate nature didn't change at
innate nature didn't change at all.
greed,
greed, fear,
innate nature didn't change at all.
greed, fear, attack,
greed, fear, attack, counterattack.
Anything
Anything you
Anything you see
Anything you see in
Anything you see in Monkey
Anything you see in Monkey Island
Anything you see in Monkey Island is
Anything you see in Monkey Island is in
every
every day's
Anything you see in Monkey Island is in
every day's newspaper.
>> No
>> No different
>> No different at
>> No different at all.
>> No different at all. There's
>> No different at all. There's no
difference
difference between
>> No different at all. There's no
difference between human
difference between human society
>> No different at all. There's no
difference between human society and
Monkey
Monkey Island.
Monkey Island. Little
Monkey Island. Little groups
Monkey Island. Little groups ganging
Monkey Island. Little groups ganging up
on
on each
Monkey Island. Little groups ganging up
on each other,
on each other, little
Monkey Island. Little groups ganging up
on each other, little gossipers
on each other, little gossipers like
this,
this, people
this, people getting
this, people getting some
this, people getting some quick
this, people getting some quick sex
this, people getting some quick sex on
the
the side
this, people getting some quick sex on
the side while
the side while the
this, people getting some quick sex on
the side while the females
the side while the females not
this, people getting some quick sex on
the side while the females not looking,
people
people running
people running in
people running in to
people running in to grab
people running in to grab things.
people running in to grab things. Sully
was
was telling
people running in to grab things. Sully
was telling me
was telling me about
people running in to grab things. Sully
was telling me about he
was telling me about he was
people running in to grab things. Sully
was telling me about he was watching
was telling me about he was watching how
life
life is.
life is. You
life is. You know,
life is. You know, monkey
life is. You know, monkey grabs
something,
something, then
life is. You know, monkey grabs
something, then a
something, then a bigger
life is. You know, monkey grabs
something, then a bigger monkey
something, then a bigger monkey comes
along
along and
along and takes
along and takes it
along and takes it away
along and takes it away from
along and takes it away from him.
along and takes it away from him. Then
along and takes it away from him. Then a
bigger
bigger monkey
along and takes it away from him. Then a
bigger monkey comes
bigger monkey comes and
along and takes it away from him. Then a
bigger monkey comes and knocks
bigger monkey comes and knocks him
along and takes it away from him. Then a
bigger monkey comes and knocks him out
and
and takes
and takes it
and takes it away
and takes it away from
and takes it away from him.
and takes it away from him. Then
and takes it away from him. Then the
and takes it away from him. Then the big
monkey
monkey comes
and takes it away from him. Then the big
monkey comes along,
monkey comes along, hits
and takes it away from him. Then the big
monkey comes along, hits him
monkey comes along, hits him over
and takes it away from him. Then the big
monkey comes along, hits him over the
head
head and
head and takes
head and takes the
head and takes the whole
head and takes the whole deal.
So
So that's
head and takes the whole deal.
So that's today's
So that's today's political
head and takes the whole deal.
So that's today's political news,
So that's today's political news, isn't
it?
So,
So, the
it?
So, the position
So, the position politically
it?
So, the position politically we're
So, the position politically we're going
to
to take
to take now
to take now is
to take now is stand
to take now is stand up
to take now is stand up and
take
take us
to take now is stand up and
take us on.
take us on. You
to take now is stand up and
take us on. You got
take us on. You got big
to take now is stand up and
take us on. You got big trouble.
take us on. You got big trouble. Whoa.
The
The best
The best defense
The best defense is
The best defense is a
The best defense is a good
The best defense is a good offense,
The best defense is a good offense, huh?
Well,
it's
it's been
it's been tried
it's been tried all
it's been tried all different
it's been tried all different ways.
We'll
We'll see
it's been tried all different ways.
We'll see how
We'll see how it
it's been tried all different ways.
We'll see how it works
We'll see how it works this
it's been tried all different ways.
We'll see how it works this time.
I
I see
I see how
I see how it
I see how it worked
I see how it worked in
I see how it worked in World
I see how it worked in World War
I see how it worked in World War II.
Pacifism
Pacifism and
I see how it worked in World War II.
Pacifism and peace
Pacifism and peace are
I see how it worked in World War II.
Pacifism and peace are not
Pacifism and peace are not the
I see how it worked in World War II.
Pacifism and peace are not the same
thing.
All right.
All right. So
thing.
All right. So we'll
All right. So we'll take
thing.
All right. So we'll take a
All right. So we'll take a stand
thing.
All right. So we'll take a stand and
look
look fierce
look fierce and
look fierce and see
look fierce and see if
look fierce and see if that
look fierce and see if that holds
look fierce and see if that holds off
anybody
anybody with
look fierce and see if that holds off
anybody with any
anybody with any common
look fierce and see if that holds off
anybody with any common sense.
anybody with any common sense. But
look fierce and see if that holds off
anybody with any common sense. But megal
megalomaniacs
megalomaniacs don't
megalomaniacs don't have
megalomaniacs don't have common
megalomaniacs don't have common sense.
If
If you
megalomaniacs don't have common sense.
If you see
If you see a
megalomaniacs don't have common sense.
If you see a walk
If you see a walk across
megalomaniacs don't have common sense.
If you see a walk across the
If you see a walk across the the
megalomaniacs don't have common sense.
If you see a walk across the the line
will
will shoot
will shoot you.
will shoot you. That's
will shoot you. That's the
will shoot you. That's the walk
will shoot you. That's the walk across
the
the line
will shoot you. That's the walk across
the line because
the line because there's
will shoot you. That's the walk across
the line because there's some
the line because there's some nuts
will shoot you. That's the walk across
the line because there's some nuts and
bolts
bolts missing.
Nobody
Nobody would
bolts missing.
Nobody would do
Nobody would do anything
bolts missing.
Nobody would do anything so
Nobody would do anything so stupid
bolts missing.
Nobody would do anything so stupid is
what
what we
what we rely
what we rely on.
what we rely on. We've
what we rely on. We've been
what we rely on. We've been wrong
what we rely on. We've been wrong over
and
and over
what we rely on. We've been wrong over
and over again.
Nobody
Nobody would
Nobody would be
Nobody would be so
Nobody would be so stupid
Nobody would be so stupid as
Nobody would be so stupid as the
Nobody would be so stupid as the so
Nobody would be so stupid as the so and
so.
so. Oh
Nobody would be so stupid as the so and
so. Oh yeah,
so. Oh yeah, they
Nobody would be so stupid as the so and
so. Oh yeah, they would.
They
They would.
So
So we
They would.
So we have
So we have um
They would.
So we have um the
So we have um the karmic
They would.
So we have um the karmic unity
So we have um the karmic unity of
They would.
So we have um the karmic unity of the
universe.
Then
creation
creation expressing
creation expressing itself
uh
uh through
creation expressing itself
uh through consciousness
uh through consciousness and
creation expressing itself
uh through consciousness and the
uh through consciousness and the energy
of
of life
of life evolving
of life evolving up
of life evolving up through
of life evolving up through the
of life evolving up through the animal
kingdom.
kingdom. We
of life evolving up through the animal
kingdom. We see
kingdom. We see consciousness
of life evolving up through the animal
kingdom. We see consciousness becoming
more
more and
more and more
more and more conscious,
more
more and
more and more conscious,
more and more
more and more subtle,
more and more conscious,
more and more subtle, more
more and more subtle, more advanced
progression
progression of
progression of consciousness
progression of consciousness up
progression of consciousness up to
progression of consciousness up to the
point
point of
progression of consciousness up to the
point of homo
point of homo sapien.
progression of consciousness up to the
point of homo sapien. Huh?
Homo
Homo sapien.
Then
Then we
Homo sapien.
Then we see
Then we see homo
Homo sapien.
Then we see homo sapien
Then we see homo sapien calibrated
Homo sapien.
Then we see homo sapien calibrated at
Then we see homo sapien calibrated at 90
at
at the
at the time
at the time of
at the time of Buddha,
at the time of Buddha, 100
at the time of Buddha, 100 at
at the time of Buddha, 100 at the
at the time of Buddha, 100 at the time
of
of Jesus,
190 throughout
190 throughout the
190 throughout the centuries.
190 throughout
190 throughout the
190 throughout the centuries.
190 throughout the centuries,
1700s.
1700s. Let's
1700s. Let's just
1700s. Let's just do
1700s. Let's just do it
1700s. Let's just do it because
1700s. Let's just do it because I
1700s. Let's just do it because I don't
know
know if
1700s. Let's just do it because I don't
know if we
know if we ever
1700s. Let's just do it because I don't
know if we ever did
know if we ever did it
1700s. Let's just do it because I don't
know if we ever did it here.
Uh
Uh the
Uh the consciousness
Uh the consciousness level
Uh the consciousness level of
Uh the consciousness level of mankind
Uh the consciousness level of mankind in
the
the 1700s,
Uh the consciousness level of mankind in
the 1700s, we
the 1700s, we have
Uh the consciousness level of mankind in
the 1700s, we have permission
the 1700s, we have permission to
Uh the consciousness level of mankind in
the 1700s, we have permission to ask
that
that here
that here was
that here was over
that here was over 185.
Oh,
Oh, 185.
that here was over 185.
Oh, 185. In
Oh, 185. In the
that here was over 185.
Oh, 185. In the 1900s,
Oh, 185. In the 1900s, in
that here was over 185.
Oh, 185. In the 1900s, in the
Oh, 185. In the 1900s, in the early
1900s,
1900s, it
1900s, it was
1900s, it was at
1900s, it was at one
1900s, it was at one uh
1900s, it was at one uh was
1900s, it was at one uh was over
1900s, it was at one uh was over 185.
188.
The
The turn
The turn of
The turn of the
The turn of the in
The turn of the in 1900,
The turn of the in 1900, consciousness
level
level of
The turn of the in 1900, consciousness
level of mankind
level of mankind was
The turn of the in 1900, consciousness
level of mankind was over
level of mankind was over 188.
The turn of the in 1900, consciousness
level of mankind was over 188. 189.
level of mankind was over 188. 189. 189.
Okay.
In
In the
Okay.
In the 1950s,
In the 1950s, the
Okay.
In the 1950s, the consciousness
In the 1950s, the consciousness level
Okay.
In the 1950s, the consciousness level of
mankind
mankind was
mankind was over
mankind was over 190.
mankind was over 190. 191.
mankind was over 190. 191. It
mankind was over 190. 191. It was
mankind was over 190. 191. It was still
at
at 190.
In
In 1980,
In 1980, the
In 1980, the consciousness
In 1980, the consciousness level
In 1980, the consciousness level of
mankind
mankind was
In 1980, the consciousness level of
mankind was over
mankind was over 190.
In 1980, the consciousness level of
mankind was over 190. Was
mankind was over 190. Was it
In 1980, the consciousness level of
mankind was over 190. Was it 192?
Well,
Well, at
Well, at 99
Well, at 99 190.
Well, at 99 190. In
Well, at 99 190. In 1986,
Well, at 99 190. In 1986, the
consciousness
consciousness level
Well, at 99 190. In 1986, the
consciousness level of
consciousness level of mankind
Well, at 99 190. In 1986, the
consciousness level of mankind was
consciousness level of mankind was over
190.
190. Was
190. Was just
190. Was just 191,
193,
193, 195.
1986,
1988,
1988, the
1986,
1988, the consciousness
1988, the consciousness level
1986,
1988, the consciousness level of
1988, the consciousness level of mankind
was
was over
was over 200.
was over 200. Was
was over 200. Was it
was over 200. Was it 205?
was over 200. Was it 205? 206.
Wow.
Wow. Right
was over 200. Was it 205? 206.
Wow. Right there
Wow. Right there in
was over 200. Was it 205? 206.
Wow. Right there in the
Wow. Right there in the late
was over 200. Was it 205? 206.
Wow. Right there in the late 80s,
suddenly
suddenly all
suddenly all of
the
the potentiality
suddenly all of
the potentiality for
the potentiality for human
suddenly all of
the potentiality for human life
the potentiality for human life totally
changed
of
of a
changed
of a greater
of a greater significance
changed
of a greater significance than
of a greater significance than the
temperature
temperature of
temperature of the
temperature of the earth
temperature of the earth going
temperature of the earth going up
temperature of the earth going up 2°
to
to go
temperature of the earth going up 2°
to go from
to go from one
temperature of the earth going up 2°
to go from one you
to go from one you see
temperature of the earth going up 2°
to go from one you see 190
to go from one you see 190 in
temperature of the earth going up 2°
to go from one you see 190 in my
to go from one you see 190 in my own
lifetime
lifetime then
lifetime then consciousness
lifetime then consciousness level
lifetime then consciousness level went
up
up let's
lifetime then consciousness level went
up let's see
up let's see when
lifetime then consciousness level went
up let's see when I
up let's see when I was
lifetime then consciousness level went
up let's see when I was born
up let's see when I was born when
lifetime then consciousness level went
up let's see when I was born when I
up let's see when I was born when I was
born
born when
born when I
born when I was
born when I was born
born when I was born the
born when I was born the consciousness
level
level mankind
born when I was born the consciousness
level mankind time
level mankind time was
born when I was born the consciousness
level mankind time was over
180 182
180 182 184
180 182 184 184
When
When I
180 182 184 184
When I was
When I was born
180 182 184 184
When I was born it
When I was born it was
180 182 184 184
When I was born it was 184
When I was born it was 184 now
180 182 184 184
When I was born it was 184 now it's
When I was born it was 184 now it's 207
that's
that's a
that's a very
that's a very very
that's a very very major
that's a very very major change
that's a very very major change very
major
major change
it
it means
major change
it means that
it means that karmically
major change
it means that karmically you
it means that karmically you might
major change
it means that karmically you might say
the
the entire
the entire human
the entire human race
the entire human race has
the entire human race has evolved
you
you see
the entire human race has evolved
you see we're
you see we're carried
the entire human race has evolved
you see we're carried along
you see we're carried along by
the entire human race has evolved
you see we're carried along by the
you see we're carried along by the wave
of
of the
of the advance
of the advance of
of the advance of consciousness
of the advance of consciousness of
of the advance of consciousness of all
of
of mankind.
The
The karmic
The karmic potentiality
The karmic potentiality of
The karmic potentiality of humanness
itself
as
as well
as well as
as well as one's
as well as one's own
as well as one's own individual
as well as one's own individual karma.
One
One also
as well as one's own individual karma.
One also shares
One also shares sort
as well as one's own individual karma.
One also shares sort of
One also shares sort of in
as well as one's own individual karma.
One also shares sort of in ethnic
One also shares sort of in ethnic karma
uh
uh national
uh national karma.
uh national karma. If
uh national karma. If you
uh national karma. If you live
uh national karma. If you live in
uh national karma. If you live in a
certain
certain country,
uh national karma. If you live in a
certain country, you
certain country, you sort
uh national karma. If you live in a
certain country, you sort of
certain country, you sort of share
uh national karma. If you live in a
certain country, you sort of share the
fate
fate of
fate of that
fate of that whole
fate of that whole country,
fate of that whole country, don't
fate of that whole country, don't you?
When
When it
fate of that whole country, don't you?
When it goes
When it goes down,
fate of that whole country, don't you?
When it goes down, you
When it goes down, you go
fate of that whole country, don't you?
When it goes down, you go down
When it goes down, you go down with
fate of that whole country, don't you?
When it goes down, you go down with it.
So
So we
So we have
So we have a
So we have a an
So we have a an infinite
So we have a an infinite number
So we have a an infinite number of
components
to
to what
to what one
to what one would
to what one would call
to what one would call one's
to what one would call one's own
individual
individual karma.
to what one would call one's own
individual karma. It's
individual karma. It's not
to what one would call one's own
individual karma. It's not individual
but
but we
but we call
but we call it
but we call it individual.
but we call it individual. Unique
but we call it individual. Unique in
that
that certain
but we call it individual. Unique in
that certain patterns
that certain patterns peculiar
but we call it individual. Unique in
that certain patterns peculiar to
that certain patterns peculiar to your
own
own prior
own prior lifetimes
u
u are
own prior lifetimes
u are influencing
u are influencing it.
Well,
Well, let's
Well, let's just
Well, let's just reaffirm
Well, let's just reaffirm that
Well, let's just reaffirm that with
kinesiology.
Um
Um what
Um what I
Um what I just
Um what I just said
Um what I just said is
Um what I just said is a
Um what I just said is a fact
Um what I just said is a fact resist.
Okay.
Most
Most people
Most people have
Most people have lived
Most people have lived um
Most people have lived um most
Most people have lived um most people
Most people have lived um most people in
this
this room
Most people have lived um most people in
this room have
this room have lived
Most people have lived um most people in
this room have lived many
this room have lived many previous
physical
physical lifetimes.
The
The average
physical lifetimes.
The average would
The average would be
physical lifetimes.
The average would be more
The average would be more than
physical lifetimes.
The average would be more than 8,
The average would be more than 8, 12,
20,
20, 25.
20, 25. The
20, 25. The average
20, 25. The average of
20, 25. The average of lifetimes
20, 25. The average of lifetimes of
everybody
everybody in
20, 25. The average of lifetimes of
everybody in this
everybody in this room
20, 25. The average of lifetimes of
everybody in this room is
everybody in this room is about
20, 25. The average of lifetimes of
everybody in this room is about 24
everybody in this room is about 24 25
26.
26. So
26. So that's
26. So that's just
26. So that's just of
26. So that's just of academic
26. So that's just of academic interest.
Uh
Uh so
26. So that's just of academic interest.
Uh so if
Uh so if all
26. So that's just of academic interest.
Uh so if all of
Uh so if all of us
26. So that's just of academic interest.
Uh so if all of us have
Uh so if all of us have lived
26. So that's just of academic interest.
Uh so if all of us have lived an
Uh so if all of us have lived an average
of
of 24
of 24 lifetimes,
of 24 lifetimes, some
of 24 lifetimes, some people
of 24 lifetimes, some people are
of 24 lifetimes, some people are greedy
and
and live
of 24 lifetimes, some people are greedy
and live 50
and live 50 or
of 24 lifetimes, some people are greedy
and live 50 or 60
and live 50 or 60 and
of 24 lifetimes, some people are greedy
and live 50 or 60 and others
and live 50 or 60 and others have
of 24 lifetimes, some people are greedy
and live 50 or 60 and others have only
had
had four
had four or
had four or five.
Some
Some people
had four or five.
Some people are
Some people are smart
had four or five.
Some people are smart and
Some people are smart and only
had four or five.
Some people are smart and only had
Some people are smart and only had one
previous
previous lifetime
previous lifetime and
previous lifetime and this
previous lifetime and this is
previous lifetime and this is going
previous lifetime and this is going to
be
be the
previous lifetime and this is going to
be the last.
be the last. You
previous lifetime and this is going to
be the last. You know,
I
I got
I got it
I got it the
I got it the last
I got it the last time.
The
The importance
I got it the last time.
The importance of
The importance of it
I got it the last time.
The importance of it is
The importance of it is you
I got it the last time.
The importance of it is you got
The importance of it is you got it
I got it the last time.
The importance of it is you got it now.
The
The importance
The importance is
The importance is that
The importance is that we
The importance is that we have
The importance is that we have it
The importance is that we have it now.
However,
However, what
The importance is that we have it now.
However, what we're
However, what we're trying
The importance is that we have it now.
However, what we're trying to
However, what we're trying to do
The importance is that we have it now.
However, what we're trying to do is
recontextualize
recontextualize it
recontextualize it so
recontextualize it so that
recontextualize it so that way
recontextualize it so that way you
recontextualize it so that way you don't
take
take it
recontextualize it so that way you don't
take it so
take it so personally.
recontextualize it so that way you don't
take it so personally. So
take it so personally. So you
recontextualize it so that way you don't
take it so personally. So you don't
take it so personally. So you don't feel
bad
bad about
bad about it
bad about it because
bad about it because I
bad about it because I don't
bad about it because I don't like
bad about it because I don't like to
encourage
encourage people
bad about it because I don't like to
encourage people into
encourage people into spiritual
introspection
unless
the
the capacities
the capacities to
the capacities to be
the capacities to be hard
the capacities to be hard on
the capacities to be hard on yourself
the capacities to be hard on yourself is
alleviated.
alleviated. In
the capacities to be hard on yourself is
alleviated. In psychoanalysis
alleviated. In psychoanalysis the
the capacities to be hard on yourself is
alleviated. In psychoanalysis the first
rule,
rule, you
rule, you know,
rule, you know, I
rule, you know, I did
rule, you know, I did psychoanalysis
rule, you know, I did psychoanalysis and
I
I was
rule, you know, I did psychoanalysis and
I was psycho
I was psycho analyzed.
Uh
Uh the
Uh the first
Uh the first rule
Uh the first rule in
Uh the first rule in in
Uh the first rule in in psychoanalysis
was
was to
Uh the first rule in in psychoanalysis
was to approach
was to approach the
Uh the first rule in in psychoanalysis
was to approach the patient
was to approach the patient from
Uh the first rule in in psychoanalysis
was to approach the patient from the
side
side of
side of the
side of the super
side of the super ego.
side of the super ego. First
side of the super ego. First relieve
their
their excessive
side of the super ego. First relieve
their excessive punitive
their excessive punitive conscience
before
before you
before you start
before you start digging
before you start digging up
before you start digging up material
from
from the
before you start digging up material
from the unconscious.
First
First get
First get the
First get the conscience
First get the conscience to
First get the conscience to be
First get the conscience to be a
First get the conscience to be a little
bit
bit more
First get the conscience to be a little
bit more reasonable
before
before you
before you start
before you start looking
before you start looking at
ulterior
ulterior motives
before you start looking at
ulterior motives and
ulterior motives and things
before you start looking at
ulterior motives and things that
ulterior motives and things that are
repressed.
repressed. The
repressed. The reason
repressed. The reason they're
repressed. The reason they're repressed
is
is because
repressed. The reason they're repressed
is because they're
is because they're so
repressed. The reason they're repressed
is because they're so hateful
is because they're so hateful because
they
they make
they make you
they make you feel
they make you feel so
they make you feel so guilty
because
because they're
they make you feel so guilty
because they're so
because they're so awful
they make you feel so guilty
because they're so awful that
because they're so awful that you
wouldn't
wouldn't tell
wouldn't tell anybody
wouldn't tell anybody on
wouldn't tell anybody on the
wouldn't tell anybody on the planet.
wouldn't tell anybody on the planet. Now
you're
you're supposed
wouldn't tell anybody on the planet. Now
you're supposed to
you're supposed to lay
wouldn't tell anybody on the planet. Now
you're supposed to lay on
you're supposed to lay on the
wouldn't tell anybody on the planet. Now
you're supposed to lay on the couch
you're supposed to lay on the couch and
reveal
reveal them
reveal them to
reveal them to your
reveal them to your analyst.
So
the
the analyst
the analyst aligns
the analyst aligns himself
the analyst aligns himself with
the analyst aligns himself with the
person's
person's healthy
the analyst aligns himself with the
person's healthy healthy
person's healthy healthy side
the analyst aligns himself with the
person's healthy healthy side and
person's healthy healthy side and tries
to
to amilarate
the
the sadistic
to amilarate
the sadistic nature
the sadistic nature of
to amilarate
the sadistic nature of the
the sadistic nature of the super
to amilarate
the sadistic nature of the super ego.
The
The conscience
The conscience tends
The conscience tends to
The conscience tends to be
The conscience tends to be sadistic.
You
You see
The conscience tends to be sadistic.
You see that
You see that expressed
The conscience tends to be sadistic.
You see that expressed in
You see that expressed in society.
We
We don't
We don't want
We don't want to
We don't want to just
We don't want to just capture
We don't want to just capture the
We don't want to just capture the bad
people.
people. We
We don't want to just capture the bad
people. We want
people. We want to
We don't want to just capture the bad
people. We want to kill
people. We want to kill them,
exterminate
exterminate them,
exterminate them, electrocute
exterminate them, electrocute them,
exterminate them, electrocute them, and
torture
torture them
exterminate them, electrocute them, and
torture them a
torture them a little
exterminate them, electrocute them, and
torture them a little bit
torture them a little bit before
exterminate them, electrocute them, and
torture them a little bit before they
go.
Yes.
Yes. And
go.
Yes. And that's
Yes. And that's what
go.
Yes. And that's what the
Yes. And that's what the super
go.
Yes. And that's what the super ego
Yes. And that's what the super ego and
your
your That's
your That's what
your That's what your
your That's what your super
your That's what your super ego
your That's what your super ego has
your That's what your super ego has in
store
store for
your That's what your super ego has in
store for you,
store for you, folks.
That
That which
That which you
That which you would
That which you would condemn
That which you would condemn others
That which you would condemn others to
is
is exactly
That which you would condemn others to
is exactly what
is exactly what your
That which you would condemn others to
is exactly what your unconscious
condemns
condemns you
condemns you to.
You
You cannot
condemns you to.
You cannot judge
You cannot judge savagely
condemns you to.
You cannot judge savagely out
You cannot judge savagely out there
condemns you to.
You cannot judge savagely out there and
think
think that
think that when
think that when it
think that when it comes
think that when it comes up
think that when it comes up within
yourself
yourself because
think that when it comes up within
yourself because the
yourself because the super
think that when it comes up within
yourself because the super ego
yourself because the super ego will
think that when it comes up within
yourself because the super ego will not
differentiate
differentiate between
differentiate between you
differentiate between you between
differentiate between you between you
and
and others.
Stealing
Stealing a
Stealing a cookie
requires
requires death.
That's
That's the
That's the kind
That's the kind of
That's the kind of superhero
That's the kind of superhero I
That's the kind of superhero I used
That's the kind of superhero I used to
have.
have. I
That's the kind of superhero I used to
have. I mean,
have. I mean, I
That's the kind of superhero I used to
have. I mean, I know
have. I mean, I know it.
God,
God, I
God, I told
God, I told you
God, I told you about
God, I told you about the
God, I told you about the Jansen
swimsuit
swimsuit billboard.
God, I told you about the Jansen
swimsuit billboard. Good
swimsuit billboard. Good god.
only
only death
only death would.
So
So we
only death would.
So we want
So we want to
only death would.
So we want to amilarate
So we want to amilarate our
only death would.
So we want to amilarate our view
So we want to amilarate our view of
the
the world
the world and
the world and our
the world and our relationship
the world and our relationship with
the world and our relationship with the
world
world because
the world and our relationship with the
world because the
world because the world
the world and our relationship with the
world because the world is
world because the world is a
the world and our relationship with the
world because the world is a projection
of
of the
of the ego.
of the ego. The
of the ego. The savagery
of the ego. The savagery that
of the ego. The savagery that you
hold
hold against
of the ego. The savagery that you
hold against the
hold against the world
is
is nothing
is nothing but
is nothing but a
is nothing but a mirror
is nothing but a mirror that
is nothing but a mirror that you
is nothing but a mirror that you hold
against
against yourself.
Now
Now you
Now you must
Now you must have
Now you must have very
Now you must have very severe
Now you must have very severe things
that
that you're
Now you must have very severe things
that you're holding
that you're holding against
Now you must have very severe things
that you're holding against yourself.
Otherwise,
everyone
everyone would
Otherwise,
everyone would become
everyone would become enlightened.
Realize
Realize that
Realize that the
Realize that the self,
Realize that the self, the
Realize that the self, the source
Realize that the self, the source of
that
that which
Realize that the self, the source of
that which is
that which is listening
Realize that the self, the source of
that which is listening right
that which is listening right now
Realize that the self, the source of
that which is listening right now is
God.
Everybody
Everybody just
God.
Everybody just became
Everybody just became enlightened.
Some
Some of
Some of you
Some of you didn't
Some of you didn't accept
Some of you didn't accept it.
No.
Why
Why not?
Maybe
Maybe we
Why not?
Maybe we should
Maybe we should try
Why not?
Maybe we should try it
Maybe we should try it the
Why not?
Maybe we should try it the other
Maybe we should try it the other way.
Anyone
Anyone who
Anyone who doesn't
Anyone who doesn't completely
Anyone who doesn't completely totally
surrender
surrender to
Anyone who doesn't completely totally
surrender to God
surrender to God right
Anyone who doesn't completely totally
surrender to God right now,
surrender to God right now, we
Anyone who doesn't completely totally
surrender to God right now, we shall
elect what electrocute.
So
So I'll
elect what electrocute.
So I'll let
So I'll let go.
Okay.
So
So spiritual
Okay.
So spiritual work
So spiritual work is
Okay.
So spiritual work is becoming
So spiritual work is becoming acquainted
with
with the
with the subtleties.
The
The subtleties.
You
You become
You become aware
You become aware of
You become aware of it
You become aware of it subtly.
You become aware of it subtly. And
You become aware of it subtly. And now
the
the question
You become aware of it subtly. And now
the question is
the question is how
You become aware of it subtly. And now
the question is how to
the question is how to approach
You become aware of it subtly. And now
the question is how to approach it.
the question is how to approach it. how
to
to approach
to approach it,
to approach it, how
to approach it, how to
to approach it, how to undo
to approach it, how to undo that
propensity
without
without going
without going into
without going into excessive
without going into excessive guilt
without going into excessive guilt about
it.
You
You can't
You can't go
You can't go into
You can't go into squirming,
hair,
hair, shirt,
You can't go into squirming,
hair, shirt, self-
hair, shirt, self- torture
You can't go into squirming,
hair, shirt, self- torture over
hair, shirt, self- torture over every
indelicate
indelicate comment
indelicate comment you
indelicate comment you might
indelicate comment you might have
indelicate comment you might have made
off
off hand.
I
I tend
I tend to
I tend to but
after
after a
I tend to but
after a while
after a while you'll
I tend to but
after a while you'll see
after a while you'll see that
I tend to but
after a while you'll see that it's
after a while you'll see that it's an
indulgence.
Excessive
Excessive guilt
indulgence.
Excessive guilt is
Excessive guilt is just
indulgence.
Excessive guilt is just another
indulgence,
indulgence, another
indulgence, another indulgence.
It's
It's another
indulgence, another indulgence.
It's another addiction.
It's another addiction. It's
indulgence, another indulgence.
It's another addiction. It's another
spiritual
spiritual error
spiritual error too.
So
So one
spiritual error too.
So one has
So one has to
spiritual error too.
So one has to surrender
So one has to surrender one's
spiritual error too.
So one has to surrender one's sense
So one has to surrender one's sense of
guilt
guilt and
guilt and self-punitive
guilt and self-punitive quality
guilt and self-punitive quality to
guilt and self-punitive quality to God.
The
The willingness
guilt and self-punitive quality to God.
The willingness to
The willingness to surrender
self-punitive
self-hatred
guilt
guilt and
guilt and shame.
The
The next
guilt and shame.
The next block
The next block that
guilt and shame.
The next block that comes
The next block that comes up
guilt and shame.
The next block that comes up when
The next block that comes up when you
try
try to
try to do
try to do that
try to do that is
try to do that is that
try to do that is that there's
try to do that is that there's a
try to do that is that there's a belief
system
system especially
try to do that is that there's a belief
system especially arising
system especially arising out
try to do that is that there's a belief
system especially arising out of
Christianity
that
that the
Christianity
that the only
that the only propitiation
Christianity
that the only propitiation for
that the only propitiation for sin
Christianity
that the only propitiation for sin is
suffering.
And
And you'll
suffering.
And you'll find
And you'll find that
suffering.
And you'll find that the
And you'll find that the real
suffering.
And you'll find that the real Christian
is
is really
is really addicted
is really addicted to
is really addicted to suffering.
They
They are.
is really addicted to suffering.
They are. They
They are. They are.
is really addicted to suffering.
They are. They are. And
They are. They are. And the
is really addicted to suffering.
They are. They are. And the way
They are. They are. And the way to
is really addicted to suffering.
They are. They are. And the way to God
is
is through
is through suffering,
is through suffering, penance,
crawling
crawling through
is through suffering, penance,
crawling through the
crawling through the streets
is through suffering, penance,
crawling through the streets of
crawling through the streets of the
is through suffering, penance,
crawling through the streets of the city
on
on over
on over the
on over the cobblestones
on over the cobblestones with
on over the cobblestones with the
on over the cobblestones with the blood
running
running out
on over the cobblestones with the blood
running out of
running out of your
on over the cobblestones with the blood
running out of your knees,
not
not eating,
not eating, not
not eating, not taking
not eating, not taking a
not eating, not taking a bath,
crawling
crawling from
not eating, not taking a bath,
crawling from here
crawling from here to
some
some holy
some holy place.
Penance,
Penance, suffering,
some holy place.
Penance, suffering, pain
Penance, suffering, pain than
some holy place.
Penance, suffering, pain than our
addictions,
addictions, their
addictions, their excesses.
their
their indulgences
addictions, their excesses.
their indulgences that
their indulgences that one
addictions, their excesses.
their indulgences that one has
their indulgences that one has to
addictions, their excesses.
their indulgences that one has to be
willing
willing to
willing to surrender
willing to surrender to
willing to surrender to God.
That
That which
willing to surrender to God.
That which is
That which is the
willing to surrender to God.
That which is the infinite
That which is the infinite source
willing to surrender to God.
That which is the infinite source of
That which is the infinite source of all
of
of creation
of creation is
not
not impressed
of creation is
not impressed by
not impressed by bleeding
of creation is
not impressed by bleeding knees,
self
self flagagillation,
self flagagillation, burning
self flagagillation, burning off
self flagagillation, burning off your
fingers
fingers and
self flagagillation, burning off your
fingers and toes,
fingers and toes, chopping
self flagagillation, burning off your
fingers and toes, chopping off
fingers and toes, chopping off your
thumb,
other
other insanities,
spiritual
spiritual insanity.
spiritual insanity. So
the
the total
spiritual insanity. So
the total you
the total you know
spiritual insanity. So
the total you know the
the total you know the totality
spiritual insanity. So
the total you know the totality of
the total you know the totality of all
of
of creation
of creation now
shines
shines forth
of creation now
shines forth as
shines forth as one's
of creation now
shines forth as one's existence
shines forth as one's existence at
of creation now
shines forth as one's existence at this
moment
and
and as
moment
and as a
and as a result
moment
and as a result of
and as a result of karmic
moment
and as a result of karmic propensities.
One
One is
One is at
One is at this
One is at this particular
One is at this particular point
One is at this particular point in
One is at this particular point in some
kind
kind of
One is at this particular point in some
kind of a
kind of a purgatorial
realm
realm where
realm where the
realm where the opportunity
realm where the opportunity to
realm where the opportunity to transcend
all
all that
realm where the opportunity to transcend
all that is
all that is present
realm where the opportunity to transcend
all that is present at
all that is present at all
realm where the opportunity to transcend
all that is present at all times
in
in a
in a true
in a true purgatory.
in a true purgatory. Then
in a true purgatory. Then you
in a true purgatory. Then you get
in a true purgatory. Then you get to
undo
undo the
in a true purgatory. Then you get to
undo the negatives
undo the negatives of
in a true purgatory. Then you get to
undo the negatives of the
undo the negatives of the past
and
and choose
and choose the
and choose the positive.
and choose the positive. You
and choose the positive. You get
and choose the positive. You get a
chance
chance to
and choose the positive. You get a
chance to undo.
We've
We've got
We've got ministers
We've got ministers here
We've got ministers here who
We've got ministers here who are
authorities
authorities on
We've got ministers here who are
authorities on purgatory.
authorities on purgatory. I'm
We've got ministers here who are
authorities on purgatory. I'm not
authority
authority on
authority on purgatory.
authority on purgatory. It
authority on purgatory. It just
authority on purgatory. It just has
always
always seemed
authority on purgatory. It just has
always seemed to
always seemed to me
authority on purgatory. It just has
always seemed to me that
always seemed to me that in
authority on purgatory. It just has
always seemed to me that in a
always seemed to me that in a domain
where
where you
where you can
where you can go
where you can go from
where you can go from the
where you can go from the most
where you can go from the most horid
where you can go from the most horid to
the
the most
where you can go from the most horid to
the most exquisite
that
that that
that that that
that that that is
that that that is really
that that that is really the
that that that is really the nature
that that that is really the nature of
purgatory.
purgatory. Limbo
that that that is really the nature of
purgatory. Limbo is
purgatory. Limbo is where
that that that is really the nature of
purgatory. Limbo is where you
purgatory. Limbo is where you just
that that that is really the nature of
purgatory. Limbo is where you just hang
out
out and
out and and
out and and wait
out and and wait to
out and and wait to go
out and and wait to go one
out and and wait to go one place
out and and wait to go one place or
another.
another. I'm
out and and wait to go one place or
another. I'm trying
another. I'm trying to
out and and wait to go one place or
another. I'm trying to remember
another. I'm trying to remember Catholic
theology.
Limbo
Limbo is
theology.
Limbo is where
Limbo is where you
theology.
Limbo is where you sort
Limbo is where you sort of
theology.
Limbo is where you sort of hang
Limbo is where you sort of hang out.
theology.
Limbo is where you sort of hang out. You
don't
don't go
don't go one
don't go one place
don't go one place or
don't go one place or another.
don't go one place or another. You
don't go one place or another. You sort
of
of mark
don't go one place or another. You sort
of mark in
of mark in time
don't go one place or another. You sort
of mark in time or
of mark in time or something.
don't go one place or another. You sort
of mark in time or something. Purgatory,
you
you get
you get a
you get a chance
you get a chance to
you get a chance to undo
you get a chance to undo your
you get a chance to undo your errors
you get a chance to undo your errors and
earn
earn your
you get a chance to undo your errors and
earn your way
earn your way into
you get a chance to undo your errors and
earn your way into higher
earn your way into higher dimensions.
The
The heavens
The heavens are
The heavens are then
The heavens are then the
The heavens are then the consequence
The heavens are then the consequence of
having
having undone
the
the required
the required amount
the required amount of
the required amount of negative
the required amount of negative karma
that
that one's
the required amount of negative karma
that one's consciousness
that one's consciousness level
the required amount of negative karma
that one's consciousness level is
that one's consciousness level is now
consistent
consistent with
consistent with more
consistent with more heavenly
consistent with more heavenly domains.
We
We get
consistent with more heavenly domains.
We get from
We get from research
consistent with more heavenly domains.
We get from research that
consciousness
consciousness that
consciousness that that
consciousness that that that
consciousness that that that we
consciousness that that that we need
consciousness that that that we need a
savior
savior below
consciousness that that that we need a
savior below levels
savior below levels of
consciousness that that that we need a
savior below levels of 600.
savior below levels of 600. Let's
consciousness that that that we need a
savior below levels of 600. Let's see.
Entities
Entities who
Entities who u
Entities who u leave
Entities who u leave the
Entities who u leave the body
Entities who u leave the body less
Entities who u leave the body less than
600 require
600 require the
Entities who u leave the body less than
600 require the intervention
600 require the intervention of
Entities who u leave the body less than
600 require the intervention of a
600 require the intervention of a savior
to
to enter
to enter heaven.
Yeah.
Yeah. All
to enter heaven.
Yeah. All right.
Yeah. All right. So
to enter heaven.
Yeah. All right. So a
Yeah. All right. So a savior,
to enter heaven.
Yeah. All right. So a savior, a
Yeah. All right. So a savior, a guru,
to enter heaven.
Yeah. All right. So a savior, a guru, a
higher
higher teaching
higher teaching is
higher teaching is necessary.
The
The ancient
higher teaching is necessary.
The ancient uh
The ancient uh the
higher teaching is necessary.
The ancient uh the ancient
The ancient uh the ancient um
higher teaching is necessary.
The ancient uh the ancient um wisdom
The ancient uh the ancient um wisdom is
that
that without
that without the
that without the assistance
that without the assistance of
that without the assistance of higher
truth
truth from
that without the assistance of higher
truth from whatever
truth from whatever its
that without the assistance of higher
truth from whatever its source,
truth from whatever its source, the
likelihood
likelihood is
likelihood is that
likelihood is that unaded
likelihood is that unaded the
likelihood is that unaded the individual
lacks
lacks sufficient
likelihood is that unaded the individual
lacks sufficient spiritual
lacks sufficient spiritual power
likelihood is that unaded the individual
lacks sufficient spiritual power to
overcome
overcome the
overcome the ego.
overcome the ego. That
overcome the ego. That makes
overcome the ego. That makes the
overcome the ego. That makes the ego
sound
sound quite
overcome the ego. That makes the ego
sound quite formidable,
sound quite formidable, doesn't
overcome the ego. That makes the ego
sound quite formidable, doesn't it?
sound quite formidable, doesn't it? God,
I'm
I'm scared
I'm scared of
I'm scared of the
I'm scared of the ego.
I'm scared of the ego. I'm
I'm scared of the ego. I'm sorry
I'm scared of the ego. I'm sorry I
I'm scared of the ego. I'm sorry I said
that.
That's
That's a
That's a fact.
All
All right.
That's a fact.
All right. So
All right. So just
That's a fact.
All right. So just spiritual
All right. So just spiritual truth
That's a fact.
All right. So just spiritual truth such
as
as knowledge
as knowledge in
as knowledge in itself
as knowledge in itself has
as knowledge in itself has a
as knowledge in itself has a has
as knowledge in itself has a has the
as knowledge in itself has a has the the
intrinsic
intrinsic action
as knowledge in itself has a has the the
intrinsic action of
intrinsic action of a
as knowledge in itself has a has the the
intrinsic action of a guru
intrinsic action of a guru exist.
as knowledge in itself has a has the the
intrinsic action of a guru exist. The
truth
truth itself.
truth itself. Okay.
truth itself. Okay. To
truth itself. Okay. To to
truth itself. Okay. To to merely
truth itself. Okay. To to merely hear
the
the truth
truth itself. Okay. To to merely hear
the truth already
the truth already has
the
the effect
the effect of
the effect of the
the effect of the blessing
the effect of the blessing of
the effect of the blessing of the
the effect of the blessing of the guru
is
is this.
the effect of the blessing of the guru
is this. Okay.
is this. Okay. Okay.
All right.
All right. So
All right. So to
All right. So to merely
All right. So to merely hear,
All right. So to merely hear, to
All right. So to merely hear, to merely
know
know certain
All right. So to merely hear, to merely
know certain things
know certain things is
All right. So to merely hear, to merely
know certain things is already
elevating,
elevating, already
elevating, already advances
elevating, already advances one's
consciousness
has
has a
has a catalytic
has a catalytic effect.
Sometimes
Sometimes just
has a catalytic effect.
Sometimes just one
Sometimes just one little
has a catalytic effect.
Sometimes just one little piece
Sometimes just one little piece of
information
information like
information like solves
information like solves all
information like solves all kinds
information like solves all kinds of
little
little things
information like solves all kinds of
little things in
little things in the
information like solves all kinds of
little things in the puzzle.
little things in the puzzle. They
information like solves all kinds of
little things in the puzzle. They all
make
make sense.
make sense. Sometimes
make sense. Sometimes karmic
make sense. Sometimes karmic research
does
does that.
make sense. Sometimes karmic research
does that. comically
does that. comically search
make sense. Sometimes karmic research
does that. comically search back
does that. comically search back and
make sense. Sometimes karmic research
does that. comically search back and you
find
find some
find some single
find some single event
find some single event or
find some single event or collection
find some single event or collection of
events
events or
find some single event or collection of
events or propensities
events or propensities in
find some single event or collection of
events or propensities in certain
lifetimes.
Uh
Uh and
lifetimes.
Uh and and
Uh and and now
lifetimes.
Uh and and now you
Uh and and now you see
lifetimes.
Uh and and now you see that
Uh and and now you see that over
lifetimes.
Uh and and now you see that over and
over
over again
over again you're
over again you're asked
over again you're asked to
over again you're asked to go
over again you're asked to go to
transcend
transcend that
over again you're asked to go to
transcend that to
transcend that to transcend
over again you're asked to go to
transcend that to transcend that
transcend that to transcend that to
transcend
transcend that
transcend that to
transcend that to value
money
money over
transcend that to value
money over life.
Okay.
In
In the
Okay.
In the lifetime
In the lifetime I'm
Okay.
In the lifetime I'm thinking
In the lifetime I'm thinking of
Okay.
In the lifetime I'm thinking of I
In the lifetime I'm thinking of I valued
money
money over
money over life
money over life which
money over life which is
money over life which is greed
money over life which is greed over
life.
Yeah.
to
to let
Yeah.
to let people
to let people die
Yeah.
to let people die out
to let people die out of
Yeah.
to let people die out of greed.
to let people die out of greed. To
Yeah.
to let people die out of greed. To to
value
value gain,
value gain, greed,
value gain, greed, money,
value gain, greed, money, treasure
over
over the
value gain, greed, money, treasure
over the value
over the value of
value gain, greed, money, treasure
over the value of human
over the value of human life,
value gain, greed, money, treasure
over the value of human life, to
sacrifice
sacrifice human
sacrifice human life
sacrifice human life for
sacrifice human life for money.
sacrifice human life for money. So
that's
that's a
sacrifice human life for money. So
that's a pretty
that's a pretty common
sacrifice human life for money. So
that's a pretty common one,
that's a pretty common one, right?
Anybody
Anybody who's
Anybody who's lived
Anybody who's lived before
Anybody who's lived before is
Anybody who's lived before is likely
have
have done
Anybody who's lived before is likely
have done that,
have done that, right?
Why?
Why? Because
Why? Because human
Why? Because human consciousness
Why? Because human consciousness has
evolved
evolved from
Why? Because human consciousness has
evolved from the
evolved from the animal
Why? Because human consciousness has
evolved from the animal kingdom.
Unless
Unless you're
Unless you're a
Unless you're a greedy
Unless you're a greedy animal,
Unless you're a greedy animal, you
really
really don't
Unless you're a greedy animal, you
really don't survive.
really don't survive. How
Unless you're a greedy animal, you
really don't survive. How long
really don't survive. How long does
Unless you're a greedy animal, you
really don't survive. How long does an
altruistic
altruistic animal
altruistic animal survive?
Here,
Here, Hubert,
altruistic animal survive?
Here, Hubert, you
Here, Hubert, you can
altruistic animal survive?
Here, Hubert, you can have
Here, Hubert, you can have my
altruistic animal survive?
Here, Hubert, you can have my bone.
And
And if
And if there's
And if there's any
And if there's any left,
And if there's any left, I'll
And if there's any left, I'll have
what's
what's left.
I'm
I'm sorry.
Well,
Well, you
I'm sorry.
Well, you get
Well, you get smaller
I'm sorry.
Well, you get smaller and
Well, you get smaller and smaller
I'm sorry.
Well, you get smaller and smaller and
finally
finally you
finally you follow
finally you follow her.
Uh,
so
so our
so our first
so our first commitment
so our first commitment is
so our first commitment is to
so our first commitment is to be
so our first commitment is to be a
so our first commitment is to be a good
animal.
animal. A
so our first commitment is to be a good
animal. A good
animal. A good animal,
so our first commitment is to be a good
animal. A good animal, you
animal. A good animal, you have
so our first commitment is to be a good
animal. A good animal, you have to
animal. A good animal, you have to have
a
a certain
a certain gusto
a certain gusto for
a certain gusto for life
and
and a
a certain gusto for life
and a certain
and a certain love
a certain gusto for life
and a certain love of
and a certain love of life
a certain gusto for life
and a certain love of life and
enthusiasm
enthusiasm for
enthusiasm for life.
enthusiasm for life. You
enthusiasm for life. You got
enthusiasm for life. You got to
enthusiasm for life. You got to have
enthusiasm for life. You got to have the
capacity
capacity to
enthusiasm for life. You got to have the
capacity to get
capacity to get in
enthusiasm for life. You got to have the
capacity to get in there
capacity to get in there and
enthusiasm for life. You got to have the
capacity to get in there and walk.
There's
There's times
There's times when
There's times when you
There's times when you got
There's times when you got to
There's times when you got to do
There's times when you got to do that.
That's
That's the
There's times when you got to do that.
That's the only
That's the only spiritual
There's times when you got to do that.
That's the only spiritual thing
That's the only spiritual thing you
There's times when you got to do that.
That's the only spiritual thing you can
do.
Feeble
Feeble monks
do.
Feeble monks aren't
Feeble monks aren't worth
do.
Feeble monks aren't worth a
Feeble monks aren't worth a nickel.
I'm
I'm praying.
Get
Get off
I'm praying.
Get off your
Get off your knees,
I'm praying.
Get off your knees, old
Get off your knees, old man.
I'm praying.
Get off your knees, old man. Sweep
Get off your knees, old man. Sweep the
floor.
floor. Don't
floor. Don't you
floor. Don't you see
floor. Don't you see all
floor. Don't you see all the
floor. Don't you see all the crap
floor. Don't you see all the crap around
here?
So,
one
one of
So,
one of my
one of my missions
So,
one of my missions was
one of my missions was um
one
one of
one of my
one of my secret
one of my secret ambitions
one of my secret ambitions I'll
one of my secret ambitions I'll have
one of my secret ambitions I'll have to
let
let go.
one of my secret ambitions I'll have to
let go. It
let go. It was
one of my secret ambitions I'll have to
let go. It was to
let go. It was to be
one of my secret ambitions I'll have to
let go. It was to be a
let go. It was to be a verger
one of my secret ambitions I'll have to
let go. It was to be a verger in
let go. It was to be a verger in a
one of my secret ambitions I'll have to
let go. It was to be a verger in a great
cathedral.
Can
Can you
cathedral.
Can you imagine?
Can you imagine? You
cathedral.
Can you imagine? You know,
Can you imagine? You know, you're
cathedral.
Can you imagine? You know, you're the
janitor.
janitor. You
janitor. You don't
janitor. You don't have
janitor. You don't have to
janitor. You don't have to talk
janitor. You don't have to talk to
anybody,
anybody, say
janitor. You don't have to talk to
anybody, say anything
anybody, say anything to
janitor. You don't have to talk to
anybody, say anything to anybody.
People
People are
People are idiotic.
People are idiotic. You
People are idiotic. You don't
People are idiotic. You don't have
People are idiotic. You don't have to
listen
listen to
People are idiotic. You don't have to
listen to their
listen to their paddle.
You
You get
You get to
You get to hear
You get to hear the
You get to hear the choir
You get to hear the choir practicing
Thursday
Thursday nights,
You get to hear the choir practicing
Thursday nights, Wednesday
Thursday nights, Wednesday nights.
You get to hear the choir practicing
Thursday nights, Wednesday nights. You
get
get to
get to live
get to live around
get to live around incense,
stained
stained glass
get to live around incense,
stained glass windows,
stained glass windows, incredible
sculpture,
sculpture, incredible
sculpture, incredible beauty.
It's
It's the
sculpture, incredible beauty.
It's the way
It's the way to
sculpture, incredible beauty.
It's the way to God.
I
I think
I think God
I think God is
I think God is jealous
I think God is jealous of
I think God is jealous of the
keeps
keeps the
I think God is jealous of the
keeps the job
keeps the job of
I think God is jealous of the
keeps the job of janitor
keeps the job of janitor in
I think God is jealous of the
keeps the job of janitor in the
keeps the job of janitor in the great
cathedral
for
for his
cathedral
for his favorite
for his favorite ones.
If
If I'm
If I'm going
If I'm going to
If I'm going to have
If I'm going to have another
If I'm going to have another lifetime,
I'd
I'd like
If I'm going to have another lifetime,
I'd like to
I'd like to be
If I'm going to have another lifetime,
I'd like to be a
I'd like to be a verger
If I'm going to have another lifetime,
I'd like to be a verger and
I'd like to be a verger and a
If I'm going to have another lifetime,
I'd like to be a verger and a great
I'd like to be a verger and a great no
one
cuz
cuz then
one
cuz then by
cuz then by then
one
cuz then by then I'll
cuz then by then I'll have
one
cuz then by then I'll have all
cuz then by then I'll have all kinds
one
cuz then by then I'll have all kinds of
regulations.
fingerprint
fingerprint register
fingerprint register and
fingerprint register and uh
fingerprint register and uh you
fingerprint register and uh you know
fingerprint register and uh you know I
mean
mean you'll
fingerprint register and uh you know I
mean you'll have
mean you'll have ver
fingerprint register and uh you know I
mean you'll have ver vger
mean you'll have ver vger regs
fingerprint register and uh you know I
mean you'll have ver vger regs coming
out
out from
out from the
out from the welfare
out from the welfare department
so
so the
out from the welfare department
so the day
so the day of
out from the welfare department
so the day of the
so the day of the vir
out from the welfare department
so the day of the vir cathedral
so the day of the vir cathedral is
out from the welfare department
so the day of the vir cathedral is over
to
to see
to see that's
to see that's a
to see that's a oh
to see that's a oh I
to see that's a oh I see
to see that's a oh I see what
to see that's a oh I see what that
to see that's a oh I see what that is
that's
that's an
to see that's a oh I see what that is
that's an attachment
that's an attachment to
to see that's a oh I see what that is
that's an attachment to a
that's an attachment to a previous
lifetimehu
thank
thank you
all
all right
all right so
all right so that
all right so that hankering
all right so that hankering which
all right so that hankering which came
up
up this
all right so that hankering which came
up this morning.
up this morning. The
all right so that hankering which came
up this morning. The minute
up this morning. The minute I
all right so that hankering which came
up this morning. The minute I hear
up this morning. The minute I hear that
music,
music, it
music, it throws
music, it throws me
music, it throws me into
music, it throws me into the
music, it throws me into the ecstasy
music, it throws me into the ecstasy of
beauty,
beauty, you
music, it throws me into the ecstasy of
beauty, you know,
beauty, you know, which
music, it throws me into the ecstasy of
beauty, you know, which is
beauty, you know, which is a
music, it throws me into the ecstasy of
beauty, you know, which is a very
beauty, you know, which is a very rapid
pathway
pathway to
pathway to God.
When
When you
pathway to God.
When you because
When you because to
pathway to God.
When you because to just
When you because to just immerse
pathway to God.
When you because to just immerse oneself
in
in beauty,
the
the oneness
in beauty,
the oneness of
the oneness of beauty
in beauty,
the oneness of beauty and
the oneness of beauty and God
in beauty,
the oneness of beauty and God and
the oneness of beauty and God and the
self
self suddenly
the
the barriers
self suddenly
the barriers dissolve.
the barriers dissolve. One
self suddenly
the barriers dissolve. One is
the barriers dissolve. One is all
self suddenly
the barriers dissolve. One is all of
God.
So
just
just as
just as aversions
just as aversions come
just as aversions come from
just as aversions come from past
lifetimes
when
when I
when I heard
when I heard that
when I heard that music
when I heard that music I
when I heard that music I longed
when I heard that music I longed uh
when I heard that music I longed uh I
could
could feel
when I heard that music I longed uh I
could feel the
could feel the longing
for
for that
for that lifetime
for that lifetime to
for that lifetime to be
for that lifetime to be a
for that lifetime to be a vger.
for that lifetime to be a vger. I
for that lifetime to be a vger. I didn't
realize
realize a
for that lifetime to be a vger. I didn't
realize a previous
realize a previous lifetime
for that lifetime to be a vger. I didn't
realize a previous lifetime I
realize a previous lifetime I thought
for that lifetime to be a vger. I didn't
realize a previous lifetime I thought it
was
was a
was a fantasy
was a fantasy lifetime
to
to be
was a fantasy lifetime
to be the
to be the virgin
was a fantasy lifetime
to be the virgin in
to be the virgin in a
was a fantasy lifetime
to be the virgin in a great
to be the virgin in a great cathedral.
And
And of
And of course
And of course when
And of course when I
And of course when I go
And of course when I go to
And of course when I go to Europe
And of course when I go to Europe I
And of course when I go to Europe I go
from
from cathedral
And of course when I go to Europe I go
from cathedral to
from cathedral to cathedral.
Some
Some people
Some people go
Some people go from
Some people go from Berlin
Some people go from Berlin to
Some people go from Berlin to Paris
Some people go from Berlin to Paris to
London.
London. I
Some people go from Berlin to Paris to
London. I just
London. I just go
Some people go from Berlin to Paris to
London. I just go from
London. I just go from St.
Some people go from Berlin to Paris to
London. I just go from St. Pat's,
London. I just go from St. Pat's, you
know,
know, one
know, one cathedral
know, one cathedral to
know, one cathedral to another.
know, one cathedral to another. Um,
know, one cathedral to another. Um, so
that
that attachment
know, one cathedral to another. Um, so
that attachment to
that attachment to cathedrals
know, one cathedral to another. Um, so
that attachment to cathedrals um
that attachment to cathedrals um to
know, one cathedral to another. Um, so
that attachment to cathedrals um to be
of
of silent
of silent service
of silent service to
of silent service to God
in
in the
of silent service to God
in the presence
in the presence of
of silent service to God
in the presence of that
in the presence of that beauty
of silent service to God
in the presence of that beauty as
in the presence of that beauty as a
of silent service to God
in the presence of that beauty as a form
of
of worship
uh
is
is an
is an attachment.
So
So the
is an attachment.
So the karma
So the karma then
is an attachment.
So the karma then plays
So the karma then plays a
is an attachment.
So the karma then plays a part
So the karma then plays a part in
is an attachment.
So the karma then plays a part in our
ambitions,
our
daydreams,
our the
our the limitation
daydreams,
our the limitation of
our the limitation of what
daydreams,
our the limitation of what we
our the limitation of what we think
daydreams,
our the limitation of what we think we
can
can be
can be or
can be or accomplish
can be or accomplish in
can be or accomplish in this
can be or accomplish in this lifetime.
Obviously
Obviously people
can be or accomplish in this lifetime.
Obviously people in
Obviously people in a
can be or accomplish in this lifetime.
Obviously people in a group
Obviously people in a group like
can be or accomplish in this lifetime.
Obviously people in a group like this
have
have heard
have heard uh
have heard uh the
have heard uh the have
have heard uh the have responded
have heard uh the have responded to
have heard uh the have responded to that
which
which with
have heard uh the have responded to that
which with within
which with within them
have heard uh the have responded to that
which with within them is
which with within them is telling
have heard uh the have responded to that
which with within them is telling them
that
that the
that the pathway
that the pathway to
that the pathway to spiritual
that the pathway to spiritual evolution
is
is theirs.
that the pathway to spiritual evolution
is theirs. So
is theirs. So people
that the pathway to spiritual evolution
is theirs. So people in
is theirs. So people in a
that the pathway to spiritual evolution
is theirs. So people in a room
is theirs. So people in a room like
that the pathway to spiritual evolution
is theirs. So people in a room like this
have
have already
have already evolved
have already evolved to
have already evolved to an
have already evolved to an incredibly
advanced
advanced degree.
have already evolved to an incredibly
advanced degree. Advanced
advanced degree. Advanced degree.
Advanced
Advanced degree.
We
We said
Advanced degree.
We said that
We said that only
Advanced degree.
We said that only 4%
We said that only 4% of
Advanced degree.
We said that only 4% of the
We said that only 4% of the world's
population
population ever
population ever gets
population ever gets over
population ever gets over the
population ever gets over the 400s.
population ever gets over the 400s. 4%
let's
let's see
population ever gets over the 400s. 4%
let's see gets
let's see gets over
population ever gets over the 400s. 4%
let's see gets over only
let's see gets over only only
population ever gets over the 400s. 4%
let's see gets over only only 4%
let's see gets over only only 4% get
population ever gets over the 400s. 4%
let's see gets over only only 4% get out
are
are able
are able to
are able to transcend
are able to transcend logic
are able to transcend logic logic
are able to transcend logic logic and
reason.
So
So although
So although this
So although this is
So although this is the
So although this is the crown
So although this is the crown jewel,
logic
logic and
So although this is the crown jewel,
logic and reason
logic and reason is
So although this is the crown jewel,
logic and reason is the
logic and reason is the alleged
So although this is the crown jewel,
logic and reason is the alleged crown
jewel
jewel of
jewel of man.
You
You know,
the
the difference
the difference between
the difference between men
the difference between men and
the difference between men and animals
is
is that
the difference between men and animals
is that men
is that men can
the difference between men and animals
is that men can think.
is that men can think. Yeah.
the difference between men and animals
is that men can think. Yeah. Right.
Uh
this
this is
Uh
this is supposedly
this is supposedly the
Uh
this is supposedly the crown
this is supposedly the crown jewel
Uh
this is supposedly the crown jewel of
man
man from
man from the
man from the viewpoint
man from the viewpoint of
man from the viewpoint of education.
um
um the
man from the viewpoint of education.
um the viewpoint
um the viewpoint of
man from the viewpoint of education.
um the viewpoint of the
um the viewpoint of the social
man from the viewpoint of education.
um the viewpoint of the social social
evolution,
the
the capacity
evolution,
the capacity to
the capacity to think
evolution,
the capacity to think and
the capacity to think and reason
to
to um
to um be
to um be able
to um be able to
to um be able to develop
to um be able to develop science
to um be able to develop science and
to um be able to develop science and all
the
the great
to um be able to develop science and all
the great benefits
the great benefits of
to um be able to develop science and all
the great benefits of science.
the great benefits of science. So
to um be able to develop science and all
the great benefits of science. So the
400s
400s are
400s are enormously
400s are enormously beneficial.
400s are enormously beneficial. Without
the
the 400s,
400s are enormously beneficial. Without
the 400s, half
the 400s, half of
400s are enormously beneficial. Without
the 400s, half of us
the 400s, half of us wouldn't
400s are enormously beneficial. Without
the 400s, half of us wouldn't be
the 400s, half of us wouldn't be in
400s are enormously beneficial. Without
the 400s, half of us wouldn't be in this
room.
room. We
room. We would
room. We would have
room. We would have died
room. We would have died of
things
things that
room. We would have died of
things that we
things that we now
room. We would have died of
things that we now cure
things that we now cure with
room. We would have died of
things that we now cure with penicellin
and
and streptoy
and streptoy and
and streptoy and surgery
and streptoy and surgery and
and streptoy and surgery and many
and streptoy and surgery and many other
things.
So
So reason
So reason is
So reason is the
So reason is the great
So reason is the great salvation
So reason is the great salvation from
the
the animal
So reason is the great salvation from
the animal world.
So
So down
So down here
So down here we're
So down here we're stuck
So down here we're stuck in
So down here we're stuck in the
So down here we're stuck in the animal
world.
world. Then
So down here we're stuck in the animal
world. Then we
world. Then we transcend
So down here we're stuck in the animal
world. Then we transcend into
world. Then we transcend into humanness
and
and with
and with the
and with the exception
and with the exception of
and with the exception of kitties
and with the exception of kitties and
dogs.
We
We somehow
We somehow passed
We somehow passed us
We somehow passed us by.
We somehow passed us by. I
We somehow passed us by. I don't
We somehow passed us by. I don't know
how
how they
We somehow passed us by. I don't know
how they got
how they got up
We somehow passed us by. I don't know
how they got up there.
We
We we
We we hit
We we hit willingness.
We we hit willingness. See
We we hit willingness. See willingness
is
is different
We we hit willingness. See willingness
is different than
is different than ambition.
We we hit willingness. See willingness
is different than ambition. Ambition
will
will get
will get you
will get you through
will get you through medical
will get you through medical school.
You
You got
will get you through medical school.
You got to
You got to be
will get you through medical school.
You got to be a
You got to be a workhorse.
will get you through medical school.
You got to be a workhorse. But
You got to be a workhorse. But to
will get you through medical school.
You got to be a workhorse. But to be
You got to be a workhorse. But to be a
good
good doctor
good doctor takes
good doctor takes something
good doctor takes something else.
good doctor takes something else. Takes
willingness
willingness will
good doctor takes something else. Takes
willingness will then
willingness will then it
good doctor takes something else. Takes
willingness will then it takes
willingness will then it takes something
different.
different. Willingness,
different. Willingness, acceptance,
and
and uh
different. Willingness, acceptance,
and uh easygoingness
and uh easygoingness and
different. Willingness, acceptance,
and uh easygoingness and then
and uh easygoingness and then finally
different. Willingness, acceptance,
and uh easygoingness and then finally an
unconditional
unconditional compassion
unconditional compassion for
unconditional compassion for human
suffering.
But
But those
But those are
But those are beyond
But those are beyond reason.
But
But in
But those are beyond reason.
But in a
But in a group
But those are beyond reason.
But in a group like
But in a group like this,
But those are beyond reason.
But in a group like this, we
But in a group like this, we know
But those are beyond reason.
But in a group like this, we know that
because
because of
because of one's
because of one's karmic
because of one's karmic propensity
because of one's karmic propensity that
one
one is
because of one's karmic propensity that
one is evolved
one is evolved up
because of one's karmic propensity that
one is evolved up into
one is evolved up into the
because of one's karmic propensity that
one is evolved up into the 400s.
one is evolved up into the 400s. In
because of one's karmic propensity that
one is evolved up into the 400s. In the
400s
400s we
400s we read,
400s we read, we
400s we read, we go
400s we read, we go to
400s we read, we go to lectures.
um
we
we visit
we visit cathedrals,
we visit cathedrals, we
we visit cathedrals, we begin
we visit cathedrals, we begin to
appreciate
that
that there
that there is
that there is already
that there is already within
that there is already within us
that there is already within us the
higher
higher uh
that there is already within us the
higher uh levels
higher uh levels of
that there is already within us the
higher uh levels of consciousness
higher uh levels of consciousness and
it's
it's merely
it's merely a
it's merely a matter
it's merely a matter of
it's merely a matter of identifying
it's merely a matter of identifying with
them.
So
So everyone
So everyone here
So everyone here already
So everyone here already has
So everyone here already has the
So everyone here already has the highest
level
level of
So everyone here already has the highest
level of consciousness
level of consciousness within
So everyone here already has the highest
level of consciousness within them.
And
And the
And the difficulty
And the difficulty then
And the difficulty then is
And the difficulty then is not
And the difficulty then is not the
failure
failure to
And the difficulty then is not the
failure to acknowledge
failure to acknowledge it
And the difficulty then is not the
failure to acknowledge it because
failure to acknowledge it because many
people
people in
people in this
people in this room
people in this room are
people in this room are quite
people in this room are quite devout
but
the
the habit
the habit of
the habit of identifying
with
with the
the habit of identifying
with the mind
with the mind with
the habit of identifying
with the mind with the
with the mind with the ego
the habit of identifying
with the mind with the ego with
with the mind with the ego with logic
the habit of identifying
with the mind with the ego with logic as
who
who you
who you are.
who you are. So
who you are. So the
who you are. So the problem
who you are. So the problem then
who you are. So the problem then is
really
really one
who you are. So the problem then is
really one of
really one of identification.
To
To identify
To identify with
To identify with the
To identify with the content
To identify with the content rather
To identify with the content rather than
the
the context
To identify with the content rather than
the context to
the context to identify
To identify with the content rather than
the context to identify with
the context to identify with the
To identify with the content rather than
the context to identify with the content
of
of form,
of form, logic,
of form, logic, reason,
of form, logic, reason, feeling
of form, logic, reason, feeling etc.
of form, logic, reason, feeling etc. And
to
to fail
of form, logic, reason, feeling etc. And
to fail to
to fail to realize
of form, logic, reason, feeling etc. And
to fail to realize that
to fail to realize that one
of form, logic, reason, feeling etc. And
to fail to realize that one is
context.
Karen,
are
are you
are you there?
Let's
Let's have
are you there?
Let's have that
Let's have that music
are you there?
Let's have that music at
Let's have that music at 7:50
are you there?
Let's have that music at 7:50 again
Let's have that music at 7:50 again and
then
then we'll
then we'll take
then we'll take a
then we'll take a break.
then we'll take a break. I'm
then we'll take a break. I'm going
then we'll take a break. I'm going to
get
get out
then we'll take a break. I'm going to
get out of
get out of those
then we'll take a break. I'm going to
get out of those seats
get out of those seats until
then we'll take a break. I'm going to
get out of those seats until I
get out of those seats until I tell
then we'll take a break. I'm going to
get out of those seats until I tell you.
You
You wouldn't
You wouldn't give
You wouldn't give me
You wouldn't give me permission.
Anybody
Anybody ever
You wouldn't give me permission.
Anybody ever seen
Anybody ever seen Neil
You wouldn't give me permission.
Anybody ever seen Neil Call
Anybody ever seen Neil Call Sunday
nights
nights the
nights the History
nights the History Channel?
nights the History Channel? It's
hysterical.
hysterical. You're
nights the History Channel? It's
hysterical. You're a
hysterical. You're a vet
nights the History Channel? It's
hysterical. You're a vet of
hysterical. You're a vet of World
nights the History Channel? It's
hysterical. You're a vet of World War
II.
II. But
II. But the
II. But the lead
II. But the lead actor
II. But the lead actor in
II. But the lead actor in that,
II. But the lead actor in that, he
II. But the lead actor in that, he comes
on
on like
II. But the lead actor in that, he comes
on like a
on like a caricature
II. But the lead actor in that, he comes
on like a caricature of
on like a caricature of a
II. But the lead actor in that, he comes
on like a caricature of a a
on like a caricature of a a top
sergeant,
sergeant, you
sergeant, you know,
sergeant, you know, and
sergeant, you know, and he
sergeant, you know, and he says,
sergeant, you know, and he says, "Don't
touch
touch that
sergeant, you know, and he says, "Don't
touch that channel.
touch that channel. Nobody
sergeant, you know, and he says, "Don't
touch that channel. Nobody gave
touch that channel. Nobody gave you
permission.
permission. I'll
permission. I'll tell
permission. I'll tell you
permission. I'll tell you when
permission. I'll tell you when it's
permission. I'll tell you when it's time
to
to leave
permission. I'll tell you when it's time
to leave this
to leave this program."
It
It just
It just breaks
It just breaks me
It just breaks me up
It just breaks me up because
it
it represents
It just breaks me up because
it represents that
it represents that anything
It just breaks me up because
it represents that anything if
recontextualizes
totally
totally changes
recontextualizes
totally changes its
totally changes its flavor
recontextualizes
totally changes its flavor and
significance.
significance. You
significance. You see,
significance. You see, in
significance. You see, in other
significance. You see, in other words,
in
in that
significance. You see, in other words,
in that context,
in that context, his
significance. You see, in other words,
in that context, his attitude
in that context, his attitude is
hysterically
hysterically funny
because
because you're
hysterically funny
because you're not
because you're not victim.
hysterically funny
because you're not victim. In
because you're not victim. In another
circumstance,
circumstance, he
circumstance, he would
circumstance, he would be
circumstance, he would be terrifying.
When
When I
circumstance, he would be terrifying.
When I was
When I was 17
circumstance, he would be terrifying.
When I was 17 years
When I was 17 years old,
circumstance, he would be terrifying.
When I was 17 years old, the
When I was 17 years old, the top
circumstance, he would be terrifying.
When I was 17 years old, the top bosen's
mate,
mate, you
mate, you know,
mate, you know, would
mate, you know, would terrify
mate, you know, would terrify me.
mate, you know, would terrify me. He'd
say,
say, "THOSE
mate, you know, would terrify me. He'd
say, "THOSE PILLOWS
say, "THOSE PILLOWS ARE
mate, you know, would terrify me. He'd
say, "THOSE PILLOWS ARE NOT
say, "THOSE PILLOWS ARE NOT STRAIGHT
LINE."
LINE." HOLY
LINE." HOLY CHRIST,
LINE." HOLY CHRIST, your
LINE." HOLY CHRIST, your heart
LINE." HOLY CHRIST, your heart was
LINE." HOLY CHRIST, your heart was hard.
So,
So, the
LINE." HOLY CHRIST, your heart was hard.
So, the context
So, the context was
LINE." HOLY CHRIST, your heart was hard.
So, the context was different.
So, the context was different. What
happened
happened to
happened to that
happened to that beautiful
happened to that beautiful music?
happened to that beautiful music? I
wanted
wanted to
happened to that beautiful music? I
wanted to hear
wanted to hear that
happened to that beautiful music? I
wanted to hear that again.
That
That brings
That brings you
That brings you back
That brings you back to
That brings you back to the
That brings you back to the truth
That brings you back to the truth of
that
that which
That brings you back to the truth of
that which you
that which you truly
That brings you back to the truth of
that which you truly are
and
and we
and we forget
you
reality.
have
have you
reality.
have you all
have you all here
reality.
have you all here today
have you all here today as
reality.
have you all here today as a
have you all here today as a blessing.
We'll
We'll be
We'll be back
We'll be back in
We'll be back in half
We'll be back in half hour.
Halleluah.
Halle
Hallelu
Hallelujah.
>> So
>> So that
>> So that which
>> So that which is
>> So that which is God
>> So that which is God and
>> So that which is God and that
>> So that which is God and that which
>> So that which is God and that which is
beauty
beauty are
>> So that which is God and that which is
beauty are one
beauty are one thing.
I
I don't
I don't like
I don't like to
I don't like to talk
I don't like to talk about
I don't like to talk about halfway
through
through the
I don't like to talk about halfway
through the heart
>> because
>> because it's
>> because it's doesn't
>> because it's doesn't last
>> because it's doesn't last long.
>> Adoration,
>> Adoration, devotional,
>> because it's doesn't last long.
>> Adoration, devotional, worship.
Someone
Someone asked,
Someone asked, "How
Someone asked, "How do
Someone asked, "How do you
Someone asked, "How do you get
Someone asked, "How do you get beyond
>> the
>> the thinkingness
Someone asked, "How do you get beyond
>> the thinkingness of
>> the thinkingness of the
Someone asked, "How do you get beyond
>> the thinkingness of the mind?"
>> And
>> And beauty
>> And beauty is
>> And beauty is one
>> And beauty is one of
>> And beauty is one of the
>> And beauty is one of the most
>> And beauty is one of the most immediate
ones.
>> Beauty
>> Beauty of
>> Beauty of the
>> Beauty of the music
>> Beauty of the music takes
>> Beauty of the music takes you
>> Beauty of the music takes you out
>> Beauty of the music takes you out of
thinking
thinking this
>> Beauty of the music takes you out of
thinking this in
thinking this in one
>> Beauty of the music takes you out of
thinking this in one instant.
Halleluah.
>> It's
>> It's like
Halleluah.
>> It's like incredible
>> It's like incredible beauty
Halleluah.
>> It's like incredible beauty immobilizes
the
the mind.
So
So beauty
the mind.
So beauty then
So beauty then is
the
the awareness
of
of the
the awareness
of the grace
of the grace of
the awareness
of the grace of God
which
which is
which is different
which is different than
discussing
discussing the
which is different than
discussing the various
discussing the various things
which is different than
discussing the various things we
discussing the various things we disced.
does
it's
it's the
does
it's the um
it's the um way
does
it's the um way around
it's the um way around the
does
it's the um way around the mind.
Somebody
Somebody asked
Somebody asked how
Somebody asked how do
Somebody asked how do you
Somebody asked how do you how
Somebody asked how do you how do
Somebody asked how do you how do you
stop
stop that
Somebody asked how do you how do you
stop that thinking?
You
You become
You become enamored
You become enamored of
You become enamored of God
You become enamored of God instead
You become enamored of God instead of
enamored
enamored of
You become enamored of God instead of
enamored of the
enamored of the thoughts.
To
To discern
To discern the
To discern the presence
To discern the presence of
To discern the presence of God
To discern the presence of God and
To discern the presence of God and all
that
that exists
is
is a
is a gift
is a gift that
is a gift that suddenly
is a gift that suddenly comes
is a gift that suddenly comes forth
is a gift that suddenly comes forth of
its
its own
when
the
the willingness
when
the willingness to
the willingness to surrender
when
the willingness to surrender all
the willingness to surrender all that
stands
stands in
stands in its
stands in its way.
The
The gratification,
stands in its way.
The gratification, the
The gratification, the satisfaction,
stands in its way.
The gratification, the satisfaction, the
excitement
excitement of
excitement of thinking
excitement of thinking this,
feeling
feeling this,
excitement of thinking this,
feeling this, emotions.
It's
It's a
It's a great
It's a great leap
It's a great leap because
we
we transcend
the
instincts
instincts of
the
instincts of the
instincts of the animal.
the
instincts of the animal. We
instincts of the animal. We transcend
the
the thinkingness
the thinkingness of
homo
homo sapien
and
and respond
and respond to
and respond to the
and respond to the divinity
and respond to the divinity within
and respond to the divinity within us.
We
We said
and respond to the divinity within us.
We said this
We said this morning
and
and verified
and verified it.
Out
Out of
and verified it.
Out of the
Out of the unmanifest
and verified it.
Out of the unmanifest arises
Out of the unmanifest arises the
manifest.
Out
Out of
manifest.
Out of the
Out of the manifest
manifest.
Out of the manifest arises
Out of the manifest arises existence
manifest.
Out of the manifest arises existence as
beingness.
And
And with
beingness.
And with that
And with that existence
beingness.
And with that existence arises
consciousness
and
and the
consciousness
and the energy
and the energy of
consciousness
and the energy of life.
Therefore,
Therefore, all
Therefore, all that
Therefore, all that has
Therefore, all that has life
Therefore, all that has life arises
Therefore, all that has life arises from
the
the unmanifest
Therefore, all that has life arises from
the unmanifest to
the unmanifest to the
Therefore, all that has life arises from
the unmanifest to the manifest
the unmanifest to the manifest through
existence
existence and
existence and beingness
existence and beingness through
consciousness
and
and awareness.
All
All that
and awareness.
All that is
All that is created
and awareness.
All that is created by
All that is created by God
and awareness.
All that is created by God has
All that is created by God has within
and awareness.
All that is created by God has within it
divinity.
Let's
Let's see
divinity.
Let's see if
Let's see if that's
divinity.
Let's see if that's so
all
all that
all that exists
all that exists has
all that exists has within
all that exists has within it
all that exists has within it this
all that exists has within it this its
source
source as
all that exists has within it this its
source as divinity
source as divinity resist.
Consequently,
Consequently, then
Consequently, then the
Consequently, then the awareness
Consequently, then the awareness of
Consequently, then the awareness of the
presence
presence of
Consequently, then the awareness of the
presence of God
presence of God as
Consequently, then the awareness of the
presence of God as a
presence of God as a source
Consequently, then the awareness of the
presence of God as a source of
presence of God as a source of one's
Consequently, then the awareness of the
presence of God as a source of one's own
existence
existence is
existence is innate
within
within consciousness
existence is innate
within consciousness itself.
It
It is
It is already
It is already present
and
and it's
It is already present
and it's only
and it's only a
It is already present
and it's only a matter
and it's only a matter of
letting
letting go
letting go the
letting go the identifications
letting go the identifications with
letting go the identifications with all
that
that stand
letting go the identifications with all
that stand in
that stand in its
letting go the identifications with all
that stand in its way.
The
The purposes
The purposes of
The purposes of the
The purposes of the lectures
prior
prior to
The purposes of the lectures
prior to last
prior to last month
The purposes of the lectures
prior to last month were
prior to last month were to
by
by familiarity
by familiarity and
by familiarity and by
by familiarity and by description
by familiarity and by description and
by familiarity and by description and by
analysis
understand
understand the
understand the structure
understand the structure of
understand the structure of the
understand the structure of the ego
and
and by
understand the structure of the ego
and by understanding
and by understanding it
understand the structure of the ego
and by understanding it have
and by understanding it have the
capacity
capacity to
capacity to disassemble
capacity to disassemble it.
And
And we
capacity to disassemble it.
And we always
And we always start
capacity to disassemble it.
And we always start the
And we always start the lectures
by
by reminding
by reminding ourselves
that
that all
by reminding ourselves
that all that
that all that is
by reminding ourselves
that all that is is
that all that is is what
by reminding ourselves
that all that is is what it
that all that is is what it is
by reminding ourselves
that all that is is what it is by
that all that is is what it is by virtue
of
of the
of the divinity
of the divinity of
of the divinity of its
of the divinity of its creation.
of the divinity of its creation. Each
thing
thing is
of the divinity of its creation. Each
thing is only
thing is only becoming
of the divinity of its creation. Each
thing is only becoming manifesting
thing is only becoming manifesting its
you
you might
you might say
you might say karmic
you might say karmic propensity
you might say karmic propensity to
you might say karmic propensity to be
that
that which
you might say karmic propensity to be
that which it
that which it is.
Therefore,
Therefore, there's
Therefore, there's no
Therefore, there's no reason
Therefore, there's no reason to
Therefore, there's no reason to worry
about
about God
or
or reaching
or reaching God
or reaching God or
or reaching God or being
or reaching God or being with
or reaching God or being with God
or reaching God or being with God or
anything
anything because
or reaching God or being with God or
anything because one
anything because one is
or reaching God or being with God or
anything because one is constantly
anything because one is constantly in
the
the presence
the presence of
the presence of God
who
who is
the presence of God
who is the
who is the source
the presence of God
who is the source of
who is the source of consciousness
out
out of
out of which
out of which arises
out of which arises you're
out of which arises you're worrying
about
about God.
There's
There's no
There's no need
There's no need to
There's no need to worry
There's no need to worry about
There's no need to worry about God.
There's
There's only
There's no need to worry about God.
There's only the
There's only the capacity
There's no need to worry about God.
There's only the capacity to
There's only the capacity to appreciate
beauty.
The
The the
beauty.
The the exquisite
The the exquisite power
beauty.
The the exquisite power of
perfection.
perfection. So
perfection. So beauty
perfection. So beauty rep
perfection. So beauty rep is
a
a style
perfection. So beauty rep is
a style of
a style of recognizing
perfection. So beauty rep is
a style of recognizing the
a style of recognizing the perfection
perfection. So beauty rep is
a style of recognizing the perfection of
all
all that
all that exists.
As
As spiritual
all that exists.
As spiritual awareness
As spiritual awareness progresses,
all that exists.
As spiritual awareness progresses, the
awareness
awareness of
awareness of the
awareness of the perfection
awareness of the perfection and
intrinsic
intrinsic beauty
awareness of the perfection and
intrinsic beauty of
intrinsic beauty of all
awareness of the perfection and
intrinsic beauty of all that
intrinsic beauty of all that exists
becomes
becomes overwhelming.
And
And at
becomes overwhelming.
And at a
And at a certain
becomes overwhelming.
And at a certain point,
And at a certain point, it
becomes overwhelming.
And at a certain point, it becomes
incapacitating.
And
And if
incapacitating.
And if the
And if the music
incapacitating.
And if the music is
And if the music is beautiful
incapacitating.
And if the music is beautiful enough,
you
you can't
you can't stand
you can't stand up
you can't stand up and
you can't stand up and talk.
you can't stand up and talk. You
you can't stand up and talk. You have
you can't stand up and talk. You have to
sit
sit down.
Whether
Whether the
Whether the body
Whether the body eats
Whether the body eats or
Whether the body eats or doesn't
Whether the body eats or doesn't eat,
you
you can
Whether the body eats or doesn't eat,
you can see
you can see how
Whether the body eats or doesn't eat,
you can see how quickly
you can see how quickly all
Whether the body eats or doesn't eat,
you can see how quickly all that
you can see how quickly all that becomes
irrelevant.
You
You go
irrelevant.
You go into
You go into a
irrelevant.
You go into a state
You go into a state of
irrelevant.
You go into a state of spiritual
ecstasy.
The
The survival
ecstasy.
The survival of
The survival of the
ecstasy.
The survival of the physicality
The survival of the physicality depends
on
on your
on your neighbors.
If
If you
on your neighbors.
If you have
If you have friendly
on your neighbors.
If you have friendly neighbors
If you have friendly neighbors that
on your neighbors.
If you have friendly neighbors that drop
in,
in, the
in, the body
in, the body survives.
in, the body survives. If
in, the body survives. If not,
in, the body survives. If not, it
doesn't.
doesn't. And
in, the body survives. If not, it
doesn't. And it's
doesn't. And it's totally
in, the body survives. If not, it
doesn't. And it's totally immaterial.
Somebody
Somebody says
Somebody says it's
Somebody says it's time
Somebody says it's time to
Somebody says it's time to eat
Somebody says it's time to eat now
Somebody says it's time to eat now and
so
so you
Somebody says it's time to eat now and
so you eat
so you eat otherwise
Somebody says it's time to eat now and
so you eat otherwise you'll
so you eat otherwise you'll completely
forget
forget all
forget all about
forget all about it.
So
So as
forget all about it.
So as we
So as we get
forget all about it.
So as we get into
So as we get into the
forget all about it.
So as we get into the higher
So as we get into the higher levels
forget all about it.
So as we get into the higher levels of
the
the 500s,
the 500s, you
the 500s, you know,
you
you get
the 500s, you know,
you get into
you get into a
the 500s, you know,
you get into a benevolence
you get into a benevolence towards
the 500s, you know,
you get into a benevolence towards life,
a
a benevolence
a benevolence towards
a benevolence towards yourself,
benevolence
benevolence to
a benevolence towards yourself,
benevolence to all
benevolence to all that
a benevolence towards yourself,
benevolence to all that exists.
There's
There's a
There's a benevolence
There's a benevolence towards
even
even the
There's a benevolence towards
even the most
even the most horrific
because
because it
because it cannot
because it cannot help
because it cannot help itself
because it cannot help itself but
because it cannot help itself but be
what
what it
because it cannot help itself but be
what it is.
It
It doesn't
It doesn't have
It doesn't have the
It doesn't have the karmic
whatever
whatever it
It doesn't have the karmic
whatever it takes
whatever it takes to
It doesn't have the karmic
whatever it takes to not
whatever it takes to not be
It doesn't have the karmic
whatever it takes to not be other
whatever it takes to not be other than
that
that which
that which it
that which it is.
And
And then
that which it is.
And then in
And then in a
that which it is.
And then in a greater
And then in a greater level,
one
one says
one says there's
one says there's no
one says there's no reason
one says there's no reason for
one says there's no reason for it
one says there's no reason for it to
one says there's no reason for it to be
other
other than
one says there's no reason for it to be
other than what
other than what it
one says there's no reason for it to be
other than what it is.
It
It can
It can just
It can just be
It can just be what
It can just be what it
It can just be what it is.
Not
Not particularly
It can just be what it is.
Not particularly saintly,
but
but so
but so it
but so it is
but so it is what
but so it is what it
but so it is what it is.
And
And there's
but so it is what it is.
And there's letting
And there's letting go,
but so it is what it is.
And there's letting go, wanting
And there's letting go, wanting to
change
change anything
change anything as
change anything as it
change anything as it is.
change anything as it is. Because
change anything as it is. Because you
see,
see, the
change anything as it is. Because you
see, the only
see, the only thing
change anything as it is. Because you
see, the only thing you
see, the only thing you want
change anything as it is. Because you
see, the only thing you want to
see, the only thing you want to change
is
is your
is your perception
is your perception of
is your perception of it
is your perception of it all
is your perception of it all and
is your perception of it all and your
judgmentalism
judgmentalism about
is your perception of it all and your
judgmentalism about it.
judgmentalism about it. You
is your perception of it all and your
judgmentalism about it. You want
judgmentalism about it. You want bin
Laden
Laden to
Laden to be
Laden to be different
Laden to be different than
Laden to be different than what
Laden to be different than what he
Laden to be different than what he is.
No,
No, I
Laden to be different than what he is.
No, I don't
No, I don't want
Laden to be different than what he is.
No, I don't want Bin
No, I don't want Bin Laden
Laden to be different than what he is.
No, I don't want Bin Laden to
No, I don't want Bin Laden to be
different
different than
different than what
different than what he
different than what he is.
different than what he is. Then
different than what he is. Then who
would
would be
different than what he is. Then who
would be bin
would be bin Laden?
Somebody's
Somebody's got
Somebody's got to
Somebody's got to be
Somebody's got to be the
Somebody's got to be the bad
Somebody's got to be the bad example
Somebody's got to be the bad example of
the
the day.
Somebody's got to be the bad example of
the day. You
the day. You know,
getting
getting their
getting their Muslim
getting their Muslim all
getting their Muslim all gone
getting their Muslim all gone here,
getting their Muslim all gone here, you
know,
know, all
getting their Muslim all gone here, you
know, all the
know, all the bad
getting their Muslim all gone here, you
know, all the bad guys
know, all the bad guys of
getting their Muslim all gone here, you
know, all the bad guys of when
know, all the bad guys of when I
getting their Muslim all gone here, you
know, all the bad guys of when I was
young,
new
new guys
young,
new guys arise
new guys arise on
young,
new guys arise on the
new guys arise on the stage.
And
And in
And in the
And in the highest
And in the highest dimension,
And in the highest dimension, one
And in the highest dimension, one sees
that
that that
And in the highest dimension, one sees
that that is
that that is all
like
like a
like a hologram.
And
And there's
like a hologram.
And there's no
And there's no point
like a hologram.
And there's no point to
And there's no point to change
like a hologram.
And there's no point to change the
hologram
hologram because
hologram because it's
hologram because it's evolving
hologram because it's evolving out
hologram because it's evolving out of
its
its own
hologram because it's evolving out of
its own intrinsic
its own intrinsic innate
perfect
perfect balance
perfect balance and
perfect balance and order
perfect balance and order within
perfect balance and order within itself.
All
All is
perfect balance and order within itself.
All is merely
All is merely becoming
perfect balance and order within itself.
All is merely becoming that
All is merely becoming that which
perfect balance and order within itself.
All is merely becoming that which it
All is merely becoming that which it is
in
in its
in its expression
in its expression within
in its expression within physicality.
There's
There's no
in its expression within physicality.
There's no need
There's no need to
in its expression within physicality.
There's no need to change
There's no need to change anything.
We
We become
We become our
We become our potential.
We become our potential. Not
We become our potential. Not because
it's
it's going
We become our potential. Not because
it's going to
it's going to do
We become our potential. Not because
it's going to do something
it's going to do something for
We become our potential. Not because
it's going to do something for the
world,
world, not
world, not because
world, not because it's
world, not because it's going
world, not because it's going to
world, not because it's going to do
something
something for
world, not because it's going to do
something for us.
Those
Those are
Those are kindly
Those are kindly thoughts.
Kindly
Kindly thoughts.
But
But in
But in actuality
But in actuality the
But in actuality the overall
consciousness
consciousness field
But in actuality the overall
consciousness field of
consciousness field of mankind
is
elevating
elevating is
is
elevating is going
elevating is going developing
is
elevating is going developing because
elevating is going developing because of
who
who we
who we are.
The
The only
who we are.
The only thing
The only thing you
who we are.
The only thing you need
The only thing you need to
who we are.
The only thing you need to do
The only thing you need to do the
who we are.
The only thing you need to do the better
the
the life
the life of
the life of all
the life of all mankind
is
is to
the life of all mankind
is to appreciate
is to appreciate the
the life of all mankind
is to appreciate the beauty
is to appreciate the beauty of
the life of all mankind
is to appreciate the beauty of that
incredible
incredible music.
You've
You've done
incredible music.
You've done all
You've done all you
incredible music.
You've done all you can
You've done all you can do
incredible music.
You've done all you can do to
acknowledge
acknowledge the
acknowledge the presence
acknowledge the presence of
acknowledge the presence of God,
acknowledge the presence of God, to
acknowledge the presence of God, to feel
the
the exquisite
acknowledge the presence of God, to feel
the exquisite joy
the exquisite joy of
acknowledge the presence of God, to feel
the exquisite joy of that
the exquisite joy of that beauty.
Sends
Sends out
Sends out a
Sends out a vibration
of
of such
Sends out a vibration
of such immense
of such immense power.
You
You see,
You see, because
You see, because power
You see, because power cannot
You see, because power cannot be
resisted
resisted whereas
You see, because power cannot be
resisted whereas force
resisted whereas force can.
That
That power
That power of
That power of your
That power of your adoration
That power of your adoration of
That power of your adoration of God,
your
your love,
That power of your adoration of God,
your love, your
your love, your devotion
radiates
radiates out
radiates out and
radiates out and elevates
radiates out and elevates the
radiates out and elevates the whole
field
field of
radiates out and elevates the whole
field of consciousness
and
and it
and it affects
and it affects millions
and it affects millions of
and it affects millions of people
and it affects millions of people who
are
are even
and it affects millions of people who
are even not
are even not even
and it affects millions of people who
are even not even aware
are even not even aware they're
and it affects millions of people who
are even not even aware they're being
afflicted.
Just
Just as
afflicted.
Just as the
Just as the person
afflicted.
Just as the person is
Just as the person is about
afflicted.
Just as the person is about to
Just as the person is about to do
afflicted.
Just as the person is about to do this
something,
something, he
something, he says
something, he says he
something, he says he lets
something, he says he lets it
something, he says he lets it go.
something, he says he lets it go. He
doesn't
doesn't know
something, he says he lets it go. He
doesn't know why
doesn't know why he
something, he says he lets it go. He
doesn't know why he let
doesn't know why he let it
something, he says he lets it go. He
doesn't know why he let it go.
It's
It's because
It's because the
It's because the field
It's because the field is
It's because the field is so
It's because the field is so high
It's because the field is so high now
It's because the field is so high now it
makes
makes that
It's because the field is so high now it
makes that kind
makes that kind of
It's because the field is so high now it
makes that kind of an
makes that kind of an action
It's because the field is so high now it
makes that kind of an action almost
impossible.
So
So what
impossible.
So what we
So what we do
impossible.
So what we do then
is
is by
is by the
is by the realization
is by the realization of
is by the realization of our
is by the realization of our own
is by the realization of our own innate
perfection
in
in impact
in impact the
in impact the consciousness
in impact the consciousness of
in impact the consciousness of all
in impact the consciousness of all of
mankind.
re
re reccalibrated
re reccalibrated u
re reccalibrated u the
re reccalibrated u the level
re reccalibrated u the level of
consciousness
consciousness as
re reccalibrated u the level of
consciousness as it
has
has moved
has moved forward
has moved forward over
has moved forward over the
has moved forward over the centuries
in
in the
has moved forward over the centuries
in the late
in the late 1980s.
has moved forward over the centuries
in the late 1980s. That
in the late 1980s. That was
has moved forward over the centuries
in the late 1980s. That was the
in the late 1980s. That was the time
has moved forward over the centuries
in the late 1980s. That was the time of
the
the harmonic
the harmonic conversions.
That
That was
the harmonic conversions.
That was the
That was the time
the harmonic conversions.
That was the time when
That was the time when all
the harmonic conversions.
That was the time when all the
That was the time when all the spiritual
committed
committed people
committed people in
committed people in the
committed people in the world
committed people in the world joined
together
together at
committed people in the world joined
together at a
together at a certain
committed people in the world joined
together at a certain hour
together at a certain hour in
committed people in the world joined
together at a certain hour in the
morning.
morning. We
morning. We all
morning. We all woke
morning. We all woke up
morning. We all woke up at
morning. We all woke up at 4:00
morning. We all woke up at 4:00 or
something
something and
morning. We all woke up at 4:00 or
something and prayed
something and prayed for
morning. We all woke up at 4:00 or
something and prayed for peace.
That
That was
That was the
That was the time
That was the time when
That was the time when monolithic
atheistic
atheistic communism
collapsed.
All
All of
collapsed.
All of those
All of those things.
collapsed.
All of those things. And
All of those things. And I
collapsed.
All of those things. And I suppose
All of those things. And I suppose there
was
was some
was some kind
was some kind of
was some kind of a
was some kind of a confluence
astrologically.
Not
Not because
Not because the
Not because the astrologic
Not because the astrologic formation
causes
causes things,
Not because the astrologic formation
causes things, but
causes things, but because
Not because the astrologic formation
causes things, but because that
causes things, but because that which
brings
brings peace
brings peace brings
simultaneously
simultaneously many
brings peace brings
simultaneously many things
simultaneously many things all
brings peace brings
simultaneously many things all at
simultaneously many things all at the
same
same time
same time that
same time that are
same time that are in
same time that are in concordance
same time that are in concordance with
each
each other.
same time that are in concordance with
each other. Huh.