What
What occasion
What occasion the
What occasion the jump
What occasion the jump over
What occasion the jump over to
What occasion the jump over to the
What occasion the jump over to the 200s?
Well,
Well, we
What occasion the jump over to the 200s?
Well, we said
Well, we said the
What occasion the jump over to the 200s?
Well, we said the the
Well, we said the the most
What occasion the jump over to the 200s?
Well, we said the the most incredible
thing
thing that
thing that ever
thing that ever happened
thing that ever happened I
thing that ever happened I I
thing that ever happened I I think
thing that ever happened I I think other
than
the
the the
the the the
the the the great
the the the great gurus
the the the great gurus that
the the the great gurus that the
the the the great gurus that the great
avatars
was
was in
was in the
was in the late
was in the late '8s
was in the late '8s when
was in the late '8s when consciousness
level
level went
was in the late '8s when consciousness
level went from
level went from 190
was in the late '8s when consciousness
level went from 190 to
level went from 190 to 207.
As
As I've
As I've said
As I've said before,
As I've said before, it
As I've said before, it was
As I've said before, it was at
As I've said before, it was at the
As I've said before, it was at the time
of
of the
As I've said before, it was at the time
of the harmonic
of the harmonic convergence.
As I've said before, it was at the time
of the harmonic convergence. It
of the harmonic convergence. It was
As I've said before, it was at the time
of the harmonic convergence. It was at
the
the time
the time of
uh
uh what
the time of
uh what was
uh what was it?
the time of
uh what was it? World
uh what was it? World peace
the time of
uh what was it? World peace day
uh what was it? World peace day or
something.
something. Everybody
something. Everybody woke
something. Everybody woke up
something. Everybody woke up at
something. Everybody woke up at 4:00
something. Everybody woke up at 4:00 and
we
we all
something. Everybody woke up at 4:00 and
we all prayed
we all prayed for
something. Everybody woke up at 4:00 and
we all prayed for peace.
we all prayed for peace. All
something. Everybody woke up at 4:00 and
we all prayed for peace. All those
things
things occurred
things occurred at
things occurred at the
things occurred at the same
things occurred at the same time
things occurred at the same time and
about
about the
things occurred at the same time and
about the same
about the same time
things occurred at the same time and
about the same time monolithic
about the same time monolithic communism
fell
fell over
fell over and
fell over and many
fell over and many other
fell over and many other events.
But
But the
fell over and many other events.
But the destiny
But the destiny of
fell over and many other events.
But the destiny of mankind
But the destiny of mankind then
fell over and many other events.
But the destiny of mankind then um
But the destiny of mankind then um has
become
become quite
become quite different.
become quite different. The
become quite different. The destiny
become quite different. The destiny of
man
man at
become quite different. The destiny of
man at 207
man at 207 is
become quite different. The destiny of
man at 207 is considerably
man at 207 is considerably different
than
than 190.
than 190. 190
than 190. 190 means
than 190. 190 means endless
than 190. 190 means endless hell.
Endless
Endless hell
than 190. 190 means endless hell.
Endless hell and
Endless hell and 207
than 190. 190 means endless hell.
Endless hell and 207 means
Endless hell and 207 means only
localized
localized hell.
localized hell. It
localized hell. It means
localized hell. It means sort
localized hell. It means sort of
localized hell. It means sort of that
[laughter]
the
the mankind
the mankind is
the mankind is going
the mankind is going to
the mankind is going to progress.
Uh
Uh I'm
the mankind is going to progress.
Uh I'm just
Uh I'm just telling
the mankind is going to progress.
Uh I'm just telling you
Uh I'm just telling you things
the mankind is going to progress.
Uh I'm just telling you things that
Uh I'm just telling you things that are
in
in the
in the book
in the book I'm
in the book I'm finishing
in the book I'm finishing now,
in the book I'm finishing now, but
in the book I'm finishing now, but I'll
just
just we'll
in the book I'm finishing now, but I'll
just we'll ask
just we'll ask about
in the book I'm finishing now, but I'll
just we'll ask about it.
just we'll ask about it. Um
in the book I'm finishing now, but I'll
just we'll ask about it. Um in
just we'll ask about it. Um in the
in the book I'm finishing now, but I'll
just we'll ask about it. Um in the book
we
we announced
we announced the
we announced the um
we announced the um the
we announced the um the evolution
we announced the um the evolution of
mankind
mankind is
we announced the um the evolution of
mankind is progressing
mankind is progressing and
we announced the um the evolution of
mankind is progressing and and
mankind is progressing and and partly
his
his nervous
his nervous system
his nervous system is
his nervous system is changing.
his nervous system is changing. Resist.
in
in order
his nervous system is changing. Resist.
in order to
in order to be
his nervous system is changing. Resist.
in order to be able
in order to be able to
his nervous system is changing. Resist.
in order to be able to handle
in order to be able to handle higher
energies
energies resist
energies resist the
energies resist the mankind
energies resist the mankind up
energies resist the mankind up to
energies resist the mankind up to now
could
could only
energies resist the mankind up to now
could only handle
could only handle an
energies resist the mankind up to now
could only handle an energy
could only handle an energy up
energies resist the mankind up to now
could only handle an energy up to
could only handle an energy up to 1,000
resist
resist now
resist now on
resist now on great
resist now on great very
resist now on great very rarely
resist now on great very rarely but
occasion
occasion it
resist now on great very rarely but
occasion it can
occasion it can go
resist now on great very rarely but
occasion it can go over
occasion it can go over a
resist now on great very rarely but
occasion it can go over a thousand
that's
that's first
that's first time
that's first time in
that's first time in history
that's first time in history resist
that's first time in history resist all
right
right uh
that's first time in history resist all
right uh and
right uh and it
that's first time in history resist all
right uh and it and
right uh and it and it
that's first time in history resist all
right uh and it and it preages
[clears throat]
[clears throat] the
[clears throat] the evolution
[clears throat] the evolution the
appearance
appearance of
[clears throat] the evolution the
appearance of a
appearance of a new
[clears throat] the evolution the
appearance of a new um
appearance of a new um [clears throat]
yeah
yeah of
yeah of homo
yeah of homo spiritus
yeah of homo spiritus is
yeah of homo spiritus is it
yeah of homo spiritus is it okay
yeah of homo spiritus is it okay the
evolution
evolution of
yeah of homo spiritus is it okay the
evolution of homo
evolution of homo spiritus
yeah of homo spiritus is it okay the
evolution of homo spiritus you
evolution of homo spiritus you see
yeah of homo spiritus is it okay the
evolution of homo spiritus you see homo
sapiion
sapiion came
sapiion came off
sapiion came off there.
But
But to
sapiion came off there.
But to handle
But to handle higher
sapiion came off there.
But to handle higher energies,
But to handle higher energies, you
really
really need
really need a
really need a different
really need a different nervous
really need a different nervous system.
This
This nervous
really need a different nervous system.
This nervous system
This nervous system is
really need a different nervous system.
This nervous system is horrendous.
This nervous system is horrendous. If
you're
you're going
you're going to
you're going to go
you're going to go over
you're going to go over 600,
you're going to go over 600, it's
you're going to go over 600, it's not
made
made to
you're going to go over 600, it's not
made to go
made to go over
you're going to go over 600, it's not
made to go over 600.
Uh
Uh you
Uh you really
Uh you really need
Uh you really need a
Uh you really need a different
Uh you really need a different nervous
system.
So
So in
So in a
So in a way,
So in a way, it
So in a way, it pre
So in a way, it pre to
So in a way, it pre to me
So in a way, it pre to me uh
So in a way, it pre to me uh the
So in a way, it pre to me uh the the
prophesied
prophesied um
uh
uh return
uh return of
uh return of Christ
uh return of Christ to
uh return of Christ to earth.
uh return of Christ to earth. To
uh return of Christ to earth. To me,
uh return of Christ to earth. To me, the
return
return of
uh return of Christ to earth. To me, the
return of Christ
return of Christ to
uh return of Christ to earth. To me, the
return of Christ to earth
return of Christ to earth is
uh return of Christ to earth. To me, the
return of Christ to earth is not
return of Christ to earth is not a
physicality.
It's
It's the
physicality.
It's the uh
It's the uh return
physicality.
It's the uh return of
It's the uh return of the
physicality.
It's the uh return of the it
It's the uh return of the it it
physicality.
It's the uh return of the it it means
that
that consciousness
will
will dominate
that consciousness
will dominate mankind
will dominate mankind because
that consciousness
will dominate mankind because up
will dominate mankind because up till
the
the late
the late 80s
the late 80s mankind
the late 80s mankind was
the late 80s mankind was dominated
the late 80s mankind was dominated by
energies
energies that
the late 80s mankind was dominated by
energies that were
energies that were satanic
the late 80s mankind was dominated by
energies that were satanic and
energies that were satanic and luciferic
primarily.
Mankind
Mankind was
primarily.
Mankind was only
Mankind was only interested
primarily.
Mankind was only interested in
slaughtering
slaughtering each
slaughtering each other.
slaughtering each other. The
slaughtering each other. The great
hordes
hordes that
slaughtering each other. The great
hordes that came
hordes that came down
slaughtering each other. The great
hordes that came down on
hordes that came down on Europe
slaughtering each other. The great
hordes that came down on Europe and
hordes that came down on Europe and the
Roman
Roman Empire,
Roman Empire, the
Roman Empire, the only
Roman Empire, the only thing
Roman Empire, the only thing they
Roman Empire, the only thing they were
interested
interested in
Roman Empire, the only thing they were
interested in was
interested in was slaughtering
everybody.
everybody. They
everybody. They slaughtered
everybody. They slaughtered them
everybody. They slaughtered them all,
killed
killed them.
And
And uh
And uh then
And uh then they
And uh then they made
And uh then they made the
And uh then they made the great
discovery
discovery that
And uh then they made the great
discovery that live
discovery that live people
And uh then they made the great
discovery that live people were
discovery that live people were worth
more
more than
more than dead
more than dead people.
more than dead people. And
more than dead people. And slavery
more than dead people. And slavery was
born.
And
And you
And you see,
And you see, if
And you see, if we
And you see, if we recontextualize
slavery,
slavery, it
And you see, if we recontextualize
slavery, it was
slavery, it was a
And you see, if we recontextualize
slavery, it was a great
slavery, it was a great advance.
And you see, if we recontextualize
slavery, it was a great advance. Instead
of
of getting
of getting slaughtered
of getting slaughtered by
of getting slaughtered by the
of getting slaughtered by the tens
of getting slaughtered by the tens of
thousands,
thousands, we
of getting slaughtered by the tens of
thousands, we now
thousands, we now corral
of getting slaughtered by the tens of
thousands, we now corral 5,000
thousands, we now corral 5,000 and
of getting slaughtered by the tens of
thousands, we now corral 5,000 and we
sold
sold you
sold you off.
sold you off. [laughter]
And
And of
sold you off. [laughter]
And of course,
And of course, the
sold you off. [laughter]
And of course, the buyer
And of course, the buyer was
sold you off. [laughter]
And of course, the buyer was buying
And of course, the buyer was buying you
like
like cattle.
like cattle. And
like cattle. And cattle
like cattle. And cattle are
like cattle. And cattle are worth
like cattle. And cattle are worth money.
So
So they
like cattle. And cattle are worth money.
So they saw
So they saw to
like cattle. And cattle are worth money.
So they saw to it
So they saw to it you
like cattle. And cattle are worth money.
So they saw to it you were
So they saw to it you were fed
like cattle. And cattle are worth money.
So they saw to it you were fed basically
were
were taken
were taken care
were taken care of.
were taken care of. The
were taken care of. The alternate
were taken care of. The alternate was
just
just to
were taken care of. The alternate was
just to be
just to be killed
were taken care of. The alternate was
just to be killed on
just to be killed on the
were taken care of. The alternate was
just to be killed on the battlefield
just to be killed on the battlefield and
die
die of
die of your
die of your wounds.
So
So rather
die of your wounds.
So rather than
So rather than dying
die of your wounds.
So rather than dying slowly
So rather than dying slowly of
die of your wounds.
So rather than dying slowly of your
wounds
wounds uh
wounds uh on
wounds uh on the
wounds uh on the battlefield
wounds uh on the battlefield you
wounds uh on the battlefield you got
wounds uh on the battlefield you got to
uh
uh work
wounds uh on the battlefield you got to
uh work for
uh work for somebody
wounds uh on the battlefield you got to
uh work for somebody else.
uh work for somebody else. And
wounds uh on the battlefield you got to
uh work for somebody else. And I
uh work for somebody else. And I think
in
in a
in a certain
in a certain way
in a certain way you
in a certain way you earned
in a certain way you earned a
in a certain way you earned a certain
karma
karma by
in a certain way you earned a certain
karma by doing
karma by doing so
in a certain way you earned a certain
karma by doing so certain
karma by doing so certain karma
in a certain way you earned a certain
karma by doing so certain karma by
karma by doing so certain karma by doing
so.
the
the willingness
so.
the willingness to
the willingness to um
so.
the willingness to um surrender
the willingness to um surrender one's
life
life to
life to service.
life to service. [clears throat]
That
That service
life to service. [clears throat]
That service may
That service may take
life to service. [clears throat]
That service may take all
That service may take all different
kinds
kinds of
kinds of forms
kinds of forms depending
kinds of forms depending on
kinds of forms depending on what
kinds of forms depending on what your
level
level of
kinds of forms depending on what your
level of consciousness
level of consciousness is.
kinds of forms depending on what your
level of consciousness is. So
level of consciousness is. So service
means
means something
means something different
means something different here.
means something different here. Service
out
out of
means something different here. Service
out of love
out of love to
means something different here. Service
out of love to God
out of love to God will
means something different here. Service
out of love to God will mean
out of love to God will mean something
quite
quite different
quite different here
quite different here than
quite different here than it
quite different here than it will
quite different here than it will from
here
here from
quite different here than it will from
here from here
here from here from
quite different here than it will from
here from here from here
here from here from here from
quite different here than it will from
here from here from here from here
here from here from here from here from
here.
here
here service
here.
here service to
here service to God
here.
here service to God might
here service to God might be
here.
here service to God might be mean
here service to God might be mean to
here.
here service to God might be mean to you
the
the willingness
the willingness to
the willingness to kill
the willingness to kill Americans
the willingness to kill Americans for
God.
God. Huh?
the willingness to kill Americans for
God. Huh? That's
God. Huh? That's how
the willingness to kill Americans for
God. Huh? That's how it's
God. Huh? That's how it's being
the willingness to kill Americans for
God. Huh? That's how it's being held
God. Huh? That's how it's being held in
mind
mind truly
mind truly by
mind truly by those
mind truly by those people.
mind truly by those people. I
mind truly by those people. I think
mind truly by those people. I think the
naive
naive are
mind truly by those people. I think the
naive are brainwashed
naive are brainwashed that
mind truly by those people. I think the
naive are brainwashed that way.
naive are brainwashed that way. I
mind truly by those people. I think the
naive are brainwashed that way. I think
those
those who
those who brainwash
those who brainwash them
those who brainwash them are
those who brainwash them are not
those who brainwash them are not deluded
and
and don't
those who brainwash them are not deluded
and don't really
and don't really believe
those who brainwash them are not deluded
and don't really believe that
and don't really believe that at
those who brainwash them are not deluded
and don't really believe that at all,
but
but they
but they know
but they know it
but they know it works.
Uh
Uh let's
but they know it works.
Uh let's see
Uh let's see if
but they know it works.
Uh let's see if that's
Uh let's see if that's so
we
we have
we have permission
we have permission to
we have permission to ask
we have permission to ask this
we have permission to ask this question
in
in front
we have permission to ask this question
in front of
in front of this
we have permission to ask this question
in front of this audience.
Those
Those who
Those who blow
Those who blow themselves
Those who blow themselves up
Those who blow themselves up to
Those who blow themselves up to kill
Americans
Americans for
Those who blow themselves up to kill
Americans for Allah
Americans for Allah are
Those who blow themselves up to kill
Americans for Allah are intrinsically
naive.
naive. Resist.
naive. Resist. Intrinsically
naive. Resist. Intrinsically have
naive. Resist. Intrinsically have been
uh
uh spiritually
naive. Resist. Intrinsically have been
uh spiritually raped.
uh spiritually raped. Resist.
Intrinsically
Intrinsically have
Intrinsically have been
Intrinsically have been brainwashed.
resist
the
the source
the source of
the source of their
the source of their brainwasher
um
um is
the source of their brainwasher
um is um
not
not innocent
not innocent resist
not innocent resist is
not innocent resist is aware
not innocent resist is aware of
not innocent resist is aware of what
it's
it's doing
not innocent resist is aware of what
it's doing and
it's doing and comes
not innocent resist is aware of what
it's doing and comes from
it's doing and comes from the
not innocent resist is aware of what
it's doing and comes from the lower
astral
astral resist.
astral resist. Okay.
astral resist. Okay. So
astral resist. Okay. So those
astral resist. Okay. So those are
astral resist. Okay. So those are the
people
people who
astral resist. Okay. So those are the
people who are
people who are destined
astral resist. Okay. So those are the
people who are destined not
people who are destined not to
astral resist. Okay. So those are the
people who are destined not to be
enlightened.
They
They rape
enlightened.
They rape the
They rape the innocent
enlightened.
They rape the innocent of
They rape the innocent of the
spiritually
spiritually pure
spiritually pure and
spiritually pure and tell
spiritually pure and tell them
spiritually pure and tell them to
spiritually pure and tell them to do
that
that which
spiritually pure and tell them to do
that which is
that which is the
spiritually pure and tell them to do
that which is the opposite.
that which is the opposite. Okay.
spiritually pure and tell them to do
that which is the opposite. Okay. Now
actually
actually to
actually to a
actually to a certain
actually to a certain degree
actually to a certain degree you
actually to a certain degree you can
because
because uh
actually to a certain degree you can
because uh you
because uh you see
actually to a certain degree you can
because uh you see your
because uh you see your consciousness
actually to a certain degree you can
because uh you see your consciousness a
great
great deal
great deal of
great deal of it
great deal of it can
great deal of it can be
great deal of it can be looking
great deal of it can be looking in
great deal of it can be looking in one
direction
direction and
great deal of it can be looking in one
direction and part
direction and part of
great deal of it can be looking in one
direction and part of it
direction and part of it looking
great deal of it can be looking in one
direction and part of it looking at
another.
another. You
another. You know
another. You know you
another. You know you can
another. You know you can be
another. You know you can be walking
through
through the
another. You know you can be walking
through the park
through the park and
another. You know you can be walking
through the park and also
through the park and also looking
another. You know you can be walking
through the park and also looking for
also
also looking
also looking for
also looking for a
also looking for a gumball
also looking for a gumball machine.
also looking for a gumball machine. In
other
other words,
also looking for a gumball machine. In
other words, you're
other words, you're not
also looking for a gumball machine. In
other words, you're not losing
other words, you're not losing contact
with
with the
with the whole
with the whole park
with the whole park just
with the whole park just cuz
with the whole park just cuz you're
looking
looking at
with the whole park just cuz you're
looking at a
looking at a gumball
with the whole park just cuz you're
looking at a gumball machine.
uh
uh and
uh and yet
uh and yet if
uh and yet if you
uh and yet if you don't
uh and yet if you don't parcel
uh and yet if you don't parcel out
uh and yet if you don't parcel out part
of
of your
uh and yet if you don't parcel out part
of your attention.
of your attention. So
uh and yet if you don't parcel out part
of your attention. So part
of your attention. So part of
uh and yet if you don't parcel out part
of your attention. So part of your
attention
attention is
attention is focused
attention is focused here
attention is focused here in
attention is focused here in spiritual
work
work the
attention is focused here in spiritual
work the the
work the the it's
attention is focused here in spiritual
work the the it's quite
work the the it's quite a
attention is focused here in spiritual
work the the it's quite a subtle
work the the it's quite a subtle balance
between
between how
between how much
between how much energy
between how much energy is
between how much energy is within
between how much energy is within how
much
much is
between how much energy is within how
much is without
much is without how
between how much energy is within how
much is without how much
much is without how much is
between how much energy is within how
much is without how much is in
much is without how much is in the
context
context and
context and how
context and how much
context and how much is
context and how much is in
context and how much is in the
context and how much is in the content.
The
The prevailing
context and how much is in the content.
The prevailing technique
The prevailing technique that
context and how much is in the content.
The prevailing technique that I
The prevailing technique that I suggest
to
to people
to people is
to people is one
to people is one really
to people is one really of
contemplation.
contemplation. is
to people is one really of
contemplation. is it's
contemplation. is it's really
to people is one really of
contemplation. is it's really a
contemplation
contemplation in
contemplation in a
contemplation in a way
contemplation in a way an
contemplation in a way an ongoing
contemplation in a way an ongoing thing
of
of its
contemplation in a way an ongoing thing
of its own
of its own that
contemplation in a way an ongoing thing
of its own that as
of its own that as things
contemplation in a way an ongoing thing
of its own that as things arise
of its own that as things arise one
spontaneously
spontaneously after
spontaneously after a
spontaneously after a while
spontaneously after a while becomes
spontaneous
surreners
surreners them
surreners them to
surreners them to God
surreners them to God and
surreners them to God and relinquishes
one
one one's
surreners them to God and relinquishes
one one's attachment
as
as the
as the fear
as the fear that
as the fear that kitty
as the fear that kitty has
as the fear that kitty has lost
as the fear that kitty has lost arises
the
the fear
as the fear that kitty has lost arises
the fear is
the fear is instantly
the
the spiritual
the spiritual master
the spiritual master within
the spiritual master within me
the spiritual master within me demands
now
now that
the spiritual master within me demands
now that I
now that I release
the spiritual master within me demands
now that I release it
now that I release it as
the spiritual master within me demands
now that I release it as it
now that I release it as it arises
the spiritual master within me demands
now that I release it as it arises is
within
within one
within one minute
within one minute later
within one minute later it's
within one minute later it's no
within one minute later it's no longer
there.
So
So we
So we surrender
So we surrender things
So we surrender things to
So we surrender things to God
So we surrender things to God as
So we surrender things to God as they
arise
arise in
So we surrender things to God as they
arise in the
arise in the very
So we surrender things to God as they
arise in the very process
arise in the very process of
So we surrender things to God as they
arise in the very process of arriving
this
this as
this as it
this as it as
this as it as as
this as it as as they
this as it as as they arise
this as it as as they arise you
this as it as as they arise you you.
this as it as as they arise you you. So
surrendering
surrendering is
this as it as as they arise you you. So
surrendering is a
surrendering is a continuous
this as it as as they arise you you. So
surrendering is a continuous process.
The
The fixity
The fixity of
The fixity of focus
The fixity of focus if
The fixity of focus if I
The fixity of focus if I could
The fixity of focus if I could say
The fixity of focus if I could say I
have
have any
The fixity of focus if I could say I
have any fixity
have any fixity of
The fixity of focus if I could say I
have any fixity of focus
have any fixity of focus when
The fixity of focus if I could say I
have any fixity of focus when in
have any fixity of focus when in the
world
world it
world it or
world it or at least
world it or at least it
world it or at least it was
the
the surrenderingness
world it or at least it was
the surrenderingness of
the surrenderingness of everything
world it or at least it was
the surrenderingness of everything as
the surrenderingness of everything as it
arises.
Whether
Whether 10
arises.
Whether 10 million
die
die in
die in a
die in a civil
die in a civil war
die in a civil war in
certain
certain place
die in a civil war in
certain place in
certain place in the
die in a civil war in
certain place in the world
certain place in the world is
irrelevant.
It's
It's irrelevant
irrelevant.
It's irrelevant when
It's irrelevant when 10
irrelevant.
It's irrelevant when 10 million
It's irrelevant when 10 million die.
You
You have
You have to
You have to be
You have to be in
You have to be in a
You have to be in a certain
You have to be in a certain space
You have to be in a certain space to
understand
understand the
You have to be in a certain space to
understand the truth
understand the truth of
You have to be in a certain space to
understand the truth of that.
understand the truth of that. First
You have to be in a certain space to
understand the truth of that. First of
all,
all, no
all, no death
all, no death is
all, no death is possible.
The
The quality
all, no death is possible.
The quality of
The quality of life
all, no death is possible.
The quality of life is
The quality of life is such
all, no death is possible.
The quality of life is such that
The quality of life is such that it
all, no death is possible.
The quality of life is such that it is
not
not possible
not possible for
not possible for life
not possible for life to
not possible for life to die.
not possible for life to die. No,
it's
it's a
not possible for life to die. No,
it's a good
it's a good thing
not possible for life to die. No,
it's a good thing in
it's a good thing in spiritual
not possible for life to die. No,
it's a good thing in spiritual work
it's a good thing in spiritual work to
get
get over
get over the
get over the fear
get over the fear of
get over the fear of death.
get over the fear of death. One
get over the fear of death. One is
get over the fear of death. One is to
get over the fear of death. One is to re
one
one is
get over the fear of death. One is to re
one is to
one is to realize
get over the fear of death. One is to re
one is to realize that
one is to realize that it's
get over the fear of death. One is to re
one is to realize that it's said
one is to realize that it's said already
and
and secondly
and secondly you
and secondly you don't
and secondly you don't experience
and secondly you don't experience it
anyway.
anyway. Nobody
and secondly you don't experience it
anyway. Nobody can
anyway. Nobody can experience
and secondly you don't experience it
anyway. Nobody can experience your
anyway. Nobody can experience your own
physical
physical death.
physical death. We
physical death. We reaffirm
physical death. We reaffirm that
physical death. We reaffirm that each
time
it's
it's not
it's not possible
it's not possible to
it's not possible to experience
it's not possible to experience your
it's not possible to experience your own
physical
physical death.
it's not possible to experience your own
physical death. Resist.
physical death. Resist. Correct.
it's not possible to experience your own
physical death. Resist. Correct. You
cannot
cannot experience
cannot experience your
cannot experience your own
cannot experience your own death.
cannot experience your own death. First
of
of all,
cannot experience your own death. First
of all, it's
of all, it's said.
cannot experience your own death. First
of all, it's said. Secondly,
of all, it's said. Secondly, you're
cannot experience your own death. First
of all, it's said. Secondly, you're not
going
going to
going to experience
going to experience it
going to experience it anyway.
Thirdly,
Thirdly, life
going to experience it anyway.
Thirdly, life is
Thirdly, life is not
going to experience it anyway.
Thirdly, life is not capable
Thirdly, life is not capable of
going to experience it anyway.
Thirdly, life is not capable of being
killed.
You
You the
killed.
You the the
You the the intrinsic
killed.
You the the intrinsic essence
You the the intrinsic essence and
quality
quality of
quality of life
quality of life is
quality of life is that
quality of life is that it's
indestructible.
indestructible. That's
quality of life is that it's
indestructible. That's a
indestructible. That's a fact.
It's
It's like
It's like the
It's like the law
It's like the law of
It's like the law of the
It's like the law of the conservation
It's like the law of the conservation of
matter.
matter. The
It's like the law of the conservation of
matter. The law
matter. The law of
It's like the law of the conservation of
matter. The law of conservation
matter. The law of conservation of
It's like the law of the conservation of
matter. The law of conservation of life
is
is even
is even more
uh
uh true.
Life
Life can
Life can change
Life can change form,
Life can change form, but
Life can change form, but you
Life can change form, but you cannot
kill
kill life.
Life can change form, but you cannot
kill life. Not
kill life. Not possible
Life can change form, but you cannot
kill life. Not possible to
kill life. Not possible to kill
Life can change form, but you cannot
kill life. Not possible to kill life.
The
The minus
The minus swaddle
The minus swaddle fly
The minus swaddle fly goes
The minus swaddle fly goes right
The minus swaddle fly goes right off
into
into his
The minus swaddle fly goes right off
into his own
into his own into
The minus swaddle fly goes right off
into his own into his
into his own into his uh
The minus swaddle fly goes right off
into his own into his uh etheric
into his own into his uh etheric body
and
and he
and he goes
and he goes keeps
and he goes keeps right
and he goes keeps right on
and he goes keeps right on flying
and he goes keeps right on flying and
then
then he
and he goes keeps right on flying and
then he gets
then he gets reborn
and he goes keeps right on flying and
then he gets reborn as
then he gets reborn as another
and he goes keeps right on flying and
then he gets reborn as another fly.
Hardly
Hardly notices
Hardly notices the
Hardly notices the difference.
Wasn't
Wasn't I
Hardly notices the difference.
Wasn't I here
Wasn't I here before?
Hardly notices the difference.
Wasn't I here before? He
Wasn't I here before? He says
Hardly notices the difference.
Wasn't I here before? He says to
himself.
Can't
Can't remember
himself.
Can't remember if
Can't remember if I
himself.
Can't remember if I was
Can't remember if I was on
himself.
Can't remember if I was on this
Can't remember if I was on this ship
himself.
Can't remember if I was on this ship or
not.
not. Was
not. Was I?
not. Was I? This
not. Was I? This is
not. Was I? This is where
not. Was I? This is where the
not. Was I? This is where the hamburgers
are.
are. Oh
not. Was I? This is where the hamburgers
are. Oh yeah.
are. Oh yeah. [laughter]
Yeah.
Because
Because life
Yeah.
Because life cannot
Because life cannot be
Yeah.
Because life cannot be destroyed.
There's
There's no
There's no po
There's no po point
There's no po point in
There's no po point in mourning
There's no po point in mourning death.
No
No death
There's no po point in mourning death.
No death is
No death is possible.
There's no po point in mourning death.
No death is possible. So
No death is possible. So what
There's no po point in mourning death.
No death is possible. So what are
No death is possible. So what are you
crying
crying about?
crying about? What
crying about? What are
crying about? What are you
crying about? What are you fearing?
crying about? What are you fearing? What
are
are you
crying about? What are you fearing? What
are you saying?
are you saying? Isn't
crying about? What are you fearing? What
are you saying? Isn't that
are you saying? Isn't that awful?
crying about? What are you fearing? What
are you saying? Isn't that awful? 30
million
million died.
million died. Why
million died. Why is
million died. Why is it
million died. Why is it awful?
million died. Why is it awful? It's
awful
awful to
million died. Why is it awful? It's
awful to you.
Did
Did somebody
Did somebody tell
Did somebody tell you
Did somebody tell you that's
Did somebody tell you that's bad?
Did somebody tell you that's bad? Common
belief
belief is
Did somebody tell you that's bad? Common
belief is that
belief is that it's
Did somebody tell you that's bad? Common
belief is that it's bad.
So
So you
So you keep
So you keep surrendering
So you keep surrendering things
So you keep surrendering things until
one
one has
So you keep surrendering things until
one has completely
one has completely and
So you keep surrendering things until
one has completely and totally
surrendered
surrendered all
surrendered all of
surrendered all of life
surrendered all of life to
surrendered all of life to God.
Everything
Everything as
surrendered all of life to God.
Everything as it
Everything as it arises
and
and then
and then you
and then you realize
and then you realize that
and then you realize that what
and then you realize that what you've
been
been surrendering
and then you realize that what you've
been surrendering wasn't
been surrendering wasn't a
and then you realize that what you've
been surrendering wasn't a reality
been surrendering wasn't a reality in
the
the first
the first place.
the first place. All
the first place. All the
the first place. All the great
sacrifices
sacrifices you
the first place. All the great
sacrifices you thought
sacrifices you thought you
the first place. All the great
sacrifices you thought you were
sacrifices you thought you were making
were
were all
were all illusions.
Sacrificing
Sacrificing your
were all illusions.
Sacrificing your physicality
Sacrificing your physicality to
were all illusions.
Sacrificing your physicality to God.
Sacrificing your physicality to God. You
thought
thought you
thought you were
thought you were surrendering
thought you were surrendering life
thought you were surrendering life to
God.
God. You
thought you were surrendering life to
God. You aren't
God. You aren't surrendering
thought you were surrendering life to
God. You aren't surrendering your
God. You aren't surrendering your life
to
to God.
Life
Life cannot
to God.
Life cannot be
Life cannot be surrendered
to God.
Life cannot be surrendered to
Life cannot be surrendered to anything.
Life
Life is
Life is ongoing
forever
because
because life
because life itself
because life itself is
because life itself is the
because life itself is the expression
because life itself is the expression of
God.
God. And
because life itself is the expression of
God. And unless
God. And unless you
because life itself is the expression of
God. And unless you can
God. And unless you can kill
because life itself is the expression of
God. And unless you can kill God,
God. And unless you can kill God, you
can't
can't kill
can't kill life.
We
We have
can't kill life.
We have our
We have our preferences.
can't kill life.
We have our preferences. So
We have our preferences. So all
can't kill life.
We have our preferences. So all you're
letting
letting go
letting go is
letting go is preferences.
letting go is preferences. a
letting go is preferences. a preference
that
that you
letting go is preferences. a preference
that you continue
that you continue as
letting go is preferences. a preference
that you continue as this
that you continue as this physicality
and
and in
and in the
and in the end
and in the end of
and in the end of story
and in the end of story and
and in the end of story and you
and in the end of story and you become
enamored
enamored of
and in the end of story and you become
enamored of its
enamored of its story.
and in the end of story and you become
enamored of its story. It
enamored of its story. It isn't
and in the end of story and you become
enamored of its story. It isn't that
you're
you're willing
you're willing to
you're willing to die.
you're willing to die. It's
you're willing to die. It's just
you're willing to die. It's just you
don't
don't want
you're willing to die. It's just you
don't want to
don't want to give
you're willing to die. It's just you
don't want to give up
don't want to give up the
you're willing to die. It's just you
don't want to give up the story.
[laughter]
What's
What's more
[laughter]
What's more fascinating
What's more fascinating than
[laughter]
What's more fascinating than the
What's more fascinating than the story
of
of your
of your own
of your own life?
of your own life? Tell
of your own life? Tell me
of your own life? Tell me nothing,
right?
right? I
of your own life? Tell me nothing,
right? I mean,
right? I mean, is
of your own life? Tell me nothing,
right? I mean, is it
right? I mean, is it intrinsic?
of your own life? Tell me nothing,
right? I mean, is it intrinsic? It's
intransic,
intransic, isn't
intransic, isn't it?
intransic, isn't it? It's
intransic, isn't it? It's the
intransic, isn't it? It's the great
romance
romance of
intransic, isn't it? It's the great
romance of all
romance of all time
intransic, isn't it? It's the great
romance of all time because
romance of all time because we're
intransic, isn't it? It's the great
romance of all time because we're all
romance of all time because we're all in
love
love with
love with ourselves
love with ourselves secretly
and
and our
love with ourselves secretly
and our story
and our story is
love with ourselves secretly
and our story is is
and our story is is the
love with ourselves secretly
and our story is is the greatest
and our story is is the greatest story
and
and uh
well
well anyway
and uh
well anyway I
well anyway I forget
and uh
well anyway I forget what
well anyway I forget what the
and uh
well anyway I forget what the question
was.
[clears throat]
What
What was
What was the
What was the question?
I
I guess
What was the question?
I guess we
I guess we answered
What was the question?
I guess we answered it.
I guess we answered it. [laughter]
When
When dying,
When dying, does
When dying, does going
When dying, does going into
When dying, does going into the
When dying, does going into the light
keep
keep you
When dying, does going into the light
keep you in
keep you in the
When dying, does going into the light
keep you in the cycle
keep you in the cycle of
When dying, does going into the light
keep you in the cycle of reincarnation?
I
I don't
I don't quite
I don't quite get
I don't quite get there.
Um,
well,
well, it's
well, it's asking
well, it's asking about
well, it's asking about reincarnation,
which
which is
well, it's asking about reincarnation,
which is really
which is really next
well, it's asking about reincarnation,
which is really next month's
which is really next month's lecture.
[laughter]
jumping
jumping the
[laughter]
jumping the gun.
jumping the gun. It
[laughter]
jumping the gun. It It
jumping the gun. It It has
[laughter]
jumping the gun. It It has to
jumping the gun. It It has to do
[laughter]
jumping the gun. It It has to do with
jumping the gun. It It has to do with uh
the
the sense
the sense of
the sense of the
the sense of the reality
the sense of the reality of
the sense of the reality of that
the sense of the reality of that which
is
is experiencing
the sense of the reality of that which
is experiencing what
is experiencing what is
the sense of the reality of that which
is experiencing what is it
is experiencing what is it experiencing.
The
The only
The only death
The only death that's
The only death that's possible
The only death that's possible is
The only death that's possible is death
of
of the
The only death that's possible is death
of the ego.
The
The only
The only death,
The only death, there's
The only death, there's only
The only death, there's only one
The only death, there's only one death
possible.
possible. One
The only death, there's only one death
possible. One one
possible. One one only
The only death, there's only one death
possible. One one only has
possible. One one only has to
The only death, there's only one death
possible. One one only has to die
possible. One one only has to die once
in
in all
in all these
in all these lifetimes.
You
You can
in all these lifetimes.
You can live
You can live 10,000
in all these lifetimes.
You can live 10,000 lifetimes,
You can live 10,000 lifetimes, but
you're
you're only
you're only really
you're only really going
you're only really going to
you're only really going to die
you're only really going to die once.
And
And that's
you're only really going to die once.
And that's one
And that's one of
you're only really going to die once.
And that's one of the
And that's one of the requirements
you're only really going to die once.
And that's one of the requirements to
reach
reach enlightenment.
reach enlightenment. And
reach enlightenment. And the
reach enlightenment. And the requirement
is
is the
reach enlightenment. And the requirement
is the willingness
is the willingness to
reach enlightenment. And the requirement
is the willingness to uh
is the willingness to uh die
cuz
cuz you
cuz you don't
cuz you don't get
cuz you don't get any
cuz you don't get any chance
cuz you don't get any chance to
cuz you don't get any chance to die.
cuz you don't get any chance to die. You
get
get hit
cuz you don't get any chance to die. You
get hit by
get hit by a
cuz you don't get any chance to die. You
get hit by a bowl
get hit by a bowl of
cuz you don't get any chance to die. You
get hit by a bowl of lightning,
get hit by a bowl of lightning, you
cuz you don't get any chance to die. You
get hit by a bowl of lightning, you just
go
go out.
go out. It's
go out. It's great
go out. It's great being
go out. It's great being out.
go out. It's great being out. There's
the
the body
go out. It's great being out. There's
the body all
the body all fried
go out. It's great being out. There's
the body all fried up
the body all fried up there.
Well,
Well, that
Well, that was
Well, that was a
Well, that was a killer
Well, that was a killer that
Well, that was a killer that one.
I
I mean,
Well, that was a killer that one.
I mean, you
I mean, you had
Well, that was a killer that one.
I mean, you had a
I mean, you had a lot
Well, that was a killer that one.
I mean, you had a lot of
I mean, you had a lot of so
Well, that was a killer that one.
I mean, you had a lot of so many
I mean, you had a lot of so many deaths,
you
you know,
you know, they
you know, they piled
you know, they piled up
you know, they piled up over
you know, they piled up over time.
you know, they piled up over time. Dying
at
at the
you know, they piled up over time. Dying
at the oars,
that
that was
that was a
that was a victory.
So
So each
that was a victory.
So each death
So each death seems
that was a victory.
So each death seems to
So each death seems to accomplish
that was a victory.
So each death seems to accomplish some
great
great gain.
great gain. You
great gain. You know
great gain. You know when
great gain. You know when I
great gain. You know when I died
great gain. You know when I died at
great gain. You know when I died at the
h
h I
great gain. You know when I died at the
h I surrendered
and
and I
and I thought
and I thought they
and I thought they can't
and I thought they can't keep
and I thought they can't keep me
and I thought they can't keep me tied
and I thought they can't keep me tied to
this
this goddamn
and I thought they can't keep me tied to
this goddamn thing
this goddamn thing and
and I thought they can't keep me tied to
this goddamn thing and I
this goddamn thing and I just
and I thought they can't keep me tied to
this goddamn thing and I just let
this goddamn thing and I just let myself
die
die and
die and instantly
die and instantly I
die and instantly I was
die and instantly I was out
die and instantly I was out of
die and instantly I was out of it.
die and instantly I was out of it. Whoa,
I'm
I'm free
die and instantly I was out of it. Whoa,
I'm free as
I'm free as a
die and instantly I was out of it. Whoa,
I'm free as a bird.
So
So each
So each death
So each death then
So each death then [clears throat]
seems
seems to
So each death then [clears throat]
seems to have
seems to have within
So each death then [clears throat]
seems to have within it
seems to have within it a
So each death then [clears throat]
seems to have within it a spiritual
lesson.
The
The only
lesson.
The only one
The only one death
lesson.
The only one death you
The only one death you can
lesson.
The only one death you can actually
The only one death you can actually do
which
which we
which we won't
which we won't really
which we won't really get
which we won't really get up
which we won't really get up to
which we won't really get up to the
which we won't really get up to the last
uh
uh lecture.
which we won't really get up to the last
uh lecture. There's
uh lecture. There's only
which we won't really get up to the last
uh lecture. There's only one
uh lecture. There's only one death
which we won't really get up to the last
uh lecture. There's only one death you
actually
actually experience
actually experience and
actually experience and that
actually experience and that is
actually experience and that is the
experience
experience of
actually experience and that is the
experience of death
experience of death itself.
actually experience and that is the
experience of death itself. It's
experience of death itself. It's the
only
only time
only time you've
only time you've ever
only time you've ever had
only time you've ever had a
only time you've ever had a chance
only time you've ever had a chance to
experience
experience it
only time you've ever had a chance to
experience it and
experience it and it's
only time you've ever had a chance to
experience it and it's the
experience it and it's the only
only time you've ever had a chance to
experience it and it's the only time
you'll
you'll ever
you'll ever have
you'll ever have to
you'll ever have to go
you'll ever have to go through
you'll ever have to go through it.
you'll ever have to go through it. And
people
people need
you'll ever have to go through it. And
people need to
people need to be
you'll ever have to go through it. And
people need to be coached
people need to be coached in
you'll ever have to go through it. And
people need to be coached in advance
about
about that
about that state
about that state because
about that state because if
about that state because if you're
about that state because if you're a
serious
serious spiritual
about that state because if you're a
serious spiritual student,
serious spiritual student, sooner
about that state because if you're a
serious spiritual student, sooner or
later
later you'll
later you'll meet
later you'll meet that
later you'll meet that door.
later you'll meet that door. So
later you'll meet that door. So that
that'll
that'll be
later you'll meet that door. So that
that'll be the
that'll be the last
later you'll meet that door. So that
that'll be the last lecture.
that'll be the last lecture. How
later you'll meet that door. So that
that'll be the last lecture. How to
that'll be the last lecture. How to get
through
through that
through that door.
through that door. There's
through that door. There's only
through that door. There's only one
death
death you're
through that door. There's only one
death you're after.
death you're after. All
through that door. There's only one
death you're after. All right?
death you're after. All right? So
through that door. There's only one
death you're after. All right? So the
preparation
preparation for
preparation for what's
preparation for what's required
preparation for what's required at
preparation for what's required at the
final
final door
preparation for what's required at the
final door is
final door is what's
preparation for what's required at the
final door is what's going
final door is what's going on
preparation for what's required at the
final door is what's going on now.
final door is what's going on now. Your
devotion
devotion to
devotion to God
devotion to God has
devotion to God has to
devotion to God has to be
devotion to God has to be absolute.
devotion to God has to be absolute. The
devotion
devotion to
devotion to God has to be absolute. The
devotion to God
devotion to God has
devotion to God has to be absolute. The
devotion to God has to
devotion to God has to supersede
devotion to God has to be absolute. The
devotion to God has to supersede all
else.
And
And that's
else.
And that's what
And that's what carries
else.
And that's what carries you
And that's what carries you through
else.
And that's what carries you through the
final
final door
final door is
final door is the
final door is the willingness
final door is the willingness to
surrender
surrender what
final door is the willingness to
surrender what you
surrender what you think
final door is the willingness to
surrender what you think and
surrender what you think and belief
final door is the willingness to
surrender what you think and belief in
your
your most
your most inner
your most inner conviction
your most inner conviction is
your most inner conviction is life
itself.
itself. We
your most inner conviction is life
itself. We said
itself. We said attractor
your most inner conviction is life
itself. We said attractor fields.
itself. We said attractor fields. We
said
said from
said from the
said from the viewpoint
said from the viewpoint of
said from the viewpoint of nonlinear
nonlinear
nonlinear dynamics
said from the viewpoint of nonlinear
nonlinear dynamics chaos
nonlinear dynamics chaos theory.
said from the viewpoint of nonlinear
nonlinear dynamics chaos theory. Each
nonlinear dynamics chaos theory. Each of
these
these fields
these fields that
these fields that calibrates
these fields that calibrates here
these fields that calibrates here is
these fields that calibrates here is a
calibrated
calibrated field
these fields that calibrates here is a
calibrated field of
calibrated field of energy
these fields that calibrates here is a
calibrated field of energy at
calibrated field of energy at the
these fields that calibrates here is a
calibrated field of energy at the center
of
of which
of which there
of which there is
of which there is a
of which there is a so-called
of which there is a so-called attractor
field.
field. There's
of which there is a so-called attractor
field. There's an
field. There's an attractor
of which there is a so-called attractor
field. There's an attractor field.
You
You might
You might picture
You might picture it
You might picture it like
You might picture it like when
You might picture it like when you
You might picture it like when you see
the
the birds
You might picture it like when you see
the birds as
the birds as they
You might picture it like when you see
the birds as they as
the birds as they as they
You might picture it like when you see
the birds as they as they swing
the birds as they as they swing about
You might picture it like when you see
the birds as they as they swing about in
a
a huge
a huge flock
a huge flock and
a huge flock and the
a huge flock and the design
a huge flock and the design that
a huge flock and the design that they
play.
play. What
a huge flock and the design that they
play. What you're
play. What you're seeing
a huge flock and the design that they
play. What you're seeing is
play. What you're seeing is the
demonstration
demonstration of
demonstration of an
demonstration of an inner
demonstration of an inner invisible
attractor
attractor field
demonstration of an inner invisible
attractor field and
attractor field and that
demonstration of an inner invisible
attractor field and that attractor
attractor field and that attractor field
is
is dominating
is dominating them.
is dominating them. So
is dominating them. So what
is dominating them. So what you
is dominating them. So what you think
is dominating them. So what you think is
that
that each
is dominating them. So what you think is
that each bird
that each bird is
is dominating them. So what you think is
that each bird is following
that each bird is following another
is dominating them. So what you think is
that each bird is following another bird
like
like uh
like uh pilots
like uh pilots in
like uh pilots in the
like uh pilots in the sky.
like uh pilots in the sky. No,
like uh pilots in the sky. No, they're
not.
not. Each
like uh pilots in the sky. No, they're
not. Each bird
not. Each bird is
like uh pilots in the sky. No, they're
not. Each bird is following
not. Each bird is following the
like uh pilots in the sky. No, they're
not. Each bird is following the inner
not. Each bird is following the inner h
inner
inner song.
inner song. His
inner song. His own
inner song. His own inner
inner song. His own inner song
inner song. His own inner song is
telling
telling him
inner song. His own inner song is
telling him to
telling him to go
inner song. His own inner song is
telling him to go this
telling him to go this way.
inner song. His own inner song is
telling him to go this way. And
telling him to go this way. And this
bird's
bird's inner
bird's inner song
bird's inner song is
bird's inner song is also
bird's inner song is also telling
bird's inner song is also telling him
bird's inner song is also telling him to
go
go this
bird's inner song is also telling him to
go this way.
go this way. And
bird's inner song is also telling him to
go this way. And this
go this way. And this bird's
bird's inner song is also telling him to
go this way. And this bird's inner
go this way. And this bird's inner song.
Each
Each bird
Each bird is
Each bird is independently
Each bird is independently controlled
Each bird is independently controlled by
the
the energy
Each bird is independently controlled by
the energy field.
the energy field. They're
Each bird is independently controlled by
the energy field. They're not
the energy field. They're not controlled
by
by each
by each other.
by each other. They're
by each other. They're not
by each other. They're not like
by each other. They're not like pilots.
10 ft
10 ft from
by each other. They're not like pilots.
10 ft from you,
10 ft from you, 10
by each other. They're not like pilots.
10 ft from you, 10 ft
10 ft from you, 10 ft from
by each other. They're not like pilots.
10 ft from you, 10 ft from you,
10 ft from you, 10 ft from you, 32
by each other. They're not like pilots.
10 ft from you, 10 ft from you, 32 ft
from
from you,
from you, 44t
from you, 44t from
from you, 44t from you.
That's
That's the
from you, 44t from you.
That's the ego's
That's the ego's view
from you, 44t from you.
That's the ego's view of
That's the ego's view of it.
from you, 44t from you.
That's the ego's view of it. No,
That's the ego's view of it. No, each
from you, 44t from you.
That's the ego's view of it. No, each of
these
these birds
these birds is
these birds is surrendered
these birds is surrendered to
these birds is surrendered to be
these birds is surrendered to be the
servant
servant of
these birds is surrendered to be the
servant of its
servant of its inner
these birds is surrendered to be the
servant of its inner guide.
servant of its inner guide. And
these birds is surrendered to be the
servant of its inner guide. And it
servant of its inner guide. And it goes
uh
uh as
uh as it's
uh as it's guided
uh as it's guided by
uh as it's guided by the
uh as it's guided by the inner
uh as it's guided by the inner attractor
field.
And
And the
And the way
And the way we
And the way we isolate
And the way we isolate and
And the way we isolate and identify
And the way we isolate and identify an
attractor
attractor field
And the way we isolate and identify an
attractor field is
attractor field is merely
And the way we isolate and identify an
attractor field is merely by
kinesiology.
The
The number
kinesiology.
The number of
The number of people
kinesiology.
The number of people over
The number of people over 200.
kinesiology.
The number of people over 200. We
The number of people over 200. We say
it's
it's increased.
it's increased. Yes.
it's increased. Yes. Um
it's increased. Yes. Um when
it's increased. Yes. Um when we
it's increased. Yes. Um when we wrote
the
the book
it's increased. Yes. Um when we wrote
the book in
the book in 95,
it's increased. Yes. Um when we wrote
the book in 95, I
the book in 95, I think
it's increased. Yes. Um when we wrote
the book in 95, I think we
the book in 95, I think we did
it's increased. Yes. Um when we wrote
the book in 95, I think we did the
calibrations
calibrations in
calibrations in 94.
uh
uh consciousness
calibrations in 94.
uh consciousness level.
uh consciousness level. We
calibrations in 94.
uh consciousness level. We said
uh consciousness level. We said that
calibrations in 94.
uh consciousness level. We said that um
I
I have
I have to forget
I have to forget all
I have to forget all these
I have to forget all these numbers
I have to forget all these numbers now
but
but uh
the
the number
the number of
the number of people
the number of people on
the number of people on the
the number of people on the planet
the number of people on the planet who
have
have risen
the number of people on the planet who
have risen in
have risen in their
the number of people on the planet who
have risen in their level
have risen in their level of
consciousness
consciousness has
consciousness has increased
consciousness has increased quite
consciousness has increased quite a
consciousness has increased quite a bit.
It's
It's uh
consciousness has increased quite a bit.
It's uh it
It's uh it was
consciousness has increased quite a bit.
It's uh it was 80%
It's uh it was 80% of
consciousness has increased quite a bit.
It's uh it was 80% of the
It's uh it was 80% of the people
consciousness has increased quite a bit.
It's uh it was 80% of the people were
less
less than
less than 200
less than 200 now
less than 200 now it's
less than 200 now it's only
less than 200 now it's only 78%.
less than 200 now it's only 78%. So
less than 200 now it's only 78%. So the
consciousness
consciousness level
less than 200 now it's only 78%. So the
consciousness level of
consciousness level of mankind
less than 200 now it's only 78%. So the
consciousness level of mankind is
constantly
constantly rising.
constantly rising. I
constantly rising. I mean
constantly rising. I mean groups
constantly rising. I mean groups like
this
this and
constantly rising. I mean groups like
this and the
this and the spiritual
constantly rising. I mean groups like
this and the spiritual work
this and the spiritual work they
constantly rising. I mean groups like
this and the spiritual work they do
this and the spiritual work they do you
know
know affects
know affects the
know affects the whole
know affects the whole field
know affects the whole field of
consciousness.
consciousness. I
know affects the whole field of
consciousness. I mean
consciousness. I mean what
know affects the whole field of
consciousness. I mean what we're
consciousness. I mean what we're doing
and
and saying
and saying today
and saying today is
and saying today is affecting
um
the
the whole
the whole world.
the whole world. Let's
the whole world. Let's see
that's
that's a
the whole world. Let's see
that's a fact
that's a fact resist
the
the ripples
the ripples that
the ripples that go
the ripples that go out
the ripples that go out are
the ripples that go out are affecting
the
the whole
the ripples that go out are affecting
the whole field
the whole field of
the ripples that go out are affecting
the whole field of consciousness.
the whole field of consciousness. So
the ripples that go out are affecting
the whole field of consciousness. So all
the
the people
the people in
the people in the
the people in the world
the people in the world committed
the people in the world committed to
the
the evolution
the people in the world committed to
the evolution of
the evolution of consciousness
radiate
radiate out
radiate out into
radiate out into the
radiate out into the field
radiate out into the field and
radiate out into the field and that
field
field is
radiate out into the field and that
field is like
field is like the
radiate out into the field and that
field is like the sea
field is like the sea and
radiate out into the field and that
field is like the sea and that
field is like the sea and that sea
radiate out into the field and that
field is like the sea and that sea then
supports
supports the
supports the consciousness
supports the consciousness of
supports the consciousness of everyone.
People
People of
supports the consciousness of everyone.
People of elsewhere
People of elsewhere wake
supports the consciousness of everyone.
People of elsewhere wake up
People of elsewhere wake up in
supports the consciousness of everyone.
People of elsewhere wake up in the
morning
morning and
morning and they
morning and they suddenly
morning and they suddenly make
morning and they suddenly make a
different
different decision
morning and they suddenly make a
different decision today
different decision today than
morning and they suddenly make a
different decision today than they
different decision today than they have
made
made all
made all their
made all their life.
made all their life. I've
made all their life. I've always
made all their life. I've always thought
this
this way
made all their life. I've always thought
this way and
this way and suddenly
made all their life. I've always thought
this way and suddenly they
this way and suddenly they say
made all their life. I've always thought
this way and suddenly they say you
this way and suddenly they say you know
I
I could
I could see
I could see it
I could see it this
I could see it this way.
Well,
Well, there
I could see it this way.
Well, there that
Well, there that energy
I could see it this way.
Well, there that energy out
Well, there that energy out there
I could see it this way.
Well, there that energy out there makes
it
it harder
it harder to
it harder to be
it harder to be negative.
it harder to be negative. So,
it harder to be negative. So, it's
harder
harder to
it harder to be negative. So, it's
harder to be
harder to be negative
it harder to be negative. So, it's
harder to be negative now
harder to be negative now than
it harder to be negative. So, it's
harder to be negative now than it
harder to be negative now than it was.
[laughter]
It's
It's very
[laughter]
It's very hard
It's very hard to
[laughter]
It's very hard to be
It's very hard to be negative.
[laughter]
It's very hard to be negative. I
It's very hard to be negative. I mean,
you
you got
you got to
you got to work
you got to work at
you got to work at it
you got to work at it nowadays,
you got to work at it nowadays, you
know.
You
You got
You got to
You got to go
You got to go off
You got to go off in
You got to go off in some
You got to go off in some god
You got to go off in some god aful
You got to go off in some god aful place
on
on the
You got to go off in some god aful place
on the planet
on the planet and
You got to go off in some god aful place
on the planet and listen
on the planet and listen to
You got to go off in some god aful place
on the planet and listen to some
on the planet and listen to some really
weird
weird people
weird people and
weird people and get
weird people and get brainwashed
weird people and get brainwashed in
order
order to
weird people and get brainwashed in
order to be
order to be that
weird people and get brainwashed in
order to be that way.
order to be that way. You
weird people and get brainwashed in
order to be that way. You know,
order to be that way. You know, now
weird people and get brainwashed in
order to be that way. You know, now it's
hard
hard to
hard to do
hard to do that.
Uh
do
do the
do the demands
do the demands of
do the demands of ordinary
do the demands of ordinary life
interfere
interfere with
do the demands of ordinary life
interfere with uh
interfere with uh spiritual
do the demands of ordinary life
interfere with uh spiritual evolution
and
and work?
and work? Uh
and work? Uh no.
and work? Uh no. As
and work? Uh no. As we
and work? Uh no. As we said,
and work? Uh no. As we said, everything
gets
gets contextualized
and work? Uh no. As we said, everything
gets contextualized differently
gets contextualized differently now.
Everything
Everything gets
Everything gets contextualized.
And
And you
Everything gets contextualized.
And you shine
And you shine everything
Everything gets contextualized.
And you shine everything out
And you shine everything out of
Everything gets contextualized.
And you shine everything out of love
And you shine everything out of love for
God.
God. You
God. You uh
God. You uh sweep
God. You uh sweep the
God. You uh sweep the floor
God. You uh sweep the floor out
God. You uh sweep the floor out of
devotion
devotion to
God. You uh sweep the floor out of
devotion to one's
devotion to one's children
God. You uh sweep the floor out of
devotion to one's children and
devotion to one's children and family.
You
You peel
You peel the
You peel the potatoes
You peel the potatoes for
You peel the potatoes for the
You peel the potatoes for the same
reason.
Can
Can techniques
Can techniques which
Can techniques which lower
Can techniques which lower one's
Can techniques which lower one's brain
wave
wave frequency
Can techniques which lower one's brain
wave frequency also
wave frequency also raise
Can techniques which lower one's brain
wave frequency also raise one's
wave frequency also raise one's level
Can techniques which lower one's brain
wave frequency also raise one's level of
consciousness?
H
H I
consciousness?
H I don't
H I don't know
consciousness?
H I don't know how
H I don't know how to
consciousness?
H I don't know how to rest
H I don't know how to rest up.
consciousness?
H I don't know how to rest up. What
they're
they're meaning
they're meaning is
they're meaning is uh
they're meaning is uh they're
they're meaning is uh they're talking
about
about here
they're meaning is uh they're talking
about here alpha
about here alpha alpha
they're meaning is uh they're talking
about here alpha alpha wave
about here alpha alpha wave training.
Uh
Uh the
Uh the answer
Uh the answer to
Uh the answer to this
Uh the answer to this is
Uh the answer to this is yes.
Uh the answer to this is yes. Huh?
Uh the answer to this is yes. Huh? Says
yes.
yes. There
Uh the answer to this is yes. Huh? Says
yes. There are
yes. There are various
Uh the answer to this is yes. Huh? Says
yes. There are various uh
yes. There are various uh techniques.
Uh the answer to this is yes. Huh? Says
yes. There are various uh techniques. Um
[laughter]
or
or does
[laughter]
or does it
or does it work
[laughter]
or does it work in
or does it work in the
[laughter]
or does it work in the opposite
direction?
direction? Works
direction? Works in
direction? Works in the
direction? Works in the opposite
direction.
direction. And
direction? Works in the opposite
direction. And the
direction. And the more
direction? Works in the opposite
direction. And the more advanced
direction. And the more advanced your
consciousness
consciousness gets,
consciousness gets, the
consciousness gets, the slower
consciousness gets, the slower your
brain
brain waves
consciousness gets, the slower your
brain waves get.
brain waves get. And
consciousness gets, the slower your
brain waves get. And uh
brain waves get. And uh finally,
consciousness gets, the slower your
brain waves get. And uh finally, they
they
they become
they become ridiculously
they become ridiculously low.
>> [laughter]
>> You
>> You wonder
>> You wonder how
>> You wonder how you
>> You wonder how you survive.
>> You wonder how you survive. Anyway,
there
there is
>> You wonder how you survive. Anyway,
there is a
there is a brain
>> You wonder how you survive. Anyway,
there is a brain wave
there is a brain wave every
>> You wonder how you survive. Anyway,
there is a brain wave every once
there is a brain wave every once in
>> You wonder how you survive. Anyway,
there is a brain wave every once in a
while
while that
while that keeps
while that keeps you
while that keeps you going.
[laughter]
To
To function
To function effectively
To function effectively in
To function effectively in the
To function effectively in the world,
you
you got
To function effectively in the world,
you got to
you got to have
To function effectively in the world,
you got to have 15
you got to have 15 cycles
To function effectively in the world,
you got to have 15 cycles per
you got to have 15 cycles per second.
14 15.
14 15. So,
14 15. So, I
14 15. So, I have
14 15. So, I have great
14 15. So, I have great hopes
14 15. So, I have great hopes that
President
President Bush
14 15. So, I have great hopes that
President Bush is
President Bush is running
14 15. So, I have great hopes that
President Bush is running at
President Bush is running at about
14 15. So, I have great hopes that
President Bush is running at about 400
[laughter]
is
is running
[laughter]
is running at
is running at beta
[laughter]
is running at beta rhythm
is running at beta rhythm 10
[laughter]
is running at beta rhythm 10 to
is running at beta rhythm 10 to 14
[laughter]
is running at beta rhythm 10 to 14 or
whatever
whatever it
whatever it is.
whatever it is. Hm.
whatever it is. Hm. [clears throat]
We
We didn't
whatever it is. Hm. [clears throat]
We didn't really
We didn't really answer
whatever it is. Hm. [clears throat]
We didn't really answer the
We didn't really answer the Bush
question.
question. The
question. The Bush
question. The Bush question
question. The Bush question is
question. The Bush question is uh
question. The Bush question is uh is
question. The Bush question is uh is one
in
in which
question. The Bush question is uh is one
in which you
in which you how
question. The Bush question is uh is one
in which you how you
in which you how you contextualize
question. The Bush question is uh is one
in which you how you contextualize it
to
to um
to um defend
to um defend um
to um defend um one's
to um defend um one's honor
to um defend um one's honor to
to um defend um one's honor to to
to um defend um one's honor to to defend
the
the innocent
to
to stand
to stand for
to stand for truth
to stand for truth is
to stand for truth is the
to stand for truth is the archetypally
the
the spiritual
to stand for truth is the archetypally
the spiritual warrior.
The
The spiritual
The spiritual warrior
The spiritual warrior is
The spiritual warrior is not
The spiritual warrior is not aggressive.
The
The spiritual
The spiritual warrior is not aggressive.
The spiritual warrior
The spiritual warrior however
The spiritual warrior is not aggressive.
The spiritual warrior however is
extremely
extremely fierce
extremely fierce if
extremely fierce if you
extremely fierce if you challenge
extremely fierce if you challenge him
within
within ourselves.
extremely fierce if you challenge him
within ourselves. Sooner
within ourselves. Sooner or
extremely fierce if you challenge him
within ourselves. Sooner or later
within ourselves. Sooner or later we
extremely fierce if you challenge him
within ourselves. Sooner or later we get
confronted
and
and we
confronted
and we have
and we have to
confronted
and we have to find
and we have to find within
confronted
and we have to find within ourself
and we have to find within ourself the
strength
strength to
strength to stand
strength to stand up
strength to stand up and
strength to stand up and defend
strength to stand up and defend truth
which
which is
strength to stand up and defend truth
which is not
which is not an
strength to stand up and defend truth
which is not an act
which is not an act of
strength to stand up and defend truth
which is not an act of aggression.
which is not an act of aggression. It's
an
an act
an act of
an act of assertion
an act of assertion and
an act of assertion and it's
an act of assertion and it's an
an act of assertion and it's an act
an act of assertion and it's an act of
confirmation.
If
If suddenly
If suddenly somebody
If suddenly somebody comes
If suddenly somebody comes and
If suddenly somebody comes and starts
destroying
destroying your
If suddenly somebody comes and starts
destroying your world
destroying your world or
If suddenly somebody comes and starts
destroying your world or destroying
destroying your world or destroying your
people
people or
people or destroying
people or destroying your
people or destroying your country
people or destroying your country then
out
out of
people or destroying your country then
out of love
out of love for
people or destroying your country then
out of love for the
out of love for the remainder
people or destroying your country then
out of love for the remainder I
out of love for the remainder I mean
people or destroying your country then
out of love for the remainder I mean out
of
of love
of love one
of love one defends
uh
uh against
of love one defends
uh against undo
uh against undo aggression
of love one defends
uh against undo aggression huh
it
it would
it would be
it would be um
it would be um Bush's
it would be um Bush's responsibility
in
in fact
it would be um Bush's responsibility
in fact his
in fact his his
it would be um Bush's responsibility
in fact his his oath
in fact his his oath of
it would be um Bush's responsibility
in fact his his oath of office
in fact his his oath of office would
require
require that
require that he
require that he support
require that he support the
require that he support the constitution
and
and that
require that he support the constitution
and that he
and that he defend
require that he support the constitution
and that he defend the
and that he defend the life
require that he support the constitution
and that he defend the life of
and that he defend the life of Americans
when
when they're
when they're under
when they're under attack.
when they're under attack. That's
when they're under attack. That's his
constitutional
commitment.
commitment. And
commitment. And I
commitment. And I think
commitment. And I think it
commitment. And I think it would
commitment. And I think it would be
commitment. And I think it would be a
spiritual
spiritual failure
commitment. And I think it would be a
spiritual failure not
spiritual failure not to
commitment. And I think it would be a
spiritual failure not to do
spiritual failure not to do so.
commitment. And I think it would be a
spiritual failure not to do so. Let's
see.
see. Okay,
see. Okay, let's
see. Okay, let's just
see. Okay, let's just see
see. Okay, let's just see if
see. Okay, let's just see if that's
see. Okay, let's just see if that's so
the
the president's
see. Okay, let's just see if that's so
the president's um
the president's um commitment
see. Okay, let's just see if that's so
the president's um commitment which
the president's um commitment which he
has
has taken
has taken an
has taken an oath
has taken an oath is
has taken an oath is to
has taken an oath is to defend
has taken an oath is to defend the
American
American people
has taken an oath is to defend the
American people against
American people against undue
has taken an oath is to defend the
American people against undue aggression
resistance.
resistance. Yeah,
resistance. Yeah, he's
resistance. Yeah, he's under
resistance. Yeah, he's under oath
resistance. Yeah, he's under oath to
resistance. Yeah, he's under oath to do
what
what he's
resistance. Yeah, he's under oath to do
what he's doing
what he's doing and
resistance. Yeah, he's under oath to do
what he's doing and he
what he's doing and he would
resistance. Yeah, he's under oath to do
what he's doing and he would be
what he's doing and he would be quite
resistance. Yeah, he's under oath to do
what he's doing and he would be quite um
uh
uh in
uh in error
uh in error not
uh in error not to
uh in error not to do
uh in error not to do so
uh in error not to do so to
uh in error not to do so to defend
uh in error not to do so to defend u
uh in error not to do so to defend u the
innocent.
innocent. So
uh in error not to do so to defend u the
innocent. So if
innocent. So if someone
uh in error not to do so to defend u the
innocent. So if someone is
innocent. So if someone is attacking
your
your home
your home and
your home and your
your home and your family
your home and your family or
your home and your family or your
children
children then
your home and your family or your
children then um
children then um you
your home and your family or your
children then um you ethically
children then um you ethically and
spiritually
spiritually uh
spiritually uh are
spiritually uh are entitled
spiritually uh are entitled to
spiritually uh are entitled to defend
uh
that
that which
that which is
that which is being
that which is being attacked.
You
You remember
that which is being attacked.
You remember when
You remember when uh
that which is being attacked.
You remember when uh Jesus
You remember when uh Jesus uh
that which is being attacked.
You remember when uh Jesus uh chased
You remember when uh Jesus uh chased the
money
money changers
money changers out
money changers out of
money changers out of the
money changers out of the temple?
money changers out of the temple? Um
money changers out of the temple? Um I
was
was wondering
money changers out of the temple? Um I
was wondering what
was wondering what that
money changers out of the temple? Um I
was wondering what that meant.
was wondering what that meant. You
money changers out of the temple? Um I
was wondering what that meant. You mean
he
he was
he was angry
he was angry and
he was angry and had
he was angry and had a
he was angry and had a fit
he was angry and had a fit or
he was angry and had a fit or something?
Didn't
Didn't seem
he was angry and had a fit or something?
Didn't seem like
Didn't seem like Jesus
he was angry and had a fit or something?
Didn't seem like Jesus to
Didn't seem like Jesus to me
he was angry and had a fit or something?
Didn't seem like Jesus to me would
Didn't seem like Jesus to me would have
a
a fit
a fit about
a fit about the
a fit about the thing.
>> No,
>> No, but
a fit about the thing.
>> No, but he
>> No, but he came
a fit about the thing.
>> No, but he came into
>> No, but he came into out
a fit about the thing.
>> No, but he came into out of
>> No, but he came into out of his
spiritual
spiritual warrior
spiritual warrior and
spiritual warrior and said
spiritual warrior and said this
spiritual warrior and said this is
spiritual warrior and said this is an
non-
non- integrous
spiritual warrior and said this is an
non- integrous and
non- integrous and it's
spiritual warrior and said this is an
non- integrous and it's a
non- integrous and it's a desecration
spiritual warrior and said this is an
non- integrous and it's a desecration of
what
what the
what the temple
what the temple stands
what the temple stands for.
what the temple stands for. So
what the temple stands for. So he
what the temple stands for. So he was
like
like defending
what the temple stands for. So he was
like defending the
like defending the truth.
what the temple stands for. So he was
like defending the truth. You
like defending the truth. You understand
what
what I'm
what I'm saying?
what I'm saying? That
what I'm saying? That explained
what I'm saying? That explained it.
what I'm saying? That explained it. So
that
that was
what I'm saying? That explained it. So
that was the
that was the first
what I'm saying? That explained it. So
that was the first time
that was the first time I
what I'm saying? That explained it. So
that was the first time I really
understand
understand what
understand what what
understand what what he
understand what what he was
understand what what he was about
understand what what he was about there.
He
He was
understand what what he was about there.
He was sort
He was sort of
understand what what he was about there.
He was sort of like
He was sort of like indignant
understand what what he was about there.
He was sort of like indignant about
He was sort of like indignant about the
desecration.
desecration. So
desecration. So like
desecration. So like each
desecration. So like each of
desecration. So like each of us
desecration. So like each of us feels
desecration. So like each of us feels a
certain
certain indign
desecration. So like each of us feels a
certain indign indignation
that
that the
that the innocence
that the innocence of
that the innocence of these
probably
probably extremely
that the innocence of these
probably extremely devoted
Muslim
Muslim boys
Muslim boys is
Muslim boys is being
Muslim boys is being raped
Muslim boys is being raped and
Muslim boys is being raped and taken
over
over by
Muslim boys is being raped and taken
over by that
over by that which
Muslim boys is being raped and taken
over by that which is
over by that which is non-integrous.
and
and telling
and telling them
and telling them lies
and telling them lies and
and telling them lies and getting
and telling them lies and getting them
to
to destroy
and telling them lies and getting them
to destroy themsel
to destroy themsel in
and telling them lies and getting them
to destroy themsel in service
to destroy themsel in service to
and telling them lies and getting them
to destroy themsel in service to that
which
which is
which is the
which is the opposite
which is the opposite of
which is the opposite of love
which is the opposite of love and
which is the opposite of love and truth.
All
All of
which is the opposite of love and truth.
All of us
All of us feel
which is the opposite of love and truth.
All of us feel a
All of us feel a certain
which is the opposite of love and truth.
All of us feel a certain indignation
about
about it.
about it. Indignation.
You
You can
about it. Indignation.
You can take
You can take any
about it. Indignation.
You can take any young
You can take any young child,
about it. Indignation.
You can take any young child, you
You can take any young child, you know,
and
and brainwash
and brainwash them
and brainwash them and
and brainwash them and uh
and brainwash them and uh into
and brainwash them and uh into believing
anything.
anything. And
and brainwash them and uh into believing
anything. And anybody's
anything. And anybody's seen
and brainwash them and uh into believing
anything. And anybody's seen um
anything. And anybody's seen um things
on
on the
on the History
on the History Channel
on the History Channel about
on the History Channel about life
on the History Channel about life in
on the History Channel about life in in
Hitler's
Hitler's Germany
on the History Channel about life in in
Hitler's Germany remembers
Hitler's Germany remembers how
on the History Channel about life in in
Hitler's Germany remembers how the
children
children were
children were carefully
children were carefully brainwashed
children were carefully brainwashed from
childhood.
uh
uh they
uh they couldn't
uh they couldn't believe
uh they couldn't believe anything
uh they couldn't believe anything else
except
except what
uh they couldn't believe anything else
except what they
except what they believed.
uh they couldn't believe anything else
except what they believed. So
except what they believed. So their
innocence,
innocence, their
innocence, their intrinsic
innocence, their intrinsic innocence
innocence, their intrinsic innocence is
uh
uh is
innocence, their intrinsic innocence is
uh is um
uh is um taken
innocence, their intrinsic innocence is
uh is um taken advantage
uh is um taken advantage of.
innocence, their intrinsic innocence is
uh is um taken advantage of. On
uh is um taken advantage of. On the
other
other hand,
other hand, you
other hand, you have
other hand, you have to
other hand, you have to defend
other hand, you have to defend yourself
against
against them.
other hand, you have to defend yourself
against them. You
against them. You understand?
other hand, you have to defend yourself
against them. You understand? You
against them. You understand? You don't
have
have to
have to make
have to make somebody
have to make somebody wrong
have to make somebody wrong to
have to make somebody wrong to defend
yourself
yourself against
have to make somebody wrong to defend
yourself against them.
yourself against them. Out
have to make somebody wrong to defend
yourself against them. Out of
yourself against them. Out of innocence,
they
they can
they can run
they can run you
they can run you over.
Out
Out of
they can run you over.
Out of innocence,
Out of innocence, they
they can run you over.
Out of innocence, they can
Out of innocence, they can kill
they can run you over.
Out of innocence, they can kill you.
Out of innocence, they can kill you. Uh
but
but so
but so you
but so you have
but so you have to
but so you have to take
but so you have to take u
but so you have to take u protect
but so you have to take u protect self-p
protection.
protection. So
but so you have to take u protect self-p
protection. So that's
protection. So that's how
but so you have to take u protect self-p
protection. So that's how I
protection. So that's how I see
but so you have to take u protect self-p
protection. So that's how I see Bush.
He's
He's he's
He's he's obligated.
He's he's obligated. He's
He's he's obligated. He's obligated
He's he's obligated. He's obligated to
defend
defend the
He's he's obligated. He's obligated to
defend the country
defend the country against
He's he's obligated. He's obligated to
defend the country against that
defend the country against that which
He's he's obligated. He's obligated to
defend the country against that which he
considers
considers to
considers to be
considers to be attack.
considers to be attack. The
considers to be attack. The other
considers to be attack. The other thing
about
about politics
considers to be attack. The other thing
about politics is,
about politics is, you
considers to be attack. The other thing
about politics is, you know,
about politics is, you know, because
what
what we
what we know
what we know about
what we know about politics
what we know about politics only
what we know about politics only comes
through
through the
what we know about politics only comes
through the media.
through the media. Well,
what we know about politics only comes
through the media. Well, what
through the media. Well, what comes
through
through the
through the media
through the media has
through the media has been
through the media has been strained,
mangled,
mangled, distorted,
through the media has been strained,
mangled, distorted, and
mangled, distorted, and twisted
through the media has been strained,
mangled, distorted, and twisted and
decided,
decided, and
decided, and you
decided, and you don't
decided, and you don't know
decided, and you don't know what
decided, and you don't know what the
truth
truth is.
decided, and you don't know what the
truth is. So,
truth is. So, you
decided, and you don't know what the
truth is. So, you can't
truth is. So, you can't really
decided, and you don't know what the
truth is. So, you can't really have
truth is. So, you can't really have a
political
political opinion
political opinion because
political opinion because you
political opinion because you don't
political opinion because you don't know
what
what the
political opinion because you don't know
what the political
what the political facts
political opinion because you don't know
what the political facts really
what the political facts really are.
I've
I've been
I've been in
I've been in circles
I've been in circles back
I've been in circles back east
I've been in circles back east where
over
over lunch
I've been in circles back east where
over lunch like
over lunch like it
I've been in circles back east where
over lunch like it was
over lunch like it was nothing
I've been in circles back east where
over lunch like it was nothing at
over lunch like it was nothing at all.
Great
Great baronss
Great baronss of
Great baronss of industry
Great baronss of industry and
Great baronss of industry and finance
would
would say,
Great baronss of industry and finance
would say, "Oh,
would say, "Oh, come
Great baronss of industry and finance
would say, "Oh, come on.
would say, "Oh, come on. Quarter
Great baronss of industry and finance
would say, "Oh, come on. Quarter of
would say, "Oh, come on. Quarter of a
point."
point." Yeah.
point." Yeah. All right.
point." Yeah. All right. Quarter
point." Yeah. All right. Quarter of
point." Yeah. All right. Quarter of a
point.
point. The
point." Yeah. All right. Quarter of a
point. The lives
point. The lives of
point." Yeah. All right. Quarter of a
point. The lives of millions
point. The lives of millions of
point." Yeah. All right. Quarter of a
point. The lives of millions of people
have
have just
have just gotten
have just gotten screwed.
have just gotten screwed. [laughter]
A
A quarter
have just gotten screwed. [laughter]
A quarter point.
A quarter point. Everybody's
have just gotten screwed. [laughter]
A quarter point. Everybody's mortgage
across
across 50
across 50 million
across 50 million people.
across 50 million people. Well,
across 50 million people. Well, you're
talking
talking about
across 50 million people. Well, you're
talking about billions.
talking about billions. You
across 50 million people. Well, you're
talking about billions. You know what
I'm
I'm saying?
I'm saying? So,
I'm saying? So, does
I'm saying? So, does the
I'm saying? So, does the public
I'm saying? So, does the public know
that
that went
I'm saying? So, does the public know
that went on?
that went on? No.
I'm saying? So, does the public know
that went on? No. Do
that went on? No. Do we
I'm saying? So, does the public know
that went on? No. Do we know
that went on? No. Do we know what
I'm saying? So, does the public know
that went on? No. Do we know what uh
Bush
Bush knows
Bush knows about
Bush knows about the
Bush knows about the international
situation?
situation? We
Bush knows about the international
situation? We don't
situation? We don't know
Bush knows about the international
situation? We don't know what
situation? We don't know what it
Bush knows about the international
situation? We don't know what it is.
situation? We don't know what it is. Uh
do
do we
do we know
do we know what
do we know what the
do we know what the Secret
do we know what the Secret Service
knows?
knows? We
do we know what the Secret Service
knows? We don't
knows? We don't know
do we know what the Secret Service
knows? We don't know what
knows? We don't know what anybody
do we know what the Secret Service
knows? We don't know what anybody knows.
We
We can
We can only
We can only go
We can only go by
We can only go by what.
We can only go by what. So
We can only go by what. So our
We can only go by what. So our opinions
are
are already
We can only go by what. So our opinions
are already manipulated
are already manipulated by
We can only go by what. So our opinions
are already manipulated by the
are already manipulated by the media.
You
You see,
You see, the
You see, the media
You see, the media are
You see, the media are constantly
manipulating.
manipulating. The
You see, the media are constantly
manipulating. The news
manipulating. The news broadcast
You see, the media are constantly
manipulating. The news broadcast is
constantly
constantly manipulating
constantly manipulating you.
constantly manipulating you. For
instance,
instance, just
constantly manipulating you. For
instance, just by
instance, just by how
constantly manipulating you. For
instance, just by how many
instance, just by how many seconds
constantly manipulating you. For
instance, just by how many seconds they
give
give to
give to one
give to one scene
give to one scene rather
give to one scene rather than
give to one scene rather than another
scene,
scene, you
give to one scene rather than another
scene, you know.
scene, you know. So
give to one scene rather than another
scene, you know. So if
scene, you know. So if they're
give to one scene rather than another
scene, you know. So if they're over
scene, you know. So if they're over on
one
one side,
one side, they'll
one side, they'll show
one side, they'll show you
one side, they'll show you all
one side, they'll show you all the
wounded
wounded Palestinians
one side, they'll show you all the
wounded Palestinians dying
wounded Palestinians dying there.
one side, they'll show you all the
wounded Palestinians dying there. And
wounded Palestinians dying there. And if
they're
they're on
they're on the
they're on the other
they're on the other side,
they're on the other side, they
they're on the other side, they show
they're on the other side, they show you
all
all the
they're on the other side, they show you
all the wounded
all the wounded Israelis
they're on the other side, they show you
all the wounded Israelis dying
all the wounded Israelis dying there.
And
And there's
And there's always
And there's always the
And there's always the dead
And there's always the dead baby
And there's always the dead baby and
And there's always the dead baby and the
crying
crying mother.
And there's always the dead baby and the
crying mother. Always.
crying mother. Always. That
And there's always the dead baby and the
crying mother. Always. That really
crying mother. Always. That really rips
people
people up.
people up. That's
people up. That's the
people up. That's the old
people up. That's the old guaranteed
one.
one. Always
people up. That's the old guaranteed
one. Always the
one. Always the mother
people up. That's the old guaranteed
one. Always the mother with
one. Always the mother with the
people up. That's the old guaranteed
one. Always the mother with the dying
baby.
Which
Which side
baby.
Which side you
Which side you give
baby.
Which side you give the
Which side you give the most
baby.
Which side you give the most seconds
Which side you give the most seconds to
is
is the
is the way
is the way you
is the way you blow
is the way you blow influence
is the way you blow influence the
is the way you blow influence the minds
of
of the
is the way you blow influence the minds
of the populace.
of the populace. The
is the way you blow influence the minds
of the populace. The collective
of the populace. The collective minds
is the way you blow influence the minds
of the populace. The collective minds of
the
the populace
the populace is
the populace is like
the populace is like a
the populace is like a musical
instrument
instrument and
the populace is like a musical
instrument and the
instrument and the media
the populace is like a musical
instrument and the media merchants
instrument and the media merchants know
how
how to
how to play
how to play it.
how to play it. Nothing
how to play it. Nothing to
how to play it. Nothing to it.
The
The whole
populace
populace is
populace is like
playable.
You
You can
You can just
You can just play
You can just play them
You can just play them this
You can just play them this way
You can just play them this way or
You can just play them this way or play
them
them that
You can just play them this way or play
them that way.
them that way. Give
You can just play them this way or play
them that way. Give them
them that way. Give them a
You can just play them this way or play
them that way. Give them a few
them that way. Give them a few more
seconds
seconds this
seconds this way
seconds this way and
seconds this way and you'll
seconds this way and you'll see
seconds this way and you'll see the
votes
votes go
seconds this way and you'll see the
votes go up.
votes go up. Give
seconds this way and you'll see the
votes go up. Give it
votes go up. Give it a
seconds this way and you'll see the
votes go up. Give it a few
votes go up. Give it a few more
seconds this way and you'll see the
votes go up. Give it a few more seconds
this
this way,
this way, the
this way, the votes
this way, the votes go
this way, the votes go down.
So
So the
this way, the votes go down.
So the real
So the real maestros
this way, the votes go down.
So the real maestros of
So the real maestros of the
this way, the votes go down.
So the real maestros of the media
So the real maestros of the media play
the
the public
the public like
the public like a
the public like a musical
the public like a musical instrument.
Any
Any kind
the public like a musical instrument.
Any kind of
Any kind of music
the public like a musical instrument.
Any kind of music you
Any kind of music you want
or
or decide
or decide any
or decide any kind
or decide any kind of
or decide any kind of music
or decide any kind of music you
or decide any kind of music you want.
or decide any kind of music you want. We
can
can get
or decide any kind of music you want. We
can get any
can get any kind
or decide any kind of music you want. We
can get any kind of
can get any kind of music
or decide any kind of music you want. We
can get any kind of music we
can get any kind of music we want
or decide any kind of music you want. We
can get any kind of music we want out
can get any kind of music we want out of
public
public sentiment
public sentiment by
public sentiment by political
manipulation.
manipulation. This
public sentiment by political
manipulation. This is
manipulation. This is all
public sentiment by political
manipulation. This is all unconscious.
Most
Most you
Most you know
Most you know don't
Most you know don't forget
Most you know don't forget most
Most you know don't forget most people
are
are unconscious.
Most you know don't forget most people
are unconscious. spiritually
are unconscious. spiritually aware
people
people start
people start seeing
people start seeing through
people start seeing through these
illusions
and
and um
the
the brainwashing
and um
the brainwashing of
the brainwashing of it
and um
the brainwashing of it to
the brainwashing of it to believe
and um
the brainwashing of it to believe in
certain
certain beliefs.
certain beliefs. So
certain beliefs. So we
certain beliefs. So we can't
certain beliefs. So we can't really
judge
judge what
certain beliefs. So we can't really
judge what goes
judge what goes on
certain beliefs. So we can't really
judge what goes on because
judge what goes on because we
certain beliefs. So we can't really
judge what goes on because we don't
judge what goes on because we don't know
what
what goes
what goes on.
what goes on. Who
what goes on. Who knows
what goes on. Who knows what
what goes on. Who knows what goes
what goes on. Who knows what goes on
what goes on. Who knows what goes on in
the
the secret
what goes on. Who knows what goes on in
the secret rooms.
I
I say
I say I've
I say I've been
I say I've been in
I say I've been in clubs
I say I've been in clubs that
I say I've been in clubs that were
I say I've been in clubs that were so
exclusive
exclusive the
I say I've been in clubs that were so
exclusive the world
exclusive the world doesn't
I say I've been in clubs that were so
exclusive the world doesn't even
exclusive the world doesn't even know
they
they exist
they exist and
they exist and there
they exist and there decisions
they exist and there decisions are
they exist and there decisions are made
just
just like
they exist and there decisions are made
just like willy-nilly
just like willy-nilly that
they exist and there decisions are made
just like willy-nilly that affect
just like willy-nilly that affect the
lives
lives of
lives of millions
lives of millions million.
lives of millions million. Nobody
lives of millions million. Nobody gets
to
to vote
lives of millions million. Nobody gets
to vote on
to vote on it.
your
your mortgage
your mortgage rate
your mortgage rate just
your mortgage rate just goes
your mortgage rate just goes up.
your mortgage rate just goes up. That's
all.
all. You
your mortgage rate just goes up. That's
all. You didn't
all. You didn't get
your mortgage rate just goes up. That's
all. You didn't get to
all. You didn't get to vote
your mortgage rate just goes up. That's
all. You didn't get to vote on
all. You didn't get to vote on it.
your mortgage rate just goes up. That's
all. You didn't get to vote on it. The
Congress
Congress didn't
Congress didn't get
Congress didn't get to
Congress didn't get to vote
Congress didn't get to vote on
Congress didn't get to vote on it.
Congress didn't get to vote on it. The
president
president didn't
Congress didn't get to vote on it. The
president didn't get
president didn't get to
Congress didn't get to vote on it. The
president didn't get to vote
president didn't get to vote on
Congress didn't get to vote on it. The
president didn't get to vote on it.
Nobody
Nobody got
Nobody got to
Nobody got to vote
Nobody got to vote on
Nobody got to vote on it.
Okay.
Okay. Um,
Nobody got to vote on it.
Okay. Um, can
Okay. Um, can a
Nobody got to vote on it.
Okay. Um, can a person
Okay. Um, can a person reach
Nobody got to vote on it.
Okay. Um, can a person reach the
Okay. Um, can a person reach the high
600s?
600s? Oh,
600s? Oh, yeah.
600s? Oh, yeah. This
600s? Oh, yeah. This is
600s? Oh, yeah. This is a
600s? Oh, yeah. This is a cute
600s? Oh, yeah. This is a cute question.
Can
Can a
600s? Oh, yeah. This is a cute question.
Can a person
Can a person reach
600s? Oh, yeah. This is a cute question.
Can a person reach the
Can a person reach the level
600s? Oh, yeah. This is a cute question.
Can a person reach the level of
Can a person reach the level of 600
without
without passing
without passing through
without passing through the
without passing through the 500s?
without passing through the 500s? And
without passing through the 500s? And if
so,
so, must
without passing through the 500s? And if
so, must then
so, must then go
without passing through the 500s? And if
so, must then go back
so, must then go back and
without passing through the 500s? And if
so, must then go back and backfill
so, must then go back and backfill the
500s.
500s. That's
500s. That's good.
>> [laughter]
>> That
>> That That's
>> That That's a
>> That That's a really
>> That That's a really cute
>> That That's a really cute question.
You
You find
>> That That's a really cute question.
You find yourself
You find yourself up
>> That That's a really cute question.
You find yourself up at
You find yourself up at 600
>> That That's a really cute question.
You find yourself up at 600 and
You find yourself up at 600 and say,
>> That That's a really cute question.
You find yourself up at 600 and say, "Oh
man,
man, I
man, I forgot
man, I forgot the
man, I forgot the 500.
man, I forgot the 500. [laughter]
I
I got
man, I forgot the 500. [laughter]
I got to
I got to go
man, I forgot the 500. [laughter]
I got to go back
I got to go back there
man, I forgot the 500. [laughter]
I got to go back there and
I got to go back there and shovel
man, I forgot the 500. [laughter]
I got to go back there and shovel some
more
more dirt
more dirt and
more dirt and earn
more dirt and earn my
more dirt and earn my uh
more dirt and earn my uh chevrons."
more dirt and earn my uh chevrons." Huh?
No.
No. The
more dirt and earn my uh chevrons." Huh?
No. The peculiar
No. The peculiar thing
more dirt and earn my uh chevrons." Huh?
No. The peculiar thing about
No. The peculiar thing about it
more dirt and earn my uh chevrons." Huh?
No. The peculiar thing about it is
No. The peculiar thing about it is uh
you
you see
you see context
you see context is
you see context is so
you see context is so complex,
you see context is so complex, it's
you see context is so complex, it's not
comprehensible.
That's
That's the
That's the wisdom
That's the wisdom of
That's the wisdom of surrendering
That's the wisdom of surrendering all
judgmentalism
judgmentalism to
That's the wisdom of surrendering all
judgmentalism to God.
judgmentalism to God. Because
That's the wisdom of surrendering all
judgmentalism to God. Because the
reality
reality is
reality is so
reality is so profoundly
reality is so profoundly complex.
reality is so profoundly complex. It's
only
only when
reality is so profoundly complex. It's
only when you
only when you see
reality is so profoundly complex. It's
only when you see it
only when you see it you
reality is so profoundly complex. It's
only when you see it you realize
only when you see it you realize it's
staggering.
staggering. It's
staggering. It's profoundly
staggering. It's profoundly complex.
Everything
Everything that
staggering. It's profoundly complex.
Everything that ever
Everything that ever existed
staggering. It's profoundly complex.
Everything that ever existed anywhere
Everything that ever existed anywhere in
existence
existence throughout
existence throughout of
existence throughout of all
existence throughout of all of
existence throughout of all of what
existence throughout of all of what we
call
call time
existence throughout of all of what we
call time is
call time is influencing
existence throughout of all of what we
call time is influencing subtly
call time is influencing subtly and
powerfully
powerfully every
powerfully every single
powerfully every single decision,
thought,
thought, choice.
powerfully every single decision,
thought, choice. Every
thought, choice. Every place
powerfully every single decision,
thought, choice. Every place you
thought, choice. Every place you put
your
your foot
your foot is
your foot is already
your foot is already the
your foot is already the result
your foot is already the result of
your foot is already the result of the
entire
entire universe
your foot is already the result of the
entire universe throughout
entire universe throughout all
your foot is already the result of the
entire universe throughout all the
entire universe throughout all the time
to
to make
to make the
to make the decision
to make the decision to
to make the decision to use
to make the decision to use that
to make the decision to use that as
to make the decision to use that as a
demonstration
demonstration to
to make the decision to use that as a
demonstration to this
demonstration to this audience
to make the decision to use that as a
demonstration to this audience right
demonstration to this audience right at
this
this moment
this moment where
this moment where the
this moment where the thought
this moment where the thought came
this moment where the thought came from
is
is already
this moment where the thought came from
is already the
is already the result
this moment where the thought came from
is already the result of
is already the result of billions
this moment where the thought came from
is already the result of billions and
trillions
trillions and
trillions and multi-quadrillions
of
of events,
trillions and multi-quadrillions
of events, circumstances,
influences
influences etc.
This
This also,
influences etc.
This also, as
This also, as we'll
influences etc.
This also, as we'll get
This also, as we'll get to
influences etc.
This also, as we'll get to in
This also, as we'll get to in the
influences etc.
This also, as we'll get to in the next
time,
time, goes
time, goes out
time, goes out through
time, goes out through goes
time, goes out through goes on
time, goes out through goes on through
time, goes out through goes on through a
whole
whole whole
time, goes out through goes on through a
whole whole sequences
whole whole sequences of
time, goes out through goes on through a
whole whole sequences of time
whole whole sequences of time and
events.
events. The
events. The beginning
events. The beginning of
events. The beginning of the
events. The beginning of the evolution
of
of consciousness
in
in the
in the universe
in the universe throughout
in the universe throughout all
in the universe throughout all of
in the universe throughout all of time,
then
then through
in the universe throughout all of time,
then through the
then through the animal
in the universe throughout all of time,
then through the animal kingdom,
then through the animal kingdom, then
in the universe throughout all of time,
then through the animal kingdom, then up
through
through mankind,
through mankind, and
through mankind, and in
through mankind, and in the
through mankind, and in the dissolution
of
of the
through mankind, and in the dissolution
of the ego.
of the ego. so
through mankind, and in the dissolution
of the ego. so profoundly
of the ego. so profoundly complex
through mankind, and in the dissolution
of the ego. so profoundly complex then
one
one can
one can suddenly
one can suddenly jump
one can suddenly jump from
one can suddenly jump from almost
one can suddenly jump from almost any
level
level up
one can suddenly jump from almost any
level up to
level up to an
one can suddenly jump from almost any
level up to an extremely
level up to an extremely high
one can suddenly jump from almost any
level up to an extremely high state
level up to an extremely high state for
reasons
reasons unknown.
reasons unknown. I
reasons unknown. I always
reasons unknown. I always tell
reasons unknown. I always tell people
when
when you
reasons unknown. I always tell people
when you start
when you start going
reasons unknown. I always tell people
when you start going into
when you start going into bliss
reasons unknown. I always tell people
when you start going into bliss states
when
when things
when things start
when things start to
when things start to suddenly
when things start to suddenly you
when things start to suddenly you look
beautiful.
beautiful. You're
when things start to suddenly you look
beautiful. You're driving
beautiful. You're driving along
when things start to suddenly you look
beautiful. You're driving along and
beautiful. You're driving along and all
of a
of a sudden
of a sudden everything
of a sudden everything is
of a sudden everything is like
incredible
incredible technically
of a sudden everything is like
incredible technically it's
incredible technically it's like
of a sudden everything is like
incredible technically it's like God
incredible technically it's like God was
that
that beautiful
that beautiful profound
that beautiful profound stillness
that beautiful profound stillness seems
to
to prevail
that beautiful profound stillness seems
to prevail over
to prevail over all
that beautiful profound stillness seems
to prevail over all things
to prevail over all things and
that beautiful profound stillness seems
to prevail over all things and light
starts
starts to
starts to come
starts to come from
starts to come from within
starts to come from within yourself
starts to come from within yourself and
you
you realize
starts to come from within yourself and
you realize that's
you realize that's who
starts to come from within yourself and
you realize that's who you
you realize that's who you are.
starts to come from within yourself and
you realize that's who you are. It's
time
time to
time to let
time to let your
time to let your friends
time to let your friends know
time to let your friends know that
you're
you're spiritually
time to let your friends know that
you're spiritually very
you're spiritually very serious
[laughter]
because
because someday
[laughter]
because someday while
because someday while in
[laughter]
because someday while in the
because someday while in the middle
[laughter]
because someday while in the middle of
because someday while in the middle of a
bagel
bagel you
bagel you suddenly
bagel you suddenly get
bagel you suddenly get blissed
bagel you suddenly get blissed out
bagel you suddenly get blissed out and
and
and uh
bagel you suddenly get blissed out and
and uh they
and uh they call
bagel you suddenly get blissed out and
and uh they call the
and uh they call the doctors
bagel you suddenly get blissed out and
and uh they call the doctors you
and uh they call the doctors you had
bagel you suddenly get blissed out and
and uh they call the doctors you had a
tonic
tonic or
tonic or bliss
tonic or bliss out
tonic or bliss out or
tonic or bliss out or what
tonic or bliss out or what that
chiridananda
chiridananda you
tonic or bliss out or what that
chiridananda you know
chiridananda you know can
tonic or bliss out or what that
chiridananda you know can be
chiridananda you know can be very
paralyzing
paralyzing I've
paralyzing I've been
paralyzing I've been in
paralyzing I've been in it
paralyzing I've been in it and
paralyzing I've been in it and uh
paralyzing I've been in it and uh you
you
you cannot
paralyzing I've been in it and uh you
you cannot function
you cannot function there's
paralyzing I've been in it and uh you
you cannot function there's no
you cannot function there's no desire
paralyzing I've been in it and uh you
you cannot function there's no desire to
function
function where
function where the
function where the body
function where the body falls
function where the body falls over
function where the body falls over and
and
and dies
function where the body falls over and
and dies so
and dies so much
function where the body falls over and
and dies so much the
and dies so much the better.
function where the body falls over and
and dies so much the better. You
couldn't
couldn't care
couldn't care less.
couldn't care less. It's
couldn't care less. It's not
couldn't care less. It's not a
couldn't care less. It's not a reality.
And
And if
couldn't care less. It's not a reality.
And if you
And if you still
couldn't care less. It's not a reality.
And if you still have
And if you still have an
couldn't care less. It's not a reality.
And if you still have an attachment
And if you still have an attachment to
love,
love, not
love, not love
love, not love itself,
love, not love itself, but
love, not love itself, but an
love, not love itself, but an attachment
to
to love,
love, not love itself, but an attachment
to love, you
to love, you make
love, not love itself, but an attachment
to love, you make make
to love, you make make I
love, not love itself, but an attachment
to love, you make make I I
to love, you make make I I consider
love, not love itself, but an attachment
to love, you make make I I consider an
error
error to
error to well,
error to well, no,
error to well, no, I
error to well, no, I won't
error to well, no, I won't consider
error to well, no, I won't consider an
error.
error. Not
error to well, no, I won't consider an
error. Not an
error. Not an error.
error to well, no, I won't consider an
error. Not an error. It
error. Not an error. It was
error to well, no, I won't consider an
error. Not an error. It was the
error. Not an error. It was the right
thing
thing to
thing to do
thing to do decide
thing to do decide to
thing to do decide to do
thing to do decide to do it
thing to do decide to do it for
thing to do decide to do it for the
thing to do decide to do it for the sake
of
of someone
thing to do decide to do it for the sake
of someone else
of someone else to
thing to do decide to do it for the sake
of someone else to come
of someone else to come back
thing to do decide to do it for the sake
of someone else to come back in
of someone else to come back in the
thing to do decide to do it for the sake
of someone else to come back in the body
and
and resume
and resume life.
No,
No, it's
and resume life.
No, it's not
No, it's not an
and resume life.
No, it's not an error.
No, it's not an error. But
and resume life.
No, it's not an error. But uh
so
so you
so you don't
so you don't have
so you don't have to
so you don't have to go
so you don't have to go back
so you don't have to go back and
backfill.
backfill. uh
so you don't have to go back and
backfill. uh because
backfill. uh because you
so you don't have to go back and
backfill. uh because you suddenly
transcend
transcend whole.
transcend whole. You
transcend whole. You see,
transcend whole. You see, you
transcend whole. You see, you can
transcend whole. You see, you can go
there
there from
transcend whole. You see, you can go
there from the
there from the pits
transcend whole. You see, you can go
there from the pits of
there from the pits of hell.
transcend whole. You see, you can go
there from the pits of hell. In
there from the pits of hell. In this
experience
experience here,
experience here, it
experience here, it was
experience here, it was at
experience here, it was at the
experience here, it was at the pits
experience here, it was at the pits of
hell.
hell. It
experience here, it was at the pits of
hell. It must
hell. It must have
experience here, it was at the pits of
hell. It must have been
oh
oh lower
oh lower than
oh lower than here.
oh lower than here. The
oh lower than here. The pits
oh lower than here. The pits of
oh lower than here. The pits of hell
oh lower than here. The pits of hell are
down
down below
oh lower than here. The pits of hell are
down below here.
down below here. Uh
oh lower than here. The pits of hell are
down below here. Uh I
down below here. Uh I don't
oh lower than here. The pits of hell are
down below here. Uh I don't want
down below here. Uh I don't want to
scare
scare people
scare people and
scare people and tell
scare people and tell them
scare people and tell them what
scare people and tell them what it's
like
like there.
scare people and tell them what it's
like there. But
like there. But anyway,
scare people and tell them what it's
like there. But anyway, the
like there. But anyway, the pits,
scare people and tell them what it's
like there. But anyway, the pits, you
can
can go
can go from
can go from the
can go from the pits
can go from the pits of
can go from the pits of hell
can go from the pits of hell up
can go from the pits of hell up to
can go from the pits of hell up to an
extremely
extremely high
can go from the pits of hell up to an
extremely high state
extremely high state and
can go from the pits of hell up to an
extremely high state and bypass
extremely high state and bypass all
can go from the pits of hell up to an
extremely high state and bypass all of
it.
Uh
Uh why
it.
Uh why is
Uh why is that?
it.
Uh why is that? Because
Uh why is that? Because the
it.
Uh why is that? Because the ego
Uh why is that? Because the ego is
it.
Uh why is that? Because the ego is not
Uh why is that? Because the ego is not a
reality.
reality. You
reality. You have
reality. You have to
reality. You have to undo
reality. You have to undo that
reality. You have to undo that which
doesn't
doesn't exist.
reality. You have to undo that which
doesn't exist. You
doesn't exist. You just
reality. You have to undo that which
doesn't exist. You just have
doesn't exist. You just have to
reality. You have to undo that which
doesn't exist. You just have to bypass
it.
it. You
it. You don't
it. You don't have
it. You don't have to
it. You don't have to disassemble
it. You don't have to disassemble the
ego
ego because
it. You don't have to disassemble the
ego because it's
ego because it's only
it. You don't have to disassemble the
ego because it's only illusion
ego because it's only illusion that
it. You don't have to disassemble the
ego because it's only illusion that that
keeps
keeps it
keeps it in
keeps it in place.
Um
how
how many
how many no
it
it you
how many no
it you can
it you can go
how many no
it you can go up
it you can go up hundreds
how many no
it you can go up hundreds and
it you can go up hundreds and hundreds
of
of points
of points in
of points in an
of points in an instant.
And
And well,
of points in an instant.
And well, it
And well, it isn't
of points in an instant.
And well, it isn't just
And well, it isn't just an
of points in an instant.
And well, it isn't just an instant,
And well, it isn't just an instant, but
all
all of
all of a
all of a sudden
all of a sudden the
all of a sudden the landscape
all of a sudden the landscape changes
and
and one's
all of a sudden the landscape changes
and one's reality
and one's reality changes.
all of a sudden the landscape changes
and one's reality changes. Sense
and one's reality changes. Sense of
all of a sudden the landscape changes
and one's reality changes. Sense of who
you
you are
you are changes
you are changes and
you are changes and one
you are changes and one has
you are changes and one has just
transcended
transcended all
you are changes and one has just
transcended all of
transcended all of it.
you are changes and one has just
transcended all of it. Now
transcended all of it. Now that
you are changes and one has just
transcended all of it. Now that state
may
may not
may not last
may not last in
may not last in the
may not last in the beginning.
may not last in the beginning. Spiritual
workers
workers get
may not last in the beginning. Spiritual
workers get discouraged
workers get discouraged because
may not last in the beginning. Spiritual
workers get discouraged because they'll
go
go into
go into a
go into a really
go into a really great
go into a really great state
go into a really great state and
go into a really great state and then
disappears.
Though
Though that's
Though that's the
Though that's the black
Though that's the black knight
Though that's the black knight of
Though that's the black knight of the
soul
soul and
Though that's the black knight of the
soul and the
soul and the Christian
Though that's the black knight of the
soul and the Christian saints,
soul and the Christian saints, a
Though that's the black knight of the
soul and the Christian saints, a number
of
of them
of them have
of them have written
of them have written about
of them have written about it.
of them have written about it. St.
of them have written about it. St. and
person
person and
of them have written about it. St. and
person and that
person and that person.
of them have written about it. St. and
person and that person. Um,
person and that person. Um, oh
of them have written about it. St. and
person and that person. Um, oh woe
lover,
lover, where
lover, where I
lover, where I have
lover, where I have you
lover, where I have you left
lover, where I have you left me
lover, where I have you left me in
destitute
destitute and
lover, where I have you left me in
destitute and uh
destitute and uh blackness
lover, where I have you left me in
destitute and uh blackness and
destitute and uh blackness and despair
because
the
the presence
because
the presence is
the presence is so
because
the presence is so exquisite
the presence is so exquisite that
because
the presence is so exquisite that should
it
it leave
it leave you
it leave you feel
it leave you feel a
it leave you feel a tremendous
it leave you feel a tremendous sense
it leave you feel a tremendous sense of
loss.
So
So in
So in the
So in the beginning
So in the beginning these
So in the beginning these states
So in the beginning these states may
come
come but
So in the beginning these states may
come but not
come but not stay.
So in the beginning these states may
come but not stay. They
come but not stay. They may
So in the beginning these states may
come but not stay. They may come
come but not stay. They may come and
disappear
disappear and
disappear and come
disappear and come and
disappear and come and disappear
disappear and come and disappear but
each
each one
disappear and come and disappear but
each one sets
each one sets each
disappear and come and disappear but
each one sets each one
each one sets each one sets
disappear and come and disappear but
each one sets each one sets a
each one sets each one sets a different
level
level of
level of what's
level of what's possible
level of what's possible even
level of what's possible even though
level of what's possible even though in
the
the beginning
level of what's possible even though in
the beginning it
the beginning it may
level of what's possible even though in
the beginning it may not
the beginning it may not stay.
level of what's possible even though in
the beginning it may not stay. This
the beginning it may not stay. This is
common
common in
common in Zen
common in Zen meditation.
common in Zen meditation. You
common in Zen meditation. You can
common in Zen meditation. You can go
into
into a
common in Zen meditation. You can go
into a state
into a state of
common in Zen meditation. You can go
into a state of sator
into a state of sator and
common in Zen meditation. You can go
into a state of sator and then
into a state of sator and then it
common in Zen meditation. You can go
into a state of sator and then it leaves
you
you when
you when you
you when you get
you when you get up
you when you get up and
you when you get up and walk
you when you get up and walk around
you when you get up and walk around the
room.
room. In
you when you get up and walk around the
room. In fact
room. In fact in
you when you get up and walk around the
room. In fact in Sanskrit
room. In fact in Sanskrit classically
you when you get up and walk around the
room. In fact in Sanskrit classically um
these
these various
these various states
these various states have
these various states have been
these various states have been well
calibrated
calibrated over
these various states have been well
calibrated over the
calibrated over the years
these various states have been well
calibrated over the years in
calibrated over the years in Hindu
these various states have been well
calibrated over the years in Hindu uh
calibrated over the years in Hindu uh in
the
the Hindu
the Hindu tradition.
There
There are
the Hindu tradition.
There are states
There are states where
the Hindu tradition.
There are states where uh
There are states where uh in
the Hindu tradition.
There are states where uh in meditation
you
you go
you go into
you go into an
you go into an extreme
you go into an extreme state
you go into an extreme state but
you go into an extreme state but then
when
when you
you go into an extreme state but then
when you get
when you get up
you go into an extreme state but then
when you get up and
when you get up and walk
you go into an extreme state but then
when you get up and walk around
when you get up and walk around it
disappears.
There's
There's extreme
disappears.
There's extreme states
There's extreme states let's
disappears.
There's extreme states let's say
There's extreme states let's say in
disappears.
There's extreme states let's say in the
beginning
beginning that
beginning that only
beginning that only happen
beginning that only happen when
beginning that only happen when your
eyes
eyes are
beginning that only happen when your
eyes are closed
eyes are closed and
beginning that only happen when your
eyes are closed and you
eyes are closed and you lose
beginning that only happen when your
eyes are closed and you lose them
eyes are closed and you lose them if
beginning that only happen when your
eyes are closed and you lose them if you
open
open your
open your eyes.
open your eyes. Then
open your eyes. Then as
open your eyes. Then as you
open your eyes. Then as you get
open your eyes. Then as you get more
advanced
advanced the
open your eyes. Then as you get more
advanced the states
advanced the states of
open your eyes. Then as you get more
advanced the states of samadei
advanced the states of samadei persist
even
even though
even though you
even though you open
even though you open your
even though you open your eyes.
Then
Then as
even though you open your eyes.
Then as you
Then as you get
even though you open your eyes.
Then as you get more
Then as you get more advanced
even though you open your eyes.
Then as you get more advanced the
Then as you get more advanced the state
of
of samadei
of samadei persist
of samadei persist even
of samadei persist even though
of samadei persist even though you
of samadei persist even though you get
up
up and
of samadei persist even though you get
up and begin
up and begin to
of samadei persist even though you get
up and begin to walk
up and begin to walk around.
You
You get
You get up
You get up and
You get up and walk
You get up and walk around
You get up and walk around and
You get up and walk around and that
state
state continues.
Then
Then there's
Then there's states
Then there's states beyond
Then there's states beyond that
Then there's states beyond that which
are
are permanent
Then there's states beyond that which
are permanent and
are permanent and nothing
Then there's states beyond that which
are permanent and nothing affects
are permanent and nothing affects it
Then there's states beyond that which
are permanent and nothing affects it but
but
but you
but you yes
but you yes they're
but you yes they're permanent
but you yes they're permanent but
but you yes they're permanent but you
can't
can't function.
but you yes they're permanent but you
can't function. You're
can't function. You're per
but you yes they're permanent but you
can't function. You're per but
can't function. You're per but you
but you yes they're permanent but you
can't function. You're per but you can't
function.
function. Then
function. Then there
function. Then there is
function. Then there is probably
function. Then there is probably the
ultimate
ultimate state
function. Then there is probably the
ultimate state in
ultimate state in which
function. Then there is probably the
ultimate state in which it
ultimate state in which it persists
function. Then there is probably the
ultimate state in which it persists and
yet
yet you
yet you are
yet you are able
yet you are able to
yet you are able to function
yet you are able to function again.
Nothing
Nothing you
yet you are able to function again.
Nothing you do
Nothing you do changes
yet you are able to function again.
Nothing you do changes the
Nothing you do changes the inner
reality.
reality. It
reality. It is
reality. It is that
reality. It is that which
reality. It is that which is
reality. It is that which is clear
reality. It is that which is clear and
obvious
obvious beyond
reality. It is that which is clear and
obvious beyond all
obvious beyond all time.
reality. It is that which is clear and
obvious beyond all time. And
obvious beyond all time. And that
reality. It is that which is clear and
obvious beyond all time. And that which
you
you are
you are is
you are is a
you are is a very
you are is a very obvious
you are is a very obvious and
you are is a very obvious and clear
beyond
beyond all
you are is a very obvious and clear
beyond all time.
beyond all time. But
you are is a very obvious and clear
beyond all time. But by
beyond all time. But by forcing
you are is a very obvious and clear
beyond all time. But by forcing one's
attention
attention on
attention on a
attention on a detail,
attention on a detail, you
attention on a detail, you can
attention on a detail, you can force
yourself
yourself to
attention on a detail, you can force
yourself to see
yourself to see what
attention on a detail, you can force
yourself to see what is
yourself to see what is out
attention on a detail, you can force
yourself to see what is out there.
Ramano
Ramano Maharshi
Ramano Maharshi described
Ramano Maharshi described that
um
and
and it
and it may
and it may have
and it may have been
and it may have been useful
and it may have been useful in
and it may have been useful in having
and it may have been useful in having in
refunctioning
refunctioning the
and it may have been useful in having in
refunctioning the world.
refunctioning the world. would
and it may have been useful in having in
refunctioning the world. would say
refunctioning the world. would say the
if
if you
if you focus
if you focus your
if you focus your consciousness
if you focus your consciousness on
if you focus your consciousness on the
outer
outer world
if you focus your consciousness on the
outer world you're
outer world you're more
if you focus your consciousness on the
outer world you're more able
outer world you're more able to
if you focus your consciousness on the
outer world you're more able to you're
able
able to
able to function
able to function there
able to function there and
able to function there and if
able to function there and if and
able to function there and if and then
you
you can
able to function there and if and then
you can withdraw
you can withdraw it
able to function there and if and then
you can withdraw it and
you can withdraw it and it
able to function there and if and then
you can withdraw it and it all
you can withdraw it and it all the
energy
energy goes
energy goes back
energy goes back into
energy goes back into the
energy goes back into the self.
energy goes back into the self. So
energy goes back into the self. So how
to
to balance
energy goes back into the self. So how
to balance all
to balance all energy
energy goes back into the self. So how
to balance all energy being
to balance all energy being in
energy goes back into the self. So how
to balance all energy being in the
to balance all energy being in the self
which
which may
which may be
which may be incapacitating
which may be incapacitating and
which may be incapacitating and all
energy
energy being
which may be incapacitating and all
energy being in
energy being in the
which may be incapacitating and all
energy being in the world
energy being in the world is
which may be incapacitating and all
energy being in the world is a
energy being in the world is a matter
which may be incapacitating and all
energy being in the world is a matter of
learning.
So
let's
let's have
let's have the
let's have the mantra
[laughter]
to
to remind
to remind us
to remind us the
to remind us the purpose
to remind us the purpose for
to remind us the purpose for which
to remind us the purpose for which we're
here
here today.
to remind us the purpose for which we're
here today. Because
here today. Because the
to remind us the purpose for which we're
here today. Because the mantra
here today. Because the mantra mount
verbally
verbally at
verbally at 740
verbally at 740 automatically
verbally at 740 automatically puts
verbally at 740 automatically puts you
there
there where
verbally at 740 automatically puts you
there where the
there where the great
verbally at 740 automatically puts you
there where the great cathedral.
[music]
>> The
>> The exquisite
[music]
>> The exquisite beauty
>> The exquisite beauty world
>> shines
>> shines forth.
>> [music and singing]
[music and singing]
>> Then
>> Then one
[music and singing]
>> Then one sees
>> Then one sees the
[music and singing]
>> Then one sees the divinity
>> Then one sees the divinity of
[music and singing]
>> Then one sees the divinity of all
>> Then one sees the divinity of all that
exists.
The
The expression
exists.
The expression of
The expression of all
exists.
The expression of all that
The expression of all that exists
[music]
is
is God
[music]
is God manifesting
is God manifesting himself
as
as that
as that which
as that which you
as that which you are
as that which you are in
as that which you are in the
as that which you are in the present.
[music]
Oh
my
my [music]
[singing]
she
[music]
[singing]
Oh
Oh [singing]
she
she [music]
>> [singing]
[music]
[singing]
>> Thank
>> Thank you
[singing]
>> Thank you very
>> Thank you very much
[singing]
>> Thank you very much and
>> Thank you very much and we'll
[singing]
>> Thank you very much and we'll reconvene
in
in an
in an hour.
in an hour. [music]
[singing]
>> God
>> God bless
>> God bless you
>> God bless you all.
>> Okay.
>> First
>> First question
>> First question is,
>> First question is, what
>> First question is, what is
>> First question is, what is the
>> First question is, what is the one
>> First question is, what is the one thing
I
I still
>> First question is, what is the one thing
I still want
I still want in
>> First question is, what is the one thing
I still want in the
I still want in the world?
>> [laughter]
>> Will
>> Will the
>> [laughter]
>> Will the artist
>> Will the artist please
>> [laughter]
>> Will the artist please stand
>> Will the artist please stand up?
>> [laughter]
>> Will the artist please stand up? Who
>> Will the artist please stand up? Who is
it?
it? Where
it? Where are
it? Where are you?
>> Every
>> Every time,
it? Where are you?
>> Every time, every
>> Every time, every meeting,
it? Where are you?
>> Every time, every meeting, he
>> Every time, every meeting, he brings
it? Where are you?
>> Every time, every meeting, he brings me
something
something incredible.
something incredible. A
something incredible. A t-shirt
something incredible. A t-shirt with
something incredible. A t-shirt with my
past
past lives.
something incredible. A t-shirt with my
past lives. Uh
past lives. Uh today
something incredible. A t-shirt with my
past lives. Uh today we
past lives. Uh today we have
something incredible. A t-shirt with my
past lives. Uh today we have a
scripture.
scripture. Uh
scripture. Uh and
scripture. Uh and uh
scripture. Uh and uh a
scripture. Uh and uh a 46
scripture. Uh and uh a 46 Lincoln
Continental
in
in stained
in stained glass.
in stained glass. I
in stained glass. I mean,
in stained glass. I mean, that's
in stained glass. I mean, that's quite
stunning.
The
The ice
The ice shovel
The ice shovel is
The ice shovel is by
The ice shovel is by habit
The ice shovel is by habit you
The ice shovel is by habit you let
The ice shovel is by habit you let go
The ice shovel is by habit you let go of
everything
everything you
The ice shovel is by habit you let go of
everything you want
everything you want as
The ice shovel is by habit you let go of
everything you want as you
everything you want as you the
The ice shovel is by habit you let go of
everything you want as you the wanting
goes
goes up.
goes up. So
goes up. So I
goes up. So I might
goes up. So I might have
goes up. So I might have just
disappeared
disappeared the
goes up. So I might have just
disappeared the continental.
Let's
Let's see.
Let's see. I
Let's see. I still
Let's see. I still want
Let's see. I still want the
Let's see. I still want the continental
resist.
resist. Oh,
Let's see. I still want the continental
resist. Oh, I
resist. Oh, I hung
Let's see. I still want the continental
resist. Oh, I hung on
resist. Oh, I hung on to
Let's see. I still want the continental
resist. Oh, I hung on to it.
resist. Oh, I hung on to it. [laughter]
Boy,
Boy, I
Boy, I got
Boy, I got scared
Boy, I got scared there
Boy, I got scared there for
Boy, I got scared there for a
Boy, I got scared there for a second.
He
He goes
Boy, I got scared there for a second.
He goes illusion
He goes illusion is
Boy, I got scared there for a second.
He goes illusion is if
He goes illusion is if you
Boy, I got scared there for a second.
He goes illusion is if you don't
He goes illusion is if you don't want
it,
it, you
it, you won't
it, you won't get
it, you won't get it.
it, you won't get it. You
it, you won't get it. You know what
it, you won't get it. You know what I
mean?
mean? [laughter]
That
That wanting
That wanting it
That wanting it is
That wanting it is what
That wanting it is what gets
That wanting it is what gets it
That wanting it is what gets it for
That wanting it is what gets it for you.
So
So the
That wanting it is what gets it for you.
So the way
So the way I
That wanting it is what gets it for you.
So the way I prevent
So the way I prevent it
That wanting it is what gets it for you.
So the way I prevent it is
So the way I prevent it is I
That wanting it is what gets it for you.
So the way I prevent it is I keep
wanting
wanting it
wanting it which
wanting it which prevents
wanting it which prevents it
wanting it which prevents it from
happening
happening in
wanting it which prevents it from
happening in my
happening in my life
wanting it which prevents it from
happening in my life and
happening in my life and then
wanting it which prevents it from
happening in my life and then I
happening in my life and then I won't
wanting it which prevents it from
happening in my life and then I won't be
attached
attached to
attached to it.
attached to it. [laughter]
Um
Um in
attached to it. [laughter]
Um in talking
Um in talking about
attached to it. [laughter]
Um in talking about spiritual
Um in talking about spiritual work
there's
there's some
there's some things
there's some things I
there's some things I think
there's some things I think about
there's some things I think about you
know
know that
there's some things I think about you
know that I
know that I should
there's some things I think about you
know that I should have
know that I should have said.
One
One is
One is when
One is when you're
One is when you're making
One is when you're making when
One is when you're making when you
One is when you're making when you get
into
into a
One is when you're making when you get
into a it's
into a it's like
One is when you're making when you get
into a it's like the
into a it's like the energy
One is when you're making when you get
into a it's like the energy of
into a it's like the energy of spiritual
work
work um
work um keeps
work um keeps getting
work um keeps getting stronger
work um keeps getting stronger and
stronger.
stronger. Finally,
work um keeps getting stronger and
stronger. Finally, one
decides
decides to
decides to really
decides to really go
decides to really go for
decides to really go for the
decides to really go for the final
decides to really go for the final run.
You
You know
decides to really go for the final run.
You know what
You know what I'm
decides to really go for the final run.
You know what I'm saying?
You know what I'm saying? [laughter]
What
What that
What that really
What that really consists
What that really consists of
What that really consists of is
What that really consists of is a
What that really consists of is a fixity
of
of attention.
What that really consists of is a fixity
of attention. a
of attention. a relentless
uh
uh staying
uh staying with
uh staying with it.
uh staying with it. Let's
uh staying with it. Let's see
uh staying with it. Let's see how
uh staying with it. Let's see how I'm
not
not expressing
uh staying with it. Let's see how I'm
not expressing that
not expressing that correctly
uh staying with it. Let's see how I'm
not expressing that correctly verbally.
Um
some
some people
Um
some people say,
some people say, "Well,
Um
some people say, "Well, I've
some people say, "Well, I've done
spiritual
spiritual work
spiritual work on
spiritual work on and
spiritual work on and off
spiritual work on and off for
spiritual work on and off for 30
spiritual work on and off for 30 years
and
and I'm
spiritual work on and off for 30 years
and I'm still
and I'm still where
spiritual work on and off for 30 years
and I'm still where I
and I'm still where I was."
spiritual work on and off for 30 years
and I'm still where I was." Well,
and I'm still where I was." Well, they
meditate
meditate a
meditate a little
meditate a little there,
meditate a little there, they
meditate a little there, they pray
meditate a little there, they pray a
little
little there,
meditate a little there, they pray a
little there, they
little there, they go
meditate a little there, they pray a
little there, they go to
little there, they go to a
meditate a little there, they pray a
little there, they go to a workshop
there,
there, they
there, they hear
there, they hear a
there, they hear a speaker
there, they hear a speaker there,
there, they hear a speaker there, they
read
read that.
there, they hear a speaker there, they
read that. It's
read that. It's all
there, they hear a speaker there, they
read that. It's all sort
read that. It's all sort of
there, they hear a speaker there, they
read that. It's all sort of sporadic.
Huh?
That's
That's all
Huh?
That's all right.
That's all right. When
Huh?
That's all right. When you
That's all right. When you have
Huh?
That's all right. When you have time,
let's
let's say
let's say you're
let's say you're quite
let's say you're quite a
let's say you're quite a bit
let's say you're quite a bit in
let's say you're quite a bit in the
world
world and
let's say you're quite a bit in the
world and you're
world and you're accumulating
let's say you're quite a bit in the
world and you're accumulating data
world and you're accumulating data that
you
you know
you know you're
you know you're going
you know you're going to
you know you're going to use
you know you're going to use at
you know you're going to use at a
you know you're going to use at a later
date,
date, certain
you know you're going to use at a later
date, certain understandings,
date, certain understandings, certain
comprehensions
comprehensions come
comprehensions come about.
But
But then
comprehensions come about.
But then there
But then there comes
comprehensions come about.
But then there comes a
But then there comes a time
comprehensions come about.
But then there comes a time when
it
it means
it means to
it means to do
it means to do whatever
it means to do whatever practice
it means to do whatever practice you're
doing
doing without
it means to do whatever practice you're
doing without exception
doing without exception all
it means to do whatever practice you're
doing without exception all the
doing without exception all the time.
A
A very
A very high
A very high state
A very high state can
A very high state can arise
in
in temporal
A very high state can arise
in temporal time
in temporal time rather
A very high state can arise
in temporal time rather brief
in temporal time rather brief if
A very high state can arise
in temporal time rather brief if one
in temporal time rather brief if one is
committedly
committedly persistent.
The
The devotion
committedly persistent.
The devotion to
The devotion to the
committedly persistent.
The devotion to the truth
The devotion to the truth becomes
overwhelming.
The
The love
overwhelming.
The love for
The love for God
overwhelming.
The love for God pulls
The love for God pulls you.
overwhelming.
The love for God pulls you. It
The love for God pulls you. It isn't
that
that you're
that you're driving
that you're driving it.
that you're driving it. It's
that you're driving it. It's now
that you're driving it. It's now you're
being
being pulled
that you're driving it. It's now you're
being pulled by
being pulled by your
that you're driving it. It's now you're
being pulled by your own
being pulled by your own destiny,
that you're driving it. It's now you're
being pulled by your own destiny, by
one's
one's own
one's own karmic
one's own karmic commitment.
one's own karmic commitment. Let's
one's own karmic commitment. Let's say
you've
you've chosen
one's own karmic commitment. Let's say
you've chosen the
you've chosen the ultimate
one's own karmic commitment. Let's say
you've chosen the ultimate destiny.
you've chosen the ultimate destiny. Now
that
that begins
that begins to
that begins to pull
that begins to pull you
that begins to pull you and
that begins to pull you and attract
that begins to pull you and attract you.
It
It isn't
that begins to pull you and attract you.
It isn't that
It isn't that you're
that begins to pull you and attract you.
It isn't that you're being
It isn't that you're being driven
that begins to pull you and attract you.
It isn't that you're being driven by
It isn't that you're being driven by it.
It's
It's being
It's being that
It's being that you're
It's being that you're being
It's being that you're being pulled
It's being that you're being pulled by
it
it cuz
It's being that you're being pulled by
it cuz that's
it cuz that's your
It's being that you're being pulled by
it cuz that's your destiny.
My
My guess
My guess would
My guess would be
My guess would be that's
My guess would be that's the
My guess would be that's the destiny
My guess would be that's the destiny of
everyone
everyone here.
My guess would be that's the destiny of
everyone here. Otherwise,
everyone here. Otherwise, they
My guess would be that's the destiny of
everyone here. Otherwise, they wouldn't
be
be here.
Then
Then comes
be here.
Then comes a
Then comes a time
be here.
Then comes a time for
Then comes a time for becoming
be here.
Then comes a time for becoming really
very
very serious
very serious about
very serious about it.
very serious about it. At
very serious about it. At that
very serious about it. At that point,
let's
let's say
very serious about it. At that point,
let's say you
let's say you use
very serious about it. At that point,
let's say you use the
let's say you use the technique
very serious about it. At that point,
let's say you use the technique that
let's say you use the technique that I
uh
uh used
uh used the
uh used the most
uh used the most was
uh used the most was uh
uh used the most was uh surrendering
uh used the most was uh surrendering and
letting
letting go
uh used the most was uh surrendering and
letting go everything
letting go everything as
uh used the most was uh surrendering and
letting go everything as the
letting go everything as the very
uh used the most was uh surrendering and
letting go everything as the very moment
it
it arises.
it arises. So
it arises. So that
it arises. So that what
it arises. So that what arises
it arises. So that what arises in
consciousness
consciousness is
it arises. So that what arises in
consciousness is like
consciousness is like a
it arises. So that what arises in
consciousness is like a wave.
consciousness is like a wave. It's
it arises. So that what arises in
consciousness is like a wave. It's like
1/100th
1/100th of
1/100th of a
1/100th of a second
1/100th of a second it's
1/100th of a second it's coming.
1/100th of a second it's coming. It
peaks
peaks and
1/100th of a second it's coming. It
peaks and then
peaks and then it
1/100th of a second it's coming. It
peaks and then it leaves.
peaks and then it leaves. So
1/100th of a second it's coming. It
peaks and then it leaves. So the
peaks and then it leaves. So the letting
goess
goess is
goess is at
goess is at the
goess is at the peak
goess is at the peak of
goess is at the peak of it.
goess is at the peak of it. So
goess is at the peak of it. So that
goess is at the peak of it. So that one
is
is constantly
goess is at the peak of it. So that one
is constantly like
is constantly like floating
goess is at the peak of it. So that one
is constantly like floating over
is constantly like floating over the
waves.
waves. In
waves. In other
waves. In other words,
waves. In other words, all
waves. In other words, all these
thoughts
thoughts begin
waves. In other words, all these
thoughts begin to
thoughts begin to arise
waves. In other words, all these
thoughts begin to arise and
thoughts begin to arise and you
waves. In other words, all these
thoughts begin to arise and you intuit
it
it their
it their intention
it their intention of
it their intention of you
it their intention of you and
it their intention of you and you
already
already release
it their intention of you and you
already release that
already release that intention.
Surrender
Surrender everything
Surrender everything to
Surrender everything to God.
Surrender everything to God. So
Surrender everything to God. So this
becomes
becomes continuous
Surrender everything to God. So this
becomes continuous continuous
becomes continuous continuous nonstop.
I
I remember
I remember trying
I remember trying to
I remember trying to let
I remember trying to let go
I remember trying to let go of
I remember trying to let go of a
I remember trying to let go of a severe
attachment
and
and for
and for 11
and for 11 days
and for 11 days I
and for 11 days I sat
and for 11 days I sat and
and for 11 days I sat and did
and for 11 days I sat and did nothing
but
but let
and for 11 days I sat and did nothing
but let let
but let let this
and for 11 days I sat and did nothing
but let let this go.
Every
Every thought,
Every thought, every
Every thought, every feeling,
Every thought, every feeling, every
memory,
memory, everything
as
as it
as it arose
as it arose was
as it arose was surrendered.
You
You see,
as it arose was surrendered.
You see, because
You see, because the
as it arose was surrendered.
You see, because the energy
You see, because the energy behind
as it arose was surrendered.
You see, because the energy behind some
thoughts
thoughts is
thoughts is accumulated
thoughts is accumulated through
thoughts is accumulated through many
lifetimes.
lifetimes. The
thoughts is accumulated through many
lifetimes. The grief
lifetimes. The grief that
thoughts is accumulated through many
lifetimes. The grief that you
lifetimes. The grief that you feel
thoughts is accumulated through many
lifetimes. The grief that you feel when
you
you lose
you lose a
you lose a member
you lose a member of
you lose a member of your
you lose a member of your family
you lose a member of your family now
you lose a member of your family now is
not
not just
you lose a member of your family now is
not just due
not just due to
you lose a member of your family now is
not just due to losing
not just due to losing them.
you lose a member of your family now is
not just due to losing them. This
not just due to losing them. This person
here
here and
here and now.
here and now. It's
here and now. It's from
here and now. It's from all
here and now. It's from all the
here and now. It's from all the deaths
of
of all
here and now. It's from all the deaths
of all the
of all the lifetimes
here and now. It's from all the deaths
of all the lifetimes accumulated
of all the lifetimes accumulated as
here and now. It's from all the deaths
of all the lifetimes accumulated as an
accumulation
accumulation of
accumulation of energy.
accumulation of energy. So
accumulation of energy. So when
accumulation of energy. So when you
begin
begin surrendering
accumulation of energy. So when you
begin surrendering that
begin surrendering that you
accumulation of energy. So when you
begin surrendering that you may
begin surrendering that you may pull
accumulation of energy. So when you
begin surrendering that you may pull up
a
a major
a major a
a major a major
a major a major one
a major a major one that's
a major a major one that's accumulated
through
through many
a major a major one that's accumulated
through many lifetimes.
This
This particular
This particular one
This particular one as
This particular one as I
This particular one as I say
This particular one as I say was
non-stop
non-stop for
This particular one as I say was
non-stop for 11
non-stop for 11 days
This particular one as I say was
non-stop for 11 days morning
non-stop for 11 days morning and
This particular one as I say was
non-stop for 11 days morning and night
just
just went
just went on
just went on and
just went on and on
just went on and on and
just went on and on and on
just went on and on and on and
just went on and on and on and on
just went on and on and on and on and
finally
finally it
just went on and on and on and on and
finally it stopped
finally it stopped gone
just went on and on and on and on and
finally it stopped gone forever
again
again will
again will you
again will you be
again will you be subject
again will you be subject to
again will you be subject to that.
again will you be subject to that. Okay
then
then arises
again will you be subject to that. Okay
then arises the
then arises the next
again will you be subject to that. Okay
then arises the next one.
then arises the next one. So
again will you be subject to that. Okay
then arises the next one. So serious
spiritual
spiritual work
is
is a
spiritual work
is a continuous
is a continuous willingness
spiritual work
is a continuous willingness to
is a continuous willingness to let
things
things go
things go as
things go as they
things go as they arise
things go as they arise in
things go as they arise in the
things go as they arise in the technique
that
that I
things go as they arise in the technique
that I share.
that I share. Uhhuh.
The
The letting
The letting go,
The letting go, the
The letting go, the willingness
The letting go, the willingness to
surrender,
surrender, wanting
The letting go, the willingness to
surrender, wanting to
surrender, wanting to control
The letting go, the willingness to
surrender, wanting to control everything
as
as it
as it arises.
as it arises. The
as it arises. The willingness
as it arises. The willingness to
surrender,
surrender, wanting
as it arises. The willingness to
surrender, wanting to
surrender, wanting to change
as it arises. The willingness to
surrender, wanting to change it,
have
have it
have it your
have it your way,
have it your way, the
have it your way, the refusal
have it your way, the refusal to
surrender
surrender it
have it your way, the refusal to
surrender it to
surrender it to God.
Very
Very often
Very often one
Very often one has
Very often one has illusions
Very often one has illusions about
Very often one has illusions about the
nature
nature of
Very often one has illusions about the
nature of reality
nature of reality that
Very often one has illusions about the
nature of reality that has
nature of reality that has they
Very often one has illusions about the
nature of reality that has they have
nature of reality that has they have to
be
be let
be let go
be let go also
be let go also that
be let go also that there's
be let go also that there's a
be let go also that there's a good
be let go also that there's a good and
be let go also that there's a good and a
bad
bad there's
be let go also that there's a good and a
bad there's a
bad there's a desirable
be let go also that there's a good and a
bad there's a desirable and
bad there's a desirable and undesirable
that's
that's all
that's all in
that's all in your
that's all in your mind.
that's all in your mind. So
you
you realize
that's all in your mind. So
you realize that
you realize that the
that's all in your mind. So
you realize that the sun
you realize that the sun shines
that's all in your mind. So
you realize that the sun shines and
you realize that the sun shines and then
the
the clouds
the clouds come
the clouds come up
the clouds come up and
the clouds come up and then
the clouds come up and then the
the clouds come up and then the rain
falls
falls and
the clouds come up and then the rain
falls and the
falls and the grass
the clouds come up and then the rain
falls and the grass grows
falls and the grass grows up
the clouds come up and then the rain
falls and the grass grows up and
falls and the grass grows up and dies.
The
The stock
The stock market
The stock market goes
The stock market goes up
The stock market goes up and
The stock market goes up and down.
The stock market goes up and down. Age
comes
comes and
The stock market goes up and down. Age
comes and goes.
comes and goes. People
The stock market goes up and down. Age
comes and goes. People arise
comes and goes. People arise and
The stock market goes up and down. Age
comes and goes. People arise and leave.
So
So you
So you see
So you see there's
So you see there's the
So you see there's the eb
So you see there's the eb and
So you see there's the eb and flow.
And
And if
So you see there's the eb and flow.
And if one
And if one is
So you see there's the eb and flow.
And if one is at
And if one is at this
So you see there's the eb and flow.
And if one is at this part
And if one is at this part of
So you see there's the eb and flow.
And if one is at this part of the
And if one is at this part of the cycle,
there's
there's no
there's no point
there's no point de
there's no point de you
there's no point de you know
there's no point de you know crying
about
about it
there's no point de you know crying
about it because
about it because the
there's no point de you know crying
about it because the cycle
about it because the cycle will
there's no point de you know crying
about it because the cycle will cycle
itself
itself out.
itself out. You
itself out. You see
itself out. You see and
itself out. You see and by
itself out. You see and by surrendering
oneself
oneself to
itself out. You see and by surrendering
oneself to whatever
oneself to whatever is
itself out. You see and by surrendering
oneself to whatever is cycling
oneself to whatever is cycling up
itself out. You see and by surrendering
oneself to whatever is cycling up um
oneself to whatever is cycling up um is
how
how one
how one disappears
how one disappears it
how one disappears it eventually.
how one disappears it eventually. You
disappear
disappear it
how one disappears it eventually. You
disappear it by
disappear it by choosing
how one disappears it eventually. You
disappear it by choosing to
disappear it by choosing to be
how one disappears it eventually. You
disappear it by choosing to be with
disappear it by choosing to be with it
and
and letting
and letting go
and letting go wanting
and letting go wanting to
and letting go wanting to change
and letting go wanting to change it
and letting go wanting to change it as
it
it arises.
To
To do
To do that
To do that particular
To do that particular technique
To do that particular technique means
To do that particular technique means to
do
do it
To do that particular technique means to
do it continuously
no
no matter
no matter what
no matter what non-stop.
Usually
Usually one
no matter what non-stop.
Usually one can
Usually one can do
no matter what non-stop.
Usually one can do a
Usually one can do a run
no matter what non-stop.
Usually one can do a run for
Usually one can do a run for a
no matter what non-stop.
Usually one can do a run for a period
and
and then
and then of
and then of course
and then of course when
and then of course when you
and then of course when you get
and then of course when you get more
adept
adept at
and then of course when you get more
adept at it
adept at it to
and then of course when you get more
adept at it to go
adept at it to go back
and then of course when you get more
adept at it to go back in
adept at it to go back in the
and then of course when you get more
adept at it to go back in the ultimate
state
state you
state you know
state you know it
state you know it takes
state you know it takes about
state you know it takes about an
state you know it takes about an hour
state you know it takes about an hour of
releasing
releasing all
state you know it takes about an hour of
releasing all the
releasing all the things
state you know it takes about an hour of
releasing all the things that
releasing all the things that have
state you know it takes about an hour of
releasing all the things that have been
accumulated
accumulated and
accumulated and then
accumulated and then the
accumulated and then the state
accumulated and then the state takes
over
over and
accumulated and then the state takes
over and then
over and then but
accumulated and then the state takes
over and then but then
over and then but then you're
immobilized
immobilized in
immobilized in this
immobilized in this in
immobilized in this in functioning
immobilized in this in functioning as
far
far as
immobilized in this in functioning as
far as the
far as the world
immobilized in this in functioning as
far as the world is
far as the world is concerned.
immobilized in this in functioning as
far as the world is concerned. See,
far as the world is concerned. See, but
you
you you
you you know
you you know it's
you you know it's close
you you know it's close by.
you you know it's close by. And
let's
let's say
you you know it's close by. And
let's say a
let's say a wish
you you know it's close by. And
let's say a wish like
let's say a wish like wishing
you you know it's close by. And
let's say a wish like wishing to
let's say a wish like wishing to be
comprehended
comprehended and
comprehended and understood
comprehended and understood by
comprehended and understood by all
comprehended and understood by all to
whom
whom I'm
comprehended and understood by all to
whom I'm speaking,
whom I'm speaking, you
comprehended and understood by all to
whom I'm speaking, you see,
whom I'm speaking, you see, has
comprehended and understood by all to
whom I'm speaking, you see, has to
whom I'm speaking, you see, has to be
surrendered
surrendered because
surrendered because the
surrendered because the comprehension
surrendered because the comprehension of
the
the truth
surrendered because the comprehension of
the truth of
the truth of what
surrendered because the comprehension of
the truth of what I'm
the truth of what I'm saying
surrendered because the comprehension of
the truth of what I'm saying is
the truth of what I'm saying is not
surrendered because the comprehension of
the truth of what I'm saying is not up
to
to the
to the speaker.
to the speaker. So
to the speaker. So those
to the speaker. So those illusions
to the speaker. So those illusions arise
and
and as
to the speaker. So those illusions arise
and as they
and as they arise,
to the speaker. So those illusions arise
and as they arise, you
and as they arise, you let
to the speaker. So those illusions arise
and as they arise, you let them
and as they arise, you let them go.
to the speaker. So those illusions arise
and as they arise, you let them go. That
the
the comprehension
the comprehension of
the comprehension of what
the comprehension of what is
the comprehension of what is being
the comprehension of what is being said
is
is up
the comprehension of what is being said
is up to
is up to God
the comprehension of what is being said
is up to God and
is up to God and what
the comprehension of what is being said
is up to God and what is
is up to God and what is being
the comprehension of what is being said
is up to God and what is being said
is up to God and what is being said is
up
up to
up to God.
up to God. And
up to God. And there
up to God. And there isn't
up to God. And there isn't any
up to God. And there isn't any person
saying
saying them
up to God. And there isn't any person
saying them in
saying them in the
up to God. And there isn't any person
saying them in the first
saying them in the first place.
up to God. And there isn't any person
saying them in the first place. So
there's
there's no
there's no person
there's no person who
there's no person who wishes
there's no person who wishes that
there's no person who wishes that you
should
should get
there's no person who wishes that you
should get it
should get it better.
there's no person who wishes that you
should get it better. [laughter]
But
But you
But you can
But you can see
But you can see old
But you can see old ego
But you can see old ego habits
But you can see old ego habits arise,
you
you know.
But you can see old ego habits arise,
you know. So
you know. So then
But you can see old ego habits arise,
you know. So then when
you know. So then when one
But you can see old ego habits arise,
you know. So then when one surreners
everything
everything that
everything that stands
everything that stands in
everything that stands in the
everything that stands in the way
everything that stands in the way of
everything that stands in the way of the
presence,
the
the presence
the presence is
the presence is so
the presence is so obvious,
the presence is so obvious, so
the presence is so obvious, so startling
and
and so
the presence is so obvious, so startling
and so overwhelming
and so overwhelming that
the presence is so obvious, so startling
and so overwhelming that there
and so overwhelming that there is
the presence is so obvious, so startling
and so overwhelming that there is no
question
question about
question about it.
It
It is
question about it.
It is profound.
It is profound. It
question about it.
It is profound. It is
It is profound. It is total.
question about it.
It is profound. It is total. It
It is profound. It is total. It is
allencompassing.
allencompassing. Totally
allencompassing. Totally overwhelming.
Totally
Totally transforming
allencompassing. Totally overwhelming.
Totally transforming and
Totally transforming and completely
unmistakable.
[laughter]
Completely
Completely unmistakable.
Completely unmistakable. That's
Completely unmistakable. That's the
minor
minor understatement
Completely unmistakable. That's the
minor understatement of
minor understatement of the
Completely unmistakable. That's the
minor understatement of the world.
minor understatement of the world. So
Completely unmistakable. That's the
minor understatement of the world. So I
wanted
wanted to
wanted to make
wanted to make that
wanted to make that clear
wanted to make that clear that
wanted to make that clear that um
wanted to make that clear that um you
can't
can't complain
wanted to make that clear that um you
can't complain the
can't complain the spirit
wanted to make that clear that um you
can't complain the spirit your
can't complain the spirit your work
wanted to make that clear that um you
can't complain the spirit your work you
hasn't
hasn't worked
hasn't worked for
hasn't worked for you
hasn't worked for you because
hasn't worked for you because it's
hasn't worked for you because it's a
profound
profound commitment.
hasn't worked for you because it's a
profound commitment. If
profound commitment. If you're
hasn't worked for you because it's a
profound commitment. If you're doing
profound commitment. If you're doing the
course
course of
course of miracles,
course of miracles, let's
course of miracles, let's say,
course of miracles, let's say, it
course of miracles, let's say, it means
you
you got
course of miracles, let's say, it means
you got to
you got to forgive
course of miracles, let's say, it means
you got to forgive everything
you got to forgive everything all
course of miracles, let's say, it means
you got to forgive everything all the
time
time continuously,
time continuously, no
time continuously, no matter
time continuously, no matter what.
Doesn't
Doesn't mean
time continuously, no matter what.
Doesn't mean you
Doesn't mean you can
time continuously, no matter what.
Doesn't mean you can make
Doesn't mean you can make an
time continuously, no matter what.
Doesn't mean you can make an exception
here,
here, an
here, an exception
here, an exception there.
here, an exception there. [laughter]
You
You know,
here, an exception there. [laughter]
You know, it
You know, it means
here, an exception there. [laughter]
You know, it means continuously
because
because the
because the one
because the one or
because the one or two
because the one or two things
because the one or two things you
because the one or two things you hide
behind
behind is
because the one or two things you hide
behind is usually
behind is usually a
because the one or two things you hide
behind is usually a stack.
behind is usually a stack. That's
because the one or two things you hide
behind is usually a stack. That's why
you're
you're hanging
you're hanging on
you're hanging on to
you're hanging on to it.
you're hanging on to it. [laughter]
It's
It's not
you're hanging on to it. [laughter]
It's not just
It's not just this
you're hanging on to it. [laughter]
It's not just this sie
It's not just this sie you
you're hanging on to it. [laughter]
It's not just this sie you hate.
It's not just this sie you hate. It's
you're hanging on to it. [laughter]
It's not just this sie you hate. It's a
whole
whole stack.
[laughter]
And
And so
And so all
And so all of
And so all of that
And so all of that hides
And so all of that hides behind
And so all of that hides behind this
one.
one. So
And so all of that hides behind this
one. So it's
one. So it's not
And so all of that hides behind this
one. So it's not just
one. So it's not just an
And so all of that hides behind this
one. So it's not just an innocent,
one. So it's not just an innocent, well,
I
I think
I think I'll
I think I'll skip
I think I'll skip my
I think I'll skip my ex-mother-in-law.
No,
No, she
I think I'll skip my ex-mother-in-law.
No, she was
No, she was adorable.
I think I'll skip my ex-mother-in-law.
No, she was adorable. And
No, she was adorable. And uh
I think I'll skip my ex-mother-in-law.
No, she was adorable. And uh when
No, she was adorable. And uh when you
see
see her
see her for
see her for what
see her for what she
see her for what she is,
the
the value
see her for what she is,
the value of
the value of humor,
see her for what she is,
the value of humor, humor
the value of humor, humor is
see her for what she is,
the value of humor, humor is also
the value of humor, humor is also a
spiritual
spiritual technique
spiritual technique because
spiritual technique because what
spiritual technique because what humor
does
does is
spiritual technique because what humor
does is it
does is it increases
spiritual technique because what humor
does is it increases the
does is it increases the con
spiritual technique because what humor
does is it increases the con it
does is it increases the con it you
enlarge
enlarge the
enlarge the context
enlarge the context to
enlarge the context to the
enlarge the context to the point
enlarge the context to the point that
enlarge the context to the point that it
disappears.
disappears. polarities
seeming
seeming opposites
seeming opposites dissolve
seeming opposites dissolve into
uh
uh the
seeming opposites dissolve into
uh the the
uh the the comedy
seeming opposites dissolve into
uh the the comedy dissolves
uh the the comedy dissolves what
seeming opposites dissolve into
uh the the comedy dissolves what it
seems
seems like
seems like the
seems like the opposite
seems like the opposite ends.
seems like the opposite ends. So
seems like the opposite ends. So comedy
and
and tragedy
seems like the opposite ends. So comedy
and tragedy winning
and tragedy winning and
seems like the opposite ends. So comedy
and tragedy winning and losing
and tragedy winning and losing all
become
become one
become one and
become one and the
become one and the same
become one and the same and
become one and the same and it's
humorous
humorous you
become one and the same and it's
humorous you see.
humorous you see. So
become one and the same and it's
humorous you see. So humor
humorous you see. So humor is
become one and the same and it's
humorous you see. So humor is another
spiritual
spiritual technique
spiritual technique whereby
spiritual technique whereby you
spiritual technique whereby you dissolve
the
the seeming
spiritual technique whereby you dissolve
the seeming polarity
the seeming polarity of
spiritual technique whereby you dissolve
the seeming polarity of the
the seeming polarity of the opposites
which
which also
which also an
which also an illusion
which also an illusion but
which also an illusion but in
which also an illusion but in so
which also an illusion but in so doing.
So
So as
which also an illusion but in so doing.
So as you
So as you get
which also an illusion but in so doing.
So as you get closer
So as you get closer and
which also an illusion but in so doing.
So as you get closer and closer
So as you get closer and closer to
really
really high
really high state,
really high state, you
really high state, you can't
really high state, you can't stop
laughing
laughing sometimes
really high state, you can't stop
laughing sometimes for
laughing sometimes for I
really high state, you can't stop
laughing sometimes for I mean
laughing sometimes for I mean everything
is
is just
is just everything
is just everything is
is just everything is funny,
is just everything is funny, you
is just everything is funny, you know.
And
And uh
so
so someone
so someone said
so someone said here,
so someone said here, but
so someone said here, but as
so someone said here, but as you
so someone said here, but as you get
near
near a
so someone said here, but as you get
near a state
near a state of
so someone said here, but as you get
near a state of joy,
near a state of joy, isn't
so someone said here, but as you get
near a state of joy, isn't that
near a state of joy, isn't that this
question
question here?
question here? Uh
no,
no, that's
question here? Uh
no, that's not
no, that's not someone
question here? Uh
no, that's not someone said
no, that's not someone said as
question here? Uh
no, that's not someone said as you
no, that's not someone said as you get
near
near a
near a state
near a state of
near a state of joy,
near a state of joy, she
near a state of joy, she starts
near a state of joy, she starts to
near a state of joy, she starts to cry.
And
And um
near a state of joy, she starts to cry.
And um crying
And um crying is
near a state of joy, she starts to cry.
And um crying is um
And um crying is um signi
near a state of joy, she starts to cry.
And um crying is um signi is
And um crying is um signi is a
near a state of joy, she starts to cry.
And um crying is um signi is a signal
And um crying is um signi is a signal of
the
the onset
the onset of
the onset of a
the onset of a certain
the onset of a certain state
the onset of a certain state of
consciousness.
One
One cries
One cries out
One cries out of
One cries out of um
One cries out of um let's
One cries out of um let's see
One cries out of um let's see it
One cries out of um let's see it has
names
names in
One cries out of um let's see it has
names in Catholic
names in Catholic theology
the
the ecclesiastic
the ecclesiastic uh
the ecclesiastic uh vernacular
the ecclesiastic uh vernacular there
the ecclesiastic uh vernacular there is
a
a word
the ecclesiastic uh vernacular there is
a word for
a word for it.
>> Huh?
>> Rapture.
Rapture
Rapture is
>> Rapture.
Rapture is a
Rapture is a little
>> Rapture.
Rapture is a little is
Rapture is a little is a
>> Rapture.
Rapture is a little is a little
Rapture is a little is a little higher.
Rapture
Rapture is
Rapture is higher.
Uh,
Uh, agape
Rapture is higher.
Uh, agape means
Uh, agape means unconditional
Rapture is higher.
Uh, agape means unconditional love,
right?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Well,
right?
>> Yeah. Well, there
>> Yeah. Well, there is
right?
>> Yeah. Well, there is a
>> Yeah. Well, there is a going
right?
>> Yeah. Well, there is a going into
>> Yeah. Well, there is a going into a
state
state of
state of exquisite
state of exquisite sweetness
which
which makes
state of exquisite sweetness
which makes you
which makes you cry.
state of exquisite sweetness
which makes you cry. The
which makes you cry. The crying
state of exquisite sweetness
which makes you cry. The crying is
which makes you cry. The crying is not
out
out of
out of sadness.
The
The crying
out of sadness.
The crying is
The crying is out
out of sadness.
The crying is out of
The crying is out of a
out of sadness.
The crying is out of a joy
and
and but
and but it's
and but it's a
and but it's a tempered
and but it's a tempered joy.
and but it's a tempered joy. It's
and but it's a tempered joy. It's not
the
the joy
and but it's a tempered joy. It's not
the joy of
the joy of high
and but it's a tempered joy. It's not
the joy of high ecstasy.
the joy of high ecstasy. So
and but it's a tempered joy. It's not
the joy of high ecstasy. So these
the joy of high ecstasy. So these are
different
different levels
different levels and
different levels and in
different levels and in some
different levels and in some other
writing
writing I
different levels and in some other
writing I do
writing I do try
different levels and in some other
writing I do try to
writing I do try to discern
different levels and in some other
writing I do try to discern the
writing I do try to discern the various
levels.
levels. Ecstasy
is
is something
levels. Ecstasy
is something different.
is something different. Ecstasy
levels. Ecstasy
is something different. Ecstasy is
is something different. Ecstasy is um
an
an ecstasy
an ecstasy in
an ecstasy in the
an ecstasy in the presence
an ecstasy in the presence of
an ecstasy in the presence of God
an ecstasy in the presence of God which
is
is beyond
an ecstasy in the presence of God which
is beyond description
an
an extreme
an extreme ecstasy
and
and extreme
an extreme ecstasy
and extreme joy.
and extreme joy. So
an extreme ecstasy
and extreme joy. So the
and extreme joy. So the states
an extreme ecstasy
and extreme joy. So the states of
lovingness,
lovingness, bliss,
joy,
extreme
extreme ecstasy,
how
how do
extreme ecstasy,
how do they
how do they resolve
extreme ecstasy,
how do they resolve themselves?
how do they resolve themselves? Because
you
you can't
you can't really
you can't really live
you can't really live in
you can't really live in that
you can't really live in that state.
You
You can't
you can't really live in that state.
You can't really
You can't really live
you can't really live in that state.
You can't really live in
You can't really live in this
you can't really live in that state.
You can't really live in this dimension
in
in that
in that state
in that state or
in that state or survive
in that state or survive in
in that state or survive in this.
in that state or survive in this. So
what
what is
in that state or survive in this. So
what is the
what is the res
in that state or survive in this. So
what is the res resolution
what is the res resolution of
in that state or survive in this. So
what is the res resolution of these
states?
states? The
states? The resolution
states? The resolution is
states? The resolution is one
states? The resolution is one surreners
the
the joy,
states? The resolution is one surreners
the joy, the
the joy, the ecstasy
states? The resolution is one surreners
the joy, the ecstasy because
the joy, the ecstasy because the
states? The resolution is one surreners
the joy, the ecstasy because the rule
the joy, the ecstasy because the rule is
everything
everything is
everything is surrendered
everything is surrendered to
everything is surrendered to God.
You
You surrender
everything is surrendered to God.
You surrender the
You surrender the joy,
everything is surrendered to God.
You surrender the joy, the
You surrender the joy, the bliss,
everything is surrendered to God.
You surrender the joy, the bliss, the
ecstasy
that
that may
ecstasy
that may not
that may not even
ecstasy
that may not even come
that may not even come to
ecstasy
that may not even come to you
that may not even come to you for
ecstasy
that may not even come to you for a
couple
couple weeks.
couple weeks. [laughter]
After
After a
couple weeks. [laughter]
After a couple
After a couple weeks,
couple weeks. [laughter]
After a couple weeks, suddenly
After a couple weeks, suddenly it's
couple weeks. [laughter]
After a couple weeks, suddenly it's like
a
a knowingness
a knowingness is
a knowingness is to
a knowingness is to surrender
a knowingness is to surrender even
a knowingness is to surrender even the
joy.
And
And when
And when the
And when the joy
And when the joy and
And when the joy and the
And when the joy and the ecstasy
and
and the
And when the joy and the ecstasy
and the exquisite
and the exquisite bliss
And when the joy and the ecstasy
and the exquisite bliss is
and the exquisite bliss is surrendered
to
to God,
then
then comes
to God,
then comes the
then comes the ultimate
to God,
then comes the ultimate state.
A
A peace
A peace beyond
A peace beyond description.
A
A piece
A peace beyond description.
A piece of
A piece of such
A peace beyond description.
A piece of such dimension
it
it transforms
all
all that
it transforms
all that exists
into
into an
into an infinite
into an infinite and
into an infinite and profound
into an infinite and profound peace.
into an infinite and profound peace. The
peace
peace of
into an infinite and profound peace. The
peace of God
peace of God which
into an infinite and profound peace. The
peace of God which is
peace of God which is beyond
into an infinite and profound peace. The
peace of God which is beyond all
understanding.
Then
there
there is
there is an
there is an inner
there is an inner quietude
there is an inner quietude which
there is an inner quietude which is
inerturbable
inerturbable no
there is an inner quietude which is
inerturbable no matter
inerturbable no matter what
there is an inner quietude which is
inerturbable no matter what happens.
So
So that
So that is
So that is the
So that is the ultimate
So that is the ultimate resolution
So that is the ultimate resolution of
the
the high
So that is the ultimate resolution of
the high states
the high states in
So that is the ultimate resolution of
the high states in which
the high states in which emotions
So that is the ultimate resolution of
the high states in which emotions are
still
pulled
pulled in
still
pulled in whether
pulled in whether it's
still
pulled in whether it's joy,
pulled in whether it's joy, ecstasy.
The
The willingness
The willingness to
The willingness to surrender
The willingness to surrender that
The willingness to surrender that state
requires
requires the
The willingness to surrender that state
requires the the
requires the the resol,
The willingness to surrender that state
requires the the resol, you
requires the the resol, you know,
resolve
to
to be
resolve
to be willing
to be willing to
resolve
to be willing to let
to be willing to let go,
resolve
to be willing to let go, happiness,
to be willing to let go, happiness, joy,
and
and an
and an infinite
and an infinite ecstasy
for
for God
and an infinite ecstasy
for God is
for God is a
and an infinite ecstasy
for God is a great
for God is a great demand.
And
And unless
And unless one
And unless one has
And unless one has acquired
And unless one has acquired that
And unless one has acquired that skill,
it's
it's unlikely
And unless one has acquired that skill,
it's unlikely going
it's unlikely going to
And unless one has acquired that skill,
it's unlikely going to happen
because
because it
because it is
because it is dazzling
because it is dazzling beyond
because it is dazzling beyond all
imagination.
And
And to
And to think
And to think that
And to think that one
And to think that one has
And to think that one has to
And to think that one has to let
And to think that one has to let this
And to think that one has to let this go
seems
seems unthinkable.
But
But beyond
But beyond it
But beyond it is
But beyond it is something
But beyond it is something even
But beyond it is something even greater.
The
The profound
But beyond it is something even greater.
The profound peace
The profound peace of
But beyond it is something even greater.
The profound peace of God
The profound peace of God which
But beyond it is something even greater.
The profound peace of God which is
beyond
beyond all
beyond all understanding
is
is the
beyond all understanding
is the ultimate.
Uh
some
some of
Uh
some of these
some of these are
Uh
some of these are funny.
some of these are funny. Anyway,
[laughter]
this
this is
[laughter]
this is funny,
this is funny, too.
[laughter]
this is funny, too. Yeah,
this is funny, too. Yeah, this
[laughter]
this is funny, too. Yeah, this is
this is funny, too. Yeah, this is funny.
We
We already
We already answered
We already answered that
We already answered that one,
We already answered that one, huh?
We already answered that one, huh? Can
people
people below
We already answered that one, huh? Can
people below 200
people below 200 find
We already answered that one, huh? Can
people below 200 find accurate
people below 200 find accurate answers
to
to questions?
to questions? Um,
to questions? Um, yeah.
to questions? Um, yeah. Ask
to questions? Um, yeah. Ask somebody
who's
who's over
to questions? Um, yeah. Ask somebody
who's over 200.
who's over 200. [laughter]
There's
There's nothing
There's nothing magical
There's nothing magical about
There's nothing magical about 200.
There's nothing magical about 200. This
is
is integrity.
Integrity
Integrity is
Integrity is the
Integrity is the willingness
Integrity is the willingness to
Integrity is the willingness to tell
Integrity is the willingness to tell the
truth
truth about
Integrity is the willingness to tell the
truth about yourself
truth about yourself and
Integrity is the willingness to tell the
truth about yourself and about
truth about yourself and about all
things
things to
things to the
things to the best
things to the best of
things to the best of your
things to the best of your ability
things to the best of your ability to
things to the best of your ability to be
responsible.
The
The difficulty
The difficulty with
The difficulty with a
The difficulty with a psychopath
The difficulty with a psychopath is
The difficulty with a psychopath is even
when
when you've
The difficulty with a psychopath is even
when you've got
when you've got them
The difficulty with a psychopath is even
when you've got them fingerprinted,
when you've got them fingerprinted, you
got
got the
got the DNA
got the DNA and
got the DNA and you
got the DNA and you got
got the DNA and you got a
got the DNA and you got a videotape
got the DNA and you got a videotape on
him,
him, he
got the DNA and you got a videotape on
him, he sits
him, he sits there
got the DNA and you got a videotape on
him, he sits there and
him, he sits there and says,
got the DNA and you got a videotape on
him, he sits there and says, "I
him, he sits there and says, "I didn't
do
do it."
do it." It's
do it." It's profound.
do it." It's profound. You
do it." It's profound. You see
do it." It's profound. You see it
do it." It's profound. You see it on
television
television all
do it." It's profound. You see it on
television all the
television all the time.
do it." It's profound. You see it on
television all the time. They
television all the time. They got
do it." It's profound. You see it on
television all the time. They got DNA
all
all over
all over the
all over the place,
all over the place, all
all over the place, all over
all over the place, all over the
all over the place, all over the body,
all
all over
all over the place, all over the body,
all over the
all over the walls,
all over the place, all over the body,
all over the walls, all
all over the walls, all over
all over the place, all over the body,
all over the walls, all over his
all over the walls, all over his car.
They
They got
They got a
They got a photograph
They got a photograph of
They got a photograph of him.
They got a photograph of him. They
They got a photograph of him. They got
his
his fingerprints.
They got a photograph of him. They got
his fingerprints. And
his fingerprints. And he
They got a photograph of him. They got
his fingerprints. And he says,
his fingerprints. And he says, "I
They got a photograph of him. They got
his fingerprints. And he says, "I didn't
do
do it."
do it." [laughter]
What
What can
do it." [laughter]
What can you
What can you say
do it." [laughter]
What can you say about
What can you say about that?
Uh,
Uh, what
Uh, what can
Uh, what can you
Uh, what can you say
Uh, what can you say about
Uh, what can you say about that?
Uh, what can you say about that? Okay,
let's
let's see.
Uh, what can you say about that? Okay,
let's see. We're
let's see. We're allowed
Uh, what can you say about that? Okay,
let's see. We're allowed to
let's see. We're allowed to see.
Uh, what can you say about that? Okay,
let's see. We're allowed to see. I'm
allowed
allowed to
allowed to ask
allowed to ask you
allowed to ask you what
allowed to ask you what can
allowed to ask you what can we
allowed to ask you what can we say
allowed to ask you what can we say what
what
what it
allowed to ask you what can we say what
what it is
what it is about
allowed to ask you what can we say what
what it is about that.
what it is about that. Um,
allowed to ask you what can we say what
what it is about that. Um, that's
what it is about that. Um, that's what
I'm
I'm thinking
I'm thinking in
I'm thinking in mind
I'm thinking in mind is
I'm thinking in mind is a
I'm thinking in mind is a fact.
I'm thinking in mind is a fact. Resist.
They're
They're possessed
I'm thinking in mind is a fact. Resist.
They're possessed by
They're possessed by lower
I'm thinking in mind is a fact. Resist.
They're possessed by lower astrals.
Resist.
Resist. Thank
Resist. Thank you.
Resist. Thank you. The
Resist. Thank you. The reason
Resist. Thank you. The reason when
Resist. Thank you. The reason when the
person
person says
Resist. Thank you. The reason when the
person says I
person says I didn't
Resist. Thank you. The reason when the
person says I didn't do
person says I didn't do it,
Resist. Thank you. The reason when the
person says I didn't do it, they
person says I didn't do it, they didn't.
Lower
Lower astral
Lower astral did
Lower astral did it.
Lower astral did it. And
Lower astral did it. And I
Lower astral did it. And I see
Lower astral did it. And I see them
Lower astral did it. And I see them all
the
the time
Lower astral did it. And I see them all
the time on
the time on TV
Lower astral did it. And I see them all
the time on TV and
the time on TV and many
Lower astral did it. And I see them all
the time on TV and many times
the time on TV and many times these
criminals
criminals um
criminals um who
criminals um who kill
criminals um who kill many
criminals um who kill many people
uh
uh will
criminals um who kill many people
uh will will
uh will will say
criminals um who kill many people
uh will will say uh
uh will will say uh from
criminals um who kill many people
uh will will say uh from a
uh will will say uh from a certain
criminals um who kill many people
uh will will say uh from a certain level
of
of truth
of truth I
of truth I I
of truth I I didn't
of truth I I didn't do
of truth I I didn't do that
of truth I I didn't do that if
of truth I I didn't do that if he
of truth I I didn't do that if he means
his
his ego.
of truth I I didn't do that if he means
his ego. No,
his ego. No, he
of truth I I didn't do that if he means
his ego. No, he didn't
his ego. No, he didn't do
of truth I I didn't do that if he means
his ego. No, he didn't do that.
his ego. No, he didn't do that. But
of truth I I didn't do that if he means
his ego. No, he didn't do that. But the
entity
entity that
entity that prevails
entity that prevails with
entity that prevails with has
entity that prevails with has taken
entity that prevails with has taken over
his
his consciousness.
So
So to
So to um
for
for some
So to um
for some reason
for some reason then
So to um
for some reason then if
for some reason then if you
So to um
for some reason then if you deny
for some reason then if you deny the
truth
truth um
truth um you're
truth um you're not
truth um you're not allowed
truth um you're not allowed to
truth um you're not allowed to access
the
the truth.
It's
It's like
It's like you
It's like you can't
It's like you can't have
It's like you can't have the
It's like you can't have the benefits
It's like you can't have the benefits of
honesty
honesty without
It's like you can't have the benefits of
honesty without all
honesty without all without
It's like you can't have the benefits of
honesty without all without being
honest.
honest. So
honest. So I
honest. So I think
honest. So I think that's
honest. So I think that's the
honest. So I think that's the answer
honest. So I think that's the answer to
that.
The
The most
The most important
The most important thing
The most important thing you
The most important thing you want
The most important thing you want to
know
know about
The most important thing you want to
know about any
know about any teacher
The most important thing you want to
know about any teacher or
know about any teacher or entity
The most important thing you want to
know about any teacher or entity that
channels
channels from
channels from the
channels from the other
channels from the other side.
channels from the other side. Somebody
asked
asked me
channels from the other side. Somebody
asked me about
asked me about a
channels from the other side. Somebody
asked me about a teacher
asked me about a teacher on
channels from the other side. Somebody
asked me about a teacher on the
asked me about a teacher on the other
side.
side. The
side. The name
side. The name begins
side. The name begins with
side. The name begins with K.
side. The name begins with K. Um
side. The name begins with K. Um that
teacher
teacher is
side. The name begins with K. Um that
teacher is over
teacher is over 350
side. The name begins with K. Um that
teacher is over 350 or
teacher is over 350 or so.
side. The name begins with K. Um that
teacher is over 350 or so. 350
teacher is over 350 or so. 350 then
[clears throat]
uh
uh 350
[clears throat]
uh 350 is
uh 350 is a
[clears throat]
uh 350 is a very
uh 350 is a very intelligent
[clears throat]
uh 350 is a very intelligent and
integrous.
integrous. So
integrous. So that's
integrous. So that's a
integrous. So that's a very
integrous. So that's a very good
integrous. So that's a very good teacher
for
for for
integrous. So that's a very good teacher
for for a
for for a certain
integrous. So that's a very good teacher
for for a certain degree.
for for a certain degree. And
integrous. So that's a very good teacher
for for a certain degree. And when
for for a certain degree. And when you
get
get when
get when you
get when you outgrow
get when you outgrow a
get when you outgrow a teacher,
get when you outgrow a teacher, you
get when you outgrow a teacher, you sort
of
of sense
get when you outgrow a teacher, you sort
of sense that
of sense that you're
get when you outgrow a teacher, you sort
of sense that you're outgrowing
of sense that you're outgrowing the
teacher
teacher and
teacher and you
teacher and you look
teacher and you look for
teacher and you look for somebody
teacher and you look for somebody for
something
something or
teacher and you look for somebody for
something or some
something or some teacher
teacher and you look for somebody for
something or some teacher that's
somewhat
somewhat higher.
uh
it
it isn't
it isn't the
it isn't the height
it isn't the height of
it isn't the height of the
it isn't the height of the teacher
it isn't the height of the teacher the
it
it isn't
it isn't the height of the teacher the
it isn't the
it isn't the calibrated
it isn't the height of the teacher the
it isn't the calibrated level
it isn't the calibrated level it's
it isn't the height of the teacher the
it isn't the calibrated level it's the
suitability
suitability for
suitability for yourself
suitability for yourself suitability
um
um because
suitability for yourself suitability
um because otherwise
um because otherwise what
suitability for yourself suitability
um because otherwise what the
um because otherwise what the teacher
suitability for yourself suitability
um because otherwise what the teacher is
saying
saying doesn't
saying doesn't make
saying doesn't make any
saying doesn't make any sense
saying doesn't make any sense to
saying doesn't make any sense to you
saying doesn't make any sense to you if
you
you say
saying doesn't make any sense to you if
you say this
you say this teacher
saying doesn't make any sense to you if
you say this teacher doesn't
you say this teacher doesn't make
saying doesn't make any sense to you if
you say this teacher doesn't make any
sense
sense at
sense at all
sense at all that's
sense at all that's probably
sense at all that's probably the
sense at all that's probably the wrong
teacher
teacher because
sense at all that's probably the wrong
teacher because uh
teacher because uh if
sense at all that's probably the wrong
teacher because uh if if
teacher because uh if if you're
sense at all that's probably the wrong
teacher because uh if if you're here
teacher because uh if if you're here and
the
the teacher
the teacher is
the teacher is here
the teacher is here they'll
the teacher is here they'll make
the teacher is here they'll make sense
to
But
But if
But if you're
But if you're hearing
But if you're hearing the
But if you're hearing the teachers
But if you're hearing the teachers way
up
up here,
But if you're hearing the teachers way
up here, they
up here, they may
But if you're hearing the teachers way
up here, they may say
up here, they may say you
But if you're hearing the teachers way
up here, they may say you can't
up here, they may say you can't make
But if you're hearing the teachers way
up here, they may say you can't make you
can't
can't really
can't really make
can't really make sense
can't really make sense of
can't really make sense of it.
So
So we
can't really make sense of it.
So we have
So we have to
can't really make sense of it.
So we have to decide
So we have to decide what's
can't really make sense of it.
So we have to decide what's best
So we have to decide what's best for
can't really make sense of it.
So we have to decide what's best for us
at
at a
at a certain
at a certain time.
at a certain time. And
at a certain time. And sometimes
kinesiology
kinesiology is
at a certain time. And sometimes
kinesiology is useful
kinesiology is useful with
at a certain time. And sometimes
kinesiology is useful with that.
kinesiology is useful with that. You
at a certain time. And sometimes
kinesiology is useful with that. You say
this
this teacher
this teacher is
this teacher is good
this teacher is good for
this teacher is good for me
this teacher is good for me at
this teacher is good for me at this
time.
time. Yes.
this teacher is good for me at this
time. Yes. No.
time. Yes. No. Right.
this teacher is good for me at this
time. Yes. No. Right. And
time. Yes. No. Right. And that
this teacher is good for me at this
time. Yes. No. Right. And that teacher
is
is good
is good for
is good for you
is good for you right
is good for you right now.
Uh
the
the level
the level of
the level of consciousness
the level of consciousness one
the level of consciousness one will
reach
reach in
the level of consciousness one will
reach in this
reach in this lifetime
the level of consciousness one will
reach in this lifetime is
reach in this lifetime is predestined.
I
I would
I would say
I would say no.
Because
Because choice
I would say no.
Because choice is
Because choice is always
I would say no.
Because choice is always present.
The
The the
The the consciousness
The the consciousness level
The the consciousness level that
The the consciousness level that you
enter
enter life
The the consciousness level that you
enter life with
enter life with at
The the consciousness level that you
enter life with at birth
enter life with at birth is
The the consciousness level that you
enter life with at birth is already
preset
preset by
preset by your
preset by your karmic
preset by your karmic inheritance.
And
And what
preset by your karmic inheritance.
And what happens
And what happens to
preset by your karmic inheritance.
And what happens to you
And what happens to you during
preset by your karmic inheritance.
And what happens to you during this
And what happens to you during this life
is
is not
predetermined
predetermined innately.
However,
However, the
However, the circumstances
However, the circumstances that
However, the circumstances that you
However, the circumstances that you find
yourself
yourself in,
However, the circumstances that you find
yourself in, the
yourself in, the local
However, the circumstances that you find
yourself in, the local conditions
yourself in, the local conditions will
certainly
certainly influence
certainly influence what
certainly influence what choices
certainly influence what choices you
make.
make. So
certainly influence what choices you
make. So there
make. So there is
certainly influence what choices you
make. So there is a
make. So there is a certain
certainly influence what choices you
make. So there is a certain karmic
spillover
spillover you
spillover you might
spillover you might say.
spillover you might say. However,
spillover you might say. However, you
can
can go
spillover you might say. However, you
can go from
can go from the
spillover you might say. However, you
can go from the depths
can go from the depths of
spillover you might say. However, you
can go from the depths of hell
can go from the depths of hell to
spillover you might say. However, you
can go from the depths of hell to the
highest
highest states.
Um
Um so
highest states.
Um so I
Um so I think
highest states.
Um so I think the
Um so I think the answer
highest states.
Um so I think the answer is
Um so I think the answer is correct.
You're
You're not
You're not you're
You're not you're not
You're not you're not constrained
You're not you're not constrained by
You're not you're not constrained by any
predetermination
predetermination resist.
You're not you're not constrained by any
predetermination resist. That's
predetermination resist. That's true.
You
You know
You know you're
You know you're not
You know you're not constrained
You know you're not constrained by
You know you're not constrained by any
predetermination.
Uh
Uh you're
Uh you're not
Uh you're not limited
Uh you're not limited in
Uh you're not limited in any
Uh you're not limited in any way.
Uh you're not limited in any way. Uh
Uh you're not limited in any way. Uh you
start
start surrendering
Uh you're not limited in any way. Uh you
start surrendering things
start surrendering things as
Uh you're not limited in any way. Uh you
start surrendering things as they
start surrendering things as they occur.
every
every feeling,
every feeling, thought,
every feeling, thought, idea,
positionality,
perception
perception and
perception and you
perception and you can
perception and you can escalate
perception and you can escalate very
very
very rapidly.
perception and you can escalate very
very rapidly. You
very rapidly. You can
perception and you can escalate very
very rapidly. You can go
very rapidly. You can go up
perception and you can escalate very
very rapidly. You can go up 150
very rapidly. You can go up 150 points
in
in one
in one lecture.
in one lecture. Uh
so
what
what does
what does this
what does this say?
The
The you
what does this say?
The you do
The you do kinesiology.
Do
Do you
Do you check
Do you check for
Do you check for what?
Do you check for what? Unconscious
slides.
for
for unconscious
for unconscious blocks.
>> Oh.
>> Oh. Oh.
for unconscious blocks.
>> Oh. Oh. Oh.
>> Oh. Oh. Oh. Unconscious
for unconscious blocks.
>> Oh. Oh. Oh. Unconscious blocks.
Well,
Well, yes,
Well, yes, you
Well, yes, you could
Well, yes, you could you
Well, yes, you could you can
Well, yes, you could you can have
Well, yes, you could you can have a
Well, yes, you could you can have a an
area
area that's
Well, yes, you could you can have a an
area that's obscure
area that's obscure and
Well, yes, you could you can have a an
area that's obscure and you
area that's obscure and you you
Well, yes, you could you can have a an
area that's obscure and you you can
area that's obscure and you you can pray
about
about that
about that and
about that and I
about that and I I
about that and I I asked
about that and I I asked God
about that and I I asked God to
about that and I I asked God to reveal
to
to me,
about that and I I asked God to reveal
to me, you
to me, you know,
about that and I I asked God to reveal
to me, you know, what
to me, you know, what is
about that and I I asked God to reveal
to me, you know, what is the
to me, you know, what is the meaning
about that and I I asked God to reveal
to me, you know, what is the meaning of
that?
that? What
that? What is
that? What is the
that? What is the context
that? What is the context which
that? What is the context which makes
this
this seem
that? What is the context which makes
this seem to
this seem to be
that? What is the context which makes
this seem to be true
this seem to be true to
that? What is the context which makes
this seem to be true to me?
this seem to be true to me? And
that? What is the context which makes
this seem to be true to me? And you
this seem to be true to me? And you can
also
also use
also use kinesiology
also use kinesiology and
also use kinesiology and you
also use kinesiology and you can
also use kinesiology and you can also
also use kinesiology and you can also do
karmic
karmic research
also use kinesiology and you can also do
karmic research as
karmic research as to
okay.
Uh
Uh the
okay.
Uh the sound
Uh the sound of
okay.
Uh the sound of ah
Uh the sound of ah the
okay.
Uh the sound of ah the sound
Uh the sound of ah the sound of
okay.
Uh the sound of ah the sound of ah
Uh the sound of ah the sound of ah you
know
know the
know the book
know the book by
know the book by John
know the book by John Diamond
know the book by John Diamond your
know the book by John Diamond your body
doesn't
doesn't lie
know the book by John Diamond your body
doesn't lie behavioral
doesn't lie behavioral kinesiology
um
um has
um has to
um has to do
um has to do with
um has to do with uh
um has to do with uh the
um has to do with uh the sound
um has to do with uh the sound ah
um has to do with uh the sound ah the
sound
sound ah
um has to do with uh the sound ah the
sound ah is
sound ah is different
um has to do with uh the sound ah the
sound ah is different than
sound ah is different than the
um has to do with uh the sound ah the
sound ah is different than the sound
and
and as
and as we
and as we pointed
and as we pointed out
and as we pointed out in
and as we pointed out in one
and as we pointed out in one lecture
considerably
considerably different
and as we pointed out in one lecture
considerably different from
considerably different from a
uh
uh the
uh the sound
uh the sound ah
uh the sound ah makes
uh the sound ah makes you
uh the sound ah makes you go
uh the sound ah makes you go stronger
kinesiology.
So
So if
So if you
So if you feel
So if you feel blown
So if you feel blown out,
So if you feel blown out, upset
So if you feel blown out, upset and
disturbed
disturbed by
So if you feel blown out, upset and
disturbed by something,
disturbed by something, you
So if you feel blown out, upset and
disturbed by something, you know
disturbed by something, you know the
thyic
thyic thump.
thyic thump. You
thyic thump. You go.
Everybody
Everybody here
thyic thump. You go.
Everybody here know
Everybody here know that
thyic thump. You go.
Everybody here know that one.
Knock
Knock myself
Knock myself out
Knock myself out with
Knock myself out with that
Knock myself out with that one.
That
That activates
Knock myself out with that one.
That activates the
That activates the thymus
Knock myself out with that one.
That activates the thymus glad
That activates the thymus glad gland
which
which controls
which controls the
which controls the acupuncture
which controls the acupuncture system.
It
It tends
which controls the acupuncture system.
It tends to
It tends to take
which controls the acupuncture system.
It tends to take you
It tends to take you out
which controls the acupuncture system.
It tends to take you out of
It tends to take you out of a
which controls the acupuncture system.
It tends to take you out of a negative
field
field and
field and back
field and back into
field and back into a
field and back into a positive
field and back into a positive field.
field and back into a positive field. A
person
person may
field and back into a positive field. A
person may not
person may not do
field and back into a positive field. A
person may not do well
person may not do well kinesiology
because
because if
because if they've
because if they've been
because if they've been listening
recently
recently to
because if they've been listening
recently to music
recently to music the
because if they've been listening
recently to music the calibrates
recently to music the calibrates quite
low.
low. There's
low. There's certain
low. There's certain certain
low. There's certain certain uh
low. There's certain certain uh rock
groups
groups for
low. There's certain certain uh rock
groups for instance
groups for instance and
low. There's certain certain uh rock
groups for instance and if
groups for instance and if they
low. There's certain certain uh rock
groups for instance and if they use
groups for instance and if they use them
as
as background
as background and
as background and you're
as background and you're watching
as background and you're watching an
advertisement
advertisement and
as background and you're watching an
advertisement and you
advertisement and you don't
as background and you're watching an
advertisement and you don't realize
advertisement and you don't realize that
the
the energy
the energy of
the energy of the
the energy of the music
the energy of the music in
the energy of the music in the
the energy of the music in the back
the energy of the music in the back is
what's
what's blowing
the energy of the music in the back is
what's blowing you
what's blowing you out
the energy of the music in the back is
what's blowing you out your
what's blowing you out your acupuncture
system
system right
system right now
system right now and
system right now and you'll
system right now and you'll get
system right now and you'll get a
system right now and you'll get a false
negative
that
that that
that that particular
that that particular exercise
at
at the
that that particular exercise
at the same
at the same time
that that particular exercise
at the same time you
at the same time you picture
that that particular exercise
at the same time you picture something
or
or someone
or someone you
or someone you love
or someone you love will
or someone you love will straighten
or someone you love will straighten you
back
back out
or someone you love will straighten you
back out again
and
and the
and the effect
and the effect of
and the effect of negative
and the effect of negative advertisement
ments,
ments, sound,
and the effect of negative advertisement
ments, sound, music.
ments, sound, music. Um,
one
one was
one was recently
one was recently on
one was recently on the
one was recently on the news,
one was recently on the news, Pepsicola
was
was going
one was recently on the news, Pepsicola
was going to
was going to was
one was recently on the news, Pepsicola
was going to was contracting
was going to was contracting with
one was recently on the news, Pepsicola
was going to was contracting with some
rock
rock singer
rock singer or
rock singer or something
rock singer or something like
rock singer or something like that.
rock singer or something like that. And
I
I think
rock singer or something like that. And
I think it
I think it was
rock singer or something like that. And
I think it was Bill
I think it was Bill O'Reilly
rock singer or something like that. And
I think it was Bill O'Reilly got
I think it was Bill O'Reilly got peed
off
off about
off about it
off about it and
off about it and Ray
off about it and Ray sell
off about it and Ray sell about
off about it and Ray sell about it.
Anyway,
Anyway, Pepsicola
off about it and Ray sell about it.
Anyway, Pepsicola let
Anyway, Pepsicola let this
off about it and Ray sell about it.
Anyway, Pepsicola let this guy
Anyway, Pepsicola let this guy go.
off about it and Ray sell about it.
Anyway, Pepsicola let this guy go. Well,
let's
let's see
let's see what
let's see what the
let's see what the energy
let's see what the energy of
let's see what the energy of that
let's see what the energy of that of
that
that enterprise
let's see what the energy of that of
that enterprise would
that enterprise would have
let's see what the energy of that of
that enterprise would have been.
that enterprise would have been. We
let's see what the energy of that of
that enterprise would have been. We have
permission
permission to
permission to ask
permission to ask the
permission to ask the energy
permission to ask the energy of
permission to ask the energy of that
particular
particular kind
permission to ask the energy of that
particular kind of
particular kind of music.
permission to ask the energy of that
particular kind of music. is
particular kind of music. is you
permission to ask the energy of that
particular kind of music. is you know
it's
it's below
it's below 100
it's below 100 below
it's below 100 below 90
it's
it's about
it's below 100 below 90
it's about 95
it's about 95 about
it's below 100 below 90
it's about 95 about 95
>> so
>> so you
>> so you see
>> so you see if
>> so you see if you
>> so you see if you advertise
>> so you see if you advertise a
>> so you see if you advertise a product
and
and you
>> so you see if you advertise a product
and you put
and you put on
>> so you see if you advertise a product
and you put on music
and you put on music that
>> so you see if you advertise a product
and you put on music that calibrates
and you put on music that calibrates at
what
what you're
what you're doing
what you're doing is
what you're doing is destroying
what you're doing is destroying your
customer
customer base
customer base [laughter]
because
because that
customer base [laughter]
because that association
because that association is
customer base [laughter]
because that association is made
unconsciously
all
all right
so
so on
so on the
so on the other
so on the other hand
so on the other hand a
so on the other hand a and
so on the other hand a and the
so on the other hand a and the sound
so on the other hand a and the sound m
both
both ah
so on the other hand a and the sound m
both ah So,
both ah So, amen
so on the other hand a and the sound m
both ah So, amen has
both ah So, amen has both
so on the other hand a and the sound m
both ah So, amen has both of
both ah So, amen has both of them.
so on the other hand a and the sound m
both ah So, amen has both of them. Let's
go
go with
go with ah.
go with ah. Ah,
go with ah. Ah, makes
go with ah. Ah, makes one
go with ah. Ah, makes one go
go with ah. Ah, makes one go strong.
Makes
Makes one
go with ah. Ah, makes one go strong.
Makes one go
Makes one go strong.
Oh,
Oh, is
Oh, is over
Oh, is over 700.
Oh,
Oh, is
Oh, is over 700.
Oh, is over
Oh, is over 720.
Oh,
Oh, is
Oh, is over
Oh, is over 740.
Oh,
Oh, is
Oh, is over 740.
Oh, is over
Oh, is over 750.
Oh, is over 740.
Oh, is over 750. Oh,
Oh, is over 750. Oh, is
Oh, is over 740.
Oh, is over 750. Oh, is over
Oh, is over 750. Oh, is over 7080.
Oh, is over 740.
Oh, is over 750. Oh, is over 7080. Oh,
Oh, is over 750. Oh, is over 7080. Oh, I
was
was telling
was telling you
was telling you about
was telling you about this
was telling you about this homem.
>> Yes,
>> Yes, I
was telling you about this homem.
>> Yes, I know.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I'm
>> Oh, I'm [laughter]
>> Oh, I'm [laughter] sorry.
Well,
Well, let's
>> Oh, I'm [laughter] sorry.
Well, let's do
Well, let's do this
>> Oh, I'm [laughter] sorry.
Well, let's do this song
Well, let's do this song for
>> Oh, I'm [laughter] sorry.
Well, let's do this song for fun
>> because
>> because you're
>> because you're doing
>> because you're doing it
>> because you're doing it and
>> because you're doing it and I'm
>> because you're doing it and I'm feeling
it.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, okay.
>> Oh, okay. [laughter]
>> Well,
>> Well, they're
>> Oh, okay. [laughter]
>> Well, they're asking
>> Well, they're asking about
>> Oh, okay. [laughter]
>> Well, they're asking about various
sounds,
you
you know,
sounds,
you know, in
>> do
>> do the
>> do the m
>> do the m and
>> do the m and let
>> do the m and let everyone
>> do the m and let everyone meditate
>> do the m and let everyone meditate cuz
that's
that's so
>> do the m and let everyone meditate cuz
that's so nice.
>> You're
>> You're do
>> You're do your
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yeah.
>> You're do your
>> Oh, yeah. Oh,
>> Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah.
>> You're do your
>> Oh, yeah. Oh, yeah. [laughter]
Various
Various sounds
Various sounds have
Various sounds have different
Various sounds have different effects.
What
What were
Various sounds have different effects.
What were we
What were we talking
Various sounds have different effects.
What were we talking about?
the
the radio.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yes.
the radio.
>> Oh, yes. Yes.
>> Oh, yes. Yes. Well,
the radio.
>> Oh, yes. Yes. Well, uh,
>> Oh, yes. Yes. Well, uh, let's
the radio.
>> Oh, yes. Yes. Well, uh, let's go.
>> Oh, yes. Yes. Well, uh, let's go. Aum.
No.
Aum
Aum makes
No.
Aum makes you
Aum makes you go
No.
Aum makes you go strong.
Aum makes you go strong. Is
No.
Aum makes you go strong. Is it?
120,
120, 180,
120, 180, 190,
120, 180, 190, 200,
120, 180, 190, 200, 210.
120, 180, 190, 200, 210. Okay.
120, 180, 190, 200, 210. Okay. Aum
is
is quite
120, 180, 190, 200, 210. Okay. Aum
is quite a
is quite a bit
120, 180, 190, 200, 210. Okay. Aum
is quite a bit lower
is quite a bit lower than
120, 180, 190, 200, 210. Okay. Aum
is quite a bit lower than OM.
is quite a bit lower than OM. Okay.
120, 180, 190, 200, 210. Okay. Aum
is quite a bit lower than OM. Okay. The
um
um mantra
um mantra that
um mantra that we
um mantra that we play
um mantra that we play is
um mantra that we play is uh
um mantra that we play is uh 740.
um mantra that we play is uh 740. All
right.
right. Let's
um mantra that we play is uh 740. All
right. Let's see
right. Let's see where
um mantra that we play is uh 740. All
right. Let's see where we
right. Let's see where we can
um mantra that we play is uh 740. All
right. Let's see where we can go
right. Let's see where we can go with
them.
We
We have
them.
We have permission.
We have permission. Amen.
them.
We have permission. Amen. Jesus
is
is over
is over 700.
Oh
Oh is
is over 700.
Oh is over
Oh is over 780.
Home
Home is
Home is over
Home is over 790.
Oh
Oh is
Home is over 790.
Oh is over
Oh is over 800.
Oh
can
all
all the
all the oh
all the oh Lord
all the oh Lord amen.
The
The Lord
all the oh Lord amen.
The Lord God
The Lord God and
all the oh Lord amen.
The Lord God and son
The Lord God and son are
all the oh Lord amen.
The Lord God and son are one.
920 Oh,
920 Oh, they're
920 Oh, they're going
920 Oh, they're going to
920 Oh, they're going to pick
920 Oh, they're going to pick up
920 Oh, they're going to pick up the
sound
sound of
sound of the
sound of the I
sound of the I see
sound of the I see what
sound of the I see what they're
sound of the I see what they're picking
up.
>> Okay.
>> 990.
>> 990. They're
>> Okay.
>> 990. They're picking
>> 990. They're picking up
>> Okay.
>> 990. They're picking up this
>> 990. They're picking up this energy
>> Okay.
>> 990. They're picking up this energy of
this
this consciousness
this consciousness is
this consciousness is over
this consciousness is over 990.
>> I
>> I see.
this consciousness is over 990.
>> I see. Okay.
>> So,
>> So, it
>> So, it isn't
>> So, it isn't the
>> So, it isn't the sound
>> So, it isn't the sound itself,
>> So, it isn't the sound itself, but
>> So, it isn't the sound itself, but um
>> yes.
>> So,
>> So, the
>> So, the sound
>> So, the sound it
>> So, the sound it is
>> So, the sound it is very
>> So, the sound it is very high.
>> So, the sound it is very high. the
>> So, the sound it is very high. the sound
ah
ah makes
>> So, the sound it is very high. the sound
ah makes you
ah makes you go
>> So, the sound it is very high. the sound
ah makes you go strong
ah makes you go strong with
>> So, the sound it is very high. the sound
ah makes you go strong with kinesiology
and
and that's
and that's why
and that's why Dr.
and that's why Dr. Diamond
and that's why Dr. Diamond uses
and that's why Dr. Diamond uses haha.
So
So we've
and that's why Dr. Diamond uses haha.
So we've done
So we've done it
and that's why Dr. Diamond uses haha.
So we've done it in
So we've done it in fact
and that's why Dr. Diamond uses haha.
So we've done it in fact in
So we've done it in fact in groups
because
because I've
because I've given
because I've given lectures
because I've given lectures on
consciousness
consciousness and
because I've given lectures on
consciousness and kinesiology
consciousness and kinesiology for
because I've given lectures on
consciousness and kinesiology for many
years.
years. We
years. We had
years. We had uh
years. We had uh groups
years. We had uh groups at
years. We had uh groups at um
years. We had uh groups at um Sedona
years. We had uh groups at um Sedona um
whatchamacall
whatchamacall there
years. We had uh groups at um Sedona um
whatchamacall there was
whatchamacall there was a
years. We had uh groups at um Sedona um
whatchamacall there was a rehab
whatchamacall there was a rehab place
for
for alcoholism.
for alcoholism. A
for alcoholism. A very
for alcoholism. A very excellent
for alcoholism. A very excellent one
too.
too. About
for alcoholism. A very excellent one
too. About 20
too. About 20 beds,
for alcoholism. A very excellent one
too. About 20 beds, 26
too. About 20 beds, 26 beds.
for alcoholism. A very excellent one
too. About 20 beds, 26 beds. And
too. About 20 beds, 26 beds. And we
would
would do
would do this
would do this with
would do this with a
would do this with a group
would do this with a group and
would do this with a group and people
would
would go
would do this with a group and people
would go come
would go come in
would do this with a group and people
would go come in blown
would go come in blown out
would do this with a group and people
would go come in blown out by
would go come in blown out by their
drugs
drugs and
drugs and alcohol
drugs and alcohol and
drugs and alcohol and rock
drugs and alcohol and rock music
drugs and alcohol and rock music and
drugs and alcohol and rock music and all
that
that stuff.
drugs and alcohol and rock music and all
that stuff. And
that stuff. And uh
drugs and alcohol and rock music and all
that stuff. And uh and
that stuff. And uh and they
drugs and alcohol and rock music and all
that stuff. And uh and they would
that stuff. And uh and they would go
like
like that
like that and
like that and then
like that and then they
like that and then they would
like that and then they would first
they'd
they'd be
like that and then they would first
they'd be weak.
they'd be weak. You
like that and then they would first
they'd be weak. You know,
they'd be weak. You know, we'd
like that and then they would first
they'd be weak. You know, we'd ask
they'd be weak. You know, we'd ask them
something
something true
something true and
something true and they
something true and they would
something true and they would go
something true and they would go weak
something true and they would go weak to
truth.
truth. Uh-oh.
And
And uh
And uh then
And uh then we
And uh then we would
And uh then we would have
And uh then we would have them
And uh then we would have them do
And uh then we would have them do these
exercises
exercises and
And uh then we would have them do these
exercises and now
exercises and now they
And uh then we would have them do these
exercises and now they would
exercises and now they would go
And uh then we would have them do these
exercises and now they would go strong
with
with truth
with truth and
with truth and weak
with truth and weak with
with truth and weak with falsehood.
with truth and weak with falsehood. So
the
the difficulty
with truth and weak with falsehood. So
the difficulty with
the difficulty with certain
with truth and weak with falsehood. So
the difficulty with certain kinds
the difficulty with certain kinds of
music
music is
music is that
music is that it
music is that it reverses
music is that it reverses the
music is that it reverses the field
music is that it reverses the field that
which
which is
music is that it reverses the field that
which is you
which is you know
music is that it reverses the field that
which is you know if
which is you know if you
music is that it reverses the field that
which is you know if you listen
which is you know if you listen to
certain
certain groups
certain groups rock
certain groups rock groups
certain groups rock groups now
certain groups rock groups now you
certain groups rock groups now you will
go
go strong
certain groups rock groups now you will
go strong with
go strong with that
certain groups rock groups now you will
go strong with that which
go strong with that which is
certain groups rock groups now you will
go strong with that which is uh
go strong with that which is uh truly
wicked
wicked and
wicked and you
wicked and you go
wicked and you go weak
wicked and you go weak with
wicked and you go weak with that
wicked and you go weak with that which
is
is divine.
wicked and you go weak with that which
is divine. So
is divine. So there
wicked and you go weak with that which
is divine. So there is
is divine. So there is a
wicked and you go weak with that which
is divine. So there is a very
is divine. So there is a very serious
problem
problem affecting
problem affecting the
problem affecting the youth.
problem affecting the youth. You
problem affecting the youth. You know
problem affecting the youth. You know it
is
is the
problem affecting the youth. You know it
is the main
is the main channel
problem affecting the youth. You know it
is the main channel on
is the main channel on which
the
the conscious
the conscious level
the conscious level of
the conscious level of youth
the conscious level of youth is
the conscious level of youth is being
undermined
undermined is
the conscious level of youth is being
undermined is coming
undermined is coming through
the conscious level of youth is being
undermined is coming through the
invisible
invisible soundless
invisible soundless vibration
invisible soundless vibration that
invisible soundless vibration that goes
along
along with
invisible soundless vibration that goes
along with such
along with such music.
invisible soundless vibration that goes
along with such music. The
along with such music. The world
invisible soundless vibration that goes
along with such music. The world thinks
it's
it's the
it's the lyrics.
it's the lyrics. It's
it's the lyrics. It's not
it's the lyrics. It's not the
it's the lyrics. It's not the lyrics.
The
The lyrics
it's the lyrics. It's not the lyrics.
The lyrics are
The lyrics are bloody
it's the lyrics. It's not the lyrics.
The lyrics are bloody and
The lyrics are bloody and horrible.
it's the lyrics. It's not the lyrics.
The lyrics are bloody and horrible. But
uh
without
without the
uh
without the lyrics,
without the lyrics, the
uh
without the lyrics, the energy
without the lyrics, the energy that
accompanies
accompanies the
accompanies the music
accompanies the music is
accompanies the music is demonic,
accompanies the music is demonic, you
might
might say,
accompanies the music is demonic, you
might say, in
might say, in its
accompanies the music is demonic, you
might say, in its effect
might say, in its effect on
accompanies the music is demonic, you
might say, in its effect on human
beings.
beings. And
beings. And that
beings. And that that
beings. And that that it
beings. And that that it makes
beings. And that that it makes them
beings. And that that it makes them go
weak
weak with
beings. And that that it makes them go
weak with truth
weak with truth and
beings. And that that it makes them go
weak with truth and strong
weak with truth and strong with
beings. And that that it makes them go
weak with truth and strong with that
which
which is
which is false.
Uh-huh.
Now
Now when
Now when people
Now when people go
Now when people go through
Now when people go through a
Now when people go through a course
Now when people go through a course of
miracles
miracles by
Now when people go through a course of
miracles by lesson
miracles by lesson 75
Now when people go through a course of
miracles by lesson 75 to
miracles by lesson 75 to 90,
Now when people go through a course of
miracles by lesson 75 to 90, he
miracles by lesson 75 to 90, he said
Now when people go through a course of
miracles by lesson 75 to 90, he said the
normally
normally noxious
normally noxious stimuli
normally noxious stimuli like
normally noxious stimuli like artificial
light
light etc.
normally noxious stimuli like artificial
light etc. no
light etc. no longer
normally noxious stimuli like artificial
light etc. no longer make
light etc. no longer make one
normally noxious stimuli like artificial
light etc. no longer make one go
light etc. no longer make one go weak.
What
What is
What is the
What is the reason
What is the reason for
What is the reason for this?
What is the reason for this? Oh
What is the reason for this? Oh well
um
um according
What is the reason for this? Oh well
um according to
um according to the
What is the reason for this? Oh well
um according to the course
um according to the course itself
What is the reason for this? Oh well
um according to the course itself uh
you're
you're only
you're only subject
you're only subject to
you're only subject to what
you're only subject to what you
you're only subject to what you hold
you're only subject to what you hold in
mind.
mind. Eventually
you're only subject to what you hold in
mind. Eventually your
mind. Eventually your own
you're only subject to what you hold in
mind. Eventually your own consciousness
becomes
becomes stronger
becomes stronger than
becomes stronger than the
becomes stronger than the the
becomes stronger than the the positive
power
power of
becomes stronger than the the positive
power of your
power of your own
becomes stronger than the the positive
power of your own consciousness
power of your own consciousness is
stronger
stronger than
stronger than the
stronger than the negative
stronger than the negative influence
stronger than the negative influence of
what
what you
stronger than the negative influence of
what you might
what you might call
stronger than the negative influence of
what you might call adverse
what you might call adverse uh
stronger than the negative influence of
what you might call adverse uh energies
or
or vibrations.
Um,
Um, eventually
or vibrations.
Um, eventually you
Um, eventually you become
or vibrations.
Um, eventually you become immune
Um, eventually you become immune to
fear.
fear. For
fear. For instance,
fear. For instance, uh,
fear. For instance, uh, as
fear. For instance, uh, as I
fear. For instance, uh, as I said,
fear. For instance, uh, as I said, you
know,
know, what
fear. For instance, uh, as I said, you
know, what would
know, what would you
fear. For instance, uh, as I said, you
know, what would you do
know, what would you do if
fear. For instance, uh, as I said, you
know, what would you do if somebody's
about
about to
about to blow
about to blow you
about to blow you away
about to blow you away with
about to blow you away with a
about to blow you away with a 45?
about to blow you away with a 45? You
just
just go
because
because I
because I mean,
because I mean, it's
because I mean, it's his
because I mean, it's his problem.
because I mean, it's his problem. He's
going
going to
because I mean, it's his problem. He's
going to have
going to have to
because I mean, it's his problem. He's
going to have to face
going to have to face the
because I mean, it's his problem. He's
going to have to face the consequences
of
of blowing
of blowing you
of blowing you away.
of blowing you away. I'm
of blowing you away. I'm not
of blowing you away. I'm not worried
about
about it.
of blowing you away. I'm not worried
about it. Uh,
that's
that's true.
that's true. That's
that's true. That's what
that's true. That's what you
that's true. That's what you do.
that's true. That's what you do. I
that's true. That's what you do. I mean,
I
I hate
that's true. That's what you do. I mean,
I hate loud
I hate loud sounds.
that's true. That's what you do. I mean,
I hate loud sounds. [laughter]
That's
That's exactly
That's exactly what
That's exactly what you
That's exactly what you do.
That's exactly what you do. You
That's exactly what you do. You go
>> [laughter]
>> You
>> You make
>> You make a
>> You make a face
>> You make a face so
>> You make a face so he'll
>> You make a face so he'll laugh.
>> You make a face so he'll laugh. So
>> You make a face so he'll laugh. So that
just
just as
>> You make a face so he'll laugh. So that
just as he
just as he pulls
>> You make a face so he'll laugh. So that
just as he pulls the
just as he pulls the trigger,
>> You make a face so he'll laugh. So that
just as he pulls the trigger, he
realizes,
realizes, "Oh,
realizes, "Oh, shoot.
realizes, "Oh, shoot. I
realizes, "Oh, shoot. I shouldn't
realizes, "Oh, shoot. I shouldn't have
done
done that."
realizes, "Oh, shoot. I shouldn't have
done that." [laughter]
So
So you
So you serve
So you serve him
So you serve him at
So you serve him at the
So you serve him at the last
So you serve him at the last moment
because
because as
So you serve him at the last moment
because as he
because as he pulls
So you serve him at the last moment
because as he pulls the
because as he pulls the trigger,
So you serve him at the last moment
because as he pulls the trigger, he
realizes,
realizes, "Jesus,
realizes, "Jesus, I
realizes, "Jesus, I just
realizes, "Jesus, I just made
realizes, "Jesus, I just made a
realizes, "Jesus, I just made a bad
realizes, "Jesus, I just made a bad one.
Bad
Bad mistake."
realizes, "Jesus, I just made a bad one.
Bad mistake." He
Bad mistake." He gets
realizes, "Jesus, I just made a bad one.
Bad mistake." He gets that
Bad mistake." He gets that because
realizes, "Jesus, I just made a bad one.
Bad mistake." He gets that because of
your
your willingness
your willingness to
your willingness to love
your willingness to love him
your willingness to love him and
your willingness to love him and forgive
him
him even
your willingness to love him and forgive
him even though
him even though he's
your willingness to love him and forgive
him even though he's killing
him even though he's killing him.
So
So suddenly
So suddenly he
So suddenly he wakes
So suddenly he wakes up
So suddenly he wakes up and
So suddenly he wakes up and says,
So suddenly he wakes up and says, "Wow,
that's
that's the
So suddenly he wakes up and says, "Wow,
that's the wrong
that's the wrong way
So suddenly he wakes up and says, "Wow,
that's the wrong way to
that's the wrong way to go."
So suddenly he wakes up and says, "Wow,
that's the wrong way to go." And
that's the wrong way to go." And um
that's
that's why
that's why you
that's why you grin
that's why you grin and
that's why you grin and smile
that's why you grin and smile at
whoever's
whoever's shooting
that's why you grin and smile at
whoever's shooting you
whoever's shooting you to
that's why you grin and smile at
whoever's shooting you to keep
whoever's shooting you to keep them
laughing.
laughing. You
laughing. You know what
laughing. You know what I'm
laughing. You know what I'm saying?
[laughter]
Got
Got to
Got to keep
Got to keep them
Got to keep them laughing
Got to keep them laughing because
otherwise
otherwise you
Got to keep them laughing because
otherwise you might
otherwise you might go
Got to keep them laughing because
otherwise you might go to
otherwise you might go to bad
Got to keep them laughing because
otherwise you might go to bad places.
You
You know what
You know what I
You know what I mean?
You know what I mean? You
You know what I mean? You don't
You know what I mean? You don't want
You know what I mean? You don't want to
go
go there.
You know what I mean? You don't want to
go there. All right.
go there. All right. Um
so
so as
so as consciousness
so as consciousness advances,
so as consciousness advances, you're
you're
you're less
so as consciousness advances, you're
you're less and
you're less and less
so as consciousness advances, you're
you're less and less uh
you're less and less uh subject
so as consciousness advances, you're
you're less and less uh subject to
you're less and less uh subject to in
negativity.
negativity. One
negativity. One is
negativity. One is reason
negativity. One is reason is
negativity. One is reason is you
negativity. One is reason is you don't
give
give it
negativity. One is reason is you don't
give it any
give it any energy.
negativity. One is reason is you don't
give it any energy. You
give it any energy. You don't
negativity. One is reason is you don't
give it any energy. You don't give
give it any energy. You don't give it
any
any power
any power and
any power and you
any power and you begin
any power and you begin realizing
any power and you begin realizing the
nature
nature of
any power and you begin realizing the
nature of God
nature of God is
any power and you begin realizing the
nature of God is such
nature of God is such that
any power and you begin realizing the
nature of God is such that the
nature of God is such that the essence
and
and the
and the truth
and the truth of
and the truth of who
and the truth of who you
and the truth of who you are
and the truth of who you are is
unaffected
unaffected by
and the truth of who you are is
unaffected by anything
unaffected by anything in
and the truth of who you are is
unaffected by anything in the
unaffected by anything in the world.
and the truth of who you are is
unaffected by anything in the world. And
the
the only
the only thing
the only thing that
the only thing that interferes
the only thing that interferes with
the only thing that interferes with it
is
is as
the only thing that interferes with it
is as belief
is as belief systems.
So
So the
So the only
So the only power
the
the only
So the only power
the only thing
the only thing that
So the only power
the only thing that has
the only thing that has power
So the only power
the only thing that has power over
the only thing that has power over you
is
is the
is the beliefs
is the beliefs of
is the beliefs of your
is the beliefs of your own
is the beliefs of your own mind.
is the beliefs of your own mind. So
is the beliefs of your own mind. So that
is
is apparently
is the beliefs of your own mind. So that
is apparently because
is apparently because that's
is the beliefs of your own mind. So that
is apparently because that's the
is apparently because that's the lesson
around
around lesson
around lesson 75
around lesson 75 in
around lesson 75 in the
around lesson 75 in the course
around lesson 75 in the course of
miracles.
Um,
can
can you
Um,
can you Well,
can you Well, this
Um,
can you Well, this has
can you Well, this has to
Um,
can you Well, this has to do
can you Well, this has to do with
aligning
aligning one's
aligning one's gifts
aligning one's gifts and
aligning one's gifts and purpose
aligning one's gifts and purpose with
one's
one's spiritual
aligning one's gifts and purpose with
one's spiritual journey.
one's spiritual journey. I
aligning one's gifts and purpose with
one's spiritual journey. I would
one's spiritual journey. I would say
that's
that's [clears throat]
the
the totality
that's [clears throat]
the totality of
the totality of a
that's [clears throat]
the totality of a commitment.
the totality of a commitment. You
that's [clears throat]
the totality of a commitment. You commit
all
all your
all your assets,
all your assets, everything
all your assets, everything that
all your assets, everything that that
you're
you're capable
all your assets, everything that that
you're capable of.
you're capable of. If
all your assets, everything that that
you're capable of. If you're
you're capable of. If you're a
all your assets, everything that that
you're capable of. If you're a good
engineer,
you
you dedicate
engineer,
you dedicate your
you dedicate your engineering
engineer,
you dedicate your engineering skills
you dedicate your engineering skills to
serving
serving mankind
serving mankind in
serving mankind in whatever
serving mankind in whatever way,
serving mankind in whatever way, whether
it's
it's providing
serving mankind in whatever way, whether
it's providing a
it's providing a factory
serving mankind in whatever way, whether
it's providing a factory from
it's providing a factory from which
people
people are
people are going
people are going to
people are going to earn
people are going to earn a
people are going to earn a living
people are going to earn a living and
life
life is
people are going to earn a living and
life is going
life is going to
people are going to earn a living and
life is going to be
life is going to be supported
people are going to earn a living and
life is going to be supported by
life is going to be supported by the
people are going to earn a living and
life is going to be supported by the so
you
you you
you you surrender
you you surrender whatever
you you surrender whatever skills
you you surrender whatever skills you
have,
have, music
you you surrender whatever skills you
have, music or
have, music or art,
you you surrender whatever skills you
have, music or art, whatever
have, music or art, whatever your
talents
talents may
talents may be.
talents may be. teaching
talents may be. teaching you
talents may be. teaching you you
talents may be. teaching you you teach
the
the children
talents may be. teaching you you teach
the children but
the children but you're
talents may be. teaching you you teach
the children but you're teaching
the children but you're teaching them
from
from a
from a certain
from a certain energy
from a certain energy which
from a certain energy which is
from a certain energy which is a
from a certain energy which is a so
from a certain energy which is a so it's
the
the context
from a certain energy which is a so it's
the context from
the context from which
from a certain energy which is a so it's
the context from which you're
the context from which you're teaching
the
the children
the children not
the children not just
the children not just the
the children not just the content
because
because there
the children not just the content
because there are
because there are some
the children not just the content
because there are some teachers
because there are some teachers that
inspire
inspire you
inspire you and
inspire you and then
inspire you and then there's
inspire you and then there's other
teachers
teachers that
inspire you and then there's other
teachers that discourage
teachers that discourage you
inspire you and then there's other
teachers that discourage you uh
teachers that discourage you uh there's
teachers
teachers that
teachers that are
teachers that are very
teachers that are very traumatic
teachers that are very traumatic you
teachers that are very traumatic you can
have
have a
teachers that are very traumatic you can
have a teacher
have a teacher in
teachers that are very traumatic you can
have a teacher in grade
have a teacher in grade school
teachers that are very traumatic you can
have a teacher in grade school that
takes
takes years
takes years to
takes years to recover
takes years to recover from
takes years to recover from right
takes years to recover from right many
years
years to
takes years to recover from right many
years to recover
years to recover from
takes years to recover from right many
years to recover from I
years to recover from I mean
takes years to recover from right many
years to recover from I mean a
horrendously
horrendously uh
horrific
horrific teacher
horrendously uh
horrific teacher Yeah.
Um
you
you talk
Um
you talk about
you talk about surrendering
Um
you talk about surrendering to
you talk about surrendering to God.
Um
you talk about surrendering to God. If
in
in non-duality
in non-duality there
in non-duality there is
in non-duality there is no
in non-duality there is no separation
in non-duality there is no separation or
separate
separate this
in non-duality there is no separation or
separate this or
separate this or that,
in non-duality there is no separation or
separate this or that, then
separate this or that, then what
in non-duality there is no separation or
separate this or that, then what is
separate this or that, then what is the
God
God that
God that we're
God that we're surrendering
God that we're surrendering to
God that we're surrendering to or
God that we're surrendering to or being
devoted
devoted to?
Or
Or you
Or you can't
Or you can't answer
Or you can't answer that
Or you can't answer that question
without
without begging
Or you can't answer that question
without begging the
without begging the question.
Or you can't answer that question
without begging the question. [laughter]
What
What is
What is the
What is the what
What is the what of
What is the what of godness?
That's
That's really
What is the what of godness?
That's really good.
That's really good. All right.
What is the what of godness?
That's really good. All right. So,
That's really good. All right. So, we'll
have
have to
have to uh
have to uh we'll
have to uh we'll have
have to uh we'll have to
have to uh we'll have to re
have to uh we'll have to re re
um
identify
identify the
identify the nature
identify the nature of
identify the nature of God.
identify the nature of God. We
identify the nature of God. We did
identify the nature of God. We did the
nature
nature of
identify the nature of God. We did the
nature of God.
nature of God. I
identify the nature of God. We did the
nature of God. I think
nature of God. I think wasn't
identify the nature of God. We did the
nature of God. I think wasn't it
nature of God. I think wasn't it the
last
last time
last time that
last time that we
last time that we went
last time that we went through
last time that we went through 10
statements
statements and
last time that we went through 10
statements and as
statements and as a
last time that we went through 10
statements and as a group
statements and as a group we
last time that we went through 10
statements and as a group we all
statements and as a group we all did
kinesiology.
All right.
All right. The
kinesiology.
All right. The God
All right. The God is
kinesiology.
All right. The God is um
All right. The God is um so
kinesiology.
All right. The God is um so we'll
All right. The God is um so we'll have
to
to go
to go through
to go through the
to go through the levels
to go through the levels of
to go through the levels of God.
God
God is
to go through the levels of God.
God is um
God is um ultimately
to go through the levels of God.
God is um ultimately what
God is um ultimately what you
to go through the levels of God.
God is um ultimately what you define
God is um ultimately what you define God
as
in
in language
experientially
out
out of
experientially
out of the
out of the unmanifest
experientially
out of the unmanifest beyond
out of the unmanifest beyond all
experientially
out of the unmanifest beyond all form.
The
The infinite
The infinite potentiality
The infinite potentiality which
The infinite potentiality which is
The infinite potentiality which is a
totally
totally and
The infinite potentiality which is a
totally and completely
totally and completely unlimited
is
is the
is the Godhead
is the Godhead described
is the Godhead described classically
is the Godhead described classically as
the
the Godhead
out
out of
out of the
out of the voidness.
out of the voidness. It
out of the voidness. It says
out of the voidness. It says in
out of the voidness. It says in Genesis,
out
out of
out of the voidness. It says in Genesis,
out of the
out of the non
out of the voidness. It says in Genesis,
out of the non form
arose
arose the
arose the manifest
as
as a
arose the manifest
as a consequence
of
of the
of the creator
of the creator whose
of the creator whose essence
of the creator whose essence is
that
that which
of the creator whose essence is
that which creates
and
and which
and which is
and which is continuously
and which is continuously present.
It
It is
and which is continuously present.
It is out
It is out of
and which is continuously present.
It is out of the
It is out of the potential,
the
the infinite
the infinite power
the infinite power that
the infinite power that it
the infinite power that it takes
the infinite power that it takes to
bring
bring existence
the infinite power that it takes to
bring existence out
bring existence out of
the infinite power that it takes to
bring existence out of non-existence.
So
So both
So both existence
So both existence and
So both existence and non-existence
So both existence and non-existence are
points
points of
So both existence and non-existence are
points of view,
points of view, positionalities.
There
There is
There is neither
There is neither existence
There is neither existence nor
non-existence.
non-existence. There
There is neither existence nor
non-existence. There is
non-existence. There is only
a
a point
a point of
a point of observation.
a point of observation. But
a point of observation. But that
a point of observation. But that is
about
about 850.
It's
It's not
It's not a
It's not a problem
It's not a problem till
It's not a problem till you
It's not a problem till you get
It's not a problem till you get around
850.
850. And
It's not a problem till you get around
850. And you
850. And you get
It's not a problem till you get around
850. And you get around
850. And you get around there,
It's not a problem till you get around
850. And you get around there, you
850. And you get around there, you call
me
me and
me and I'll
me and I'll help
me and I'll help you
me and I'll help you through
me and I'll help you through that
me and I'll help you through that one.
Do
Do I
me and I'll help you through that one.
Do I exist
Do I exist or
me and I'll help you through that one.
Do I exist or not
Do I exist or not exist?
me and I'll help you through that one.
Do I exist or not exist? Well,
Do I exist or not exist? Well, I'll
me and I'll help you through that one.
Do I exist or not exist? Well, I'll tell
you.
Stop
Stop asking
you.
Stop asking the
Stop asking the question
you.
Stop asking the question and
Stop asking the question and it
you.
Stop asking the question and it solves
itself.
itself. Oh,
itself. Oh, yeah.
itself. Oh, yeah. Right.
itself. Oh, yeah. Right. Anyway,
[laughter]
I
I would
I would imagine
I would imagine the
I would imagine the person
I would imagine the person is
I would imagine the person is talking
about
about um
I would imagine the person is talking
about um experientially
There
There is
There is a
There is a level
There is a level at
There is a level at which
There is a level at which the
There is a level at which the infinite
reality
reality is
There is a level at which the infinite
reality is experienced
reality is experienced as
There is a level at which the infinite
reality is experienced as nothingness.
It's
It's very
It's very profound.
It's
It's very
It's very profound.
It's very overwhelming.
It's very overwhelming. Let's
It's very profound.
It's very overwhelming. Let's calibrate
the
the void.
We
We have
the void.
We have permission
We have permission to
the void.
We have permission to calibrate
We have permission to calibrate the
the void.
We have permission to calibrate the void
to
to 900,
to 900, 920,
to 900, 920, 960,
to 900, 920, 960, about
to 900, 920, 960, about 960.
to 900, 920, 960, about 960. That's
right.
a
a very
a very high
a very high state.
a very high state. The
a very high state. The pathway
a very high state. The pathway of
negation,
negation, the
a very high state. The pathway of
negation, the Buddhist
negation, the Buddhist pathway
a very high state. The pathway of
negation, the Buddhist pathway commonly
in
in which
in which the
in which the ultimate
in which the ultimate reality
in which the ultimate reality is
in which the ultimate reality is called
void
void is
in which the ultimate reality is called
void is the
void is the pathway
in which the ultimate reality is called
void is the pathway of
void is the pathway of negation.
Negation
Negation will
Negation will to
Negation will to get
Negation will to get and
Negation will to get and at
Negation will to get and at 960
Negation will to get and at 960 you
Negation will to get and at 960 you go
into
into the
Negation will to get and at 960 you go
into the void
into the void which
Negation will to get and at 960 you go
into the void which is
very
very very
very very impressive
very very impressive and
very very impressive and unless
very very impressive and unless one
very very impressive and unless one has
been
been made
very very impressive and unless one has
been made aware
been made aware in
very very impressive and unless one has
been made aware in advance
been made aware in advance one
very very impressive and unless one has
been made aware in advance one would
think
think this
think this is
think this is the
think this is the ultimate
think this is the ultimate reality.
It
It certainly
think this is the ultimate reality.
It certainly seems
It certainly seems ultimate
until
a
a little
until
a little knowingness
a little knowingness within
until
a little knowingness within notices
a little knowingness within notices the
absence
absence of
absence of love
void
void of
absence of love
void of everything.
And
And the
And the absence
And the absence of
And the absence of love
And the absence of love is
And the absence of love is what
And the absence of love is what tells
you
you this
And the absence of love is what tells
you this ain't
you this ain't it.
And the absence of love is what tells
you this ain't it. It's
you this ain't it. It's almost
And the absence of love is what tells
you this ain't it. It's almost it
you this ain't it. It's almost it but
not
not quite
not quite it.
As
As you
not quite it.
As you let
As you let go
not quite it.
As you let go identifying
As you let go identifying with
not quite it.
As you let go identifying with content,
you
you progressively
you progressively identify
you progressively identify and
experience
experience the
you progressively identify and
experience the reality
experience the reality of
you progressively identify and
experience the reality of context
experience the reality of context until
finally
finally it
finally it becomes
finally it becomes overwhelming.
It's
It's the
finally it becomes overwhelming.
It's the substrate
It's the substrate of
finally it becomes overwhelming.
It's the substrate of consciousness
itself
behind
behind mind.
itself
behind mind. So
behind mind. So we
itself
behind mind. So we we'll
behind mind. So we we'll go
itself
behind mind. So we we'll go back
behind mind. So we we'll go back to
this.
this. We'll
this. We'll just
this. We'll just review
this. We'll just review this
this. We'll just review this one
this. We'll just review this one uh
chart.
So
So this
So this uh
So this uh you
So this uh you begin
So this uh you begin with
So this uh you begin with usually
So this uh you begin with usually start
from
from the
So this uh you begin with usually start
from the bottom
from the bottom and
So this uh you begin with usually start
from the bottom and you
from the bottom and you move
So this uh you begin with usually start
from the bottom and you move up.
from the bottom and you move up. form
So this uh you begin with usually start
from the bottom and you move up. form is
the
the ego
the ego linear
the ego linear uh
the ego linear uh world
the ego linear uh world of
the ego linear uh world of that
the ego linear uh world of that which
the ego linear uh world of that which we
think
think is
the ego linear uh world of that which we
think is real.
think is real. How
the ego linear uh world of that which we
think is real. How do
think is real. How do you
the ego linear uh world of that which we
think is real. How do you know
think is real. How do you know that
the ego linear uh world of that which we
think is real. How do you know that you
know
know that?
know that? Because
know that? Because it's
know that? Because it's registering
someplace.
someplace. How
know that? Because it's registering
someplace. How does
someplace. How does it
know that? Because it's registering
someplace. How does it register?
someplace. How does it register? It
registers
registers as
registers as a
registers as a recognition.
registers as a recognition. You
recognize
recognize a
registers as a recognition. You
recognize a thought,
recognize a thought, a
registers as a recognition. You
recognize a thought, a feeling,
recognize a thought, a feeling, a
registers as a recognition. You
recognize a thought, a feeling, a form.
You
You call
You call it
You call it doggy,
You call it doggy, kitty,
You call it doggy, kitty, whatever
You call it doggy, kitty, whatever you
want
want to
You call it doggy, kitty, whatever you
want to call
want to call it.
In
In meditation,
In meditation, you
In meditation, you then
In meditation, you then go
In meditation, you then go come
In meditation, you then go come back
from
from the
In meditation, you then go come back
from the content
from the content of
In meditation, you then go come back
from the content of what's
from the content of what's being
In meditation, you then go come back
from the content of what's being um
witnessed
witnessed and
witnessed and realize
witnessed and realize that
witnessed and realize that there's
witnessed and realize that there's a
watcher
watcher experiencer.
witnessed and realize that there's a
watcher experiencer. How
watcher experiencer. How do
witnessed and realize that there's a
watcher experiencer. How do you
watcher experiencer. How do you know
what's
what's going
what's going on
what's going on in
what's going on in your
what's going on in your mind
what's going on in your mind here?
Because
Because there's
what's going on in your mind here?
Because there's a
Because there's a watcher
what's going on in your mind here?
Because there's a watcher experiencer
that's
that's already
that's already a
that's already a substrate
that's already a substrate to
that's already a substrate to the
content.
content. There's
that's already a substrate to the
content. There's a
content. There's a watcher
that's already a substrate to the
content. There's a watcher experiencer.
Now,
Now, the
Now, the interesting
Now, the interesting thing
Now, the interesting thing is
Now, the interesting thing is that
Now, the interesting thing is that all
this
this is
Now, the interesting thing is that all
this is all
this is all this
Now, the interesting thing is that all
this is all this whole
this is all this whole phenomena
Now, the interesting thing is that all
this is all this whole phenomena is
going
going on
going on of
going on of its
going on of its own.
going on of its own. And
going on of its own. And somewhere
going on of its own. And somewhere along
in
in meditation
going on of its own. And somewhere along
in meditation you
in meditation you realize
going on of its own. And somewhere along
in meditation you realize there
in meditation you realize there is
going on of its own. And somewhere along
in meditation you realize there is no
eye
eye doing
eye doing any
eye doing any of
eye doing any of this.
There
There is
eye doing any of this.
There is no
There is no eye
eye doing any of this.
There is no eye that
There is no eye that is
eye doing any of this.
There is no eye that is recognizing
form,
form, naming
form, naming form.
There
There is
form, naming form.
There is a
There is a watcher
form, naming form.
There is a watcher experience.
There is a watcher experience. There's
form, naming form.
There is a watcher experience. There's a
within
within itself
within itself within
within itself within awareness
there's
there's an
within itself within awareness
there's an automatic
there's an automatic there's
within itself within awareness
there's an automatic there's an
automatic
automatic field
automatic field in
automatic field in which
automatic field in which thinkingness
watching
watching feeling
automatic field in which thinkingness
watching feeling this
is
is happening
is happening of
is happening of its
is happening of its own.
is happening of its own. Just
is happening of its own. Just like
protoplasm
protoplasm bleeds
is happening of its own. Just like
protoplasm bleeds on
protoplasm bleeds on its
is happening of its own. Just like
protoplasm bleeds on its own,
protoplasm bleeds on its own, you
is happening of its own. Just like
protoplasm bleeds on its own, you don't
say,
say, "I
say, "I think
say, "I think I
say, "I think I will
say, "I think I will bleed
say, "I think I will bleed from
say, "I think I will bleed from this
wound."
wound." Protoplasm
say, "I think I will bleed from this
wound." Protoplasm does
wound." Protoplasm does it
say, "I think I will bleed from this
wound." Protoplasm does it because
that's
that's the
that's the nature
that's the nature of
that's the nature of protoplasm.
that's the nature of protoplasm. You
stick
stick it,
that's the nature of protoplasm. You
stick it, it
stick it, it recoils,
that's the nature of protoplasm. You
stick it, it recoils, it
stick it, it recoils, it bleeds.
that's the nature of protoplasm. You
stick it, it recoils, it bleeds. You
realize
realize something
realize something impersonal
realize something impersonal is
realize something impersonal is going
realize something impersonal is going on
that
that within
realize something impersonal is going on
that within mind
that within mind there
realize something impersonal is going on
that within mind there is
that within mind there is a
realize something impersonal is going on
that within mind there is a witness
witnessing
witnessing all
witnessing all no
witnessing all no matter
witnessing all no matter what
witnessing all no matter what the
content
content is.
witnessing all no matter what the
content is. Same
content is. Same witness
witnessing all no matter what the
content is. Same witness sees
content is. Same witness sees this
movie,
movie, same
movie, same witness
movie, same witness sees
movie, same witness sees that
movie, same witness sees that movie,
same
same witness
movie, same witness sees that movie,
same witness sees
same witness sees that
movie, same witness sees that movie,
same witness sees that movie.
same witness sees that movie. The
witness
witness doesn't
witness doesn't change
witness doesn't change the
witness doesn't change the movie.
witness doesn't change the movie. The
movie
you
you stop
you stop identifying
you stop identifying with
you stop identifying with form.
you stop identifying with form. You
you stop identifying with form. You stop
by
by identifying
you stop identifying with form. You stop
by identifying with
by identifying with this
you stop identifying with form. You stop
by identifying with this phenomena.
Recognition
Recognition obviously
Recognition obviously comes
Recognition obviously comes out
Recognition obviously comes out of
Recognition obviously comes out of the
past.
past. And
Recognition obviously comes out of the
past. And you
past. And you realize
Recognition obviously comes out of the
past. And you realize that
past. And you realize that you're
Recognition obviously comes out of the
past. And you realize that you're the
watcher
watcher experiencer.
watcher experiencer. And
watcher experiencer. And then
watcher experiencer. And then you
watcher experiencer. And then you begin
to
to look
watcher experiencer. And then you begin
to look for
to look for where
watcher experiencer. And then you begin
to look for where does
to look for where does the
watcher experiencer. And then you begin
to look for where does the watcher
experiencer
experiencer coming
experiencer coming out
experiencer coming out of?
experiencer coming out of? It's
experiencer coming out of? It's coming
out
out of
experiencer coming out of? It's coming
out of a
out of a more
experiencer coming out of? It's coming
out of a more subtle
out of a more subtle prevailing
experiencer coming out of? It's coming
out of a more subtle prevailing field.
These
These are
These are called
These are called the
These are called the subtle
These are called the subtle levels
These are called the subtle levels in
classic
classic uh
These are called the subtle levels in
classic uh Hindu
classic uh Hindu or
These are called the subtle levels in
classic uh Hindu or whatever
classic uh Hindu or whatever spiritual
tradition.
The
The subtle
tradition.
The subtle bodies,
The subtle bodies, the
tradition.
The subtle bodies, the subtle
The subtle bodies, the subtle bodies.
This
This is
This is physicality
This is physicality of
This is physicality of the
This is physicality of the ego.
This is physicality of the ego. You
start
start going
This is physicality of the ego. You
start going up
start going up through
This is physicality of the ego. You
start going up through the
start going up through the so-called
subtle
subtle bodies
subtle bodies and
subtle bodies and through
subtle bodies and through the
subtle bodies and through the various
chakras
chakras and
subtle bodies and through the various
chakras and the
chakras and the various
subtle bodies and through the various
chakras and the various subtle
chakras and the various subtle bodies.
You
You go
You go to
You go to the
You go to the watcher,
You go to the watcher, the
You go to the watcher, the experiencer,
which
which is
You go to the watcher, the experiencer,
which is the
which is the third
You go to the watcher, the experiencer,
which is the third eye
which is the third eye of
You go to the watcher, the experiencer,
which is the third eye of I
which is the third eye of I forget
You go to the watcher, the experiencer,
which is the third eye of I forget which
body.
body. They've
body. They've all
body. They've all got
body. They've all got wonderful
body. They've all got wonderful names.
And
And you
body. They've all got wonderful names.
And you come
And you come to
body. They've all got wonderful names.
And you come to awareness
And you come to awareness itself.
body. They've all got wonderful names.
And you come to awareness itself. You
realize
realize there's
realize there's only
realize there's only one
realize there's only one constant
realize there's only one constant no
matter
matter what's
realize there's only one constant no
matter what's going
matter what's going on
realize there's only one constant no
matter what's going on and
matter what's going on and that's
awareness.
The
The content
awareness.
The content of
The content of awareness
awareness.
The content of awareness may
The content of awareness may shift
awareness.
The content of awareness may shift all
the
the time
the time but
the time but the
the time but the one
the time but the one basic
the time but the one basic principle
which
which is
the time but the one basic principle
which is operative
which is operative always
is
is awareness.
How
How do
is awareness.
How do you
How do you know
is awareness.
How do you know that?
How do you know that? You
is awareness.
How do you know that? You know
How do you know that? You know because
observing
observing and
observing and witnessing
observing and witnessing is
observing and witnessing is going
observing and witnessing is going on
observing and witnessing is going on all
the
the time.
Awareness
Awareness and
Awareness and the
Awareness and the is
Awareness and the is the
Awareness and the is the nature
Awareness and the is the nature of
Awareness and the is the nature of the
observer
observer witness
Awareness and the is the nature of the
observer witness and
observer witness and again
Awareness and the is the nature of the
observer witness and again that's
observer witness and again that's not
personal
personal it's
personal it's happening
personal it's happening of
personal it's happening of its
personal it's happening of its own
personal it's happening of its own that
which
which is
personal it's happening of its own that
which is attending
which is attending to
personal it's happening of its own that
which is attending to the
which is attending to the lecture
personal it's happening of its own that
which is attending to the lecture is
which is attending to the lecture is not
personal
is
is consciousness
personal
is consciousness itself
it
it has
it has that
it has that quality
it has that quality of
it has that quality of registering
what's
what's going
it has that quality of registering
what's going on.
So
So it
So it doesn't
So it doesn't require
So it doesn't require a
So it doesn't require a personal
So it doesn't require a personal you
So it doesn't require a personal you at
all.
The
The light
The light of
The light of consciousness
The light of consciousness then
The light of consciousness then begin
you
you begin
The light of consciousness then begin
you begin to
you begin to look
The light of consciousness then begin
you begin to look at
you begin to look at consciousness
The light of consciousness then begin
you begin to look at consciousness as
the
the substrate
the substrate of
the substrate of thinkingness,
the substrate of thinkingness, mind,
thought
etc.
etc. Under
etc. Under the
etc. Under the light
etc. Under the light of
etc. Under the light of consciousness,
you
you begin
etc. Under the light of consciousness,
you begin to
you begin to sense
etc. Under the light of consciousness,
you begin to sense that
you begin to sense that there
etc. Under the light of consciousness,
you begin to sense that there is
you begin to sense that there is an
overall
overall field
overall field and
overall field and that
overall field and that is
overall field and that is the
overall field and that is the context
out
out of
overall field and that is the context
out of which
out of which you
overall field and that is the context
out of which you experience
out of which you experience your
overall field and that is the context
out of which you experience your own
existence
or
or experience
existence
or experience yourself
or experience yourself as
existence
or experience yourself as existing
or experience yourself as existing which
again
again is
again is a
again is a jump
again is a jump in
again is a jump in conclusion
again is a jump in conclusion because
the
the reality
again is a jump in conclusion because
the reality is
the reality is that
again is a jump in conclusion because
the reality is that which
the reality is that which you
again is a jump in conclusion because
the reality is that which you are
neither
neither exists
neither exists nor
neither exists nor non-exist
neither exists nor non-exist because
neither exists nor non-exist because it
is
is actually
neither exists nor non-exist because it
is actually unmanifest.
Now
Now what
Now what was
Now what was the
Now what was the question?
Oh,
Oh, the
Now what was the question?
Oh, the what?
Oh, the what? The
Now what was the question?
Oh, the what? The whatness
Oh, the what? The whatness of
Now what was the question?
Oh, the what? The whatness of God.
Oh, the what? The whatness of God. Yes.
That
That one
That one is
the
the very
That one is
the very substrate
the very substrate of
That one is
the very substrate of consciousness
itself.
One
One is
itself.
One is the
One is the source
itself.
One is the source out
One is the source out of
itself.
One is the source out of which
One is the source out of which the
substrate
substrate of
substrate of consciousness
substrate of consciousness arises.
That
That which
substrate of consciousness arises.
That which is
That which is the
substrate of consciousness arises.
That which is the substrate
That which is the substrate of
substrate of consciousness arises.
That which is the substrate of creation
and
and all
and all that
and all that exists
and all that exists is
and all that exists is not
and all that exists is not different
than
than the
and all that exists is not different
than the self
than the self of
and all that exists is not different
than the self of your
than the self of your own
and all that exists is not different
than the self of your own existence.
And
And there's
And there's the
And there's the awareness
And there's the awareness that
And there's the awareness that that
which
which you
And there's the awareness that that
which you are
which you are is
And there's the awareness that that
which you are is identical
which you are is identical with
And there's the awareness that that
which you are is identical with all
which you are is identical with all that
is.
is. And
is. And that's
is. And that's the
is. And that's the realization
is. And that's the realization of
is. And that's the realization of God
is. And that's the realization of God is
allness.
I
I don't
I don't think
I don't think we
I don't think we even
I don't think we even have
I don't think we even have that
I don't think we even have that on
there.
there. Uh
I don't think we even have that on
there. Uh the
there. Uh the ultimate
I don't think we even have that on
there. Uh the ultimate reality
is
is the
is the oneness
is the oneness and
is the oneness and the
is the oneness and the allness
is the oneness and the allness of
existence
existence that
is the oneness and the allness of
existence that takes
existence that takes you
is the oneness and the allness of
existence that takes you beyond
existence that takes you beyond 960.
is the oneness and the allness of
existence that takes you beyond 960. We
said
said 960
said 960 was
said 960 was void
said 960 was void in
said 960 was void in which
said 960 was void in which the
said 960 was void in which the ultimate
experiential
experiential reality
said 960 was void in which the ultimate
experiential reality is
void
void or
void or non-existence
and
and then
void or non-existence
and then you
and then you realize
void or non-existence
and then you realize that's
and then you realize that's an
void or non-existence
and then you realize that's an illusion.
You
You transcend
You transcend go
You transcend go that
You transcend go that you
You transcend go that you let
You transcend go that you let that
You transcend go that you let that go
and
and you
You transcend go that you let that go
and you realize
and you realize that
You transcend go that you let that go
and you realize that the
and you realize that the ultimate
reality
reality is
reality is the
reality is the allness.
reality is the allness. God
reality is the allness. God is
reality is the allness. God is the
source
source of
reality is the allness. God is the
source of the
source of the allness
reality is the allness. God is the
source of the allness of
source of the allness of all
reality is the allness. God is the
source of the allness of all that
exists.
exists. The
exists. The very
exists. The very source
exists. The very source of
exists. The very source of existence
itself.
itself. If
exists. The very source of existence
itself. If you
itself. If you meditate
exists. The very source of existence
itself. If you meditate on
itself. If you meditate on existence,
if
if you
if you meditate
if you meditate on
if you meditate on the
if you meditate on the quality
if you meditate on the quality of
existence
existence itself,
you'll
you'll automatically
you'll automatically get
you'll automatically get taken
you'll automatically get taken to
you'll automatically get taken to the
question
question of
you'll automatically get taken to the
question of and
question of and a
you'll automatically get taken to the
question of and a realization
question of and a realization of
you'll automatically get taken to the
question of and a realization of the
source
source of
source of existence
source of existence itself.
source of existence itself. Not
existence
existence as
source of existence itself. Not
existence as this
existence as this or
source of existence itself. Not
existence as this or existence
existence as this or existence is
source of existence itself. Not
existence as this or existence is that,
but
but the
but the fact
but the fact of
but the fact of existence.
How
How can
but the fact of existence.
How can that
How can that which
but the fact of existence.
How can that which non-exists
How can that which non-exists suddenly
exist?
What
What in
exist?
What in the
What in the world
exist?
What in the world would
What in the world would have
exist?
What in the world would have the
infinite
infinite power
to
to create
infinite power
to create the
to create the capacity
infinite power
to create the capacity for
to create the capacity for existence
itself?
So
So the
itself?
So the basic
So the basic evidence
itself?
So the basic evidence for
So the basic evidence for the
itself?
So the basic evidence for the presence
of
of God
of God within
of God within you
of God within you is
of God within you is is
of God within you is is your
of God within you is is your own
existence.
existence. Without
of God within you is is your own
existence. Without divinity,
existence. Without divinity, no
existence
existence is
existence is possible.
existence is possible. Because
existence is possible. Because in
[clears throat]
[clears throat] the
existence is possible. Because in
[clears throat] the beginning
[clears throat] the beginning there
existence is possible. Because in
[clears throat] the beginning there was
only
only the
only the void,
only the void, the
only the void, the nothingness
only the void, the nothingness and
voidness.
voidness. And
only the void, the nothingness and
voidness. And there
voidness. And there was
only the void, the nothingness and
voidness. And there was not.
voidness. And there was not. So
only the void, the nothingness and
voidness. And there was not. So the
that
that which
that which was
that which was before
that which was before the
that which was before the allness
that which was before the allness of
that which was before the allness of the
universes
was
was the
was the potent
was the potent the
was the potent the infinite
was the potent the infinite potentiality
which
which in
was the potent the infinite potentiality
which in itself
which in itself was
was the potent the infinite potentiality
which in itself was void.
which in itself was void. Void
was the potent the infinite potentiality
which in itself was void. Void of
which in itself was void. Void of form.
Void
Void of
Void of form.
Out
Out of
Void of form.
Out of the
Out of the void
Void of form.
Out of the void arose
creation.
creation. And
creation. And we've
creation. And we've already
creation. And we've already outlined
creation. And we've already outlined how
evolution
evolution is
creation. And we've already outlined how
evolution is merely
evolution is merely the
creation. And we've already outlined how
evolution is merely the way
evolution is merely the way in
creation. And we've already outlined how
evolution is merely the way in which
creation
creation brings
creation brings itself
creation brings itself into
manifestation.
I
I saw
I saw a
I saw a really
I saw a really interesting
I saw a really interesting program
I saw a really interesting program on
I saw a really interesting program on TV
the
the other
I saw a really interesting program on TV
the other night
the other night about
I saw a really interesting program on TV
the other night about about
the other night about about army
I saw a really interesting program on TV
the other night about about army ants.
Army,
Army, you
Army, you know,
Army, you know, you
Army, you know, you learn
Army, you know, you learn all
Army, you know, you learn all about
Army, you know, you learn all about the
ego
ego and
Army, you know, you learn all about the
ego and human
ego and human nature
Army, you know, you learn all about the
ego and human nature and
ego and human nature and a
Army, you know, you learn all about the
ego and human nature and a lot
ego and human nature and a lot of
spiritual
spiritual information
spiritual information from
spiritual information from watching
animal
animal programs
spiritual information from watching
animal programs because
animal programs because animal
spiritual information from watching
animal programs because animal programs
reveal
reveal so
reveal so much
reveal so much and
reveal so much and suddenly
reveal so much and suddenly as
reveal so much and suddenly as you're
watching
watching an
reveal so much and suddenly as you're
watching an animal
watching an animal program,
reveal so much and suddenly as you're
watching an animal program, you
watching an animal program, you know,
you
you get
you get a
you get a profound
you get a profound truth
you get a profound truth about
you get a profound truth about the
reality
reality of
you get a profound truth about the
reality of life
reality of life itself.
But
But here
But here are
But here are these
But here are these army
But here are these army ants
But here are these army ants and
But here are these army ants and they're
very
very ferocious.
They're
They're fearsome.
They're fearsome. It
They're fearsome. It was
They're fearsome. It was the
They're fearsome. It was the 10
They're fearsome. It was the 10 most
dangerous
dangerous animals
They're fearsome. It was the 10 most
dangerous animals on
dangerous animals on the
They're fearsome. It was the 10 most
dangerous animals on the planet.
dangerous animals on the planet. Number
one
one was
one was the
one was the army
one was the army ant.
one was the army ant. More
one was the army ant. More ferocious
than
than a
one was the army ant. More ferocious
than a water
than a water buffalo.
one was the army ant. More ferocious
than a water buffalo. More
than a water buffalo. More ferocious
than
than a
than a killer
than a killer dog.
than a killer dog. More
than a killer dog. More ferocious.
than a killer dog. More ferocious. The
most
most ferocious
than a killer dog. More ferocious. The
most ferocious thing
most ferocious thing on
than a killer dog. More ferocious. The
most ferocious thing on the
most ferocious thing on the planet
than a killer dog. More ferocious. The
most ferocious thing on the planet is
most ferocious thing on the planet is an
army
army ant.
army ant. They
army ant. They are
army ant. They are formidable.
army ant. They are formidable. The
army ant. They are formidable. The only
reason
reason we
army ant. They are formidable. The only
reason we aren't
reason we aren't all
army ant. They are formidable. The only
reason we aren't all destroyed
reason we aren't all destroyed by
army ant. They are formidable. The only
reason we aren't all destroyed by army
ants
ants is
ants is they're
ants is they're very
ants is they're very much
ants is they're very much smaller
ants is they're very much smaller than
we
we are.
ants is they're very much smaller than
we are. [laughter]
If
If they
If they were
If they were the
If they were the same
If they were the same size,
If they were the same size, there
wouldn't
wouldn't be
If they were the same size, there
wouldn't be any
wouldn't be any human
If they were the same size, there
wouldn't be any human beings
wouldn't be any human beings left
because
because they
because they eat
because they eat everything
because they eat everything in
because they eat everything in their
because they eat everything in their in
their
their pathway.
because they eat everything in their in
their pathway. And
their pathway. And they're
because they eat everything in their in
their pathway. And they're very
their pathway. And they're very they're
they're
they're built
they're built as
they're built as killers.
they're built as killers. They've
they're built as killers. They've got
these
these big
they're built as killers. They've got
these big giant
these big giant things
they're built as killers. They've got
these big giant things that
these big giant things that just
they're built as killers. They've got
these big giant things that just squish
you
you to
you to death
you to death and
you to death and pierce
you to death and pierce you
you to death and pierce you to
you to death and pierce you to death.
And
And then
you to death and pierce you to death.
And then they
And then they got
you to death and pierce you to death.
And then they got killer
And then they got killer tails
you to death and pierce you to death.
And then they got killer tails on
And then they got killer tails on them
and
and they're
and they're very,
and they're very, very
and they're very, very powerful
and they're very, very powerful for
their
their size.
and they're very, very powerful for
their size. And
their size. And they
and they're very, very powerful for
their size. And they got
their size. And they got these
and they're very, very powerful for
their size. And they got these giant
jaws.
jaws. So
jaws. So if
jaws. So if these
jaws. So if these don't
jaws. So if these don't get
jaws. So if these don't get you,
jaws. So if these don't get you, these
will.
will. And
jaws. So if these don't get you, these
will. And they'll
will. And they'll turn
jaws. So if these don't get you, these
will. And they'll turn around
will. And they'll turn around and
jaws. So if these don't get you, these
will. And they'll turn around and sting
you
you and
you and knock
you and knock you
you and knock you out
you and knock you out that
you and knock you out that way.
you and knock you out that way. So
you and knock you out that way. So these
army
army ants
you and knock you out that way. So these
army ants are
army ants are really
you and knock you out that way. So these
army ants are really quite
army ants are really quite impressive.
And
And they
And they they
And they they arise
And they they arise by
And they they arise by the
And they they arise by the billions.
They
They they
And they they arise by the billions.
They they eat
They they eat everything
And they they arise by the billions.
They they eat everything in
They they eat everything in its
And they they arise by the billions.
They they eat everything in its path.
They
They eat
They eat all
They eat all living
They eat all living things
They eat all living things within
They eat all living things within their
path.
path. like
They eat all living things within their
path. like [laughter]
and
and one
and one interesting
and one interesting thing
and one interesting thing there's
and one interesting thing there's a
certain
certain kind
and one interesting thing there's a
certain kind of
certain kind of an
and one interesting thing there's a
certain kind of an army
certain kind of an army ant
and one interesting thing there's a
certain kind of an army ant a
certain kind of an army ant a soldier
ant
ant whose
ant whose abdomen
first
first of
ant whose abdomen
first of all
first of all these
ant whose abdomen
first of all these killer
first of all these killer ants
ant whose abdomen
first of all these killer ants are
first of all these killer ants are very
adept
adept at
adept at calculating
adept at calculating the
adept at calculating the size
adept at calculating the size of
adept at calculating the size of the
other
other army
adept at calculating the size of the
other army they
other army they can
adept at calculating the size of the
other army they can send
other army they can send back
adept at calculating the size of the
other army they can send back scouts
other army they can send back scouts and
send
send back
send back signals
send back signals uh-uh
send back signals uh-uh if
send back signals uh-uh if they
send back signals uh-uh if they withdraw
or
or if
send back signals uh-uh if they withdraw
or if they
or if they it's
send back signals uh-uh if they withdraw
or if they it's if
or if they it's if they're
send back signals uh-uh if they withdraw
or if they it's if they're more
or if they it's if they're more powerful
the
the the
the the scouts
the the scouts will
the the scouts will signal
the the scouts will signal Uhhuh.
the the scouts will signal Uhhuh. in
which
which case
the the scouts will signal Uhhuh. in
which case they
which case they attack
the the scouts will signal Uhhuh. in
which case they attack and
which case they attack and destroy
the the scouts will signal Uhhuh. in
which case they attack and destroy the
other
other colony.
Uh
Uh unlike
other colony.
Uh unlike uh
Uh unlike uh people
other colony.
Uh unlike uh people who
Uh unlike uh people who often
other colony.
Uh unlike uh people who often don't
Uh unlike uh people who often don't know
they've
they've lost
they've lost the
they've lost the war
they've lost the war and
they've lost the war and make
they've lost the war and make you
they've lost the war and make you drop
another
another Adam
they've lost the war and make you drop
another Adam a
another Adam a bomb
they've lost the war and make you drop
another Adam a bomb on
another Adam a bomb on them
they've lost the war and make you drop
another Adam a bomb on them before
another Adam a bomb on them before they
get
get the
get the point.
get the point. [laughter]
So
So anyway,
get the point. [laughter]
So anyway, this
So anyway, this army
get the point. [laughter]
So anyway, this army ant
So anyway, this army ant particular,
he's
he's a
he's a specialist
he's a specialist uh
he's a specialist uh specialist
specialist
specialist third
he's a specialist uh specialist
specialist third class,
specialist third class, right?
he's a specialist uh specialist
specialist third class, right? So
specialist third class, right? So his
abdomen
abdomen can
abdomen can grow
abdomen can grow like
abdomen can grow like this
abdomen can grow like this and
abdomen can grow like this and at
abdomen can grow like this and at the
proper
proper moment
abdomen can grow like this and at the
proper moment at
proper moment at the
abdomen can grow like this and at the
proper moment at the right
proper moment at the right time
abdomen can grow like this and at the
proper moment at the right time he
explodes.
explodes. This
explodes. This army
explodes. This army explodes
explodes. This army explodes and
explodes. This army explodes and when
explodes. This army explodes and when he
does
does he
explodes. This army explodes and when he
does he spits
does he spits this
explodes. This army explodes and when he
does he spits this inner
does he spits this inner uh
explodes. This army explodes and when he
does he spits this inner uh toxic
poisonous
poisonous chemical
poisonous chemical that
poisonous chemical that he's
poisonous chemical that he's held
poisonous chemical that he's held within
his
his abdomen.
poisonous chemical that he's held within
his abdomen. So
his abdomen. So he
poisonous chemical that he's held within
his abdomen. So he he
his abdomen. So he he commits
poisonous chemical that he's held within
his abdomen. So he he commits suicide
in
in order
in order to
in order to kill
in order to kill the
in order to kill the enemy
and
and in
in order to kill the enemy
and in so
and in so doing
in order to kill the enemy
and in so doing brings
and in so doing brings about
in order to kill the enemy
and in so doing brings about I'm
and in so doing brings about I'm sure
in order to kill the enemy
and in so doing brings about I'm sure in
his
his own
his own little
his own little mind
his own little mind salvation,
his own little mind salvation, right?
[laughter]
He
He gets
He gets nine
He gets nine lady
He gets nine lady hands
He gets nine lady hands on
He gets nine lady hands on the
He gets nine lady hands on the other
side
[laughter]
and
and you
[laughter]
and you say
and you say to
[laughter]
and you say to yourself,
and you say to yourself, you
[laughter]
and you say to yourself, you know,
and you say to yourself, you know, how
does
does this
does this differ
does this differ from
does this differ from human
consciousness
consciousness at
does this differ from human
consciousness at all?
It
It doesn't
It doesn't differ
It doesn't differ at
It doesn't differ at all.
It doesn't differ at all. It's
It doesn't differ at all. It's identical
identical
identical thinking,
It doesn't differ at all. It's identical
identical thinking, contextualization,
techniques
techniques even.
techniques even. You
techniques even. You blow
techniques even. You blow yourself
techniques even. You blow yourself up
techniques even. You blow yourself up to
kill
kill the
techniques even. You blow yourself up to
kill the enemy
kill the enemy for
techniques even. You blow yourself up to
kill the enemy for the
kill the enemy for the sake
techniques even. You blow yourself up to
kill the enemy for the sake of
kill the enemy for the sake of uh
winning
winning your
winning your side
winning your side winning.
winning your side winning. I
winning your side winning. I mean,
winning your side winning. I mean, this
is
is incredible,
winning your side winning. I mean, this
is incredible, isn't
is incredible, isn't it?
winning your side winning. I mean, this
is incredible, isn't it? This
is incredible, isn't it? This little
winning your side winning. I mean, this
is incredible, isn't it? This little ant
knows
knows all
knows all this
knows all this already,
knows all this already, and
knows all this already, and we're
knows all this already, and we're just
learning
learning it.
How
How can
How can the
How can the ant
How can the ant know
How can the ant know more
How can the ant know more than
How can the ant know more than we
How can the ant know more than we do?
How can the ant know more than we do? I
mean,
mean, they
How can the ant know more than we do? I
mean, they know
mean, they know when
How can the ant know more than we do? I
mean, they know when they're
mean, they know when they're winning,
and
and when
and when they're
and when they're not
and when they're not winning,
and when they're not winning, and
and when they're not winning, and when
they're
they're not
and when they're not winning, and when
they're not winning,
they're not winning, they
and when they're not winning, and when
they're not winning, they take
they're not winning, they take off.
and when they're not winning, and when
they're not winning, they take off. You
know,
know, we
know, we hang
know, we hang in
know, we hang in until
know, we hang in until they've
slaughtered
slaughtered every
know, we hang in until they've
slaughtered every last
slaughtered every last German
know, we hang in until they've
slaughtered every last German or
China
China or
China or whatever.
China or whatever. You
China or whatever. You know,
after
after the
China or whatever. You know,
after the war
after the war is
China or whatever. You know,
after the war is lost,
after the war is lost, they
China or whatever. You know,
after the war is lost, they throw
after the war is lost, they throw in
more
more and
more and more
more and more legions
more and more legions of
more and more legions of soldiers
more and more legions of soldiers who
are
are then
more and more legions of soldiers who
are then slaughtered
are then slaughtered in
more and more legions of soldiers who
are then slaughtered in the
are then slaughtered in the meat.
more and more legions of soldiers who
are then slaughtered in the meat. And
are then slaughtered in the meat. And uh
how
how come
how come the
how come the ant
how come the ant knows
how come the ant knows more
how come the ant knows more than
how come the ant knows more than that?
So
I
I just
I just thought
I just thought it
I just thought it was
I just thought it was interesting
because
because the
I just thought it was interesting
because the evolution
because the evolution of
I just thought it was interesting
because the evolution of consciousness
you
you see
you see that
you see that the
you see that the the
you see that the the visible
you see that the the visible world
you see that the the visible world of
life
life animal
you see that the the visible world of
life animal life
life animal life is
you see that the the visible world of
life animal life is nothing
life animal life is nothing but
you see that the the visible world of
life animal life is nothing but the
outpitching
outpitching of
outpitching of that
outpitching of that which
outpitching of that which has
outpitching of that which has already
occurred
occurred on
outpitching of that which has already
occurred on on
occurred on on the
outpitching of that which has already
occurred on on the level
occurred on on the level of
consciousness.
consciousness. So
consciousness. So evolution
consciousness. So evolution is
consciousness. So evolution is obviously
occurring
occurring on
consciousness. So evolution is obviously
occurring on the
occurring on the level
consciousness. So evolution is obviously
occurring on the level of
occurring on the level of consciousness.
So
So this
So this whole
So this whole paradigm
So this whole paradigm of
So this whole paradigm of army
So this whole paradigm of army and
scouts
scouts and
So this whole paradigm of army and
scouts and winning
scouts and winning and
So this whole paradigm of army and
scouts and winning and blowing
scouts and winning and blowing yourself
up
up against
up against the
up against the army
up against the army already
up against the army already exists
up against the army already exists on
the
the you
up against the army already exists on
the you might
the you might say
up against the army already exists on
the you might say psychic
the you might say psychic plane
up against the army already exists on
the you might say psychic plane right
let's
let's see
let's see if
let's see if that's
let's see if that's so
let's see if that's so okay
let's see if that's so okay so
let's see if that's so okay so this
pattern
pattern already
let's see if that's so okay so this
pattern already exists
pattern already exists on
let's see if that's so okay so this
pattern already exists on the
pattern already exists on the psychic
plane
plane okay
plane okay this
plane okay this pattern
plane okay this pattern which
plane okay this pattern which I've
plane okay this pattern which I've just
described
described is
plane okay this pattern which I've just
described is coming
described is coming from
plane okay this pattern which I've just
described is coming from the
described is coming from the lower
astral
astral resist
astral resist it's
astral resist it's an
astral resist it's an or
astral resist it's an or lower
astral resist it's an or lower astral
pattern
pattern resist
astral resist it's an or lower astral
pattern resist which
pattern resist which then
astral resist it's an or lower astral
pattern resist which then manifests
through
through anything
through anything that
through anything that calibrates
through anything that calibrates under
200 resistance.
200 resistance. Okay.
through anything that calibrates under
200 resistance. Okay. So,
200 resistance. Okay. So, anything
through anything that calibrates under
200 resistance. Okay. So, anything that
calibrates
calibrates under
calibrates under 200
calibrates under 200 is
calibrates under 200 is game
is
is fair
calibrates under 200 is game
is fair game
is fair game for
calibrates under 200 is game
is fair game for the
is fair game for the lower
calibrates under 200 is game
is fair game for the lower asteroid
resist.
resist. Wow.
resist. Wow. No
resist. Wow. No wonder
resist. Wow. No wonder that
resist. Wow. No wonder that explains
resist. Wow. No wonder that explains the
phenomena
phenomena of the
resist. Wow. No wonder that explains the
phenomena of the world,
phenomena of the world, right?
resist. Wow. No wonder that explains the
phenomena of the world, right? Anything
that's
that's not
that's not integrous
that's not integrous and
that's not integrous and not
that's not integrous and not committed
to
to truth
that's not integrous and not committed
to truth is
to truth is fair
that's not integrous and not committed
to truth is fair game
to truth is fair game to
that's not integrous and not committed
to truth is fair game to be
to truth is fair game to be dominated
that's not integrous and not committed
to truth is fair game to be dominated by
the
the lower
the lower astral
the lower astral h.
Therefore,
Therefore, the
the lower astral h.
Therefore, the murderer
Therefore, the murderer easily
the lower astral h.
Therefore, the murderer easily gets
taken
taken over
taken over because
taken over because he
taken over because he just
taken over because he just crashed
taken over because he just crashed from
200 down
200 down to
taken over because he just crashed from
200 down to minus
200 down to minus something
taken over because he just crashed from
200 down to minus something or
200 down to minus something or other.
And
And instantly
And instantly he's
And instantly he's he's
And instantly he's he's now
And instantly he's he's now fair
And instantly he's he's now fair game
for
for an
And instantly he's he's now fair game
for an entity
for an entity to
And instantly he's he's now fair game
for an entity to take
for an entity to take over.
And instantly he's he's now fair game
for an entity to take over. Okay.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So then
All right. So then I
All right. So then I see
All right. So then I see what
All right. So then I see what the
All right. So then I see what the whole
pattern
pattern is.
All right. So then I see what the whole
pattern is. It
pattern is. It makes
All right. So then I see what the whole
pattern is. It makes sense.
pattern is. It makes sense. So
All right. So then I see what the whole
pattern is. It makes sense. So we
pattern is. It makes sense. So we learn
a
a lot
a lot about
a lot about spirituality
a lot about spirituality from
a lot about spirituality from watching
the
the animal
a lot about spirituality from watching
the animal channel.
the animal channel. [laughter]
Uh
yes.
yes. How
Uh
yes. How does
yes. How does the
Uh
yes. How does the how
yes. How does the how can
Uh
yes. How does the how can you
yes. How does the how can you raise
Uh
yes. How does the how can you raise a
child
child not
child not to
child not to develop
child not to develop an
child not to develop an ego?
child not to develop an ego? Well,
child not to develop an ego? Well, you
can't
[laughter]
you
you can
[laughter]
you can you
you can you can
[laughter]
you can you can give
you can you can give them
[laughter]
you can you can give them spiritual
standards
standards because
standards because by
standards because by spiritual
standards because by spiritual standards
unconsciously
unconsciously if
standards because by spiritual standards
unconsciously if not
unconsciously if not consciously
standards because by spiritual standards
unconsciously if not consciously the
child
child will
child will then
child will then begin
child will then begin evaluating
child will then begin evaluating its
child will then begin evaluating its own
behavior.
If
If you're
If you're a
If you're a good
If you're a good parent
If you're a good parent and
If you're a good parent and and
If you're a good parent and and loved,
you
you know,
If you're a good parent and and loved,
you know, so
you know, so that
If you're a good parent and and loved,
you know, so that you're
you know, so that you're incorporated
within
within their
within their psyche,
within their psyche, interjected,
within their psyche, interjected, it's
called
called in
within their psyche, interjected, it's
called in psychoanalysis,
called in psychoanalysis, you
within their psyche, interjected, it's
called in psychoanalysis, you interject
the
the parent.
If
If it's
the parent.
If it's a
If it's a good
the parent.
If it's a good parent,
If it's a good parent, that
the parent.
If it's a good parent, that becomes
If it's a good parent, that becomes the
ego
ego ideal.
ego ideal. In
ego ideal. In Freudian
ego ideal. In Freudian language,
ego ideal. In Freudian language, the
ego ideal. In Freudian language, the ego
ego
ego ideal
ego ideal. In Freudian language, the ego
ego ideal is
ego ideal is the
ego ideal. In Freudian language, the ego
ego ideal is the ultimate
ego ideal is the ultimate of
ego ideal. In Freudian language, the ego
ego ideal is the ultimate of what
ego ideal is the ultimate of what you
want
want to
want to become.
want to become. So
want to become. So if
want to become. So if your
want to become. So if your father
teaches
teaches you
want to become. So if your father
teaches you not
teaches you not to
want to become. So if your father
teaches you not to flinch
teaches you not to flinch in
want to become. So if your father
teaches you not to flinch in the
teaches you not to flinch in the face
want to become. So if your father
teaches you not to flinch in the face of
pain,
then
then you
pain,
then you develop
then you develop the
pain,
then you develop the capacity
then you develop the capacity to
pain,
then you develop the capacity to get
have
have amputations
have amputations without
have amputations without anesthesia
because
because this
have amputations without anesthesia
because this is
because this is an
have amputations without anesthesia
because this is an ideal
because this is an ideal that
have amputations without anesthesia
because this is an ideal that you
powerfully
powerfully energize.
powerfully energize. So
powerfully energize. So the
powerfully energize. So the parents
powerfully energize. So the parents are
setting
setting up
powerfully energize. So the parents are
setting up our
setting up our ideals
powerfully energize. So the parents are
setting up our ideals and
setting up our ideals and standards
powerfully energize. So the parents are
setting up our ideals and standards by
which
which the
which the child
which the child is
which the child is consciously
which the child is consciously as
which the child is consciously as they
grow
grow up.
which the child is consciously as they
grow up. We
grow up. We teach
which the child is consciously as they
grow up. We teach them
grow up. We teach them to
which the child is consciously as they
grow up. We teach them to be
grow up. We teach them to be kind
which the child is consciously as they
grow up. We teach them to be kind to
animals
animals to
animals to be
animals to be kind
animals to be kind to
animals to be kind to each
animals to be kind to each other
animals to be kind to each other to
forgive
forgive instead
animals to be kind to each other to
forgive instead of
forgive instead of retaliating
to
to try
to try and
to try and see
to try and see that
to try and see that the
to try and see that the other
to try and see that the other person
can't
can't help
to try and see that the other person
can't help being
can't help being the
to try and see that the other person
can't help being the way
can't help being the way they
to try and see that the other person
can't help being the way they are
because
because you
because you can't
because you can't forgive
because you can't forgive them
because you can't forgive them if
because you can't forgive them if you
see
see them
because you can't forgive them if you
see them as
see them as bad
because you can't forgive them if you
see them as bad but
see them as bad but you
because you can't forgive them if you
see them as bad but you can
see them as bad but you can feel
because you can't forgive them if you
see them as bad but you can feel sorry
for
for them
for them as
for them as not
for them as not being
for them as not being able
for them as not being able to
for them as not being able to help
themsel
themsel and
for them as not being able to help
themsel and pray
themsel and pray for
for them as not being able to help
themsel and pray for them.
themsel and pray for them. So
for them as not being able to help
themsel and pray for them. So we
themsel and pray for them. So we set
for them as not being able to help
themsel and pray for them. So we set up
these
these spiritual
these spiritual ideals
these spiritual ideals which
these spiritual ideals which um
these spiritual ideals which um become
incorporated
incorporated within
these spiritual ideals which um become
incorporated within one's
incorporated within one's sense
these spiritual ideals which um become
incorporated within one's sense of
ethics
ethics and
ethics and uh
uh
uh so
ethics and uh
uh so I
uh so I think
ethics and uh
uh so I think we
uh so I think we do
ethics and uh
uh so I think we do a
uh so I think we do a lot
ethics and uh
uh so I think we do a lot for
uh so I think we do a lot for our
children
children by
bringing
bringing our
children by
bringing our own
bringing our own spiritual
children by
bringing our own spiritual awareness
bringing our own spiritual awareness as
something
something that
something that we
something that we strive
something that we strive for.
something that we strive for. You
something that we strive for. You also
want
want to
something that we strive for. You also
want to set
want to set up
something that we strive for. You also
want to set up a
want to set up a mechanism
something that we strive for. You also
want to set up a mechanism whereby
want to set up a mechanism whereby the
child
child doesn't
child doesn't feel
child doesn't feel guilt
child doesn't feel guilt if
child doesn't feel guilt if they
child doesn't feel guilt if they fail
child doesn't feel guilt if they fail to
reach
reach that
child doesn't feel guilt if they fail to
reach that level.
reach that level. This
child doesn't feel guilt if they fail to
reach that level. This is
reach that level. This is what
child doesn't feel guilt if they fail to
reach that level. This is what we
reach that level. This is what we strive
for.
for. And
for. And we
for. And we sometimes
for. And we sometimes fail
for. And we sometimes fail because
the
the nature
for. And we sometimes fail because
the nature of
the nature of the
for. And we sometimes fail because
the nature of the mind
the nature of the mind and
for. And we sometimes fail because
the nature of the mind and the
the nature of the mind and the human
brain
brain is
brain is that
brain is that we're
brain is that we're not
brain is that we're not going
brain is that we're not going to
brain is that we're not going to win
every
every time.
But
But that's
But that's all
But that's all right
But that's all right because
But that's all right because it
But that's all right because it isn't
whether
whether you
But that's all right because it isn't
whether you win
whether you win or
But that's all right because it isn't
whether you win or lose.
whether you win or lose. It's
But that's all right because it isn't
whether you win or lose. It's the
direction
direction that
direction that you
direction that you go.
direction that you go. So
direction that you go. So if
direction that you go. So if the
direction that you go. So if the child
just
just gets
direction that you go. So if the child
just gets the
just gets the the
direction that you go. So if the child
just gets the the direction
just gets the the direction is
direction that you go. So if the child
just gets the the direction is of
just gets the the direction is of caring
for
for yourself
for yourself and
for yourself and caring
for yourself and caring for
for yourself and caring for others
for yourself and caring for others and
trying
trying to
for yourself and caring for others and
trying to perfect
trying to perfect yourself
for yourself and caring for others and
trying to perfect yourself as
trying to perfect yourself as best
for yourself and caring for others and
trying to perfect yourself as best you
can,
can, that's
can, that's going
can, that's going to
can, that's going to be
can, that's going to be an
can, that's going to be an ideal
can, that's going to be an ideal that's
going
going to
can, that's going to be an ideal that's
going to stay
going to stay with
can, that's going to be an ideal that's
going to stay with them
going to stay with them stay
can, that's going to be an ideal that's
going to stay with them stay with
going to stay with them stay with them
all
all these
all these many
all these many years
all these many years since.
all these many years since. Mhm.
So
the
the beauty
the beauty of
the beauty of spirituality,
the beauty of spirituality, the
the beauty of spirituality, the beauty
of
of religion
the beauty of spirituality, the beauty
of religion at
of religion at its
the beauty of spirituality, the beauty
of religion at its highest
of religion at its highest expression
can
can stay
can stay with
can stay with you
can stay with you for
can stay with you for a
can stay with you for a lifetime.
Uh
Uh just
can stay with you for a lifetime.
Uh just to
Uh just to experience
can stay with you for a lifetime.
Uh just to experience a
Uh just to experience a great
can stay with you for a lifetime.
Uh just to experience a great cathedral
and
and the
and the with
and the with the
and the with the full
and the with the full choir
and the with the full choir and
and the with the full choir and a
and the with the full choir and a full
orchestra
orchestra and
and the with the full choir and a full
orchestra and the
orchestra and the sun
and the with the full choir and a full
orchestra and the sun coming
orchestra and the sun coming through
and the with the full choir and a full
orchestra and the sun coming through the
windows
windows and
windows and the
windows and the beautiful
windows and the beautiful incense,
windows and the beautiful incense, the
magnificence
magnificence of
windows and the beautiful incense, the
magnificence of the
magnificence of the architecture,
windows and the beautiful incense, the
magnificence of the architecture, the
carving,
carving, the
carving, the obvious
carving, the obvious um
carving, the obvious um reverence
carving, the obvious um reverence of
carving, the obvious um reverence of the
people
people is
carving, the obvious um reverence of the
people is a
people is a profound
carving, the obvious um reverence of the
people is a profound impact
people is a profound impact in
carving, the obvious um reverence of the
people is a profound impact in your
psyche.
psyche. You
psyche. You know
psyche. You know that
psyche. You know that forever
psyche. You know that forever will
psyche. You know that forever will be
have
have an
psyche. You know that forever will be
have an impact
have an impact and
psyche. You know that forever will be
have an impact and every
have an impact and every anything
psyche. You know that forever will be
have an impact and every anything that
falls
falls less
falls less than
falls less than that
falls less than that subtly
falls less than that subtly uh
falls less than that subtly uh will
falls less than that subtly uh will not
be
be accepted
falls less than that subtly uh will not
be accepted within
be accepted within the
falls less than that subtly uh will not
be accepted within the mind.
be accepted within the mind. You
falls less than that subtly uh will not
be accepted within the mind. You may
accept
accept it
accept it for
accept it for 20
accept it for 20 or
accept it for 20 or 30
accept it for 20 or 30 years
accept it for 20 or 30 years but
accept it for 20 or 30 years but after
accept it for 20 or 30 years but after a
while
while you
accept it for 20 or 30 years but after a
while you give
while you give it
accept it for 20 or 30 years but after a
while you give it up.
What's
What's uh
What's uh I
What's uh I don't
What's uh I don't never
What's uh I don't never had
What's uh I don't never had this
What's uh I don't never had this one.
What's
What's the
What's uh I don't never had this one.
What's the sighting
What's the sighting of
What's uh I don't never had this one.
What's the sighting of fo
What's the sighting of fo all
What's uh I don't never had this one.
What's the sighting of fo all about
and
and being
and being abducted
and being abducted by
and being abducted by aliens?
and being abducted by aliens? I
and being abducted by aliens? I don't
know
know if
and being abducted by aliens? I don't
know if we
know if we can
and being abducted by aliens? I don't
know if we can allow
know if we can allow to
and being abducted by aliens? I don't
know if we can allow to act
know if we can allow to act this.
and being abducted by aliens? I don't
know if we can allow to act this. We
might
might blow
might blow some
might blow some of the
might blow some of the people
might blow some of the people out
might blow some of the people out here.
Can [laughter]
Can [laughter] we
might blow some of the people out here.
Can [laughter] we ask
Can [laughter] we ask that
might blow some of the people out here.
Can [laughter] we ask that question?
>> Okay,
>> Okay, we
>> Okay, we have
>> Okay, we have permission
>> Okay, we have permission to
>> Okay, we have permission to ask
>> Okay, we have permission to ask this
>> Okay, we have permission to ask this in
front
front of
>> Okay, we have permission to ask this in
front of this
front of this audience.
>> Oh,
>> this
>> this is
>> Oh,
>> this is an
>> this is an integrous
>> Oh,
>> this is an integrous audience,
>> mature
>> mature and
>> mature and can
>> mature and can handle
>> mature and can handle it.
UFOs
UFOs are
>> mature and can handle it.
UFOs are primarily
UFOs are primarily perceptual
misinterpretations.
misinterpretations. resist.
The
The a
misinterpretations. resist.
The a UFO
The a UFO is
misinterpretations. resist.
The a UFO is commonly
The a UFO is commonly defined
misinterpretations. resist.
The a UFO is commonly defined is
The a UFO is commonly defined is an
existent
existent reality
existent reality resist.
existent reality resist. No,
existent reality resist. No, not
existent reality resist. No, not an
existent
existent reality.
existent reality resist. No, not an
existent reality. I
existent reality. I saw
existent reality resist. No, not an
existent reality. I saw UFOs
existent reality. I saw UFOs one
existent reality resist. No, not an
existent reality. I saw UFOs one time
then
then I
then I test
then I test it
then I test it out
then I test it out with
then I test it out with a
then I test it out with a kinesiologist
says
says they
then I test it out with a kinesiologist
says they weren't.
Darn
Darn it.
I'll
I'll tell
Darn it.
I'll tell you
I'll tell you how
Darn it.
I'll tell you how it
I'll tell you how it came
Darn it.
I'll tell you how it came about.
>> Okay?
>> Because
>> Because it
>> Okay?
>> Because it explains
>> Because it explains how
>> Okay?
>> Because it explains how anybody
>> Because it explains how anybody can
>> Okay?
>> Because it explains how anybody can come
to
to believe
to believe this.
to believe this. friends
to believe this. friends were
to believe this. friends were driving
to believe this. friends were driving in
another
another car.
to believe this. friends were driving in
another car. We
another car. We were
to believe this. friends were driving in
another car. We were going
another car. We were going up
to believe this. friends were driving in
another car. We were going up to
another car. We were going up to First
Mesa
Mesa up
Mesa up to
Mesa up to uh
Mesa up to uh some
Mesa up to uh some Indian
Mesa up to uh some Indian reservation.
What?
What? We
Mesa up to uh some Indian reservation.
What? We were
What? We were going
Mesa up to uh some Indian reservation.
What? We were going up
What? We were going up to
Mesa up to uh some Indian reservation.
What? We were going up to the
What? We were going up to the snake
dancer
dancer or
dancer or something.
dancer or something. Anyway,
dancer or something. Anyway, we're
dancer or something. Anyway, we're in
separate
separate cars.
dancer or something. Anyway, we're in
separate cars. And
separate cars. And as
dancer or something. Anyway, we're in
separate cars. And as we
separate cars. And as we up
dancer or something. Anyway, we're in
separate cars. And as we up to
separate cars. And as we up to Flagstaff
or
or uh
or uh or
or uh or no,
or uh or no, we're
or uh or no, we're going
or uh or no, we're going from
or uh or no, we're going from Flagstaff
on
on up
or uh or no, we're going from Flagstaff
on up towards
on up towards uh
or uh or no, we're going from Flagstaff
on up towards uh First
on up towards uh First Mesa
or uh or no, we're going from Flagstaff
on up towards uh First Mesa up
on up towards uh First Mesa up there.
or uh or no, we're going from Flagstaff
on up towards uh First Mesa up there. I
forget
forget the
forget the name
forget the name of
forget the name of the
forget the name of the Indian
forget the name of the Indian town.
>> Um
>> Um but
forget the name of the Indian town.
>> Um but anyway,
>> Um but anyway, I
forget the name of the Indian town.
>> Um but anyway, I saw
>> Um but anyway, I saw two
forget the name of the Indian town.
>> Um but anyway, I saw two silvery
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, right.
>> Yeah, right. Yeah,
>> Yeah, right. Yeah, two
>> Yeah, right. Yeah, two silvery
uh
uh space
>> Yeah, right. Yeah, two silvery
uh space vehicles
uh space vehicles or
>> Yeah, right. Yeah, two silvery
uh space vehicles or planes
uh space vehicles or planes or
>> Yeah, right. Yeah, two silvery
uh space vehicles or planes or balloons
or
or something
or something and
or something and they
or something and they were
or something and they were way
or something and they were way up
or something and they were way up in
or something and they were way up in the
sky
sky and
or something and they were way up in the
sky and they're
sky and they're quite
or something and they were way up in the
sky and they're quite a
sky and they're quite a bit
or something and they were way up in the
sky and they're quite a bit distant.
Probably
Probably 30
Probably 30 miles
Probably 30 miles ahead
Probably 30 miles ahead of
Probably 30 miles ahead of us.
All
All of
Probably 30 miles ahead of us.
All of a
All of a sudden,
Probably 30 miles ahead of us.
All of a sudden, they
All of a sudden, they stopped.
Probably 30 miles ahead of us.
All of a sudden, they stopped. All
All of a sudden, they stopped. All of a
sudden,
sudden, they
sudden, they moved
sudden, they moved sideways
sudden, they moved sideways like
sudden, they moved sideways like that.
They
They moved
sudden, they moved sideways like that.
They moved at
They moved at right
sudden, they moved sideways like that.
They moved at right angles
They moved at right angles quickly.
I
I thought,
I thought, "Good
I thought, "Good God,
I thought, "Good God, what
I thought, "Good God, what is
I thought, "Good God, what is that?"
I thought, "Good God, what is that?" So,
when
when we
I thought, "Good God, what is that?" So,
when we arrived
when we arrived at
I thought, "Good God, what is that?" So,
when we arrived at our
when we arrived at our destination,
I thought, "Good God, what is that?" So,
when we arrived at our destination, we
got
got out of
got out of the
got out of the cars
got out of the cars and
got out of the cars and I
got out of the cars and I said,
got out of the cars and I said, Did
got out of the cars and I said, Did you
see
see that?
got out of the cars and I said, Did you
see that? He
see that? He says,
got out of the cars and I said, Did you
see that? He says, "Yeah,
see that? He says, "Yeah, those
got out of the cars and I said, Did you
see that? He says, "Yeah, those big
silvery
silvery spheres
silvery spheres that
silvery spheres that suddenly
silvery spheres that suddenly moved
silvery spheres that suddenly moved at
right
right angles."
silvery spheres that suddenly moved at
right angles." Wow.
right angles." Wow. We
silvery spheres that suddenly moved at
right angles." Wow. We thought
right angles." Wow. We thought we've
seen
seen UFOs.
Only
Only a
seen UFOs.
Only a UFO
Only a UFO can
seen UFOs.
Only a UFO can go
Only a UFO can go from
seen UFOs.
Only a UFO can go from a
Only a UFO can go from a standstill,
make
make a
make a right
make a right angle,
make a right angle, and
make a right angle, and go
make a right angle, and go somewhere.
[laughter]
Let's
Let's just
[laughter]
Let's just test
Let's just test my
[laughter]
Let's just test my personal
Let's just test my personal experience.
They
They look
They look like
They look like UFOs.
They look like UFOs. Resist.
They look like UFOs. Resist. I
They look like UFOs. Resist. I semi
believed
believed that
They look like UFOs. Resist. I semi
believed that they
believed that they were
They look like UFOs. Resist. I semi
believed that they were UFOs
believed that they were UFOs at
They look like UFOs. Resist. I semi
believed that they were UFOs at the
time.
time. Resist.
They
They were
time. Resist.
They were not
They were not UFOs.
time. Resist.
They were not UFOs. Resist.
So
So even
So even though
So even though you
So even though you see
So even though you see perception
So even though you see perception as
So even though you see perception as I
described
described the
So even though you see perception as I
described the perception,
described the perception, you
So even though you see perception as I
described the perception, you would
described the perception, you would say
well
well I
well I don't
well I don't believe
well I don't believe in
well I don't believe in UFOs
well I don't believe in UFOs but
well I don't believe in UFOs but by
well I don't believe in UFOs but by God
what
what were
well I don't believe in UFOs but by God
what were those
what were those things?
well I don't believe in UFOs but by God
what were those things? How
what were those things? How could
well I don't believe in UFOs but by God
what were those things? How could they
go
go at
go at a
go at a right
go at a right angle
go at a right angle like
go at a right angle like that?
go at a right angle like that? Suddenly
out
out of
go at a right angle like that? Suddenly
out of nowhere
out of nowhere pair
go at a right angle like that? Suddenly
out of nowhere pair of
out of nowhere pair of them
go at a right angle like that? Suddenly
out of nowhere pair of them you
out of nowhere pair of them you know
suddenly
suddenly go
suddenly go off
suddenly go off like
suddenly go off like that.
suddenly go off like that. So
suddenly go off like that. So you
suddenly go off like that. So you can
see
see how
suddenly go off like that. So you can
see how people
see how people can
suddenly go off like that. So you can
see how people can easily
see how people can easily arrive
suddenly go off like that. So you can
see how people can easily arrive at
see how people can easily arrive at the
belief
belief that
belief that there
belief that there are
belief that there are such
belief that there are such things.
Uh
Uh because
belief that there are such things.
Uh because perception
Uh because perception is.
belief that there are such things.
Uh because perception is. What
Uh because perception is. What about
being
being abducted
being abducted by
being abducted by aliens?
being abducted by aliens? Oh,
being abducted by aliens? Oh, this
being abducted by aliens? Oh, this is
scary.
scary. I
being abducted by aliens? Oh, this is
scary. I don't
scary. I don't know
being abducted by aliens? Oh, this is
scary. I don't know if
scary. I don't know if I
being abducted by aliens? Oh, this is
scary. I don't know if I want
scary. I don't know if I want to
being abducted by aliens? Oh, this is
scary. I don't know if I want to know
this
this one.
this one. [laughter]
I'm
I'm susceptible
this one. [laughter]
I'm susceptible to
I'm susceptible to getting
this one. [laughter]
I'm susceptible to getting abducted
I'm susceptible to getting abducted by
aliens.
aliens. Resist.
[laughter]
It's
It's possible.
It's possible. I
It's possible. I know
It's possible. I know the
It's possible. I know the answer
It's possible. I know the answer to
It's possible. I know the answer to this
one.
one. It's
It's possible. I know the answer to this
one. It's possible
one. It's possible to
It's possible. I know the answer to this
one. It's possible to be
one. It's possible to be physically
abducted
abducted by
abducted by aliens.
abducted by aliens. Resist.
abducted by aliens. Resist. It's
possible
possible for
abducted by aliens. Resist. It's
possible for your
possible for your astral
abducted by aliens. Resist. It's
possible for your astral body
possible for your astral body to
abducted by aliens. Resist. It's
possible for your astral body to be
abducted.
abducted. resist.
abducted. resist. There's
abducted. resist. There's where
abducted. resist. There's where the
abducted. resist. There's where the big
event
event is
abducted. resist. There's where the big
event is happening.
event is happening. See,
abducted. resist. There's where the big
event is happening. See, the
event is happening. See, the event
abducted. resist. There's where the big
event is happening. See, the event is
happening.
happening. People
happening. People will
happening. People will see
happening. People will see apocalyptic
uh
uh endings
happening. People will see apocalyptic
uh endings of
uh endings of the
happening. People will see apocalyptic
uh endings of the world
uh endings of the world and
happening. People will see apocalyptic
uh endings of the world and all.
uh endings of the world and all. You're
talking
talking about
talking about a
talking about a different
talking about a different dimension.
It's
It's so
talking about a different dimension.
It's so it's
It's so it's true
talking about a different dimension.
It's so it's true in
It's so it's true in that
talking about a different dimension.
It's so it's true in that dimension.
There
There was
There was a
There was a spiritual
There was a spiritual teacher
There was a spiritual teacher well
There was a spiritual teacher well known
here
here in
There was a spiritual teacher well known
here in Sedona
here in Sedona now
There was a spiritual teacher well known
here in Sedona now deceased
who
who described
who described that
who described that he
who described that he experienced
who described that he experienced this
vision
and
and all
and all he
and all he all
and all he all his
and all he all his followers
and all he all his followers prepared
for
for the
and all he all his followers prepared
for the eventualities
for the eventualities you
and all he all his followers prepared
for the eventualities you know
underground
underground houses
underground houses and
underground houses and the
underground houses and the final
underground houses and the final days
and
and survivalism
underground houses and the final days
and survivalism and
and survivalism and all.
uh
the
the conviction
uh
the conviction with
the conviction with which
uh
the conviction with which he
the conviction with which he told
uh
the conviction with which he told it
the conviction with which he told it was
convincing
convincing to
convincing to the
convincing to the listener
but
but what
convincing to the listener
but what you
but what you don't
convincing to the listener
but what you don't get
but what you don't get is
convincing to the listener
but what you don't get is he
but what you don't get is he he's
describing
describing accurately
what
what went
describing accurately
what went on
what went on but
describing accurately
what went on but what
what went on but what goes
describing accurately
what went on but what goes on
what went on but what goes on in
describing accurately
what went on but what goes on in a
different
different dimension
understand
understand that
different dimension
understand that there's
understand that there's different
dimensions
dimensions we
dimensions we live
dimensions we live in
dimensions we live in a
dimensions we live in a different
dimension
so
so he
so he was
so he was talking
so he was talking about
so he was talking about a
so he was talking about a lower
so he was talking about a lower astral
vision
the
the same
the same as
the same as the
the same as the book
the same as the book of
the same as the book of re
the same as the book of re revelation
He's
He's talking
the same as the book of re revelation
He's talking from
He's talking from the
the same as the book of re revelation
He's talking from the same
He's talking from the same level
the same as the book of re revelation
He's talking from the same level about
70 as
70 as the
70 as the book
70 as the book of
70 as the book of revelations
70 as the book of revelations through.
So
So throughout
70 as the book of revelations through.
So throughout history
So throughout history mankind
70 as the book of revelations through.
So throughout history mankind has
reported
reported with
reported with great
reported with great conviction
reported with great conviction because
it
it was
reported with great conviction because
it was experiential
it was experiential and
reported with great conviction because
it was experiential and real
that
that such
that such and
that such and such
that such and such is
that such and such is true.
that such and such is true. The
that such and such is true. The only
thing
thing they
that such and such is true. The only
thing they didn't
thing they didn't know
that such and such is true. The only
thing they didn't know it
thing they didn't know it is
that such and such is true. The only
thing they didn't know it is not
thing they didn't know it is not the
same
same dimension
same dimension as
same dimension as this.
I
I can
same dimension as this.
I can have
I can have a
same dimension as this.
I can have a patient
I can have a patient who
same dimension as this.
I can have a patient who goes
I can have a patient who goes into
same dimension as this.
I can have a patient who goes into a
state
state psych
state psych that
state psych that we
state psych that we would
state psych that we would call
state psych that we would call from
state psych that we would call from our
viewpoint
viewpoint psychotic
state psych that we would call from our
viewpoint psychotic state
viewpoint psychotic state illusional
state
state which
state which all
state which all these
state which all these tremendously
horrible
horrible paranoid
state which all these tremendously
horrible paranoid happenings
horrible paranoid happenings are
happenings
happenings are
happenings are being
happenings are being kidnapped
happenings are being kidnapped and
tortured
tortured and
happenings are being kidnapped and
tortured and killed
tortured and killed and
happenings are being kidnapped and
tortured and killed and all
tortured and killed and all this
happenings are being kidnapped and
tortured and killed and all this and
experientially
experientially subjectively
experientially subjectively it's
experientially subjectively it's a
reality
reality to
experientially subjectively it's a
reality to the
reality to the person.
There's
There's no
There's no point
There's no point in
There's no point in trying
There's no point in trying to
There's no point in trying to talk
people
people out
There's no point in trying to talk
people out paranoid
people out paranoid delusions
There's no point in trying to talk
people out paranoid delusions because
they're
they're you're
they're you're not
they're you're not going
they're you're not going to
they're you're not going to talk
they're you're not going to talk them
out
out of
they're you're not going to talk them
out of it
out of it because
they're you're not going to talk them
out of it because they're
out of it because they're experiential
reality
is
is for
reality
is for the
is for the same
reality
is for the same reason
is for the same reason you
reality
is for the same reason you think
is for the same reason you think that
reality
is for the same reason you think that I
have
have two
have two legs.
have two legs. You
have two legs. You see
have two legs. You see two
have two legs. You see two legs
have two legs. You see two legs here
experientially.
experientially. You
have two legs. You see two legs here
experientially. You say
experientially. You say he
have two legs. You see two legs here
experientially. You say he has
experientially. You say he has two
have two legs. You see two legs here
experientially. You say he has two legs.
Now
Now somebody
Now somebody says
Now somebody says he
Now somebody says he doesn't
Now somebody says he doesn't have
Now somebody says he doesn't have two
legs.
legs. He
Now somebody says he doesn't have two
legs. He only
legs. He only had
Now somebody says he doesn't have two
legs. He only had one
legs. He only had one leg.
Now somebody says he doesn't have two
legs. He only had one leg. I
legs. He only had one leg. I saw
Now somebody says he doesn't have two
legs. He only had one leg. I saw two
legs.
legs. You
legs. You know
legs. You know what
legs. You know what I'm
legs. You know what I'm saying?
legs. You know what I'm saying? The
subjective
subjective reality
legs. You know what I'm saying? The
subjective reality is
subjective reality is convincing
legs. You know what I'm saying? The
subjective reality is convincing because
it
it is
it is an
it is an experience
it is an experience is
it is an experience is experiential.
It's
It's not
it is an experience is experiential.
It's not that
It's not that they're
it is an experience is experiential.
It's not that they're mistaken.
It's not that they're mistaken. It's
it is an experience is experiential.
It's not that they're mistaken. It's not
that.
that. It's
that. It's just
that. It's just that
that. It's just that they
that. It's just that they don't
understand.
understand. It's
that. It's just that they don't
understand. It's a
understand. It's a different
that. It's just that they don't
understand. It's a different dimension.
There
There are
There are various
There are various ways
There are various ways to
There are various ways to access
There are various ways to access other
dimensions.
dimensions. Drugs,
There are various ways to access other
dimensions. Drugs, all
dimensions. Drugs, all kinds
There are various ways to access other
dimensions. Drugs, all kinds of
dimensions. Drugs, all kinds of weird
There are various ways to access other
dimensions. Drugs, all kinds of weird um
esoteric
uh
uh practices,
esoteric
uh practices, certain
uh practices, certain tantric
esoteric
uh practices, certain tantric practices.
They're
They're all
They're all designed
They're all designed twirling
They're all designed twirling around,
going
going going
They're all designed twirling around,
going going into
going going into a
They're all designed twirling around,
going going into a trance,
going going into a trance, using
They're all designed twirling around,
going going into a trance, using various
kinds
kinds of
kinds of drugs,
kinds of drugs, shamans,
kinds of drugs, shamans, and
kinds of drugs, shamans, and exercises
and
and sorcery
kinds of drugs, shamans, and exercises
and sorcery and
and sorcery and invoking
kinds of drugs, shamans, and exercises
and sorcery and invoking demons.
and sorcery and invoking demons. You
kinds of drugs, shamans, and exercises
and sorcery and invoking demons. You can
begin
begin to
begin to explore
begin to explore other
begin to explore other dimensions.
begin to explore other dimensions. If
you're
you're seriously
begin to explore other dimensions. If
you're seriously spiritually
you're seriously spiritually committed,
I
I advise
I advise against
I advise against it
I advise against it strongly.
I advise against it strongly. [laughter]
One
One of
I advise against it strongly. [laughter]
One of these
One of these is
I advise against it strongly. [laughter]
One of these is going
One of these is going to
I advise against it strongly. [laughter]
One of these is going to grab
One of these is going to grab you
I advise against it strongly. [laughter]
One of these is going to grab you by
One of these is going to grab you by the
ankle
ankle and
ankle and say,
ankle and say, "Gotcha.
ankle and say, "Gotcha. [laughter]
Gotcha.
Gotcha."
Gotcha." Why?
Gotcha." Why? Because
these
these other
Gotcha." Why? Because
these other dimensions
these other dimensions have
Gotcha." Why? Because
these other dimensions have been
these other dimensions have been there
Gotcha." Why? Because
these other dimensions have been there a
long,
long, long
long, long time,
long, long time, longer
long, long time, longer than
long, long time, longer than humans.
The
The lower
long, long time, longer than humans.
The lower dimension
The lower dimension has
long, long time, longer than humans.
The lower dimension has been
The lower dimension has been a
long, long time, longer than humans.
The lower dimension has been a powerful
dimension
dimension longer
dimension longer than
dimension longer than mankind.
We're
We're just
dimension longer than mankind.
We're just amateurs.
We're just amateurs. Let's
dimension longer than mankind.
We're just amateurs. Let's see
We're just amateurs. Let's see if
dimension longer than mankind.
We're just amateurs. Let's see if that's
true.
The
The lower
true.
The lower astral
The lower astral preceded
true.
The lower astral preceded keep
The lower astral preceded keep mankind
resist
resist and
resist and has
resist and has been
resist and has been there
resist and has been there for
resist and has been there for millennia
long
long before
resist and has been there for millennia
long before mankind
long before mankind arose.
resist and has been there for millennia
long before mankind arose. There
long before mankind arose. There you
resist and has been there for millennia
long before mankind arose. There you go.
The
The other
The other dimensions,
The other dimensions, the
The other dimensions, the lower
The other dimensions, the lower astral
entities
entities have
The other dimensions, the lower astral
entities have been
kings
kings and
kings and gods
kings and gods of
kings and gods of their
kings and gods of their own
kings and gods of their own domains
kings and gods of their own domains for
millennia
millennia before
kings and gods of their own domains for
millennia before mankind
millennia before mankind even
kings and gods of their own domains for
millennia before mankind even appeared.
So,
So, you're
So, you're not
So, you're not going
So, you're not going to
So, you're not going to go
So, you're not going to go into
So, you're not going to go into their
dimension
without
paying
paying the
without
paying the entrance
paying the entrance fee.
without
paying the entrance fee. [laughter]
That's
That's why
That's why I
That's why I I
That's why I I advise
That's why I I advise people
That's why I I advise people to
That's why I I advise people to avoid
channeling
channeling because
That's why I I advise people to avoid
channeling because you
channeling because you don't
That's why I I advise people to avoid
channeling because you don't know
channeling because you don't know where
it's
it's coming
it's coming from.
it's coming from. You
it's coming from. You don't
it's coming from. You don't know
it's coming from. You don't know what
the
the intention
it's coming from. You don't know what
the intention of
the intention of the
it's coming from. You don't know what
the intention of the entity
the intention of the entity is
it's coming from. You don't know what
the intention of the entity is on
the intention of the entity is on the
other
other side.
other side. You
other side. You can
other side. You can you
other side. You can you have
other side. You can you have a
other side. You can you have a hard
enough
enough time
being
being able
being able to
being able to comprehend
being able to comprehend the
being able to comprehend the intention
and
and level
being able to comprehend the intention
and level of
and level of consciousness
being able to comprehend the intention
and level of consciousness and
and level of consciousness and spiritual
integrity
integrity of
integrity of people
integrity of people that
integrity of people that are
integrity of people that are here
visible
visible and
integrity of people that are here
visible and in
visible and in bodies.
integrity of people that are here
visible and in bodies. Can
visible and in bodies. Can you
integrity of people that are here
visible and in bodies. Can you imagine
what
what you're
what you're trying
what you're trying to
what you're trying to do
what you're trying to do with
what you're trying to do with something
on
on the
what you're trying to do with something
on the other
on the other side
what you're trying to do with something
on the other side named
on the other side named Joshua
what you're trying to do with something
on the other side named Joshua and
on the other side named Joshua and he's
talking
talking to
talking to you
talking to you from
talking to you from ancient
talking to you from ancient mystery
schools
schools and
talking to you from ancient mystery
schools and oh
schools and oh my
talking to you from ancient mystery
schools and oh my god
schools and oh my god give
talking to you from ancient mystery
schools and oh my god give me
schools and oh my god give me a
talking to you from ancient mystery
schools and oh my god give me a break.
I'll
I'll give
I'll give you
I'll give you a
I'll give you a magical
I'll give you a magical sign
I'll give you a magical sign and
I'll give you a magical sign and symbol.
You
You do
I'll give you a magical sign and symbol.
You do that
You do that and
I'll give you a magical sign and symbol.
You do that and you'll
You do that and you'll become
I'll give you a magical sign and symbol.
You do that and you'll become an
initiate
initiate in
initiate in the
initiate in the mystery
initiate in the mystery school
initiate in the mystery school of
[laughter]
right
all
all the
right
all the spiritual
all the spiritual truth
right
all the spiritual truth you
all the spiritual truth you ever
right
all the spiritual truth you ever need
throughout
throughout this
throughout this and
throughout this and any
throughout this and any other
throughout this and any other lifetime
is
is already
throughout this and any other lifetime
is already readily
is already readily available
throughout this and any other lifetime
is already readily available on
is already readily available on this
planet
planet because
planet because the
planet because the truth
planet because the truth is
planet because the truth is spoken
planet because the truth is spoken by
every
every avatar
planet because the truth is spoken by
every avatar every
every avatar every great
planet because the truth is spoken by
every avatar every great guru
every avatar every great guru every
great
great integrous
great integrous teacher
great integrous teacher has
great integrous teacher has always
great integrous teacher has always been
the
the same
great integrous teacher has always been
the same and
the same and you
great integrous teacher has always been
the same and you don't
the same and you don't need
great integrous teacher has always been
the same and you don't need any
the same and you don't need any other
and
and the
and the reason
and the reason you're
and the reason you're looking
and the reason you're looking for
something
something else
and the reason you're looking for
something else is
something else is because
and the reason you're looking for
something else is because you
something else is because you don't
don't
don't want
don't want to
don't want to do
don't want to do It's
don't want to do It's real.
It's
It's a
don't want to do It's real.
It's a way
It's a way of
don't want to do It's real.
It's a way of escaping
It's a way of escaping legitimate
don't want to do It's real.
It's a way of escaping legitimate real
spiritual
spiritual work
spiritual work is
spiritual work is to
spiritual work is to go
spiritual work is to go off
spiritual work is to go off with
spiritual work is to go off with guru
baba
baba who's
spiritual work is to go off with guru
baba who's channeled
baba who's channeled from
spiritual work is to go off with guru
baba who's channeled from the
baba who's channeled from the other
spiritual work is to go off with guru
baba who's channeled from the other side
and
and tells
and tells you
and tells you to
and tells you to buy
and tells you to buy llamas
and tells you to buy llamas this
and tells you to buy llamas this year
and
and sell
and tells you to buy llamas this year
and sell them
and sell them on
and tells you to buy llamas this year
and sell them on the
and sell them on the stock
and tells you to buy llamas this year
and sell them on the stock market
and sell them on the stock market or
whatever.
whatever. You
whatever. You know what
whatever. You know what I
whatever. You know what I mean?
whatever. You know what I mean? All
whatever. You know what I mean? All this
kind
kind of
whatever. You know what I mean? All this
kind of BS.
kind of BS. Why
whatever. You know what I mean? All this
kind of BS. Why would
kind of BS. Why would God
whatever. You know what I mean? All this
kind of BS. Why would God be
kind of BS. Why would God be of
whatever. You know what I mean? All this
kind of BS. Why would God be of any
interest?
interest? You
interest? You know
interest? You know what
interest? You know what you
interest? You know what you do
interest? You know what you do with
interest? You know what you do with your
assets
assets and
interest? You know what you do with your
assets and all
assets and all cuz
interest? You know what you do with your
assets and all cuz to
assets and all cuz to God
interest? You know what you do with your
assets and all cuz to God they
assets and all cuz to God they aren't
even
even assets.
Only
Only you
even assets.
Only you think
Only you think it's
even assets.
Only you think it's an
Only you think it's an asset.
[clears throat]
No,
all
all the
all the truth
all the truth that's
all the truth that's been
all the truth that's been necessary
all the truth that's been necessary to
know
know to
all the truth that's been necessary to
know to reach
know to reach every
all the truth that's been necessary to
know to reach every enlightened
know to reach every enlightened state
all
all the
all the way
all the way to
all the way to saintthood
all the way to saintthood and
all the way to saintthood and all
all the way to saintthood and all the
way
way to
all the way to saintthood and all the
way to enlightenment
way to enlightenment has
all the way to saintthood and all the
way to enlightenment has already
way to enlightenment has already been
spoken
spoken is
spoken is already
spoken is already available
spoken is already available and
spoken is already available and anything
else
else is
spoken is already available and anything
else is just
else is just an
spoken is already available and anything
else is just an avoidance.
Let's
Let's see
Let's see if
Let's see if that's
Let's see if that's so
everything
everything else
Let's see if that's so
everything else is
everything else is an
Let's see if that's so
everything else is an avoidance
everything else is an avoidance and
Let's see if that's so
everything else is an avoidance and a
resistance
resistance and
resistance and unconscious
resistance and unconscious resistance.
Okay.
Okay. So,
resistance and unconscious resistance.
Okay. So, seeking
Okay. So, seeking out
resistance and unconscious resistance.
Okay. So, seeking out that
Okay. So, seeking out that which
resistance and unconscious resistance.
Okay. So, seeking out that which is
Okay. So, seeking out that which is not
the
the truth
the truth is
the truth is an
the truth is an unconscious
the truth is an unconscious resistance
to
to the
the truth is an unconscious resistance
to the truth.
to the truth. Because
the truth is an unconscious resistance
to the truth. Because to
to the truth. Because to reach
the truth is an unconscious resistance
to the truth. Because to reach the
truth,
truth, you
truth, you got
truth, you got to
truth, you got to surrender
truth, you got to surrender certain
illusions
illusions about
truth, you got to surrender certain
illusions about yourself
illusions about yourself and
truth, you got to surrender certain
illusions about yourself and you
illusions about yourself and you would
rather
rather believe
rather believe in
the
the mystification
rather believe in
the mystification from
the mystification from some
rather believe in
the mystification from some enchanting
Baba
Baba on
Baba on the other
Baba on the other side
rather
rather than
Baba on the other side
rather than surrender
rather than surrender the
Baba on the other side
rather than surrender the fact
rather than surrender the fact that
you're
you're getting
you're getting a
you're getting a lot
you're getting a lot of
you're getting a lot of juice
you're getting a lot of juice out
you're getting a lot of juice out of
being
being mad
you're getting a lot of juice out of
being mad at
being mad at people.
you're getting a lot of juice out of
being mad at people. You
being mad at people. You know
you're getting a lot of juice out of
being mad at people. You know what
being mad at people. You know what I'm
saying?
saying? legitimate
saying? legitimate spiritual
saying? legitimate spiritual work
saying? legitimate spiritual work may
seem
seem boring
saying? legitimate spiritual work may
seem boring and
seem boring and mundane
saying? legitimate spiritual work may
seem boring and mundane and
seem boring and mundane and psy
saying? legitimate spiritual work may
seem boring and mundane and psy compared
to
to the
to the excitement
to the excitement of
to the excitement of mystical
to the excitement of mystical chants
to the excitement of mystical chants and
mystical
mystical symbols
to the excitement of mystical chants and
mystical symbols and
mystical symbols and mystical
to the excitement of mystical chants and
mystical symbols and mystical insight
information
um
and
and ascending
and ascending in
and ascending in the
and ascending in the hierarchy
which
which usually
and ascending in the hierarchy
which usually cost
which usually cost you
and ascending in the hierarchy
which usually cost you a
which usually cost you a few
and ascending in the hierarchy
which usually cost you a few thousand
each
each one
each one you
each one you get
each one you get to
each one you get to go
each one you get to go from
each one you get to go from the
each one you get to go from the junior
to
to senior
each one you get to go from the junior
to senior to
to senior to master
each one you get to go from the junior
to senior to master to
to senior to master to super
each one you get to go from the junior
to senior to master to super master
to senior to master to super master this
is
is five
is five grand
is five grand this
is five grand this is
is five grand this is 10
is five grand this is 10 grand
is five grand this is 10 grand this
is five grand this is 10 grand this is
20 grand
20 grand this
is five grand this is 10 grand this is
20 grand this is
20 grand this is 25
is five grand this is 10 grand this is
20 grand this is 25 grand
So
So there
So there seems
So there seems to
So there seems to be
So there seems to be some
So there seems to be some other
motivation.
motivation. H
uh
uh we'll
uh we'll take
uh we'll take a
uh we'll take a break.
uh we'll take a break. Um
uh we'll take a break. Um got
uh we'll take a break. Um got a
uh we'll take a break. Um got a couple
of
of minutes
uh we'll take a break. Um got a couple
of minutes and
of minutes and then
uh we'll take a break. Um got a couple
of minutes and then afterwards
of minutes and then afterwards we'll
just
just sort
just sort of
just sort of have
just sort of have informal
just sort of have informal questions
just sort of have informal questions and
I'll
I'll meet
just sort of have informal questions and
I'll meet and
I'll meet and talk
just sort of have informal questions and
I'll meet and talk with
I'll meet and talk with people
just sort of have informal questions and
I'll meet and talk with people as
I'll meet and talk with people as they
wish.
Um
there's
there's a
there's a question
there's a question about
there's a question about astral
there's a question about astral travel.
Well,
Well, I've
there's a question about astral travel.
Well, I've already
Well, I've already pretty
there's a question about astral travel.
Well, I've already pretty much
Well, I've already pretty much answered
it.
If
If you
it.
If you want
If you want to
it.
If you want to reach
If you want to reach enlightenment,
it.
If you want to reach enlightenment, it's
best
best to
best to avoid
best to avoid astral
best to avoid astral travel.
best to avoid astral travel. Astral
travel
travel can
best to avoid astral travel. Astral
travel can take
travel can take you
best to avoid astral travel. Astral
travel can take you to
travel can take you to an
best to avoid astral travel. Astral
travel can take you to an infinite
number
number of
number of realms.
number of realms. Each
number of realms. Each realm
number of realms. Each realm is
number of realms. Each realm is ruled
number of realms. Each realm is ruled by
a
a demi-
number of realms. Each realm is ruled by
a demi- goodod.
a demi- goodod. Resist
number of realms. Each realm is ruled by
a demi- goodod. Resist who
a demi- goodod. Resist who is
number of realms. Each realm is ruled by
a demi- goodod. Resist who is in
a demi- goodod. Resist who is in turn
ruled
ruled by
ruled by another
ruled by another one
ruled by another one in
ruled by another one in an
ruled by another one in an endless
infinite
infinite number
ruled by another one in an endless
infinite number of
infinite number of possible
ruled by another one in an endless
infinite number of possible dimensions.
You
You see,
You see, thank
You see, thank you.
You
You see
You see, thank you.
You see this
You see this is
You see, thank you.
You see this is only
You see this is only one
You see, thank you.
You see this is only one dimension
You see this is only one dimension but
there's
there's an
there's an infinite
there's an infinite number
there's an infinite number of
dimensions.
Out
Out of
Out of the
Out of the impotent
Out of the impotent infinite
potentiality
of
of everythingness
of everythingness arises
of everythingness arises an
of everythingness arises an infinite
number
number of
of everythingness arises an infinite
number of realms.
number of realms. There's
of everythingness arises an infinite
number of realms. There's an
number of realms. There's an infinite
number
number of
number of realms
number of realms of
number of realms of which
number of realms of which is
number of realms of which is this
number of realms of which is this only
one.
You
You have
You have enough
You have enough trouble
You have enough trouble understanding
this
this one.
You have enough trouble understanding
this one. [laughter]
There's
There's no
There's no point
There's no point of
There's no point of taking
There's no point of taking on
There's no point of taking on other
realms.
Each
Each which
Each which each
Each which each of
Each which each of which
Each which each of which is
Each which each of which is tailored
Each which each of which is tailored for
a
a different
Each which each of which is tailored for
a different purpose
a different purpose by
Each which each of which is tailored for
a different purpose by different
entities
uh
uh in
entities
uh in a
uh in a different
entities
uh in a different context
uh in a different context which
entities
uh in a different context which you
don't
don't not
don't not which
don't not which you
don't not which you don't
don't not which you don't know.
Even
Even if
don't not which you don't know.
Even if you
Even if you get
don't not which you don't know.
Even if you get intreated
Even if you get intreated to
don't not which you don't know.
Even if you get intreated to join
something
something from
something from another
something from another dimension,
remember
remember one
something from another dimension,
remember one fact
remember one fact that
something from another dimension,
remember one fact that you're
remember one fact that you're not
something from another dimension,
remember one fact that you're not going
there.
They're
They're in
there.
They're in a
They're in a different
there.
They're in a different dimension.
and
and you're
and you're not
and you're not going
and you're not going to
and you're not going to go
and you're not going to go where
and you're not going to go where they
are.
are. So
and you're not going to go where they
are. So even
are. So even if
and you're not going to go where they
are. So even if you
are. So even if you do
and you're not going to go where they
are. So even if you do what
are. So even if you do what they
and you're not going to go where they
are. So even if you do what they say,
you're
you're not
you're not going
you're not going to
you're not going to be
you're not going to be one
you're not going to be one of
you're not going to be one of them
because
because they're
you're not going to be one of them
because they're in
because they're in a
you're not going to be one of them
because they're in a dimension
because they're in a dimension which
does
does not
does not include
does not include you.
They've
They've leaked
does not include you.
They've leaked through.
They've leaked through. They
does not include you.
They've leaked through. They might
They've leaked through. They might say
you
you get
you get that
you get that on
you get that on radios.
you get that on radios. The
you get that on radios. The the
you get that on radios. The the purpose
of
of a
you get that on radios. The the purpose
of a limiting
of a limiting circuit
you get that on radios. The the purpose
of a limiting circuit in
of a limiting circuit in a
you get that on radios. The the purpose
of a limiting circuit in a radio.
of a limiting circuit in a radio. In
you get that on radios. The the purpose
of a limiting circuit in a radio. In the
old
old days,
old days, if
old days, if you
old days, if you turn
old days, if you turn on
old days, if you turn on a
old days, if you turn on a radio,
old days, if you turn on a radio, you
got
got all
old days, if you turn on a radio, you
got all the
got all the stations
old days, if you turn on a radio, you
got all the stations from
got all the stations from all
old days, if you turn on a radio, you
got all the stations from all around
Chicago
Chicago and
Chicago and Milwaukee
Chicago and Milwaukee and
Chicago and Milwaukee and Chbboan
Chicago and Milwaukee and Chbboan and
Wisconsin.
Wisconsin. You
Chicago and Milwaukee and Chbboan and
Wisconsin. You have
Wisconsin. You have to
Chicago and Milwaukee and Chbboan and
Wisconsin. You have to have
Wisconsin. You have to have limiting
circuits.
circuits. The
circuits. The limiting
circuits. The limiting circuits
circuits. The limiting circuits prevents
all
all these
circuits. The limiting circuits prevents
all these cross
all these cross channels
circuits. The limiting circuits prevents
all these cross channels because
otherwise
otherwise everything
otherwise everything you
otherwise everything you turn
otherwise everything you turn on
otherwise everything you turn on you're
going
going to
otherwise everything you turn on you're
going to get
going to get four
otherwise everything you turn on you're
going to get four or
going to get four or five
otherwise everything you turn on you're
going to get four or five channels.
These
These limiting
These limiting So
These limiting So these
These limiting So these limiting
circuits
circuits are
These limiting So these limiting
circuits are there
circuits are there to
These limiting So these limiting
circuits are there to prevent
circuits are there to prevent crossing
over
over from
over from one
over from one channel
over from one channel to
over from one channel to another.
So
So first
over from one channel to another.
So first master
So first master this
over from one channel to another.
So first master this channel
So first master this channel and
over from one channel to another.
So first master this channel and then
So first master this channel and then if
you
you want
you want to
you want to go
you want to go to
you want to go to elsewhere
you want to go to elsewhere go
you want to go to elsewhere go ahead.
Except
Except when
you want to go to elsewhere go ahead.
Except when you
Except when you master
you want to go to elsewhere go ahead.
Except when you master this
Except when you master this channel
you want to go to elsewhere go ahead.
Except when you master this channel you
find
find there
find there really
find there really are
find there really are no
find there really are no other
find there really are no other channels.
There
There aren't
find there really are no other channels.
There aren't any
There aren't any other
find there really are no other channels.
There aren't any other real
There aren't any other real dimensions.
But
But that
But that in
But that in itself
But that in itself is
But that in itself is an
But that in itself is an illusion.
But that in itself is an illusion. But
you
you got
But that in itself is an illusion. But
you got to
you got to then
But that in itself is an illusion. But
you got to then be
you got to then be the
But that in itself is an illusion. But
you got to then be the master
you got to then be the master of
But that in itself is an illusion. But
you got to then be the master of all
dimensions
dimensions and
dimensions and transcend
dimensions and transcend all
dimensions and transcend all that.
dimensions and transcend all that. You
got
got to
dimensions and transcend all that. You
got to be
got to be over
dimensions and transcend all that. You
got to be over a thousand.
got to be over a thousand. That
dimensions and transcend all that. You
got to be over a thousand. That takes
1,200
1,200 to
1,200 to realize.
First
First master
1,200 to realize.
First master this
First master this dimension
1,200 to realize.
First master this dimension and
First master this dimension and then
1,200 to realize.
First master this dimension and then see
if
if there
if there are
if there are any
if there are any other
if there are any other dimensions.
if there are any other dimensions. And
if
if you
if there are any other dimensions. And
if you want
if you want to
if there are any other dimensions. And
if you want to go
if you want to go there
if there are any other dimensions. And
if you want to go there and
if you want to go there and then
if there are any other dimensions. And
if you want to go there and then you
realize
realize there
realize there are
realize there are no
realize there are no other
realize there are no other dimensions
because
because the
realize there are no other dimensions
because the completion
because the completion of
realize there are no other dimensions
because the completion of alleness
because the completion of alleness is
all
all that
all that there
all that there is.
all that there is. Huh?
all that there is. Huh? And
all that there is. Huh? And it
all that there is. Huh? And it is
greater
greater than
all that there is. Huh? And it is
greater than all
greater than all dimensions.
One
One could
One could spend
One could spend an
One could spend an infinite
One could spend an infinite amount
One could spend an infinite amount of
time
time just
One could spend an infinite amount of
time just exploring
time just exploring one
One could spend an infinite amount of
time just exploring one of
time just exploring one of these
alternate
alternate dimensions.
alternate dimensions. You
alternate dimensions. You can
alternate dimensions. You can listen
alternate dimensions. You can listen to
WGN
WGN round
alternate dimensions. You can listen to
WGN round the
WGN round the clock.
alternate dimensions. You can listen to
WGN round the clock. You
WGN round the clock. You can
alternate dimensions. You can listen to
WGN round the clock. You can also
WGN round the clock. You can also get
WBBM.
WBBM. You
WBBM. You can
WBBM. You can also
WBBM. You can also get
WBBM. You can also get WS.
WBBM. You can also get WS. You
WBBM. You can also get WS. You can
WBBM. You can also get WS. You can also
get
get WTMJ.
WBBM. You can also get WS. You can also
get WTMJ. can
get WTMJ. can also
WBBM. You can also get WS. You can also
get WTMJ. can also get
get WTMJ. can also get and
WBBM. You can also get WS. You can also
get WTMJ. can also get and you
get WTMJ. can also get and you would
WBBM. You can also get WS. You can also
get WTMJ. can also get and you would see
that
that you
that you would
that you would spend
that you would spend an
that you would spend an inf
that you would spend an inf infinity
that you would spend an inf infinity in
exploring
exploring all
that you would spend an inf infinity in
exploring all the
exploring all the potential
that you would spend an inf infinity in
exploring all the potential dimensions
none
none of
none of which
none of which is
none of which is necessary
because
because the
none of which is necessary
because the ultimate
because the ultimate reality
none of which is necessary
because the ultimate reality beyond
because the ultimate reality beyond all
of
of them
of them is
of them is exactly
of them is exactly the
of them is exactly the same.
of them is exactly the same. The
ultimate
ultimate reality
of them is exactly the same. The
ultimate reality beyond
ultimate reality beyond all
of them is exactly the same. The
ultimate reality beyond all of
ultimate reality beyond all of them
of them is exactly the same. The
ultimate reality beyond all of them is
exactly
exactly the
exactly the same.
exactly the same. Let's
exactly the same. Let's see
exactly the same. Let's see if
exactly the same. Let's see if that's
exactly the same. Let's see if that's a
fact.
The
The ultimate
The ultimate reality
The ultimate reality beyond
The ultimate reality beyond all
dimensions
dimensions is
The ultimate reality beyond all
dimensions is something
dimensions is something I
The ultimate reality beyond all
dimensions is something I may
dimensions is something I may ask
The ultimate reality beyond all
dimensions is something I may ask right
now
now is
now is exactly
now is exactly the
now is exactly the same
now is exactly the same for
now is exactly the same for all
now is exactly the same for all exist.
Okay.
Okay. So
now is exactly the same for all exist.
Okay. So there's
Okay. So there's no
now is exactly the same for all exist.
Okay. So there's no advantage
Okay. So there's no advantage to
now is exactly the same for all exist.
Okay. So there's no advantage to any
other
other dimension
other dimension in
other dimension in which
other dimension in which master
other dimension in which master so
other dimension in which master so and
so
so takes
other dimension in which master so and
so takes you
so takes you to
other dimension in which master so and
so takes you to this
so takes you to this astral
other dimension in which master so and
so takes you to this astral realm
so takes you to this astral realm who
then
then meets
then meets you
then meets you with
then meets you with somebody
then meets you with somebody else
then meets you with somebody else who
takes
takes you
then meets you with somebody else who
takes you another
takes you another astral
then meets you with somebody else who
takes you another astral realm.
takes you another astral realm. And
there
there are
there are people
there are people in
there are people in Sedona
there are people in Sedona that
there are people in Sedona that spent
their
their whole
there are people in Sedona that spent
their whole lifetime
their whole lifetime doing
there are people in Sedona that spent
their whole lifetime doing that.
their whole lifetime doing that. They're
on
on realm
on realm number
on realm number 42.
on realm number 42. You
on realm number 42. You know what
on realm number 42. You know what I
mean?
mean? [laughter]
I
I got
I got news
I got news for
I got news for them.
I got news for them. You
I got news for them. You only
I got news for them. You only got
I got news for them. You only got about
9999,000
9999,000 more
I got news for them. You only got about
9999,000 more realms
9999,000 more realms to
I got news for them. You only got about
9999,000 more realms to explore.
And
And in
And in the
And in the year
And in the year 5,942,
you'll
you'll get
And in the year 5,942,
you'll get a
you'll get a teacher
And in the year 5,942,
you'll get a teacher who
you'll get a teacher who says,
And in the year 5,942,
you'll get a teacher who says, "Hey,
you're
you're chasing
you're chasing your
you're chasing your tail."
you're chasing your tail." Because
you're chasing your tail." Because as
you
you chase
you're chasing your tail." Because as
you chase your
you chase your tail,
you're chasing your tail." Because as
you chase your tail, more
you chase your tail, more dimensions
you're chasing your tail." Because as
you chase your tail, more dimensions are
getting
getting spun
getting spun off
getting spun off the
getting spun off the wheel.
getting spun off the wheel. You
understand?
understand? There's
getting spun off the wheel. You
understand? There's an
understand? There's an infinite
getting spun off the wheel. You
understand? There's an infinite number.
And
And that
And that is
And that is the
And that is the whole
And that is the whole purpose
And that is the whole purpose of
And that is the whole purpose of the
lower
lower astral
is
is to
is to keep
is to keep you
is to keep you going
is to keep you going round
is to keep you going round and
is to keep you going round and round
endlessly
endlessly and
is to keep you going round and round
endlessly and never
endlessly and never becoming
enlightened.
enlightened. Because
enlightened. Because that
enlightened. Because that which
enlightened. Because that which hates
God
God has
enlightened. Because that which hates
God has set
God has set itself
enlightened. Because that which hates
God has set itself up
God has set itself up to
enlightened. Because that which hates
God has set itself up to distract
God has set itself up to distract all
that
that is
that is attracted
that is attracted to
that is attracted to God.
that is attracted to God. So
that is attracted to God. So don't
forget
forget that
that is attracted to God. So don't
forget that as
forget that as you
that is attracted to God. So don't
forget that as you evolve,
forget that as you evolve, you're
that is attracted to God. So don't
forget that as you evolve, you're going
to
to become
to become meek.
to become meek. You're
to become meek. You're going
to become meek. You're going to
to become meek. You're going to become
the
the target.
to become meek. You're going to become
the target. You're
the target. You're going
to become meek. You're going to become
the target. You're going to
the target. You're going to become
that
that which
that which all
that which all that
that which all that hates
that which all that hates God
that which all that hates God um
that which all that hates God um is
attracted
attracted to
that which all that hates God um is
attracted to and
attracted to and wants
that which all that hates God um is
attracted to and wants to
attracted to and wants to pull
that which all that hates God um is
attracted to and wants to pull out
attracted to and wants to pull out of
the
the game.
the game. Okay.
So
the
the upside
the upside of
the upside of love
the upside of love is
the upside of love is bliss,
the upside of love is bliss, happiness,
and
and the
the upside of love is bliss, happiness,
and the awareness
and the awareness that
the upside of love is bliss, happiness,
and the awareness that love
and the awareness that love and
the upside of love is bliss, happiness,
and the awareness that love and God
and the awareness that love and God are
one
one and
one and the
one and the same.
one and the same. The
one and the same. The downside
one and the same. The downside is
one and the same. The downside is and
one and the same. The downside is and we
then
then we'll
one and the same. The downside is and we
then we'll quit.
then we'll quit. The
one and the same. The downside is and we
then we'll quit. The downside
then we'll quit. The downside is
one and the same. The downside is and we
then we'll quit. The downside is when
you
you get
you get into
you get into a
you get into a state
you get into a state of
you get into a state of bliss
you get into a state of bliss lovingness
is
is you
you get into a state of bliss lovingness
is you drop
is you drop your
you get into a state of bliss lovingness
is you drop your guard.
You
You see
You see everyone
You see everyone is
You see everyone is pure
You see everyone is pure and
You see everyone is pure and innocent.
They're
They're innocent
You see everyone is pure and innocent.
They're innocent but
They're innocent but not
You see everyone is pure and innocent.
They're innocent but not pure.
Don't
Don't forget
Don't forget the
Don't forget the sheep
Don't forget the sheep and
Don't forget the sheep and wolf's
clothing.
clothing. So
Don't forget the sheep and wolf's
clothing. So when
clothing. So when they
Don't forget the sheep and wolf's
clothing. So when they see
clothing. So when they see that
Don't forget the sheep and wolf's
clothing. So when they see that you're
clothing. So when they see that you're a
blissful,
blissful, happy
blissful, happy little
blissful, happy little spiritual
blissful, happy little spiritual warrior
and
and you're
blissful, happy little spiritual warrior
and you're bumbling
and you're bumbling down
blissful, happy little spiritual warrior
and you're bumbling down the
and you're bumbling down the street,
blissful, happy little spiritual warrior
and you're bumbling down the street, you
become
become fair
become fair game
become fair game for
become fair game for every
become fair game for every lower
become fair game for every lower astral
that
that could
become fair game for every lower astral
that could like
that could like to
become fair game for every lower astral
that could like to pull
that could like to pull you
become fair game for every lower astral
that could like to pull you out
that could like to pull you out of
become fair game for every lower astral
that could like to pull you out of the
circuit.
circuit. Okay?
Without
Without seeing
circuit. Okay?
Without seeing them
Without seeing them as
circuit. Okay?
Without seeing them as evil,
you
you just
you just realize
you just realize you
you just realize you you
you just realize you you want
you just realize you you want to
you just realize you you want to decline
the
the invitation.
You
You want
You want to
You want to decline
You want to decline the
You want to decline the invitation
You want to decline the invitation to
follow
follow that
You want to decline the invitation to
follow that which
follow that which is
You want to decline the invitation to
follow that which is non-integrous.
follow that which is non-integrous. If
it
it doesn't
it doesn't meet
it doesn't meet the
it doesn't meet the test
it doesn't meet the test of
it doesn't meet the test of integrity,
you
you know,
it doesn't meet the test of integrity,
you know, Jesus
you know, Jesus said
it doesn't meet the test of integrity,
you know, Jesus said just
you know, Jesus said just avoid
it doesn't meet the test of integrity,
you know, Jesus said just avoid it.
you know, Jesus said just avoid it. You
don't
don't have
don't have to
don't have to fight
don't have to fight it.
don't have to fight it. You
don't have to fight it. You don't
don't have to fight it. You don't have
to
to go
don't have to fight it. You don't have
to go against
to go against it.
don't have to fight it. You don't have
to go against it. You
to go against it. You don't
don't have to fight it. You don't have
to go against it. You don't have
to go against it. You don't have to
denounce
denounce it.
denounce it. Just
denounce it. Just don't
denounce it. Just don't go
denounce it. Just don't go there.
denounce it. Just don't go there. Just
don't
don't vote
denounce it. Just don't go there. Just
don't vote for
don't vote for that
denounce it. Just don't go there. Just
don't vote for that candidate.
[laughter]
And
And you
[laughter]
And you know
And you know who
[laughter]
And you know who I
And you know who I mean.
People
People can
People can be
People can be uh
People can be uh genuine
People can be uh genuine to
People can be uh genuine to their
People can be uh genuine to their own
belief
belief systems
People can be uh genuine to their own
belief systems except
belief systems except their
People can be uh genuine to their own
belief systems except their own
belief systems except their own belief
systems
systems are
systems are delusional.
systems are delusional. That's
systems are delusional. That's the
systems are delusional. That's the only
problem.
problem. [laughter]
All right.
All right. So,
All right. So, we'll
All right. So, we'll stop
All right. So, we'll stop now
All right. So, we'll stop now and
All right. So, we'll stop now and all
the
the that
All right. So, we'll stop now and all
the that want
the that want to
All right. So, we'll stop now and all
the that want to uh
the that want to uh after
All right. So, we'll stop now and all
the that want to uh after uh
the that want to uh after uh a
All right. So, we'll stop now and all
the that want to uh after uh a break,
we'll
we'll answer
we'll answer more
we'll answer more questions.
we'll answer more questions. We'll
we'll answer more questions. We'll meet
people
people personally,
we'll answer more questions. We'll meet
people personally, maybe
people personally, maybe answer
we'll answer more questions. We'll meet
people personally, maybe answer some
people personally, maybe answer some of
their
their personal
their personal questions.
And
And no
their personal questions.
And no blissing
And no blissing out
their personal questions.
And no blissing out while
And no blissing out while on
their personal questions.
And no blissing out while on duty.
We
We just
We just thought
We just thought we'd
We just thought we'd ask
We just thought we'd ask answer
We just thought we'd ask answer some
more
more questions.
Something
Something something
Something something came
Something something came up
Something something came up about
Something something came up about the
lower
lower astral.
Um,
Um, everything
Um, everything I've
Um, everything I've learned
Um, everything I've learned about
Um, everything I've learned about it
Um, everything I've learned about it is
you
you don't
Um, everything I've learned about it is
you don't want
you don't want to
Um, everything I've learned about it is
you don't want to go
you don't want to go there.
>> Let
>> Let me
>> Let me ask
>> Let me ask that
>> Let me ask that question.
>> Let me ask that question. Somebody
>> Let me ask that question. Somebody asked
the
the question,
>> Let me ask that question. Somebody asked
the question, can
the question, can you
>> Let me ask that question. Somebody asked
the question, can you evolve
the question, can you evolve upwards
from
from the
from the lower
from the lower astral?
from the lower astral? We
from the lower astral? We have
permission
permission to
from the lower astral? We have
permission to ask
permission to ask this
from the lower astral? We have
permission to ask this in
permission to ask this in front
from the lower astral? We have
permission to ask this in front of
permission to ask this in front of this
audience.
audience. Resist.
[sighs]
>> Do
>> Do you
>> Do you have
>> Do you have the
>> Do you have the karmic
>> Do you have the karmic permission
>> Do you have the karmic permission to
>> Do you have the karmic permission to to
to
to evolve
>> Do you have the karmic permission to to
to evolve from
to evolve from the
>> Do you have the karmic permission to to
to evolve from the lower
to evolve from the lower astral?
>> Do you have the karmic permission to to
to evolve from the lower astral? Resist.
That's
That's why
That's why you
That's why you don't
That's why you don't want
That's why you don't want to
That's why you don't want to go
That's why you don't want to go there.
Remember
Remember the
That's why you don't want to go there.
Remember the Buddhist
Remember the Buddhist said,
That's why you don't want to go there.
Remember the Buddhist said, "Fortunate
are
are you
are you that
are you that you're
are you that you're a
are you that you're a human
are you that you're a human being."
are you that you're a human being." Slim
are
are the
are you that you're a human being." Slim
are the chances
are the chances to
are you that you're a human being." Slim
are the chances to be
are the chances to be born
are you that you're a human being." Slim
are the chances to be born a
are the chances to be born a human
because
because the
because the human
because the human has
because the human has the
because the human has the chance
because the human has the chance to
evolve
evolve all
because the human has the chance to
evolve all the
evolve all the way
because the human has the chance to
evolve all the way to
evolve all the way to enlightenment.
Rarer
Rarer still
Rarer still is
Rarer still is the
Rarer still is the desire
Rarer still is the desire to
Rarer still is the desire to reach
enlightenment.
enlightenment. And
Rarer still is the desire to reach
enlightenment. And rarer
enlightenment. And rarer still
Rarer still is the desire to reach
enlightenment. And rarer still are
enlightenment. And rarer still are those
who
who have
who have heard
who have heard of
who have heard of enlightenment,
who have heard of enlightenment, be
who have heard of enlightenment, be born
a
a human,
who have heard of enlightenment, be born
a human, and
a human, and have
who have heard of enlightenment, be born
a human, and have not
a human, and have not taken
who have heard of enlightenment, be born
a human, and have not taken advantage
a human, and have not taken advantage of
this
this golden
this golden opportunity.
this golden opportunity. Therefore,
waste
waste no
this golden opportunity. Therefore,
waste no time.
Waste
Waste no
Waste no time.
You
You can
Waste no time.
You can waste
You can waste no
Waste no time.
You can waste no time
You can waste no time very
Waste no time.
You can waste no time very simply
because
because as
because as everything
because as everything arises
because as everything arises in
because as everything arises in the
ordinary
ordinary course
because as everything arises in the
ordinary course of
ordinary course of ordinary
because as everything arises in the
ordinary course of ordinary life,
ordinary course of ordinary life, you
just
just constantly
just constantly surrender
just constantly surrender to
just constantly surrender to God.
just constantly surrender to God. You
know,
know, you
just constantly surrender to God. You
know, you don't
know, you don't have
just constantly surrender to God. You
know, you don't have to
know, you don't have to be
just constantly surrender to God. You
know, you don't have to be a
know, you don't have to be a rocket
scientist
scientist to
scientist to figure
scientist to figure out
scientist to figure out how
scientist to figure out how to
scientist to figure out how to do
scientist to figure out how to do that.
You
You know,
scientist to figure out how to do that.
You know, could
You know, could I
scientist to figure out how to do that.
You know, could I would
You know, could I would I
scientist to figure out how to do that.
You know, could I would I be
You know, could I would I be willing
scientist to figure out how to do that.
You know, could I would I be willing to
surrender
surrender that
surrender that to
surrender that to God?
surrender that to God? Those
surrender that to God? Those of
surrender that to God? Those of you
surrender that to God? Those of you who
have
have done
surrender that to God? Those of you who
have done the
have done the 12step
surrender that to God? Those of you who
have done the 12step programs,
have done the 12step programs, the
surrender that to God? Those of you who
have done the 12step programs, the third
step
step is
step is you
step is you surrender
step is you surrender your
step is you surrender your life
step is you surrender your life to
step is you surrender your life to God
as
as you
step is you surrender your life to God
as you understand
as you understand him.
step is you surrender your life to God
as you understand him. And
as you understand him. And of
step is you surrender your life to God
as you understand him. And of course,
the
the miracles
the miracles all
the miracles all all
the miracles all all the
the miracles all all the really
the miracles all all the really basic
spiritual
spiritual programs,
the miracles all all the really basic
spiritual programs, many
spiritual programs, many of
the miracles all all the really basic
spiritual programs, many of which
calibrate
calibrate in
calibrate in two
calibrate in two or
calibrate in two or 300s,
calibrate in two or 300s, but
calibrate in two or 300s, but they're
calibrate in two or 300s, but they're ba
they're
they're solid
calibrate in two or 300s, but they're ba
they're solid basic
they're solid basic stuff
calibrate in two or 300s, but they're ba
they're solid basic stuff to
they're solid basic stuff to surrender
everything
everything to
everything to God,
everything to God, to
everything to God, to hold
everything to God, to hold back
everything to God, to hold back nothing.
um
um to
everything to God, to hold back nothing.
um to ask
um to ask God
everything to God, to hold back nothing.
um to ask God questions
um to ask God questions if
everything to God, to hold back nothing.
um to ask God questions if you
um to ask God questions if you don't
know
know the
know the answer
know the answer to
know the answer to ask
know the answer to ask for
know the answer to ask for guidance
know the answer to ask for guidance from
your
your own
know the answer to ask for guidance from
your own from
your own from the
know the answer to ask for guidance from
your own from the Holy
your own from the Holy Spirit
know the answer to ask for guidance from
your own from the Holy Spirit within
you.
you. Ask
you. Ask for
you. Ask for a
you. Ask for a miracle
and
and uh
you. Ask for a miracle
and uh you
and uh you can
you. Ask for a miracle
and uh you can often
and uh you can often just
you. Ask for a miracle
and uh you can often just tell
and uh you can often just tell the
you. Ask for a miracle
and uh you can often just tell the Holy
Spirit
Spirit I
Spirit I don't
Spirit I don't get
Spirit I don't get it
Spirit I don't get it and
Spirit I don't get it and just
Spirit I don't get it and just and
Spirit I don't get it and just and all
of a
of a sudden
Spirit I don't get it and just and all
of a sudden you
of a sudden you say
Spirit I don't get it and just and all
of a sudden you say I
of a sudden you say I don't
Spirit I don't get it and just and all
of a sudden you say I don't get
of a sudden you say I don't get it
Spirit I don't get it and just and all
of a sudden you say I don't get it as
you
you walk
you walk out
you walk out suddenly
you walk out suddenly you
you walk out suddenly you get
you walk out suddenly you get it.
you walk out suddenly you get it. I
you walk out suddenly you get it. I mean
[laughter]
very
very prompt
very prompt I
very prompt I don't know
very prompt I don't know you
very prompt I don't know you get
very prompt I don't know you get very
prompt
prompt answers
very prompt I don't know you get very
prompt answers a
prompt answers a lot
very prompt I don't know you get very
prompt answers a lot of
prompt answers a lot of times.
Um
is
is there
Um
is there an
is there an ultimately
Um
is there an ultimately best
is there an ultimately best process
Um
is there an ultimately best process for
releasing
releasing surrendering
releasing surrendering etc
releasing surrendering etc everything
releasing surrendering etc everything to
God
God that's
releasing surrendering etc everything to
God that's the
God that's the willingness
releasing surrendering etc everything to
God that's the willingness we
God that's the willingness we said
releasing surrendering etc everything to
God that's the willingness we said the
power
power of
power of willingness
see
see devotion
power of willingness
see devotion love
see devotion love takes
power of willingness
see devotion love takes many
see devotion love takes many forms
power of willingness
see devotion love takes many forms one
form
form it
form it takes
form it takes is
form it takes is is
form it takes is is a
form it takes is is a powerful
form it takes is is a powerful decision
when
when you
form it takes is is a powerful decision
when you make
when you make a
form it takes is is a powerful decision
when you make a decision
when you make a decision to
form it takes is is a powerful decision
when you make a decision to say
when you make a decision to say no
form it takes is is a powerful decision
when you make a decision to say no to
that
that which
that which is
that which is non-integrous
that's
that's really
that which is non-integrous
that's really a
that's really a very
that which is non-integrous
that's really a very powerful
that's really a very powerful step
uh
uh I'm
uh I'm not
uh I'm not going
uh I'm not going to
uh I'm not going to go
uh I'm not going to go there
uh I'm not going to go there and
whatever
whatever the
uh I'm not going to go there and
whatever the consequences.
whatever the consequences. I'm
uh I'm not going to go there and
whatever the consequences. I'm not
whatever the consequences. I'm not going
there.
there. Um,
there. Um, so
there. Um, so commitment,
there. Um, so commitment, the
willingness
willingness to
there. Um, so commitment, the
willingness to um,
willingness to um, let
there. Um, so commitment, the
willingness to um, let everything
willingness to um, let everything go.
there. Um, so commitment, the
willingness to um, let everything go. It
doesn't
doesn't mean
doesn't mean you're
doesn't mean you're going
doesn't mean you're going to
doesn't mean you're going to succeed
doesn't mean you're going to succeed the
first
first time
doesn't mean you're going to succeed the
first time you
first time you let
doesn't mean you're going to succeed the
first time you let go
first time you let go of
doesn't mean you're going to succeed the
first time you let go of a
first time you let go of a certain
desire
desire or
desire or wantingness
desire or wantingness or
desire or wantingness or resentment.
Doesn't
Doesn't mean
desire or wantingness or resentment.
Doesn't mean necessarily
Doesn't mean necessarily the
desire or wantingness or resentment.
Doesn't mean necessarily the first
Doesn't mean necessarily the first time
you
you let
you let it
you let it go.
you let it go. We
you let it go. We said
you let it go. We said because
you let it go. We said because a
you let it go. We said because a lot
you let it go. We said because a lot of
these
these things
you let it go. We said because a lot of
these things are
these things are an
you let it go. We said because a lot of
these things are an accumulation
these things are an accumulation of
you let it go. We said because a lot of
these things are an accumulation of of
many
many lifetimes
many lifetimes and
many lifetimes and we'll
many lifetimes and we'll get
many lifetimes and we'll get to
many lifetimes and we'll get to that
next
next week.
many lifetimes and we'll get to that
next week. a
next week. a repetitive
uh
uh pattern
uh pattern shows
uh pattern shows up
uh pattern shows up over
uh pattern shows up over long
uh pattern shows up over long expanses
of
of time.
uh pattern shows up over long expanses
of time. You
of time. You know
uh pattern shows up over long expanses
of time. You know this
of time. You know this is
uh pattern shows up over long expanses
of time. You know this is just
of time. You know this is just one
uh pattern shows up over long expanses
of time. You know this is just one uh
episode.
episode. Uh
episode. Uh one's
episode. Uh one's life
episode. Uh one's life is
episode. Uh one's life is not
episode. Uh one's life is not this
episode.
episode. This
episode. Uh one's life is not this
episode. This is
episode. This is just
episode. Uh one's life is not this
episode. This is just an
episode. This is just an episode.
episode. Uh one's life is not this
episode. This is just an episode. This
is
is this
is this particular
is this particular physicality.
is this particular physicality. One's
life
life transcends
uh
uh many
uh many physicalities.
uh many physicalities. So
uh many physicalities. So a
uh many physicalities. So a pattern
uh many physicalities. So a pattern can
persist
persist and
uh many physicalities. So a pattern can
persist and persist
persist and persist and
uh many physicalities. So a pattern can
persist and persist and persist.
persist and persist and persist. So
uh many physicalities. So a pattern can
persist and persist and persist. So as
you
you let
you let go,
try
try to
you let go,
try to let
try to let go
you let go,
try to let go of
try to let go of it,
you let go,
try to let go of it, it
try to let go of it, it doesn't
you let go,
try to let go of it, it doesn't always
let
let go
let go right
let go right away.
let go right away. But
let go right away. But the
let go right away. But the very
let go right away. But the very fact
that
that you
let go right away. But the very fact
that you were
that you were willing
let go right away. But the very fact
that you were willing to
that you were willing to surrender
let go right away. But the very fact
that you were willing to surrender it
and
and that
and that you
and that you did
and that you did actually
and that you did actually go
and that you did actually go through
and that you did actually go through the
process
process is
and that you did actually go through the
process is already
process is already a
and that you did actually go through the
process is already a karmic
process is already a karmic merit
and that you did actually go through the
process is already a karmic merit so
that
that eventually
that eventually you're
that eventually you're building
that eventually you're building up
that eventually you're building up you
might
might say
that eventually you're building up you
might say undoing
might say undoing all
that eventually you're building up you
might say undoing all the
might say undoing all the negative
karmas
karmas and
karmas and de
karmas and de and
karmas and de and now
karmas and de and now all
karmas and de and now all of a
karmas and de and now all of a sudden
one
one day
karmas and de and now all of a sudden
one day you
one day you you
karmas and de and now all of a sudden
one day you you let
one day you you let it
karmas and de and now all of a sudden
one day you you let it go
one day you you let it go and
karmas and de and now all of a sudden
one day you you let it go and it
disappears.
I
I don't
disappears.
I don't know
I don't know they
disappears.
I don't know they just
I don't know they just don't
disappears.
I don't know they just don't get
I don't know they just don't get you
disappears.
I don't know they just don't get you mad
anymore.
anymore. You
anymore. You used
anymore. You used to
anymore. You used to fantasize
anymore. You used to fantasize killing
them
them and
anymore. You used to fantasize killing
them and murdering
them and murdering them
anymore. You used to fantasize killing
them and murdering them and
them and murdering them and getting
eaten
eaten with
eaten with them
eaten with them and
eaten with them and now
eaten with them and now you
eaten with them and now you don't
eaten with them and now you don't give
eaten with them and now you don't give a
rap
rap about
eaten with them and now you don't give a
rap about them
rap about them one
eaten with them and now you don't give a
rap about them one way
rap about them one way or
eaten with them and now you don't give a
rap about them one way or the
rap about them one way or the other
eaten with them and now you don't give a
rap about them one way or the other like
little
little mice.
little mice. You
little mice. You know
little mice. You know mice
little mice. You know mice run
little mice. You know mice run around.
And
And I
little mice. You know mice run around.
And I think
And I think they're
little mice. You know mice run around.
And I think they're cute.
And I think they're cute. You
little mice. You know mice run around.
And I think they're cute. You know,
And I think they're cute. You know, at
one
one time
one time I'm
one time I'm sure
one time I'm sure I
one time I'm sure I hated
one time I'm sure I hated them,
one time I'm sure I hated them, was
afraid
afraid of
one time I'm sure I hated them, was
afraid of them,
afraid of them, and
one time I'm sure I hated them, was
afraid of them, and uh
afraid of them, and uh you
one time I'm sure I hated them, was
afraid of them, and uh you know,
afraid of them, and uh you know, but
one time I'm sure I hated them, was
afraid of them, and uh you know, but I
now
now I
now I think
now I think they're
now I think they're sort
now I think they're sort of
now I think they're sort of cute.
now I think they're sort of cute. So
now I think they're sort of cute. So I
chased
chased them
now I think they're sort of cute. So I
chased them out.
chased them out. I
now I think they're sort of cute. So I
chased them out. I hate
chased them out. I hate to
now I think they're sort of cute. So I
chased them out. I hate to kill
chased them out. I hate to kill them
because
because then
because then I'll
because then I'll miss
because then I'll miss them
because then I'll miss them and
because then I'll miss them and they're
going
going to
because then I'll miss them and they're
going to go
going to go off
because then I'll miss them and they're
going to go off in
going to go off in another
because then I'll miss them and they're
going to go off in another body
elsewhere,
elsewhere, but
elsewhere, but not
elsewhere, but not in
elsewhere, but not in my
elsewhere, but not in my backyard
elsewhere, but not in my backyard where
I
I can
elsewhere, but not in my backyard where
I can have
I can have fun
elsewhere, but not in my backyard where
I can have fun with
I can have fun with them.
elsewhere, but not in my backyard where
I can have fun with them. So
uh
uh can
uh can you
uh can you elaborate
uh can you elaborate calibrations
uh can you elaborate calibrations beyond
10,000?
Uh
Uh such
Uh such calibrations
Uh such calibrations are
Uh such calibrations are possible.
Uh such calibrations are possible. We
don't
don't want
Uh such calibrations are possible. We
don't want to
don't want to really
Uh such calibrations are possible. We
don't want to really go
don't want to really go into
Uh such calibrations are possible. We
don't want to really go into this.
don't want to really go into this. Yeah.
Okay.
Okay. Such
Okay. Such calibrations
Okay. Such calibrations are
Okay. Such calibrations are not
possible.
>> We
>> We have
>> We have permission.
>> We
>> We have
>> We have permission.
>> We have permission. We
>> We have permission. We just
>> We have permission.
>> We have permission. We just to
>> We have permission. We just to answer
the
the question.
the question. It's
the question. It's possible
the question. It's possible for
the question. It's possible for the
physical
physical nervous
the question. It's possible for the
physical nervous system
physical nervous system to
the question. It's possible for the
physical nervous system to handle
everything
everything something
everything something over
everything something over a
everything something over a thousand.
everything something over a thousand. It
it's
it's possible
everything something over a thousand. It
it's possible for
it's possible for the
everything something over a thousand. It
it's possible for the human
it's possible for the human nervous
system
to
to handle
system
to handle consciousness
to handle consciousness energies
system
to handle consciousness energies over
1,000.
1,000. No.
1,000. No. Says
1,000. No. Says no.
Uh,
somebody
somebody said
somebody said if
somebody said if you
somebody said if you if
somebody said if you if this
somebody said if you if this last
somebody said if you if this last time
you
you came
somebody said if you if this last time
you came out
you came out of
somebody said if you if this last time
you came out of the
you came out of the void,
somebody said if you if this last time
you came out of the void, did
you came out of the void, did you
somebody said if you if this last time
you came out of the void, did you leave
the
the last
the last you
the last you left
the last you left the
the last you left the last
the last you left the last time
the last you left the last time in
the last you left the last time in the
void?
void? Resist.
the last you left the last time in the
void? Resist. We
void? Resist. We have
the last you left the last time in the
void? Resist. We have permission
void? Resist. We have permission on
the last you left the last time in the
void? Resist. We have permission on that
one.
one. The
one. The prior
one. The prior lifetime
one. The prior lifetime was
one. The prior lifetime was left
one. The prior lifetime was left in
one. The prior lifetime was left in the
void.
void. Resist.
one. The prior lifetime was left in the
void. Resist. Yes.
void. Resist. Yes. For
one. The prior lifetime was left in the
void. Resist. Yes. For prior
void. Resist. Yes. For prior lifetime,
in
in fact,
in fact, the
in fact, the the
in fact, the the ultimate
in fact, the the ultimate truth
in fact, the the ultimate truth was
voidness
voidness as
in fact, the the ultimate truth was
voidness as far
voidness as far as
in fact, the the ultimate truth was
voidness as far as I
voidness as far as I knew.
in fact, the the ultimate truth was
voidness as far as I knew. And
voidness as far as I knew. And uh
that's
that's a
that's a certain
spiritual
spiritual pathway
that's a certain
spiritual pathway which
spiritual pathway which is
that's a certain
spiritual pathway which is integrous
because
because it's
because it's based
because it's based on
because it's based on a
because it's based on a conviction
because it's based on a conviction that
that
that is
because it's based on a conviction that
that is the
that is the ultimate
because it's based on a conviction that
that is the ultimate truth
that is the ultimate truth and
because it's based on a conviction that
that is the ultimate truth and it's
based
based on
based on a
based on a mistransation
based on a mistransation I
based on a mistransation I think
based on a mistransation I think of
based on a mistransation I think of the
teaching
teaching of
based on a mistransation I think of the
teaching of the
teaching of the Buddha.
Um
because
because it
Um
because it is
because it is only
Um
because it is only really
because it is only really a
Um
because it is only really a matter
because it is only really a matter of
contextualization.
The
The difference
contextualization.
The difference between
The difference between allness
contextualization.
The difference between allness and
nothingness
nothingness is
nothingness is a
nothingness is a very
nothingness is a very subtle
nothingness is a very subtle discernment
on
on a
nothingness is a very subtle discernment
on a certain
on a certain level
nothingness is a very subtle discernment
on a certain level that
on a certain level that which
nothingness is a very subtle discernment
on a certain level that which is
on a certain level that which is all
thereby
thereby becomes
thereby becomes nothing.
thereby becomes nothing. You
thereby becomes nothing. You understand?
Because
Because to
thereby becomes nothing. You understand?
Because to be
Because to be something
thereby becomes nothing. You understand?
Because to be something you
Because to be something you would
thereby becomes nothing. You understand?
Because to be something you would have
to
to be
to be differentiated
to be differentiated from
to be differentiated from the
to be differentiated from the rest.
to be differentiated from the rest. So
to
to be
to be differentiated from the rest. So
to be all
to be all that
to be differentiated from the rest. So
to be all that is
to be all that is is
to be differentiated from the rest. So
to be all that is is in
to be all that is is in a
to be differentiated from the rest. So
to be all that is is in a way
to be all that is is in a way being
nothing
nothing but
nothing but it
nothing but it is
nothing but it is more
nothing but it is more complicated
nothing but it is more complicated than
that
that u
nothing but it is more complicated than
that u verbalization
that u verbalization about
nothing but it is more complicated than
that u verbalization about it.
So
So this
So this the
So this the capacity
So this the capacity to
So this the capacity to let
So this the capacity to let things
So this the capacity to let things go
So this the capacity to let things go is
first
first of
So this the capacity to let things go is
first of all
first of all a
So this the capacity to let things go is
first of all a matter
first of all a matter of
So this the capacity to let things go is
first of all a matter of practice,
first of all a matter of practice, a
matter
matter of
matter of direction,
matter of direction, a
matter of direction, a p
matter of direction, a p a
matter of direction, a p a matter
matter of direction, a p a matter of
habit,
habit, a
matter of direction, a p a matter of
habit, a matter
habit, a matter a
matter of direction, a p a matter of
habit, a matter a matter
habit, a matter a matter of
matter of direction, a p a matter of
habit, a matter a matter of willingness
and
and basically
and basically it's
and basically it's really
and basically it's really devotional.
So
So the
and basically it's really devotional.
So the underpinning
So the underpinning of
and basically it's really devotional.
So the underpinning of any
So the underpinning of any spiritual
practice
practice is
practice is devotion.
Um
Um the
practice is devotion.
Um the willingness
Um the willingness to
practice is devotion.
Um the willingness to surrender
Um the willingness to surrender all
practice is devotion.
Um the willingness to surrender all to
God.
Um
Um and
God.
Um and that's
Um and that's what
God.
Um and that's what gives
Um and that's what gives us
God.
Um and that's what gives us its
Um and that's what gives us its its
power.
With
With practice
power.
With practice it
With practice it becomes
power.
With practice it becomes uh
With practice it becomes uh habit.
power.
With practice it becomes uh habit. With
practice
practice it
practice it becomes
practice it becomes habitual.
Uh
Uh you
practice it becomes habitual.
Uh you let
Uh you let go
practice it becomes habitual.
Uh you let go to
Uh you let go to change
practice it becomes habitual.
Uh you let go to change it.
I
I was
I was talking
I was talking out
I was talking out back
I was talking out back about
I was talking out back about being
stopped
stopped by
I was talking out back about being
stopped by a
stopped by a cop
I was talking out back about being
stopped by a cop at
stopped by a cop at 1:00
I was talking out back about being
stopped by a cop at 1:00 in
stopped by a cop at 1:00 in the
I was talking out back about being
stopped by a cop at 1:00 in the morning
on
on 89A.
Yeah.
Yeah. We
on 89A.
Yeah. We were
Yeah. We were the
on 89A.
Yeah. We were the only
Yeah. We were the only ones
on 89A.
Yeah. We were the only ones on
Yeah. We were the only ones on the
on 89A.
Yeah. We were the only ones on the whole
highway.
highway. Nobody's
highway. Nobody's out
highway. Nobody's out there
highway. Nobody's out there at
highway. Nobody's out there at 1:00
except
except me
highway. Nobody's out there at 1:00
except me and
except me and this
highway. Nobody's out there at 1:00
except me and this squad
except me and this squad car
highway. Nobody's out there at 1:00
except me and this squad car behind
except me and this squad car behind me.
And
And I
And I figure
And I figure I'm
And I figure I'm looking
And I figure I'm looking at
And I figure I'm looking at my
speedometer.
speedometer. I'm
And I figure I'm looking at my
speedometer. I'm thinking
speedometer. I'm thinking I'm
And I figure I'm looking at my
speedometer. I'm thinking I'm going
speedometer. I'm thinking I'm going 40.
Now,
Now, why
Now, why is
Now, why is this
Now, why is this guy
Now, why is this guy telling
Now, why is this guy telling me?
Now, why is this guy telling me? So,
finally
finally pulls
Now, why is this guy telling me? So,
finally pulls me
finally pulls me over,
Now, why is this guy telling me? So,
finally pulls me over, flashes,
finally pulls me over, flashes, lights,
and
and I
and I said,
and I said, "Uh,
and I said, "Uh, what
and I said, "Uh, what can
and I said, "Uh, what can it
and I said, "Uh, what can it be?"
and I said, "Uh, what can it be?" He
says,
says, "You're
and I said, "Uh, what can it be?" He
says, "You're weaving?"
Weaving?
Weaving? What
Weaving? What is
Weaving? What is weaving?
Weaving? What is weaving? He
Weaving? What is weaving? He said,
"You're
"You're going
Weaving? What is weaving? He said,
"You're going back
"You're going back and
Weaving? What is weaving? He said,
"You're going back and forth
"You're going back and forth over
Weaving? What is weaving? He said,
"You're going back and forth over the
yellow
yellow line."
yellow line." I'm
yellow line." I'm thinking,
yellow line." I'm thinking, "We're
yellow line." I'm thinking, "We're the
only
only people
yellow line." I'm thinking, "We're the
only people on
only people on the
yellow line." I'm thinking, "We're the
only people on the whole
only people on the whole highway.
yellow line." I'm thinking, "We're the
only people on the whole highway. What
am
am I
am I going to
am I going to do?
am I going to do? Stay
am I going to do? Stay in
am I going to do? Stay in my
am I going to do? Stay in my lane?
There's
There's nobody
am I going to do? Stay in my lane?
There's nobody else
There's nobody else here
am I going to do? Stay in my lane?
There's nobody else here but
There's nobody else here but me."
[laughter]
So,
So, he
[laughter]
So, he says,
So, he says, "Are
[laughter]
So, he says, "Are are
So, he says, "Are are you
[laughter]
So, he says, "Are are you drinking?"
So, he says, "Are are you drinking?" I
said,
said, "No,
said, "No, I
said, "No, I haven't
said, "No, I haven't had
said, "No, I haven't had a
said, "No, I haven't had a drink
said, "No, I haven't had a drink in
said, "No, I haven't had a drink in 40
years."
years." So
said, "No, I haven't had a drink in 40
years." So he
years." So he says,
said, "No, I haven't had a drink in 40
years." So he says, "Uh,
years." So he says, "Uh, you
said, "No, I haven't had a drink in 40
years." So he says, "Uh, you take
years." So he says, "Uh, you take dope,
smoke
smoke stuff?"
smoke stuff?" I
smoke stuff?" I said,
smoke stuff?" I said, "No."
[laughter]
"You
"You willing
"You willing to
"You willing to take
"You willing to take a
"You willing to take a so
"You willing to take a so and
"You willing to take a so and so
"You willing to take a so and so test?"
I
I says,
"You willing to take a so and so test?"
I says, "Sure."
I says, "Sure." He
"You willing to take a so and so test?"
I says, "Sure." He says,
I says, "Sure." He says, "Walk
"You willing to take a so and so test?"
I says, "Sure." He says, "Walk this
yellow
yellow line."
yellow line." I
yellow line." I walk
yellow line." I walk the
yellow line." I walk the yellow
yellow line." I walk the yellow line.
yellow line." I walk the yellow line. He
said,
said, "I
yellow line." I walk the yellow line. He
said, "I don't
said, "I don't know.
yellow line." I walk the yellow line. He
said, "I don't know. There's
said, "I don't know. There's still
something
something wrong
something wrong with
something wrong with you."
something wrong with you." [laughter]
And
And he's
something wrong with you." [laughter]
And he's scratching
And he's scratching his
something wrong with you." [laughter]
And he's scratching his head.
And he's scratching his head. He
something wrong with you." [laughter]
And he's scratching his head. He said,
"Well,
"Well, what
"Well, what do
"Well, what do you
"Well, what do you think's
"Well, what do you think's the
"Well, what do you think's the matter
with
with you?"
"Well, what do you think's the matter
with you?" All right.
with you?" All right. And
"Well, what do you think's the matter
with you?" All right. And I
with you?" All right. And I said,
"Well, what do you think's the matter
with you?" All right. And I said, "You
know,
know, you
know, you want
know, you want me
know, you want me to
know, you want me to be
know, you want me to be truthful?"
know, you want me to be truthful?" He
says,
says, "Yeah."
know, you want me to be truthful?" He
says, "Yeah." I
says, "Yeah." I said,
know, you want me to be truthful?" He
says, "Yeah." I said, "I
says, "Yeah." I said, "I don't
know, you want me to be truthful?" He
says, "Yeah." I said, "I don't feel
says, "Yeah." I said, "I don't feel like
I'm
I'm really
I'm really in
I'm really in my
I'm really in my body."
[cheering]
He
He said,
He said, "Good
He said, "Good God."
He said, "Good God." He
He said, "Good God." He says,
He said, "Good God." He says, "I've
He said, "Good God." He says, "I've had
this
this exactly
He said, "Good God." He says, "I've had
this exactly the
this exactly the same
He said, "Good God." He says, "I've had
this exactly the same experience."
So,
So, it
So, it was
So, it was a
So, it was a an
So, it was a an actual
So, it was a an actual experience.
So, it was a an actual experience. said,
you
you know,
So, it was a an actual experience. said,
you know, I'm
you know, I'm stringing
So, it was a an actual experience. said,
you know, I'm stringing this
you know, I'm stringing this to
So, it was a an actual experience. said,
you know, I'm stringing this to God
you know, I'm stringing this to God and
uh
uh you
uh you know,
uh you know, if
uh you know, if he
uh you know, if he gives
uh you know, if he gives me
uh you know, if he gives me a
uh you know, if he gives me a ticket,
uh you know, if he gives me a ticket, he
gives
gives me
uh you know, if he gives me a ticket, he
gives me a
gives me a ticket,
uh you know, if he gives me a ticket, he
gives me a ticket, so
gives me a ticket, so let
uh you know, if he gives me a ticket, he
gives me a ticket, so let it
gives me a ticket, so let it be.
uh you know, if he gives me a ticket, he
gives me a ticket, so let it be. You
know,
know, he
know, he said,
know, he said, gosh,
know, he said, gosh, he
know, he said, gosh, he said,
know, he said, gosh, he said, I'm
know, he said, gosh, he said, I'm glad
to
to have
know, he said, gosh, he said, I'm glad
to have met
to have met you.
know, he said, gosh, he said, I'm glad
to have met you. And
to have met you. And then
know, he said, gosh, he said, I'm glad
to have met you. And then I
to have met you. And then I told
know, he said, gosh, he said, I'm glad
to have met you. And then I told him,
I'm
I'm a
I'm a doctor
I'm a doctor and
I'm a doctor and a
I'm a doctor and a psychiatrist
I'm a doctor and a psychiatrist and
I'm a doctor and a psychiatrist and all
that
that gave
I'm a doctor and a psychiatrist and all
that gave really
that gave really more
I'm a doctor and a psychiatrist and all
that gave really more firepower.
that gave really more firepower. And
I'm a doctor and a psychiatrist and all
that gave really more firepower. And I
told
told him,
told him, yeah,
told him, yeah, I
told him, yeah, I go
told him, yeah, I go out
told him, yeah, I go out by
told him, yeah, I go out by if
told him, yeah, I go out by if I
told him, yeah, I go out by if I don't
remember
remember to
told him, yeah, I go out by if I don't
remember to come
remember to come back
told him, yeah, I go out by if I don't
remember to come back in
remember to come back in it,
told him, yeah, I go out by if I don't
remember to come back in it, I
remember to come back in it, I can
wander
wander off
wander off because,
wander off because, you
wander off because, you know,
wander off because, you know, if
wander off because, you know, if you're
wandering
wandering across
wander off because, you know, if you're
wandering across in
wandering across in the
wander off because, you know, if you're
wandering across in the middle
wandering across in the middle of
wander off because, you know, if you're
wandering across in the middle of the
night,
night, you're
night, you're not
night, you're not thinking
night, you're not thinking about
night, you're not thinking about what
you're
you're doing,
night, you're not thinking about what
you're doing, you
you're doing, you know.
night, you're not thinking about what
you're doing, you know. So
you're doing, you know. So anyway,
night, you're not thinking about what
you're doing, you know. So anyway, he
was
was greatly
was greatly relieved.
was greatly relieved. He
was greatly relieved. He said,
was greatly relieved. He said, "This
worried
worried me
was greatly relieved. He said, "This
worried me for
worried me for years."
was greatly relieved. He said, "This
worried me for years." He
worried me for years." He said, "Now
was greatly relieved. He said, "This
worried me for years." He said, "Now I
know
know what
know what it
know what it is."
know what it is." I
know what it is." I said,
know what it is." I said, "You
know what it is." I said, "You just
know what it is." I said, "You just will
yourself
yourself to
know what it is." I said, "You just will
yourself to be
yourself to be back
know what it is." I said, "You just will
yourself to be back in
yourself to be back in the
know what it is." I said, "You just will
yourself to be back in the body."
yourself to be back in the body." And
bang,
bang, you
bang, you go
bang, you go back.
bang, you go back. Terrific.
bang, you go back. Terrific. You
bang, you go back. Terrific. You know,
we
we left
bang, you go back. Terrific. You know,
we left the
we left the best
bang, you go back. Terrific. You know,
we left the best buddies,
we left the best buddies, shook
bang, you go back. Terrific. You know,
we left the best buddies, shook hands,
hugged.
So,
So, one
hugged.
So, one sign
So, one sign of
hugged.
So, one sign of being
So, one sign of being out
hugged.
So, one sign of being out of
So, one sign of being out of your
hugged.
So, one sign of being out of your body
is
is you
is you weave.
[laughter]
But
But he
But he was
But he was really
But he was really a
But he was really a nice
But he was really a nice officer.
But he was really a nice officer. You
know,
know, he
But he was really a nice officer. You
know, he really
know, he really was.
But he was really a nice officer. You
know, he really was. He
know, he really was. He said,
But he was really a nice officer. You
know, he really was. He said, "I
know, he really was. He said, "I really
had
had been
had been worried
had been worried about
had been worried about that."
had been worried about that." And
had been worried about that." And here
he
he found
had been worried about that." And here
he found somebody
he found somebody he
had been worried about that." And here
he found somebody he could
he found somebody he could ask
had been worried about that." And here
he found somebody he could ask about
he found somebody he could ask about it.
And
And I
And I said,
And I said, you
And I said, you know,
And I said, you know, you're
And I said, you know, you're not
And I said, you know, you're not just
not
not connected
And I said, you know, you're not just
not connected with
not connected with your
And I said, you know, you're not just
not connected with your body
not connected with your body space,
which
which is
which is one
which is one problem
which is one problem that
which is one problem that you
which is one problem that you have
which is one problem that you have when
you're
you're first
which is one problem that you have when
you're first going
you're first going into
which is one problem that you have when
you're first going into certain
you're first going into certain higher
states.
states. You
states. You don't
states. You don't know
states. You don't know where
states. You don't know where your
states. You don't know where your body
is
is in
states. You don't know where your body
is in space.
is in space. It
states. You don't know where your body
is in space. It was
is in space. It was it's
states. You don't know where your body
is in space. It was it's very
is in space. It was it's very difficult
to
to navigate
to navigate because
to navigate because that
to navigate because that which
to navigate because that which is
to navigate because that which is the
central
central controller
to navigate because that which is the
central controller is
central controller is gone.
to navigate because that which is the
central controller is gone. See,
everything
everything you
everything you do
everything you do is
everything you do is oriented
everything you do is oriented from
everything you do is oriented from some
imaginary
imaginary space
everything you do is oriented from some
imaginary space somewhere
imaginary space somewhere in
everything you do is oriented from some
imaginary space somewhere in the
imaginary space somewhere in the middle
of
of your
of your head.
of your head. When
of your head. When that
of your head. When that disappears,
where
where you
of your head. When that disappears,
where you are
where you are in
of your head. When that disappears,
where you are in space
where you are in space is
of your head. When that disappears,
where you are in space is not
where you are in space is not all
of your head. When that disappears,
where you are in space is not all that
clear
clear at
clear at all.
clear at all. It's
clear at all. It's still
clear at all. It's still not
clear at all. It's still not all
clear at all. It's still not all that
clear
clear very
clear at all. It's still not all that
clear very often.