So we're part of that emergence.
We're the leading edge of homospiritus,
the evolution of
a new
being
almost spiritous.
When the the evolution of consciousness
crossed over 200, it signal the
emergence of a new
level of life, a new potentiality of
life
because it's a more powerful level of
consciousness.
Then it
is of assistance to spiritual
progression
to my
guess is that spiritual
awareness will progress more rapidly and
reach more people than it has in the
past. Profoundly affect more aspects of
society.
We see that within the last few months.
We see that
that
back when the consciousness level was
below 190
when I grew up winning gain wealth
prestige fame
having a cat Cadillac titles
degrees
all the gains the worldly gains
the corner office with two windows
Having three secretaries,
the right address
that which was sought was gain.
Its downside was victory over one's
enemy.
Kill the Japs, kill the Nazis, kill
somebody.
Oh, so kill somebody. Kill your enemies.
So
the criteria of success were you went to
war, you killed your enemies, then you
came home, got a degree straight A, got
doctorates, made millions of dollars,
lived in the best place.
That was the signal of success
to be a millionaire.
There's a TV program.
I want to be a millionaire.
I mean, it sounds stupid, you know, so
juvenile, but at the time it was very
exciting.
I remember when the $64 question was
$64 to get you from here to New York and
back. You know, now it wouldn't get you
to Cottonwood.
Wouldn't get you in out of Walmart,
that's for sure.
I'll say, "By God, this time I'm going
to Walmart and I'm just going to buy
those screens. That's all I'm buying.
Those grills. $163 it cost me.
$16 grills."
Well,
now we see all that's changed.
Now, winning over our enemies is even
questioned. We're going through
soularching.
We got some really heavy duty enemies
out there and the whole country is
examining their conscience. Is it okay
to go after your enemies or not? Defend
yourself against them or stand up to
them or put them out of business before
they do you in.
So the new
yard stick of success, the new yard
stick in society is integrity.
Integrity is where it's at right now.
Because of lack of integrity, we see the
multi-millionaire corporations collapse.
Enron and Altel and Mil work and Pom
Gump and all those cray
ticky names. Anyway,
they sought the old paradigm.
Success at any cost. Man, what's wrong
with that?
back at the time of the robber barons. I
mean that what was wrong with that?
There wasn't anything immoral about
working the workers to death and firing
them before Christmas.
You big corporations always fired them
the week before Christmas. And I say,
"Good God, have they no sense at all?
Don't they have any public relations
person? They have just injured their
corporation
far more. or they spend millions on
advertising and then they find they
always do all the big layoffs the week
before Christmas
in the public esteem they went from here
down to here you know couldn't they wait
till the week after Christmas
always the week before Christmas I don't
know if you grew up in the 50s and 40s
and 60s they all lay them off the week
before Christmas
now the new level
to which we're answerable now is
integrity
because Because of lack of integrity,
the famous lady with her own magazine
and all multi-millionaire had resigned
from the board of directors of the stock
market.
Not because she was convicted of
anything, but because her integrity
integrity was now in question. That was
never heard of years ago.
All of you who are older, did you ever
hear of anybody getting knocked off the
border directly to some corporation for
lack of integrity? Never heard of it. He
got his job by being having lack of
integrity.
If you didn't have lack of integrity,
you're never going to be a salesman in
that company. I'll tell you,
tell him anything. Just get them to sign
the D line and make sure the check gets
certified. That's the rule.
When I was a salesman, you're supposed
to company the customer to the bank.
Roofing and siding.
Roofing and siding. I saw roofing and
siding. House to house. Lord, forgive
me. Yeah.
Oh yes.
Oh. All right. So we have a new paradigm
of reality now. A very powerful
paradigm.
Even the networks
whose own integrity is questionable at
times are touting integrity as the new
paradigm of reality, not success. Nobody
gives a crap about your success. Being a
millionaire doesn't mean anything. All
kinds of poor folks became millionaires
during the tech high-tech stock market
expansion.
I had patients that could hardly afford
a tank of gas to be truthful with you.
But they were millionaires.
Every day they check their stocks on the
on their computer, you know. God, they
were worth $10 million. You know, by
noon they're worth the $12 million. By 3
in the afternoon, they're worth $14
million.
Except they lacked integrity. You see?
So now I want to be a millionaire. It
sounds sort of stupid. Everybody got a
chance to shot to be a millionaire. If
you didn't, your aunt did or your
neighbor did. I mean, being a
millionaire doesn't mean anything.
Success doesn't mean anything.
What holds up long term is integrity.
And everybody knows that
the businesses we calibrated before we
published power versus force as integras
is now the biggest corporation in the
world the entire world.
If that doesn't prove an integrity pace,
then what does?
So business now, some members of this
group here are working
to carry that message into business that
your bottom line nowadays doesn't depend
on how many you sell. That'll give you a
little pop on your stock, but it's not
going to carry it through. I wouldn't
put that in your 401k, folks.
What you better put in your 401k is
integrity.
So that 30 years from now when you need
that 401k, it hasn't gone down the
drain. And the only thing I know that'll
keep it from going down the drain is
integrity.
Why? Because integrity itself, just like
the broken window drags that which is
negative to it, that which is positive
pulls that which is positive to it.
I'd like to be a greeter in Walmarts.
I'd really like that as a job. I mean, I
just love you. You imagine just hug
people all day and love them.
What can I do for you?
Where's the underwear?
Where's the hats?
I mean, what a fun job. You know, that
was as fun as being a cab driver. I like
being a cab driver. Oh, that was fun.
Be a cab driver. You chatter and you're
friends with all the people. By the time
they leave the cab, you're less best
buddies. You know what I mean? He wants
your phone number. He wants you to come
to his sister's birthday party next
week.
The chance to just love lots of people
unconditionally is just, you know, a
really great opportunity.
It's probably why I gave up being a vger
in a cathedral.
The life of the solitary monk has its
virtue.
Everybody needs a life as a solitary
monk. And um it's a great life
because through that absolute
aloneeness, the simplicity to just have
a candle and a stick and a book in a in
a chair, you really don't need anything
more. You really do not need anything
more. And when I came out to Sedona,
that's the way we lived for quite a
while. With a box, a candle with an
apple and a cot from a dinosaur.
It was fantastic.
Then life got worse. I started to own
things.
Got worse and worse.
Oh man.
Become a captive of your own
possessions.
to become their slave, their servant.
All right?
So we find God through simplicity,
through renunciation.
The renunciation
can be physical, social.
is internal to renounce
to be willing to surrender out of
devotion to God the satisfaction and the
gratification one gets out of one's
mental gerations
to juice revenge to juice resentment to
juice self-pity
at the same time not make them wrong.
You see, we let go these positions. We
let go our attachment to them, but not
out of guilt and making them wrong.
I like to complain and grumble.
I say to her, "Honey,
if we didn't have each other to complain
and grumble to, who the heck would we
talk to?" Now, one of our forms of love
is we both listen to each other's
grumbles.
The air conditioning on my car doesn't
work now, and I can't drive it to
Phoenix now because it doesn't work.
She says, "Oh, that's awful. You can
take my car.
The close neighbor who works with us,
Lou, has has computer trouble with his
car. I hope he complains to somebody. He
hasn't complained to me, but if I were
him, I'd complain about it. I paid good
money for the car. The computer doesn't
work.
You got to have somebody to grumble to
and be human with. So,
you see, you take your own self with a
dash of salt. You know what I mean?
You can't take yourself too seriously.
You can indulge yourself, but not take
it too seriously. You can have a
tantrum. You can throw yourself on the
floor. It's good. It's good. It's fun.
You just throw yourself on the floor and
just scream with anger and hit the
floor.
Well, then everybody is a six-month-old.
So you don't make it wrong. You see what
I mean? Within all of us is the is the
vindictive judge. You're going to be put
away and suffer for this young man
and never see the light of day.
You see? Yes, sir.
So to transcend something, you have to
be able to accept it. To accept it, you
have to get off right and wrong about
it. It just is that way. There's ugly
little creatures in the sea.
Their mothers love them, but nobody else
does.
It's all right for them to be there
because consciousness evolves and it and
it expresses itself in form
throughout its evolution.
So if we look around the manifest world,
we see all these levels of
consciousness.
some lower than what we even have on the
chart.
Poisonous little things that live at the
bottom of the sea.
Uh
so it's like all these levels of
consciousness
express themsel in form
and each one then is like a stepping
stone.
So we look within ourself and we see all
that's possible within the field of
consciousness.
All the positives and all the things we
call negatives and all.
And we get off a positionality about our
own positionalities.
It's natural to have positionalities.
Right and wrong, good and evil,
love and hate. Um they're not opposites.
They're positionalities.
They're all positionalities along the
same line. They're not opposites. So we
have to always confirm that
because to undo the ego, you have to let
go positionalities. And positionalities
are set set up by the dualistic
thinkingness of the mind. The mind tends
to think in dualistic
dualistic um for those that haven't seen
it here.
here. In one instant, you'll get what it
takes 50 years of meditation to get.
This will save you all kinds of monk
times
and the lousy food that goes with being
a monk.
Turnup's crap. I mean,
you hang out in the wrong monkery where
humility takes a dietary form.
Porridge and turnups. That's all you get
there. Hardly any clothes to wear.
Forget turning on the heat in the winter
time. Austerity and renunciation.
And then you become a rack of bones.
As we said, there's no
such thing as polarities. What we see
here is the presence of heat. And as the
presence of heat diminishes now we call
it something different. We call it cold
and we call this zero. But you can see
that's arbitrary. There's only one
variable. The presence of heat or its
absence. That's all.
There's the presence of love or its
absence.
So we become friendly. The first form
that forgiveness
becoming benign, benevolent, forgiving,
generous, compassionate, accepting,
affectionate
is toward yourself.
We practice it by looking out into the
world and seeing what is it out there
that we're still still judgmental about,
can't accept, can't forgive, etc.
Because that's within yourself. Project
that out into the world.
So the world serves then it serves us
spiritually
that the structure of society and its
operations are
the ego projected out there for us to
understand.
So that way the world serves us. It's a
constant source of teaching, of
learning, of opportunity,
capacity to witness because it's out
there. It's easier to accept.
We can see the cruelty out there because
it's out there and it's them
because of guilt. We don't see it within
oursel.
We become more sensitive to it.
And then what we do is because we're
spiritually committed is we let it go
within ourself.
And in so doing we serve the world.
Everything that we let go within ourself
we let go also
within the world within the level of the
field of consciousness itself is
affecting everyone. So
um let's see if that's so
Um,
everything I serve within myself
therefore serves the world. Is this
everything you do within yourself,
you're thereby serving the world. Why?
Because you're part of the world. So you
can't forgive it in yourself and not
have the world benefit because you are
the world. You are one with the world.
Therefore, all the spiritual work we do
within oursel,
we can consciously dedicate it to God,
consciously dedicated to our fellow
human beings.
It's better than
better than parades. Parades don't
really change anything.
Down with whatever. You know what I
mean? It's okay for adolescence. It's
part of college life. You get out there
and get in a parade, a protest parade
about something. So we we end up loving
all of life in all of its expressions
without judgmentalism
and in so doing we accept it within
ourself and the vice versa. That which
we accept within ourself
we see that there's nothing we need to
do. If this is a exercise gym, if this
is purgatorial,
then why would you want to eliminate all
the possibilities to express all the
aspects of consciousness out there?
If they can't beat up little babies here
in this neighborhood, they're going to
find some other little neighborhood to
beat up little babies because the
horrific is part of nature.
The horrific.
There's no point then
to try to change what's out there
because the world as we see it then is a
projection from our own ego. So we heal
it within ourself and in healing it
within ourself we heal it within the
world.
That must be so because we see that
consciousness is progressing.
It's poised at 207.
207 is very profound.
Integrity is stunningly enormously
important. It is the whole crux.
It's the fulcrum upon which the balance
tips one way or the other is integrity
that calibrates at 200. Huh. So
we see the important what is the
importance of the scale of
consciousness? It's just that it makes
visible
that which seems to be un less real if
it's only verbalized.
If we only verbalize it, right? But if
we also put it in sort of a visible
form. See, this is the way the mind is
used to thinking. We've been trained
this way from kindergarten on up to
think logically, to put things in form
and concept
comprehensible. So the 400s are very
um useful because they're the great
spring springboard
uh on up to the higher levels.
We see that there's one that has the 200
line demarcated with some kind of a
color or something to emphasize its
importance. Yeah, this one's a better
one. This one is really a better visual
because it points out it emphasizes
uh the importance of to this level here.
This is the most crucial level
uh on the whole map because
from here once you cross this line the
rest is practically guaranteed.
Well, not guaranteed.
But the rest is accessible.
The more one rises, the more one is
likely to rise.
Let's see if that's all. Okay. The
higher one gets, the more likely one is
to get ever higher. Resist. Okay. So,
the more you advance, the more you're
likely to advance.
And the more you advance from wanting to
to advance, the the more advanced you
get to be more advanced.
So it's an upward spiral once you even
be begin to become interested in
spiritual matters.
Once you have the slightest interest in
spirituality uh
then you're already on your way.
Therefore, there's no worry, no need to
worry because nobody would be at a
meeting like this unless they were
scheduled for enlightenment
any more than you would be at divers's
lessons unless you unless you're
planning to go deep sea diving.
So, we could say then the way is certain
for all of those.
And though the Buddhist said that once
you've heard of enlightenment, you'll
never be satisfied with anything less.
To merely have heard it already imprints
consciousness
to be in the presence of those who have
gone.
The root already impresses a vibration
within consciousness.
Nothing less will suffice ever more.
And so the end is certain.
So we can stop worrying about it.
Don't worry about it.
You don't have to worry about it.
See, because we're not just repelled
from that which has occurred in the
past.
We are attracted by that which is
destined in the future.
It's only within the
Newtonian paradigm
that one sees present things as being
caused by the past.
In
the quantum potential in the quantum
reality, the future is just as powerful
as the past. One is not more, one is not
greater than the other. The influence of
the future
is equal
to the what should we call it the pull
of the future is as great or greater
than the drag of the past. We'll put it
in common image.
We have permission to ask that resist.
That is a fact. Resist. Oh wow.
>> Hey, don't worry about your past.
Everybody here has a fantastic future.
Resist.
>> Of course.
You're not here out of guilt or out of
the past. You're here out of the joy
that's pulling you to the future.
You're like magnetically attracted to
truth, love, that which is benign, that
which is forgiving
towards beauty, towards kindness,
towards gentleness
to become the expression of one's
infinite potentiality.
And we do this out of an innate devotion
to God.
people. I see people all the time that
are devoted to God and not even aware
that they are.
That's a fact. Resist.
Isn't that funny?
They're already on their way. I can They
look like a little iron filing and a big
powerful magnet is holding them up in
the air and they're worrying about
whether they're going to get there. And
I have to laugh at it because they're
obviously suspended.
It's because we're powerfully attracted
by our infinite potential
that we're here
or not here but somebody some lecture
someplace some meditation someplace some
workbook some mantra
some form of worship.
One of the best forms of worship is
integrity.
Integrity is a way of worshiping God.
It's a way of acknowledging
God
in ordinary life. How can I best honor
God except by doing the best carpentry I
can do?
And I'm all nicked up from recent
carpentry.
So just to make a little store room
is nothing
except that you want it to be the best
little store room you can make out of
the available materials, time, etc.
To be integrous then to be integrous
within oneself
benefits all of mankind.
To be integrous is a way of worshiping
God.
To bring integrity to the workplace,
you see, because your integrity
influences everybody else.
And
the new
measure of success is going to be
integrity.
That's a whole new paradigm. That's the
emergence of homosspiritus.
The book I'm finishing now,
we talk about the emergence of homo
spiritus.
Uh a new emergence on the evolutionary
tree. And I think homosspiritis is going
to require
a different nervous system
because once you get over 5 600 it's
tough.
Um there is in actuality the emergence
of homo spiritus
resist
is an actual new branch off the
evolutionary tree resist.
it will eventuate into we have
permission
um
the evolution of the nervous system
itself is just this nervous system is
not made for over 600 resist this
nervous system is not made for over 600
and uh so if mankind is going to keep
hanging into the physical domain and uh
having a physical body and the same time
evolving spiritually is a point where
some better apparatus is required.
Um
so that le the late '8s then was to me
you know the prophecy about the second
coming of Christ. Well because people
think of themselves as bodies they
expect uh um a physicality to appear and
announce itself as the return of Jesus.
Actually I think the emergence of
consciousness over 200 was the
unli of the emergence of of Christ
consciousness resist
the return of Christ to the earth then
would be signaled by the crossing over
from that which is ungodly to that which
is godly resist.
Mhm.
So to me the second coming of Christ
means
the reemergence of Christ consciousness
as becoming
dominant within the human progressively
dominant within the human domain. See,
because that which is benevolent and
loving
um
is kind and kindness means not to shock
people.
You understand? If I was um capable of
influencing the evolution of human
consciousness,
it would be to bring it slowly
and progressively and even ever more
pleasurably, exquisitly, delightfully,
joyfully into manifestation
and not just flop. You know what I mean?
Because you got to get used to it.
You have to get used to a calmer, more
peaceful, more loving
uh it's shocking to people.
It's shocking to yourself even when you
suddenly make a giant leap in
consciousness and suddenly you're almost
stunned by the beauty and the silence
and the presence of God as
love
with an intensity beyond which one could
even imagine.
The presence of God as infinite love is
overwhelming
and it does take you out the world.
Anybody
who's seriously committed to spiritual
work, I always tell them, be sure your
relatives know what you're up to or your
friend or somebody.
Because at any moment, one can go into a
state that cannot be conveyed,
described.
One becomes speechless.
Motion is almost impossible.
In higher states, you become weak.
Everything is slowed down.
you forget about eating, you know,
forget about all physical things.
So, you need somebody to know that
you're a spiritually committed person.
And if you go into a silent state of
bliss,
he doesn't need shock treatment, doesn't
need a shot of thorazine.
You can suggest eating this with soup,
but you may not get much of an answer to
it.
Spiritual work is very serious work. It
can bring about profound changes both
physically and
within one's sense of reality,
sense of self.
It can change profoundly and in an
instant with no forewarning.
More usually one begins to feel joy more
often. Begin to notice the beauty of
things that you didn't notice before.
There are certain sort of warnings
coming up in advance.
You notice how beautiful everyone is.
You tend to fall in love with
everything.
There's that falling in love phase where
you fall in love with all of life and
everything in it and everyone.
And that's sort of a warning
to get your affairs in order.
Get your affairs in order
because one is like led to
that which you need to be led to. And
then the willingness to surrender even
that to God,
even ecstasy,
spiritual ecstasy beyond description
comes up to be surrendered
to thee, oh God.
One time I was dancing in front of the
altar
at midnight
in the chapel over here.
Chapel of the Holy Cross. They didn't
used to lock it.
It was open all night and the candles
burned all night and the music was on
all night
and all the visitors had left and at
12:00 or 1 in the morning you could go
there
and meditate all alone in this chapel
with the candle and the music and the
beauty and you would just go into an
ecstatic state beyond description.
Now they lock it up, turn off the music
and put the lights out. It's
health department or somebody
and such ecstatic states.
Uh
the ecstatic state
was described by Rama Krishna. So after
I learned that Rama Krishna went into
it, I quit worrying about it.
Such ecstatic state. So somebody has to
tell you that those states are there.
They're going to be experienced. If
you're being attracted by the ultimate
potentiality
of the evolution of human consciousness,
then you're going to be pulled through
those states.
And when ecstasy beyond description,
the willingness to surrender it even
that to God,
when that's surrendered to God,
then the most awesome of all,
a piece of such profoundity, of such
extent, in such dimension,
and of such expression through its
quality and its exquisite presence takes
the place of
ecstasy
and that gets you beyond 599.
We got we told you how to get beyond the
400s
now the 500s.
This you see the rean reverence love
lovingness
brings one up to an exquisite joyfulness
within which there is a serenity.
The revelation of the presence of God
and a transfiguration takes place within
the person. You will never be the same.
You will never be the same again. to
experience the presence of God when it's
is not possible to go back.
Then up here is is the states
this is just joy but up here should be
ecstasy.
Out of joy
that moves on to an ecstasy that's
beyond description
beyond comprehension.
That exquisite bliss, that ecstatic
ecstasy,
the willingness to surrender even that
to God brings
an infinite state
which is all prevailing
which is the absolute rel reality that
prevails
and in due time
one can go back into the world and
be alive to the world without it being
disturbed at all.
The state is always present.
Then one witnesses
what was the person the persona
returns to interact with the world if
that's one's karmic propensity.
If that's one's karmic propensity,
one may or may not return to the world.
Most do not.
Most once you hit that state of peace,
that's it. One is finished with the
world
and there is no obligation to remain.
But for unknown
karmic reasons,
one may stay.
In that case, the persona
is given permission to react to
reactivate within the world to
respond to the world in a way the world
comprehends within their dimensions of
reality
and learns to refunction in the world.
By that time one has located spiritual
teachers that are aware of such
conditions.
And I think it's the duty of the teacher
always to warn
not warn to educate about what these
states are how they come about
to know that
it's all right.
It's all right to feel bliss and ecstasy
and it's all right to
let the body fall over.
If it ceases to breathe, then it's
immaterial.
One is not obligated to breathe it
again.
Some people rebreathe it when it stops
breathing cuz out of a sense of
obligation.
So one at that point one releases that
sense of obligation and becomes
detached. You're not obliged to the
world or anyone in it. So that's one of
the last attachments.
One lets go.
On the way of spiritual progression,
seeing as this is a class of people who
are destined for the ultimate or they
wouldn't be here, we already reaffirmed
that
along the way. those especially when you
get into the 500s,
you begin to pull up
um that
which is opposed to spirituality which
is threatened by it.
And
one has to watch
that benevolence and lovingness does not
take the form of
naivity.
an ignorance and fall back into a
different ignorance
to be loving but at the same time guard
the gates.
There's a certain phase in the 500s
where one becomes um
um a target of that which is
non-integrous.
They see your vulnerability. There is a
certain phase in that level where you
cannot see anything with love. And
so
one has to still preserve integrity. So
the safeguard then
in the 500s the levels of love is still
then
to recall integrity
is what they are presenting to you
integrous
um because it can be cleverly conveyed
to sell what you know for a price
etc. it comes up as a temptation.
So I've spoken in previous lectures
about
the luciferic temptation of power over
others
uh money, power, fame
and seduction in its various forms.
Certain entities will see a person in
that blissful state of lovingness
as vulnerable. So
one's protection then is integrity.
It's not loving to allow others to be
non-integorous with you.
That's confusing love with passivity.
It's not of service to yourself or
others
to allow that which is non-intigorous
to have an effect on your life.
So I have integrity then we have to let
executives go
in and the name of the business because
for the business to survive it has to be
based on the rock of integrity which
will survive success.
Without integrity
you cannot survive success.
All right. So, we've talked enough of
this morning about
the evolution of consciousness because
as it manifests as yourself, you
personalize it. You personalize it. But
what you're personalizing itself is not
personal. It's consciousness.
And you are merely calling it
me or myself.
But that's just what you're calling it.
So when you see that you're just calling
it that and that it's innately it's
neither this nor that nor is it here nor
there. One realizes that what is
speaking as consciousness itself what is
presenting itself to your own awareness
is the divinity within expressing itself
as the joy of one's own existence.
source of joy then is the awareness of
the presence of God within
as one's own existence.
Thank you Lord for the existence of all
in this audience
and thank you for my existence and for
sharing it with you because we
apparently are all destined for the same
place.
Thank you.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu
Halleluah.
Hallelu.
Hallelu
Halleluahalleluah.
Hallelujah.
>> If you can't find God, all you have to
do is turn this music on
and do nothing else.
You hear the essence of the exquisite
presence expressing itself as beauty
and infinite compassion.
The way to God is extremely radical at
times.
Pick up a prayer here, a hymn there,
attend a workshop here, read a book
there.
I can't figure out I can't seem to make
any progress.
One finds that which is sympatical with
oneself and then persists with it with a
dogged
determination
and absolute commitment beyond all
commitments.
If you find it through this music,
you play this music round the clock
now and forever more.
You don't need to eat. You don't have to
go to the bathroom. Have to go anywhere.
Don't have to answer the phone.
There comes a time when you decide to
make the run for it.
It can be a mantra. It can be a
meditation.
It can be meditating on a guru.
It can be something that you consider
divine, sacred.
And you go with it
no matter what.
No matter what.
And if you
don't eat after a couple weeks and death
faces you, so you die.
So
that's the least of it.
Dying is a snap. Is a college way out.
He's taken by everybody.
Yeah, brother. Going to get to heaven by
dying? Forget it.
No, you you get there by a fixity, a
focus and a determination.
It's an act of the spiritual will.
It is by an act of the spiritual will
that you have already chosen your future
and that's why you're here.
I got a letter the other day. It says,
"I've read the first six pages of the
preface and I have to talk to you right
away.
Is that a fact? That is a fact that I've
read the first six pages and I must talk
to you right away.
I mean that uh it was it was adorable.
You know
we get delued delused with uh all the
forms of communication existent
nowadays. The fax goes round the clock.
The email never stops. The computer
never stops. The telephone never stops.
The answering machine never stops. The
answering service never stops.
It's not possible to answer it all and I
read everything and I sort of mentally
communicate an answer
but it's not possible within the
physical domain to handle it.
First of all, I can't type
and uh
the office has bought a computer and I
can't find the on switch.
I'm I'm not lying. I'm not there is no
on or off switch. So
because I couldn't get beyond that
point, I gave it up. And I mean if you
can't even find the onoff switch, do
stock, you know, it's not for you. You
know, it's not in your dimension
somehow.
I just want to apologize to all the
people who sent such beautiful
communications and I cannot answer them
all. We try to answer questions here.
The answers to most of the questions
that people send are already within the
written material or the visuals.
Uh I try to include everything that
could possibly come up so that
very often if a thing is not understood,
it hasn't been meditated on. That's all.
You haven't looked at it long enough.
And
um most questions I feel like saying
well look at it and call me back in 20
years.
Those are the things I looked at.
It's like as you focus on a situation
mentally and ask for God's help to
resolve it. Ask to see it differently.
Ask for the miraculous. Pray to the Holy
Spirit. and rattle the gates of heaven.
When it's karmically allowed, you
suddenly see it. You suddenly see the
answer and it resolves itself.
Um,
so
spiritual work is different than
intellectual work. Intellectual work is
asking a specific and then getting a
specific answer and now you feel
satisfied
which is too bad.
The actual answer comes from
reflecting on a thing. So we talked
during these lectures about the style of
a spiritually uh committed person
becomes more and more contemplative
so that all that arises one
more or less contemplates
and in that way eventually bypass
the polarities.
Isn't peace good? And isn't war awful?
No. War is terrific.
And peace is terrific. And frankly,
they're actually the same. Except to the
observer, they look like opposites.
Right now, the country is involved in
the situation.
Should they should we be pacifist or
activist?
Should we be reactive or proactive?
That's where it really comes down to.
People who are old enough remember World
War II and when and what went on that
time. So those who have not learned from
history are condemned to repeat it. Huh?
I remember the prime minister of England
taking a pacifist position with Adolf
Hitler and says, "Oh, he's a he's an
okay guy. All we have to do is this,
that, and the other." Right? So, you
cannot confuse passivity with peace
because very often passivity brings war.
I lived through the era in which
passivity brought the death of 70
million people
>> after World War II, you know, after the
world in 1929,
Secretary of State, the new Secretary of
State was Stimson, I believe. Simpson.
We had an intelligence service of course
during World War I
and then it continued after World War I.
and his first day in office as Secretary
of State, the intelligence service
presented its report for the day
to the Secretary of State who said,
quote, "Gentlemen, do not read other
gentlemen's mail."
That cost us another 70 million people
dead. Cost us Pearl Harbor.
I want to clarify that pacifism is not
the same as taking the action that takes
you to peace because peace
takes integrity. Integrity does not
allow itself to play ball with non-
integrity. Right?
Truth is often
the courage to stand one's ground and
say no further, no more. Right? Somebody
asked me that question during the
intermission.
What is the integra's stance?
The integra stance is not to
allow your monastery to be ravaged by
wolves.
You have to protect your monastery.
To transcend the opposites then is to
stop seeing one thing as
one thing and the other thing is its
opposite.
One has to be in a very high state to
see
like death
or makes no difference.
Die by the droves, die singly
because the evolution of consciousness
takes us through these various forms
and you're somersault with them and you
go the way of the Dao or you break. Huh?
When it's time for war, you go with the
war. When it's time for peace, you go
for peace. So what should a person do
about it?
One should hold an integrous
desire for peace
and pray
and then allow
divine will to express itself in the
karmic expression of humankind.
How many times do you have to die in war
before you see it's absurd? A lot of
times apparently
over and over and over again people
choose it. Yes.
over and over again
until people learn that part of
spirituality is integrity.
Integrity means
to stop playing victim. It's not
integrous to allow your husband to beat
you all the time.
Not integrous to allow your children to
be abused. It's not integrous to allow
people to steal from you.
The illusion that one has to transcend
in politics is that other people are
like you.
I got news for you. Other people are not
like you at all.
Other people think you're a stupid
idiot.
The presumption, you see, from
an educated
um
consciousness level of 430
is to presume that other people are like
us. They wouldn't do that. They'd bring
destruction on their own people.
Of course they would. And of course they
would bring destruction on their own
people. We see it over and over again.
The leaders of other countries are not
in the same level of consciousness.
Megalamomania
doesn't care if their whole country gets
wiped out. It's very hard for sane
people to realize the degree of insanity
of megalomania.
Hitler not only didn't care because all
his people got killed,
he thought they deserved it. In fact,
what was left standing, he would have
eliminated if the generals had followed
his orders to burn Berlin to the ground.
the recent dictator out of the Balkans
who's on trial in the UN Court of
Appeals or whatever it is
the same way.
Megalamania is the you might say
the extreme opposite of what we would
imagine divinity would being be.
That which is comes from the lower
astral
hates humans,
hates humanity.
That which is dominated by the lashal.
We have permission to ask resist.
Hates humanity.
Resist.
Hates humanity. So you're going to put
your trust
in a dictator of another country that
hates humanity
doesn't hate you. It hates its own
people.
The megalomaniac is not satisfied until
you are wiped out and also his country.
He wants all of mankind destroyed.
You remember there was an era there
during the communist era when they were
planning the mega bomb that if they lost
the war would eliminate all of human
life.
Therefore
to be spiritual doesn't mean to be
foolish or blind to denial
and sacrifice needlessly.
However, everything that mankind goes
through serves an ultimate lesson.
And we go through the same lesson over
and over until we get it.
You can't hand the keys to the car to a
drinking alcoholic who is also psychotic
and off his meds.
Because you're spiritual.
No folks, it won't happen that way.
Doesn't. So, one of we the lesson those
are one of the lessons we learn along
the spiritual pathway
is that naivity
is different than ign ignorance and
that's different from innocence
and they are all different than denial.
What passes as spirituality is often
denial.
a posturing ignorance
in assumed innocence
which innocence itself does not need to
assume.
Just like humility does not have to
assume the position of pseudo humility.
The goody goody side of spirituality is
available everywhere.
The goody goody side of spirituality
has a big trap to it. Otherwise,
everybody would be enlightened.
It was easy to skyrocket to a thousand.
Everybody be there. We'd all be off this
planet. Turn it back to the dinosaurs.
They knew what to do with it.
Kill each other without being pious
about it.
They were honest.
You look good. I'm going to eat you. I'm
going to kill you. Okay.
I mean, no pretense that uh you know,
he's just an innocent good fellow. And
if we all pray for him, Tyrannosaurus
Rex will become like the rest of us.
Tyrannosaurus Rex will not become like
the rest of us because he's run by
energies from a different domain.
All right? So
part of being spiritual is starting to
become integrous.
It requires honesty and strength. Part
of the spiritual
is the spiritual warrior who stands up
and defends the truth.
Bin Laden is not going to become a good
guy and change his mind.
It ain't going to be
the enemies of that which we have are
enemies because they hate that which we
have and that which we are. Why does the
lower astral hate,
humanity?
It's because humanity has the chance to
return to God and they do not.
those who have chosen
to deny God.
Okay. The hatred that would that emerges
on this planet stems from the lower
astral resist.
Stems from the lower astral. It stems
from that which hates mankind. Resist.
It stems from that which would
like to destroy mankind.
Would like to destroy God.
and destroy all who seek God.
All right? So that should take care of
naivity. You're not exactly walking
amongst friends every moment of every
day.
That which hates God seeks to dominate
and did dominate until the late late 18
1980s.
Consciousness of mankind was below 200.
That which
is hates God let's say
really dominated the consciousness of
mankind the late 19 18 1980s
only now are we crossing over where
integrity has a chance
by turn by by before I turn over the
cards in my checkbook to somebody I want
to see is credit rating
Is that not spiritual? No, that's
spiritual.
Pseudospiritual is, oh, I trust
everybody. I'm sure I can give anybody
my checkbook and the keys to my car. And
I know I can depend on him to return it.
I got news for you. I had to go down
after waiting a month to Cottonwood and
get my car because it was still sitting
in the driveway cuz he was on a bender.
I never would have gotten my car back if
I waited for the goodness of mankind to
blossom through this idiot.
So being spiritual doesn't mean being a
stupid willow.
I say that because people that are pu,
you know, naive wallows get taken.
They get taken and not only not just
financially, they get taken spiritually.
I got a new guru for you.
So that which is dilletterious to the
true pathway
loves to snare the really committed
spiritual seeker. And what's his
downside? His downside is his naive.
Therefore, as a teacher, it's my
responsibility
to get off the sweet willow path
of flowers and hearts and hymns
and get with it that you got to be real
to be spiritual.
You have to be able to accept the
reality of how it is,
not get into pretense.
A lot of prayer is just pretenseful.
You can pray up a storm for being loud.
No, you weren't.
He doesn't want to go where you want to
go.
If he wanted to go where you would you
want to go, he wouldn't be aligned with
the lower astral forces.
You understand?
He wouldn't be he wouldn't be there. So,
all right.
There are things I don't know that I can
share everything I know. So, let's see.
Um, we can answer this resist. Um, the
fact is no.
Okay. Those who have chosen
to deny God, to hate God, etc. are not
allowed to be delivered from hell. It
says
they have chosen hell.
All right. So, there's some serious
spiritual errors that apparently
there's some uh there's some spiritual
errors you really want to avoid.
The energy of the teacher, the guru, can
it advance your consciousness or undo
negative karma? Let's see.
We have permission to answer that. The
answer is yes.
Um, I didn't know that the presence of
the teacher.
Oh, I see. Being aligned. Let's see. Oh,
I see. Being aligned with the it's the
align with God, not the teacher. And
does the negative karma resist? Okay.
Yes. Because one's of one's devotion to
God, one seeks a teacher. And it's
because of one's devotion to God that
then the acting it out within the
physical domain uh releases the negative
karma. That's true.
Um
much of the effect of the teacher is
vibrational. Resist.
Much of the effect of the teacher on
one's consciousness is strictly
vibrational. It's strictly the energy
energy of the field resist. It's
impersonal resist.
It's the
uh the power of divinity through the
vibrational energy the karmic field is
expressing itself. I see in the oh I see
in the uh atmic body resist. Okay.
Yes. That the the energy field then of
the teacher vibrates
one's own
um aura picks it up. I remember
consciously picking it up from the
karmapa. I saw the karmapa once many
years ago and I just got the vibrational
field.
Had nothing to do with the karmappa. Had
to do with the vibrational field but I
caught it at that instant.
You were catching it before too
when we were into the music together.
Divinity is um available everywhere.
The recognition of it as beauty is
a constant opportunity to reach God. One
tunes in on beauty
listens to beauty.
The sound of God is silent.
The sound of God is present at all
times.
Behind the talkingness, behind the noise
is a profound and infinite silence
in which is the presence
so powerful
that one has to resist it in order to
keep functioning in the world. And so
beautiful music like that will take you
right out.
You have to sit down. it takes you right
out of it because of the vibration of
the beauty. Um so in the high 500s it
becomes sometimes very difficult to
function
because one is crying all the time and
every little thing it's beauty just
knocks you out.
You have to stay away from kitties. They
blow you away.
You have to stay away from lovers.
People that are in love. They're
terrible.
One time I always missed the plane. I
was sitting there waiting for the plane
and this couple looked at each other and
wow, you could just see the load there.
I almost did not make the plane.
I had to bring myself back.
Okay. Um,
hell.
Yeah,
there's different levels to hell. I
don't know if I want to talk about hell
today, folks.
Um
uh we can discuss this today.
There's various kinds of hell. There's
different dimensions of hells or
different hells.
The hell that I was in, you still had a
chance. Resist. Oh, thank you, Lord.
I guess if you're even kind to one
simple little beetle, you get to
experience hell but with the chance for
salvation
because I don't think there's much
deeper levels than I was at. Let's see.
We can discuss this resist. Okay.
Uh the level of this experience was
about as low as it gets. Resist.
Wow. And others have to stay there
forever.
Jesus Christ.
People um joke about hell, fool around
to hell. Um and basically people are
scared to death of it and um with good
reason
because it's worse than your wildest
imagination of how awful it can be.
One's worst imagination is merely the
frosting on the top. From there, it
becomes staggeringly worse.
Nor is there any chance of hope
anywhere.
In fact, it even says on the way down,
abandon hope.
That artist
who wrote that, Donnie, I don't know how
he knew that,
but there it is. And it's very very
visible.
Abandon all hope. And when you go beyond
hopelessness,
there is a realm unimaginable.
And yet there still remain that chance
at that level. And I said, "If there is
a God, I ask him to help me.
The next experience was a shining forth
of the presence of God as all us
in sheer brilliance
exquisite
self-revealing
wordless silent
ever present.
The quality of divinity
is stunning.
It is all that is, includes all that is,
and is one's reality.
Uh, beyond time, beyond then or now,
I think we spoke that now is an illusion
the same as past and future. There is no
now any more than there is a then or a
to be.
The reality is an alwaysness
of forever allness. Allness alwaysness
which is one's reality.
The celestial realms are more like that
music. The music takes you really into a
celestial realm.
Heavenly is to be in the exquisite state
that that music takes you to
and never have to leave it.
One can just be in a state of exquisite
joy endlessly
because always is always
until one elects to leave it for some
reason.
I don't know what got me off in all
this. This course guitar did that.
This card did that. You gave it to me.
It's your fault.
I don't like talking about such things.
There are certainly pitfalls and so we
want to be sure and mention them. The
seduction of the innocent. So the danger
of the 500s, the danger of the 400s,
we've already discussed endless
thinkingness,
uh
confusing
abstract concept with reality whereas
where it's actually only an a concept.
the 500s that I've already discussed
with you the downside of the 500s
to get into denial
that all we have to do is be good guys
with Mr. Hitler and he will certainly
keep his agreement with us.
He will not keep his agreement with us.
uh that which is not integrous does not
keep agreements. There's no point in
signing peace treaties with somebody who
calibrates at 90.
He thinks you're an idiot.
I mean, we suckered him in on that one,
did we?
So, it doesn't mean being a fool. To be
spiritual doesn't mean to be a fool.
Let's see.
How does one transcend the fear of one's
own extinction? Yes, that's a good term
for it.
One has to be willing to become extinct
to dissolve into nothing
to no longer exist
to surrender existence itself that's
called for but we won't get that to that
to the last lecture
I don't want anybody getting enlightened
between now and the last lecture
You have to be a card carrying member to
cross the last doorway.
There there is certain confrontations.
So each each you see along the way
there's confrontations and trials.
Spiritual teachings are different. The
teachers and the teachings are
different. And the downside is different
for each of these levels.
You see, if you're over if you're
overcoming fear, then cowardice is going
to take you out, isn't it? This is the
test to see whether or not you can walk
into the bullets and die for your
country.
Yeah, you're going to walk into them
bullets and you are going to die.
That's for sure.
And then you shoot right up here.
When I committed for Harry Kerry, I
remember the experience was
agonizing beyond description. Agonizing.
The pain was far worse than what you can
imagine.
It was horrific.
And with an unstoppable
will
I went through it
and came out ecstatic.
to be on the body was great.
The body was agonizing
and I was ecstatic.
Ecstatic.
Never have to face that one again
to overcome fear. So then the some of
the things that we decry they seem
we decry Harry Kerry let's say
but it was called for.
So I set up a situation in which that
was the only
thing that could be done and save one's
honor and I did it.
Don't have to do it again.
But there isn't any other way.
You have to actually walk into the
bullets and actually die for your
country. You have to actually rip your
guts out and die
for one's faith.
So the lessons of spirituality call
forth then things that seem within the
world quite extreme. We say, "Oh, that's
extreme. Look at all the warriors that
had to die.
How are they going to transcend that
fear of physical death unless you walk
right into it?
You can't pretend in your mind. Oh, I
won't be afraid of giving up my body for
God. Well, we'll see. Chop.
Too late to change your mind now as the
sword goes through your skull.
In a split instant, you realize that
you've just made it. Ecstatic.
I told you about the time that warrior
and myself killed each other.
Man, we really did it too.
Both of us burst into laughter. I killed
him for Jesus and he killed me for
Allah. I mean, it was ecstatic. We both
went out of body and
God Jesus amazing. All right. So, you
got to be willing then to take to go to
considerable extremes.
Your family will think you're mad. They
may call the police, call the
psychiatrist.
That was the function I had back east. I
was a consultant to the Zen monastery,
the Episcopal Dasis, the Catholics
Dasis, the nuns,
various monasteries and religious uh
retreat centers. This
is this guy delusional or is he, you
know, what is his state?
Because once you've got that commitment
to God, nothing will stop you. You see,
doctor, he's going to whatchamacallit.
And I say, well, yes, let him. But then
he'll die. That's true.
The world thinks in very benile terms,
boy, he's going to die of that. And I
said, right.
As true he is.
Is he in a state of ecstasy or is he
catatonic?
Is this a person in high ecstasy or is
this a bipolar manic in the religiosity?
And sometimes it's pretty hard to tell.