I say right now I'm working on finishing
the book called I and
then the book beyond that will have
about a thousand calibrations and many
of the questions that were asked will be
uh in that book
and many of them are frequent you know
what about the white brotherhood the
calibrate around 700. What about Alice
Bailey? She calibrates over 400.
Um, many questions such as that.
Um,
somebody asked me about spirit guides.
I've never really asked about spirit
guides.
Uh,
we have permission to ask about spirit
guides. My feeling is that there are
well-intentioned entities whose company
you've earned uh through good karma from
the celestial realms. What I just said
is true. Resist. Okay, that answers it.
That's most likely what that through
some karmic merit one has the assistance
of uh
uh you might say teachers, spirit people
call them spirit guides.
I only had let's see one such
experience. I think I went to the Monroe
Institute and learned astral projection.
And one time in an older state of
consciousness, I think it was level 12
for those of you who have done
the Monroe uh tapes, uh I was concerned
about something about the future. So,
I'm intentioning
uh a vision about some something off in
the distant future. All of a sudden, a
voice in my head said, "Try living one
day at a time.
brought me back to reality. Uh
the Monroe Institute was an interesting
place. You know, Monroe wrote journeys
out of the body.
Uh a very endearing book because here's
his naive engineer who never heard about
out of body or any such things. And he
starts astrop projecting every night and
having exciting adventures all over the
astral universe.
and some of them amorous. And then he
comes back in in the body in bed with
his wife and he wakes up feeling guilty
because he's had these adventures out
there.
And then Monroe being an engineer trying
to tried to find a huge sound and uh a
difference in frequencies between the
two ears to set up a an interval beat,
you know, and teach people how to go
into an older state of consciousness and
go out of body and all their state of
consciousness. But all of a sudden,
Monroe was a a very nice guy. He's not
dead. And uh but you go there to
Virginia for 10 days. You spend all day
laying on a mattress
uh learning how to
take off in uh various alder states.
I remember one time I took off and uh
then we used to arrange to meet in
various astral universes.
One time I took off. When I came back in
the body I went in upside down
back in the body. In the body and I'm
looking out the back of my skull. down
at the floor and I had to back out of
the body and redock, you know,
>> the thymus stump. Somebody asked me
about
taught by George Diamond and um to
activate the immune system.
It's a useful way to quickly get out of
a bad space. Uh breathe the energy up
the spine to a higher chakra
and do the thymus thump at the same
time. Uh ask God for a miracle.
If you're full of hatred, you got too
much energy in the spleen. So you
picture the energy flowing up the
forget the name of the track up your
spine shashimi or whatever it's called
up to the heart to love one's enemies up
to the throat to speak the truth up to
the third eye to see the truth and up to
God that you surrender all such to
almighty god etc and do the thyus thump
at the same time and it works very good
and if you drink diipsepsy
simultaneously you can't Those
are just quick emergencies when you're
in a bad space.
>> Is it a good idea to use the map of
consciousness to like determine the
level you're at and you have to somehow
find like a reasonable goal to try
achieve?
>> Well, the purpose of uh the map of
consciousness is to give you some kind
of a general map. Um,
energies tend to congregate, you might
say. Well, not congregate, but let's say
uh
prevail, tend to prevail.
We know there is such a thing as the
uh
entrainment. So if you subscribe to
subscribe to something
then to some degree you entrain with
that level of consciousness
on a nonlinear domain and it has a
certain dominance into your thought
stream so that you tend to focus in
listen in.
If the atheric
is full of zillions of billions of
possible thoughts and streams of
thoughts etc. Why do you pick the one
that you pick? Because you're probably
tuned to a certain strata.
That's the danger of
that's the danger of the MTV kind of
entertainment. the danger of
u certain kinds of modern
music
began with I think heavy metal rock came
out of the Mottown sound actually it's a
specific beat which John Diamond wrote
about and your body doesn't lie
it's an an so-called anopestic beat the
anopestic beat which is aligned with the
music makes you go weak with kinesiology
ology.
So that if if your hearing is blocked
off with white sound and ear muffs and
somebody plays that kind of music,
you will instantly go weak and you'll
stay weak for at least 20 minutes
afterwards. So
the entrainment of the consciousness of
young people who put on they they put on
what do you call these machines that
they walk around with their ears on
them.
Anyway, they're entraining their
consciousness not just to the lyrics of
the music because the naive person
thinks it's the lyrics of the music.
Kill your sister, rape your mother, all
that kind of stuff that they think
that's bad. No, that isn't bad.
That's the good part. The bad part,
the bad part is the silent frequency
vibration, the carrier wave.
So all these, you might say, are running
on carrier waves. Carrier waves.
You pick up the carrier wave of that to
which you ascribe.
There's a whole generations whose
con frequencies of the consciousness
dominating their their thinkingness is
drawn from the lower astral
and they'll tell you why did you shoot
your classmates? I don't know. I just
wanted to see what it was like to kill
somebody.
I mean, is that bizarre or what? Huh?
Did that come out of this kid's mind?
No. It came out of a field.
That's the field is dominating his
consciousness. So when you add drugs to
it, which increases susceptibility,
then you add the an energy field which
entrains the brain waves.
And then you have them play a video game
where you rip somebody else's heart out
or kill them or mutilate them. I mean,
you have him do this 50, 100,000 times.
So, he's now a trained, brutal,
heartless killer. That's what he is. May
look to you like a 12-year-old, but I
see what he is. He's not a 12-year-old.
He's already pulled a train killer out
of the astral, which is occupying his
consciousness right now.
So, when he goes out and kills six or
eight people with no feeling whatsoever,
everybody thinks a 12-year-old did that.
No 12-year-old did that. There was no
12-year-old there.
12y old
there left a long time ago and he's now
possessed by an entity that calibrates
at that energy field. So a whole
generation of youth is being you know
brainwashed and trained
conditioned
um to do that which is thoughtless and
uncaring. And
the video games is a new one born every
day. Uh there's a new one called riot I
think or something that's being produced
in Hawaii or some place or China.
Anyway, uh the whole game is to to
become part of a riot and destroy the
city and destroy the town and kill the
people. See, now the game is to do that
over and over again. Well, how many
times can you repetitively do a thing
before it becomes second nature?
Like riding a bicycle. I mean, sooner or
later it's second nature. So,
I forgot what the question was that
brought up that.
>> Can you use a map of consciousness to
determine like an appropriate level of
growth for a person?
>> No, that isn't really what it's for.
It's more like a temperature scale. It's
more like uh how the weather is there.
It's more um you can tell by your
prevailing level of commitment, by your
prevailing view of God, yourself, the
world.
um the process you're going through your
predominant emotional field. You know,
most people can pretty much guess, you
know, where you are.
That's only of academic interest anyway.
It's a shorthand way of denoting
a way of being in the world. A way of
being in the world because each level
has its each level has its lessons to be
learned. Each less lesson each level has
its own gratifications
to commit to a manual project and
complete it is very very gratifying.
Yeah. So whatever the level you're at,
it has its own challenges.
You your challenge might be to forgive
your mother-in-law and love her no
matter what. Even if she is a you know
what.
Well, the shift there of course is to
shift your perception of her and your
experience of her and the your spiritual
commitment is the willingness to see her
differently and forgiveness
and um to stop personalizing it and see
you know she's that way because that's
the way she is. Not because of you she's
that way. It's because she's that way
because of that she's that way.
It's difficult to stop personalizing
everything and putting yourself into the
arena of everything that occurs in this
world. People were that way before you
were born and they're going to be that
way after you're dead. So there's no
point of taking it personally.
They're not doing it for your
entertainment. They're doing it because
that's the way they are. They're mean
and gruff and nasty or self-centered or
whatever you want to think they are, but
they're not doing that because of you.
they're just doing that cuz that's the
way they are, you know. So to quit
taking things personally is uh
means to become detached.
That allows uh your perception of the
person to be corrected. All a sudden it
dawns on you. They're not being that way
with you. They're just being that way
because that's who they are. They're
that way with themsel. Yeah.
and uh
you stop feeling hurt because they're
that way. Some people are gruff and mean
and and horrid
and they don't mean anything by it.
They're just gruff, mean, and horrid.
The nurse where I go to the girls ranch,
you know, there's no doctor around. So,
I start going to the girls ranch where I
got 50 girls and uh one nurse says to
the other, "Don't pay any attention to
him. And he's just grumping today.
Grumping. You know, she's just affirming
your reality. You know what I'm saying?
I get there and I've got to make out all
these forms that the government
requires. She's going to grump about the
government. Sure enough, he did. Godamn
government's always thinking of all the
This is where all the taxpayers money
goes and it's all useless and it's got
nothing to do in this better anyway.
It's just bureaucratic, you know. So,
he's just grumping. That's all. He's not
grumping at you.
I wasn't grumping at the nurse. I didn't
even know she was there.
No, you're just you're just just uh
see that part of the personality which
re gets re-energized in order to retain
in the world, you know, is comical and
uh it just does whatever it does in
response to the situation, but it's not
yourself in the first place. And you can
disconnect from it and discontinue it
anytime you want. It runs on because
society expects certain things, certain
responses. At first, you don't make any
responses and you withdraw from the
world because
there's nothing to say, nor is anyone
really intelligible.
Uh
it doesn't make any sense at all what
people are saying. But
after a while, you learn how to uh be in
the world, and it it's entertaining. And
you don't take any of these roles
personally. They're just all social
roles that pop into the space because
people expect you to say something
that make them happy, you say something.
You know what I mean?
>> How can children be backed out of the
video game training?
>> Huh? How can children be backed out?
>> Oh,
threats,
>> bribery,
no, it's a phenomena. It's a phenomena.
It's it's like um a port hole through
which the lower astral pours into this
domain.
The most open port hole for the lower
astral to this domain is the electronic
media, MTV, the music that goes with
that lifestyle.
Uh the languaging of it, the
invalidation of the dignity of human
life
is uh subtle. U
most adults are concerned about the
lyrics, but it's not really the lyrics.
uh although they probably play a small
part, but um kill your sister, you're
not necessarily going to run around and
kill her because of that. But if your
brain waves become
uh entrained by a lower astral, you
might just suddenly do it because you
felt like doing it cuz you wanted to see
what it felt like to kill your sister.
So the motivation is different than what
people think. They think it comes from
the languaging. It doesn't. comes from
uh suggestion uh brought up by that
energy field. Let's see if what we're
saying is the truth. I mean that could
be long my teeth.
I just said this is a fact is it that's
fact. It isn't the lyrics and it isn't
the specifics. It's the unseen
invisible.
Um
for the same reason any spiritual
teacher or any teaching that you read,
you're picking up a frequency and a
vibration. And uh
if you like Mr. Gdata Maharaj, then
you're probably going to like Ramano
Maharshi as well because they're both in
the SE about 700. And uh White
Brotherhood is probably also going to
make sense to you. So if you're if
you're trained to to hear on that level,
then you'll hear most most things that
are on that level. You'll will make
sense to you. It'll appeal to you. Uh so
the teachers that appeal to you at
different levels are appropriate for
that particular level. Also within
yourself there's multiple personalities
you might say multiple aspects to your
personality, subpersonalities,
archetypes, whatever you want to call
them. And part of you may be attuned to
one teacher and part of you attuned to
another. This one you really get a lot
out of and this one you don't because
you have different aspects to your
personality which is another thing that
puzzles people in their spiritual work.
one aspect of of your life is uh going
well and another suddenly goes haywire.
Well, when you're single, you picture,
oh, won't it be nice the little white
picket fence and the little wife, oh
golly, it's going to be so swell and the
little kids, you know, and then you get
married and settle down and all that and
and and now the duck that comes up
wanting domestic bliss and happiness and
security is satisfied.
That duck goes down, the next duck comes
up. What about the wild wonderful time
all the singles are having out there.
God, he can't wait to get out now and
they hit the road and meet with all the
bimbos and the wild music and all the
crazy strippers and oh boy, oh boy,
bikinis. They're wearing them downtown
and all. And he sees all this lur stuff
on television. He think, man, look what
I'm missing.
Locked up here with the wife and kids.
The ball and chain. So,
he starts flirting with a girl at work,
gets involved,
they have a big fight over it, he
leaves. Okay, now he's got his freedom.
Wow. He's out there. He does, you know
what? Till he's blew in the face, till
he can't do it anymore.
After 12 or 13 different encounters, it
suddenly gets raggedy again. Jesus
Christ. Here I'm all by myself with a
bottle of whiskey and uh she's left and
I got a hangover.
I just hope she's not pregnant. And
Christ that cost me a fortune already.
And
he starts hankering for the little
picket fence and the good wife and the
kids. You see what I'm saying?
though he quits his job because now the
adventurer wants to meet with danger and
he buys a race car and he goes out there
and drives like a crazy 20-year-old
and uh facing danger every day is what
he's all about. So you see how you shift
from one thing the next thing is his
Harley. He jumps on his Harley and you
see how each sat but the Harley driver
the the wild drunken Harley person now
longs for the comfort of a family in a
home right.
Funny thing you know you read these
things like in the paper in the Arizona
Republic a few weeks ago. There's always
some guy cleaning his gun at home that
shoots somebody in the family. It's
amazing.
He shoots his wife or a month ago it was
he shot his three-month-old. You know,
imagine this guy. He's got to first of
all, you got to clean your gun in the
presence of a family member, which is,
you know, severe violation of any kind
of sanity. Now, now, not only that, but
the gun is loaded. Plus, he's got the
safety off the gun. Plus all the objects
in the room, this little bitty thing
about this big, and it's always a fatal
shot. Never blows off their ear, blows
off the toes of a three-year-old. No,
it's always a fatal shot. Instant death.
How does he manage to forget the safety
on the trigger pointed exactly at the
kid's heart and it's only a kid 3 years
old? Kill a dead air in the mackerel.
You tell me how that happens. H.
He was only cleaning his gun with the
safety off and it just happened to be
loaded with a bullet in it and it just
happened. When you think of all the
points in the room it could have hit,
>> it just happened to hit the
three-year-old right smack in the heart.
You know, how does that happen?
That was an actual case about a month
ago.
It's you never never read of a guy
shooting his Harley-Davidson.
Yeah. Cleaning my gun and I blew my
Harley-Davidson right through the wall.
Yeah.
Now they never scratched their
Harley-Davidson. They just killed the
kids, the mother, the wife, the
mother-in-law, killed his grandmother
while cleaning a gun.
Those things make you think, huh?
How high is Harley Davidson celebrating?
mind comes in our life
>> tends to manifest. Yeah. Tends.
>> So if if a if a lot of problems or
difficult situations come in our life,
can we just change our attention and
then get more pleasant things?
>> It's just a metaphysical observation
over the years and rather common to many
that what you hold the mind tends to
manifest. We were surmising that it
could be u that it operates via the
quantum potentiality, the infinite
quantum potentiality
that um what you hold in mind, the
energy of it literally affects
uh the t the tendencies, the
propensities,
the likelihoods within the physical
domain.
You see, because the quantum
potentiality is a potentiality, a
potentiality, infinite potentiality, not
necessarily an actuality, but it's a
potentiality.
So in the physics and mathematics of the
nonlinear domain so-called chaos theory
the likelihood of this uh happening
you see is
a function of
a nonlinear mathematical
we would think within the world of form
probability but as the as You see from
the Heisenberg principle
then
a choice is going to perhaps increase
the frequency with which this this
choice this this actuality manifests.
Yeah. Does that make any sense?
Mhm. It would be like you're increasing
the charge on it. Anybody who's into
spiritual work and tends to hold things
you see and it has to be nonvolitional.
It isn't like you say, "Well, dear God,
I must have a new Mercedes-Benz." You
see, it's more like your love for it.
There's a certain car that I've uh I've
loved. Yes. All my life.
And um don't have to have that car.
Haven't asked God for that car.
>> And brought it. It's a beautiful car.
A 46 Lincoln Continental
>> and uh to me it was the most beautiful
car ever made. It was elegant.
Uh it was beautifully uh proportioned,
you know, great car. And anyway, a very
uh rich man used to pick me up
hitchhiking every morning in one. And uh
and I just love that car, you see. So u
all these years I've you know every once
in a while I'll see something reminds me
of a 46 lane. I've never seen one since
uh on the road, but if one manifested, I
wouldn't be surprised, you know, just
having
uh so it's more like you appreciate it
or um you appreciate its special beauty,
let's say, might tend to make it
manifest
>> like cream,
>> like cream puff.
Well, the places I've found to live over
the years have always been the been
exactly what I was holding in mind. But
suddenly suddenly somebody call up and
say the place right next to me is
suddenly vacant and you're the only one
I want living there. So I said, "Okay."
So I went over and looked at it and I
got it was, you know, a little house out
in the woods right near the water. So
that's just what I had in mind. Same
thing happened back east. Well, I just
thought of a place in the middle of the
woods. Sure enough, it suddenly came out
of nowhere.
It isn't that you're causing it. It's
not that you're causing it, but from
statistical probability or the
mathematics of chaos theory, the
likelihood is increasing as a result of
your observation. You know, that's the
Heisenberg principle that just just
merely thinking about it or observing it
already changes the expected frequency
of a certain occurrence,
but it's done so non-mathematically.
It's not it's not within the capacity of
the differential calculus to to say that
it's a non-statistical
we call it miraculous
the miracle when we say in the course of
miracles if you ask the Holy Spirit for
for a miracle and uh you're already
incre increasing the likelihood of that
happening by the mere mentioning of
and mentioning it. So the Heisenberg
principle which is the crossover you
might say from the world of logic to the
world of nonlinear
non-logical
then is
to merely observe it to merely think it
already has changed the probability.
Mhm.
You haven't caused it but your influence
is the probability. Mhm. What level
would Albert Einstein
Deepak Chopra
reach on the map of consciousness and
Mahatma Gandhi?
Mahatma Gandhi 700.
Uh
Einstein was 499.
>> Deepak chakra I don't know.
Um,
do you have um do you state uh
information about the use of meridian
energy therapies to um
alter break up some of these uh fields
intentionally?
>> I don't know what you mean by meridian
energy therapy.
Um I'm talking about um energy therapies
where people tap on while
>> I'm not familiar with them.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> You see the the level of consciousness
is set up by great many things. One is
karma and the other is spiritual
intention.
uh the degree of devotion, the
willingness to surrender the benefits of
the ego to the unknown benefits of the
spirit which are unless you've
experienced them more of a hope than a
reality and you're taking it uh on faith
from the word of others that
surrendering these um
ego payoffs is worth uh the surrender.
You don't really know yourself
experientially that that's so.
You know, it's like telling somebody if
you give up uh addicted to alcohol
drinking your life will be better. Well,
he doesn't know that that's so. He can
only take somebody else's word for it,
but he doesn't really know because he
has no experience upon which to base
that.
So the level of consciousness then is
really a manifestation of your degree of
commitment and your integrity and the
level of evolution of consciousness that
you've reached. People can make great
jumps in one lifetime.
Uh when we said the statistical average
for mankind as a whole was five points
in a lifetime.
uh you know many people go down. There's
as many as go down as go up and uh
uh and some very extremely well-known
people have gone down. If you calibrate
their level of consciousness early in
their career when they were at their
peak, it's quite high. And when you
calibrated it later, they went down
appear apparently. um power over others,
greed, um the desire for um whatever
followers for uh control of others and
fame or fortune
uh or the seduction of others uh control
of other people's minds.
For some reason, they they fell and uh
their level later in life is much lower.
Uh that happened with Napoleon for one
thing. I think with Adolf Hitler I think
when he wrote mine comp his
consciousness was considerably higher
than it was a few years before his death
and the same happened with Napoleon
Bonapart.
Earlier in his career he was an
integrous military person but then a
victory brought him megalamania. rather
than being grateful for his winnings uh
or satisfied by them it created a
egotistical cravingness. So Napoleon
let's ask if we have permission to do
Napoleon we'll just do Napoleon as an
example you know Napoleon at the height
of his career we have permission to ask
about Napoleon was over 450 460 you know
Napoleon was a very bright guy and it
calibrated a level about 460
that's the level of presidents of the
United States they run around 450 uh
Supreme Court justices uh run in the
high 400s
Okay. Napoleon before he died was over
200 resist.
He went below 200 before he died. He was
over 70, 80, 85.
So from 450 he went dove down to 85.
So
whereas one can evolve spiritually, one
can also succumb.
And um
it's a matter of one's choices. You can
see how success then becomes its own the
danger of success which of course is
well known. Success precedes pride you
know precedes a fall. So to be begin to
believe your own publicity
can lead to one's own downfall.
So Napoleon was started out you might
say as a legitimate military careerist
uh also became a very brilliant
politician and then succumbed to vanity
and egotism
and went down the tubes.
>> Yes. And it happens when
one such as Napoleon that has made this
drop in the level of consciousness
leaves the body then does the
>> you have to make it a short question
please.
>> All right. Does the spirit gravitate
towards then that lower um energy
attractor pattern?
>> I don't know what she's saying. She
said, um, which level would he, uh,
gravitate towards, the 450?
>> Oh, I don't know. Because that would be
a choice you would make.
>> It would be a choice.
>> You're talking about the karmic
propensity as he leaves the body at 70
or whatever he was at,
>> right?
Well, then that would bring us to
the infinite justice of creation. As we
said that the infinite context out of
which all of creation arises is one
karmic unity.
All that happens within
the universe is happening spontaneously
of its own as a consequence of that
which it is.
That which it is,
the operational reality of that which it
is is set up by its own intention, its
own spiritual commitment.
As
you pray with great intensity and are
willing to let go the satisfaction of
some ego
uh benefit for a higher one, your
polarity changes the charge. If you
picture yourself as a little iron
filing, your polarity just char changed
and so did the energy. The charge on
your little particle just changed,
right?
The so-called soul, that part which is
non-physical that leaves the physical
body and determines one's karmic
destiny,
you might say, is like a tiny computer
chip within it has recorded all that's
ever happened, every decision ever made.
And all of that you might say
accumulates as a certain weight and a
certain polarity
uh even within the nonlinear domain as
though it had a design to it so that it
would fit here but not fit there and be
attracted to this but not attracted to
that. So in a giant electromagnetic
field when you turn on the power
everything within that field instantly
lines up according to the power of the
field. If you change the power of the
field, everything in it instantly
changes.
Um, so if you're a little iron filing
and you say yes to God, instantly you're
pulled in this direction. If you say no
to God, instantly you because your
polarity is opposite. So I always think
of the lower astral as people whose
polarity
is the opposite of God. Yeah. So is
repelled. So you see people within your
own lifetime who are actually repelled
by love.
Icky, huh?
There's whole countries where love is
illegal. You can be executed for
exhibiting love by Paul Pots's
government. Any public exhibition of
affection or love was punishable by
instant death.
Actually illegal in the entire country.
What's the name of that country?
Yeah, Paul
used to be
>> Yeah. Right. Okay. Yes. Any public
display of affection or lovingness was
pay you could be put away or killed
>> on increasing serotonin natural versus
unal?
>> I can't hear what you're saying.
>> I can't hear you either. You have to
speak. recommendations on increasing
your serotonin and natural versus
synthetic.
>> You're asking about medications,
anti-depressants.
>> Yes. Natural versus
>> Oh, natural I I have had no luck with
whatsoever. I've tried them all. And
many people who don't want to take
medication, I say, why don't you try,
you know, whatever was ostensively
helping depression at the time. I never
saw any benefit from it. It could be
because in a doctor's office you're not
seeing the mild cases
the you know the mild cases that are
immunable to naturopathic remedies I
probably didn't see because it worked
for them and therefore they never saw
saw me. So what I probably saw was those
cases more severe
where u those particular remedies didn't
work. Huh.
Yes.
>> I notic that some people pray to Jesus
and some people pray to God.
Does it make any difference or
>> what did she say?
>> She said some people pray to Jesus and
some people pray to God.
>> Oh, does that make a difference?
>> Oh, well, I think the intention is
different. Uh or the intention can be
the same. It can be the in the intention
is the same. It doesn't really make any
difference.
I don't think it makes any difference,
but we'll see.
Well, in a way, when you're praying to
Jesus, you're asking for salvation. I
mean, it if if you're praying to the
aspect of Jesus Christ as savior, that
is one thing, right?
uh if you're praying to Jesus Christ as
God manifest
then that's a somewhat different
motivation. Okay, we have permission to
ask us resist.
It makes no difference in which context
one prays to Jesus Christ resist.
It does make a difference
to pray to Jesus as savior
is different than praying to Jesus as
God manifest resistant. H
all right
>> we need to do more research on that one.
>> Oh well it's all right. So intention is
what's making our if we just pray to
Jesus the same as if we were praying to
God the effect is the same resist. Yes.
Because most people identify Jesus as
God made man. So they're really praying
to God. Most people are praying to God
made man resist.
Um
hm
what would be the difference when you're
asking God for salvation
it's different than asking for
enlightenment and it's different than so
it would then the intention would be
whether the the intention is one of
praise acknowledgment appeal
all right so the difference would be one
and the intention resist
All right. The intention of asking Jesus
to be one's savior
is
greater than praying to Jesus as God as
acknowledgement resistance. No.
All right. So the acknowledgment of
Jesus as God manifest is the highest
intention. resist h
we find out all kinds of things we don't
know what they mean
you ask the question
but the inference that we get is the
intention is somewhat different
to acknowledge God manifest as man as
Jesus
and then to see Jesus is as savior is
somewhat different. Okay, there's a
subtlety.
I don't know that in practicality it
makes all that much difference. Let's
see.
From a practical viewpoint, it doesn't
make much difference. Resist. That's
what I suspected.
That's what Krishna says. No matter what
name you might use for me, if your
intention is devo is devotional. If your
devotion is to me as the supreme, I will
acknowledge you by whatever name you
call me. Yeah, that's what Krishna says.
>> You said earlier that we have different
aspects of our personality and I'm
wondering do each of these aspects have
their own calibration level and is our
our calibrable level? you see all all
we've done is is just you know like
found the telescope and discovered that
you can see the planets with it and I
mean you know our knowledge of this is
so rudimentary
it would take a large size class in
which we all divide up various projects
and go into groups of three or four and
each one researches a project
all right so there's the various
archetypes and subpersonalities
all of these have chakras is
right.
All of them have chakras and all of them
have
a karmic
unli
out of which they arose.
You can be more familiar with one aspect
your personality and its history than
others.
Each level, each aspect, subpersonality
then may have a different
karmic source, a different calibrated
level of consciousness.
It could have
um a great great deal of heart to it.
It could have a great deal of solar
plexus to it. It could have a great deal
of wisdom to it.
So each aspect then your personality
could have its own evolutionary destiny
and degree of wisdom and evolution.
Some aspects of our personality may be
quite perfected and others not so
perfected.
Certainly the very fact that we are are
genderized in a animal body
shows either a selection or propensity
or
a karmic choice.
One could after many lifetimes as a
warrior
and a good one. I got everything you
could get out of being the warrior.
Can't go anymore with it.
Choose not to be a warrior anymore
in this lifetime. Yeah, I was a warrior
during World War II, but not really in
the vein of a warrior. I was more in the
um
because there was no fear of death
anymore. I served a totally different
function than in any previous lifetime.
But that pretty much finished off
warrior. You know,
warrior is pretty much gone with me.
But you could decide that your capacity
to be affectionate to children and
family is what's lacking now in your
personality and come back as a woman
next time to try to perfect
those qualities more traditionally
accepted as woman. You know
the caringness for others.
So a person might make choices to
balance out. However, that would not
happen once you reach a certain degree
of enlightenment because you're still
working within form. What you're saying
is you want to perfect the form.
But once you transcend form, there's no
point to perfect it. If I'm neither a
warrior nor a mo nor a mother, I don't
have to perfect either one cuz I'm
that is not what I am.
To realize the truth of that which you
are would really be the ultimate
destination and purpose for all of those
selections to be to feel oneself
complete
to own one's muse and uh pursue music or
art
to own the workman to so all the various
to own the thinker the student you see
you can own all these various roles
within yourself is though to perfect the
personality.
But if you're not the personality,
there's no point to perfect it.
>> Huh?
>> I don't see anybody. Oh, yes. Okay.
>> Um,
now I heard uh after you get past form,
it even gets to a point where uh where
you basically say the body are no more.
I mean, where the body itself will
actually just be no more. Is that true
that you get to such a state that it
would just you would realize it so I
don't know that
he
>> he's saying he's saying that at one
point in enlightenment there is no form.
>> Yes there there's no body there's no
form there just spirit.
>> Yeah.
>> He's asking if that is true.
The body is there as the same as
anything else in the room.
That what changes is is not your it is
not you yourself.
On another level it uh belongs to you.
Not really belongs in the sense of
possession.
It's more like your shadow that follows
you around. your shadow belongs to you
and yet you're not your shadow.
Um
it seems to v have varied at various
times
uh including disappearing as a
experiential reality
and I think I described one time when
I'd left the world for some time and
lived alone in a really an ashram of a
monastery for one person that was me
and forget to eat for periods of time
and it's all there was piece of cheese
and a diet Pepsi in the refrigerator.
That was it. And uh and I remember u
suddenly seeing this form in the mirror
one day and I went into shock. In the
world is that? I thought it was somebody
in the house with me.
I I laughed. I realized it was this body
here. I went back and looked at it.
Another time
I walked through the wall and that
really hurt when you
walk smack into the wall. Just expected
to walk right through it. and was quite
amazed that the wall the wall in this
physicality
interfaced with stunning uh
so there's identification with the body
as though it's not even there's the lack
of awareness of the body there's um a
diminished interest in the body so all
these various aspects have happened
uh it's an entertaining uh uh puppet
kind of accompaniment. It's more right.
I'd say at the present time it's like a
pet.
It's a fun thing. I mean, I enjoy it and
I enjoy it at times, but I mean, it is a
fun thing and um
especially if you get help taking care
of it, so it's not so much of a problem.
You don't identify with it. That's all.
Uh
you see all it's it's very these are not
explic these are not things you can
really explain.
But suddenly there's a shift where all
it is one becomes the context. One is
the context. One realizes one is the
context including including all of the
content. It's not excluding content
because all that is the oneness of all
that is is not only context but content
as well.
So the body is within the content
but it's contextualized totally
differently.
Its appearance or its disappearance is
of significance to other people. To
oneself it's of no significance.
Whether it is or isn't comes or goes is
of really no significance but it is of
significance to others in the world. So
it goes about its destined business. And
I always call it a karmic windup toy. It
just goes about its thing whatever it's
doing. It's talking here today and
without a body you couldn't talk to
people.
You ever try that? Every conversation
with you. So it serves a purpose and uh
it runs its purposeful course which I
think is sort of a to me I sense it like
a karmic momentum
like it's some kind of an agreement and
it was set upon that c set upon its
course. You see a a great ship at sea uh
a great oil tanker u
when you shut off his engine it doesn't
stop its momentum its propensity it may
take it five or six miles before it
finally comes to a stop. So, I always
have a feeling about the actions of this
lifetime that they're like um a karmic u
um
whatever and that it just floats. It
continues on its way through the water
of its own. It's not paddling. It
doesn't wish to go this way or that way.
It just um automatically floats that
way.
We haven't talked today about love, you
see, and we're saving that for another
time.
Uh
we're trying to clear the decks for
love. We're trying to remove
all the positionalities of the ego. Out
of which come the dualities
which
finesse the negativities which block
love
when all the decks cleared before we
even talk about love.
So we haven't talked at all about the
coloration that change the shift of
perception and subjective uh
awarenesses which come about as the
heart chakra opens and the condolini
energy swamps you.
It's better not to be driving 75 at the
highway when it happens.
It's better to slowly take your foot off
the pedal.
Do not put your brake on when the I see
patients, you know, not patients but
visitors from all over the world. And uh
the uh diversity of spiritual experience
is really amazing.
uh an immense diversity of ways in which
people
uh be experience the presence of spirit
within them and the different
expressions.
Some people will go into incredible
states but only under very specific
conditions
uh conditions that are not even logical.
They just don't go into a bliss state in
in the great cathedral. They they go
into it only in a purple elevator when
it hits the 18th floor or something.
Very specific things. I don't know.
Whenever I go in that elevator, I feel
the presence of God. And when I'm not, I
just don't feel it. I don't know.
Almost as specific as that.
Only very specific conditions or
situations.
And other people that comes on
spontaneously, unexpectedly, no warning.
Right in the midst of the most unlikely
activity comes an infinite presence out
of nowhere, unbidden, unasked,
unexpected.
So the diversity of spiritual experience
and how it is experienced, how it's
experienced within the physical body.
You were asking me about the physical
body.
The spiritual work can bring a great
variety of experiences within the
physical body. As you feel the energies
begin to shift, you can feel very
strange and bizarre sensations and
vibrations going through your energy
system, the peripheral energy system.
You can feel incredible energies going
up your spine and up up your back up
into your brain and very exquisite too.
And then it pours down and goes out the
heart and goes various places in the
world unbidden and does
mysterious things all on its own.
Uh then there is levels of consciousness
where
the slightest imperfection in some
aspect of some archetype
out of from some time in place
can bring until it's cleared a very
painful sensation.
Um up to the 600s and 700s it's
extremely pleasant. Beyond that, it can
become increasingly painful
periods of excruciating burning
sensations.
I was very happy to run across the fact
that the Buddha said that the Buddha
said he felt like his bones were cracked
and he was attacked by demons and all
kinds of things.
Um so it's like one pulls up the you
might say the impurities which are now
extremely painful
in a lower energy field uh you can
dislike somebody and feel justified in
fact even happy about it. As
one's consciousness evolves
uh no such imperfection is allowed to
pass.
One may feel a sudden pain in the heart
and you realize that that lady that you
didn't like on the street car is an
imperfection and what about her? Well,
you don't like people that look like so
and so for what reason? And then the
memories come up and then the
forgiveness comes up and then the pain
disappears. So there's also a level
where any imperfection is absolutely
painfully intolerable.
So there's a great many different
physical
kinds of experiences that one can
experience
those spiritual systems which rely on uh
pay a great deal of attention to the
energy fields the chakra systems and the
energy in the various chakra systems
the so-called condolini energy
are following a different emphasis
emphasis.
But in the end, the same spiritual goals
have to be accomplished.
Whether you pull energy up from your
toes to your heart or whether you learn
to love your mother-in-law, it's all
going to be the same. They're both going
to have to be handled. But as you learn
to love, the energy pours up of its own.
I've never really checked out whether
you know to what a veil trying to
manipulate the energies themsel
uh what they're good for.
There's that very interesting book by
Gapy Krishna called condundolini energy.
I think that's the name of the book.
Yeah. In which Gapy
remember in that he he's meditating and
he purposely is breathing energy up the
spine to the crown chakra.
All of a sudden he feels this shot of
exquisite energy but it only hits one
side of his brain.
And after that he's lopsided. totally
lopsided. One side of him behaves in one
way and the other side in the other way.
You know, it's a very funny, interesting
book and very appealing, you know. Uh
so I don't know. I I would think I would
want a teacher pretty well advanced in
manipulating uh energies for their own
sake. I haven't researched that myself.
There are certain specific practices
which I have mentioned which can be
handy. Whether you can reach
enlightenment by just sitting there in
meditative position and picturing light
and energy going up to the crown chakra
or not I don't know.
Such is possibly the case. Resist. Such
is possibly the case. It would be fired
by one's um
spiritual commitment. exist uh the
intention the intensity of the intention
is already such a profound surrender
uh to the will of God that the mechanics
of it then are only the out picturing of
that which has already been an inner
spiritual decision. It's funny because
when I lived like uh in a monastery that
was sort of what my life was. It was
just one spiritual practice after
another and life was prayer and
spiritual practice and meditation and
meditating for 6 8 hours at a time
and not eating for days and
becoming detached from everything in the
world.
uh if you felt the desire to eat, you
instantly let go of the desire to eat
and you didn't eat unless you have no
desire to eat.
And uh I later did a video tape on that
on how to lose weight.
It's simple. Never eat when you're
hungry.
You see, because that's a conditioned
reflex, you know, like Pavlov's bell,
you feel hunger. First of all, you call
that hunger. Well, that empowers it
already is hunger. The way to get over
that is never call it anything.
Never label anything.
And that's how you can fall down and
twist your ankle and by surrendering to
it within minutes get up and walk away
like nothing happened.
You don't call it a twisted ankle. You
don't call it pain.
There's a nonverbal experiencing of
whatever is flowing in towards you and
you let go resisting it completely and
become one with it. As you do that, the
pain leaves your ankle and it becomes
diffused. You could feel the pain in
your whole aura and you completely and
totally surrender to it and you can't
call it pain. If you call it pain,
you're going to suffer.
You call it nothing at all. You just
surrender to the presence of whatever
that is. And within minutes it
disappears and you get up and you walk
away.
And that's how you take off weight.
You don't call yourself you can't call
it hunger. That's labeling it and giving
it power that it doesn't have. Instead,
there's this sensation. What you do is
you lay down and you let go resisting
the sensation just like you do with the
twisted ankle. Don't call it hunger.
That's a whole that's a program.
You lay down and you let go resisting
this sensation. You let go resisting the
sensation.
All of a sudden it becomes diffuse. It's
not in your stomach at all. It's
everywhere in your aura.
You lay down and you let go resisting
this sensation.
After about five or minutes or so, it
disappears.
Then you get up and walk away from it.
whether you eat or not is immaterial. At
that point, you can eat.
The other trick to pull on it is never
allow yourself to get hungry.
Anticipate. What time do you always get
hungry? You get hungry dinner. Dinner
time 6:00, right? 4:30 you when you're
not hungry, you have a piece of cheese
and some crackers.
5:00 you have half a banana. When dinner
comes around, you're not even going to
be hungry.
That you just snacked when you weren't
hungry. Right? So I call that
prophylactic eating. So there's
prophylactic eating and letting go,
resisting it until you've unconditioned
yourself to Pavlov's bell. You see, if
you get a sensation and you label that
hunger,
then you feed it. Now you just reinforce
the Pavlovian conditioning. So every
time you eat when you're hungry, you
reinforce the Pavlovian conditioning.
Consequently, you can't get off of it.
Now you're at the effect of hunger.
You're at the effect of the belief in
hunger.
The wor the best that you can do is
resist it and suffer and feel miserable,
but you're not going to lose weight.
You took off a few pounds, but I'll tell
you in a year it'll be back. So, because
you haven't changed the conditioning.
So, it's simple. Never eat when you're
hungry. Anticipate in advance when
you're going to be hungry. Have
something now when you're not hungry. If
you're not hungry, half a hamburger will
be quite satisfying because you're not
hungry in the first place. Eat two hot
dogs, one half of a lollipop, and you'll
be satisfied.
Now, I admitted our daily menu, didn't
I?
That's how you decondition yourself to
anything. So, those are, see, the Buddha
said, uh, through sense we become
attached. And the Buddha emphasized the
importance of detachment.
To detach means to decondition yourself
means to perceive of it, to understand
what's happening from a different way.
So I'm trying to explain a different
way. Never label it. Never call it
anything. Never resist it. And it loses
its power over you. In that way, you can
go to the dentist and feel no pain. Huh?
They can take off your they could do an
orthopedic amputation and you experience
no pain at all. But the instant you
resist it or call it pain, then it's
very severe.
As they munch on the bone, you can
shrink right through the ceiling. That
comes from resisting it. So,
and when we get to
meditative techniques, we'll talk more
about
the now of riding the crest of the
moment.
The minute you label a thing anticipated
or resisted, you're off the crest of the
moment.
If you stay in the exact moment of now
means you cannot resist anything
whatsoever.
Then
you're in a very high space and you can
transcend vertically in an instant into
a great space. Then you're beyond
suffering. To suffer is to resist the
wave. Huh? Pain is one thing. Suffering
is another. They're not the same thing
at all. You have to recondition your
mind. Pain is one thing. Suffering is
something else.
It's possible to experience incredible
pain without any suffering. And it's
possible to suffer a great deal without
actually being in pain.
So you dissociate the two things.
Suffering is the resistance of that
which is painful. But when you let go
resisting pain, it loses its capacity to
cause you to suffer. Anybody who's ever
had narcotics knows that.
If you ever got had a gallbladder attack
and they give you a shot of opium, it's
incredible. The pain is still there, but
it doesn't bother you in the slightest.
You don't even care if it's there
because it's not you. You're not
suffering from it.
And it's a delightful and miraculous
state. And you can see why opium was
called many years ago or morphine was
called God's own medicine because it
took you out of the suffering.
Uh but the pain still was there.
Um, so it's a dissociating. So pain is
one thing. Suffering is another and
letting go, resisting things is the way
out of the pain of anything.
Any more questions and then we'll stop
and we'll talk to anybody who wants to
talk. And
>> oh, I just love
>> slay everybody.
>> And I want to hear how Mother Teresa and
Gorbachev came to endorse your book.
>> Mother Teresa,
Mother Teresa calibrates at 700. She has
enormous heart
and I experienced the truth of her when
I was uh I went into incredible state
and after that I couldn't practice for
some time but I then I slowly went back
after some period of time um and what
actually happened was very severe cases
came from all over the world I
eventually ended up with the biggest
psychiatric practice in the United
States actually 2,000 outpatient
patients, a thousand new patients a
year. I had 50 employees, 26 offices and
laboratories, research laboratories,
etc.
And I had a huge hospital practice as
well. And into the hospital came the
worst possible cases,
given up by everybody, hopeless, and
some incredible just to witness them.
They'd be wound up in wet sheets brought
in in a
manacles uh from Maryland or someplace
and this uh writhing body would be put
on the floor
and then there was instantly seeing
through the eyes seeing the self seeing
the self of the entity within this
psychotic mess.
Instantly there was like a healingness.
The healingness was of the spirit
within.
And at that point the entity within
couldn't have cared less about
uh the state of the mind body. It like
realized its own truth. And in that
instant there was a healing
uh which was what Mother Teresa did. She
looked into the soul
of the ugly dying
of
what was it they died of in those years?
>> Huh?
>> Leopards.
>> Yes. Yes.
That was what went on.
I have permission to ask that. Resist.
The answer is yes. Resist. Yes.
Precisely the same phenomena. So
therefore, I understood her heart. Um
and so when I wrote her, you know, she
wrote me back and uh and uh there was
like an awareness of the level out of
which uh
her heart was
uh coming. There was like a mut
awareness of heart there. She understood
heart. You know, in the lecture I'm
giving today, I should probably be bored
with it.
Why do you talk about such things?
And they're not necessary. Huh? Because
if you can come through a heart that
calibrates at 700, of course, who needs
it? But that's a different lecture.
We're not talking about the heart today.
I don't want anybody loving anybody to
lecture on heart.
We have to build to that. It's a because
that's the most difficult of all. It's
very hard to deliver such a
discussion because it begins to come up
and overwhelm
you and it's difficult to talk. So
any more questions and then we'll
meet with anybody that wants to say
hello etc. Huh? Or is that sufficient?
Yes.
>> I'm confused about if if my body is a
result of karma running itself then how
am I still to have the spiritual
experiences within this body to
disidentify
>> well because I mean you're not the body
huh so the condition of the body or
whether you identify with the body is
really irrelevant to your spiritual
evolution
we would say that karmically you've
inherited the necessity
by having a physical body to overcome
those residuals from
uh the body's evolution uh through the
animal kingdom.
Everybody here has to learn how to
handle hunger, anger, fear, loss,
defense, aggression because everybody
here has a physical body and for it to
survive certain things then will tend to
persist.
So there is a certain necessity then
that befalls anyone who has a human body
just emanating from their bodiness
itself. Right?
And to correct all those propensities is
what we talked about this morning
because they translate into the
positionalities of the ego and as you
let them go the identification with the
body disappears. When that does, whether
it survives or not is really immaterial.
Whether it dies or whether it gets blown
up is immaterial. I remember because I'd
had that experience at age 12 in the
Navy. Your mind sweepers are blowing up
and falling and going going down in the
tornadoes or not the tornadoes whatever
they typhoon etc. And there wasn't the
slightest fear of anything at all. Just
there was uh I in fact I was in a joyful
state all the time high as hell. And uh
you know if you died great I mean there
was no identification with the body. So
the the bodiness does not hold you back.
It's only your identification with the
bodiness. Just as in it isn't the ego
that's holding you back. It's your
identification with the ego. So you
don't have to un undo or destroy the
ego. You just have to stop identifying
with it as who you are.
Okay. So, we'll stop here and I thank
you all and anybody wants to say hello,
I'll be glad to
tell you.
>> Are you going to calibrate the audience?
>> Oh, yes.
>> Great. What was 8? 130.
>> Calgiate. We have permission to
calibrate the audience. We just There
were 435, 437, 438, 439, 440, 441. Oh my
god, they went up 10 points. Yeah. Let's
see. Let's make sure.
>> No, it was 20, wasn't it?
>> They went up was 340. They went
>> what?
>> They went up 10 points.
>> 432.
>> 431. They went up to 440. 441.
It went from 431 to 440. Nine points.
That's equivalent of two lifetimes.
You know me.
Two lifetimes earnings now.
>> $10. Yeah. $10 for a lifetime.
>> Yeah, we went up 10 points. That's
really nice.