I guess I'm on. It's on, right?
It's on. Today we're speaking on no
mind.
So So
and uh what there is to say about it, I
can't think of
no mind. as she was pinning me up with
all these things. I thought the best way
to become a good Christian is to be a
Buddhist.
Yeah, there's a wonderful Buddhist
community here and a wonderful Christian
community. And uh I always say uh the
way to become a good Buddhist is to be a
good Christian and vice versa because
the essence of truth remains the same
throughout the ages.
And um the novelty of
uh the lectures we give is that um
a means of uh ascertaining truth which
was not before available became
available.
And we then had a way of going back over
spiritual and religious history
uh throughout all of time and um
reaffirming and discovering clarifying
many things. So the books that we've
been writing have to do with
clarification
because spiritual reality is difficult
to comprehend by by the mind
and what's been written about it over
the centuries has sometimes been
misleading. Plus there is a great deal
that is erroneous in what is considered
to be spiritual literature.
And we recommend that exercise where you
go through your spiritual library
and um everything makes you go strong
you put in one pile. Everything makes
you go weak you put in another pile. And
it's quite an amazing discovery.
Sort of weed out the poppycock. And uh
what's the reason for that? It's because
the mind just loves things that are
mysterious, magical,
uh, occult and, um, ooh, ooh, sounding.
And we get trapped by that, the intrigue
of the magical
and confusing the magical with the
miraculous, two different realms.
Uh
so today uh we're really going to
summarize what we've said so far.
The series of lectures has really been
preparatory to become acquainted with
the nature of the ego and it's this and
therefore to disassemble it. And we
started out to do so
the very first lecture which we repeat
every time.
I want you to become aware that
everything is happening spontaneously of
its own.
Everything here is spontaneously
becoming what it is and is not being
caused by anything. There is no cause
within
reality.
the subject of non-duality which has to
do with no mind
which has to do with no mind.
uh
the most basic understanding and it's
the reason it was the very first thing
we spoke of
is the realization that causality itself
is an illusion because the entire ego is
based on the notion of causality.
To transcend the notion of causality
actually is quite a high comprehension
to transcend causality.
Now we asked about that one time. Mhm.
The transcendence of causality. We have
permission to ask this resist is over
996 997 998
999.
Wow. So that would make it a little
difficult, wouldn't it? Because
the ego is based on the concept that
everything is being caused by something
else
and that nothing really can exist
therefore
as it is without being caused by
something else.
So
we repeat this each time because to
merely hear this, to merely know it,
begins to undo its power.
Because creation
that which is manifests by virtue of the
grace by virtue of the grace of its
source which is the creator.
The un the unmanifest
becoming manifest
is
creation itself
the source of every of all existence.
There's only one power in the universe
sufficiently powerful
to account for existence itself.
Each of us comes in thinking well I came
into this world due to the genes of my
parents and because of the whole long
sequence of genes is how we account for
our present existence of the human race.
as you were. Creation is continuous
by grace. Each instant
everything is becoming the fulfillment
of its infinite of its potential.
Everything is manifesting the power of
creation by virtue of its source.
To acknowledge
God as the source of one's existence is
a very very powerful statement and
already takes consciousness
uh leaps ahead.
It's the source of power of the United
States Constitution
which calibrates at 700 the highest in
the world by virtue of the divinity of
our creator. Out of that comes all
rights. All rights of our citizens.
Not by vote, not by
the power of politics, not by arm might,
not by the
force of a dictator, but by virtue of
the divinity of our creator. That puts
it at 700.
Consequently, to try to remove the
acknowledgement
is not really in the service of one's
own spiritual advancement or that of
others.
Which brings us to one of the great
difficulties of mind
and that is you understand that mind
works
on content within a certain context. So
we can shorten this whole trip of
transcending mind which we've tried to
do throughout all these lectures by
disassembling it. And then we finally
get to the core of something we can
address.
We all do letting go. We all do
surrendering. We all try to become
um nonattached to the world. Let go of
versions and attractions.
And this is sort of continuous. It's
also sort of a continuous meditation.
It's really a contemplation
and there's a borderline between
contemplation and meditation in which
you go about through the day
with a certain equinimity because as
each thing comes up, you let it go. As
it comes up, you let it go. As you as it
comes up, you let it go. And just as we
were leaving this morning, the kitty was
missing.
Ready to go. And the kitty's missing.
The screen is over.
Where is kitty?
Oh god.
So it's interesting what the mind does
at that moment. You know, it instantly
detachs from this kitty. All kitties are
kittiness and let go for kittiness will
represent itself. And so I said to
Susan, I I affirm the positive. Not that
he's lost, but kitty always returns.
Kitty always returns, which is a fact.
And so she called Brock and said,
"Kitty's missing." So Brock went, he
lives right near us. Brock went to his
front door and the kitty walked in. I
mean, is there a problem?
What is the problem?
Kitty had no problem. Sat down and purr
and fine.
Everything that presents itself to mind,
everything that every little tool of the
mind, every mechanism of the mind, we're
dealing with content within context.
To see all things as content
within usually an unstated context
is one way to quickly transcend mind.
Mind focuses on content.
The content is a statement, a fact.
Kitty is missing,
whatever. The content then triggers all
kinds of emotional reactions. As you can
see, how can we go without kitty? I
mean, what might happen to kitty? The
dog might get kitty. The raccoon might
get kitty. I went outside. Sure enough,
there's a big raccoon out there. Skunks
all over the place.
Coyotes who will eat kitties.
Dogs. I mean, what are we living in a
zoo here? What is this? Wildlife zoo.
All right.
So the only thing you can do is
surrender kitty who is the content
to God who is the infinite context
and you formalize it by asking the Holy
Spirit
to find Kitty.
Holy Spirit was pretty quick this
morning. Couple of minutes
constantly dissolving content into
context. All right. You'll see that
almost all human error, 90% of human
error, is the failure to define context.
Every night on TV, we see,
you know, rather shocking examples of
literally looking at content and
completely ignoring context
because the truth of content depends
completely on context.
In fact, without context, content has no
meaning at all. cell.
Last night on television, there's some
woman who was a abysmally abused in the
airport going through the examination
line. And night after night, there's
some poor creature there who's had her
wooden leg removed and stripped naked.
And
night after night, there's an atrocity.
Atrocities are committed by these people
who check you out at the count of the
check-in counter. totally missing the
whole point, isn't it? I mean, the total
missing of the intention of the whole
thing is so drastic.
If you're looking for black people, you
don't stop stop all the white people on
the street, do you? You're looking for
white people, you don't stop all the
black people on the street. If you're
looking for men, you don't stop all the
women, do you?
And so we see an absurdity, an absurdity
where the context is totally lost
that people should not be harassed
because of their race as the intention
and then its application becomes the
opposite becomes an absurdity. You see?
Oh Lord. And
so context transforms everything.
When the fire danger is high, which it
was at the last lecture, fire danger, we
had huge fires all over Arizona.
You're not allowed to go camping. Not
allowed to go camping. You can say,
"Well, it's my right. I pay taxes. I
have a right to camp."
But the context has changed.
Extreme fire danger. So I just cite them
as examples we can see every night on
television where ignoring context you
see the absurdity of what would
otherwise be sensible content. Nobody
argues that people should not be
discriminated against by virtue of race,
culture or whatever.
And then what happens to that truth?
That truth then becomes actually its
opposite. it actually becomes its
opposite.
I feel these I think these people at the
check-in counter are on a combined
program to destroy this thing because
it's so absurd. So they they take it to
the other extreme to try and get it
overturned because, you know,
stopping every little old lady who has a
steel pin in her hip is not the way to
find
whatever those elitas or whatever those
people are.
It's not the way to find them actually.
And uh mathematically it was uh
discovered that the chances are
diminished by 6,000 to one by following
our current check-in style uh diminishes
its effectiveness by 6,000%.
So
if we stopped all that, our chances of
finding a real shoe bomber would be
6,000 times higher.
The whole thing is absurd, is it not?
Can you imagine a shoe bomber and he's
going to go to heaven and uh taking all
these innocent people with him? The way
you get to heaven is you wear bombs in
your shoes and you blow up all kinds of
innocent people. And there's people that
buy this as truth.
So the extent to which truth becomes
mangled
when content is taken out of context.
Huh?
It's possible.
And of course it's a big problem in our
current society. Maybe for 50 million
years or 40 million years or whatever
because homo sapien is really a
transitional life form.
Homo sapiion is transitional. We like to
look at homo sapien as the crowning
glory of evolution above the monkeys and
all those things below us. You see? And
now modern man in our own fantasy,
modern man is the most advanced creature
that could be really
will soon be going to the moon. No, we
went to the moon. We still be going. No,
we're going to Jupiter. So, we're going
someplace always to show the advancing
superiority of the human race. Huh?
Let's see if if what do we call current
man? Homo sapien, right? Homo sapiens.
Yeah,
homo sapien. We have permission to ask
this. resist homo sapien is a transitory
uh genus resist transitory
not permanent
man wasn't permanent chromagnam man
wasn't per permanent homo rectus
antustraliathecus
is that right
all those folks back there yeah
cousins
all those cousins back there were
transitory
and we are transitory.
This couldn't possibly be the ultimate
uh possibility of evolution.
Absurdity,
what you watch on TV every night, strip
searching a little old lady with the
steel pin in her hip.
That can't possibly be the ultimate
evolution of consciousness, huh?
I'm glad we got the answer we got.
What have we gotten? This is it, folks.
Oh, wow.
So, how far can you go with an animal
body? I mean, you got an animal body and
you've got this consciousness. I mean,
how much farther can you go with it? You
know, we got the Olympics to see how far
you can strain it.
What can you get out of this combination
of things here?
I've lost interest in eating years ago
or any other activity that it does.
It entertains me and without it my wife
would be floren.
And so I say, "Well, keep it." Cuz
without it, without it, she'd say,
"Where are you?
People
get attached to the body. So
it's inevitable. It's part of the animal
nature to be attached to the body. So
we trace the evolution of consciousness
from its origination up through the
evolution of
life forms on the planet. And the book I
is a dazzling chapter on it.
dazzling chapter
tracking the evolution of the energy of
life as it evolves over millennia over
hundreds of millions of years.
And of course as it does it goes up
through the animal kingdom and as it
goes through the animal kingdom and we
have a physical brain with all kinds of
animal
parts in it which still fire off onest.
Uh and so
where where evolution
takes us, the animal has evolved to the
point where it can think and now it's
becoming spiritually conscious
and that we mark the late 1980s when the
consciousness level of mankind went over
200 for the first time.
In the book I said that marks the
appearance of a new genus homo spirit.
Let's see if that's a fact or my
fantasy. Could be my fantasy.
Um, that is a factor it. Okay.
Homospiritus. Okay. We can't ask about
the future. Uh,
homospiritus. Um,
the the nervous system of mankind can
only go handle calibrated energies up to
about 600.
To push it over 600 is um you got to be
really weird to do that.
It's extremely arduous anyway
to evolve through into lovingness as the
way you are in the world. 500 we
calibrate that 500
lovingness is the way you are. It's what
you become. 540 is unconditional
lovingness.
Not as an emotion, not as something that
goes between yourself and that which is
out there, but it's what you have
become, you know, like the hummingbird
becomes his humming.
He just does that cuz that's what he is,
you know. So, he doesn't aspire to
anything. It's just what the hummingbird
is. What the hummingbird does is just
hum and it sucks nectar and plugs
flowers. It does that because that's
what it is. That's what it is.
The calibrated levels of the 500s then
indicate that that's what you have
become. It's a way of being in the
world.
It's really it then eventually becomes
the context of your life. The context of
your life then becomes
the energy field of lovingness itself
because you've let go all the obstacles.
One of the obstacles
is the mind
as we all know.
Uh under 400s um well under 200 let's
see we have this thing here. Where's our
magical thing here? It works. Wow.
That's the wrong one. Okay. It's always
the wrong one. It's supposed to be the
wrong one. When you turn the light on,
it's supposed to be the wrong one.
That is traditional.
And of course, it's supposed to be fuzzy
like that. You probably think we don't
want it that way, but actually we want
it to be fuzzy
so people can say it's fuzzy. You say,
"Oh, it is." And then you correct it and
everybody's happy. I don't know how you
correct it, but there's some way you
could do that.
If you turn it one way or the other, it
corrects itself. Okay.
All right. So below here we have really
animal problems. We have animal
problems.
The reason we trace the evolution of
consciousness is because when you see
its origin, you stop feeling guilt,
shame. You stop hating it. You stop
fearing it. You just say, "Oh, that's my
little animal.
It's good to give your little animal a
name.
Somebody cuts in front of you. You son
of a
There goes cuckoo again.
Inside of yourself is this invisible
animal named Cuckoo. Cuckoo. very
cuckoo.
From a human viewpoint, it's cuckoo.
From the cuckoo's viewpoint, you don't
make much sense.
You let the sob in front of you. What's
the matter with you? Aren't you a man?
Let's be aggressive. Let's get over our
inhibition about asserting ourselves.
All right, take that so give him the
finger as you go by. Harrah.
I discovered the finger late in life.
It was a joyous moment. Joyous
in heaven in Sedona. I was brought up in
a very uh
dignified uh traditional high episcopal
uh Protestant lifestyle. We didn't use
any vulgarities, crude language.
And uh the naughtiest thing my sister
and I did when we were kids, we had
pianos all over the house because my
family were all musicians.
Everybody was gone. She sat at the top
of the piano. I sat at the bottom. And
she hit the keys. We were both about
this big. And she went pew. And I went
stink. Pew. Stink. Man, we were so
wildly bad. It was just
We used those bad words. We weren't
allowed to use vulgarities.
So that was being awful.
So inside oursel there is an animal.
This animal has its own Oh yes I was
telling you about Sedona. So uh overt
expressions of uh hostility anger
vulgarities
cultury people don't do that in the best
circles and we live in the best circles
in the east. I belong to the most
eloquent club and such things were not.
So here I am in Sedona and I go out.
I'm going out. What it turns out? It
turns out I was going in the entrance.
So I was wrong to begin with. So this
woman comes in and she blows her horn at
me and is very very angry. And all of a
sudden out of my animal cuckoo I went.
I did it.
transcended hundreds of years of
culture, education,
MDs, PhDs, M's degrees,
the ultimate social club. You It's so
exclusive. No, the world doesn't even
ever even heard of this club.
You have to actually live in that
enclave to even hear the club. So
anyway,
it was victorious.
It was a wonderful moment.
I discovered that within my soul. Take
that.
Wonderful. So you can love your cuckoo
side. Huh?
There he is.
So I love this beast in me. He's really
a lion. He's a tiger.
And I love him.
I love him. Here's my guilt monger.
Here's the old monk beating himself with
chains
and he's got a hair shirt. He needles on
his bare knees until they bleed.
You ever done that? Oh, you've done it
in lifetimes. How many people have done
in previous lifetimes? Oh, a lot of you.
All kinds of people. We've done all
those things.
Here you um put yourself out of decent
human uh relationships.
We've done all these things down here.
So, we don't have to pretend they're not
there. Why would we pretend? We pretend
they're not there out of shame and
guilt.
But
that without that animal in us, you
wouldn't be walking around. Huh? You
sticky, you bleed. That's the animal
bleeding, you know, right?
So the way you disappear the dominance
of the animal in you is you own it.
Love it. I love my kitty. If I squeeze
my kitty too hard, he'd scratch.
No, he won't cuz I took his front claws
off.
Scratch me, will you?
H.
So, inside of me there is a mean
critter. No, actually, I didn't do it
out of meanness. I did it to save the
cat's life because I would have thrown
him across the room and he would have
found a fractured skull
involuntarily. He used to do this when
I'm taking a nap. I, you know, and I'm
always cold. I'm always cold all the
time. So, I got about winter time. I got
about six layers of stuff. These claws
went right through, ran into it, and I
picked the cat up and through it. I I
said, "Kitty, we got to do something
here."
I had to get my wisdom teeth taken out,
and you're going to have to get your
clothes. I mean, it's just life, you
know.
So down here, our problem is emotions.
And spiritually oriented people go into
consternation when they find out what's
hanging out in their unconscious. If you
want to know what's hanging out in your
unconscious, read Freud. He's right.
Every negative thing you can think
there, think of is in your id.
It's in there. It's in your id. And it's
repressed because you have a conscience,
which Freud call the super ego. You feel
guilty about it. I don't want to kill
anybody. It's the last thing I'd ever
do.
Anybody who says that is a killer. Watch
out. Of course, the unconscious wants to
kill people. When somebody cuts in front
of you,
you'd like to kill them.
So after a while, you see, as you admit
your animal by owning them, learning to
love them. How do you get an animal
trained is by loving them and training
them, right?
Not by locking them in a box and
pretending they don't exist.
So your animal is legitimate.
If it wasn't God's will that you have an
animal body, you wouldn't have one,
right? So the nature of creation is that
we're evolving through. So we have the
remnants of animalness.
The spiritual people call that ego. H
this part then has to do with negative
emotions.
When we start to get okay with it, we
have the courage to look at it, face it,
and we start going into integrity.
These energies here in the low 200s have
to do with attitudes.
Uh letting go positionalities, a
willingness to dig in, the willingness
to deal with the problems of being a
human and accepting it so that we arrive
at some kind of peace about it.
So at first we're dealing with
animalness, right? In our evolution,
we're dealing with all this animalness.
Uh, greed, of course, greed is the
runs the big corporations and
hits the headlines all the time. So, if
you don't get over the solar plexus, you
end up on TV that the world is peed off
that you took 500 million and left all
the widows out there just penniless and
the world takes a dim view of that. So,
the solar plexus takes off with you.
So this has to do with learning
doingness. This has to do with Sanskrit
called rajas action activity.
These are the builders of the world.
200 and up builds the world.
Designs the factories.
Sets up the commerce.
Runs the trains, the airplanes. And we
get up to the 400s
which is the dominance of life by logic
and reason in which education becomes
profoundly important in our culture.
Education is
probably the most important aspect that
we strive for. People go without all
kinds of things for education.
And then so
they go without all kinds of things to
develop this because the 400s are far
more powerful than all this. You can be
mad as all hell and nothing really
happens in the world. But you get up to
reason and logic redesign the whole
highway. You know, elect the officials
you want, learn how to raise money and
uh politics and etc. So the 400s are
very powerful
and
groups such as this one here are usually
quite ariodite compared to the rest of
the world. This is an extremely ariodite
group. I mean this is probably onetenth
of 1% of the world's population here or
less
that gets up to the 400s and then in the
400s becomes interested in spiritual
reality and begins to study it begins to
read all the great teachers. So
inspiration
together with the intellect
then we find oursel in the 400s.
So the reason and logic then serves us
well. Serves us well. Increases our
power enormously.
You can manipulate with a computer, but
it would take 100,000 people a month to
accomplish
in one second. You can accomplish a
greater amount of work in one split
second than uh a large percentage of a
whole subcontinent. If they worked all
day, hell every day couldn't accomplish
what you can accomplish because symbols
now become the great power.
So reason and logic which is in the
400s, the 400s are very very powerful.
They dominate the world right now. They
dominate civilized society.
The 400s which then
give you the intelligence to begin to
see the truth of spiritual realities,
the capacity to read and the value of
spiritual education
now becomes as you get to the top of the
400s,
what was an asset now becomes an
obstacle.
The 400's got you here and now you're
stuck with it. You're stuck with reason
and logic
and the constructions because the mind
takes positionalities
out of that positionality it
automatically instantly creates duality.
So the lecture today our purpose is to
see how can you transcend
duality.
classic pathway
let's say of Zen and various types of
Buddhism and monastic types of
meditation are to transcend the mind
altogether to experience another reality
directly
and the various techniques about which
I've written about which we've lectured
and which all of you have studied
certain realizations seem to potentiate
that transformation that transcending
the limits of the ego so that instead of
being an obstacle, it begins to serve
you. Certain things merely to hear of
them already begin to
exhilarate one's progress.
If we say nothing is it's not possible
for anything to cause anything else.
Everything is manifesting its infinite
potentiality by the grace of creation
which is continuous.
Just that just that knowingness that
thought is already powerfully
transformative. Let's see what the
calibration of that thought is. I don't
know
has just spoken. We have permission is
just that is over 800 850 900 920.
Okay. The thought has the power at 920.
That's the level of truth of the
thought. To merely hold it in mind then
and to give it a certain reverence which
we give to all truth
then empowers that thought which then
sort of goes through your mind and
cuts off a whole bunch of circuits.
See what I mean? You you like let it
loose in this
sincial nightmare we call the brain. And
it runs around on its own now and begins
to disconnect switches.
Because if causality is not what
accounts for
that which is
then the mind automatically increases,
expands its context and begins to try to
sense what it is.
All that we look at then is content.
As you mature spiritually, you look less
and less at content and look more and
more at context.
One begins to sense the field in which
that thought is occurring.
Again you see as you expand context the
context itself is limited by certain
definitions and you start letting go the
definitions
eventually context becomes
the infinite presence out of which
entire universe manifest
the unmanifest manifesting itself as the
manifest which is the source of creation
in which we experience existence.
The only possible source of existence is
divinity itself
and out of this awareness
and moving up into the heart where you
begin to see the beauty of all that
exists because you stop thinking about
it. When you stop thinking about it, you
see the beauty of all that exists.
So through the doorway of beauty
and the letting go of thinkingness
because
you're branching out your awareness to
the field instead of the content of the
field. One experiences the presence
the presence of divinity which manifests
itself as existence.
There is nothing has the power to bring
about existence from nothingness.
Once you take away causality as an
excuse, a rationalization,
causality is the ego's last
hold.
The e the Buddha defined it as the law
of dependent causation or something.
And that law is at 996.
What we're talking about today
calibrates at 998.
Nothing is causing anything.
Everything is being continuously sourced
by a continuous presence which gives it
the power to manifest its infinite
potentiality as that which it is.
So the hummingbird
as his wings go down does not cause the
next thing of his wings going up which
does not cause the next thing of this
wing going up.
The source of this wing movement is
exactly the source of this wing movement
is exactly the source. It is a
continuous source. And what the source
does is empower the potentiality to
become manifest
as existence
which we then witness as life.
Is that clear?
Of course it's clear.
Everybody here gets it and understands
it
there. Some people don't realize that
they understand it. That's all. And I
want to remove that obstacle. Everybody
here knows that or you couldn't exist.
How could you exist unless you came into
existence? I mean, it's a stupid
question, isn't it?
The source of existence obviously is how
come you exist?
Yeah.
It's a kindergarten thinking and too
much for advanced intellectual people
like us to get.
Yeah. The only way you can be here is
because you are here. Oh wow. Let's see
if that's a good one, Susie.
Let's
see that is over 9989.
Okay. So that is what they need to know.
All right. So that knowingness is
present within you. Latent but after
this morning no longer latent. It's
vibrating in everybody's aura right now.
So that knowingness is there forever.
Well, that should take care of this
morning's lecture, folks. Bye.
The pathway of duality then is is called
no mind.
No mind.
Um in this experience which occurred
within
it wasn't called no mind because there
was no mind mind to call it no mind.
I learned about no mind many years
later.
Because to reacquire mind is a project.
It is not easy. And uh most people who
don't have any mind left uh leave it
that way and we don't hear from them
again
which is frankly the best advice. I
think
the best thing to do when you go into a
blitz state and realize that love God
oneness and that which you are are one
and you're immobilized in that state.
Resist the temptation to reactivate the
body. That is my advice.
However, you may have had a prior karmic
commitment about it, but which may pull
you back in, but
so the condition of no mind.
Somebody was asking me this week, yes, I
want to answer some of the questions
that came up in the office this week. Uh
h
somebody said um
what did he say about no mind? I can't
remember what he said about no mind.
Oh yes,
it was a funny question. Uh if it's the
silence that teaches, then how can you
teach silence when you're talking? Oh
yes, this had to do with an interview
with Ramano Maharshi.
uh but Marshie in response to a question
had said
that the teaching happens as a matter of
silence.
So this person wanted to know how that
could be.
It's because the silence is always
present.
The talkingness does not eliminate the
silence. It distracts you from it.
But the silence of the energy of the
field itself transmits.
Everyone within this room is sharing
that
with we're all sharing it with each
other because we're all just one. Yeah.
And so the oneness of that knowingness
is sufficient.
So while Raman Maharshi is chattering to
you about something because he's got to
amuse this visitor because visitors are
very verbal. He's got to say something.
This guy came all the way from Cleveland
to see him.
So Ramana looks at him and he's busy
eating his porridge on his palm leaf or
something and uh that was the
transmission. Then the seeker says mama
and Ramana says yeah yeah. So the goes
away feeling happy. He said this Roman
said that but that had nothing to do
with what happened. Huh? See,
so no mind then is silent.
No mind is really nothing but the
realization of the ultimate context of
one's own existence.
So
the content the content then is your
existence.
We said that there's content meaning
comes out of content but only only
within a context.
So then let's take as a proposition for
the content your own existence
and
what is the ultimate context of your own
existence. Huh?
I don't agree with u Mari came up
questions in the office. I saw some
visitor this week
uh because of his um
uh instruction to
ask um always continuously as a
continuous contemplation. Uh who am I? I
don't agree with who am I
because who makes you look for a pronoun
looks for
you see it's already a limitation. A who
is a limitation. So, you're looking for
a who, you know, and there ain't any who
ain't a who there. And you're looking
for a not who.
You're looking for a not who. You find a
who, that ain't it.
You're looking for a condition. A what.
The sense of self within one within
is a whatness. It's an isness. It's a
condition.
And it's also
the most powerful sense of I that can
exist.
It is I. But beyond the pronoun I. So
I'm always afraid if people say, "Who am
I?" They're looking for a pronoun. A
pronoun, a self-def.
And it's going to take them right back
into the ego's definition of who you
think you are.
The infinite stillness behind Whatever
sounds we hear in the room
is yourself.
Without the infinite stillness of
yourself, you wouldn't be able to hear
anything.
Without the infinite
context of nonform, you would not be
able to experience form.
Because of the voidness of
the presence, one experiences form,
experiences existence,
is aware of what the mind is up to.
So we don't want to be scared of mind.
We handle mind the same we did the
animal.
We love mind
not our enemy.
took evolution
billions of years to develop this
incredible
uh thing here
which I know because I want to realize
the presence of God now becomes an
obstacle.
Got all the way to Mars and now how do
you get off the place?
Here we are folks
without this you never get to Mars. Uh,
what do you do once you get to Mars? You
try to figure out how to get get off
Mars. That's what you do. We got enough
gas left, Susie. I don't think we can
get off this place.
All right. So,
whether a thing is a deterrent or a
tool, whether it's an asset or a curse
is all dependent on how you look at it.
If you love all this stuff here, you
have a good time with it. I had a whale
of a good time giving that lady the
finger. I mean, it was wonderful. I just
found that beast in me and he just wow
I can be completely detached you know
this morning the cat's missing release
on the cat lots of cats nothing want to
come along
cats are a diamond dozen
well one time we did that I think in
front of the audience we'll just do it
again take care of the kittyh
we have permission to ask about kitty
there's only one orange kitty in
reality. There's only one orange kitty
and it's
the tractor field exists within the
animal realm and it manifests man, you
know, manifest serially as thousand
millions of orange kitties, but it's
always the same orange kitty.
Same orange kitty just back in the same
body. Same. You notice all orange
kitties have the same nature. They're
all the same. So anyway,
I let go of orange kitty and uh so that
was here. See the willingness to do that
and accepting that maybe kitty is gone.
The reason tells me there's going to be
a lot of kitties and I love that kitty
and I love the next kitty and the
realization of all the truth of this
brings me joyfulness and peace. And in
that joyfulness and peace I said the
holy spirit will uh ask for a miracle.
And Brock said uh you can down here. So
there you are. You see, you go through
the whole all the way down, you know,
all the way through the whole thing.
Um,
so you transcend the limitation of
content
by energizing your awareness of context.
Context. Out of the context, energizing
the context arises the miraculous.
Kitty appears and I walked up to the
bathroom door and she opened the door
and she said there's kitty.
So in the sequential
world of perception then that was the
moment of
crying with happiness right everyone's
happy
if you hold in mind kitty is lost
now you're giving power to kitty is lost
you understand
no kitty's not lost kitty always returns
home. And if kitty doesn't return home
in this physicality, orange kitty will
get impatient on the other side and
energize another orange body. I'm going
to be right back. When you hear it
purring, it's going to be the same
kitty.
Let's see if that's so
permission to just It is the same kitty.
I'm just It is the same kitty. I told
you that
somebody there had a doubt. Now you made
me go do this.
And of course, we've done the lovingness
of the kitty's purr. Everybody's seen
that. Anybody not seen the calibration
of the kitty purr?
We know kitty purr. We'll just do it for
those who have never seen it. Kitty
Kitty's purr is over 480, 490, 500, 502.
Kitty's purr is 500. Isn't that
miraculous?
In a world where they strip search old
ladies and
take a baton and whack on their steel
hip replacement,
did cats have a heart at 500? Would
Orange Kitty do that to her? No.
Orange Kitty wouldn't make a poor old
lady strip search and bang a baton
against her steel hip to make sure
that's not a bomb in there.
My god, there's a good plan.
>> Hey there, Bin Laden.
Anybody know how to get Bin Laden on the
internet? Put bombs and old ladies steal
pins in their hips.
They blow up and so does the whole ship.
You kill all those Americans
for God.
Oh boy. Insanity.
So, we don't have to get depressed about
the human condition because this morning
uh we got this is just a phase. This is
um you know we're like Cro-Magn man.
We're like u Pilttown man. We're like
they all got these great names.
Australian
erectus or something. Is that right?
>> Australus.
Popus.
Ostraopus.
Anyway, we're the current expression of
where this line of evolution is going.
So we can take that then instead of
feeling sorry for ourself. Okay, we
could accept that be willing to serve in
a way then as
a species we are serving God in being
that link in the evolution of
consciousness.
No, we're not the link. We're the
expression of the link. The evolution of
consciousness goes on in the
non-physical domain and then
sporadically expresses in the physical.
That's why evolution is sporadic. See,
evolution,
the monkey doesn't get smarter and
smarter, become a co-magnan and a PhD at
NAU, you know.
Now, he gets off the bus here and then
the main line can go to the next bus.
So, we come off like this. So, here we
are.
Homo hystericus,
homoabsurdus,
homol ludicrous,
homopatheticus,
homo funniness, hysterical. I think
humans are funny.
Anyway, you get up through here. You
see?
So, our job then our job. So as we
evolve our consciousness, we're doing it
for all that follow us. It wasn't for
Neanderthal man, we maybe we wouldn't be
here.
I don't know. I never asked that. H
let's see. We have permission to ask
that resist. Um
they serve by they served as a link in
our own evolution. So did Cromagnum man
all these people all those ones behind
and we serve in the same sequence we we
are serving just like Neanderthal man
served and um he calibrated around 70 or
something like that I think 70
called Magnan man Pilton man the one in
Germany is that Pilton man who's from
Germany
>> Neanderthal man yeah okay all right so
it's like we're part of an evolution
then
and then by willingness and grace we
accept our role in this evolution of
consciousness.
So we don't have to be resentful or
angry. Let's say we serve God then by
merely being a human being. Huh? Let's
see if that's so
we can ask that. Is it we serve God
merely by living out the life of a human
being to the best of our potentiality?
He said, "Oh,
so there goes a lot of guilt." Right.
The reason I gave her the finger God is
I was trying to evolve my consciousness
to overcome my fear of being assertive,
overcome my Protestant inhibited
background.
When I was a boy, I was very religious
and I was scrupulous. Scrupulous.
The thought of doing that would just oh
my god, you can't go to communion
tomorrow morning. The thought of putting
your finger in there, the doing it of it
would be just too horrendous to even
admit to the priest. Oh, father, have
you sinned? Oh my god, I I gave a woman
the finger the other day in Bash's
parking lot.
That's at least 50 Hail Marys and 120
our fathers. And
oh wow. We have angelic nature on one
side
and that uh animal on the other side.
And here we're balanced then between the
sort of the evolution of homospiritus.
So we we we are we are a signal um
documentation of evolution at this
point. So we are so we we are part of
the
sundereto
spiritus was it? Yeah, that's who we
are.
If we weren't homosspiritist, nor would
we be in this room. Yeah, we are
homosspiritist. That's a lot different
than cro-Magn man. A lot different then.
A lot different than lots of people who
are still on the planet.
They should get off, shouldn't they?
So on the planet then we have a whole
mix from the very bottom. We have some
humans that are uh calibrate lower than
animals.
Lots of them. They hit the headlines
every night. Serial killers, butcher up
little children, etc., etc. They always
claim they're innocent, too. That's one
mark of guilt.
They all say they're innocent. The DNA
is all over the wall, all over the kid,
all over the car, and his fingerprints
are everywhere.
I'm innocent.
Oh well.
So on the planet at this time then we
have the whole galaxy of evolution
all the way from the most horrendous
to the most beautifific all the way to
Buddha Jesus Christ Krishna all the
great saints
Mother Teresa
all the names that we rever because they
document
where consciousness has evolved what
they represent what represent
What does Mother Teresa represent? We'll
get to her next next next talk.
She'll have to wait till next time.
>> She represents unconditional love. The
heart at 700. Wow. Wow. Wow. Capacity.
Unconditional love.
All right. So as consciousness evolves
into the higher energies of lovehuh a
lot that the ego was involved in when it
was when when ego when ego is dominated
from down here it's content what you're
laying in bed at night thinking about is
totally different than when you put it
in the context of lovingness
in lovingness. Now, if you're still
annoyed with somebody,
you try to see it differently because
dislike, hatred, regret, resentments are
no longer pleasant. They're painful.
They're like a splinter. And uh when
you're angry, uh you don't mind it. You
know, when you're angry, when you're in
a lower energy field, that which is
non-integorous doesn't bother you.
They're all cutthroats.
That lifetime I've told you about,
they're all cutthroats.
Good fellows.
Ask them to kill somebody, kill it just
like that. I mean, he was a slow guy.
No question about it. As you evolve in
consciousness though,
now you can't tolerate the non-integrous
anymore.
uh your old pirate uh shipmates are no
longer welcome in your life. You know,
they try to come back into your life and
you say, "Well,
my life is taken a different way." You
know what I mean?
I just don't feel like going out and
killing and raping anymore.
What's happened to all day, man? You
lost your spirit, boy.
I thought we were going to hit some
waterfront dive and get into a brawl,
man, and the broads and, you know, knock
a few teeth in. You know, they used to
do that. I mean, even in this lifetime,
World War II, you know, I was on a mind
sweep. The biggest fun was you'd hit
short, you'd hit the bars, and uh they
called me shorty. In those days, people
weren't into political correctness. If
you're a short, you're they called you
shorty. If you were a chunky, they
called you a fatso. If you were black,
they called you black.
Nobody cared about it. It was part of
who we loved each other for that. But
pock was a pock. He loved being a pock.
I mean, we all just were who we were
with each other, you know. No, it's not
right. But
what they like to do was go ashore and
drink up a storm and uh start a brawl. I
just wasn't into brawling. You know what
I mean? Even at that point in my life, I
was just was not into brawling. And uh
but you also have to have a macho image.
So you can't look like you're a coward.
So how do you get out of brawling?
Well, you if you're not a very good
brawler, they say, "Shorty, you stand
over there and thenop
wop." That's what they did. You know,
stand out of the way.
Anyway, that's not exactly what you're
into. And we've said before, if you take
a waterfront dive, you clean it up, new
owner puts in new carpets, puts new
drapes, puts new lighting in, paints the
whole place, makes a nice new sign. He
opens up a month later, none of the old
crowd goes there anymore.
You've changed the energy. You've
changed the energy field.
So, as we become more integrous, then
that which is less than integrous, we
can no longer tolerate.
There's a a certain field where you get
there's a certain level of lovingness
here. A certain level of lovingness here
where you can't see anything except
innocence and lovingness. You can't you
can only see people as being innocent
and loving.
And you loan your money to uh crooks.
You loan your car you loan your car to
car thieves.
Your analyst says you're in denial about
the negatives of life
and you think to yourself, "What
negatives?" You know, I don't know what
this guy is talking about. You say,
"Well, he's probably of a lower
consciousness. Oh, he he sees negative
things in people." Well, God bless him.
Dear Lord, please help this man's
spirit. So, he sees the pure innocence
of all this. Right.
Well,
you you see you're looking at the self,
but your physicality is in a physicality
in which you can get hit by the bus.
So, the error is to mix levels. Mixed
levels.
I told you when I talked about the
course of miracles, trust your brother.
I have my doubts about that one.
Cost me a couple hundred thousand
as a matter of fact.
And so I have question about that
particular lesson. The rest of rest of
my girlfriend
we become less and less able to tolerate
the non-integrous.
Now sometimes the non-integrous u are
relatives or somebody that you have an
investment with etc. And now you've got
to transcend the attachment to that. You
know why? Because
the non it's not that the non-integrous
themselves are dangerous to your life.
It's very unlikely they will be. I mean,
so they take away all your money, you
know, in the space I was in. I couldn't
care less. You want all the money, take
it. I used to put a bag of money by my
front door and doesn't have money, there
is some. Help yourself.
So, it wasn't that. It's
if something is non-integrous in your
life, what happens is it it's a doorway
through which the energies of that which
is non integrate integrous now have a
play with your life. So it's more that
you want to plug up the hole the leak.
It's that they're a leak and through
them come all kinds of things. Your
bricks fail,
battery goes dead,
the ceiling begins to leak. You wonder
where the hell is all this coming from?
It's the energy field then. So, you
know, Jesus said to avoid that. Avoid
that. Don't oppose it. Pray for it.
People that are evolved see the
innocence behind it.
You can see the innocence behind it and
still decline it. So that is the
balance.
So it's a matter of balance. It's a
matter of the third eye of the Buddha
really to see
that that is non-intigorous. At the same
time it is innocent.
At the same time
you can't allow it to walk around the
house.
You can love the cobra for its intrinsic
beauty, for that which it is, but you
can't really let him run around the
house. Why? Because you're going to sit
in your chair someday and the forget the
cobra is there and goodbye. There you
go.
My mind is also a comedian. It's always
thinking of funny things
and I have to stem that. A cobra bite in
the tail is always fatal. you know the
leg it's okay but and the cobra bite
there is goodbye. So you can't have a
cobra in the house because you might sit
on it and uh so that would be an
unwanted result. So the non-integrous
brings into your life the unwanted
result and it does it innocently
by nature of its own energy of which it
is unaware.
It isn't that it's hateful, vicious,
destructive. It's just that this dog has
fleas.
I love Rover, but he's got fleas, folks.
And when you get fleas in the house,
anybody ever get dog fleas in the house?
>> Oh, boy. There's something getting them
out. One day, I had a cat that got into
the fleas. And it was like six months of
fighting fleas. It was
You wouldn't guess how I finally found
him.
Anyway, the fleas had gotten into the
rug of the car. So, I The house is
sprayed and exterminated and two weeks
later there's fleas in the house. Where
the hell they coming from? They're in
the rug of the car.
See, once it gets in, it's like fleas.
The way I found out
anyway, I found this last the last flea
in the house. I found out where he was.
So in the evolution of our
consciousness, we go through really diff
I think quite difficult and trying
periods.
Even lovingness itself, you see, has a
downside. When you see everyone is
innocent and loving, one day your car is
missing from the parking lot.
Now at that level it doesn't really
matter
in that state of consciousness. Cars
come, cars go. Big deal
in the physical domain. Insurance will
pay for it. I mean it's a nothing
really. It's a nuisance. You got to rent
a car and all that. But you you're
failing to see the meaning of it that
you allowed you allowed that opportunity
to be there by allowing something in
your life that you really don't need to
be there. It isn't that you can't live
it through. It isn't that you can't
overcome it. Of course you can.
Insurance will pay you. You'll get
another car. So what do you lose? You
lose time and energy. You've lost time
and energy.
and you've been distracted from
something that might have been more
beneficial to the world and society and
yourself.
So we're talking about sort of subtle
things for because people are seriously
committed you know have really lots of
strange experiences and I think sharing
them with each other is very beneficial
and um the books I've written have got
reach sort of extremely wide
distribution. We get all kinds of
letters and phone calls and emails and I
mean it's a torrent of communications
and a lot of them include
um you might say to the you know
oddities of human behavior
things you don't read about you don't
see them in the movies you don't see
them on television but people have
subjective very different kinds of
experiences
and uh you know in 50 years of
psychiatry I've heard everything but
Since I wrote this book and I started
getting mail from out in the world
there, there's more things that I never
even heard about as a psychiatrist. I'll
tell you, strange dislocations between
spirit and body. U strange alterations
in consciousness.
people be they they fall into the
so-called cities for a while and the
miraculous begins to happen all over the
place and
they find their consciousness can affect
electronic equipment and there's all
kinds of strange things and they don't
know what to make of it. I always tell
pe I always tell them it's best not to
mention this to anybody frankly
read up on the cities it's there in the
Sanskrit literature it's classic
but I really wouldn't confide it in
other people and when I went through
that period frankly I didn't or the few
times I did I wished I had and um
besides people the ordinary people that
around you um won't even see what you're
seeing anyway so
Um because you're living on a different
uh level, vibrational level of
consciousness, you might say, and they
don't even witness what you witness.
And the lady um gets up and walks away
without her cane. You say, "You see
that?" She said, they say, "Well, she
she didn't have a cane before sitting
there." So, what can you say about such
thing? Nothing. A lot of these
phenomena. So that's one positive reason
for becoming associated with other
people that are spiritually committed.
In the old days classically we left the
world we joined our spiritual community
and such things were well known
documented. They've been known for
centuries. Now we tend to be more
isolated from each other. We meditate by
ourself although we attend meetings and
all. there isn't that constant
interchange of communication.
Um so we need each other's support in
ways that are not so easily obtained in
today's world. Although I think you know
the internet which I don't understand at
all but there are like websites where
people talk to each other about these
things. So there is that need for
communication these phenomena in your
life.
Many things are not comprehensible until
they're recontextualized.
Huh? So when we say where are we in the
evolution of consciousness and we pick
out where we are and we see that we're a
part of an evolving species and in
probably 10 million years or less than
that we're going to be replaced by
something. For one thing, we'll have to
have a better nervous system because
this human nervous system is only
scheduled to go up to 600. At 600, the
state is one of bliss. As you go up into
higher and higher lovingness,
the these stages here, you can't stop
crying. Everything, two people look at
each other, a mother looks at her child,
and instantly you break out in tears.
It's just you can't. Or music. I've got
some music. We hear this tape we play
and at the end of the one that Brock
Brock at the buy back at the end of that
tape uh put some beautiful music which I
can't handle because then that music
starts I wouldn't be able to lecture you
you instantly break out into tears
because in beauty and incredible sense
of the presence becomes overwhelming and
it wipes out all functioning in the
world and therefore spiritual
communities serve a very very valuable
service because within that community
it's safe to share. I'm talking about a
legitimate uh spiritual community, not
some of the sort of bizarre encampments
that occur along the roadside someplace.
But those which if you calibrate them
are antigous
that state of lovingness then becomes
the new context in which
that lovingness then becomes the context
in which content now takes on a
different coloration. So you could look
at context almost like colored lights of
different intensity which surround that
which you're looking at and how those
lights are focused and their intensity
totally changes how you see it because
it's a holographic universe and what you
see is uh the product of the position
from which you're seeing it. Which is
why quantum quantum mechanics offers us
offers the inlet that road from the
logical Newtonian paradigm of reality to
the more powerful spiritual reality.
No mind is very talkative this morning.
I don't know where he got all that.
Came out of nowhere.
I said, "How can you talk with no mind
if you got no mind?" No, these people
you got to talk to them in language that
requires a mind. Instantly mind appeared
right out of nowhere.
So, it's time for a break.
Yeah. From the pathway of indication, we
might end up at the void. Say there's
nobody here, there's nobody to answer,
and therefore there's no questions.
All right. So, he's looking for the
seat. Here it is.
All right,
we have a lot of questions and I try to
put them into groups baskets so that u
we can answer many questions at the same
time just by comprehension and
understanding
as we evolve spiritually. Uh you know
we're constantly presented with uh
ambiguities.
One way to see your way out of an
ambiguity
is to ask if you're mixing levels.
Mixing levels. Are you mixing levels?
Things are true within a certain
context. In another context, they're no
longer valid. You understand?
Um
Jesus said, "Render under Caesar that
which is Caesar, to God that which is
God." So, in other words, don't mix the
levels.
Don't think you can walk around without
paying your taxes.
cuz they'll put you away.
Of course, prison is a good place to
meditate and you can become enlightened
in jail and and some people pull that
one on themselves. You know, the people
over centuries have gotten enlightened
in prison and uh I can't get away from
this world. God, you just been arrested.
You got 10 years in solitary.
There you got it.
Uh monastery for one.
I told you when I lived in a monastery
for one. Yeah. And the body disappeared.
I walked into a wall and I walked past a
mirror. There was somebody in the house.
I walked past the mirror. There's
somebody in the house for Christ sake.
Who is that? Oh my god. It's myself.
What a surprise.
All right. So, the the validity of
calibration of kinesiology. We'll answer
questions about kinesiology. I'm not a
kinesiologist
and people want uh all kinds of detailed
questions about kinesiology are better
to uh you know correspond. There's a
kinesiology
website full of all kinds of experts
with all kinds of references. If you
can't do it yourself, find somebody that
can. There's people around that are
interested in this kind of thing.
There's a lot of uh holistic
practitioners that are very good at it,
teach you how. So, I'm not an expert in
kinesiology and I explain it. Galileo
was not an expert in making telescopes.
You know, you got a telescope maker. You
got this telescope. Everybody's looking
everybody's backyard with telescopes and
he went up this way and that's sort of
where I'm at. I'm not into making
telescopes and I get all kinds of
technical questions about kinesiology
which I really am not able to answer.
We have found that um it's a technique
available to people who themselves are
integrous.
Integrity means calibrated 200 or over.
Um there's an enormous amount of power
given to you. To be able to use
kinesiology to find out things is an
enormous jump in power and that power is
just not given to people who would
misuse it. So, one reason that I delayed
publishing Power Versus Force is I
worried about that. I thought, you know,
I was going to be using it to invent
better atomic bombs and kill each other
better. You know, I can picture Ben Len
testing kinesiology. Should we hit the
World Trade Center? Yeah. Right.
Uh
so I worried about it and uh anyway it
later came to me
that it can only be used by integrous
people for integrous ends. So the
intention of the question itself has to
be integrous
and um you can change a non integorous
question into an integrous one if you
recontextualize it from a different uh
context. And um the classic one is say
in the interest of the good of all of
life
you know in the interest of the good and
the goodness of all of life for everyone
uh I have permission to ask this
question. So then you ask I have
permission to ask this question and even
though we've done it hundreds hundreds
of thousands of times as you've seen
during some of these classes we
occasionally get a no and uh we don't
even we don't have time to check out the
reason for the no at the moment.
But it's something you put aside and you
say that's something we'll have to
investigate later.
Uh so
because 85% of the population is below
200 when I wrote power versus force I
was naive about that. I thought wow
everybody can do kinesiology.
Then I found out later no you can only
do it if you're over 200. Then I looked
at the calibrated scale of consciousness
and I realized that only that means 15%
of the population can do it.
Of that 15%
is it 10% that has something wrong with
their chi energy? Let's ask u right now
approximately 15% of the population can
use it. Of that 15%
10% have some problem with their chi
energy. That is correct. You know even
people who are integris not everybody's
adept at it. So it's only one way of
ascertaining truth. Don't forget
kinesiology is really not you know it's
really a research technique. You don't
need it to reach enlightenment. Buddha
didn't know kinesiology
and all the great saints that ever
lived. Mother Teresa never heard of it.
See and u
at the time I correspond with Mother
Teresa Jesus Christ was under attack. I
think the front cover of time or was
Jesus Christ did he ever really live?
Was he a schizophrenic, homosexual, you
know,
all this kind of stuff that periodically
surfaces
and uh so the reality of the divinity of
Jesus Christ was under attack. You know,
those things come up periodically. So I
just thought Mother Teresa was would be
interested in that there's a scientific
way of validating the divinity of Christ
as part of armamentarium of the
knowingness of the religious community.
So anyway it's really a research tool.
Occasionally it would be very useful in
your life but it's not as
as as useful as you may think it is.
because understanding comes out of the
advancement of one's own consciousness.
We use it uh very often because we're
answering questions from other people or
because we're investigating new areas.
You know, in the writings we do and in
the videotapes and all, you know, we're
looking into things that mankind has
never had access to, never had access
to. It's like, you know, X-rays or the
electron microscope. uh this whole areas
of life that um there was no way of
investigating
and now we have ways of investigating it
and of course we're always coming up
with questions ourself. So one the
answer to one question you know lead
leads to the next
and there of course is that technique of
of self- testing which some people are
also good at.
So that's all I can say about
kinesiology is it's a thing in itself.