Welcome
Welcome to
Welcome to Dr.
Welcome to Dr. David
Welcome to Dr. David Hawkins
Welcome to Dr. David Hawkins Sedona
Welcome to Dr. David Hawkins Sedona 2002
series,
series, The
Welcome to Dr. David Hawkins Sedona 2002
series, The Way
series, The Way to
Welcome to Dr. David Hawkins Sedona 2002
series, The Way to God.
series, The Way to God. Lecture
Welcome to Dr. David Hawkins Sedona 2002
series, The Way to God. Lecture 5,
Perception
Perception and
Perception and Illusion:
Perception and Illusion: Distortions
Perception and Illusion: Distortions of
Reality.
Reality. Originally
Perception and Illusion: Distortions of
Reality. Originally presented
Reality. Originally presented May
Perception and Illusion: Distortions of
Reality. Originally presented May 11th,
2002 at
2002 at the
2002 at the Sedona
2002 at the Sedona Creative
2002 at the Sedona Creative Life
2002 at the Sedona Creative Life Center.
Well,
Well, I'm
2002 at the Sedona Creative Life Center.
Well, I'm still
Well, I'm still on
2002 at the Sedona Creative Life Center.
Well, I'm still on a
Well, I'm still on a Walmart
2002 at the Sedona Creative Life Center.
Well, I'm still on a Walmart high
Well, I'm still on a Walmart high rather
than
than Walmart
than Walmart yesterday
and
and uh
than Walmart yesterday
and uh it's
and uh it's higher
than Walmart yesterday
and uh it's higher than
and uh it's higher than a
than Walmart yesterday
and uh it's higher than a lot
and uh it's higher than a lot of
churches
churches in
churches in this
churches in this world.
churches in this world. I
churches in this world. I met
churches in this world. I met a
churches in this world. I met a lot
churches in this world. I met a lot of
churches
churches in
churches in this world. I met a lot of
churches in this
churches in this world.
churches in this world. I met a lot of
churches in this world. You
churches in this world. You go
churches in this world. I met a lot of
churches in this world. You go into
Walmart
Walmart and
Walmart and everybody
Walmart and everybody sort
Walmart and everybody sort of
Walmart and everybody sort of drops
their
their persona.
Walmart and everybody sort of drops
their persona. Everybody
their persona. Everybody just
Walmart and everybody sort of drops
their persona. Everybody just who
their persona. Everybody just who they
are
are like
are like right
are like right off
are like right off the
are like right off the bat.
are like right off the bat. And
are like right off the bat. And I
noticed
noticed yesterday
are like right off the bat. And I
noticed yesterday every
noticed yesterday every single
are like right off the bat. And I
noticed yesterday every single person
smiled.
Everybody
Everybody they
smiled.
Everybody they pass
Everybody they pass each
smiled.
Everybody they pass each other
Everybody they pass each other in
baskets
baskets and
baskets and they
baskets and they just
baskets and they just smile
baskets and they just smile each
baskets and they just smile each other.
Everybody's
Everybody's just
baskets and they just smile each other.
Everybody's just who
Everybody's just who they
baskets and they just smile each other.
Everybody's just who they are.
Everybody's just who they are. Holy
Walmarts.
Walmarts. Uh,
everybody
everybody drops
Walmarts. Uh,
everybody drops their
everybody drops their persona
Walmarts. Uh,
everybody drops their persona and
they're
they're just
they're just who
they're just who they
they're just who they are.
they're just who they are. And
they're just who they are. And uh,
they're just who they are. And uh, of
course,
course, your
they're just who they are. And uh, of
course, your willingness
course, your willingness to
they're just who they are. And uh, of
course, your willingness to be
course, your willingness to be who
they're just who they are. And uh, of
course, your willingness to be who you
are
are with
are with them
are with them brings
are with them brings it
are with them brings it out
are with them brings it out in
are with them brings it out in them.
are with them brings it out in them. And
everybody's
everybody's looking
are with them brings it out in them. And
everybody's looking at
everybody's looking at each
are with them brings it out in them. And
everybody's looking at each other's
baskets.
baskets. What
baskets. What are
baskets. What are you
baskets. What are you having
baskets. What are you having a
baskets. What are you having a birthday?
And
it
it was
it was really
it was really lovely.
it was really lovely. uh
it was really lovely. uh you
it was really lovely. uh you know
it was really lovely. uh you know in
Paris
Paris as
it was really lovely. uh you know in
Paris as far
Paris as far as
it was really lovely. uh you know in
Paris as far as I
Paris as far as I did
it was really lovely. uh you know in
Paris as far as I did remark
Paris as far as I did remark about
Walmarts
Walmarts and
Walmarts and uh
Walmarts and uh and
Walmarts and uh and and
Walmarts and uh and and Sam
Walmarts and uh and and Sam and
Walmarts and uh and and Sam and I
corresponded
corresponded back
Walmarts and uh and and Sam and I
corresponded back and
corresponded back and forth
Walmarts and uh and and Sam and I
corresponded back and forth and
corresponded back and forth and he
Walmarts and uh and and Sam and I
corresponded back and forth and he liked
the
the book
the book and
the book and the
the book and the and
the book and the and you
the book and the and you know
the book and the and you know I
the book and the and you know I was
looking
looking at
the book and the and you know I was
looking at integrity
looking at integrity in
the book and the and you know I was
looking at integrity in business
and
and we
and we remarked
and we remarked about
and we remarked about the
and we remarked about the integrity
and we remarked about the integrity of
Walmarts
Walmarts which
and we remarked about the integrity of
Walmarts which in
Walmarts which in those
and we remarked about the integrity of
Walmarts which in those days
Walmarts which in those days calibrated
in
in the
in the high
in the high 300s
in the high 300s well
in the high 300s well 350
in the high 300s well 350 is
willingness,
willingness, helpfulness,
good-heartedness,
uh
uh integrity
good-heartedness,
uh integrity etc.
uh integrity etc. So
good-heartedness,
uh integrity etc. So I
uh integrity etc. So I admired
good-heartedness,
uh integrity etc. So I admired his
putting
putting integrity
putting integrity uh
putting integrity uh in
putting integrity uh in into
putting integrity uh in into the
workplace
workplace into
putting integrity uh in into the
workplace into business
workplace into business and
putting integrity uh in into the
workplace into business and uh
workplace into business and uh and
putting integrity uh in into the
workplace into business and uh and so
workplace into business and uh and so we
had
had sort
had sort of
had sort of a
had sort of a a
had sort of a a mutual
had sort of a a mutual appreciation
had sort of a a mutual appreciation and
uh
uh and
had sort of a a mutual appreciation and
uh and now
uh and now we
had sort of a a mutual appreciation and
uh and now we see
uh and now we see Walmart
had sort of a a mutual appreciation and
uh and now we see Walmart has
uh and now we see Walmart has become
had sort of a a mutual appreciation and
uh and now we see Walmart has become uh
uh
uh the
uh the biggest
uh the biggest corporation
uh the biggest corporation the
uh the biggest corporation the biggest
company
company in
uh the biggest corporation the biggest
company in the
company in the entire
uh the biggest corporation the biggest
company in the entire world.
The
The W
The W somebody
The W somebody from
The W somebody from the
The W somebody from the Wall
The W somebody from the Wall Street
Journal
Journal had
The W somebody from the Wall Street
Journal had called
Journal had called me
The W somebody from the Wall Street
Journal had called me about
Journal had called me about the
The W somebody from the Wall Street
Journal had called me about the validity
of
of spiritual
of spiritual concepts
of spiritual concepts in
of spiritual concepts in the
of spiritual concepts in the workplace
in
in business
and
and I
and I think
and I think Walmart
and I think Walmart speaks
and I think Walmart speaks for
and I think Walmart speaks for itself.
You
You calibrated
and I think Walmart speaks for itself.
You calibrated 380
You calibrated 380 and
and I think Walmart speaks for itself.
You calibrated 380 and become
You calibrated 380 and become the
biggest
biggest corporation
biggest corporation in
biggest corporation in the
biggest corporation in the world.
Other
Other corporations
biggest corporation in the world.
Other corporations that
Other corporations that calibrate
biggest corporation in the world.
Other corporations that calibrate around
70 have
70 have gone
70 have gone bankrupt.
So
So uh
70 have gone bankrupt.
So uh it
So uh it would
70 have gone bankrupt.
So uh it would it's
So uh it would it's you
70 have gone bankrupt.
So uh it would it's you know
So uh it would it's you know it
70 have gone bankrupt.
So uh it would it's you know it speaks
for
for itself
for itself the
for itself the fact
for itself the fact that
for itself the fact that spiritual
principles
principles as
for itself the fact that spiritual
principles as long
principles as long as
for itself the fact that spiritual
principles as long as you
principles as long as you don't
for itself the fact that spiritual
principles as long as you don't call
them
them spiritual
them spiritual if
them spiritual if you
them spiritual if you call
them spiritual if you call things
them spiritual if you call things God
them spiritual if you call things God or
spiritual
uh
uh you
uh you get
uh you get a
uh you get a negative
uh you get a negative reaction
uh you get a negative reaction from
uh you get a negative reaction from a
segment
segment of
uh you get a negative reaction from a
segment of the
segment of the population
but
but as
but as I
but as I say
but as I say God
but as I say God sneaks
but as I say God sneaks in
but as I say God sneaks in the
but as I say God sneaks in the back
but as I say God sneaks in the back door
as
as integrity
but as I say God sneaks in the back door
as integrity integrous
as integrity integrous business
principles
principles because
principles because they
principles because they show
principles because they show up
principles because they show up in
principles because they show up in the
bottom
bottom line
Uh
Uh so
Uh so yesterday
Uh so yesterday the
Uh so yesterday the people
Uh so yesterday the people were
Uh so yesterday the people were saying
how
how may
Uh so yesterday the people were saying
how may I
how may I help
Uh so yesterday the people were saying
how may I help you?
how may I help you? I
Uh so yesterday the people were saying
how may I help you? I mean
how may I help you? I mean wow
Uh so yesterday the people were saying
how may I help you? I mean wow what
how may I help you? I mean wow what a
great
great space
great space to
great space to come
great space to come from.
great space to come from. Who
great space to come from. Who else
great space to come from. Who else in
the
the world
great space to come from. Who else in
the world comes
the world comes from
great space to come from. Who else in
the world comes from how
the world comes from how may
great space to come from. Who else in
the world comes from how may I
the world comes from how may I help
great space to come from. Who else in
the world comes from how may I help you?
Yeah
Yeah the
Yeah the motor
Yeah the motor vehicle
Yeah the motor vehicle bureau
Yeah the motor vehicle bureau doesn't
you
you know
Yeah the motor vehicle bureau doesn't
you know I
you know I mean
IRS
IRS doesn't.
IRS doesn't. Uh
IRS doesn't. Uh so
IRS doesn't. Uh so the
IRS doesn't. Uh so the the
IRS doesn't. Uh so the the world
IRS doesn't. Uh so the the world uh
the
the the
IRS doesn't. Uh so the the world uh
the the government
the the government especially
IRS doesn't. Uh so the the world uh
the the government especially you
the the government especially you could
take
take a
take a a
take a a lesson
take a a lesson from
take a a lesson from Walmart
take a a lesson from Walmart because
it's
it's attitude
take a a lesson from Walmart because
it's attitude attitude
uh
uh being
uh being responsible
uh being responsible for
uh being responsible for being
uh being responsible for being uh
friendly
friendly and
uh being responsible for being uh
friendly and helpful
friendly and helpful to
uh being responsible for being uh
friendly and helpful to everyone.
Well,
Well, I
Well, I wasn't
Well, I wasn't going
Well, I wasn't going to
Well, I wasn't going to talk
Well, I wasn't going to talk about
Walmarts
Walmarts this
Well, I wasn't going to talk about
Walmarts this morning,
Walmarts this morning, but
this
this is
this is the
this is the fifth
this is the fifth of
this is the fifth of a
this is the fifth of a series
this is the fifth of a series of
this is the fifth of a series of 12
lectures.
Um
the
the the
Um
the the design
the the design the
Um
the the design the overall
the the design the overall design
Um
the the design the overall design of
the the design the overall design of the
lectures
lectures is
lectures is to
um
create
create uh
create uh a
create uh a field
create uh a field of
create uh a field of understanding
create uh a field of understanding of
things
things that
create uh a field of understanding of
things that are
things that are very
create uh a field of understanding of
things that are very difficult
historically
historically been
historically been difficult
historically been difficult to
understand
and
and to
and to approach
and to approach it
and to approach it from
and to approach it from the
and to approach it from the side
and to approach it from the side of
and to approach it from the side of the
ego.
ego. So
and to approach it from the side of the
ego. So these
ego. So these beginning
and to approach it from the side of the
ego. So these beginning lectures
ego. So these beginning lectures have
been
been designed
been designed to
been designed to familiarize
been designed to familiarize us
been designed to familiarize us with
been designed to familiarize us with the
ego
ego and
been designed to familiarize us with the
ego and how
ego and how it
been designed to familiarize us with the
ego and how it functions.
um
um how
um how to
um how to spot
the
the fulcrum
um how to spot
the fulcrum by
the fulcrum by which
um how to spot
the fulcrum by which the
the fulcrum by which the the
um how to spot
the fulcrum by which the the ego
the fulcrum by which the the ego takes
off
off in
off in one
off in one of
off in one of two
off in one of two directions
off in one of two directions to
off in one of two directions to create
off in one of two directions to create a
dualistic
dualistic perception
off in one of two directions to create a
dualistic perception of
dualistic perception of the
off in one of two directions to create a
dualistic perception of the world.
Um
Um and
Um and so
the
the spiritual
Um and so
the spiritual advancement
the spiritual advancement then
Um and so
the spiritual advancement then is
obstructed
obstructed by
obstructed by the
obstructed by the structures
obstructed by the structures of
obstructed by the structures of the
obstructed by the structures of the ego
and
and therefore
obstructed by the structures of the ego
and therefore we've
and therefore we've spent
obstructed by the structures of the ego
and therefore we've spent several
lectures
lectures on
lectures on studying
lectures on studying the
lectures on studying the structure
lectures on studying the structure of
the
the ego
lectures on studying the structure of
the ego which
the ego which is
lectures on studying the structure of
the ego which is the
the ego which is the title
lectures on studying the structure of
the ego which is the title of
the ego which is the title of today's
lecture.
lecture. What
lecture. What is
lecture. What is the
lecture. What is the title
lecture. What is the title of
lecture. What is the title of today's
lecture?
lecture? I
lecture. What is the title of today's
lecture? I forget.
Anyway,
um
um something
Anyway,
um something about
um something about being
Anyway,
um something about being warped
um something about being warped out
Anyway,
um something about being warped out by
the
the illusion
the illusion and
perception
perception and
the illusion and
perception and illusion
perception and illusion and
the illusion and
perception and illusion and the
distortions
distortions of
distortions of reality.
So
So to
distortions of reality.
So to fully
So to fully understand
distortions of reality.
So to fully understand that
So to fully understand that then
distortions of reality.
So to fully understand that then we'll
continue
continue on
continue on the
continue on the lecture
continue on the lecture series.
continue on the lecture series. Um
today
today we're
continue on the lecture series. Um
today we're going
today we're going to
continue on the lecture series. Um
today we're going to be
today we're going to be talking
continue on the lecture series. Um
today we're going to be talking about
context
context versus
context versus content.
how
how truth
context versus content.
how truth becomes
how truth becomes distorted.
Um
it
it becomes
Um
it becomes almost
it becomes almost an
Um
it becomes almost an editorial
it becomes almost an editorial style
Um
it becomes almost an editorial style in
our
our in
our in our
our in our society
in
in which
a
a certain
a certain way
a certain way of
a certain way of distorting
a certain way of distorting reality
becomes
becomes labeled
a certain way of distorting reality
becomes labeled and
becomes labeled and given
a certain way of distorting reality
becomes labeled and given a
becomes labeled and given a political
title.
Those
Those are
title.
Those are on
Those are on the
title.
Those are on the left
Those are on the left and
title.
Those are on the left and there's
Those are on the left and there's those
on
on the
on the right.
on the right. You
on the right. You see
on the right. You see depends
on the right. You see depends on
on the right. You see depends on what
kind
kind of
on the right. You see depends on what
kind of a
kind of a spin.
on the right. You see depends on what
kind of a spin. So
kind of a spin. So we
on the right. You see depends on what
kind of a spin. So we recognize
kind of a spin. So we recognize that
on the right. You see depends on what
kind of a spin. So we recognize that in
common
common sense
common sense we
common sense we talk
common sense we talk about
common sense we talk about the
common sense we talk about the spin
doctors
but
but just
but just how
but just how does
but just how does that
but just how does that come
but just how does that come about
but just how does that come about and
what
what is
but just how does that come about and
what is the
what is the impact
but just how does that come about and
what is the impact on
what is the impact on society.
So
So in
So in our
So in our writings
So in our writings and
So in our writings and our
So in our writings and our studies
So in our writings and our studies uh
So in our writings and our studies uh we
look
look at
So in our writings and our studies uh we
look at society
look at society as
So in our writings and our studies uh we
look at society as a
look at society as a collect
So in our writings and our studies uh we
look at society as a collect as
look at society as a collect as as
So in our writings and our studies uh we
look at society as a collect as as the
collective
collective ego.
So
So looking
collective ego.
So looking at
So looking at the
collective ego.
So looking at the world
So looking at the world and
collective ego.
So looking at the world and looking
So looking at the world and looking at
yourself,
it's
it's a
yourself,
it's a lot
it's a lot easier
yourself,
it's a lot easier to
it's a lot easier to look
yourself,
it's a lot easier to look at
the
the machinations
the machinations of
the machinations of the
the machinations of the ego
uh
uh in
the machinations of the ego
uh in the
uh in the world
the machinations of the ego
uh in the world because
uh in the world because we
the machinations of the ego
uh in the world because we don't
uh in the world because we don't feel
personal
personal personal
personal personal about
personal personal about it.
personal personal about it. It's
personal personal about it. It's easy
personal personal about it. It's easy to
see
see it
personal personal about it. It's easy to
see it out
see it out there.
So
So one
So one way
So one way of
So one way of understanding
So one way of understanding our
So one way of understanding our own
So one way of understanding our own ego
is
is to
So one way of understanding our own ego
is to see
is to see how
So one way of understanding our own ego
is to see how it
is to see how it functions
So one way of understanding our own ego
is to see how it functions in
is to see how it functions in society.
Society
Society is
Society is the
Society is the big
Society is the big model
Society is the big model out
Society is the big model out there.
Society is the big model out there. One
reason
reason people
Society is the big model out there. One
reason people love
reason people love movies
Society is the big model out there. One
reason people love movies is
reason people love movies is you
Society is the big model out there. One
reason people love movies is you can
reason people love movies is you can sit
in
in the
in the safety
in the safety of
in the safety of your
in the safety of your home
in the safety of your home and
in the safety of your home and without
getting
getting personally
in the safety of your home and without
getting personally involved
uh
uh watch
uh watch the
uh watch the vagaries
uh watch the vagaries of
uh watch the vagaries of the
uh watch the vagaries of the ego
uh watch the vagaries of the ego as
uh watch the vagaries of the ego as it
works
works itself.
uh watch the vagaries of the ego as it
works itself. It's
works itself. It's easy
uh watch the vagaries of the ego as it
works itself. It's easy to
works itself. It's easy to see
uh watch the vagaries of the ego as it
works itself. It's easy to see out
there.
there. So
there. So if
there. So if we
there. So if we understand
there. So if we understand something
about
about the
there. So if we understand something
about the functions
about the functions of
there. So if we understand something
about the functions of the
about the functions of the ego,
there. So if we understand something
about the functions of the ego, its
about the functions of the ego, its its
mechanisms
mechanisms and
mechanisms and its
mechanisms and its structure
and
and we
mechanisms and its structure
and we observe
and we observe its
mechanisms and its structure
and we observe its functioning
and we observe its functioning in
mechanisms and its structure
and we observe its functioning in the
world,
world, it's
world, it's an
world, it's an easy
world, it's an easy step
world, it's an easy step then
world, it's an easy step then to
world, it's an easy step then to see
that
that it's
world, it's an easy step then to see
that it's probably
that it's probably going
world, it's an easy step then to see
that it's probably going on
that it's probably going on within
myself.
myself. If
myself. If it's
myself. If it's not
myself. If it's not going
myself. If it's not going on
myself. If it's not going on within
myself,
myself, I
myself. If it's not going on within
myself, I wouldn't
myself, I wouldn't find
myself. If it's not going on within
myself, I wouldn't find the
myself, I wouldn't find the world
interesting.
If
If it's
interesting.
If it's not
If it's not going
interesting.
If it's not going in
If it's not going in on
interesting.
If it's not going in on within
If it's not going in on within myself,
interesting.
If it's not going in on within myself, I
wouldn't
wouldn't recognize
wouldn't recognize it
wouldn't recognize it in
wouldn't recognize it in a
wouldn't recognize it in a movie.
wouldn't recognize it in a movie. So
wouldn't recognize it in a movie. So we
can
can say
wouldn't recognize it in a movie. So we
can say then
can say then that
wouldn't recognize it in a movie. So we
can say then that the
can say then that the world
wouldn't recognize it in a movie. So we
can say then that the world out
can say then that the world out there
wouldn't recognize it in a movie. So we
can say then that the world out there is
a
a projection
a projection of
a projection of what
a projection of what is
a projection of what is within
a projection of what is within us
a projection of what is within us and
studying
studying the
a projection of what is within us and
studying the world
studying the world then
a projection of what is within us and
studying the world then gives
studying the world then gives us
a projection of what is within us and
studying the world then gives us an
indirect
it's
it's easier
indirect
it's easier to
it's easier to accept
indirect
it's easier to accept it's
it's easier to accept it's easier
indirect
it's easier to accept it's easier to
it's easier to accept it's easier to see
out
out there
then
then the
out there
then the serious
then the serious student
out there
then the serious student says
then the serious student says and
out there
then the serious student says and how
then the serious student says and how is
that
that going
that going on
that going on within
that going on within myself
that going on within myself and
that going on within myself and how
that going on within myself and how is
that
that happening
that going on within myself and how is
that happening within
that happening within myself
so
so that
so that brings
so that brings us
so that brings us to
so that brings us to understanding
so that brings us to understanding that
all
all truth
so that brings us to understanding that
all truth is
well
well no
well no let's
well no let's say
well no let's say all
well no let's say all propositions
involve
involve two
well no let's say all propositions
involve two things
involve two things they
well no let's say all propositions
involve two things they involve
involve two things they involve content
and
and they
and they involve
and they involve context.
The
The content
and they involve context.
The content is
The content is a
and they involve context.
The content is a literal
The content is a literal statement
and
and everyone
and everyone presumes
and everyone presumes a
and everyone presumes a certain
and everyone presumes a certain meaning
but
but meaning
and everyone presumes a certain meaning
but meaning comes
but meaning comes out
and everyone presumes a certain meaning
but meaning comes out of
but meaning comes out of context.
So
So the
So the gross
So the gross distortions
So the gross distortions of
So the gross distortions of the
So the gross distortions of the world
that
that we
So the gross distortions of the world
that we see
that we see in
So the gross distortions of the world
that we see in everyday
that we see in everyday headlines
have
have to
have to do
have to do with
have to do with the
have to do with the failure
have to do with the failure to
identify
context.
The
The content
context.
The content is
The content is often
context.
The content is often verbatimly
correct
correct as
correct as far
correct as far as
correct as far as most
correct as far as most people's
correct as far as most people's logic
correct as far as most people's logic is
concerned
concerned and
correct as far as most people's logic is
concerned and reason
except
except within
except within it
except within it it's
except within it it's only
except within it it's only true
except within it it's only true within
except within it it's only true within a
certain
certain context
and
and the
and the failure
and the failure is
and the failure is to
and the failure is to identify
and the failure is to identify context.
This
This is
and the failure is to identify context.
This is a
This is a fault
and the failure is to identify context.
This is a fault of
This is a fault of science
uh
all
all areas
uh
all areas of
all areas of human
uh
all areas of human endeavor.
all areas of human endeavor. A
uh
all areas of human endeavor. A thing
all areas of human endeavor. A thing is
only
only true
only true within
only true within a
only true within a certain
only true within a certain context
only true within a certain context in
and
and of
only true within a certain context in
and of itself.
What
What happens
What happens is
What happens is the
What happens is the speaker
What happens is the speaker or
What happens is the speaker or the
editorial
editorial writer,
the
the newspaper
the newspaper presumes
the newspaper presumes that
the newspaper presumes that you
the newspaper presumes that you will
assume
assume a
the newspaper presumes that you will
assume a context
and
and that
and that is
and that is a
and that is a great
and that is a great very
and that is a great very great
and that is a great very great false
assumption
assumption that
and that is a great very great false
assumption that you
assumption that you will
and that is a great very great false
assumption that you will assume
assumption that you will assume the
and that is a great very great false
assumption that you will assume the same
context
context as
context as they
context as they do
context as they do because
context as they do because very
context as they do because very often
the
the context
context as they do because very often
the context that
the context that you
context as they do because very often
the context that you assume
the context that you assume is
completely
completely different.
Uh,
Uh, you
completely different.
Uh, you know,
Uh, you know, it's
completely different.
Uh, you know, it's always
Uh, you know, it's always a
completely different.
Uh, you know, it's always a joke
Uh, you know, it's always a joke when
completely different.
Uh, you know, it's always a joke when I
see
see some
see some bomber
see some bomber who
see some bomber who has
see some bomber who has just
see some bomber who has just killed
see some bomber who has just killed 52
people
people and
see some bomber who has just killed 52
people and blown
people and blown up
see some bomber who has just killed 52
people and blown up a
people and blown up a plane
see some bomber who has just killed 52
people and blown up a plane and
slaughtered
slaughtered all
slaughtered all kinds
slaughtered all kinds of
slaughtered all kinds of innocents
slaughtered all kinds of innocents and
the
the minute
slaughtered all kinds of innocents and
the minute he
the minute he gets
slaughtered all kinds of innocents and
the minute he gets arrested,
the minute he gets arrested, a
slaughtered all kinds of innocents and
the minute he gets arrested, a parade
starts
starts for
starts for his
starts for his civil
starts for his civil rights.
starts for his civil rights. You
starts for his civil rights. You know,
you
you say,
starts for his civil rights. You know,
you say, "Yeah,
you say, "Yeah, right.
starts for his civil rights. You know,
you say, "Yeah, right. What
you say, "Yeah, right. What about
starts for his civil rights. You know,
you say, "Yeah, right. What about the
civil
civil rights
civil rights of
civil rights of the
civil rights of the 3,000
civil rights of the 3,000 people
civil rights of the 3,000 people he's
just
just killed?"
civil rights of the 3,000 people he's
just killed?" You
just killed?" You know
civil rights of the 3,000 people he's
just killed?" You know what
just killed?" You know what I'm
civil rights of the 3,000 people he's
just killed?" You know what I'm saying?
uh
political
political rights
uh
political rights um
political rights um of
uh
political rights um of course
political rights um of course are
uh
political rights um of course are what
historically
historically Americans
historically Americans have
historically Americans have died
historically Americans have died for.
But
But in
historically Americans have died for.
But in this
But in this particular
historically Americans have died for.
But in this particular context
But in this particular context it
historically Americans have died for.
But in this particular context it sounds
sophomoric
sophomoric and
sophomoric and it
sophomoric and it actually
sophomoric and it actually ridicules
sophomoric and it actually ridicules the
basic
basic concept
sophomoric and it actually ridicules the
basic concept by
basic concept by misplacing
sophomoric and it actually ridicules the
basic concept by misplacing it
basic concept by misplacing it in
sophomoric and it actually ridicules the
basic concept by misplacing it in in
basic concept by misplacing it in in a
context
context that
context that almost
context that almost invalidates
context that almost invalidates its
truth.
Things
Things are
Things are only
Things are only true
Things are only true then
Things are only true then within
Things are only true then within a
certain
certain context
Things are only true then within a
certain context and
certain context and the
Things are only true then within a
certain context and the unstated
certain context and the unstated context
is
is where
is where the
is where the difficulty
is where the difficulty arises.
Am
Am I
is where the difficulty arises.
Am I making
Am I making sense
is where the difficulty arises.
Am I making sense to
Am I making sense to you
is where the difficulty arises.
Am I making sense to you this
Am I making sense to you this far?
is where the difficulty arises.
Am I making sense to you this far? Yes.
All
All truth
All truth is
All truth is only
All truth is only true
All truth is only true within
All truth is only true within a
All truth is only true within a certain
context.
context. This
All truth is only true within a certain
context. This is
context. This is recognized
All truth is only true within a certain
context. This is recognized in
context. This is recognized in so-called
situational
situational ethics
in
in which
situational ethics
in which the
in which the ethic
situational ethics
in which the ethic depends
in which the ethic depends on
situational ethics
in which the ethic depends on the
circumstances.
Even
Even courts
circumstances.
Even courts uh
Even courts uh give
circumstances.
Even courts uh give uh
Even courts uh give uh recognition
circumstances.
Even courts uh give uh recognition to
the
the fact
the fact that
the fact that context
uh
uh alters
the fact that context
uh alters the
uh alters the degree
the fact that context
uh alters the degree of
uh alters the degree of responsibility,
the
the insanity,
the insanity, the
the insanity, the defense
the insanity, the defense etc.
the insanity, the defense etc. Uh
whether
whether there's
the insanity, the defense etc. Uh
whether there's willfulness,
whether there's willfulness, intention.
Um
so
so the
Um
so the individual
so the individual then
Um
so the individual then is
so the individual then is considered
Um
so the individual then is considered to
be
be responsible
be responsible only
be responsible only within
be responsible only within a
be responsible only within a certain
context.
context. So
be responsible only within a certain
context. So we
context. So we can
be responsible only within a certain
context. So we can never
context. So we can never presume
context.
context. Context
context. Context always
context. Context always has
context. Context always has to
context. Context always has to be
explicitly
explicitly understood,
context. Context always has to be
explicitly understood, stated
explicitly understood, stated or
made
made verbatim.
made verbatim. Um
the
the infinite
made verbatim. Um
the infinite context
the infinite context is
made verbatim. Um
the infinite context is what
spirituality
spirituality is
spirituality is all
spirituality is all about.
spirituality is all about. Spirituality
is
is transcending
spirituality is all about. Spirituality
is transcending content
is transcending content to
spirituality is all about. Spirituality
is transcending content to realize
is transcending content to realize the
context
context out
context out of
context out of which
all
all arises.
In
In the
In the beginning
In the beginning of
In the beginning of all
In the beginning of all these
In the beginning of all these lectures,
I
I think
In the beginning of all these lectures,
I think we
I think we we
In the beginning of all these lectures,
I think we we start
I think we we start out
In the beginning of all these lectures,
I think we we start out with
I think we we start out with a
In the beginning of all these lectures,
I think we we start out with a statement
of
of what
of what the
of what the ultimate
of what the ultimate infinite
of what the ultimate infinite context
really
really is
of what the ultimate infinite context
really is of
really is of everyday
of what the ultimate infinite context
really is of everyday life.
The
The realization
The realization that
The realization that everything
The realization that everything is
happening
happening of
The realization that everything is
happening of its
happening of its own.
Everything
Everything we
Everything we see
Everything we see is
Everything we see is spontaneously
Everything we see is spontaneously being
what
what it
Everything we see is spontaneously being
what it is,
what it is, exactly
Everything we see is spontaneously being
what it is, exactly as
what it is, exactly as it
Everything we see is spontaneously being
what it is, exactly as it is
what it is, exactly as it is this
moment.
moment. And
moment. And each
moment. And each moment
moment. And each moment is
moment. And each moment is therefore
perfect.
For
For anything
For anything to
For anything to be
For anything to be what
For anything to be what it
For anything to be what it is
For anything to be what it is at
For anything to be what it is at this
moment,
moment, it
For anything to be what it is at this
moment, it has
moment, it has to
For anything to be what it is at this
moment, it has to fulfill
potentiality
which
which is
potentiality
which is innate
which is innate to
potentiality
which is innate to its
which is innate to its creation,
potentiality
which is innate to its creation, innate
to
to its
to its existence.
So
So that
to its existence.
So that everything
So that everything if
to its existence.
So that everything if the
So that everything if the universe
stopped
stopped this
stopped this incident,
stopped this incident, everything
stopped this incident, everything is
perfect
perfect right
stopped this incident, everything is
perfect right now.
perfect right now. Each
stopped this incident, everything is
perfect right now. Each thing
perfect right now. Each thing is
becoming
becoming that
becoming that which
becoming that which is
becoming that which is innately
becoming that which is innately its
potential.
So
So we
So we see
So we see that
So we see that the
So we see that the rose
So we see that the rose half
So we see that the rose half unfolded
So we see that the rose half unfolded is
not
not an
So we see that the rose half unfolded is
not an imperfect
not an imperfect rose.
So we see that the rose half unfolded is
not an imperfect rose. It's
not an imperfect rose. It's perfect
So we see that the rose half unfolded is
not an imperfect rose. It's perfect up
to
to this
to this point.
to this point. The
to this point. The perfect
to this point. The perfect design
to this point. The perfect design is
that
that this
to this point. The perfect design is
that this rose
that this rose should
to this point. The perfect design is
that this rose should unfold
that this rose should unfold in
to this point. The perfect design is
that this rose should unfold in this
way.
way. And
way. And at
way. And at this
way. And at this moment
way. And at this moment it
way. And at this moment it is
way. And at this moment it is the
absolute
absolute perfection
way. And at this moment it is the
absolute perfection of
absolute perfection of that
way. And at this moment it is the
absolute perfection of that which
absolute perfection of that which has
gone
gone before.
As
As you
gone before.
As you know
As you know that
gone before.
As you know that which
As you know that which has
gone before.
As you know that which has gone
As you know that which has gone before
is
is the
is the totality
is the totality of
is the totality of the
is the totality of the entire
is the totality of the entire universe
throughout
throughout all
is the totality of the entire universe
throughout all of
throughout all of time.
is the totality of the entire universe
throughout all of time. That's
throughout all of time. That's what
is the totality of the entire universe
throughout all of time. That's what it
took
took for
took for this
took for this rose
took for this rose to
took for this rose to be
took for this rose to be right
took for this rose to be right here
took for this rose to be right here at
this
this moment.
And
And if
And if the
And if the universe
And if the universe stops
And if the universe stops right
And if the universe stops right now,
And if the universe stops right now, it
has
has already
And if the universe stops right now, it
has already reached
has already reached its
And if the universe stops right now, it
has already reached its perfection
because
because its
because its perfection
because its perfection is
because its perfection is to
because its perfection is to be
because its perfection is to be half
unfolded
unfolded at
because its perfection is to be half
unfolded at this
unfolded at this moment.
To
To see
To see that
To see that that
To see that that is
To see that that is the
To see that that is the condition,
To see that that is the condition, the
state
state of
To see that that is the condition, the
state of affairs
is
is what
is what hit
is what hit me
is what hit me at
is what hit me at Walmart
is what hit me at Walmart yesterday.
Everybody
Everybody was
is what hit me at Walmart yesterday.
Everybody was just
Everybody was just spontaneously
is what hit me at Walmart yesterday.
Everybody was just spontaneously being
exactly
exactly who
exactly who they
exactly who they were
exactly who they were at
exactly who they were at the
exactly who they were at the mo
exactly who they were at the mo at
exactly who they were at the mo at that
moment
moment with
exactly who they were at the mo at that
moment with no
moment with no disguises,
exactly who they were at the mo at that
moment with no disguises, no,
moment with no disguises, no, you
exactly who they were at the mo at that
moment with no disguises, no, you know,
people
people dropped
people dropped their
people dropped their persona
people dropped their persona in
people dropped their persona in that
kind
kind of
people dropped their persona in that
kind of a
kind of a setting.
people dropped their persona in that
kind of a setting. So
kind of a setting. So the
people dropped their persona in that
kind of a setting. So the lovingness
that's
that's innate
that's innate within
that's innate within the
that's innate within the human
that's innate within the human condition
was
was able
that's innate within the human condition
was able to
was able to shine
that's innate within the human condition
was able to shine forth
You
You see
You see that
You see that also
You see that also after
You see that also after uh
You see that also after uh catastrophes
and
and all,
You see that also after uh catastrophes
and all, you
and all, you know,
You see that also after uh catastrophes
and all, you know, a
and all, you know, a shipwreck
uh
uh comm
uh comm camaraderie
and
and when
uh comm camaraderie
and when the
and when the chips
uh comm camaraderie
and when the chips are
and when the chips are down,
uh comm camaraderie
and when the chips are down, everybody
suddenly
suddenly becomes
suddenly becomes who
suddenly becomes who they
suddenly becomes who they really
suddenly becomes who they really are.
Then
Then when
suddenly becomes who they really are.
Then when they
Then when they go
suddenly becomes who they really are.
Then when they go back
Then when they go back to
suddenly becomes who they really are.
Then when they go back to work
Then when they go back to work on
suddenly becomes who they really are.
Then when they go back to work on Monday
morning,
morning, they're
morning, they're back
morning, they're back to
morning, they're back to the
morning, they're back to the same
morning, they're back to the same old
world
world speak.
morning, they're back to the same old
world speak. You
world speak. You know,
morning, they're back to the same old
world speak. You know, there's
world speak. You know, there's two
morning, they're back to the same old
world speak. You know, there's two kinds
of
of speak.
of speak. There's
of speak. There's world
of speak. There's world speak
of speak. There's world speak and
of speak. There's world speak and truth
speak.
speak. And
of speak. There's world speak and truth
speak. And in
speak. And in world
of speak. There's world speak and truth
speak. And in world speak,
speak. And in world speak, you're
expected
expected to
expected to do
expected to do to
expected to do to come
expected to do to come across
expected to do to come across with
expected to do to come across with world
speak.
speak. And
expected to do to come across with world
speak. And in
speak. And in truth
expected to do to come across with world
speak. And in truth speak
speak. And in truth speak is
expected to do to come across with world
speak. And in truth speak is is
inappropriate
inappropriate in
inappropriate in world
inappropriate in world speak.
In
In world
inappropriate in world speak.
In world speak,
In world speak, you're
inappropriate in world speak.
In world speak, you're supposed
In world speak, you're supposed to
inappropriate in world speak.
In world speak, you're supposed to say,
"No,
"No, I'm
"No, I'm not
"No, I'm not guilty."
"No, I'm not guilty." Even
"No, I'm not guilty." Even though
there's
there's 21
"No, I'm not guilty." Even though
there's 21 bodies
there's 21 bodies laying
"No, I'm not guilty." Even though
there's 21 bodies laying there,
21 kids
21 kids you
21 kids you molested.
Not
Not guilty,
21 kids you molested.
Not guilty, your
Not guilty, your honor.
Uh
Uh that's
Uh that's real world
Uh that's real world speak.
Uh that's real world speak. So
Uh that's real world speak. So we
Uh that's real world speak. So we the
context
context we
Uh that's real world speak. So we the
context we understand
context we understand speak
Uh that's real world speak. So we the
context we understand speak within
context we understand speak within a
certain
certain context.
certain context. We
certain context. We understand
certain context. We understand that
certain context. We understand that it's
world
world speak.
Sophisticated
Sophisticated people
Sophisticated people understand
Sophisticated people understand it's
world
world speak.
Sophisticated people understand it's
world speak. Most
world speak. Most of
Sophisticated people understand it's
world speak. Most of the
world speak. Most of the world
Sophisticated people understand it's
world speak. Most of the world doesn't.
Most
Most of the
Most of the world
Most of the world thinks
Most of the world thinks it's
Most of the world thinks it's truth.
World
World speak
Most of the world thinks it's truth.
World speak is
World speak is a
Most of the world thinks it's truth.
World speak is a provisional
accommodation
accommodation to
um
um the
accommodation to
um the practicalities
um the practicalities of
accommodation to
um the practicalities of the
um the practicalities of the everyday
marketplace
marketplace and
marketplace and physical
marketplace and physical survival
within
within ourselves.
marketplace and physical survival
within ourselves. However,
within ourselves. However, the
marketplace and physical survival
within ourselves. However, the condition
of
of world
of world speaking
of world speaking tends
of world speaking tends to
of world speaking tends to continue.
inner
inner voice
uh
uh continues
uh continues to
uh continues to lie
uh continues to lie to
uh continues to lie to ourself,
uh continues to lie to ourself, create
illusions.
illusions. And
uh continues to lie to ourself, create
illusions. And so
illusions. And so today,
uh continues to lie to ourself, create
illusions. And so today, what
illusions. And so today, what we
uh continues to lie to ourself, create
illusions. And so today, what we want
illusions. And so today, what we want to
do
do is
do is try
do is try to
do is try to transcend
do is try to transcend those
do is try to transcend those illusions.
One
One way,
do is try to transcend those illusions.
One way, the
One way, the most
do is try to transcend those illusions.
One way, the most important
One way, the most important way,
do is try to transcend those illusions.
One way, the most important way, which
we're
we're speaking
we're speaking of
we're speaking of today,
we're speaking of today, that
we're speaking of today, that illusion
arises
arises is
we're speaking of today, that illusion
arises is the
arises is the failure
we're speaking of today, that illusion
arises is the failure to
arises is the failure to recognize
context.
When
When we
context.
When we judge
When we judge things,
context.
When we judge things, when
When we judge things, when we
context.
When we judge things, when we judge
things
things and
things and when
things and when we
things and when we judge
things and when we judge oursel
things and when we judge oursel to
attack
attack ourselves
things and when we judge oursel to
attack ourselves and
attack ourselves and others,
things and when we judge oursel to
attack ourselves and others, the
attack ourselves and others, the only
way
way you
way you can
way you can do
way you can do that
way you can do that is
way you can do that is by
way you can do that is by removing
way you can do that is by removing it
from
from context.
The
The only
The only way
The only way you
The only way you can
The only way you can attack
The only way you can attack yourself
The only way you can attack yourself for
what
what you
The only way you can attack yourself for
what you did
what you did yesterday
The only way you can attack yourself for
what you did yesterday or
what you did yesterday or last
The only way you can attack yourself for
what you did yesterday or last year
what you did yesterday or last year or
two
two years
two years ago
two years ago or
two years ago or whatever
is
is to
two years ago or whatever
is to forget
is to forget the
two years ago or whatever
is to forget the context
is to forget the context in
two years ago or whatever
is to forget the context in which
is to forget the context in which it
happened.
So
So Monday
happened.
So Monday morning
So Monday morning quarterbacking
happened.
So Monday morning quarterbacking is
always
always facious.
always facious. Always
always facious. Always facious.
always facious. Always facious. It's
always
always felacious.
always facious. Always facious. It's
always felacious. Why?
always felacious. Why? because
always facious. Always facious. It's
always felacious. Why? because it's
always felacious. Why? because it's a
different
different context.
different context. Monday
different context. Monday morning's
truth
truth is
different context. Monday morning's
truth is not
truth is not the
different context. Monday morning's
truth is not the same
truth is not the same as
different context. Monday morning's
truth is not the same as Saturday
afternoon's
afternoon's truth.
afternoon's truth. They're
afternoon's truth. They're two
afternoon's truth. They're two different
truths.
The
The conditions
The conditions which
The conditions which existed
The conditions which existed at
The conditions which existed at the
The conditions which existed at the time
in
in the
The conditions which existed at the time
in the past
in the past are
The conditions which existed at the time
in the past are different
in the past are different than
The conditions which existed at the time
in the past are different than the
conditions
conditions which
conditions which exist
conditions which exist today.
What
What was
conditions which exist today.
What was accepted
What was accepted worldwide
conditions which exist today.
What was accepted worldwide as
What was accepted worldwide as normal
human
human behavior
can't
can't be
human behavior
can't be criticized
can't be criticized now
human behavior
can't be criticized now in
can't be criticized now in retrospect.
When
When I
When I grew
When I grew up,
When I grew up, the
When I grew up, the woman's
When I grew up, the woman's place
When I grew up, the woman's place was
When I grew up, the woman's place was in
the
the home.
When I grew up, the woman's place was in
the home. She
the home. She ruled
When I grew up, the woman's place was in
the home. She ruled it
the home. She ruled it like
When I grew up, the woman's place was in
the home. She ruled it like she
the home. She ruled it like she the
matriarch.
matriarch. The
matriarch. The woman
matriarch. The woman ruled
matriarch. The woman ruled the
matriarch. The woman ruled the house
matriarch. The woman ruled the house and
the
the man
matriarch. The woman ruled the house and
the man was
the man was supposed
matriarch. The woman ruled the house and
the man was supposed to
the man was supposed to go
matriarch. The woman ruled the house and
the man was supposed to go out
the man was supposed to go out there
matriarch. The woman ruled the house and
the man was supposed to go out there and
bring
bring home
bring home the
bring home the bacon.
He
He didn't
bring home the bacon.
He didn't rule
He didn't rule the
bring home the bacon.
He didn't rule the house.
He didn't rule the house. He
bring home the bacon.
He didn't rule the house. He expressed
his
his opinions.
his opinions. But
his opinions. But uh
his opinions. But uh if
his opinions. But uh if you
his opinions. But uh if you like
his opinions. But uh if you like your
like
like them
his opinions. But uh if you like your
like them diced
like them diced better
his opinions. But uh if you like your
like them diced better than
like them diced better than slice,
his opinions. But uh if you like your
like them diced better than slice, she
says
says dice
says dice is
says dice is better
says dice is better for
says dice is better for you
says dice is better for you diced,
says dice is better for you diced, you
know.
So
So mother
So mother ruled
So mother ruled in
So mother ruled in the
So mother ruled in the house
So mother ruled in the house and
So mother ruled in the house and she
So mother ruled in the house and she was
re
re revered
because
because she
because she was
because she was the
because she was the sustainer
because she was the sustainer of
because she was the sustainer of life.
You
You know,
because she was the sustainer of life.
You know, the
You know, the mother
because she was the sustainer of life.
You know, the mother had
You know, the mother had a
because she was the sustainer of life.
You know, the mother had a profound
importance.
importance. And
importance. And as
importance. And as a
importance. And as a boy,
importance. And as a boy, if
importance. And as a boy, if you
importance. And as a boy, if you even
importance. And as a boy, if you even if
your
your mother
importance. And as a boy, if you even if
your mother asked
your mother asked you
importance. And as a boy, if you even if
your mother asked you to
your mother asked you to whitewash
importance. And as a boy, if you even if
your mother asked you to whitewash the
basement
basement on
basement on a
basement on a Saturday
basement on a Saturday afternoon
basement on a Saturday afternoon and
basement on a Saturday afternoon and you
had
had to
basement on a Saturday afternoon and you
had to cancel
had to cancel your
basement on a Saturday afternoon and you
had to cancel your baseball
had to cancel your baseball game,
basement on a Saturday afternoon and you
had to cancel your baseball game, if
had to cancel your baseball game, if you
looked
looked even
looked even the
looked even the slightest
looked even the slightest disappointed,
your
your father
looked even the slightest disappointed,
your father would
your father would say,
looked even the slightest disappointed,
your father would say, "Wipe
your father would say, "Wipe that
looked even the slightest disappointed,
your father would say, "Wipe that look
off
off your
off your face,
off your face, young
off your face, young boy."
off your face, young boy." Young
off your face, young boy." Young man,
it's
it's disrespectful
off your face, young boy." Young man,
it's disrespectful to
it's disrespectful to your
off your face, young boy." Young man,
it's disrespectful to your mother.
it's disrespectful to your mother. Wow.
So,
So, the
So, the mother
So, the mother had
So, the mother had high,
So, the mother had high, you
So, the mother had high, you know,
tomorrow's
tomorrow's mother's
So, the mother had high, you know,
tomorrow's mother's day
tomorrow's mother's day that
So, the mother had high, you know,
tomorrow's mother's day that the
tomorrow's mother's day that the mother
had
had a
had a very
had a very high
had a very high rank
had a very high rank within
had a very high rank within her
had a very high rank within her domain.
She
She uh
had a very high rank within her domain.
She uh rules
She uh rules supreme
had a very high rank within her domain.
She uh rules supreme and
She uh rules supreme and men
had a very high rank within her domain.
She uh rules supreme and men when
She uh rules supreme and men when she
entered
entered the
entered the room
entered the room stood
entered the room stood up.
entered the room stood up. You
entered the room stood up. You know
entered the room stood up. You know that
lots
lots of
entered the room stood up. You know that
lots of you
lots of you in
entered the room stood up. You know that
lots of you in this
lots of you in this world
entered the room stood up. You know that
lots of you in this world room
lots of you in this world room I
entered the room stood up. You know that
lots of you in this world room I see
from
from your
from your age
from your age don't
from your age don't know
from your age don't know what
from your age don't know what it
from your age don't know what it means.
When
When the
from your age don't know what it means.
When the woman
When the woman entered
from your age don't know what it means.
When the woman entered the
When the woman entered the room
from your age don't know what it means.
When the woman entered the room the
When the woman entered the room the men
all
all stood
all stood up.
all stood up. You
all stood up. You see
all stood up. You see that
all stood up. You see that today?
all stood up. You see that today? No.
When
When the
all stood up. You see that today? No.
When the woman
When the woman under
all stood up. You see that today? No.
When the woman under came
When the woman under came up
all stood up. You see that today? No.
When the woman under came up to
When the woman under came up to the
doorway,
doorway, the
doorway, the man
doorway, the man opened
doorway, the man opened it
doorway, the man opened it for
doorway, the man opened it for her.
doorway, the man opened it for her. And
those
those gestures
doorway, the man opened it for her. And
those gestures were
those gestures were to
doorway, the man opened it for her. And
those gestures were to honor
those gestures were to honor her.
doorway, the man opened it for her. And
those gestures were to honor her. You
understand?
understand? Women
understand? Women were
understand? Women were being
understand? Women were being honored.
The
The women's
understand? Women were being honored.
The women's movement
The women's movement didn't
understand? Women were being honored.
The women's movement didn't get
The women's movement didn't get that.
understand? Women were being honored.
The women's movement didn't get that. It
was
was so
was so paranoid.
was so paranoid. It
was so paranoid. It didn't
was so paranoid. It didn't even
was so paranoid. It didn't even get
was so paranoid. It didn't even get it
was
was being
was so paranoid. It didn't even get it
was being honored.
was being honored. It
was so paranoid. It didn't even get it
was being honored. It thought
was being honored. It thought it
was so paranoid. It didn't even get it
was being honored. It thought it was
being
insulted.
I'll
I'll tell
I'll tell you.
I'll tell you. So
I'll tell you. So anyway,
low
low self-esteem
I'll tell you. So anyway,
low self-esteem and
low self-esteem and paranoia
I'll tell you. So anyway,
low self-esteem and paranoia cease
insult
insult everywhere.
insult everywhere. That
insult everywhere. That that's
insult everywhere. That that's the
insult everywhere. That that's the ego
egotism
egotism of
insult everywhere. That that's the ego
egotism of narcissism.
The
The entitled
The entitled attitude
The entitled attitude and
The entitled attitude and the
The entitled attitude and the narcissism
that
that undermines
The entitled attitude and the narcissism
that undermines so
that undermines so that
The entitled attitude and the narcissism
that undermines so that you
that undermines so that you think
The entitled attitude and the narcissism
that undermines so that you think that
an
an to
an to be
an to be honored
an to be honored is
an to be honored is to
an to be honored is to be
an to be honored is to be insulted.
an to be honored is to be insulted. So
anyway,
the
the mother
the mother reigns
the mother reigns supreme.
the mother reigns supreme. You
the mother reigns supreme. You didn't
use
use any
the mother reigns supreme. You didn't
use any vulgar
use any vulgar language
the mother reigns supreme. You didn't
use any vulgar language in
use any vulgar language in in
the mother reigns supreme. You didn't
use any vulgar language in in her
presence.
presence. If
presence. If you
presence. If you went
presence. If you went to
presence. If you went to a
presence. If you went to a tavern
restaurant,
restaurant, there
presence. If you went to a tavern
restaurant, there was
restaurant, there was a
presence. If you went to a tavern
restaurant, there was a separate
entrance
entrance in
entrance in the
entrance in the rear
entrance in the rear was
entrance in the rear was called
entrance in the rear was called family
entrance.
entrance. Women
entrance in the rear was called family
entrance. Women never
entrance. Women never entered
entrance in the rear was called family
entrance. Women never entered the
entrance. Women never entered the front
entrance.
entrance. That
entrance. That was
entrance. That was for
entrance. That was for the
entrance. That was for the bar
entrance. That was for the bar and
vulgarity.
vulgarity. And
entrance. That was for the bar and
vulgarity. And you
vulgarity. And you never
entrance. That was for the bar and
vulgarity. And you never saw
vulgarity. And you never saw a
entrance. That was for the bar and
vulgarity. And you never saw a single
woman
woman at
woman at a
woman at a bar.
woman at a bar. A
woman at a bar. A woman
woman at a bar. A woman walking
woman at a bar. A woman walking up
woman at a bar. A woman walking up to
woman at a bar. A woman walking up to a
bar.
bar. I
woman at a bar. A woman walking up to a
bar. I never
bar. I never saw
woman at a bar. A woman walking up to a
bar. I never saw it
bar. I never saw it in
woman at a bar. A woman walking up to a
bar. I never saw it in my
bar. I never saw it in my whole
woman at a bar. A woman walking up to a
bar. I never saw it in my whole life.
And
And the
And the first
And the first time
And the first time I
And the first time I did
And the first time I did see
And the first time I did see it,
And the first time I did see it, I
And the first time I did see it, I was
like
like shocked.
Um,
all
all right.
Um,
all right. So,
all right. So, the
Um,
all right. So, the woman's
all right. So, the woman's the
Um,
all right. So, the woman's the woman's
uh
uh rank,
uh rank, her
uh rank, her status,
uh rank, her status, her
uh rank, her status, her worth
uh rank, her status, her worth was
revered.
revered. revered.
Mother,
Mother, the
Mother, the word
Mother, the word mother
Mother, the word mother was
Mother, the word mother was revered.
Mother, the word mother was revered. The
mother
was
was respected,
was respected, revered
was respected, revered and
was respected, revered and she
was respected, revered and she was
was respected, revered and she was also
protected.
Men
Men went
Men went to
Men went to war
Men went to war to
Men went to war to protect
Men went to war to protect mother
Men went to war to protect mother and
the
the children.
Men went to war to protect mother and
the children. Her
the children. Her function
Men went to war to protect mother and
the children. Her function was
the children. Her function was revered.
Um,
Um, and
Um, and let's
Um, and let's see
Um, and let's see what
Um, and let's see what happened
Um, and let's see what happened to
Um, and let's see what happened to that.
the
the paranoid
Um, and let's see what happened to that.
the paranoid distortions
the paranoid distortions that
Um, and let's see what happened to that.
the paranoid distortions that have
fallen
fallen uh
fallen uh fallen
fallen uh fallen upon
fallen uh fallen upon mother.
fallen uh fallen upon mother. Now
um
so
so you
so you see
so you see the
so you see the context
means
means that
so you see the context
means that when
means that when people
you
you see
you see Monday
you see Monday morning
you see Monday morning quarterbacking
would
would say
you see Monday morning quarterbacking
would say woman
would say woman had
you see Monday morning quarterbacking
would say woman had an
would say woman had an inferior
position.
position. Well
position. Well this
position. Well this is
position. Well this is from
position. Well this is from Monday
morning's
morning's quarterbacking
and
and it's
and it's a
and it's a perception
and it's a perception that
and it's a perception that really
and it's a perception that really misses
the
the entire
and it's a perception that really misses
the entire reality
the entire reality of
and it's a perception that really misses
the entire reality of what
the entire reality of what went
and it's a perception that really misses
the entire reality of what went on
the entire reality of what went on in
those
those days.
those days. We
those days. We can
those days. We can look
those days. We can look back
those days. We can look back at
those days. We can look back at slavery
and
and say,
those days. We can look back at slavery
and say, "Oh,
and say, "Oh, how
those days. We can look back at slavery
and say, "Oh, how awful
and say, "Oh, how awful that
those days. We can look back at slavery
and say, "Oh, how awful that was."
and say, "Oh, how awful that was." Yeah,
it's
it's awful
it's awful 250
it's awful 250 years
it's awful 250 years later
it's awful 250 years later when
it's awful 250 years later when it's
it's awful 250 years later when it's no
longer
longer a
it's awful 250 years later when it's no
longer a world
longer a world style.
In
In the
In the years
In the years in
In the years in which
In the years in which slaver
In the years in which slaver in
In the years in which slaver in the
years
years of
In the years in which slaver in the
years of slavery,
years of slavery, it's
In the years in which slaver in the
years of slavery, it's a
years of slavery, it's a world
phenomena.
All
All the
phenomena.
All the countries
All the countries of
phenomena.
All the countries of the
All the countries of the world
phenomena.
All the countries of the world practice
slavery.
The
The Arabic
slavery.
The Arabic world
The Arabic world still
slavery.
The Arabic world still practices
The Arabic world still practices it.
So
So you
So you see
So you see by
So you see by shifting
So you see by shifting context
So you see by shifting context we
So you see by shifting context we can
look
look at
So you see by shifting context we can
look at the
look at the role
So you see by shifting context we can
look at the role of
look at the role of you
So you see by shifting context we can
look at the role of you know
look at the role of you know they
So you see by shifting context we can
look at the role of you know they can
look
look back
look back and
look back and say
look back and say how
look back and say how wrong
look back and say how wrong it
look back and say how wrong it was
look back and say how wrong it was the
way
way women
look back and say how wrong it was the
way women were
way women were held
look back and say how wrong it was the
way women were held held
way women were held held down
look back and say how wrong it was the
way women were held held down and
couldn't
couldn't get
couldn't get a
couldn't get a job
couldn't get a job in
couldn't get a job in the
couldn't get a job in the workplace.
Well
Well who
couldn't get a job in the workplace.
Well who wanted
Well who wanted to
couldn't get a job in the workplace.
Well who wanted to I
Well who wanted to I don't
couldn't get a job in the workplace.
Well who wanted to I don't know
Well who wanted to I don't know a
couldn't get a job in the workplace.
Well who wanted to I don't know a woman
that
that wanted
that wanted a
that wanted a job
that wanted a job in
that wanted a job in the
that wanted a job in the workplace.
It
It was
that wanted a job in the workplace.
It was thought
It was thought when
that wanted a job in the workplace.
It was thought when I
It was thought when I grew
that wanted a job in the workplace.
It was thought when I grew up
It was thought when I grew up that
that wanted a job in the workplace.
It was thought when I grew up that to
have
have the
have the woman
have the woman in
have the woman in the
have the woman in the house
have the woman in the house working
have the woman in the house working was
a
a disgrace.
For
For a
For a man
For a man to
For a man to have
For a man to have his
For a man to have his wife
For a man to have his wife out
For a man to have his wife out there
working
working was
For a man to have his wife out there
working was a
working was a disgrace.
For a man to have his wife out there
working was a disgrace. It
working was a disgrace. It means
For a man to have his wife out there
working was a disgrace. It means he
couldn't
couldn't afford
couldn't afford to
couldn't afford to make
couldn't afford to make a
couldn't afford to make a living.
couldn't afford to make a living. His
wife
wife had
couldn't afford to make a living. His
wife had to
wife had to go
couldn't afford to make a living. His
wife had to go to
wife had to go to work.
couldn't afford to make a living. His
wife had to go to work. It
wife had to go to work. It was
couldn't afford to make a living. His
wife had to go to work. It was pathetic.
Everybody
Everybody felt
Everybody felt sorry
Everybody felt sorry for
Everybody felt sorry for him.
Everybody felt sorry for him. And
Everybody felt sorry for him. And he
Everybody felt sorry for him. And he was
a
uh
uh he
uh he was
uh he was a
uh he was a weak
uh he was a weak sister.
uh he was a weak sister. You
uh he was a weak sister. You know,
uh he was a weak sister. You know, he
can't
can't make
uh he was a weak sister. You know, he
can't make enough
can't make enough money
uh he was a weak sister. You know, he
can't make enough money to
can't make enough money to support
uh he was a weak sister. You know, he
can't make enough money to support his
wife.
wife. For
wife. For God's
wife. For God's sake,
wife. For God's sake, she
wife. For God's sake, she she
wife. For God's sake, she she had
wife. For God's sake, she she had to
wife. For God's sake, she she had to get
a
a job
wife. For God's sake, she she had to get
a job at
a job at Walmart.
So,
So, the
So, the meaning
So, the meaning of
So, the meaning of a
So, the meaning of a woman's
So, the meaning of a woman's working
So, the meaning of a woman's working was
completely
completely different.
So, the meaning of a woman's working was
completely different. The
completely different. The only
So, the meaning of a woman's working was
completely different. The only one
completely different. The only one woman
who
who worked
who worked was
who worked was the
who worked was the spinster
who worked was the spinster who
who worked was the spinster who had
who worked was the spinster who had to.
when
when everybody
who worked was the spinster who had to.
when everybody felt
when everybody felt sorry
who worked was the spinster who had to.
when everybody felt sorry for
when everybody felt sorry for the
dispenser.
Uh
so
so you
so you see
so you see how
so you see how different
so you see how different it's
contextualized
contextualized now.
so you see how different it's
contextualized now. So
contextualized now. So you
so you see how different it's
contextualized now. So you see
contextualized now. So you see what
so you see how different it's
contextualized now. So you see what an
error
error it
error it is
error it is to
error it is to go
error it is to go into
error it is to go into retrospect
error it is to go into retrospect into
error it is to go into retrospect into a
different
different context
error it is to go into retrospect into a
different context of
different context of relationship
error it is to go into retrospect into a
different context of relationship and
humanity
humanity and
humanity and what
humanity and what was
humanity and what was normal
humanity and what was normal and
accepted
accepted and
humanity and what was normal and
accepted and expected.
accepted and expected. It
humanity and what was normal and
accepted and expected. It was
accepted and expected. It was now
normal.
normal. It
normal. It was
normal. It was expected
normal. It was expected everybody
fulfilled
fulfilled their
normal. It was expected everybody
fulfilled their social
fulfilled their social role
as
as it
as it was
as it was defined
as it was defined at
as it was defined at the
as it was defined at the time.
There
There was
as it was defined at the time.
There was no
There was no no.
as it was defined at the time.
There was no no. So
There was no no. So you
as it was defined at the time.
There was no no. So you see
There was no no. So you see now
as it was defined at the time.
There was no no. So you see now number
of
of years
of years later
of years later how
of years later how we
of years later how we can
of years later how we can make
of years later how we can make all
of years later how we can make all that
wrong.
wrong. We
of years later how we can make all that
wrong. We can
wrong. We can go
of years later how we can make all that
wrong. We can go back
wrong. We can go back 250
of years later how we can make all that
wrong. We can go back 250 years
wrong. We can go back 250 years and
of years later how we can make all that
wrong. We can go back 250 years and say
how
how it
how it was
how it was all
how it was all wrong.
We
We can
how it was all wrong.
We can go
We can go back
how it was all wrong.
We can go back hundreds
We can go back hundreds of
how it was all wrong.
We can go back hundreds of years
We can go back hundreds of years and
how it was all wrong.
We can go back hundreds of years and say
how
how it
how it was
how it was all
how it was all wrong
how it was all wrong how
how it was all wrong how the
how it was all wrong how the Irish
how it was all wrong how the Irish were
treated.
treated. The
how it was all wrong how the Irish were
treated. The Irish
treated. The Irish were
how it was all wrong how the Irish were
treated. The Irish were treated
treated. The Irish were treated worse
than
than the
than the blacks
than the blacks were
than the blacks were treated.
We
We can
than the blacks were treated.
We can say
We can say it
than the blacks were treated.
We can say it was
We can say it was very
than the blacks were treated.
We can say it was very wrong
We can say it was very wrong for
than the blacks were treated.
We can say it was very wrong for the
black
black kings
black kings of
black kings of Africa
to
to capture
other
other people
other people and
other people and sell
other people and sell them.
other people and sell them. Huh?
other people and sell them. Huh? So
other people and sell them. Huh? So if
you're
you're looking
other people and sell them. Huh? So if
you're looking for
you're looking for moral
other people and sell them. Huh? So if
you're looking for moral fault,
you're looking for moral fault, you
other people and sell them. Huh? So if
you're looking for moral fault, you keep
going
going back
going back farther
going back farther and
going back farther and farther
going back farther and farther into
going back farther and farther into the
origination.
origination. If
going back farther and farther into the
origination. If there
origination. If there was
going back farther and farther into the
origination. If there was slave
origination. If there was slave trading,
where
where did
where did they
where did they get
where did they get the
where did they get the slaves?
where did they get the slaves? They
where did they get the slaves? They got
them
them from
where did they get the slaves? They got
them from slave
them from slave traders.
where did they get the slaves? They got
them from slave traders. Where
them from slave traders. Where did
where did they get the slaves? They got
them from slave traders. Where did the
slave
slave traders
slave traders get
slave traders get them
slave traders get them from?
slave traders get them from? They
slave traders get them from? They got
them
them from
slave traders get them from? They got
them from brokers
them from brokers on
slave traders get them from? They got
them from brokers on the
them from brokers on the docks.
slave traders get them from? They got
them from brokers on the docks. Where'
the
the brokers
the brokers on
the brokers on the
the brokers on the docks
the brokers on the docks got
the brokers on the docks got get
the brokers on the docks got get them?
They
They were
the brokers on the docks got get them?
They were sold
They were sold to
the brokers on the docks got get them?
They were sold to them
They were sold to them by
the brokers on the docks got get them?
They were sold to them by the
They were sold to them by the kings.
Where'
Where' the
Where' the kings
Where' the kings get
Where' the kings get them?
Where' the kings get them? They
Where' the kings get them? They got
Where' the kings get them? They got got
them
them by
Where' the kings get them? They got got
them by intertribal
them by intertribal warfare.
That
That was
That was the
That was the lifestyle.
Instead
Instead of
That was the lifestyle.
Instead of killing
Instead of killing the
That was the lifestyle.
Instead of killing the victims,
Instead of killing the victims, they
That was the lifestyle.
Instead of killing the victims, they let
them
them live.
them live. But
them live. But now
them live. But now they
them live. But now they had
them live. But now they had to
them live. But now they had to pay
them live. But now they had to pay back
for
for their
them live. But now they had to pay back
for their life
for their life by
them live. But now they had to pay back
for their life by a
for their life by a world
them live. But now they had to pay back
for their life by a world by
for their life by a world by a
them live. But now they had to pay back
for their life by a world by a life
for their life by a world by a life of
service.
So
So from
service.
So from one
So from one context
service.
So from one context it
So from one context it was
service.
So from one context it was all
So from one context it was all wrong.
For
For another
For another context,
For another context, the
For another context, the social
For another context, the social reality
of
of the
For another context, the social reality
of the time,
of the time, you
For another context, the social reality
of the time, you can't
of the time, you can't go
For another context, the social reality
of the time, you can't go back
of the time, you can't go back 300
For another context, the social reality
of the time, you can't go back 300 years
ago
ago and
ago and say,
ago and say, you
ago and say, you know,
ago and say, you know, such
ago and say, you know, such and
ago and say, you know, such and such
ago and say, you know, such and such was
wrong.
In
In the
In the olden
In the olden days,
In the olden days, there
In the olden days, there was
In the olden days, there was over
In the olden days, there was over 500
different
different offenses
In the olden days, there was over 500
different offenses that
different offenses that were
In the olden days, there was over 500
different offenses that were punishable
by
by death.
by death. The
by death. The reign
by death. The reign of
by death. The reign of King
by death. The reign of King Louie
by death. The reign of King Louie the
something
something or
by death. The reign of King Louie the
something or other.
something or other. I
by death. The reign of King Louie the
something or other. I think
something or other. I think there's
by death. The reign of King Louie the
something or other. I think there's five
500 offenses
500 offenses that
500 offenses that you
500 offenses that you executed
500 offenses that you executed for.
So
So you
500 offenses that you executed for.
So you see
So you see how
500 offenses that you executed for.
So you see how felicia
So you see how felicia it
500 offenses that you executed for.
So you see how felicia it is
So you see how felicia it is to
500 offenses that you executed for.
So you see how felicia it is to shift
context
and
and go
context
and go in
and go in retrospect
context
and go in retrospect and
and go in retrospect and try
context
and go in retrospect and try to
and go in retrospect and try to make
wrong
wrong something
wrong something that
wrong something that in
wrong something that in the
wrong something that in the context
wrong something that in the context of
the
the time
wrong something that in the context of
the time was
the time was not
wrong something that in the context of
the time was not wrong.
the time was not wrong. It
wrong something that in the context of
the time was not wrong. It was
the time was not wrong. It was certainly
not
not wrong
not wrong for
not wrong for my
not wrong for my mother
not wrong for my mother to
not wrong for my mother to be
not wrong for my mother to be honored
for
for women
not wrong for my mother to be honored
for women to
for women to be
not wrong for my mother to be honored
for women to be honored.
I
I didn't
I didn't feel
I didn't feel like
I didn't feel like I
I didn't feel like I was
I didn't feel like I was putting
I didn't feel like I was putting women
down
down to
I didn't feel like I was putting women
down to hold
down to hold the
I didn't feel like I was putting women
down to hold the door
down to hold the door open
I didn't feel like I was putting women
down to hold the door open for
down to hold the door open for them.
I didn't feel like I was putting women
down to hold the door open for them. I
still
still don't.
So,
So, how
still don't.
So, how can
So, how can a
still don't.
So, how can a woman
So, how can a woman feel
still don't.
So, how can a woman feel insulted
So, how can a woman feel insulted if
still don't.
So, how can a woman feel insulted if I
hold
hold the
hold the door
hold the door open
hold the door open for
hold the door open for them?
hold the door open for them? I've
hold the door open for them? I've had
that
that happen.
hold the door open for them? I've had
that happen. Open
that happen. Open the
hold the door open for them? I've had
that happen. Open the carter
that happen. Open the carter and
hold the door open for them? I've had
that happen. Open the carter and they
say,
say, "Oh,
say, "Oh, I
say, "Oh, I can
say, "Oh, I can open
say, "Oh, I can open it
say, "Oh, I can open it myself."
say, "Oh, I can open it myself." So,
say, "Oh, I can open it myself." So, I
was
was inclined
say, "Oh, I can open it myself." So, I
was inclined by
was inclined by opening
say, "Oh, I can open it myself." So, I
was inclined by opening the
was inclined by opening the door
say, "Oh, I can open it myself." So, I
was inclined by opening the door that
they
they were
they were weak
they were weak and
they were weak and I
they were weak and I was
they were weak and I was superior,
they were weak and I was superior, I
guess.
guess. See,
they were weak and I was superior, I
guess. See, so
guess. See, so paranoia
they were weak and I was superior, I
guess. See, so paranoia completely
distorts
distorts the
distorts the reality.
distorts the reality. I
distorts the reality. I was
distorts the reality. I was brought
distorts the reality. I was brought up
to
to honor
distorts the reality. I was brought up
to honor women,
to honor women, stand
distorts the reality. I was brought up
to honor women, stand up
to honor women, stand up when
distorts the reality. I was brought up
to honor women, stand up when they
to honor women, stand up when they enter
the
the room,
the room, hold
the room, hold the
the room, hold the door
the room, hold the door open.
the room, hold the door open. So,
the room, hold the door open. So, I'm
honoring
honoring them.
the room, hold the door open. So, I'm
honoring them. And
honoring them. And she
the room, hold the door open. So, I'm
honoring them. And she thinks
honoring them. And she thinks she's
being
being dishonored.
being dishonored. So,
being dishonored. So, what
being dishonored. So, what a
being dishonored. So, what a shift.
Don't
Don't you
being dishonored. So, what a shift.
Don't you see
Don't you see this?
being dishonored. So, what a shift.
Don't you see this? How
Don't you see this? How context
being dishonored. So, what a shift.
Don't you see this? How context now
totally
totally changes
totally changes meaning.
totally changes meaning. Context
totally changes meaning. Context totally
changes
changes meaning.
Shift
Shift context
Shift context and
Shift context and you
Shift context and you shift
Shift context and you shift the
statement
statement to
Shift context and you shift the
statement to mean
statement to mean the
Shift context and you shift the
statement to mean the opposite.
statement to mean the opposite. To
Shift context and you shift the
statement to mean the opposite. To mean
the
the opposite.
To
To mean
the opposite.
To mean the
To mean the opposite.
This
This is
This is done
This is done all
This is done all the
This is done all the time.
This is done all the time. This
This is done all the time. This is
This is done all the time. This is done
all
all the
This is done all the time. This is done
all the time.
This
This has
This has been
This has been done
This has been done throughout
This has been done throughout history.
It's
It's uh
This has been done throughout history.
It's uh the
It's uh the Achilles
This has been done throughout history.
It's uh the Achilles heel
It's uh the Achilles heel of
This has been done throughout history.
It's uh the Achilles heel of mankind
It's uh the Achilles heel of mankind is
that
that it
that it can't
that it can't recognize
that it can't recognize truth
that it can't recognize truth from
falsehood.
So
So the
So the only
So the only real
So the only real importance
So the only real importance of
So the only real importance of the
So the only real importance of the work
I've
I've done
So the only real importance of the work
I've done so
I've done so far
So the only real importance of the work
I've done so far is
I've done so far is to
So the only real importance of the work
I've done so far is to point
I've done so far is to point out
So the only real importance of the work
I've done so far is to point out that
nowadays
nowadays there
nowadays there is
nowadays there is a
nowadays there is a means
nowadays there is a means by
nowadays there is a means by which
we
we can
nowadays there is a means by which
we can discern
we can discern truth
nowadays there is a means by which
we can discern truth from
we can discern truth from falsehood.
Throughout
Throughout all
Throughout all of
Throughout all of time,
Throughout all of time, man
Throughout all of time, man has
Throughout all of time, man has had
Throughout all of time, man has had no
compass
compass sailing
Throughout all of time, man has had no
compass sailing the
difficult
difficult and
difficult and dangerous
difficult and dangerous seas
difficult and dangerous seas of
difficult and dangerous seas of human
life
life without
difficult and dangerous seas of human
life without even
life without even a
difficult and dangerous seas of human
life without even a compass
life without even a compass to
difficult and dangerous seas of human
life without even a compass to tell
life without even a compass to tell the
truth
truth from
truth from falsehood.
So
So it's
truth from falsehood.
So it's almost
So it's almost like
truth from falsehood.
So it's almost like a
So it's almost like a new
truth from falsehood.
So it's almost like a new beginning.
Therefore,
Therefore, the
Therefore, the work
Therefore, the work we're
Therefore, the work we're doing
Therefore, the work we're doing is
Therefore, the work we're doing is is
unique
unique in
Therefore, the work we're doing is is
unique in that
unique in that I
Therefore, the work we're doing is is
unique in that I think
unique in that I think it's
Therefore, the work we're doing is is
unique in that I think it's for
unique in that I think it's for the
first
first time
first time in
first time in human
first time in human history
that
that we've
first time in human history
that we've been
that we've been able
first time in human history
that we've been able to
that we've been able to do
first time in human history
that we've been able to do legitimate,
verifiable,
verifiable, bonafideed
verifiable, bonafideed spiritual
research.
The
The only
The only spiritual
information
information we've
The only spiritual
information we've gotten
information we've gotten has
The only spiritual
information we've gotten has been
information we've gotten has been the
spontaneous
spontaneous inner
spontaneous inner awakening
spontaneous inner awakening of
spontaneous inner awakening of various
gurus
gurus and
spontaneous inner awakening of various
gurus and sages
gurus and sages and
spontaneous inner awakening of various
gurus and sages and saints
and
and beloved
and beloved individuals
and beloved individuals in
and beloved individuals in which
and beloved individuals in which it
and beloved individuals in which it has
happened
happened spontaneously
or
or as
or as the
or as the result
or as the result of
or as the result of rigorous
or as the result of rigorous spiritual
work.
So
So we
So we have
So we have the
So we have the information
So we have the information obtained
So we have the information obtained by
the
the subjective
So we have the information obtained by
the subjective awareness
the subjective awareness of
So we have the information obtained by
the subjective awareness of people
the subjective awareness of people who
become
become enlightened.
And
And interestingly
become enlightened.
And interestingly the
And interestingly the subject
become enlightened.
And interestingly the subject subjective
state
state of
the
the condition
state of
the condition we
the condition we call
state of
the condition we call reality
the condition we call reality with
state of
the condition we call reality with a
capital
capital R
capital R has
capital R has been
capital R has been the
capital R has been the same
capital R has been the same for
thousands
thousands of
capital R has been the same for
thousands of years.
thousands of years. There's
capital R has been the same for
thousands of years. There's no
variation.
Every
Every individual
variation.
Every individual who
Every individual who has
variation.
Every individual who has reached
Every individual who has reached a
certain
certain level
certain level of
certain level of consciousness
certain level of consciousness says
exactly
exactly the
certain level of consciousness says
exactly the same
exactly the same thing.
certain level of consciousness says
exactly the same thing. There's
exactly the same thing. There's no
argument.
No
No argument.
argument.
No argument. No
No argument. No difference.
Perhaps
Perhaps a
Perhaps a different
Perhaps a different style
Perhaps a different style of
presentation.
presentation. Speech
Perhaps a different style of
presentation. Speech can
presentation. Speech can be
Perhaps a different style of
presentation. Speech can be in
presentation. Speech can be in Sanskrit
or
or Latin.
Whether
Whether it's
or Latin.
Whether it's in
Whether it's in Sanskrit
or Latin.
Whether it's in Sanskrit or
Whether it's in Sanskrit or Latin
or Latin.
Whether it's in Sanskrit or Latin or
English,
English, the
English, the experience
English, the experience is
English, the experience is the
English, the experience is the same.
So
So we
English, the experience is the same.
So we have
So we have the
English, the experience is the same.
So we have the fact
So we have the fact that
spiritual
spiritual truth
spiritual truth has
spiritual truth has only
spiritual truth has only been
spiritual truth has only been arrived
spiritual truth has only been arrived at
as
as a
spiritual truth has only been arrived at
as a profoundly
as a profoundly subjective
spiritual truth has only been arrived at
as a profoundly subjective state
and
and therefore
that's
that's which
and therefore
that's which I've
that's which I've stated
and therefore
that's which I've stated in
that's which I've stated in books
and therefore
that's which I've stated in books and
research
and
and in
research
and in lectures
and in lectures is
research
and in lectures is that
and in lectures is that the
research
and in lectures is that the absolute
reality
reality is
radical
radical subjectivity.
The
The only
The only way
The only way to
The only way to know
The only way to know anything
The only way to know anything about
The only way to know anything about any
kind
kind of
The only way to know anything about any
kind of truth
kind of truth is
The only way to know anything about any
kind of truth is purely
kind of truth is purely subjective.
Purely
Purely subjective.
There's
There's no
Purely subjective.
There's no way
There's no way you
Purely subjective.
There's no way you can
There's no way you can make
Purely subjective.
There's no way you can make an
There's no way you can make an objective
statement.
There's
There's no
statement.
There's no such
There's no such thing
statement.
There's no such thing as
There's no such thing as an
statement.
There's no such thing as an objective
statement. An
statement. An objective
statement. An objective statement
statement. An objective statement would
be
be something
statement. An objective statement would
be something that
be something that exists
statement. An objective statement would
be something that exists independent
be something that exists independent of
an
an observer.
an observer. And
an observer. And in
an observer. And in as
an observer. And in as much
an observer. And in as much as
an observer. And in as much as it
an observer. And in as much as it would
there's
there's no
an observer. And in as much as it would
there's no observer,
there's no observer, there
an observer. And in as much as it would
there's no observer, there could
there's no observer, there could be
an observer. And in as much as it would
there's no observer, there could be no
objective
objective reality
objective reality because
objective reality because there
objective reality because there would
objective reality because there would be
no
no observer
objective reality because there would be
no observer to
no observer to make
objective reality because there would be
no observer to make any
no observer to make any remarks
objective reality because there would be
no observer to make any remarks about
it.
Therefore,
Therefore, the
it.
Therefore, the closest
Therefore, the closest thing
it.
Therefore, the closest thing that
science
science and
science and the
science and the world
science and the world has
science and the world has come
science and the world has come to
science and the world has come to being
able
able to
science and the world has come to being
able to make
able to make such
science and the world has come to being
able to make such statements,
able to make such statements, of
science and the world has come to being
able to make such statements, of course,
is
is revealed
is revealed now
is revealed now by
is revealed now by quantum
is revealed now by quantum mechanics
as
as subparticle
is revealed now by quantum mechanics
as subparticle physics
as subparticle physics of
is revealed now by quantum mechanics
as subparticle physics of quantum
mechanics
mechanics in
mechanics in which
the
the profound
mechanics in which
the profound role
the profound role of
mechanics in which
the profound role of consciousness
is
is now
is now demonstrated
is now demonstrated for
is now demonstrated for all
is now demonstrated for all to
is now demonstrated for all to see.
All
All of
is now demonstrated for all to see.
All of you
All of you familiar
is now demonstrated for all to see.
All of you familiar with
All of you familiar with quantum
mechanics,
mechanics, raise
mechanics, raise your
mechanics, raise your hand.
Ah,
Ah, great.
Well,
Well, I
Well, I don't
Well, I don't know
Well, I don't know anything
Well, I don't know anything about
Well, I don't know anything about it.
So,
So, I'm
Well, I don't know anything about it.
So, I'm glad
So, I'm glad you're
Well, I don't know anything about it.
So, I'm glad you're here.
We
We can
We can just
We can just look
We can just look at
We can just look at one
We can just look at one simple
We can just look at one simple fact
We can just look at one simple fact for
those
those who
We can just look at one simple fact for
those who are
those who are not
We can just look at one simple fact for
those who are not familiar
those who are not familiar with
We can just look at one simple fact for
those who are not familiar with quantum
mechanics.
mechanics. That
mechanics. That as
mechanics. That as you
mechanics. That as you get
mechanics. That as you get smaller
mechanics. That as you get smaller and
smaller
smaller particles,
mechanics. That as you get smaller and
smaller particles, we
smaller particles, we discover
mechanics. That as you get smaller and
smaller particles, we discover that
there
there are
there are no
there are no infinite
there are no infinite small
there are no infinite small particles
that
that constitute
the
the basic
the basic subatoms
the basic subatoms of
the basic subatoms of all
the basic subatoms of all things.
the basic subatoms of all things. That
the basic subatoms of all things. That a
thing
thing can
the basic subatoms of all things. That a
thing can exist
thing can exist as
the basic subatoms of all things. That a
thing can exist as either
thing can exist as either a
the basic subatoms of all things. That a
thing can exist as either a particle
thing can exist as either a particle or
a
a wave.
a wave. and
a wave. and is
a wave. and is problematic,
a wave. and is problematic, which
a wave. and is problematic, which it
will
will be.
And
And probably
And probably the
And probably the most
And probably the most interesting
experiment,
experiment, which
And probably the most interesting
experiment, which people
experiment, which people who
And probably the most interesting
experiment, which people who don't
experiment, which people who don't know
anything
anything about
anything about quantum
anything about quantum mechanics
anything about quantum mechanics find
quite
quite fascinating,
anything about quantum mechanics find
quite fascinating, is
quite fascinating, is that
anything about quantum mechanics find
quite fascinating, is that when
quite fascinating, is that when you
anything about quantum mechanics find
quite fascinating, is that when you have
an
an atom
an atom of
an atom of matter
an atom of matter and
an atom of matter and it
an atom of matter and it encounters
an atom of matter and it encounters an
atom
atom of
an atom of matter and it encounters an
atom of antimatter,
they
they negate
they negate each
they negate each other.
they negate each other. And
they negate each other. And when
they negate each other. And when that
happens,
happens, two
they negate each other. And when that
happens, two photons
happens, two photons are
they negate each other. And when that
happens, two photons are shot
happens, two photons are shot shot
they negate each other. And when that
happens, two photons are shot shot off
of
of the
of the space.
of the space. Uh
of the space. Uh these
of the space. Uh these photons
of the space. Uh these photons uh
of the space. Uh these photons uh do
of the space. Uh these photons uh do not
rotate.
Uh
Uh they
Uh they go
Uh they go in
Uh they go in opposite
Uh they go in opposite directions.
Uh they go in opposite directions. this
side
side of
Uh they go in opposite directions. this
side of the
side of the universe,
Uh they go in opposite directions. this
side of the universe, this
side of the universe, this side
Uh they go in opposite directions. this
side of the universe, this side of
side of the universe, this side of the
universe.
universe. But
universe. But if
universe. But if an
universe. But if an observer
universe. But if an observer looks
universe. But if an observer looks at
this
this photon
universe. But if an observer looks at
this photon here,
this photon here, it
universe. But if an observer looks at
this photon here, it begins
this photon here, it begins to
universe. But if an observer looks at
this photon here, it begins to rotate.
At
At the
At the very
At the very instant
At the very instant that
At the very instant that he
At the very instant that he looks
At the very instant that he looks at
this
this photon
At the very instant that he looks at
this photon and
this photon and it
At the very instant that he looks at
this photon and it starts
this photon and it starts to
At the very instant that he looks at
this photon and it starts to rotate,
this photon and it starts to rotate, the
photon
photon on
photon on the
photon on the other
photon on the other side
photon on the other side of
photon on the other side of the
photon on the other side of the universe
instantly
instantly starts
photon on the other side of the universe
instantly starts to
instantly starts to rotate
photon on the other side of the universe
instantly starts to rotate in
instantly starts to rotate in the
opposite
opposite direction.
opposite direction. even
opposite direction. even though
opposite direction. even though it's
unobserved.
The
The implication
The implication of
The implication of all
The implication of all this
The implication of all this then
The implication of all this then is
The implication of all this then is that
there
there is
The implication of all this then is that
there is some
there is some matrix
The implication of all this then is that
there is some matrix common
there is some matrix common to
The implication of all this then is that
there is some matrix common to the
entire
entire universe
entire universe which
entire universe which includes
entire universe which includes both
photons
photons within
entire universe which includes both
photons within it.
photons within it. This
entire universe which includes both
photons within it. This photon
photons within it. This photon does
entire universe which includes both
photons within it. This photon does not
cause
cause this
cause this photon
cause this photon to
cause this photon to do
cause this photon to do anything
whatsoever.
It
It has
It has no
It has no contact
It has no contact with
It has no contact with it
within
within the
It has no contact with it
within the microscopic
within the microscopic dimension
It has no contact with it
within the microscopic dimension of
Newtonian
Newtonian physics.
Newtonian physics. It
Newtonian physics. It has
Newtonian physics. It has no
relationship
relationship with
Newtonian physics. It has no
relationship with it.
That
That field
That field which
That field which quantum
That field which quantum mechanics
That field which quantum mechanics comes
closest
closest to
That field which quantum mechanics comes
closest to defining
closest to defining is
That field which quantum mechanics comes
closest to defining is what
closest to defining is what in
That field which quantum mechanics comes
closest to defining is what in spiritual
work
work we
work we refer
work we refer to
work we refer to as
work we refer to as consciousness.
When
When observed
work we refer to as consciousness.
When observed the
When observed the photon
work we refer to as consciousness.
When observed the photon begins
When observed the photon begins to
work we refer to as consciousness.
When observed the photon begins to spin
and
and the
and the photon
and the photon on
and the photon on the
and the photon on the opposite
and the photon on the opposite side
and the photon on the opposite side of
the
the universe
and the photon on the opposite side of
the universe begins
the universe begins to
and the photon on the opposite side of
the universe begins to spin
the universe begins to spin the
and the photon on the opposite side of
the universe begins to spin the opposite
direction
direction just
direction just from
direction just from the
direction just from the act
direction just from the act of
observation
observation to
direction just from the act of
observation to merely
observation to merely look
direction just from the act of
observation to merely look at
observation to merely look at it.
That's
That's the
That's the profound
That's the profound effect
That's the profound effect of
consciousness.
That
That quantum
That quantum space
That quantum space of
That quantum space of infinite
That quantum space of infinite potential
demonstrates
demonstrates how
That quantum space of infinite potential
demonstrates how consciousness
demonstrates how consciousness then
That quantum space of infinite potential
demonstrates how consciousness then can
affect
the
the manifest
affect
the manifest world
the manifest world because
affect
the manifest world because the
observation
is
is not
observation
is not measurable
is not measurable in
observation
is not measurable in the
is not measurable in the manifest
observation
is not measurable in the manifest world.
But
But it
But it its
But it its effect
But it its effect is
it
it would
But it its effect is
it would explain
it would explain then
But it its effect is
it would explain then the
it would explain then the space
But it its effect is
it would explain then the space in
it would explain then the space in which
prayer
prayer could
prayer could have
prayer could have an
prayer could have an effect.
prayer could have an effect. Prayer
changes
the
the context.
the context. It
the context. It has
the context. It has a
the context. It has a profound
energy
energy within
the context. It has a profound
energy within the
energy within the field
the context. It has a profound
energy within the field of
consciousness.
consciousness. So
consciousness. So that
consciousness. So that you
consciousness. So that you might
consciousness. So that you might say
prayer
prayer changes
consciousness. So that you might say
prayer changes the
prayer changes the spin
consciousness. So that you might say
prayer changes the spin of
prayer changes the spin of many
consciousness. So that you might say
prayer changes the spin of many photons
in
in the
in the universe.
and
and affects
in the universe.
and affects the
and affects the consciousness
in the universe.
and affects the consciousness of
and affects the consciousness of many
things
things and
things and people.
So
So that
things and people.
So that expectation
So that expectation then
things and people.
So that expectation then has
So that expectation then has an
things and people.
So that expectation then has an effect
and
and we
and we know
and we know the
and we know the common
and we know the common saying
and we know the common saying in
spiritual
spiritual work
and we know the common saying in
spiritual work what
spiritual work what you
and we know the common saying in
spiritual work what you hold
spiritual work what you hold in
and we know the common saying in
spiritual work what you hold in mind
tends
tends to
tends to manifest.
tends to manifest. It
tends to manifest. It tends
tends to manifest. It tends to
tends to manifest. It tends to manifest
because
because you're
tends to manifest. It tends to manifest
because you're influencing
because you're influencing the
tends to manifest. It tends to manifest
because you're influencing the infinite
quantum
quantum potentiality.
what
what becomes
quantum potentiality.
what becomes manifest
what becomes manifest is
quantum potentiality.
what becomes manifest is is
what becomes manifest is is merely
quantum potentiality.
what becomes manifest is is merely a
potentiality.
So
So with
potentiality.
So with prayer
So with prayer and
potentiality.
So with prayer and why
So with prayer and why what
potentiality.
So with prayer and why what we
So with prayer and why what we hold
potentiality.
So with prayer and why what we hold in
the
the power
the power of
the power of what
the power of what we
the power of what we hold
the power of what we hold in
the power of what we hold in mind,
the power of what we hold in mind, we
increase
increase the
the power of what we hold in mind, we
increase the likelihood
increase the likelihood of
the power of what we hold in mind, we
increase the likelihood of this
potentiality
potentiality arising
potentiality arising rather
potentiality arising rather than
potentiality arising rather than this
potentiality
potentiality and
potentiality arising rather than this
potentiality and the
potentiality and the collapse
potentiality arising rather than this
potentiality and the collapse of
potentiality and the collapse of the
wave
wave function.
Did
Did that
wave function.
Did that sound
Did that sound profound?
Those
Those of
Those of you
Those of you know
Those of you know something
Those of you know something about
quantum
quantum mechanics.
Those of you know something about
quantum mechanics. Is
quantum mechanics. Is that
Those of you know something about
quantum mechanics. Is that correct
quantum mechanics. Is that correct what
I
I said?
I have
I have unanimous
I said?
I have unanimous affirmation.
It's
It's the
It's the spiritual
It's the spiritual implication
It's the spiritual implication of
It's the spiritual implication of that.
You
You see,
It's the spiritual implication of that.
You see, it's
You see, it's difficult
It's the spiritual implication of that.
You see, it's difficult for
You see, it's difficult for the
It's the spiritual implication of that.
You see, it's difficult for the mind
which
which is
which is used
which is used to
which is used to worldspeak
the
the world
which is used to worldspeak
the world of
the world of the
which is used to worldspeak
the world of the Newtonian
the world of the Newtonian micro
microcosm,
the
the measurable
microcosm,
the measurable finite
the measurable finite world
microcosm,
the measurable finite world to
the measurable finite world to make
microcosm,
the measurable finite world to make the
jump
jump to
jump to the
jump to the nonlinear
jump to the nonlinear domain.
So
So we
jump to the nonlinear domain.
So we try
So we try to
jump to the nonlinear domain.
So we try to express
spiritual
spiritual reality
spiritual reality in
spiritual reality in terms
spiritual reality in terms of
spiritual reality in terms of a
progression
progression from
spiritual reality in terms of a
progression from the
progression from the known
spiritual reality in terms of a
progression from the known to
progression from the known to the
unknown
from
from the
unknown
from the linear
from the linear to
unknown
from the linear to the
from the linear to the nonlinear.
unknown
from the linear to the nonlinear. We
established
established the
established the scale
established the scale of
established the scale of consciousness
to
to try
established the scale of consciousness
to try to
to try to establish
a
a way
a way of
a way of comprehending
a way of comprehending going
a way of comprehending going from
a way of comprehending going from the
known
known to
a way of comprehending going from the
known to the
known to the unknown
a way of comprehending going from the
known to the unknown and
known to the unknown and um
a way of comprehending going from the
known to the unknown and um making
known to the unknown and um making it
more
more comprehensible
in
in a
more comprehensible
in a style
in a style of
more comprehensible
in a style of understanding
in a style of understanding which
more comprehensible
in a style of understanding which the
mind
mind is
mind is used
mind is used to.
a
a good
mind is used to.
a good part
a good part of
mind is used to.
a good part of the
a good part of the world
mind is used to.
a good part of the world re
a good part of the world re you
mind is used to.
a good part of the world re you know
refutes
refutes the
refutes the reality
refutes the reality of
refutes the reality of the
refutes the reality of the nonlinear
domain
domain than
refutes the reality of the nonlinear
domain than any
domain than any reality
refutes the reality of the nonlinear
domain than any reality to
domain than any reality to spiritual
spirituality
um
um and
spirituality
um and one
um and one reason
spirituality
um and one reason it
um and one reason it does
spirituality
um and one reason it does so
um and one reason it does so is
spirituality
um and one reason it does so is that
first
first of
first of all
first of all can't
first of all can't comprehend
first of all can't comprehend it
first of all can't comprehend it uh
first of all can't comprehend it uh the
other
other thing
first of all can't comprehend it uh the
other thing is
other thing is it
first of all can't comprehend it uh the
other thing is it doesn't
other thing is it doesn't want
first of all can't comprehend it uh the
other thing is it doesn't want to
other thing is it doesn't want to be
answerable
if
if there's
answerable
if there's a
if there's a spiritual
answerable
if there's a spiritual domain
if there's a spiritual domain it
answerable
if there's a spiritual domain it doesn't
want
want to
want to be
want to be answerable
want to be answerable to
want to be answerable to a
want to be answerable to a spiritual
reality
it
it wants
it wants to
it wants to be
it wants to be free
it wants to be free of
it wants to be free of that
it wants to be free of that threat
it wants to be free of that threat So
it wants to be free of that threat So it
can
can do
it wants to be free of that threat So it
can do what
can do what it
it wants to be free of that threat So it
can do what it wants
can do what it wants to
it wants to be free of that threat So it
can do what it wants to do.
The
The ego
The ego also
The ego also has
The ego also has another
The ego also has another way
The ego also has another way around
The ego also has another way around that
however
however and
The ego also has another way around that
however and that
however and that is
The ego also has another way around that
however and that is to
however and that is to sanctify
um
um a
um a sudo
um a sudo sort
um a sudo sort of
um a sudo sort of a
um a sudo sort of a pseudo
spiritualization
spiritualization of
um a sudo sort of a pseudo
spiritualization of that
spiritualization of that which
um a sudo sort of a pseudo
spiritualization of that which is
obviously
obviously not
obviously not spiritual.
Um
Um that's
obviously not spiritual.
Um that's the
Um that's the abuse
obviously not spiritual.
Um that's the abuse of
Um that's the abuse of the
obviously not spiritual.
Um that's the abuse of the name
Um that's the abuse of the name of
obviously not spiritual.
Um that's the abuse of the name of God
which
which we
which we see
which we see uh
which we see uh in
which we see uh in today's
which we see uh in today's society
displayed
displayed in
which we see uh in today's society
displayed in quite
displayed in quite an
which we see uh in today's society
displayed in quite an intense
displayed in quite an intense degree.
The
The idea
The idea is
The idea is the
The idea is the psychotic
The idea is the psychotic does
The idea is the psychotic does the
The idea is the psychotic does the same
thing.
thing. Oh,
The idea is the psychotic does the same
thing. Oh, God
thing. Oh, God told
The idea is the psychotic does the same
thing. Oh, God told me
thing. Oh, God told me to
The idea is the psychotic does the same
thing. Oh, God told me to do
thing. Oh, God told me to do it.
The idea is the psychotic does the same
thing. Oh, God told me to do it. Well,
now
now can
now can you
now can you say
now can you say if
now can you say if God
now can you say if God told
now can you say if God told somebody
now can you say if God told somebody to
do
do something,
now can you say if God told somebody to
do something, God
do something, God told
now can you say if God told somebody to
do something, God told me
do something, God told me to
now can you say if God told somebody to
do something, God told me to kill
do something, God told me to kill her,
so
so I
so I did.
so I did. You
so I did. You know
so I did. You know what
so I did. You know what I
so I did. You know what I mean?
God.
God. So,
the
the good
the good name
the good name of
the good name of God,
the good name of God, I'm
the good name of God, I'm starting
the good name of God, I'm starting a
the good name of God, I'm starting a a
God's
God's uh
the good name of God, I'm starting a a
God's uh name
God's uh name protection
the good name of God, I'm starting a a
God's uh name protection society.
God's uh name protection society. God
has
has been
has been slandered
has been slandered right
has been slandered right and
has been slandered right and left.
has been slandered right and left. Every
day
day is
has been slandered right and left. Every
day is headline.
day is headline. Slanders
has been slandered right and left. Every
day is headline. Slanders God.
day is headline. Slanders God. uh
we're
we're going
we're going to
we're going to kill
we're going to kill thousands
we're going to kill thousands of
we're going to kill thousands of people
in
in the
we're going to kill thousands of people
in the name
in the name of
we're going to kill thousands of people
in the name of God.
in the name of God. Uh
we're going to kill thousands of people
in the name of God. Uh so
in the name of God. Uh so God
we're going to kill thousands of people
in the name of God. Uh so God is
in the name of God. Uh so God is the
great
great excuse
great excuse for
great excuse for getting
great excuse for getting away
great excuse for getting away with
murder.
murder. Huh?
great excuse for getting away with
murder. Huh? God
murder. Huh? God is
great excuse for getting away with
murder. Huh? God is the
murder. Huh? God is the great
great excuse for getting away with
murder. Huh? God is the great excuse.
And
And some
And some religions
And some religions have
And some religions have done
And some religions have done it.
And some religions have done it. They
call
call it
And some religions have done it. They
call it in
call it in for
And some religions have done it. They
call it in for the
call it in for the good
And some religions have done it. They
call it in for the good of
call it in for the good of the
And some religions have done it. They
call it in for the good of the faith
which
which means
which means you
which means you know
uh
uh for
which means you know
uh for the
uh for the good
which means you know
uh for the good of
uh for the good of the
which means you know
uh for the good of the faith
uh for the good of the faith in
which means you know
uh for the good of the faith in the
uh for the good of the faith in the name
of
of God
of God you
of God you can
of God you can get
of God you can get away
of God you can get away with
of God you can get away with anything
anything
anything because
of God you can get away with anything
anything because once
anything because once you
of God you can get away with anything
anything because once you cite
anything because once you cite God
of God you can get away with anything
anything because once you cite God then
all
all rules
all rules of
all rules of human
all rules of human morality
all rules of human morality dissolve
and
and that
all rules of human morality dissolve
and that allows
and that allows your
all rules of human morality dissolve
and that allows your you
and that allows your you to
all rules of human morality dissolve
and that allows your you to be
and that allows your you to be free
all rules of human morality dissolve
and that allows your you to be free to
do
do anything
do anything you
do anything you want.
When
When I
do anything you want.
When I have
When I have a
do anything you want.
When I have a patient
When I have a patient who
do anything you want.
When I have a patient who hears
When I have a patient who hears God
talking
talking to
talking to them,
it's
it's dangerous
talking to them,
it's dangerous because
it's dangerous because they
talking to them,
it's dangerous because they can
it's dangerous because they can do
talking to them,
it's dangerous because they can do they
can
can and
can and will
can and will do
can and will do anything,
can and will do anything, anything
can and will do anything, anything the
voice
voice happens
can and will do anything, anything the
voice happens to
voice happens to tell
can and will do anything, anything the
voice happens to tell them.
Lower
Lower astral
Lower astral entities
Lower astral entities have
Lower astral entities have learned
Lower astral entities have learned this
over
over the
Lower astral entities have learned this
over the millennia
that
that all
that all you
that all you have
that all you have to
that all you have to do
that all you have to do is
that all you have to do is tell
that all you have to do is tell the
listener
listener that
that all you have to do is tell the
listener that you're
listener that you're God
that all you have to do is tell the
listener that you're God and
listener that you're God and you
that all you have to do is tell the
listener that you're God and you and
listener that you're God and you and you
can
can run
can run them
can run them like
can run them like a
can run them like a machine.
Yeah.
The
The lower
The lower astral
The lower astral domain
The lower astral domain is
The lower astral domain is made
The lower astral domain is made up
The lower astral domain is made up of
those
those spirits
The lower astral domain is made up of
those spirits who
those spirits who have
The lower astral domain is made up of
those spirits who have refused
those spirits who have refused God.
Refuse
Refuse God.
Refuse God. Not
Refuse God. Not those
Refuse God. Not those who
Refuse God. Not those who are
Refuse God. Not those who are unable
Refuse God. Not those who are unable to
recognize
recognize God
Refuse God. Not those who are unable to
recognize God like
recognize God like atheists
Refuse God. Not those who are unable to
recognize God like atheists or
something.
something. Atheists
something. Atheists are
something. Atheists are are
something. Atheists are are integrous.
Integris
Integris atheist.
something. Atheists are are integrous.
Integris atheist. We
Integris atheist. We once
something. Atheists are are integrous.
Integris atheist. We once asked
Integris atheist. We once asked is
something. Atheists are are integrous.
Integris atheist. We once asked is there
a
a place
a place in
a place in heaven
a place in heaven for
a place in heaven for him
a place in heaven for him and
a place in heaven for him and said
a place in heaven for him and said yes.
To
To say
a place in heaven for him and said yes.
To say that
To say that in
a place in heaven for him and said yes.
To say that in all
To say that in all due
a place in heaven for him and said yes.
To say that in all due honesty,
To say that in all due honesty, I
a place in heaven for him and said yes.
To say that in all due honesty, I can't
really
really get
really get what
really get what God
really get what God is
really get what God is all
really get what God is all about
really get what God is all about is
really get what God is all about is just
being
being honest
really get what God is all about is just
being honest and
being honest and uh
really get what God is all about is just
being honest and uh means
being honest and uh means I
really get what God is all about is just
being honest and uh means I I'm
being honest and uh means I I'm not
really get what God is all about is just
being honest and uh means I I'm not that
evolved
evolved yet.
evolved yet. I
evolved yet. I can't,
evolved yet. I can't, you
evolved yet. I can't, you know,
evolved yet. I can't, you know, it's
evolved yet. I can't, you know, it's not
a
a reality
evolved yet. I can't, you know, it's not
a reality to
a reality to me.
evolved yet. I can't, you know, it's not
a reality to me. That's
a reality to me. That's an
evolved yet. I can't, you know, it's not
a reality to me. That's an honest
statement
statement of
statement of truth.
statement of truth. You
statement of truth. You get
statement of truth. You get to
statement of truth. You get to come
statement of truth. You get to come back
here
and
and keep
and keep moving
and keep moving on
and keep moving on till
and keep moving on till it
and keep moving on till it does
and keep moving on till it does start
making
making sense
and keep moving on till it does start
making sense to
making sense to you.
and keep moving on till it does start
making sense to you. But
making sense to you. But it's
and keep moving on till it does start
making sense to you. But it's a
making sense to you. But it's a good
starting
starting place.
starting place. It
starting place. It means
starting place. It means it's
starting place. It means it's at
starting place. It means it's at least
integrity.
No,
No, the
No, the lower
No, the lower astral
No, the lower astral is
No, the lower astral is those
No, the lower astral is those who
No, the lower astral is those who were
given
given the
No, the lower astral is those who were
given the choice
given the choice and
No, the lower astral is those who were
given the choice and refuse
given the choice and refuse God.
No, the lower astral is those who were
given the choice and refuse God. That's
a
a totally
a totally different
can
can of
a totally different
can of worms.
can of worms. Um
a totally different
can of worms. Um and
can of worms. Um and we've
a totally different
can of worms. Um and we've noted
in
in doing
in doing the
in doing the spiritual
in doing the spiritual research
in doing the spiritual research a
in doing the spiritual research a lot
in doing the spiritual research a lot of
times
times that
in doing the spiritual research a lot of
times that uh
times that uh a
in doing the spiritual research a lot of
times that uh a writer
times that uh a writer at
in doing the spiritual research a lot of
times that uh a writer at one
times that uh a writer at one time
in doing the spiritual research a lot of
times that uh a writer at one time at
the
the time
the time they
the time they did
the time they did their
the time they did their writer
the time they did their writer cal
the time they did their writer cal the
writings
writings calibrated
the time they did their writer cal the
writings calibrated at
writings calibrated at a
the time they did their writer cal the
writings calibrated at a certain
writings calibrated at a certain number
and
and then
and then the
and then the teacher
somewhat
somewhat later
and then the teacher
somewhat later in
somewhat later in life
and then the teacher
somewhat later in life calibrates
somewhat later in life calibrates at
and then the teacher
somewhat later in life calibrates at a
considerably
considerably lower
considerably lower number
and
and it's
considerably lower number
and it's as
and it's as though
considerably lower number
and it's as though one
and it's as though one rises
considerably lower number
and it's as though one rises to
and it's as though one rises to a
certain
certain level
certain level of
certain level of awareness
certain level of awareness awareness
certain level of awareness awareness and
consciousness
and
and that
and that summons
and that summons forth
and that summons forth a
and that summons forth a test.
and that summons forth a test. It's
traditionally
traditionally called
and that summons forth a test. It's
traditionally called a
traditionally called a test,
and that summons forth a test. It's
traditionally called a test, a
traditionally called a test, a test
and that summons forth a test. It's
traditionally called a test, a test or
traditionally called a test, a test or a
temptation
temptation or
temptation or a
temptation or a challenge.
When
When you
temptation or a challenge.
When you make
When you make a
temptation or a challenge.
When you make a spiritual
When you make a spiritual statement
about
about your
about your spiritual
about your spiritual reality,
it's
it's almost
about your spiritual reality,
it's almost as
it's almost as though
about your spiritual reality,
it's almost as though you
it's almost as though you pull
about your spiritual reality,
it's almost as though you pull up
it's almost as though you pull up from
your
your own
your own unconscious
a
a challenge
your own unconscious
a challenge to
a challenge to that
your own unconscious
a challenge to that statement.
many
many living
many living today
many living today and
many living today and many
many living today and many living
many living today and many living in
many living today and many living in the
past,
past, many
many living today and many living in the
past, many living
past, many living in
many living today and many living in the
past, many living in the
past, many living in the far
many living today and many living in the
past, many living in the far distant
past.
Uh
Uh much
past.
Uh much to
Uh much to our
past.
Uh much to our astonishment.
So
because
because we're
So
because we're in
because we're in a
So
because we're in a way
because we're in a way the
So
because we're in a way the first
because we're in a way the first ones
really
really doing
really doing this
really doing this kind
really doing this kind of
really doing this kind of kind
really doing this kind of kind of
spiritual
spiritual research,
it's
it's sometimes
it's sometimes somewhat
it's sometimes somewhat challenging
it's sometimes somewhat challenging to
us
us what
it's sometimes somewhat challenging to
us what to
us what to do
it's sometimes somewhat challenging to
us what to do about
us what to do about this
it's sometimes somewhat challenging to
us what to do about this discovery
us what to do about this discovery and
to
to assess
to assess what
to assess what the
to assess what the impact
to assess what the impact might
to assess what the impact might be
to assess what the impact might be on
the
the world
to assess what the impact might be on
the world or
the world or socially.
uh
uh to
uh to discuss
uh to discuss certain
uh to discuss certain things.
So
So in
uh to discuss certain things.
So in a
So in a way
this
this group
this group uh
this group uh to
this group uh to whom
this group uh to whom we
this group uh to whom we speak
this group uh to whom we speak and
this group uh to whom we speak and the
readers
readers of
this group uh to whom we speak and the
readers of the
readers of the things
this group uh to whom we speak and the
readers of the things I've
readers of the things I've written
this group uh to whom we speak and the
readers of the things I've written were
really
really the
really the first
really the first ones
really the first ones in
really the first ones in in
really the first ones in in history
really the first ones in in history to
look
look at
really the first ones in in history to
look at things
look at things you
really the first ones in in history to
look at things you might
look at things you might say
really the first ones in in history to
look at things you might say to
look at things you might say to look
really the first ones in in history to
look at things you might say to look at
subjectivity
objectively.
There's
There's a
There's a mastery
There's a mastery of
There's a mastery of a
There's a mastery of a turn
There's a mastery of a turn phrase.
Uh
Uh to
There's a mastery of a turn phrase.
Uh to take
Uh to take a
There's a mastery of a turn phrase.
Uh to take a to
Uh to take a to take
There's a mastery of a turn phrase.
Uh to take a to take a
Uh to take a to take a integrous
way
way of
way of using
way of using an
way of using an integrous
way of using an integrous means
way of using an integrous means to
examine
examine that
way of using an integrous means to
examine that which
examine that which is
way of using an integrous means to
examine that which is difficult
examine that which is difficult to
understand
and
and which
understand
and which has
and which has been
understand
and which has been confused
and which has been confused over
understand
and which has been confused over the
centuries.
centuries. Now
centuries. Now the
centuries. Now the confusion
centuries. Now the confusion over
centuries. Now the confusion over the
centuries
centuries has
centuries. Now the confusion over the
centuries has been
centuries has been at
centuries. Now the confusion over the
centuries has been at great
centuries has been at great cost
centuries. Now the confusion over the
centuries has been at great cost to
mankind.
Mankind
Mankind pays
mankind.
Mankind pays a
Mankind pays a huge
mankind.
Mankind pays a huge cost.
Mankind pays a huge cost. We're
mankind.
Mankind pays a huge cost. We're not
talking
talking about
talking about academic
talking about academic nicities
talking about academic nicities today
from
from some
talking about academic nicities today
from some kind
from some kind of
talking about academic nicities today
from some kind of a
from some kind of a lofty
talking about academic nicities today
from some kind of a lofty intellectual
viewpoint.
viewpoint. We're
viewpoint. We're talking
viewpoint. We're talking about
viewpoint. We're talking about the
mistakes
mistakes that
viewpoint. We're talking about the
mistakes that will
mistakes that will cost
viewpoint. We're talking about the
mistakes that will cost you
mistakes that will cost you 40
viewpoint. We're talking about the
mistakes that will cost you 40 million
lives,
30 million
30 million lives.
lives,
30 million lives. One
30 million lives. One mistake,
lives,
30 million lives. One mistake, one
leader,
leader, 30
leader, 30 million
leader, 30 million lives.
How
How often?
leader, 30 million lives.
How often? Very
How often? Very often
leader, 30 million lives.
How often? Very often in
How often? Very often in my
leader, 30 million lives.
How often? Very often in my lifetime,
Chairman
Chairman Mayo
Chairman Mayo mis
Chairman Mayo mis totally
Chairman Mayo mis totally miscalculated
the
the human
Chairman Mayo mis totally miscalculated
the human psyche.
the human psyche. Didn't
Chairman Mayo mis totally miscalculated
the human psyche. Didn't realize
the human psyche. Didn't realize that
the
the human
the human brain
the human brain has
the human brain has a
the human brain has a a
the human brain has a a reward
the human brain has a a reward system
and
and without
the human brain has a a reward system
and without the
and without the reward
the human brain has a a reward system
and without the reward system,
and without the reward system, people
weren't
weren't going
weren't going to
weren't going to work
weren't going to work on
weren't going to work on a
weren't going to work on a collective
farm.
Chairman
Chairman Mayo's
Chairman Mayo's agricultural
Chairman Mayo's agricultural experiment
caused
caused the
Chairman Mayo's agricultural experiment
caused the greatest
caused the greatest famine
Chairman Mayo's agricultural experiment
caused the greatest famine in
caused the greatest famine in history.
I
I don't
I don't know,
I don't know, 30
I don't know, 30 million
I don't know, 30 million died
I don't know, 30 million died of
starvation.
starvation. 40,
I don't know, 30 million died of
starvation. 40, I
starvation. 40, I don't
I don't know, 30 million died of
starvation. 40, I don't know.
Stalin
Stalin killed
Stalin killed off
Stalin killed off another
Stalin killed off another 30
Stalin killed off another 30 million
Stalin killed off another 30 million and
the
the Guls
Stalin killed off another 30 million and
the Guls and
the Guls and Siberia.
Hitler
Hitler killed
Hitler killed off
Hitler killed off 70
Hitler killed off 70 million.
You're
You're talking
Hitler killed off 70 million.
You're talking about
You're talking about more
Hitler killed off 70 million.
You're talking about more people
You're talking about more people getting
killed
killed than
killed than the
killed than the entire
killed than the entire population
killed than the entire population United
States
States just
killed than the entire population United
States just in
States just in my
killed than the entire population United
States just in my lifetime.
States just in my lifetime. Just
killed than the entire population United
States just in my lifetime. Just in
States just in my lifetime. Just in my
lifetime.
And
And these
lifetime.
And these all
And these all comes
lifetime.
And these all comes all
And these all comes all come
lifetime.
And these all comes all come about
And these all comes all come about as
the
the result
the result of
the result of distortions
the result of distortions of
the result of distortions of truth
the result of distortions of truth in
which
which the
the result of distortions of truth in
which the context
which the context has
the result of distortions of truth in
which the context has been
which the context has been disguised
the result of distortions of truth in
which the context has been disguised or
falsified.
So
So what
falsified.
So what we're
So what we're talking
falsified.
So what we're talking about
So what we're talking about is
falsified.
So what we're talking about is not
necessarily
necessarily an
necessarily an academic
necessarily an academic nicity
necessarily an academic nicity at
necessarily an academic nicity at all.
We're
We're talking
necessarily an academic nicity at all.
We're talking about
We're talking about survival
necessarily an academic nicity at all.
We're talking about survival of
We're talking about survival of entire
nations
nations entire
nations entire continents
nations entire continents practically.
You
You can
nations entire continents practically.
You can wipe
You can wipe out
nations entire continents practically.
You can wipe out a
You can wipe out a whole
nations entire continents practically.
You can wipe out a whole race
You can wipe out a whole race of
nations entire continents practically.
You can wipe out a whole race of people
with
with one
with one distortion
with one distortion of
with one distortion of truth.
Now,
Now, because
with one distortion of truth.
Now, because man
Now, because man couldn't
with one distortion of truth.
Now, because man couldn't tell
Now, because man couldn't tell truth
from
from falsehood,
he
he was
from falsehood,
he was like
he was like the
from falsehood,
he was like the lamb
he was like the lamb waiting
from falsehood,
he was like the lamb waiting for
he was like the lamb waiting for the
slaughter.
All
All you
slaughter.
All you need
All you need is
slaughter.
All you need is one
All you need is one fancy
slaughter.
All you need is one fancy slogan.
Bunch
Bunch of
Bunch of students
Bunch of students throwing
Bunch of students throwing rocks
Bunch of students throwing rocks at
Bunch of students throwing rocks at the
barricades.
barricades. There
Bunch of students throwing rocks at the
barricades. There you
barricades. There you go.
Every
Every revolution
Every revolution is
Every revolution is started
Every revolution is started by
Every revolution is started by a
Every revolution is started by a bunch
of
of stupid
Every revolution is started by a bunch
of stupid kids
of stupid kids throwing
Every revolution is started by a bunch
of stupid kids throwing rocks
of stupid kids throwing rocks at
Every revolution is started by a bunch
of stupid kids throwing rocks at the
police
so
so they
police
so they can
so they can get
police
so they can get the
so they can get the police
police
so they can get the police to
so they can get the police to fire.
Once
Once the
Once the police
Once the police fire,
Once the police fire, you
Once the police fire, you got
Once the police fire, you got a
Once the police fire, you got a dead
student.
student. Camera,
dead
dead student.
Little
Little child
dead student.
Little child is
Little child is better.
dead student.
Little child is better. In
Little child is better. In the
dead student.
Little child is better. In the Middle
East,
East, they
East, they specialize
East, they specialize in
East, they specialize in slaughtered
children.
You
You get
You get a
You get a little
You get a little three-year-old
You get a little three-year-old dead
You get a little three-year-old dead on
the
the street.
Propaganda
Propaganda value
Propaganda value is
Propaganda value is tremendous.
Propaganda value is tremendous. Always
got
got the
Propaganda value is tremendous. Always
got the snipers
got the snipers to
Propaganda value is tremendous. Always
got the snipers to kill
got the snipers to kill a
Propaganda value is tremendous. Always
got the snipers to kill a kid.
got the snipers to kill a kid. You
Propaganda value is tremendous. Always
got the snipers to kill a kid. You need
a
a kid
a kid in
a kid in every
a kid in every propaganda
a kid in every propaganda shot.
You
You live
a kid in every propaganda shot.
You live in
You live in a
a kid in every propaganda shot.
You live in a place
You live in a place that's
a kid in every propaganda shot.
You live in a place that's attacked
You live in a place that's attacked by
the
the by
the by the
the by the enemy
the by the enemy and
the by the enemy and hundreds
the by the enemy and hundreds and
thousands
thousands are
the by the enemy and hundreds and
thousands are killed.
thousands are killed. What
the by the enemy and hundreds and
thousands are killed. What do
thousands are killed. What do you
the by the enemy and hundreds and
thousands are killed. What do you do
there?
there? You
there? You send
there? You send your
there? You send your kid
there? You send your kid to
there? You send your kid to school
there? You send your kid to school in
there? You send your kid to school in a
school
school bus
right
right between
right between the
right between the snipers,
right between the snipers, right?
right between the snipers, right? Have
right between the snipers, right? Have a
good
good day.
right between the snipers, right? Have a
good day. School
good day. School kids,
right between the snipers, right? Have a
good day. School kids, you
good day. School kids, you live
right between the snipers, right? Have a
good day. School kids, you live there,
folks.
folks. You
folks. You move
folks. You move your
folks. You move your grandparents
folks. You move your grandparents in.
Oh
Oh my
folks. You move your grandparents in.
Oh my god.
Oh my god. And
folks. You move your grandparents in.
Oh my god. And now
Oh my god. And now we're
folks. You move your grandparents in.
Oh my god. And now we're supposed
Oh my god. And now we're supposed to
feel
feel sorry
feel sorry for
feel sorry for you.
You
You see
feel sorry for you.
You see the
You see the manipulation
feel sorry for you.
You see the manipulation that
You see the manipulation that goes
feel sorry for you.
You see the manipulation that goes on
endlessly.
endlessly. the
endlessly. the endless
endlessly. the endless manipulation,
the
the endless
endlessly. the endless manipulation,
the endless distortion,
the
the endless
the endless energy
the endless energy that
the endless energy that the
the endless energy that the ego
the endless energy that the ego gets
the endless energy that the ego gets out
of
of this.
The
The um
The um energy
The um energy of
The um energy of being
The um energy of being right,
The um energy of being right, righteous
indignation
indignation is
The um energy of being right, righteous
indignation is addicting.
indignation is addicting. The
The um energy of being right, righteous
indignation is addicting. The world
loves
loves it.
The
The world
loves it.
The world lives
The world lives on
loves it.
The world lives on righteous
The world lives on righteous indignation
and
and mutual
and mutual provocation
so
so that
and mutual provocation
so that you
so that you can
and mutual provocation
so that you can fall
so that you can fall back
and mutual provocation
so that you can fall back into
so that you can fall back into righteous
indignation
indignation and
indignation and be
indignation and be the
indignation and be the barter
indignation and be the barter martyr.
And
And now
indignation and be the barter martyr.
And now hate
And now hate and
indignation and be the barter martyr.
And now hate and of
And now hate and of course
indignation and be the barter martyr.
And now hate and of course what
And now hate and of course what you
indignation and be the barter martyr.
And now hate and of course what you do
is
is you
is you keep
is you keep out
is you keep out of
is you keep out of awareness
is you keep out of awareness the
is you keep out of awareness the context
in
in which
is you keep out of awareness the context
in which all
in which all this
is you keep out of awareness the context
in which all this is
in which all this is happening.
is you keep out of awareness the context
in which all this is happening. And
in which all this is happening. And what
is
is the
is the context?
is the context? The
is the context? The context
is the context? The context is
is the context? The context is that
you're
you're causing
is the context? The context is that
you're causing it.
you're causing it. That's
is the context? The context is that
you're causing it. That's it.
Who
Who put
Who put your
Who put your kids
Who put your kids on
Who put your kids on the
Who put your kids on the school
Who put your kids on the school bus
Who put your kids on the school bus that
got
got blown
Who put your kids on the school bus that
got blown up
got blown up this
Who put your kids on the school bus that
got blown up this morning?
got blown up this morning? mother
Who put your kids on the school bus that
got blown up this morning? mother didn't
have
have to
have to move
have to move from
have to move from Detroit
have to move from Detroit to
have to move from Detroit to make
have to move from Detroit to make a
political
political statement
have to move from Detroit to make a
political statement so
political statement so your
have to move from Detroit to make a
political statement so your kids
political statement so your kids could
get
get blown
get blown up
get blown up on
get blown up on a
get blown up on a school
get blown up on a school bus.
get blown up on a school bus. How
get blown up on a school bus. How about
taking
taking responsibility
get blown up on a school bus. How about
taking responsibility for
taking responsibility for that?
See,
I
I don't
See,
I don't want
I don't want my
See,
I don't want my kids
I don't want my kids on
See,
I don't want my kids on a
I don't want my kids on a school
See,
I don't want my kids on a school bus
I don't want my kids on a school bus in
a
a war
a war zone.
a war zone. Thank
a war zone. Thank you.
All right.
All right. So,
a war zone. Thank you.
All right. So, taking
All right. So, taking responsibility
means
means stop
means stop creating
means stop creating a
means stop creating a false
means stop creating a false context.
It's
It's because
means stop creating a false context.
It's because of
keeping
keeping context
keeping context and
keeping context and content
keeping context and content carefully
separated
separated that
keeping context and content carefully
separated that all
separated that all the
keeping context and content carefully
separated that all the catastrophes
separated that all the catastrophes of
the
the world
the world have
the world have come
the world have come about.
So
So what
the world have come about.
So what we're
So what we're talking
the world have come about.
So what we're talking about
So what we're talking about today
the world have come about.
So what we're talking about today is
basic
you
you might
basic
you might say
you might say to
basic
you might say to all
you might say to all human
basic
you might say to all human suffering.
The
The game
The game of
The game of playing
The game of playing martyr.
The game of playing martyr. The
The game of playing martyr. The game
The game of playing martyr. The game of
provoking
provoking other
The game of playing martyr. The game of
provoking other people
provoking other people to
The game of playing martyr. The game of
provoking other people to be
provoking other people to be the
attacker.
The
The narcissistic
attacker.
The narcissistic ego
The narcissistic ego game
attacker.
The narcissistic ego game of
entitlement.
It's
It's out
entitlement.
It's out of
It's out of entitlement
entitlement.
It's out of entitlement that
It's out of entitlement that all
entitlement.
It's out of entitlement that all of
these
these phenomena
these phenomena arise.
these phenomena arise. First
these phenomena arise. First you
these phenomena arise. First you have
these phenomena arise. First you have to
misconceive.
Then
Then you
Then you have
Then you have to
Then you have to have
Then you have to have sufficient
Then you have to have sufficient egotism
out
out of
Then you have to have sufficient egotism
out of which
out of which comes
Then you have to have sufficient egotism
out of which comes entitlement.
out of which comes entitlement. And
Then you have to have sufficient egotism
out of which comes entitlement. And now
you
you who
you who feel
you who feel entitled
to
to do
you who feel entitled
to do and
to do and carry
you who feel entitled
to do and carry out
to do and carry out within
you who feel entitled
to do and carry out within the
to do and carry out within the world,
a
a distorted
a distorted perception
a distorted perception of
a distorted perception of reality.
It's
It's one
a distorted perception of reality.
It's one thing
It's one thing to
a distorted perception of reality.
It's one thing to see
It's one thing to see Americans
a distorted perception of reality.
It's one thing to see Americans as
It's one thing to see Americans as the
great
great Satan.
It's
It's another
great Satan.
It's another to
It's another to feel
great Satan.
It's another to feel entitled
It's another to feel entitled therefore
to
to bomb
to bomb and
to bomb and civilians.
to bomb and civilians. Huh?
to bomb and civilians. Huh? So
entitlement
entitlement then
to bomb and civilians. Huh? So
entitlement then gives
entitlement then gives the
to bomb and civilians. Huh? So
entitlement then gives the permission
for
for the
for the action.
The
The entitlement
for the action.
The entitlement then
The entitlement then which
for the action.
The entitlement then which in
The entitlement then which in the
for the action.
The entitlement then which in the end
entitles
entitles you
entitles you to
entitles you to eventually
entitles you to eventually go
entitles you to eventually go to
entitles you to eventually go to the
lower
lower astral
entitles you to eventually go to the
lower astral realms.
You're
You're entitled.
You're entitled. All
You're entitled. All right.
You're entitled. All right. Oh
You're entitled. All right. Oh god.
Realize
Realize that.
You're entitled. All right. Oh god.
Realize that. Okay.
Realize that. Okay. So
You're entitled. All right. Oh god.
Realize that. Okay. So because
Realize that. Okay. So because your
political
political philosophy
is
is so
political philosophy
is so incredibly
is so incredibly wonderful
political philosophy
is so incredibly wonderful now
is so incredibly wonderful now you
political philosophy
is so incredibly wonderful now you are
entitled
entitled to
entitled to enslave
entitled to enslave to
entitled to enslave to use
entitled to enslave to use the
guillotine
guillotine to
entitled to enslave to use the
guillotine to send
guillotine to send him
entitled to enslave to use the
guillotine to send him off
guillotine to send him off to
entitled to enslave to use the
guillotine to send him off to the
guillotine to send him off to the goolog
to
to put
to put them
to put them in
to put them in chains.
So
So the
to put them in chains.
So the dangerous
So the dangerous part
to put them in chains.
So the dangerous part then
So the dangerous part then comes
to put them in chains.
So the dangerous part then comes from
the
the entitlement
the entitlement of
the entitlement of the
the entitlement of the megalomaniac
the entitlement of the megalomaniac who
is
is always
the entitlement of the megalomaniac who
is always an
is always an excellent
the entitlement of the megalomaniac who
is always an excellent demagogue.
So
So the
So the demagogue
So the demagogue then
So the demagogue then uses
So the demagogue then uses this
distorted
distorted reality
plays
plays upon
plays upon the
plays upon the ignorance
plays upon the ignorance of
plays upon the ignorance of the
plays upon the ignorance of the masses.
But
But the
plays upon the ignorance of the masses.
But the the
But the the real
plays upon the ignorance of the masses.
But the the real severe
But the the real severe action
plays upon the ignorance of the masses.
But the the real severe action then
But the the real severe action then is
in
in the
in the extreme
in the extreme entitlement.
Melovich.
Um
Um we
Um we spoke
Um we spoke about
Um we spoke about him
Um we spoke about him before
Um we spoke about him before because
because
because he's
Um we spoke about him before because
because he's such
because he's such a
Um we spoke about him before because
because he's such a perfect
because he's such a perfect example.
When
When you
When you watch
When you watch him
When you watch him on
When you watch him on television,
When you watch him on television, you
see
see the
When you watch him on television, you
see the supreme
see the supreme arrogance
of
of one
of one who
of one who feels
of one who feels that
of one who feels that their
of one who feels that their own
of one who feels that their own ego
of one who feels that their own ego is
actually
actually God.
So
the
the basis
So
the basis then
the basis then is
So
the basis then is the
the basis then is the basis
So
the basis then is the basis of
the basis then is the basis of the
So
the basis then is the basis of the ego
then
then is
then is that
then is that it
then is that it assumes
then is that it assumes that
then is that it assumes that it
then is that it assumes that it is
then is that it assumes that it is God
and
the
the megalomaniac
the megalomaniac refuses
the megalomaniac refuses to
the megalomaniac refuses to accept
the megalomaniac refuses to accept that
there
there is
the megalomaniac refuses to accept that
there is another
there is another god
the megalomaniac refuses to accept that
there is another god which
there is another god which would
threaten
threaten the
threaten the divinity
threaten the divinity of
threaten the divinity of one's
threaten the divinity of one's own
threaten the divinity of one's own self.
We'll
We'll talk
threaten the divinity of one's own self.
We'll talk take
We'll talk take a
threaten the divinity of one's own self.
We'll talk take a brief
We'll talk take a brief stop
threaten the divinity of one's own self.
We'll talk take a brief stop for
We'll talk take a brief stop for a
second.
We'll
We'll just
second.
We'll just pause
We'll just pause for
second.
We'll just pause for a
We'll just pause for a few
second.
We'll just pause for a few minutes
We'll just pause for a few minutes for
everybody.
everybody. Rest
everybody. Rest for
everybody. Rest for a
everybody. Rest for a minute.
>> Oh
>> Oh yes,
everybody. Rest for a minute.
>> Oh yes, we'll
>> Oh yes, we'll do
everybody. Rest for a minute.
>> Oh yes, we'll do that.
May
May we
May we have
May we have permission
May we have permission to
May we have permission to ask
May we have permission to ask a
May we have permission to ask a group,
right?
right? Door
May we have permission to ask a group,
right? Door 420
right? Door 420 425
May we have permission to ask a group,
right? Door 420 425 430
right? Door 420 425 430 432
May we have permission to ask a group,
right? Door 420 425 430 432 434
433 434
433 434 433
433 434 433 start
433 434 433 start out
433 434 433 start out today
433 434 433 start out today 433
Well,
Well, that's
433 434 433 start out today 433
Well, that's because
Well, that's because a
433 434 433 start out today 433
Well, that's because a lot
Well, that's because a lot of
433 434 433 start out today 433
Well, that's because a lot of you
Well, that's because a lot of you have
been
been here
been here before.
You
You slid
been here before.
You slid in
You slid in here
been here before.
You slid in here at
You slid in here at 4:30.
been here before.
You slid in here at 4:30. You
You slid in here at 4:30. You didn't
start
start at
start at 4:30.
start at 4:30. So
start at 4:30. So anyway,
uh
I
I just
I just thought
I just thought we'd
I just thought we'd take
I just thought we'd take a
I just thought we'd take a a
I just thought we'd take a a brief
I just thought we'd take a a brief rest
for
for people
I just thought we'd take a a brief rest
for people to
for people to think
I just thought we'd take a a brief rest
for people to think of
for people to think of any
I just thought we'd take a a brief rest
for people to think of any questions.
What
What we
What we what
What we what we
What we what we said
What we what we said today,
What we what we said today, you
What we what we said today, you know,
has
has is
What we what we said today, you know,
has is really
has is really has
What we what we said today, you know,
has is really has a
has is really has a profound
What we what we said today, you know,
has is really has a profound impact
has is really has a profound impact and
understanding
understanding human
understanding human history.
Uh
Uh understanding
understanding human history.
Uh understanding the
Uh understanding the evolution
understanding human history.
Uh understanding the evolution of
Uh understanding the evolution of human
consciousness
consciousness as
consciousness as it
consciousness as it is
consciousness as it is revealed
consciousness as it is revealed by
civilization
civilization and
consciousness as it is revealed by
civilization and the
civilization and the history
consciousness as it is revealed by
civilization and the history of
civilization.
Um,
Um, we
civilization.
Um, we see
Um, we see the
civilization.
Um, we see the evolution
Um, we see the evolution of
civilization.
Um, we see the evolution of the
Um, we see the evolution of the ego
civilization.
Um, we see the evolution of the ego and
how
how it
how it expresses
how it expresses itself
how it expresses itself in
how it expresses itself in today's
society.
society. I'm
how it expresses itself in today's
society. I'm not
society. I'm not talking
how it expresses itself in today's
society. I'm not talking about
society. I'm not talking about ancient
history.
The
The reason
history.
The reason I
The reason I like
history.
The reason I like to
The reason I like to use
history.
The reason I like to use things
The reason I like to use things from
today's
today's headlines
today's headlines is
today's headlines is because
today's headlines is because it's
staring
staring you
today's headlines is because it's
staring you right
staring you right in
today's headlines is because it's
staring you right in the
staring you right in the face
today's headlines is because it's
staring you right in the face now.
I
I mean,
I mean, in
I mean, in my
I mean, in my lifetime,
I mean, in my lifetime, I
I mean, in my lifetime, I went
I mean, in my lifetime, I went through
all
all these
I mean, in my lifetime, I went through
all these hundreds
all these hundreds of
I mean, in my lifetime, I went through
all these hundreds of millions
all these hundreds of millions of
I mean, in my lifetime, I went through
all these hundreds of millions of people
being
being slaughtered
being slaughtered all
being slaughtered all over
being slaughtered all over the
being slaughtered all over the globe
being slaughtered all over the globe and
I
I was
being slaughtered all over the globe and
I was a
I was a witness
being slaughtered all over the globe and
I was a witness to
I was a witness to it.
being slaughtered all over the globe and
I was a witness to it. And
I was a witness to it. And um,
being slaughtered all over the globe and
I was a witness to it. And um, so
I was a witness to it. And um, so we're
not
not talking
not talking about
not talking about things
not talking about things that
not talking about things that are
abstract.
abstract. We're
not talking about things that are
abstract. We're talking
abstract. We're talking about
not talking about things that are
abstract. We're talking about things
that
that are
that are extremely
that are extremely real
that are extremely real to
that are extremely real to really
that are extremely real to really the
majority
majority of
that are extremely real to really the
majority of mankind
majority of mankind as
that are extremely real to really the
majority of mankind as of
majority of mankind as of today.
All right.
All right. So,
All right. So, we
All right. So, we will
All right. So, we will take
All right. So, we will take a
All right. So, we will take a short
break
break now
All right. So, we will take a short
break now and
break now and then
All right. So, we will take a short
break now and then we'll
break now and then we'll resume
All right. So, we will take a short
break now and then we'll resume in
break now and then we'll resume in a
minute,
minute, few
minute, few minutes.
>> Well,
>> Well, I
minute, few minutes.
>> Well, I thought
>> Well, I thought this
minute, few minutes.
>> Well, I thought this morning
>> Well, I thought this morning we'd
minute, few minutes.
>> Well, I thought this morning we'd solve
all
all the
all the problems
all the problems of
all the problems of mankind
all the problems of mankind and
all the problems of mankind and before
noon.
>> Well,
>> Well, what
>> Well, what I've
>> Well, what I've been
>> Well, what I've been sharing
>> Well, what I've been sharing with
>> Well, what I've been sharing with you
>> Well, what I've been sharing with you is
an
an is
>> Well, what I've been sharing with you is
an is is
an is is an
>> Well, what I've been sharing with you is
an is is an evolving
an is is an evolving field
>> Well, what I've been sharing with you is
an is is an evolving field of
an is is an evolving field of knowledge.
You
You understand?
You understand? And
You understand? And we
You understand? And we found
You understand? And we found an
instrument
instrument that
You understand? And we found an
instrument that opened
instrument that opened whole
You understand? And we found an
instrument that opened whole realms
before
before inaccessible.
A
A way
before inaccessible.
A way of
A way of validating
before inaccessible.
A way of validating and
A way of validating and confirming
truth.
A
A way
truth.
A way of
A way of discovering
truth.
A way of discovering things
A way of discovering things that
truth.
A way of discovering things that mankind
has
has never
has never had
has never had before.
Mankind
Mankind dealt
has never had before.
Mankind dealt with
Mankind dealt with the
has never had before.
Mankind dealt with the limitation
Mankind dealt with the limitation of
logic.
logic. Logic
logic. Logic is
logic. Logic is in
logic. Logic is in the
logic. Logic is in the 400s.
That
That reminds
logic. Logic is in the 400s.
That reminds me.
Logic.
Logic. Okay.
one
one of
Logic. Okay.
one of the
one of the great
Logic. Okay.
one of the great impediments
one of the great impediments to
enlightenment.
enlightenment. The
enlightenment. The 400s
enlightenment. The 400s is
enlightenment. The 400s is probably
enlightenment. The 400s is probably the
major
major block
enlightenment. The 400s is probably the
major block for
uh
uh an
uh an enlightened
uh an enlightened group.
uh an enlightened group. This
uh an enlightened group. This is
uh an enlightened group. This is a
uh an enlightened group. This is a very
advanced
advanced group
uh an enlightened group. This is a very
advanced group here.
advanced group here. You
uh an enlightened group. This is a very
advanced group here. You realize
advanced group here. You realize the
level
level of
level of consciousness
level of consciousness of
level of consciousness of all
level of consciousness of all of
level of consciousness of all of mankind
is
is 207.
level of consciousness of all of mankind
is 207. And
is 207. And we're
level of consciousness of all of mankind
is 207. And we're talking
is 207. And we're talking to
level of consciousness of all of mankind
is 207. And we're talking to a
is 207. And we're talking to a group
here
here that
here that starts
here that starts at
here that starts at 4:30
here that starts at 4:30 in
here that starts at 4:30 in there,
here that starts at 4:30 in there, which
is
is so
here that starts at 4:30 in there, which
is so far
is so far beyond
here that starts at 4:30 in there, which
is so far beyond the
is so far beyond the mass
here that starts at 4:30 in there, which
is so far beyond the mass of
is so far beyond the mass of humanity
that
that most
that most of
that most of humanity
that most of humanity wouldn't
that most of humanity wouldn't even
understand
understand stand
that most of humanity wouldn't even
understand stand you
understand stand you people
that most of humanity wouldn't even
understand stand you people in
understand stand you people in this
audience
audience at
audience at all.
You
You see,
audience at all.
You see, we
You see, we talked
audience at all.
You see, we talked about
You see, we talked about context.
audience at all.
You see, we talked about context. The
unsophisticated
unsophisticated person
unsophisticated person presumes
unsophisticated person presumes that
unsophisticated person presumes that the
rest
rest of
unsophisticated person presumes that the
rest of the
rest of the world
unsophisticated person presumes that the
rest of the world thinks
rest of the world thinks the
unsophisticated person presumes that the
rest of the world thinks the way
rest of the world thinks the way you
unsophisticated person presumes that the
rest of the world thinks the way you do.
I
I got
I got news
I got news for
I got news for you.
I got news for you. The
I got news for you. The rest
I got news for you. The rest of
I got news for you. The rest of the
world
world does
I got news for you. The rest of the
world does not
world does not think
I got news for you. The rest of the
world does not think the
world does not think the way
I got news for you. The rest of the
world does not think the way you
world does not think the way you do.
I got news for you. The rest of the
world does not think the way you do. In
fact,
fact, the
fact, the rest
fact, the rest of the
fact, the rest of the world
fact, the rest of the world thinks
you're
you're stupid.
The
The world
The world is
The world is not
The world is not run
The world is not run by
The world is not run by logic
The world is not run by logic and
reason.
All
All the
All the political
All the political disasters,
military
military disasters
All the political disasters,
military disasters throughout
military disasters throughout history,
including
including this
including this very
including this very day,
including this very day, are
including this very day, are based
including this very day, are based on
the
the presumption
including this very day, are based on
the presumption that
the presumption that the
including this very day, are based on
the presumption that the other
the presumption that the other people
think
think like
think like you
think like you do,
think like you do, hold
think like you do, hold the
think like you do, hold the same
think like you do, hold the same values
as
as you
think like you do, hold the same values
as you do,
as you do, are
think like you do, hold the same values
as you do, are restrained
as you do, are restrained by
think like you do, hold the same values
as you do, are restrained by the
as you do, are restrained by the same
moral
moral constraints
moral constraints that
moral constraints that you
moral constraints that you are.
moral constraints that you are. Nothing
could
could be
moral constraints that you are. Nothing
could be farther
could be farther from
moral constraints that you are. Nothing
could be farther from the
could be farther from the truth.
reason
reason and
reason and logic,
reason and logic, fairness,
humanitarianism
are
are ridiculous.
You
You think
are ridiculous.
You think that
You think that stopped
are ridiculous.
You think that stopped Chairman
You think that stopped Chairman Mayo,
Adolf
Adolf Hitler,
Adolf Hitler, anybody?
Oh,
Oh, they
Adolf Hitler, anybody?
Oh, they wouldn't
Oh, they wouldn't do
Adolf Hitler, anybody?
Oh, they wouldn't do that
Oh, they wouldn't do that because
Adolf Hitler, anybody?
Oh, they wouldn't do that because they'd
be
be killing
be killing themselves.
be killing themselves. Remember
be killing themselves. Remember the
be killing themselves. Remember the Cold
War?
War? Oh,
be killing themselves. Remember the Cold
War? Oh, they
War? Oh, they wouldn't
be killing themselves. Remember the Cold
War? Oh, they wouldn't do
War? Oh, they wouldn't do that.
be killing themselves. Remember the Cold
War? Oh, they wouldn't do that. They'd
be
be killing
be killing their
be killing their own
be killing their own people.
be killing their own people. Killing
their
their own
be killing their own people. Killing
their own people
their own people is
be killing their own people. Killing
their own people is the
their own people is the specialty
be killing their own people. Killing
their own people is the specialty of
megalomaniacs.
The
The Germans
megalomaniacs.
The Germans deserve
The Germans deserve to
megalomaniacs.
The Germans deserve to die.
The Germans deserve to die. Hitler
megalomaniacs.
The Germans deserve to die. Hitler says
Saddam
Saddam Hussein
Saddam Hussein all
Saddam Hussein all the
Saddam Hussein all the megalomaniacs
Saddam Hussein all the megalomaniacs of
the
the world
Saddam Hussein all the megalomaniacs of
the world are
the world are are
Saddam Hussein all the megalomaniacs of
the world are are run
the world are are run by
Saddam Hussein all the megalomaniacs of
the world are are run by megalamania.
Megalamania
Megalamania means
Megalamania means that
Megalamania means that the
Megalamania means that the people
Megalamania means that the people have
no
no value
Megalamania means that the people have
no value whatsoever
no value whatsoever except
Megalamania means that the people have
no value whatsoever except to
no value whatsoever except to serve
their
their vanity.
No,
No, the
their vanity.
No, the opposite
No, the opposite side
their vanity.
No, the opposite side will
No, the opposite side will not
their vanity.
No, the opposite side will not be
constrained
constrained by
constrained by that
constrained by that which
constrained by that which is
constrained by that which is reasonable
at
at all.
They
They will
They will kill
They will kill all
They will kill all their
They will kill all their own
They will kill all their own people.
So
when
when you
when you realize
when you realize that
when you realize that you
when you realize that you realize
when you realize that you realize how
dangerous
dangerous they
when you realize that you realize how
dangerous they are.
dangerous they are. They
when you realize that you realize how
dangerous they are. They are
dangerous they are. They are not
constrained
constrained by
constrained by reason
constrained by reason and
constrained by reason and logic.
Uh
Uh so
constrained by reason and logic.
Uh so we'll
Uh so we'll talk
constrained by reason and logic.
Uh so we'll talk about
Uh so we'll talk about a
constrained by reason and logic.
Uh so we'll talk about a few
Uh so we'll talk about a few things
today.
As
As I
today.
As I said
As I said the
today.
As I said the the
As I said the the the
today.
As I said the the the research
As I said the the the research is
today.
As I said the the the research is is
evolving
evolving continuously.
evolving continuously. Huh.
Uh
Uh and
evolving continuously. Huh.
Uh and new
Uh and new people
evolving continuously. Huh.
Uh and new people are
Uh and new people are part
evolving continuously. Huh.
Uh and new people are part of
Uh and new people are part of it
evolving continuously. Huh.
Uh and new people are part of it are
being
being here.
Sometimes
Sometimes uh
being here.
Sometimes uh a
Sometimes uh a re
being here.
Sometimes uh a re a
Sometimes uh a re a question
being here.
Sometimes uh a re a question will
Sometimes uh a re a question will come
up
up we
up we haven't
up we haven't looked
up we haven't looked at
up we haven't looked at it.
up we haven't looked at it. We
up we haven't looked at it. We look
up we haven't looked at it. We look at
it
it right
up we haven't looked at it. We look at
it right here
it right here here
up we haven't looked at it. We look at
it right here here and
it right here here and now.
up we haven't looked at it. We look at
it right here here and now. This
it right here here and now. This first
time
time it
time it comes
time it comes up.
Many
Many of
time it comes up.
Many of the
Many of the presumptions
time it comes up.
Many of the presumptions of
Many of the presumptions of throughout
mankind's
mankind's history
mankind's history have
mankind's history have never
mankind's history have never been
challenged.
challenged. Never
mankind's history have never been
challenged. Never been
challenged. Never been challenged.
mankind's history have never been
challenged. Never been challenged. and
many
many of
many of them
many of them are
many of them are being
many of them are being challenged
many of them are being challenged here
for
for the
many of them are being challenged here
for the first
for the first time.
We're
We're talking
We're talking about
context.
You
You cannot
You cannot look
You cannot look at
You cannot look at yesterday's
You cannot look at yesterday's events
and
and make
You cannot look at yesterday's events
and make it
and make it wrong
because
because the
because the context
because the context is
because the context is different.
Part
Part of
because the context is different.
Part of guilt
Part of guilt is
because the context is different.
Part of guilt is looking
Part of guilt is looking to
because the context is different.
Part of guilt is looking to the
Part of guilt is looking to the past,
attacking
attacking oursel
attacking oursel for
attacking oursel for what
attacking oursel for what we
attacking oursel for what we did,
attacking oursel for what we did, said,
thought
thought or
attacking oursel for what we did, said,
thought or felt
thought or felt at
attacking oursel for what we did, said,
thought or felt at that
thought or felt at that time.
But
But at
But at that
But at that time
But at that time the
But at that time the context
But at that time the context was
different.
Today
Today the
Today the context
Today the context is
Today the context is different.
Today the context is different. It
Today the context is different. It only
looks
looks wrong
Today the context is different. It only
looks wrong because
looks wrong because you're
Today the context is different. It only
looks wrong because you're making
looks wrong because you're making an
error
error of
error of context.
To
To treat
error of context.
To treat women
To treat women now
error of context.
To treat women now the
To treat women now the way
error of context.
To treat women now the way they
To treat women now the way they were
treated
in
in the
treated
in the late
in the late 1800s
treated
in the late 1800s would
in the late 1800s would be
treated
in the late 1800s would be a
in the late 1800s would be a social
error.
error. It
error. It was
error. It was not
error. It was not a
error. It was not a social
error. It was not a social error.
We
We were
error. It was not a social error.
We were talking
We were talking before
error. It was not a social error.
We were talking before about
We were talking before about how
error. It was not a social error.
We were talking before about how women
were
were treated
were treated and
were treated and I
were treated and I grew
were treated and I grew up.
were treated and I grew up. Don't
forget,
forget, when
were treated and I grew up. Don't
forget, when I
forget, when I grew
were treated and I grew up. Don't
forget, when I grew up,
forget, when I grew up, it
were treated and I grew up. Don't
forget, when I grew up, it was
forget, when I grew up, it was an
agrarian
agrarian society.
agrarian society. Most
agrarian society. Most of
agrarian society. Most of the
agrarian society. Most of the population
lived
lived on
agrarian society. Most of the population
lived on farms.
Most
Most of
Most of the
Most of the population
Most of the population lived
Most of the population lived on
Most of the population lived on farms.
You
You didn't
Most of the population lived on farms.
You didn't survive
You didn't survive without
Most of the population lived on farms.
You didn't survive without the
You didn't survive without the woman.
The
The woman's
The woman's work
The woman's work was
The woman's work was critical.
The woman's work was critical. It's
The woman's work was critical. It's one
thing
thing to
The woman's work was critical. It's one
thing to bring
thing to bring in
The woman's work was critical. It's one
thing to bring in a
thing to bring in a couple
The woman's work was critical. It's one
thing to bring in a couple of
thing to bring in a couple of hay
The woman's work was critical. It's one
thing to bring in a couple of hay wagons
full
full of
full of corn.
full of corn. It's
full of corn. It's another
full of corn. It's another thing
full of corn. It's another thing to
full of corn. It's another thing to turn
it
it into
full of corn. It's another thing to turn
it into food.
it into food. You
full of corn. It's another thing to turn
it into food. You know,
it into food. You know, you
full of corn. It's another thing to turn
it into food. You know, you could
it into food. You know, you could men
left
left by
left by themselves
left by themselves could
left by themselves could starve
left by themselves could starve to
left by themselves could starve to death
right
right next
left by themselves could starve to death
right next to
it's
it's a
it's a lot
it's a lot of
it's a lot of work
it's a lot of work to
it's a lot of work to get
it's a lot of work to get it
it's a lot of work to get it from
it's a lot of work to get it from here
to
to there.
So,
So, bringing
So, bringing home
So, bringing home the
So, bringing home the bacon
So, bringing home the bacon is
So, bringing home the bacon is one
thing.
Making
Making it
Making it happen
Making it happen for
Making it happen for you
Making it happen for you and
Making it happen for you and your
Making it happen for you and your family
is
is quite
Making it happen for you and your family
is quite another.
is quite another. So
uh
so
so we
uh
so we can't
so we can't make
uh
so we can't make things
so we can't make things wrong
uh
so we can't make things wrong by
retrospection.
You
You can't
retrospection.
You can't attack
You can't attack yourself
retrospection.
You can't attack yourself for
You can't attack yourself for yesterday
because
because the
because the only
because the only reality
because the only reality is
because the only reality is right
because the only reality is right now.
People
People say
because the only reality is right now.
People say I
People say I can't
because the only reality is right now.
People say I can't stay
People say I can't stay in
because the only reality is right now.
People say I can't stay in the
People say I can't stay in the now.
because the only reality is right now.
People say I can't stay in the now. My
mind
mind wanders
mind wanders to
mind wanders to the
mind wanders to the past
mind wanders to the past or
mind wanders to the past or the
mind wanders to the past or the future.
That's
That's an
mind wanders to the past or the future.
That's an absurdity
That's an absurdity because
mind wanders to the past or the future.
That's an absurdity because your
That's an absurdity because your mind
can
can only
can only wander
can only wander to
can only wander to the
can only wander to the past
can only wander to the past or
can only wander to the past or the
future
future in
can only wander to the past or the
future in the
future in the right
can only wander to the past or the
future in the right now.
future in the right now. So
can only wander to the past or the
future in the right now. So you're
future in the right now. So you're still
always
always in
always in the
always in the right
always in the right now.
always in the right now. It's
always in the right now. It's right
always in the right now. It's right now
you're
you're worrying
always in the right now. It's right now
you're worrying about
you're worrying about the
always in the right now. It's right now
you're worrying about the past
you're worrying about the past and
always in the right now. It's right now
you're worrying about the past and the
future.
future. You
future. You are
future. You are in
future. You are in the
future. You are in the now,
future. You are in the now, folks.
future. You are in the now, folks. So
you
you can't
future. You are in the now, folks. So
you can't get
you can't get out
future. You are in the now, folks. So
you can't get out of
you can't get out of the
future. You are in the now, folks. So
you can't get out of the now.
All
All you
All you have
All you have to
All you have to appreciate
All you have to appreciate is
All you have to appreciate is what
All you have to appreciate is what the
context
context is
All you have to appreciate is what the
context is of
context is of that
All you have to appreciate is what the
context is of that state
context is of that state of
All you have to appreciate is what the
context is of that state of now.
So
So the
So the fallacy
So the fallacy of
So the fallacy of shifting
So the fallacy of shifting context
So the fallacy of shifting context which
is
is done
So the fallacy of shifting context which
is done in
is done in politics
So the fallacy of shifting context which
is done in politics all
is done in politics all the
So the fallacy of shifting context which
is done in politics all the time.
is done in politics all the time. It's
done
done in
done in politics.
done in politics. A
done in politics. A statement
done in politics. A statement which
sounds
sounds good
done in politics. A statement which
sounds good as
sounds good as a
done in politics. A statement which
sounds good as a street
sounds good as a street slogan
done in politics. A statement which
sounds good as a street slogan is
sounds good as a street slogan is now
put
put in
put in a
put in a different
put in a different context
put in a different context of
put in a different context of an
international
international event
put in a different context of an
international event and
international event and now
put in a different context of an
international event and now you
international event and now you come
from
from moral
from moral religious
from moral religious superiority.
from moral religious superiority. You
know
know moral
from moral religious superiority. You
know moral religious
know moral religious superiority.
from moral religious superiority. You
know moral religious superiority. What
you
you don't
you don't realize
you don't realize is
you don't realize is that
you don't realize is that you're
you don't realize is that you're being
sophomoric
and
God
God saved
and
God saved us
God saved us from
and
God saved us from the
God saved us from the sophomores.
God
God save
God save us
God save us from
God save us from the
God save us from the sophomores
God save us from the sophomores because
they
they live
God save us from the sophomores because
they live in
they live in academia.
See,
See, they
See, they were
See, they were at
See, they were at the
See, they were at the college
See, they were at the college age
See, they were at the college age of
naivee
and
and they
and they stayed
and they stayed there
and they stayed there and
and they stayed there and became
and they stayed there and became a
professor.
The
The world
The world out
The world out there
The world out there they
The world out there they have
The world out there they have the
slightest
slightest contact
The world out there they have the
slightest contact with.
I
I know
I know because
I know because in
I know because in the
I know because in the practice
I know because in the practice of
medicine,
medicine, you
I know because in the practice of
medicine, you would
medicine, you would not
I know because in the practice of
medicine, you would not believe
medicine, you would not believe the
I know because in the practice of
medicine, you would not believe the BS
that
that comes
that comes out
that comes out of
that comes out of academia
that comes out of academia and
that comes out of academia and via
government
government regulations.
that comes out of academia and via
government regulations. You
government regulations. You say,
"Where's
"Where's this
"Where's this guy
"Where's this guy lived
"Where's this guy lived all
"Where's this guy lived all of
"Where's this guy lived all of his
"Where's this guy lived all of his life?
Has
Has he
"Where's this guy lived all of his life?
Has he ever
Has he ever seen
"Where's this guy lived all of his life?
Has he ever seen a
Has he ever seen a sick
"Where's this guy lived all of his life?
Has he ever seen a sick patient?"
Has he ever seen a sick patient?" I
mean,
mean, get
mean, get with
mean, get with what's
mean, get with what's real.
mean, get with what's real. You
mean, get with what's real. You know
what
what I'm
mean, get with what's real. You know
what I'm saying?
There's
There's new
There's new regulations
There's new regulations called
There's new regulations called HIPPA,
HIPPA.
They
They run,
They run, I
They run, I don't
They run, I don't know,
They run, I don't know, 58,000
They run, I don't know, 58,000 pages.
And
And of
They run, I don't know, 58,000 pages.
And of course,
And of course, I'm
They run, I don't know, 58,000 pages.
And of course, I'm responsible
And of course, I'm responsible as
They run, I don't know, 58,000 pages.
And of course, I'm responsible as a
physician
physician for
physician for knowing
physician for knowing every
physician for knowing every iota
physician for knowing every iota on
every
every page.
physician for knowing every iota on
every page. And
every page. And if
physician for knowing every iota on
every page. And if I
every page. And if I don't,
physician for knowing every iota on
every page. And if I don't, I'm
every page. And if I don't, I'm subject
to
to $250,000
to $250,000 fine
to $250,000 fine and
to $250,000 fine and 10
to $250,000 fine and 10 years
to $250,000 fine and 10 years in
to $250,000 fine and 10 years in prison.
I
I mean,
to $250,000 fine and 10 years in prison.
I mean, is
I mean, is that
to $250,000 fine and 10 years in prison.
I mean, is that friendly?
I mean, is that friendly? Is
to $250,000 fine and 10 years in prison.
I mean, is that friendly? Is that
I mean, is that friendly? Is that like
Walmart's?
The
The government
Walmart's?
The government agencies
The government agencies calibrated
Walmart's?
The government agencies calibrated 202.
You
You know
You know what
You know what that
You know what that is?
You know what that is? That's
preuncterary
honesty
honesty because
honesty because if
honesty because if you
honesty because if you aren't,
honesty because if you aren't, you
honesty because if you aren't, you get
arrested.
202 is
202 is I
202 is I don't
202 is I don't want
202 is I don't want to
202 is I don't want to get
202 is I don't want to get into
202 is I don't want to get into the
government
government right
202 is I don't want to get into the
government right now.
Are
Are you
Are you hiding
Are you hiding back
Are you hiding back here
Are you hiding back here away
Are you hiding back here away from
Are you hiding back here away from me
where
where I
Are you hiding back here away from me
where I can't
where I can't find
Are you hiding back here away from me
where I can't find you?
We're
We're going
We're going to
We're going to do
We're going to do a
We're going to do a few
We're going to do a few research
We're going to do a few research things
because
because um
we
we just
we just want
we just want to
we just want to show
we just want to show you
we just want to show you how
we just want to show you how the
we just want to show you how the field
evolves.
Now,
Now, everybody
Now, everybody in
Now, everybody in this
Now, everybody in this in
Now, everybody in this in the
Now, everybody in this in the room
Now, everybody in this in the room has
read
read lots
Now, everybody in this in the room has
read lots of
read lots of books
Now, everybody in this in the room has
read lots of books on
read lots of books on spirituality,
Now, everybody in this in the room has
read lots of books on spirituality, no
doubt.
doubt. You
doubt. You see,
doubt. You see, and
doubt. You see, and uh
doubt. You see, and uh yeah,
doubt. You see, and uh yeah, relax
doubt. You see, and uh yeah, relax for
doubt. You see, and uh yeah, relax for a
second.
second. Um
we
we read
we read all
we read all the
we read all the spiritual
we read all the spiritual material
we read all the spiritual material and
or
or we
we read all the spiritual material and
or we go
or we go to
we read all the spiritual material and
or we go to church,
or we go to church, we
we read all the spiritual material and
or we go to church, we listen
or we go to church, we listen to
we read all the spiritual material and
or we go to church, we listen to a
or we go to church, we listen to a great
lecture,
lecture, we
lecture, we feel
lecture, we feel terrific,
and
and the
lecture, we feel terrific,
and the very
and the very next
lecture, we feel terrific,
and the very next day
and the very next day we
lecture, we feel terrific,
and the very next day we curse
and the very next day we curse the
lecture, we feel terrific,
and the very next day we curse the first
guy
guy to
guy to get
guy to get cuts
guy to get cuts in
guy to get cuts in front
guy to get cuts in front of
guy to get cuts in front of us
guy to get cuts in front of us in
traffic.
traffic. We
guy to get cuts in front of us in
traffic. We say
traffic. We say to
guy to get cuts in front of us in
traffic. We say to ourselves,
traffic. We say to ourselves, "Didn't
guy to get cuts in front of us in
traffic. We say to ourselves, "Didn't I
get
get it
get it or
get it or what?
So
So to
get it or what?
So to hear
So to hear about
get it or what?
So to hear about it
So to hear about it is
get it or what?
So to hear about it is one
So to hear about it is one thing.
get it or what?
So to hear about it is one thing. For
So to hear about it is one thing. For it
to
to sink
to sink in
to sink in is
to sink in is another."
Okay.
Okay. I
to sink in is another."
Okay. I think
Okay. I think everybody
to sink in is another."
Okay. I think everybody in
Okay. I think everybody in this
to sink in is another."
Okay. I think everybody in this room,
you
you don't
you don't really
you don't really have
you don't really have a
you don't really have a spiritual
problem.
The
The only
The only problem
The only problem you
The only problem you got
The only problem you got is
The only problem you got is allowing
The only problem you got is allowing it
to
to sink
The only problem you got is allowing it
to sink in.
to sink in. What
The only problem you got is allowing it
to sink in. What keeps
to sink in. What keeps it
The only problem you got is allowing it
to sink in. What keeps it from
to sink in. What keeps it from sinking
in?
Many
Many people
in?
Many people in
Many people in this
in?
Many people in this room,
Many people in this room, I'm
in?
Many people in this room, I'm sure,
Many people in this room, I'm sure, have
spent
spent years
spent years reading
spent years reading spiritual
literature,
literature, hearing
spent years reading spiritual
literature, hearing speakers,
literature, hearing speakers, going
spent years reading spiritual
literature, hearing speakers, going to
holy
holy places.
I've
I've been
holy places.
I've been to
I've been to all
holy places.
I've been to all holy
I've been to all holy places,
holy places.
I've been to all holy places, folks.
Yeah.
And
And and
Yeah.
And and yet
And and yet a
Yeah.
And and yet a thing
And and yet a thing will
Yeah.
And and yet a thing will remain
And and yet a thing will remain the
same.
same. You
same. You say,
same. You say, "How
same. You say, "How can
same. You say, "How can that
same. You say, "How can that be?
same. You say, "How can that be? How
same. You say, "How can that be? How can
that
that be?
How
How come
How come it
How come it doesn't
How come it doesn't sink
How come it doesn't sink in?
How come it doesn't sink in? How
How come it doesn't sink in? How come
How come it doesn't sink in? How come I
don't
don't get
How come it doesn't sink in? How come I
don't get it?
don't get it? How
How come it doesn't sink in? How come I
don't get it? How come
don't get it? How come I'm
How come it doesn't sink in? How come I
don't get it? How come I'm not
transformed
transformed by
transformed by the
transformed by the wonderful
transformed by the wonderful truths
transformed by the wonderful truths I've
heard?
I
I don't
I don't know.
I
I thought
I don't know.
I thought we
I thought we would
I don't know.
I thought we would save
I thought we would save this
I don't know.
I thought we would save this for
research
research today.
research today. There
research today. There seems
research today. There seems to
research today. There seems to be
research today. There seems to be a
great
great block,
research today. There seems to be a
great block, isn't
great block, isn't there?
research today. There seems to be a
great block, isn't there? Uh
great block, isn't there? Uh we're
willing
willing to
willing to be
willing to be loving
willing to be loving towards
willing to be loving towards all
willing to be loving towards all people.
We
We noticed
willing to be loving towards all people.
We noticed that
We noticed that in
willing to be loving towards all people.
We noticed that in Walmart
We noticed that in Walmart that
willing to be loving towards all people.
We noticed that in Walmart that happens.
Everybody
Everybody was
Everybody was friendly.
Everybody was friendly. If
Everybody was friendly. If I
Everybody was friendly. If I came
Everybody was friendly. If I came down
the
the aisle
Everybody was friendly. If I came down
the aisle yesterday,
the aisle yesterday, I
Everybody was friendly. If I came down
the aisle yesterday, I was
the aisle yesterday, I was coming
Everybody was friendly. If I came down
the aisle yesterday, I was coming down
the
the aisle.
the aisle. I
the aisle. I had
the aisle. I had a
the aisle. I had a bunch
the aisle. I had a bunch of
the aisle. I had a bunch of blank
videotape
videotape things
the aisle. I had a bunch of blank
videotape things and
videotape things and I'm
the aisle. I had a bunch of blank
videotape things and I'm going
videotape things and I'm going down
the aisle. I had a bunch of blank
videotape things and I'm going down and
this
this lady
this lady looks
this lady looks sweetly
this lady looks sweetly at
this lady looks sweetly at me
this lady looks sweetly at me and
this lady looks sweetly at me and she
says,
says, "Oh,
this lady looks sweetly at me and she
says, "Oh, pardon
says, "Oh, pardon me."
this lady looks sweetly at me and she
says, "Oh, pardon me." She
says, "Oh, pardon me." She pulled
all
all the
all the way.
all the way. How
all the way. How come
all the way. How come everybody's
all the way. How come everybody's so
sweet
sweet and
all the way. How come everybody's so
sweet and loving
sweet and loving in
all the way. How come everybody's so
sweet and loving in Walmart
sweet and loving in Walmart and
all the way. How come everybody's so
sweet and loving in Walmart and on
sweet and loving in Walmart and on the
street?
street? She
street? She say
street? She say like
street? She say like this
street? She say like this and
street? She say like this and pull.
So
So it
street? She say like this and pull.
So it must
So it must be
street? She say like this and pull.
So it must be certain
So it must be certain context
street? She say like this and pull.
So it must be certain context allows
So it must be certain context allows the
truth
truth to
truth to sink
truth to sink through.
I
I don't
truth to sink through.
I don't know
I don't know what
truth to sink through.
I don't know what it
I don't know what it is
truth to sink through.
I don't know what it is why
I don't know what it is why it
truth to sink through.
I don't know what it is why it doesn't
sink
sink in.
sink in. Okay.
sink in. Okay. Why
sink in. Okay. Why it
sink in. Okay. Why it doesn't
sink in. Okay. Why it doesn't sink
sink in. Okay. Why it doesn't sink in
has
has to
sink in. Okay. Why it doesn't sink in
has to do
has to do with
sink in. Okay. Why it doesn't sink in
has to do with an
has to do with an unconscious
sink in. Okay. Why it doesn't sink in
has to do with an unconscious uh
resistance
resistance of
resistance of the
resistance of the ego
resistance of the ego exist.
It's
It's an
resistance of the ego exist.
It's an unconscious
It's an unconscious defense
resistance of the ego exist.
It's an unconscious defense mechanism
It's an unconscious defense mechanism of
the
the ego
the ego resist.
It's
It's the
the ego resist.
It's the ego
defending
defending its
defending its very
defending its very structure.
defending its very structure. Resist.
Ego
Ego is
defending its very structure. Resist.
Ego is defending
Ego is defending its
defending its very structure. Resist.
Ego is defending its very
Ego is defending its very structure.
defending its very structure. Resist.
Ego is defending its very structure. In
other
other words,
other words, to
other words, to allow
other words, to allow even
other words, to allow even one
other words, to allow even one truth
other words, to allow even one truth to
shoot
shoot through
is
is the
is the beginning
is the beginning of
is the beginning of the
is the beginning of the end
is the beginning of the end for
is the beginning of the end for the
is the beginning of the end for the ego.
That's
That's correct.
So
So the
So the ego
So the ego defends
So the ego defends it
um
um defend
So the ego defends it
um defend itself
um defend itself by
So the ego defends it
um defend itself by not
um defend itself by not allowing
So the ego defends it
um defend itself by not allowing any
immigrants.
You
You get
immigrants.
You get one
You get one sweet
immigrants.
You get one sweet loving
You get one sweet loving little
immigrants.
You get one sweet loving little old
You get one sweet loving little old lady
wanders
wanders through
wanders through you
wanders through you blown
wanders through you blown the
wanders through you blown the whole
game.
game. You
wanders through you blown the whole
game. You know what
game. You know what I
wanders through you blown the whole
game. You know what I mean?
Iris,
Iris, you're
Iris, you're not
Iris, you're not supposed
Iris, you're not supposed to
Iris, you're not supposed to be
Iris, you're not supposed to be treating
the
the people
Iris, you're not supposed to be treating
the people this
the people this way.
Oh,
Oh, I
Oh, I see.
Oh, I see. Okay.
Oh, I see. Okay. Uh,
Oh, I see. Okay. Uh, consequently,
love
love is
Oh, I see. Okay. Uh, consequently,
love is the
love is the greatest
Oh, I see. Okay. Uh, consequently,
love is the greatest danger
love is the greatest danger resist.
Oh, I see. Okay. Uh, consequently,
love is the greatest danger resist. Oh,
yes.
So,
So, the
yes.
So, the way
So, the way Oh,
yes.
So, the way Oh, I
So, the way Oh, I got
yes.
So, the way Oh, I got it.
So, the way Oh, I got it. Okay.
yes.
So, the way Oh, I got it. Okay. What
So, the way Oh, I got it. Okay. What I
just
just saw
just saw is
just saw is true.
just saw is true. Okay.
just saw is true. Okay. Okay.
just saw is true. Okay. Okay. All right.
That's
That's what
just saw is true. Okay. Okay. All right.
That's what we're
That's what we're building
just saw is true. Okay. Okay. All right.
That's what we're building up
That's what we're building up to
just saw is true. Okay. Okay. All right.
That's what we're building up to the
lectures.
lectures. Anyway,
uh
uh what
lectures. Anyway,
uh what we
uh what we said
lectures. Anyway,
uh what we said was
uh what we said was um
lectures. Anyway,
uh what we said was um you
uh what we said was um you know
lectures. Anyway,
uh what we said was um you know what
we're
we're we're
we're we're approaching
we're we're approaching it
we're we're approaching it from
we're we're approaching it from the
we're we're approaching it from the side
of
of the
we're we're approaching it from the side
of the ego
because
because when
because when we
because when we get
because when we get to
because when we get to lecture
because when we get to lecture whatever
it
it is
because when we get to lecture whatever
it is about
it is about the
because when we get to lecture whatever
it is about the heart,
I
I don't
I don't want
I don't want the
I don't want the heart
I don't want the heart impeded
I don't want the heart impeded by
I don't want the heart impeded by the
structures
structures of
I don't want the heart impeded by the
structures of the
structures of the ego.
I don't want the heart impeded by the
structures of the ego. So
structures of the ego. So first
I don't want the heart impeded by the
structures of the ego. So first we're
disassembling
disassembling the
disassembling the ego.
disassembling the ego. You
disassembling the ego. You see
disassembling the ego. You see the
disassembling the ego. You see the ego
becomes
becomes weaker
disassembling the ego. You see the ego
becomes weaker just
becomes weaker just by
disassembling the ego. You see the ego
becomes weaker just by recognizing
becomes weaker just by recognizing it
for
for what
for what it
for what it is.
It
It already
for what it is.
It already loses
It already loses its
for what it is.
It already loses its divine
It already loses its divine authority.
Remove
Remove we're
Remove we're removing
Remove we're removing the
Remove we're removing the divinity
Remove we're removing the divinity of
the
the ego.
The
The more
The more we
The more we describe
The more we describe the
The more we describe the machinations
The more we describe the machinations of
the
the ego,
The more we describe the machinations of
the ego, the
the ego, the quicker
The more we describe the machinations of
the ego, the quicker it
the ego, the quicker it is
The more we describe the machinations of
the ego, the quicker it is to
the ego, the quicker it is to see
The more we describe the machinations of
the ego, the quicker it is to see it,
the
the weaker
the weaker it
the weaker it becomes.
Because
when
when we
when we get
when we get to
when we get to the
when we get to the lecture
when we get to the lecture on
when we get to the lecture on the
when we get to the lecture on the heart,
if
if I'm
when we get to the lecture on the heart,
if I'm capable
if I'm capable of
when we get to the lecture on the heart,
if I'm capable of giving
if I'm capable of giving it,
the
the heart
the heart now
the heart now sweeps
the heart now sweeps through
the heart now sweeps through unimpeded
because
because the
the heart now sweeps through unimpeded
because the p
because the p the
the heart now sweeps through unimpeded
because the p the ego's
because the p the ego's resistances
the heart now sweeps through unimpeded
because the p the ego's resistances have
been
been weakened.
That's
That's the
been weakened.
That's the beauty
That's the beauty of
been weakened.
That's the beauty of the
That's the beauty of the course
been weakened.
That's the beauty of the course of
miracles.
Beauty
Beauty of
miracles.
Beauty of the
Beauty of the course
miracles.
Beauty of the course of
Beauty of the course of miracles.
miracles.
Beauty of the course of miracles. When
Beauty of the course of miracles. When I
saw
saw it,
saw it, I
saw it, I says,
saw it, I says, "Wow,
saw it, I says, "Wow, brilliant."
The
The ego
saw it, I says, "Wow, brilliant."
The ego course
The ego course of
saw it, I says, "Wow, brilliant."
The ego course of miracles
The ego course of miracles first
saw it, I says, "Wow, brilliant."
The ego course of miracles first de
takes
takes you
takes you through
takes you through an
takes you through an elimination
takes you through an elimination of
takes you through an elimination of the
ego
ego structure
takes you through an elimination of the
ego structure before
ego structure before it
takes you through an elimination of the
ego structure before it comes
ego structure before it comes up
takes you through an elimination of the
ego structure before it comes up with
truth.
As
As I
truth.
As I say,
As I say, lesson
truth.
As I say, lesson 76,
As I say, lesson 76, I'm
truth.
As I say, lesson 76, I'm only
As I say, lesson 76, I'm only subject
truth.
As I say, lesson 76, I'm only subject to
what
what I
what I hold
what I hold in
what I hold in mind
only
only works
what I hold in mind
only works if
only works if you've
what I hold in mind
only works if you've done
only works if you've done one
what I hold in mind
only works if you've done one through
75.
I
I said
75.
I said one
I said one time,
75.
I said one time, I
I said one time, I think
75.
I said one time, I think it's
I said one time, I think it's lesson
75.
I said one time, I think it's lesson 76
around
around in
around in there.
around in there. I
around in there. I was
around in there. I was telling
around in there. I was telling about
that
that the
around in there. I was telling about
that the students
that the students I
around in there. I was telling about
that the students I had
that the students I had in
around in there. I was telling about
that the students I had in the
that the students I had in the course
around in there. I was telling about
that the students I had in the course of
miracles
miracles who
miracles who wouldn't
miracles who wouldn't go
miracles who wouldn't go weak
miracles who wouldn't go weak with
anything
anything and
miracles who wouldn't go weak with
anything and I
anything and I and
miracles who wouldn't go weak with
anything and I and I
anything and I and I and
miracles who wouldn't go weak with
anything and I and I and I
anything and I and I and I tracked
miracles who wouldn't go weak with
anything and I and I and I tracked some
people
people that
people that were
people that were just
people that were just starting
people that were just starting the
starting
starting the
people that were just starting the
starting the course
starting the course and
people that were just starting the
starting the course and of
starting the course and of course
fluorescent
fluorescent lights
fluorescent lights made
fluorescent lights made them
fluorescent lights made them go
fluorescent lights made them go weak
fluorescent lights made them go weak and
all
all everything
fluorescent lights made them go weak and
all everything and
all everything and around
fluorescent lights made them go weak and
all everything and around 76
all everything and around 76 fluorescent
lights
lights and
lights and all
lights and all the
lights and all the stuff
lights and all the stuff that
lights and all the stuff that makes
everybody
everybody weak
lights and all the stuff that makes
everybody weak go
everybody weak go weakiology
lights and all the stuff that makes
everybody weak go weakiology no
everybody weak go weakiology no longer
and
and it's
and it's it's
and it's it's about
and it's it's about the
and it's it's about the lesson
and it's it's about the lesson I'm
and it's it's about the lesson I'm only
72 I
72 I hold
and it's it's about the lesson I'm only
72 I hold him
72 I hold him on
and it's it's about the lesson I'm only
72 I hold him on so
72 I hold him on so somebody
and it's it's about the lesson I'm only
72 I hold him on so somebody heard
72 I hold him on so somebody heard that
he
he went
he went home
he went home and
he went home and read
he went home and read that
he went home and read that lesson
he went home and read that lesson and
then
then hope
he went home and read that lesson and
then hope that
then hope that his
he went home and read that lesson and
then hope that his asthma
then hope that his asthma will
he went home and read that lesson and
then hope that his asthma will be
then hope that his asthma will be cure
the
the next
the next day.
I
I said,
the next day.
I said, "You
I said, "You forgot
the next day.
I said, "You forgot the
I said, "You forgot the first
the next day.
I said, "You forgot the first 75
lessons,
lessons, folks.
76 mean
76 mean is
lessons, folks.
76 mean is meaningful
76 mean is meaningful if
lessons, folks.
76 mean is meaningful if you've
76 mean is meaningful if you've gone
through
through one
through one through
through one through 75."
through one through 75." Oh,
through one through 75." Oh, okay.
Why?
Why? Because
through one through 75." Oh, okay.
Why? Because it
Why? Because it changes
through one through 75." Oh, okay.
Why? Because it changes the
Why? Because it changes the context.
Huh?
So,
So, that's
Huh?
So, that's what
So, that's what we're
Huh?
So, that's what we're doing
So, that's what we're doing here.
Huh?
So, that's what we're doing here. We
want
want to
want to get
want to get the
want to get the ego
want to get the ego dead
want to get the ego dead to
want to get the ego dead to rights
so
so that
want to get the ego dead to rights
so that when
so that when we
want to get the ego dead to rights
so that when we get
so that when we get to
want to get the ego dead to rights
so that when we get to the
so that when we get to the heart,
want to get the ego dead to rights
so that when we get to the heart, its
way
way will
way will be
way will be unimpeded.
All
All right.
way will be unimpeded.
All right. People
All right. People have
way will be unimpeded.
All right. People have heard
All right. People have heard of
way will be unimpeded.
All right. People have heard of the
truth
truth for
truth for all
truth for all their
truth for all their whole
truth for all their whole lifetime
truth for all their whole lifetime and
it's
it's had
truth for all their whole lifetime and
it's had no
it's had no effect
truth for all their whole lifetime and
it's had no effect on
it's had no effect on them
truth for all their whole lifetime and
it's had no effect on them whatsoever.
I
I had
I had a
I had a lady
I had a lady I
I had a lady I know
I had a lady I know well.
I had a lady I know well. She
I had a lady I know well. She said,
"I've
"I've gone
I had a lady I know well. She said,
"I've gone to
"I've gone to metaphysical
I had a lady I know well. She said,
"I've gone to metaphysical groups,
discussions,
discussions, weekend
discussions, weekend retreats
discussions, weekend retreats in
discussions, weekend retreats in him
discussions, weekend retreats in him for
35 years
35 years and
discussions, weekend retreats in him for
35 years and nothing's
35 years and nothing's changed.
That's
That's curious.
It's
It's also
That's curious.
It's also sad,
It's also sad, isn't
That's curious.
It's also sad, isn't it?
It's
It's also
It's also an
It's also an area
It's also an area for
It's also an area for research
It's also an area for research then,
isn't
isn't it?
It's also an area for research then,
isn't it? How
isn't it? How can
It's also an area for research then,
isn't it? How can you
isn't it? How can you go
It's also an area for research then,
isn't it? How can you go to
isn't it? How can you go to for
It's also an area for research then,
isn't it? How can you go to for 35
isn't it? How can you go to for 35 years
and
and not
and not have
and not have anything
and not have anything change?
and not have anything change? Huh?
Let's
Let's see.
and not have anything change? Huh?
Let's see. That's
Let's see. That's possible.
and not have anything change? Huh?
Let's see. That's possible. That
Let's see. That's possible. That still
exists
exists in
exists in the
exists in the same
exists in the same lady.
exists in the same lady. Resist.
exists in the same lady. Resist. Whoa.
My
My god.
exists in the same lady. Resist. Whoa.
My god. It
My god. It still
exists in the same lady. Resist. Whoa.
My god. It still exists
My god. It still exists in
exists in the same lady. Resist. Whoa.
My god. It still exists in the
My god. It still exists in the same
lady.
That
That was
lady.
That was 10
That was 10 years
lady.
That was 10 years ago.
That was 10 years ago. She
lady.
That was 10 years ago. She still
That was 10 years ago. She still said
that.
God.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So the
All right. So the the
All right. So the the cleaver
All right. So the the cleaver that
All right. So the the cleaver that would
cut
cut through
All right. So the the cleaver that would
cut through then
cut through then is
All right. So the the cleaver that would
cut through then is love.
cut through then is love. Resist.
All right. So the the cleaver that would
cut through then is love. Resist. Okay.
It's
It's only
It's only love.
It's only love. All right.
It's only love. All right. The
It's only love. All right. The only
thing
thing then
It's only love. All right. The only
thing then that
thing then that can
It's only love. All right. The only
thing then that can weaken
thing then that can weaken Oh,
It's only love. All right. The only
thing then that can weaken Oh, I
thing then that can weaken Oh, I get
what
what it
what it is.
what it is. All
what it is. All right.
what it is. All right. The
what it is. All right. The only
what it is. All right. The only thing
that
that can
what it is. All right. The only thing
that can weaken
that can weaken the
what it is. All right. The only thing
that can weaken the ego's
that can weaken the ego's structural
resistance
resistance to
resistance to maintain
resistance to maintain its
resistance to maintain its total
resistance to maintain its total defense
by
by letting
resistance to maintain its total defense
by letting any
by letting any spiritual
resistance to maintain its total defense
by letting any spiritual truth
by letting any spiritual truth come
resistance to maintain its total defense
by letting any spiritual truth come in
then
then the
then the only
then the only thing
then the only thing that
then the only thing that it
then the only thing that it can
then the only thing that it can do
then the only thing that it can do that
defense
defense is
then the only thing that it can do that
defense is love.
Oh,
Oh, so
Oh, so out
Oh, so out of
Oh, so out of love
Oh, so out of love then
Oh, so out of love then one
Oh, so out of love then one accepts
Oh, so out of love then one accepts what
one
one has
Oh, so out of love then one accepts what
one has just
one has just heard
Oh, so out of love then one accepts what
one has just heard as
one has just heard as truth.
It
It was
It was out
It was out of
It was out of love
It was out of love for
It was out of love for my
It was out of love for my father
and
and my
It was out of love for my father
and my grandfathers
that
that I
that I I
that I I adopted
that I I adopted their
that I I adopted their view
that I I adopted their view of
that I I adopted their view of reality
that
that women
that I I adopted their view of reality
that women were
that women were to
that I I adopted their view of reality
that women were to be
that women were to be honored.
It
It was
It was because
It was because of
It was because of my
It was because of my love
It was because of my love for
It was because of my love for them.
Reason
Reason couldn't
It was because of my love for them.
Reason couldn't have
Reason couldn't have proven
It was because of my love for them.
Reason couldn't have proven it.
Women
Women chatter
Women chatter all
Women chatter all the
Women chatter all the time.
Women chatter all the time. Drive
Women chatter all the time. Drive me
crazy.
You
You wouldn't
You wouldn't arrive
You wouldn't arrive at
You wouldn't arrive at that
You wouldn't arrive at that by
You wouldn't arrive at that by logic.
So
So out
You wouldn't arrive at that by logic.
So out of
So out of love,
You wouldn't arrive at that by logic.
So out of love, out
So out of love, out of
You wouldn't arrive at that by logic.
So out of love, out of love.
Maybe
Maybe that's
Maybe that's the
Maybe that's the effect
Maybe that's the effect of
Maybe that's the effect of the
Maybe that's the effect of the teacher.
Oh,
Oh, let's
Maybe that's the effect of the teacher.
Oh, let's see.
Oh, let's see. Somebody
Maybe that's the effect of the teacher.
Oh, let's see. Somebody asked
Oh, let's see. Somebody asked me
Maybe that's the effect of the teacher.
Oh, let's see. Somebody asked me that
question.
question. What
question. What is
question. What is this
question. What is this question?
How
How does
question. What is this question?
How does the
How does the calibr
question. What is this question?
How does the calibr Oh
How does the calibr Oh god,
question. What is this question?
How does the calibr Oh god, I
How does the calibr Oh god, I can't
question. What is this question?
How does the calibr Oh god, I can't read
this
this thing.
this thing. How
this thing. How does
this thing. How does the
this thing. How does the calibration
increase
increase from
this thing. How does the calibration
increase from watching
increase from watching versus
this thing. How does the calibration
increase from watching versus Oh,
increase from watching versus Oh, is
this thing. How does the calibration
increase from watching versus Oh, is it
>> attending?
>> attending? Oh,
>> attending? Oh, from
>> attending? Oh, from attending.
>> attending? Oh, from attending. Yeah.
>> attending? Oh, from attending. Yeah. How
does
does the
>> attending? Oh, from attending. Yeah. How
does the calibration
does the calibration increase
>> attending? Oh, from attending. Yeah. How
does the calibration increase from
watching
watching videotapes
or
or audio
watching videotapes
or audio tapes
or audio tapes as
watching videotapes
or audio tapes as compared
or audio tapes as compared to
watching videotapes
or audio tapes as compared to being
or audio tapes as compared to being here
in
in person?
in person? Oh,
in person? Oh, okay.
in person? Oh, okay. I
in person? Oh, okay. I don't know.
in person? Oh, okay. I don't know. We
noticed
noticed that
um
um the
um the calibrated
um the calibrated energy
um the calibrated energy of
um the calibrated energy of the
um the calibrated energy of the teacher
um
is
is innate
is innate to
is innate to the
is innate to the videotape
is innate to the videotape resist.
is innate to the videotape resist. Okay.
It's
It's innate
is innate to the videotape resist. Okay.
It's innate to
It's innate to the
is innate to the videotape resist. Okay.
It's innate to the audio
It's innate to the audio tape
is innate to the videotape resist. Okay.
It's innate to the audio tape resist.
It's
It's the
It's the same
It's the same as
It's the same as the
It's the same as the presence
It's the same as the presence of
It's the same as the presence of the
teacher
teacher resist.
Let's
Let's see
Let's see how
Let's see how that
Let's see how that can
Let's see how that can be.
Divinity
Divinity doesn't
Let's see how that can be.
Divinity doesn't record
Divinity doesn't record on
Let's see how that can be.
Divinity doesn't record on videotape.
Divinity doesn't record on videotape. Is
it?
Oh,
Oh, I
it?
Oh, I see.
Oh, I see. Cuz
it?
Oh, I see. Cuz it's
Oh, I see. Cuz it's out
it?
Oh, I see. Cuz it's out of
Oh, I see. Cuz it's out of form.
it?
Oh, I see. Cuz it's out of form. Okay.
Videape
Videape can
Videape can only
Videape can only record
Videape can only record content
Videape can only record content then
form
form within
Videape can only record content then
form within the
form within the Newtonian
Videape can only record content then
form within the Newtonian paradigm.
form within the Newtonian paradigm. It
doesn't
doesn't record
doesn't record the
doesn't record the infinite
divinity
divinity out
doesn't record the infinite
divinity out of
divinity out of which
doesn't record the infinite
divinity out of which the
divinity out of which the totality
doesn't record the infinite
divinity out of which the totality of
reality
reality arises
reality arises which
reality arises which is
reality arises which is reflected
through
through the
reality arises which is reflected
through the teacher.
through the teacher. Okay.
reality arises which is reflected
through the teacher. Okay. The
through the teacher. Okay. The teacher
reflects
reflects that
the
the teacher
reflects that
the teacher is
the teacher is reflecting
reflects that
the teacher is reflecting today
the teacher is reflecting today over
reflects that
the teacher is reflecting today over 800
99.
99. Okay.
99. Okay. All right.
99. Okay. All right. It
99. Okay. All right. It is
99. Okay. All right. It is calibrated.
It
It is
It is radiated
It is radiated through
It is radiated through the
It is radiated through the consciousness
of
of the
It is radiated through the consciousness
of the teacher.
of the teacher. That's
It is radiated through the consciousness
of the teacher. That's the
of the teacher. That's the value
It is radiated through the consciousness
of the teacher. That's the value of
of the teacher. That's the value of it.
I'm
I'm a
I'm a little
I'm a little disappointed.
I'm a little disappointed. I
I'm a little disappointed. I thought
I'm a little disappointed. I thought it
God
God recorded
I'm a little disappointed. I thought it
God recorded on
God recorded on videape.
I'm a little disappointed. I thought it
God recorded on videape. No.
>> Could
>> Could you
>> Could you change
>> Could you change that
>> Could you change that with
>> Could you change that with intention?
Putting
Putting your
>> Could you change that with intention?
Putting your intentionality
Putting your intentionality with
>> Could you change that with intention?
Putting your intentionality with your
>> No.
>> No. You
>> No. You see
>> No. You see what
>> No. You see what what
>> No. You see what what you
>> No. You see what what you supplement
what
what happens
>> No. You see what what you supplement
what happens is
what happens is you
>> No. You see what what you supplement
what happens is you hear
what happens is you hear the
>> No. You see what what you supplement
what happens is you hear the teacher
what happens is you hear the teacher and
that
that allows
that allows your
that allows your own
that allows your own divinity
that allows your own divinity to
that allows your own divinity to come
forth.
forth. So
that allows your own divinity to come
forth. So the
forth. So the radiance
that allows your own divinity to come
forth. So the radiance of
forth. So the radiance of divinity
that allows your own divinity to come
forth. So the radiance of divinity is
felt
felt from
felt from within.
That's
That's true.
felt from within.
That's true. Okay.
That's true. Okay. Right.
felt from within.
That's true. Okay. Right. Now,
That's true. Okay. Right. Now, the
vibration
vibration of
vibration of the
vibration of the teacher
vibration of the teacher creates
vibration of the teacher creates the
context
context which
vibration of the teacher creates the
context which brings
context which brings forth
vibration of the teacher creates the
context which brings forth the
context which brings forth the response
from
from the
from the listeners
from the listeners context
from the listeners context here.
from the listeners context here. Okay.
All
All right.
from the listeners context here. Okay.
All right. So
All right. So then
from the listeners context here. Okay.
All right. So then what
All right. So then what what
from the listeners context here. Okay.
All right. So then what what it
All right. So then what what it does
from the listeners context here. Okay.
All right. So then what what it does is
it
it removes
it removes the
it removes the the
it removes the the blocks.
it removes the the blocks. What
it removes the the blocks. What we're
trying
trying to
it removes the the blocks. What we're
trying to do
trying to do is
it removes the the blocks. What we're
trying to do is disassemble
trying to do is disassemble the
it removes the the blocks. What we're
trying to do is disassemble the ego
trying to do is disassemble the ego so
the
the radiance
the radiance of
the radiance of the
the radiance of the self
the radiance of the self shines
the radiance of the self shines forth
which
which it
the radiance of the self shines forth
which it does.
which it does. So
the radiance of the self shines forth
which it does. So it
which it does. So it the
the radiance of the self shines forth
which it does. So it the difference
which it does. So it the difference is
the
the presence
the presence creates
the presence creates a
the presence creates a certain
aura
but
but uh
but uh the
but uh the listener
it's
it's the
but uh the listener
it's the listener's
it's the listener's divinity
but uh the listener
it's the listener's divinity that
it's the listener's divinity that allows
them
them to
um
um realize
them to
um realize the
um realize the truth
them to
um realize the truth of
um realize the truth of what's
them to
um realize the truth of what's being
said.
So
So the
said.
So the truth
So the truth of
said.
So the truth of what's
So the truth of what's being
said.
So the truth of what's being said
So the truth of what's being said then
becomes
becomes acceptable
by
by virtue
becomes acceptable
by virtue of
by virtue of love.
You
You see,
You see, when
You see, when my
You see, when my father
You see, when my father and
You see, when my father and and
grandfather's
spoke
spoke about
spoke about this
spoke about this matter,
the
the ring
spoke about this matter,
the ring of
the ring of validity
was
was absolute.
was absolute. It
was absolute. It was
was absolute. It was absolute.
was absolute. It was absolute. There
was absolute. It was absolute. There was
no
no question.
Don't
Don't you
Don't you ever
Don't you ever speak
Don't you ever speak that
Don't you ever speak that way
Don't you ever speak that way to
Don't you ever speak that way to your
grandmother?
I
I mean,
I mean, that
I mean, that was
I mean, that was it.
I mean, that was it. You
I mean, that was it. You know,
I mean, that was it. You know, you
I mean, that was it. You know, you don't
question
question that.
I mean, that was it. You know, you don't
question that. You
question that. You don't
I mean, that was it. You know, you don't
question that. You don't ask
question that. You don't ask about
I mean, that was it. You know, you don't
question that. You don't ask about it.
That's
That's the
That's the way
That's the way the
That's the way the world
That's the way the world is.
That's the way the world is. So,
all
all right.
That's the way the world is. So,
all right. So,
all right. So, I
That's the way the world is. So,
all right. So, I see
all right. So, I see what
That's the way the world is. So,
all right. So, I see what it
all right. So, I see what it is.
That's the way the world is. So,
all right. So, I see what it is. What
could
could undo
could undo the
could undo the What
could undo the What could
could undo the What could undo
could undo the What could undo it
could undo the What could undo it then
would
would be
um
um the
um the respect
um the respect for
um the respect for the
um the respect for the love
um the respect for the love out
um the respect for the love out of
um the respect for the love out of which
the
the truth
um
um was
um was spoken.
um was spoken. I
um was spoken. I see
um was spoken. I see that.
um was spoken. I see that. Okay.
All right.
All right. During
um was spoken. I see that. Okay.
All right. During the
All right. During the break,
um was spoken. I see that. Okay.
All right. During the break, uh,
somebody
somebody asked
somebody asked me,
somebody asked me, "How
somebody asked me, "How do
somebody asked me, "How do you
somebody asked me, "How do you see
somebody asked me, "How do you see the
perfection
perfection of
somebody asked me, "How do you see the
perfection of 20
perfection of 20 million
somebody asked me, "How do you see the
perfection of 20 million people
perfection of 20 million people dead
bodies
bodies laying
bodies laying there?"
You
You can
bodies laying there?"
You can see
You can see it
bodies laying there?"
You can see it in
You can see it in the
bodies laying there?"
You can see it in the roads.
You can see it in the roads. H,
bodies laying there?"
You can see it in the roads. H, can
You can see it in the roads. H, can you
see
see it
see it after
see it after a
see it after a nuclear
see it after a nuclear disaster?
see it after a nuclear disaster? Huh?
If
If the
see it after a nuclear disaster? Huh?
If the perfection
If the perfection of
see it after a nuclear disaster? Huh?
If the perfection of all
If the perfection of all that
see it after a nuclear disaster? Huh?
If the perfection of all that is
If the perfection of all that is is
there
there at
there at all
there at all times,
how
how come
there at all times,
how come it
how come it looks
there at all times,
how come it looks the
how come it looks the way
there at all times,
how come it looks the way it
how come it looks the way it looks
there at all times,
how come it looks the way it looks at
times?
times? Huh?
We
We said
times? Huh?
We said as
We said as the
times? Huh?
We said as the rose
We said as the rose is
times? Huh?
We said as the rose is unfolding
We said as the rose is unfolding at
every
every instant
every instant it
every instant it is
every instant it is already
every instant it is already complete.
Huh?
At
At a
At a certain
At a certain state
At a certain state state
At a certain state state of
At a certain state state of realization
every
every instant
At a certain state state of realization
every instant is
every instant is already
At a certain state state of realization
every instant is already complete.
There's
There's nothing
There's nothing you
There's nothing you want.
There's nothing you want. There's
nothing
nothing you
There's nothing you want. There's
nothing you need.
nothing you need. There's
There's nothing you want. There's
nothing you need. There's nothing
nothing you need. There's nothing you
desire.
As
As you
desire.
As you get
As you get to
desire.
As you get to the
As you get to the end
desire.
As you get to the end of
As you get to the end of the
desire.
As you get to the end of the movie,
the
the video
the video the
the video the TV
the video the TV set
the video the TV set stops.
the video the TV set stops. You
the video the TV set stops. You don't
feel
feel any
the video the TV set stops. You don't
feel any loss
feel any loss of
the video the TV set stops. You don't
feel any loss of how
feel any loss of how the
the video the TV set stops. You don't
feel any loss of how the movie
feel any loss of how the movie ended.
Every
Every moment
Every moment is
Every moment is complete
Every moment is complete up
Every moment is complete up to
Every moment is complete up to that
moment.
There's
There's nothing
There's nothing to
There's nothing to look
There's nothing to look for,
There's nothing to look for, seek
or
or desire,
There's nothing to look for, seek
or desire, nor
or desire, nor is
There's nothing to look for, seek
or desire, nor is there
or desire, nor is there anything
There's nothing to look for, seek
or desire, nor is there anything to
regret.
If
If you
regret.
If you live
If you live on
regret.
If you live on the
If you live on the moment
regret.
If you live on the moment of
If you live on the moment of now,
there's
there's nothing
there's nothing to
there's nothing to desire
there's nothing to desire and
there's nothing to desire and nothing
there's nothing to desire and nothing to
regret
regret because
there's nothing to desire and nothing to
regret because everything
regret because everything is
there's nothing to desire and nothing to
regret because everything is already
perfect,
including
including getting
perfect,
including getting blown
including getting blown up.
It's
It's perfectly
It's perfectly fine
It's perfectly fine to
It's perfectly fine to get
It's perfectly fine to get blown
It's perfectly fine to get blown up.
It's perfectly fine to get blown up. How
you
you going
It's perfectly fine to get blown up. How
you going to
you going to get
It's perfectly fine to get blown up. How
you going to get out
you going to get out of
It's perfectly fine to get blown up. How
you going to get out of this
you going to get out of this world,
folks?
Slowly
Slowly with
folks?
Slowly with an
Slowly with an oxygen
folks?
Slowly with an oxygen tank,
peace
peace meal
peace meal through
peace meal through the
peace meal through the surgeon.
Can
Can we
peace meal through the surgeon.
Can we let
Can we let mom
peace meal through the surgeon.
Can we let mom die?
Can we let mom die? Oh,
peace meal through the surgeon.
Can we let mom die? Oh, no.
Can we let mom die? Oh, no. No,
peace meal through the surgeon.
Can we let mom die? Oh, no. No, we
Can we let mom die? Oh, no. No, we can't
let
let mom
let mom die.
Please,
Please, can
let mom die.
Please, can you
Please, can you take
let mom die.
Please, can you take out
Please, can you take out the
let mom die.
Please, can you take out the oxygen
tube?
tube? Stop
tube? Stop forcing
tube? Stop forcing the
tube? Stop forcing the food
tube? Stop forcing the food down
tube? Stop forcing the food down my
throat.
throat. No.
No.
No. Because
No. Because the
No. Because the Medicare
No. Because the Medicare regulations
don't
don't allow
No. Because the Medicare regulations
don't allow it,
don't allow it, folks.
That's
That's why.
All
All right.
Everything
Everything is
Everything is the
Everything is the perfect
Everything is the perfect expression
Everything is the perfect expression of
that
that which
Everything is the perfect expression of
that which it
that which it is.
100,000
100,000 dead
100,000 dead bodies
100,000 dead bodies just
100,000 dead bodies just blown
100,000 dead bodies just blown up
100,000 dead bodies just blown up by
100,000 dead bodies just blown up by an
atomic
atomic explosion
100,000 dead bodies just blown up by an
atomic explosion is
atomic explosion is the
100,000 dead bodies just blown up by an
atomic explosion is the perfect
expression
expression of
expression of that
expression of that of
expression of that of that.
expression of that of that. Huh.
Bin
Bin L
expression of that of that. Huh.
Bin L bombing
Bin L bombing the
expression of that of that. Huh.
Bin L bombing the trade
Bin L bombing the trade center
expression of that of that. Huh.
Bin L bombing the trade center is
Bin L bombing the trade center is the
perfect
perfect expression
perfect expression of
perfect expression of calibrated
perfect expression of calibrated energy
70.
Correct.
Correct. Correct.
Correct. Correct. That's
Correct. Correct. That's what
Correct. Correct. That's what 70
Correct. Correct. That's what 70 looks
like.
calibrated.
calibrated. Level
calibrated. Level 70
calibrated. Level 70 is
calibrated. Level 70 is the
calibrated. Level 70 is the age
calibrated. Level 70 is the age of
calibrated. Level 70 is the age of the
dinosaur.
Rapacious,
bloodthirsty.
One
One time
One time a
One time a pack
One time a pack of
One time a pack of killer
One time a pack of killer dogs,
One time a pack of killer dogs, dog,
wild
wild dog
One time a pack of killer dogs, dog,
wild dog pack
wild dog pack came
One time a pack of killer dogs, dog,
wild dog pack came through
wild dog pack came through my
One time a pack of killer dogs, dog,
wild dog pack came through my barnyard
and
and the
and the chickens
and the chickens were
and the chickens were running
and the chickens were running around.
There
There was
and the chickens were running around.
There was u
There was u three
and the chickens were running around.
There was u three or
There was u three or four
and the chickens were running around.
There was u three or four of
There was u three or four of them.
Two
Two of
Two of them
Two of them were
Two of them were breeds
Two of them were breeds that
Two of them were breeds that are
Two of them were breeds that are well
known
known for
Two of them were breeds that are well
known for mauling
known for mauling and
Two of them were breeds that are well
known for mauling and killing
known for mauling and killing children,
which
which is
which is why
which is why people
which is why people keep
which is why people keep them,
which is why people keep them, I
which is why people keep them, I guess.
Oh,
Oh, he
which is why people keep them, I guess.
Oh, he never
Oh, he never bit
which is why people keep them, I guess.
Oh, he never bit anybody.
No,
he
he was
No,
he was saving
he was saving up
No,
he was saving up for
he was saving up for this
No,
he was saving up for this one.
Nice
Nice little
Nice little three-year-old.
Some
Some guy
Nice little three-year-old.
Some guy got
Some guy got bitten
Nice little three-year-old.
Some guy got bitten 65
Some guy got bitten 65 times
Nice little three-year-old.
Some guy got bitten 65 times trying
Some guy got bitten 65 times trying to
keep
keep his
keep his little
keep his little Chihuahua
keep his little Chihuahua up
keep his little Chihuahua up in
keep his little Chihuahua up in the
keep his little Chihuahua up in the air
while
while this
keep his little Chihuahua up in the air
while this mad
while this mad beast
keep his little Chihuahua up in the air
while this mad beast of
while this mad beast of a
keep his little Chihuahua up in the air
while this mad beast of a dog
while this mad beast of a dog is
attacking
attacking him.
So
So anyway,
everything
everything is
everything is the
everything is the perfect
everything is the perfect expression
everything is the perfect expression of
what
what it
everything is the perfect expression of
what it is.
what it is. The
everything is the perfect expression of
what it is. The dinosaur
what it is. The dinosaur is
everything is the perfect expression of
what it is. The dinosaur is the
what it is. The dinosaur is the perfect
rapacious,
greedy,
looking
looking only
looking only to
looking only to myself
looking only to myself and
looking only to myself and what
looking only to myself and what I
looking only to myself and what I want.
Nothing
Nothing else
looking only to myself and what I want.
Nothing else out
Nothing else out there
looking only to myself and what I want.
Nothing else out there has
Nothing else out there has any
looking only to myself and what I want.
Nothing else out there has any rights.
It
It takes
It takes what
It takes what it
It takes what it wants
It takes what it wants and
It takes what it wants and kills
It takes what it wants and kills what
It takes what it wants and kills what it
wants
wants in
It takes what it wants and kills what it
wants in the
wants in the process.
It takes what it wants and kills what it
wants in the process. That's
wants in the process. That's energy
It takes what it wants and kills what it
wants in the process. That's energy 70.
That's
That's been
That's been allowed.
That's been allowed. That's
That's been allowed. That's the
That's been allowed. That's the World
Trade
Trade Center.
The
The consciousness
The consciousness of
The consciousness of mankind,
The consciousness of mankind, don't
forget,
forget, has
The consciousness of mankind, don't
forget, has been
forget, has been below
The consciousness of mankind, don't
forget, has been below 200,
forget, has been below 200, which
The consciousness of mankind, don't
forget, has been below 200, which is
forget, has been below 200, which is a
level
level of
level of integrity,
level of integrity, which
level of integrity, which is
level of integrity, which is just
level of integrity, which is just common
decency
decency like
level of integrity, which is just common
decency like the
decency like the IRS
throughout
throughout all
throughout all history.
throughout all history. It's
throughout all history. It's only
throughout all history. It's only the
late
late ' 80s
throughout all history. It's only the
late ' 80s that
late ' 80s that it
throughout all history. It's only the
late ' 80s that it went
late ' 80s that it went to
throughout all history. It's only the
late ' 80s that it went to 207,
late ' 80s that it went to 207, went
over
over 202.
So
So mankind
over 202.
So mankind is
So mankind is the
over 202.
So mankind is the perfect
So mankind is the perfect illustration
of
of that
of that which
of that which is
of that which is horrendous.
Mankind
Mankind up
of that which is horrendous.
Mankind up to
Mankind up to now
of that which is horrendous.
Mankind up to now has
Mankind up to now has been
of that which is horrendous.
Mankind up to now has been the
Mankind up to now has been the perfect
demonstration
demonstration of
demonstration of that
demonstration of that which
demonstration of that which is
horrendous.
Mankind
Mankind is
Mankind is the
Mankind is the demonstration
Mankind is the demonstration of
Mankind is the demonstration of that
which
which is
Mankind is the demonstration of that
which is non-intigorous
which is non-intigorous and
Mankind is the demonstration of that
which is non-intigorous and horrendous.
the
the history
the history of
the history of the
the history of the churches
the history of the churches throughout
the
the Inquisition,
the endless
the endless wars,
the endless wars, the
the endless wars, the hundredyear
the endless wars, the hundredyear wars.
In
In my
the endless wars, the hundredyear wars.
In my lifetime,
In my lifetime, I've
the endless wars, the hundredyear wars.
In my lifetime, I've already
In my lifetime, I've already lived
through.
through. I
through. I can't
through. I can't tell
through. I can't tell how
through. I can't tell how many
through. I can't tell how many wars
already.
And
And I
And I was
And I was born
And I was born right
And I was born right after
And I was born right after World
And I was born right after World War
And I was born right after World War I.
So,
So, it's
And I was born right after World War I.
So, it's been
So, it's been 40
And I was born right after World War I.
So, it's been 40 million
So, it's been 40 million here,
And I was born right after World War I.
So, it's been 40 million here, 30
million
million there,
million there, 40
million there, 40 million
million there, 40 million there
with
with some
million there, 40 million there
with some political
with some political slogan
million there, 40 million there
with some political slogan to
with some political slogan to justify
it.
Uh,
watch
watch out
watch out for
watch out for the
watch out for the idealistic
watch out for the idealistic political
slogan.
Kill
Kill more
Kill more people
Kill more people than
Kill more people than anything
Kill more people than anything else,
haven't
haven't it?
All
All right.
So,
So, each
All right.
So, each thing
So, each thing then
All right.
So, each thing then is
So, each thing then is the
All right.
So, each thing then is the perfect
representation.
You
You see,
representation.
You see, if
You see, if you
representation.
You see, if you live
You see, if you live in
representation.
You see, if you live in the
You see, if you live in the instant
representation.
You see, if you live in the instant of
moment,
you
you only
moment,
you only see
the
the bullet
the bullet coming
the bullet coming in
the bullet coming in and
the bullet coming in and going
the bullet coming in and going out
the bullet coming in and going out his
back
back and
the bullet coming in and going out his
back and the
back and the blood
the bullet coming in and going out his
back and the blood squirreling
back and the blood squirreling all
the bullet coming in and going out his
back and the blood squirreling all over
and
and it's
and it's like
and it's like a
and it's like a dance.
and it's like a dance. Huh?
and it's like a dance. Huh? See
and it's like a dance. Huh? See the
perfection
perfection of
and it's like a dance. Huh? See the
perfection of getting
perfection of getting killed
and it's like a dance. Huh? See the
perfection of getting killed by
perfection of getting killed by a
bullet.
bullet. That's
bullet. That's how
bullet. That's how you
bullet. That's how you get
bullet. That's how you get killed
bullet. That's how you get killed by
bullet. That's how you get killed by a
bullet.
bullet. That's
bullet. That's how you get killed by a
bullet. That's how
bullet. That's how it
bullet. That's how you get killed by a
bullet. That's how it happens,
bullet. That's how it happens, folks.
Just
Just like
Just like how
Just like how you
Just like how you chop
Just like how you chop your
Just like how you chop your thumb
Just like how you chop your thumb off
and
and one
Just like how you chop your thumb off
and one instant
and one instant it's
Just like how you chop your thumb off
and one instant it's absolute
perfection.
That's
That's the
perfection.
That's the perfection
That's the perfection of
perfection.
That's the perfection of cutting
That's the perfection of cutting your
thumb
thumb off
thumb off like
thumb off like that.
That's
That's the
thumb off like that.
That's the zen
That's the zen of
thumb off like that.
That's the zen of catching
That's the zen of catching chickens.
The
The zen
The zen of
The zen of catching
The zen of catching chickens
The zen of catching chickens in
The zen of catching chickens in the
The zen of catching chickens in the hen
house.
In
In one
In one instant
In one instant with
In one instant with absolute
In one instant with absolute clarity.
Hand
Hand grabs
In one instant with absolute clarity.
Hand grabs that
Hand grabs that chicken.
In one instant with absolute clarity.
Hand grabs that chicken. There's
Hand grabs that chicken. There's no
In one instant with absolute clarity.
Hand grabs that chicken. There's no me
involved.
involved. The
involved. The hand
involved. The hand grab
involved. The hand grab the
involved. The hand grab the chicken.
The
The in
involved. The hand grab the chicken.
The in intent.
The in intent. There
involved. The hand grab the chicken.
The in intent. There was
The in intent. There was no
involved. The hand grab the chicken.
The in intent. There was no block
The in intent. There was no block in
involved. The hand grab the chicken.
The in intent. There was no block in the
intent.
intent. No
intent. No hesitation.
intent. No hesitation. With
intent. No hesitation. With absolute
perfection.
Got
Got that
Got that chicken.
Got that chicken. And
Got that chicken. And when
Got that chicken. And when he's
Got that chicken. And when he's a
chicken
chicken caught,
you're
you're looking
you're looking at
you're looking at the
you're looking at the world
you're looking at the world champion
chicken
chicken catcher.
I
I didn't
I didn't get
I didn't get any
I didn't get any karate
I didn't get any karate lessons.
I didn't get any karate lessons. I
I didn't get any karate lessons. I knew
it
it was
I didn't get any karate lessons. I knew
it was there,
but
but it
but it seemed
but it seemed to
but it seemed to take
but it seemed to take too
but it seemed to take too long,
but it seemed to take too long, take
but it seemed to take too long, take you
forever.
forever. I
but it seemed to take too long, take you
forever. I knew
forever. I knew that
but it seemed to take too long, take you
forever. I knew that moment
forever. I knew that moment would
but it seemed to take too long, take you
forever. I knew that moment would open
up
up through
up through karate,
up through karate, but
up through karate, but instead
up through karate, but instead it
up through karate, but instead it opened
up
up in
up through karate, but instead it opened
up in the
up in the chicken
up through karate, but instead it opened
up in the chicken house.
That
That moment
That moment of
That moment of absolute
That moment of absolute light
That moment of absolute light where
there's
there's no
That moment of absolute light where
there's no personal
there's no personal self.
It
It was
It was the
It was the perfect
It was the perfect expression
It was the perfect expression of
It was the perfect expression of that
which
which it
It was the perfect expression of that
which it was
which it was at
It was the perfect expression of that
which it was at the
which it was at the moment
It was the perfect expression of that
which it was at the moment as
which it was at the moment as a
It was the perfect expression of that
which it was at the moment as a caught
chicken.
All
All right.
So,
So, everything
So, everything is
So, everything is being
So, everything is being perfectly
So, everything is being perfectly what
it
it is
So, everything is being perfectly what
it is at
it is at the
So, everything is being perfectly what
it is at the moment.
Hitler
Hitler was
Hitler was the
Hitler was the perfect
Hitler was the perfect demagogue.
Hitler was the perfect demagogue. I
mean,
mean, he
Hitler was the perfect demagogue. I
mean, he was
mean, he was profound.
Hitler was the perfect demagogue. I
mean, he was profound. You
mean, he was profound. You look
Hitler was the perfect demagogue. I
mean, he was profound. You look out
there
there over
there over the
there over the masses.
there over the masses. You
there over the masses. You look
there over the masses. You look at
there over the masses. You look at those
History
History Channel
there over the masses. You look at those
History Channel uh
History Channel uh World
there over the masses. You look at those
History Channel uh World War
History Channel uh World War II
there over the masses. You look at those
History Channel uh World War II and
History Channel uh World War II and you
see
see hundreds
see hundreds of
see hundreds of thousands
see hundreds of thousands of
see hundreds of thousands of people,
see hundreds of thousands of people, you
know,
know, and
see hundreds of thousands of people, you
know, and going
know, and going in
see hundreds of thousands of people, you
know, and going in this
know, and going in this great
see hundreds of thousands of people, you
know, and going in this great parade
with
with all
with all the
with all the flags
with all the flags and
with all the flags and the
with all the flags and the music.
with all the flags and the music. I
mean,
mean, it
with all the flags and the music. I
mean, it was
mean, it was fantastic.
with all the flags and the music. I
mean, it was fantastic. the
mean, it was fantastic. the perfect
expression
expression of
expression of nationalism.
Perfect.
And
And then
And then you
And then you follow
And then you follow nationalism
And then you follow nationalism through
to
to where
And then you follow nationalism through
to where it
to where it takes
And then you follow nationalism through
to where it takes you
after
after Linenrad,
half
half a
after Linenrad,
half a million
half a million dead
after Linenrad,
half a million dead Germans,
their
their bodies
their bodies being
their bodies being dragged
their bodies being dragged back
their bodies being dragged back by
their bodies being dragged back by oxen
and
and god
their bodies being dragged back by oxen
and god knows
and god knows what.
That's
That's a
That's a perfect
That's a perfect expression
That's a perfect expression of
That's a perfect expression of what
nationalism
nationalism is.
That's a perfect expression of what
nationalism is. So
nationalism is. So we
That's a perfect expression of what
nationalism is. So we can
nationalism is. So we can understand
That's a perfect expression of what
nationalism is. So we can understand the
political
political person
political person who
political person who objects
political person who objects to
nationalism.
It
It says
It says his
It says his history
It says his history has
It says his history has been
It says his history has been horrible.
It's
It's correct.
But
But nationalism
But nationalism is
But nationalism is not
But nationalism is not patriotism.
Patriotism
Patriotism is
But nationalism is not patriotism.
Patriotism is something
Patriotism is something different.
But nationalism is not patriotism.
Patriotism is something different. To
confuse
confuse nationalism
confuse nationalism and
confuse nationalism and patriotism
confuse nationalism and patriotism is
confuse nationalism and patriotism is a
grave
grave error.
confuse nationalism and patriotism is a
grave error. There's
grave error. There's one
confuse nationalism and patriotism is a
grave error. There's one of
grave error. There's one of those
confuse nationalism and patriotism is a
grave error. There's one of those errors
of
of context.
Nationalism
Nationalism is
of context.
Nationalism is one
Nationalism is one thing.
of context.
Nationalism is one thing. Patriotism
Nationalism is one thing. Patriotism is
another.
another. Patriotism
comes
comes from
another. Patriotism
comes from the
comes from the heart.
another. Patriotism
comes from the heart. Huh?
comes from the heart. Huh? The
another. Patriotism
comes from the heart. Huh? The reverence
of
of which
of which we
of which we held
of which we held women
of which we held women as
of which we held women as I
of which we held women as I grew
of which we held women as I grew up
of which we held women as I grew up came
from
from the
of which we held women as I grew up came
from the heart.
from the heart. Huh?
Feminism
Feminism is
Feminism is like
Feminism is like nationalism.
Feminism is like nationalism. It's
Feminism is like nationalism. It's a
political
political position.
Feminism is like nationalism. It's a
political position. There's
political position. There's no
Feminism is like nationalism. It's a
political position. There's no heart
here.
here. There's
here. There's no
here. There's no heart
here. There's no heart here.
here. There's no heart here. The
feminist
feminist position
here. There's no heart here. The
feminist position is
feminist position is heartless.
If
If anything,
If anything, it's
If anything, it's cruel
If anything, it's cruel and
If anything, it's cruel and heartless
If anything, it's cruel and heartless to
women.
My
My my
My my reservation
My my reservation about
My my reservation about it
My my reservation about it is
My my reservation about it is that
My my reservation about it is that it's
heartless
heartless to
My my reservation about it is that it's
heartless to women.
heartless to women. Has
My my reservation about it is that it's
heartless to women. Has no
heartless to women. Has no love
My my reservation about it is that it's
heartless to women. Has no love for
women
women at
women at all.
women at all. It
women at all. It exposes
women at all. It exposes them
women at all. It exposes them in
women at all. It exposes them in the
harshest
harshest terms
women at all. It exposes them in the
harshest terms in
harshest terms in the
women at all. It exposes them in the
harshest terms in the harshest
uh
uh structure.
So
So patriotism
uh structure.
So patriotism is
So patriotism is this
uh structure.
So patriotism is this is
So patriotism is this is expressed
uh structure.
So patriotism is this is expressed in
the
the poem
the poem as
the poem as there
the poem as there a
the poem as there a man
the poem as there a man live
the poem as there a man live to
the poem as there a man live to the
heart
heart so
the poem as there a man live to the
heart so dead
heart so dead with
the poem as there a man live to the
heart so dead with soul
heart so dead with soul so
the poem as there a man live to the
heart so dead with soul so dead
heart so dead with soul so dead who
never
never to
never to himself
never to himself has
never to himself has said
never to himself has said this
never to himself has said this is
never to himself has said this is my
never to himself has said this is my own
my
my native
never to himself has said this is my own
my native land.
You
You see?
You see? So
You see? So now
You see? So now what
You see? So now what you're
You see? So now what you're talking
about
about is
You see? So now what you're talking
about is the
about is the truth
You see? So now what you're talking
about is the truth of
about is the truth of the
You see? So now what you're talking
about is the truth of the heart.
about is the truth of the heart. Truth
of
of the
of the heart
of the heart has
of the heart has no
of the heart has no politics.
of the heart has no politics. You
understand?
Nationalism
Nationalism will
Nationalism will kill
Nationalism will kill you.
Love
Love for
Nationalism will kill you.
Love for one's
Love for one's country
Nationalism will kill you.
Love for one's country is
Love for one's country is a
Nationalism will kill you.
Love for one's country is a totally
different
different thing.
different thing. Let's
different thing. Let's see.
Patriotism
Patriotism calibrates
different thing. Let's see.
Patriotism calibrates over
Patriotism calibrates over 500,
different thing. Let's see.
Patriotism calibrates over 500, 510,
520,
520, 530,
520, 530, 540.
520, 530, 540. Patriotism
520, 530, 540. Patriotism calibrates
520, 530, 540. Patriotism calibrates at
540.
Nationalism
Nationalism calibrates
Nationalism calibrates over
Nationalism calibrates over 200
Nationalism calibrates over 200 205
Nationalism calibrates over 200 205 210
calibrates
calibrates nationalism
Nationalism calibrates over 200 205 210
calibrates nationalism calibrates
calibrates nationalism calibrates 205
2010.
All
All right.
2010.
All right. So
All right. So the
2010.
All right. So the feminist
All right. So the feminist political
position
position calibrates
position calibrates over
position calibrates over 200
position calibrates over 200 205
position calibrates over 200 205 210
215.
215. See
position calibrates over 200 205 210
215. See political
215. See political position
position calibrates over 200 205 210
215. See political position is
215. See political position is only
position calibrates over 200 205 210
215. See political position is only 210.
The
The reverence
The reverence for
The reverence for women
The reverence for women out
The reverence for women out of
The reverence for women out of which
they
they were
The reverence for women out of which
they were held
they were held as
The reverence for women out of which
they were held as I
they were held as I grew
The reverence for women out of which
they were held as I grew up
they were held as I grew up calibrates
in
in the
in the 500s.
in the 500s. See
in the 500s. See what
in the 500s. See what I'm
in the 500s. See what I'm saying?
in the 500s. See what I'm saying? So
it's
it's not
in the 500s. See what I'm saying? So
it's not necessarily
it's not necessarily progress
in the 500s. See what I'm saying? So
it's not necessarily progress to
it's not necessarily progress to go
in the 500s. See what I'm saying? So
it's not necessarily progress to go from
500 to
500 to 200.
Now
Now I'm
500 to 200.
Now I'm going
Now I'm going to
500 to 200.
Now I'm going to slam
Now I'm going to slam the
500 to 200.
Now I'm going to slam the door
Now I'm going to slam the door in
500 to 200.
Now I'm going to slam the door in your
face
face and
face and say,
face and say, "Look,
face and say, "Look, fight
face and say, "Look, fight for
yourself."
yourself." You
face and say, "Look, fight for
yourself." You know what
yourself." You know what I
face and say, "Look, fight for
yourself." You know what I mean?
Take
Take the
Take the downside
Take the downside of
Take the downside of the
Take the downside of the workplace.
Take the downside of the workplace. So
inviting
inviting people
Take the downside of the workplace. So
inviting people into
inviting people into the
Take the downside of the workplace. So
inviting people into the downside
inviting people into the downside of
Take the downside of the workplace. So
inviting people into the downside of the
workplace
is,
is, you
workplace
is, you know,
is, you know, come
workplace
is, you know, come see
is, you know, come see Kamawa.
workplace
is, you know, come see Kamawa. It's
is, you know, come see Kamawa. It's got
its
its upside.
its upside. It's
its upside. It's got
its upside. It's got its
its upside. It's got its downside.
But
But you
its upside. It's got its downside.
But you can't
But you can't hold
its upside. It's got its downside.
But you can't hold it
But you can't hold it one
its upside. It's got its downside.
But you can't hold it one is
But you can't hold it one is the
moralistic
moralistic high
moralistic high ground.
moralistic high ground. See,
moralistic high ground. See, we're
talking
talking about
moralistic high ground. See, we're
talking about is
talking about is the
moralistic high ground. See, we're
talking about is the imposition
talking about is the imposition of
moralistic high ground. See, we're
talking about is the imposition of the
supposed
supposed moralistic
supposed moralistic high
supposed moralistic high ground
supposed moralistic high ground as
supposed moralistic high ground as an
imposition,
imposition, a
supposed moralistic high ground as an
imposition, a political
imposition, a political imposition
supposed moralistic high ground as an
imposition, a political imposition on
the
the psyche
the psyche of
the psyche of society,
the psyche of society, which
the psyche of society, which is
vulnerable
and
and naive.
and naive. It's
and naive. It's vulnerber
and naive. It's vulnerber and
and naive. It's vulnerber and naive
because
because it
and naive. It's vulnerber and naive
because it doesn't
because it doesn't understand
and naive. It's vulnerber and naive
because it doesn't understand context.
That
That which
That which is
That which is of
That which is of God
That which is of God brings
That which is of God brings peace.
Brings
Brings peace.
That
That which
That which is
That which is of
That which is of God
That which is of God brings
That which is of God brings peace
That which is of God brings peace and
love.
love. Huh?
That which is of God brings peace and
love. Huh? So
love. Huh? So it's
That which is of God brings peace and
love. Huh? So it's it's
love. Huh? So it's it's you
That which is of God brings peace and
love. Huh? So it's it's you can
love. Huh? So it's it's you can tell
instantly
instantly that
instantly that which
instantly that which is
instantly that which is of
instantly that which is of God.
instantly that which is of God. It
brings
brings peace
instantly that which is of God. It
brings peace and
brings peace and love.
All right.
All right. So
All right. So that's
All right. So that's it's
All right. So that's it's the
All right. So that's it's the pe
All right. So that's it's the pe it's
that
that that
All right. So that's it's the pe it's
that that which
that that which arises
All right. So that's it's the pe it's
that that which arises out
that that which arises out of
All right. So that's it's the pe it's
that that which arises out of the
that that which arises out of the love
of
of God
of God because
of God because we're
of God because we're building
of God because we're building up
of God because we're building up to
of God because we're building up to the
lessons
lessons where
of God because we're building up to the
lessons where we're
lessons where we're talking
of God because we're building up to the
lessons where we're talking about
it's
it's the
it's the love
it's the love of
it's the love of the
it's the love of the truth
it's the love of the truth then
it's the love of the truth then that
begins
begins to
it's the love of the truth then that
begins to remove
begins to remove the
it's the love of the truth then that
begins to remove the obstacles
begins to remove the obstacles to
it's the love of the truth then that
begins to remove the obstacles to its
acceptance.
A
A person
acceptance.
A person has
A person has gone
acceptance.
A person has gone to
A person has gone to many
acceptance.
A person has gone to many many
A person has gone to many many lectures
and
and intellectually
and intellectually gotten
and intellectually gotten it
and
and nothing
and intellectually gotten it
and nothing has
and nothing has changed.
and intellectually gotten it
and nothing has changed. Huh?
So
So the
So the ego
So the ego has
So the ego has no
So the ego has no defenses
So the ego has no defenses against
So the ego has no defenses against love
really
really except
So the ego has no defenses against love
really except to
really except to try
So the ego has no defenses against love
really except to try and
really except to try and den
So the ego has no defenses against love
really except to try and den denigorate
you
you know
you know the
you know the word
put
put it
you know the word
put it down.
So
So I'm
So I'm mad
So I'm mad at
So I'm mad at feminism
So I'm mad at feminism as
So I'm mad at feminism as a
So I'm mad at feminism as a political
stance
because
because it
because it put
because it put women
because it put women down
because it put women down from
because it put women down from five
because it put women down from five over
500s
500s to
because it put women down from five over
500s to 210.
210 is
210 is a
210 is a hell
210 is a hell of
210 is a hell of a
210 is a hell of a lot
210 is a hell of a lot better
210 is a hell of a lot better than
210 is a hell of a lot better than 190.
180.
I'd
I'd rather
I'd rather be
I'd rather be a
I'd rather be a woman
I'd rather be a woman in
I'd rather be a woman in the
I'd rather be a woman in the workplace
in
in a
I'd rather be a woman in the workplace
in a political
in a political atmosphere
I'd rather be a woman in the workplace
in a political atmosphere that
calibrates
calibrates at
calibrates at 210
rather
rather than
calibrates at 210
rather than the
rather than the women
calibrates at 210
rather than the women in
rather than the women in the
calibrates at 210
rather than the women in the Arabic
countries,
countries, let's
countries, let's say.
countries, let's say. Where
countries, let's say. Where are
countries, let's say. Where are the
women
women in
countries, let's say. Where are the
women in the
women in the Arabic
countries, let's say. Where are the
women in the Arabic countries?
women in the Arabic countries? What
countries, let's say. Where are the
women in the Arabic countries? What is
the
the political
the political space
the political space that
the political space that they're
the political space that they're held
in?
in? We
the political space that they're held
in? We have
in? We have permission
the political space that they're held
in? We have permission to
in? We have permission to ask
the political space that they're held
in? We have permission to ask that
resist.
Um
Um the
resist.
Um the position
Um the position of
resist.
Um the position of the
Um the position of the veiled
resist.
Um the position of the veiled woman
who's
who's not
who's not allowed
who's not allowed to
who's not allowed to have
who's not allowed to have any
who's not allowed to have any rights
whatsoever
whatsoever is
who's not allowed to have any rights
whatsoever is over
whatsoever is over 200
over
over 150
over 150 60.
All right.
All right. The
over 150 60.
All right. The woman
All right. The woman in
over 150 60.
All right. The woman in the
All right. The woman in the Arabic
over 150 60.
All right. The woman in the Arabic world
is
is in
is in a
is in a one
is in a one field
is in a one field of
is in a one field of 160.
So
So to
is in a one field of 160.
So to come
So to come to
is in a one field of 160.
So to come to the
So to come to the United
is in a one field of 160.
So to come to the United States
So to come to the United States and
is in a one field of 160.
So to come to the United States and get
a
a job
a job is
a job is uh
a job is uh quite
a job is uh quite a
a job is uh quite a jump
a job is uh quite a jump up
a job is uh quite a jump up to
a job is uh quite a jump up to 215.
So
So you
a job is uh quite a jump up to 215.
So you see
So you see context
a job is uh quite a jump up to 215.
So you see context spells
So you see context spells everything.
a job is uh quite a jump up to 215.
So you see context spells everything. Is
that
that an
that an advance
that an advance or
it
it all
that an advance or
it all depends
it all depends on
that an advance or
it all depends on the
it all depends on the context
that an advance or
it all depends on the context in
it all depends on the context in which
you're
you're coming?
That
That which
you're coming?
That which is
That which is comes
you're coming?
That which is comes from
That which is comes from God
you're coming?
That which is comes from God is
That which is comes from God is love.
Love
Love calibrates
Love calibrates over
Love calibrates over 500.
The
The mode
Love calibrates over 500.
The mode in
The mode in which
Love calibrates over 500.
The mode in which women
The mode in which women are
Love calibrates over 500.
The mode in which women are held
The mode in which women are held within
that
that particular
part
part of
that particular
part of the
part of the world
that particular
part of the world then
part of the world then inaugurates
women.
Then integrates
Then integrates them
women.
Then integrates them to
Then integrates them to a
women.
Then integrates them to a level
Then integrates them to a level of
women.
Then integrates them to a level of 160.
Probably
Probably as
Probably as valuable
Probably as valuable as
Probably as valuable as the
Probably as valuable as the farm
animals.
Maybe
Maybe not
Maybe not quite
Maybe not quite as
Maybe not quite as valuable
Maybe not quite as valuable as
Maybe not quite as valuable as the
Maybe not quite as valuable as the farm
animals.
That's
That's true.
That's true. Women
That's true. Women are
That's true. Women are not
That's true. Women are not as
That's true. Women are not as valuable
as
as the
That's true. Women are not as valuable
as the farm
as the farm animals.
That's true. Women are not as valuable
as the farm animals. Is
as the farm animals. Is it?
That's true. Women are not as valuable
as the farm animals. Is it? That's
correct.
correct. Women
correct. Women are
correct. Women are not
correct. Women are not as
correct. Women are not as valuable
correct. Women are not as valuable as
farm
farm animals.
correct. Women are not as valuable as
farm animals. Why?
farm animals. Why? Because
correct. Women are not as valuable as
farm animals. Why? Because your
farm animals. Why? Because your life
depends
depends on
depends on farm
depends on farm animals
depends on farm animals and
depends on farm animals and women
depends on farm animals and women you
can
can sell
depends on farm animals and women you
can sell and
can sell and give
depends on farm animals and women you
can sell and give them
can sell and give them away
depends on farm animals and women you
can sell and give them away and
can sell and give them away and kill
them
them if
them if they
them if they displease
them if they displease you.
them if they displease you. Huh.
them if they displease you. Huh. How's
that
that for
them if they displease you. Huh. How's
that for Mother's
that for Mother's Day?
Uh,
Uh, okay.
Uh, okay. So
Uh, okay. So having
Uh, okay. So having a
Uh, okay. So having a tool
Uh, okay. So having a tool for
consciousness
consciousness research
Uh, okay. So having a tool for
consciousness research allows
consciousness research allows us
Uh, okay. So having a tool for
consciousness research allows us to
investigate
investigate a
investigate a lot
investigate a lot of
investigate a lot of the
investigate a lot of the premises
investigate a lot of the premises of
society,
society, a
investigate a lot of the premises of
society, a lot
society, a lot of
investigate a lot of the premises of
society, a lot of the
uh
uh slogans
uh slogans that
uh slogans that we
uh slogans that we uh
uh slogans that we uh unconsciously
accept
accept a
uh slogans that we uh unconsciously
accept a lot
accept a lot of
uh slogans that we uh unconsciously
accept a lot of the
accept a lot of the invalidations
uh slogans that we uh unconsciously
accept a lot of the invalidations of
reality.
If
If love
reality.
If love is
If love is the
reality.
If love is the biggest
If love is the biggest danger
reality.
If love is the biggest danger to
If love is the biggest danger to the
ego,
then
then that
ego,
then that which
then that which is
ego,
then that which is loving
then that which is loving in
ego,
then that which is loving in society
would
would attract
would attract attack
would attract attack from
would attract attack from that
would attract attack from that which
would attract attack from that which is
against
against love.
would attract attack from that which is
against love. that
against love. that which
would attract attack from that which is
against love. that which is
against love. that which is certain
would attract attack from that which is
against love. that which is certain by
love
love will
love will try
love will try to
love will try to attack
love will try to attack love.
love will try to attack love. Therefore,
I
I expect
is
is Walmart
is Walmart unionized?
>> No.
>> No. I
is Walmart unionized?
>> No. I would
>> No. I would expect
is Walmart unionized?
>> No. I would expect the
>> No. I would expect the unionization
is Walmart unionized?
>> No. I would expect the unionization of
Walmart
Walmart to
Walmart to be
Walmart to be the
Walmart to be the uh
Walmart to be the uh headlines
Walmart to be the uh headlines of
Walmart to be the uh headlines of 10
years
years in.
Why?
Why? Because
Why? Because it
Why? Because it works
Why? Because it works perfectly.
Why? Because it works perfectly. It's
beautiful.
beautiful. It's
Why? Because it works perfectly. It's
beautiful. It's peaceful.
beautiful. It's peaceful. It's
Why? Because it works perfectly. It's
beautiful. It's peaceful. It's safe.
And
And that'll
And that'll bring
And that'll bring out
And that'll bring out the
And that'll bring out the dragons.
We
We can
And that'll bring out the dragons.
We can politicize
We can politicize it.
And that'll bring out the dragons.
We can politicize it. Now
We can politicize it. Now start
And that'll bring out the dragons.
We can politicize it. Now start to
We can politicize it. Now start to make
it
it wrong.
Now
Now start
it wrong.
Now start to
Now start to make
it wrong.
Now start to make it
Now start to make it wrong.
Now
Now start
Now start to
Now start to uh
Now start to uh hypothesize
Now start to uh hypothesize a
Now start to uh hypothesize a correction
of
of this
Now start to uh hypothesize a correction
of this hypothetical
of this hypothetical wrong
Now start to uh hypothesize a correction
of this hypothetical wrong which
of this hypothetical wrong which of
course
course doesn't
course doesn't even
course doesn't even exist.
course doesn't even exist. And
course doesn't even exist. And they're
going
going to
course doesn't even exist. And they're
going to come
going to come in
course doesn't even exist. And they're
going to come in and
going to come in and correct
course doesn't even exist. And they're
going to come in and correct it.
going to come in and correct it. And
course doesn't even exist. And they're
going to come in and correct it. And of
course
course you're
course you're going
course you're going to
course you're going to have
course you're going to have to
course you're going to have to fork
over.
There's
There's always
There's always a
There's always a fee
There's always a fee for
There's always a fee for this.
There's always a fee for this. Yeah.
So
So all
There's always a fee for this. Yeah.
So all right,
So all right, we
There's always a fee for this. Yeah.
So all right, we watch
So all right, we watch these
There's always a fee for this. Yeah.
So all right, we watch these phenomena
then
then throughout
then throughout society.
then throughout society. We
then throughout society. We see
then throughout society. We see how
they're
they're disguised
then throughout society. We see how
they're disguised as
they're disguised as political
positions.
You
You see,
positions.
You see, it's
You see, it's not
positions.
You see, it's not really
You see, it's not really political.
Political
Political is
Political is just
Political is just a
Political is just a way
Political is just a way of
Political is just a way of looking
Political is just a way of looking at
Political is just a way of looking at a
thing.
thing. A
Political is just a way of looking at a
thing. A thing
thing. A thing is
Political is just a way of looking at a
thing. A thing is not
thing. A thing is not its
Political is just a way of looking at a
thing. A thing is not its descriptive
thing. A thing is not its descriptive is
not
not its
not its description
which
which is
not its description
which is very
which is very hard
not its description
which is very hard for
which is very hard for the
not its description
which is very hard for the intellect
which is very hard for the intellect to
see.
see. The
see. The thing
see. The thing is
see. The thing is not
see. The thing is not what
see. The thing is not what a
see. The thing is not what a description
of
of the
see. The thing is not what a description
of the thing
of the thing is.
see. The thing is not what a description
of the thing is. A
of the thing is. A description
see. The thing is not what a description
of the thing is. A description of
of the thing is. A description of a
thing
thing is
thing is only
thing is only a
thing is only a description
thing is only a description of
thing is only a description of a
thing is only a description of a thing
and
and the
thing is only a description of a thing
and the thing
and the thing is
thing is only a description of a thing
and the thing is something
and the thing is something else.
The
The thing
The thing is
The thing is here.
There's
There's a
The thing is here.
There's a certain
There's a certain sophistication
The thing is here.
There's a certain sophistication in
quantum
quantum mechanics
quantum mechanics in
quantum mechanics in that
quantum mechanics in that it
quantum mechanics in that it says
quantum mechanics in that it says that
it
it doesn't
quantum mechanics in that it says that
it doesn't call
it doesn't call uh
quantum mechanics in that it says that
it doesn't call uh reality
it doesn't call uh reality measurable
anymore.
anymore. It
anymore. It calls
anymore. It calls it
anymore. It calls it observable.
In
In quantum
anymore. It calls it observable.
In quantum mechanics,
In quantum mechanics, it
anymore. It calls it observable.
In quantum mechanics, it doesn't
In quantum mechanics, it doesn't talk
about
about measurements
8 foot
8 foot by
about measurements
8 foot by 6
8 foot by 6 foot.
about measurements
8 foot by 6 foot. And
8 foot by 6 foot. And listen
in
in quantum
in quantum mechanics
in quantum mechanics which
in quantum mechanics which is
in quantum mechanics which is the
in quantum mechanics which is the most
advanced
advanced edge
in quantum mechanics which is the most
advanced edge of
advanced edge of science.
in quantum mechanics which is the most
advanced edge of science. It
advanced edge of science. It gets
closest
closest to
closest to spiritual
closest to spiritual reality.
Um
Um there's
closest to spiritual reality.
Um there's only
Um there's only observables.
There's
There's there
There's there so
There's there so there's
There's there so there's the
There's there so there's the reason
There's there so there's the reason it's
quite
quite advanced
There's there so there's the reason it's
quite advanced is
quite advanced is because
There's there so there's the reason it's
quite advanced is because now
quite advanced is because now you
There's there so there's the reason it's
quite advanced is because now you have
intellectual
intellectual sophistication
an
an awareness
intellectual sophistication
an awareness of
an awareness of the
intellectual sophistication
an awareness of the limitation
an awareness of the limitation of
intellectual sophistication
an awareness of the limitation of the
intellect.
Um,
Um, traditional
intellect.
Um, traditional science,
Um, traditional science, God
intellect.
Um, traditional science, God bless
Um, traditional science, God bless it,
has
has brought
has brought us
has brought us all
has brought us all kinds
has brought us all kinds of
has brought us all kinds of wonderful
things.
Its
Its limitation
Its limitation is
Its limitation is that
Its limitation is that it
Its limitation is that it doesn't
realize
realize its
Its limitation is that it doesn't
realize its own
realize its own limitation.
In
In quantum
In quantum mechanics,
In quantum mechanics, you
In quantum mechanics, you you
In quantum mechanics, you you is
In quantum mechanics, you you is that
leading
leading edge
In quantum mechanics, you you is that
leading edge of
leading edge of advanced
In quantum mechanics, you you is that
leading edge of advanced theoretical
physics.
physics. It
physics. It describes
physics. It describes observables.
physics. It describes observables. It's
only
only what
physics. It describes observables. It's
only what you
only what you can
physics. It describes observables. It's
only what you can observe.
The
The measurable
The measurable is
The measurable is one
The measurable is one thing.
The measurable is one thing. Observable
is
is another.
The measurable is one thing. Observable
is another. Because
is another. Because observable
retains
retains the
retains the observer
that
that the
retains the observer
that the observer
that the observer is
retains the observer
that the observer is present.
that the observer is present. Not
retains the observer
that the observer is present. Not just
that the observer is present. Not just a
measurement
measurement existing
measurement existing by
measurement existing by itself,
but
but the
measurement existing by itself,
but the observer
but the observer now
measurement existing by itself,
but the observer now has
but the observer now has an
measurement existing by itself,
but the observer now has an influence.
So
So all
So all we
So all we can
So all we can say
So all we can say about
So all we can say about society
So all we can say about society are
So all we can say about society are what
seem
seem to
So all we can say about society are what
seem to be
seem to be our
So all we can say about society are what
seem to be our observations
seem to be our observations of
So all we can say about society are what
seem to be our observations of it.
seem to be our observations of it. The
same
same with
same with the
same with the ego.
same with the ego. So
same with the ego. So when
same with the ego. So when we
same with the ego. So when we talk
same with the ego. So when we talk about
it,
it, we're
same with the ego. So when we talk about
it, we're not
it, we're not talking
same with the ego. So when we talk about
it, we're not talking about
it, we're not talking about a
self-existent
self-existent reality.
self-existent reality. We're
self-existent reality. We're just
talking
talking about
self-existent reality. We're just
talking about observables.
We've
We've used
We've used kinesiology
We've used kinesiology as
We've used kinesiology as a
We've used kinesiology as a tool
We've used kinesiology as a tool to
We've used kinesiology as a tool to cut
through
through between
We've used kinesiology as a tool to cut
through between measurables
through between measurables and
observables
observables as
observables as a
observables as a way
observables as a way of
observables as a way of going
observables as a way of going from
observables as a way of going from one
paradigm
paradigm of
observables as a way of going from one
paradigm of reality
paradigm of reality into
observables as a way of going from one
paradigm of reality into another.
Let's
Let's see.
Let's see. Mother's
Let's see. Mother's Day.
Mother's
Mother's Day
Let's see. Mother's Day.
Mother's Day when
Mother's Day when I
Let's see. Mother's Day.
Mother's Day when I grew
Mother's Day when I grew up
Let's see. Mother's Day.
Mother's Day when I grew up calibrated
over
over 400,
over 400, 450,
over 400, 450, 500,
over 400, 450, 500, 510,
over 400, 450, 500, 510, 520.
over 400, 450, 500, 510, 520. Mother's
Day
Day calibrate
over 400, 450, 500, 510, 520. Mother's
Day calibrate over
Day calibrate over 520
over 400, 450, 500, 510, 520. Mother's
Day calibrate over 520 when
Day calibrate over 520 when I
over 400, 450, 500, 510, 520. Mother's
Day calibrate over 520 when I grow.
Wonder
Wonder what
Wonder what it
Wonder what it is
Wonder what it is today.
Wonder what it is today. Mother's
Wonder what it is today. Mother's Day
today
today calibrates
Wonder what it is today. Mother's Day
today calibrates as
today calibrates as a
Wonder what it is today. Mother's Day
today calibrates as a social
today calibrates as a social phenomena
over
over 450,
over 450, 460,
over 450, 460, 470,
over 450, 460, 470, 470.
Drop
Drop from
over 450, 460, 470, 470.
Drop from 520
Drop from 520 to
over 450, 460, 470, 470.
Drop from 520 to 470.
Intellectually
Intellectually we
Intellectually we say,
Intellectually we say, "Oh
Intellectually we say, "Oh yeah,
Intellectually we say, "Oh yeah, mom's
the
the greatest,
Intellectually we say, "Oh yeah, mom's
the greatest, the
the greatest, the most
Intellectually we say, "Oh yeah, mom's
the greatest, the most wonderful,
the greatest, the most wonderful, etc.,
etc."
etc." But
etc." But as
etc." But as a
etc." But as a social
etc." But as a social phenomena
etc." But as a social phenomena is
dropped
dropped from
etc." But as a social phenomena is
dropped from real
dropped from real reverence.
See
See the
See the reverence
See the reverence real
See the reverence real is
See the reverence real is the
realization
realization of
See the reverence real is the
realization of the
realization of the divinity
See the reverence real is the
realization of the divinity coming
through
through the
through the feminine.
The
The divinity
through the feminine.
The divinity uh
The divinity uh which
through the feminine.
The divinity uh which comes
The divinity uh which comes through
through the feminine.
The divinity uh which comes through the
feminine
feminine which
feminine which was
feminine which was the
feminine which was the basis
feminine which was the basis of
feminine which was the basis of the
reverence.
reverence. Okay.
feminine which was the basis of the
reverence. Okay. We
reverence. Okay. We rever
feminine which was the basis of the
reverence. Okay. We rever we
reverence. Okay. We rever we revere
feminine which was the basis of the
reverence. Okay. We rever we revere that
which
which we
which we intuitit
which we intuitit the
which we intuitit the divinity
which we intuitit the divinity of
which we intuitit the divinity of its
essence.
Before
Before the
Before the woman
Before the woman was
obscured
obscured by
Before the woman was
obscured by political
obscured by political slogans
Before the woman was
obscured by political slogans and
obscured by political slogans and stuff,
we
we saw
we saw her
we saw her for
we saw her for what
we saw her for what she
we saw her for what she was,
the
the reflection
we saw her for what she was,
the reflection of
the reflection of God
we saw her for what she was,
the reflection of God as
the reflection of God as nurturance,
as
as the
as the very
as the very essence
as the very essence of
as the very essence of love
as the very essence of love manifesting
within
within the
as the very essence of love manifesting
within the human
within the human domain.
as the very essence of love manifesting
within the human domain. So
within the human domain. So she
as the very essence of love manifesting
within the human domain. So she was
within the human domain. So she was held
in
in reverence
in reverence because
in reverence because of
in reverence because of the
in reverence because of the reality
in reverence because of the reality of
the
the divinity
in reverence because of the reality of
the divinity of
the divinity of her
in reverence because of the reality of
the divinity of her existence.
That's
That's what
That's what Mother's
That's what Mother's Day
That's what Mother's Day is
That's what Mother's Day is about.
The
The recognition
That's what Mother's Day is about.
The recognition of
The recognition of the
That's what Mother's Day is about.
The recognition of the divinity
The recognition of the divinity out
That's what Mother's Day is about.
The recognition of the divinity out of
which
which arises
which arises existence.
The
The existence
which arises existence.
The existence of
The existence of the
which arises existence.
The existence of the magnificence
The existence of the magnificence of
which arises existence.
The existence of the magnificence of the
feminine.
A
A guy
feminine.
A guy can
A guy can try
feminine.
A guy can try to
A guy can try to be
feminine.
A guy can try to be a
A guy can try to be a great
feminine.
A guy can try to be a great mother,
A guy can try to be a great mother, but
I'll
I'll tell
I'll tell you
I'll tell you folks,
I'll tell you folks, it's
I'll tell you folks, it's a
I'll tell you folks, it's a fake.
You're
You're trying
I'll tell you folks, it's a fake.
You're trying to
You're trying to be
I'll tell you folks, it's a fake.
You're trying to be the
You're trying to be the good
I'll tell you folks, it's a fake.
You're trying to be the good father
hoing
hoing the
hoing the bottle
hoing the bottle there,
hoing the bottle there, but
hoing the bottle there, but I'll
hoing the bottle there, but I'll tell
you,
you, it's
hoing the bottle there, but I'll tell
you, it's not
you, it's not really
hoing the bottle there, but I'll tell
you, it's not really your
you, it's not really your thing.
hoing the bottle there, but I'll tell
you, it's not really your thing. You
know
know what I'm
know what I'm saying?
I
I got
know what I'm saying?
I got a
I got a new
know what I'm saying?
I got a new compressor
I got a new compressor at
know what I'm saying?
I got a new compressor at home
I got a new compressor at home and
know what I'm saying?
I got a new compressor at home and I'm
dying
dying to
dying to go
dying to go up
dying to go up and
dying to go up and try
dying to go up and try out
dying to go up and try out my
dying to go up and try out my new
compressor
compressor that
dying to go up and try out my new
compressor that I
compressor that I got
dying to go up and try out my new
compressor that I got for
compressor that I got for Christmas,
dying to go up and try out my new
compressor that I got for Christmas, you
know,
and
and but
know,
and but you're
and but you're supposed
know,
and but you're supposed to
and but you're supposed to be
know,
and but you're supposed to be the
and but you're supposed to be the good
father
father and
father and feed
father and feed the
father and feed the baby.
father and feed the baby. Okay.
father and feed the baby. Okay. Right.
Okay.
It
It isn't
It isn't really
It isn't really real
It isn't really real because
It isn't really real because it's
It isn't really real because it's not
rooted
rooted in
the
the evolution
the evolution of
the evolution of human
the evolution of human society
throughout
throughout the
the evolution of human society
throughout the eons.
throughout the eons. It's
the evolution of human society
throughout the eons. It's not
throughout the eons. It's not rooted
the evolution of human society
throughout the eons. It's not rooted in
me
me to
me to nurse
me to nurse the
me to nurse the babies.
It's
It's I
me to nurse the babies.
It's I think
It's I think more
me to nurse the babies.
It's I think more tends
It's I think more tends to
me to nurse the babies.
It's I think more tends to be
It's I think more tends to be rooted
me to nurse the babies.
It's I think more tends to be rooted in
the
the mother.
the mother. Is
the mother. Is that
the mother. Is that right?
the mother. Is that right? You
the mother. Is that right? You might
the mother. Is that right? You might as
well
well sound
the mother. Is that right? You might as
well sound sexist
well sound sexist today.
the mother. Is that right? You might as
well sound sexist today. What?
well sound sexist today. What? That's
true.
All right.
All right. So,
true.
All right. So, each
All right. So, each thing
true.
All right. So, each thing then
represents
represents the
represents the perfection
represents the perfection of
represents the perfection of that
represents the perfection of that which
it
it is.
the
the unfolding
the unfolding of
the unfolding of the
the unfolding of the rose
the unfolding of the rose when
the unfolding of the rose when it's
the unfolding of the rose when it's half
unfolded.
Uh
Uh the
Uh the battlefield
Uh the battlefield full
Uh the battlefield full of
Uh the battlefield full of slaughtered
troops,
the
the dead
the dead civilians
the dead civilians after
the dead civilians after the
the dead civilians after the atomic
blast.
Each
Each thing
Each thing was
Each thing was exactly
Each thing was exactly what
Each thing was exactly what that
Each thing was exactly what that is.
It
It it
Each thing was exactly what that is.
It it it
It it it is
Each thing was exactly what that is.
It it it is a
It it it is a demonstration
Each thing was exactly what that is.
It it it is a demonstration the
dramatization
dramatization of
dramatization of that
dramatization of that level
dramatization of that level of
consciousness.
And
And that's
And that's what
And that's what drives
And that's what drives man.
Some
Some people
And that's what drives man.
Some people some
Some people some people
And that's what drives man.
Some people some people get
Some people some people get that
And that's what drives man.
Some people some people get that it's
not
not too
not too good
to
to have
not too good
to have a
to have a battlefield
not too good
to have a battlefield of
to have a battlefield of dead
not too good
to have a battlefield of dead people
to have a battlefield of dead people is
not
not too
not too good.
not too good. Not
not too good. Not everybody
not too good. Not everybody gets
not too good. Not everybody gets that.
not too good. Not everybody gets that. I
think
think people
not too good. Not everybody gets that. I
think people think
think people think it's
not too good. Not everybody gets that. I
think people think it's wonderful,
victorious,
victorious, and
victorious, and we'll
victorious, and we'll go
victorious, and we'll go on
victorious, and we'll go on to
victorious, and we'll go on to the
victorious, and we'll go on to the next
battle.
But
But somewhere
But somewhere in
But somewhere in the
But somewhere in the human
But somewhere in the human psyche,
But somewhere in the human psyche, they
get
get that
But somewhere in the human psyche, they
get that this
get that this is
But somewhere in the human psyche, they
get that this is not
get that this is not good.
But somewhere in the human psyche, they
get that this is not good. So
get that this is not good. So the
evolution
evolution of
evolution of human
evolution of human consciousness
evolution of human consciousness then
evolution of human consciousness then is
built
built upon
evolution of human consciousness then is
built upon what
built upon what we
evolution of human consciousness then is
built upon what we would
built upon what we would now
evolution of human consciousness then is
built upon what we would now look
built upon what we would now look at
from
from a
from a calibrated
from a calibrated level
from a calibrated level of
from a calibrated level of 430
from a calibrated level of 430 as
disasters
disasters and
from a calibrated level of 430 as
disasters and failures.
But
But that's
But that's Monday
But that's Monday morning
quarterbacking.
quarterbacking. That's
But that's Monday morning
quarterbacking. That's Monday
quarterbacking. That's Monday morning
quarterbacking.
At
At the
quarterbacking.
At the time
At the time the
quarterbacking.
At the time the victory
seemed
seemed incredible
seemed incredible and
seemed incredible and wonderful.
We've
We've conquered
seemed incredible and wonderful.
We've conquered the
We've conquered the Gauls
seemed incredible and wonderful.
We've conquered the Gauls and
We've conquered the Gauls and converted
them
them to
them to Christianity
them to Christianity or
them to Christianity or whatever
them to Christianity or whatever the
hell
hell we
them to Christianity or whatever the
hell we did
is
is a
is a great
is a great victory.
is a great victory. A
is a great victory. A great
is a great victory. A great victory.
is a great victory. A great victory. We
calibrate
calibrate the
is a great victory. A great victory. We
calibrate the energy
calibrate the energy of
is a great victory. A great victory. We
calibrate the energy of that.
calibrate the energy of that. We're
is a great victory. A great victory. We
calibrate the energy of that. We're see
it's
it's probably
it's probably around
it's probably around 120
it's probably around 120 or
it's probably around 120 or something.
So
So we
it's probably around 120 or something.
So we can't
So we can't Monday
it's probably around 120 or something.
So we can't Monday morning
So we can't Monday morning quarterback
ourself
ourself as
ourself as a
ourself as a civilization
ourself as a civilization as
ourself as a civilization as humanity
ourself as a civilization as humanity by
looking
looking back
ourself as a civilization as humanity by
looking back at
looking back at the
ourself as a civilization as humanity by
looking back at the dreadful
looking back at the dreadful past.
unvarnished.
unvarnished. The
unvarnished. The past
unvarnished. The past is
unvarnished. The past is frankly
unvarnished. The past is frankly quite
dreadful
dreadful on
unvarnished. The past is frankly quite
dreadful on the
dreadful on the level
unvarnished. The past is frankly quite
dreadful on the level of
dreadful on the level of the
unvarnished. The past is frankly quite
dreadful on the level of the collective,
on
on the
on the level
on the level of
on the level of the
on the level of the individual,
on the level of the individual, not
necessarily.
necessarily. So
on the level of the individual, not
necessarily. So in
necessarily. So in the
on the level of the individual, not
necessarily. So in the home,
necessarily. So in the home, people
on the level of the individual, not
necessarily. So in the home, people can
be
be quite
be quite loving
be quite loving calibrated
be quite loving calibrated in
be quite loving calibrated in the
be quite loving calibrated in the 500s,
but
but society
be quite loving calibrated in the 500s,
but society as
but society as an
be quite loving calibrated in the 500s,
but society as an evolving
but society as an evolving collective,
as
as you
as you can
as you can see
as you can see right
as you can see right up
as you can see right up to
as you can see right up to present
as you can see right up to present day,
I
I was
as you can see right up to present day,
I was going
I was going to
as you can see right up to present day,
I was going to say
I was going to say September
as you can see right up to present day,
I was going to say September something
or
or other,
or other, but
or other, but it's
or other, but it's not
or other, but it's not really
or other, but it's not really September
something.
something. It's
or other, but it's not really September
something. It's probably
something. It's probably yesterday
or other, but it's not really September
something. It's probably yesterday that
the
the Middle
the Middle East
the Middle East shot
the Middle East shot each
the Middle East shot each other
the Middle East shot each other up
the Middle East shot each other up over
something.
something. I'm
the Middle East shot each other up over
something. I'm sure
something. I'm sure 18
the Middle East shot each other up over
something. I'm sure 18 people
something. I'm sure 18 people got
the Middle East shot each other up over
something. I'm sure 18 people got killed
yesterday
somewhere
somewhere over
yesterday
somewhere over some
somewhere over some political
positionality.
So
So the
positionality.
So the learning
So the learning curve
positionality.
So the learning curve then
So the learning curve then what
positionality.
So the learning curve then what we're
looking
looking back
looking back looking
looking back looking at
looking back looking at is
looking back looking at is the
looking back looking at is the learning
learning
learning curve.
looking back looking at is the learning
learning curve. So
learning curve. So when
looking back looking at is the learning
learning curve. So when you
learning curve. So when you put
looking back looking at is the learning
learning curve. So when you put yourself
down
down for
down for the
down for the past
down for the past something
down for the past something you
down for the past something you did
yesterday
yesterday or
down for the past something you did
yesterday or didn't
yesterday or didn't do
down for the past something you did
yesterday or didn't do yesterday,
whatever,
whatever, all
whatever, all you're
whatever, all you're looking
whatever, all you're looking at
whatever, all you're looking at is
whatever, all you're looking at is is
whatever, all you're looking at is is at
you're
you're looking
whatever, all you're looking at is is at
you're looking at
you're looking at a
whatever, all you're looking at is is at
you're looking at a learning
you're looking at a learning curve
whatever, all you're looking at is is at
you're looking at a learning curve of
where
where it
where it was
where it was then.
where it was then. That's
where it was then. That's where
where it was then. That's where the
learning
learning curve
where it was then. That's where the
learning curve was
learning curve was then.
where it was then. That's where the
learning curve was then. Where
learning curve was then. Where you
where it was then. That's where the
learning curve was then. Where you are
now
now is
now is not
now is not the
now is not the same
now is not the same place.
now is not the same place. So
now is not the same place. So guilt,
shame,
attacking
attacking yourself,
attacking yourself, regrets,
attacking yourself, regrets, all
attacking yourself, regrets, all this
kind
kind of
attacking yourself, regrets, all this
kind of thing
kind of thing have
attacking yourself, regrets, all this
kind of thing have no
kind of thing have no validity
attacking yourself, regrets, all this
kind of thing have no validity in
reality
reality because
reality because the
reality because the context
is
is what
reality because the context
is what gives
is what gives the
reality because the context
is what gives the reality
is what gives the reality its
reality because the context
is what gives the reality its reality.
Okay,
Okay, let's
Okay, let's just
Okay, let's just see.
Okay, let's just see. All right,
Okay, let's just see. All right, it's
context
context that
Okay, let's just see. All right, it's
context that gives
context that gives reality
Okay, let's just see. All right, it's
context that gives reality meaning
context that gives reality meaning it.
Okay.
So,
So, content
Okay.
So, content has
So, content has no
Okay.
So, content has no meaning
So, content has no meaning whatsoever.
What's
What's a
What's a dead
What's a dead body
What's a dead body mean?
What's a dead body mean? It
What's a dead body mean? It doesn't
What's a dead body mean? It doesn't mean
anything.
You
You live
You live long
You live long enough,
You live long enough, you've
You live long enough, you've walked
You live long enough, you've walked over
a
a lot
You live long enough, you've walked over
a lot of
a lot of dead
You live long enough, you've walked over
a lot of dead bodies.
All
All kinds
All kinds of
All kinds of sizes,
All kinds of sizes, shapes,
All kinds of sizes, shapes, ages,
dead
dead bodies
All kinds of sizes, shapes, ages,
dead bodies by
dead bodies by the
All kinds of sizes, shapes, ages,
dead bodies by the carload.
What
What does
What does it
What does it mean
What does it mean though?
What does it mean though? Oh,
what
what does
What does it mean though? Oh,
what does anything
what does anything mean?
It's
It's context
It's context then
It's context then that
It's context then that gives
It's context then that gives everything
meaning.
meaning. It's
It's context then that gives everything
meaning. It's the
meaning. It's the divinity
It's context then that gives everything
meaning. It's the divinity of
meaning. It's the divinity of the
It's context then that gives everything
meaning. It's the divinity of the self
that
that within
that within you,
that within you, the
that within you, the self
that within you, the self with
that within you, the self with a
that within you, the self with a capital
S
S shining
that within you, the self with a capital
S shining forth
S shining forth his
that within you, the self with a capital
S shining forth his consciousness,
the
the source
the source of
the source of your
the source of your own
the source of your own existence.
So
So that's
the source of your own existence.
So that's where
So that's where we
the source of your own existence.
So that's where we find
So that's where we find God.
the source of your own existence.
So that's where we find God. You
So that's where we find God. You look
into
into the
into the fact
into the fact that
into the fact that you
into the fact that you exist.
How
How did
into the fact that you exist.
How did it
How did it come
into the fact that you exist.
How did it come that
How did it come that I
into the fact that you exist.
How did it come that I exist?
Well,
Well, in
Well, in one
Well, in one of the
Well, in one of the first
Well, in one of the first lectures,
Well, in one of the first lectures, we
tried
tried to
Well, in one of the first lectures, we
tried to transcend
tried to transcend that
Well, in one of the first lectures, we
tried to transcend that ignorance
tried to transcend that ignorance called
causality
because
because the
causality
because the ego
because the ego would
causality
because the ego would say,
because the ego would say, "Well,
causality
because the ego would say, "Well, it
because the ego would say, "Well, it was
caused
caused by
caused by genes
caused by genes and
caused by genes and chromosomes
caused by genes and chromosomes and
sperms
sperms and
caused by genes and chromosomes and
sperms and eggs
sperms and eggs and
caused by genes and chromosomes and
sperms and eggs and all
sperms and eggs and all kinds
caused by genes and chromosomes and
sperms and eggs and all kinds of
biologic
biologic peculiarities."
There's
There's nothing
biologic peculiarities."
There's nothing more
There's nothing more peculiar
biologic peculiarities."
There's nothing more peculiar than
watching
watching this
watching this sperm
watching this sperm and
watching this sperm and this
watching this sperm and this egg
watching this sperm and this egg doing
their
their thing
watching this sperm and this egg doing
their thing on
their thing on TV.
watching this sperm and this egg doing
their thing on TV. I
their thing on TV. I mean,
watching this sperm and this egg doing
their thing on TV. I mean, it's
that's
that's where
that's where you
that's where you came
that's where you came from.
that's where you came from. Yep.
Louis
Louis the
that's where you came from. Yep.
Louis the 14th
Louis the 14th came
that's where you came from. Yep.
Louis the 14th came from
Louis the 14th came from that.
that's where you came from. Yep.
Louis the 14th came from that. Yeah.
Biologic
Biologic reductionism,
Biologic reductionism, you
Biologic reductionism, you know.
Biologic reductionism, you know. No,
that's
that's that
Biologic reductionism, you know. No,
that's that isn't
that's that isn't what
Biologic reductionism, you know. No,
that's that isn't what you
that's that isn't what you are
Biologic reductionism, you know. No,
that's that isn't what you are at
that's that isn't what you are at sperm
and
and egg
and egg really
and egg really aren't
and egg really aren't what
and egg really aren't what you
and egg really aren't what you are
and egg really aren't what you are at
all.
all. No.
And
And we
And we found
And we found out
And we found out research
And we found out research in
And we found out research in fact
And we found out research in fact the
spirit
spirit doesn't
And we found out research in fact the
spirit doesn't even
spirit doesn't even enter
And we found out research in fact the
spirit doesn't even enter the
spirit doesn't even enter the embryo
till
till the
till the third
till the third month.
till the third month. Let's
till the third month. Let's just
till the third month. Let's just verify
that
that again.
That
That is
That is a
That is a fact.
That is a fact. He
That is a fact. He said
That is a fact. He said okay.
That is a fact. He said okay. All right.
So
So for
That is a fact. He said okay. All right.
So for 3
So for 3 months
That is a fact. He said okay. All right.
So for 3 months it's
So for 3 months it's just
That is a fact. He said okay. All right.
So for 3 months it's just a
So for 3 months it's just a small
That is a fact. He said okay. All right.
So for 3 months it's just a small animal
potential
potential animal
potential animal embryo
potential animal embryo there.
The
The human
potential animal embryo there.
The human spirit
The human spirit doesn't
potential animal embryo there.
The human spirit doesn't decide
The human spirit doesn't decide that
this
this is
this is suitable
this is suitable for
this is suitable for a
this is suitable for a life
this is suitable for a life experience
until
until the
this is suitable for a life experience
until the third
until the third month.
this is suitable for a life experience
until the third month. Third
until the third month. Third month
this is suitable for a life experience
until the third month. Third month now
the
the embryo
the embryo is
the embryo is up
the embryo is up for
the embryo is up for options.
the embryo is up for options. I
the embryo is up for options. I never
asked
asked about
the embryo is up for options. I never
asked about what
asked about what they
the embryo is up for options. I never
asked about what they how
asked about what they how they
the embryo is up for options. I never
asked about what they how they how
asked about what they how they how they
figure
figure it
figure it out
figure it out on
figure it out on the
figure it out on the other
figure it out on the other side.
figure it out on the other side. Okay,
George,
George, it's
figure it out on the other side. Okay,
George, it's your
George, it's your turn.
Bong,
it's
it's a
Bong,
it's a George
it's a George now.