He
sorrow.
I wanted to cover
this thing. Seems loud.
The downside of the spiritual uh
trip
because that has not covered to my
satisfaction anywhere
the challenges that arise
the traps that uh lay there and wake
in the beginning which many of you have
already experienced there's a lot of
chaotic disturbance
You think that when you become a
spiritual aspirant, you're going to walk
around feeling holy and this
boom,
cataclysmic changes, major changes.
Walk out on whole situations and walk
away from a fortune of a corporation and
say goodbye.
What are you taking with you? Well, a
hammer and pair of screwdrivers and pair
of shorts.
God will take care of the rest. And God
does. And um as you're driving down your
truck and you say to your buddy, you
know what we need is a pair of pliers.
Just then you look over on the right and
there's a pair of pliers laying there.
Such things happen all the time.
So you don't need anything.
You can walk out with nothing.
Nothing at all.
and the universe provides all that you
need
over and over again.
All right. So that's devotional faith
which we'll get to later. I don't want
to get to that because I won't be able
to keep talking too well.
We call it devotional non-duality.
I emphasize the duality part first.
Leave the devotional part to later.
Very often that which is spiritually
non-intigous
quotes itself as very spiritual and
takes the form of a cult. We didn't talk
about cults.
We talked about when you got pretty
advanced
somehow you become the target of all
that it's non-integrous to pull you
down.
You need to be forewarned that such is
very likely to happen. In fact, it will
happen.
And if you get very very evolved,
the great forces of the universe
will gang up and then you need a very
advanced teacher. And the Buddha
remarked about it.
You get a seal from all sides by the
demons, you know.
In their most visible form though are
cults. And we should know what the
characteristic of a cult is
so that I can die peacefully that I've
told you
my last deathbed. I don't want to see
some people wandering off. So
the cult is led by a charismatic leader
who's controlling. They're always
controlling and they try to control
private lives, what you should do with
your money and your relationships and
your property.
And
uh
sex is allowed to the leader but not to
anybody else.
To avoid any responsibility, it's all
blamed on a entity on the other side.
master somebody or other that way you
can avoid all responsibility because
master so and so said that you should
leave your wife she's holding you back
etc.
So then there's titles, there's stratas,
there's a commitment,
and there's oaths and pledges. And
never take an oath. I don't care how
mighty and it sounds.
Oaths and contracts etc can come back at
a later lifetime and haunt haunt you and
you won't know where it came from.
The oath in the contract is usually this
um organization on the other side.
You don't know what's on the other side,
but they're waiting.
The cult
has an exclusiveness. We're exclusive.
They have a name and their own inner
language. And you're either one of them
or not.
If you're not one of them, you're
nobody. So they proilitize very
intensely, very intense proilitizing.
They become overzealous.
They want to sign you up
for a course. Of course, the courses
escalate over time. But anyway,
and then if you want to leave the cult,
there's repercussions
sometimes quite severe, even to the
point of death.
you become anathema to the group.
So there's an us versus them. So whole
the whole structure is dualistic
and there's great oo and a's about the
leader.
What is to be respected is the truth not
the leader.
Those who want
to make something out of the personality
of the leader,
there is no personality.
The personality, the persona is just a
residual of what was and you reactivate
it in order to speak to groups. Now it
has no reality. There is no person there
to oo and a over.
What one is devoted to is truth.
Not the avenue of truth.
One is devoted to truth itself.
The speaker of truth may just is just a
convenience.
So all this agilation
of some spiritual teacher is all the
glamorization.
Be aware of it.
Greet someone some somebody or other
and everybody gif flex forget it.
The truth is the same. The self within
you is the same as the self within the
teacher. No, it's not too different.
It's not yourself and their self and
their self is better than yourself.
It's the same self.
So you worship the truth and not the
personality
in whom it may through whom it may be
spoken of. The personality is just a
tool.
It's a nothing at all
and it's eancent.
It croakkes, dies, withers away.
universe gets rid of it. It's
extraneous.
The dedication, the reverence is for
the truth itself.
If you have to sign up and become a
member
and learn the language
and follow
the cult leader.
That is not the way to truth.
In spiritual naive, we think anything
labeled spiritual is spiritual.
And we think that the spiritual and the
astral are one and the same. They are
not.
So the other discernment is between that
which is astral and that which is
personal.
Especially
newagers get trapped by the by the
astral realms
and channeling entities from the other
side etc.
All spiritual truth is spoken by people
in bodies.
If you can't see them, forget it.
All right. We said that we can stratify
which is an artificial point of
observation to stratify the level of the
consciousness. We do that for
descriptive purposes like we do
atmosphere
or depth below the sea.
It's just a convenience of description.
So
we could say these are levels of
Well, this is a a new one that Lou
Fornier did
uh in which we put the two together.
This is the population distribution of
these levels of consciousness.
This is the level of integrity
and these are the levels of power.
We should have an inverse one. These are
the levels of force.
So the levels of force
and the levels of power have an inverse
relationship with each other. All right?
So we don't want to get involved in
cults, distractions,
those are entertainments.
The levels of consciousness on
that we represent here in this domain
have their equivalent in non-physical
domains.
Yeah, there we are.
I've been following your chart and the
more I study it, the worse I get.
Doctor, what are you?
Oh,
topsy turvy. Oh. Oh my god. Look at the
wiggliness there.
That which you see that level of
consciousness within a body. That level
of consciousness exists also in the
astral realms without a physicality
because there's an infinite number of
realms.
Um
the motivations
of people as they go out of body are
going to be aligned with their level of
consciousness.
Consequently, people who are controlling
and seek power and desire to control
others when they go out of physicality
are going to stay the same.
So many of the entities on the other
side are merely control freaks.
Maybe your wife, wife of your children,
buy horses, invest in this thought, sell
your property, donate it to the group,
meaning him.
Now, you want to avoid all that.
And this is a pretty sophisticated group
and most of you have avoided it.
And one reason is because you got hooked
on it.
You're still paying off
the investments that Baba so and so told
you to make from the other side.
He doesn't have to live in this world.
So it's okay for him to say that.
All right. So, I want to just make sure
we're aware what the traps are.
I will tell you they're all fascinating.
They're fascinating. They're very
interesting.
And each one is representing a certain
h
perceptual reality as they are
experiencing it. And some of them
probably legitimately believe that they
are representing some kind of truth to
these unfortunate mortals.
So there are higher celestial realms.
There's the lower astral. So there's a
various cate categorizations of the
astral realms which correlate with the
levels of consciousness.
And as you get over 200, there are
realms of course that represent that as
well. And you get into the
eventually the celestial realms.
And some teachers coming from the
celestial realms
are bonafideed
and useless.
You're not going to say anything that's
not available here.
And the difficulty with following it
even if it's good advice is it's coming
from elsewhere.
That reliance on my teacher on the other
side. The teacher is within you.
Nonuality means there's no this getting
it from a that.
The knowingness comes from within.
As you transcend the mind, as you
dismantle the mind by removing its
positionalities upon which it thrives
and survives, when you get over being
enamored of the mind,
you begin to see it stupid.
Humility. With humility, you realize
that the mind doesn't know anything.
And the reason the mind doesn't know
anything is it is not capable of
knowing.
The mind is not capable
of knowing
any more than a ruler can tell you what
the temperature is outside.
It's not.
It's suitable only for dealing in the
perceptual world of form.
Where is our secret thing here? Here.
We keep this secret hidden from the
world.
However, for a small contribution,
we will move you up to a second level of
depth
and explain to you what it means.
So, you see the secrets
is the other sign.
Truth has no secrets. That which claims
a secret avoid.
God has no secrets. The sky has no
secrets.
The sun shines with no secrets.
All is revealed.
The only reason for a secret is to have
control over you so that I will get
something out of you in return for this
secret which makes you special.
So the attraction is one of specialness.
There are no secrets.
There are no secrets to be known.
All truth stands revealed.
It shines forth of its own.
So that which sells secrets, has secret
symbols and secret mantras and secret
sayings and secret handshakes, secret
mystical words and crap.
That's all facious.
All these things are okay on the on the
way on the way.
The only trouble is the power of
seduction is quite intense. Many of
these entities have been at it for
millennia.
Millennia
expertise. It senses from another
dimension exactly where you're
vulnerable and heads right for it.
That's why they're expert. They're
expert. They're at it.
Anybody becomes an expert at what they
do. So don't underrate the expertise of
that which would mislead you because it
is very expert.
One thing it's expert at is sounding
like the real.
That's where its real danger lies.
It sounds like the convincingly real.
Until the third eye opens in the Buddha
body, there's no way the average human
can discern it.
That's where a teacher comes in handy.
who can because it's it's obvious to the
teacher but not obvious to you. The
teacher can point out what you can't see
yet. So you take his word for it until
you see it yourself.
happily. That's why I'm so pleased with
theologic test because
all of us, myself included,
were vulnerable to spiritual seduction
and being misled
by extreme cleverness.
All right?
People become very expert at what they
do.
If people knew how expert a psychiatrist
is after 50 years of listening to to
them, they they'd shake their bones. By
the time they make the appointment, I
already know the diagnosis. I know
what's wrong with them. I can tell you
what the whole story is. I was here.
In fact, I can tell them what to do to
cure it and save the trip.
I used to do it all the time on a huge
practice, you know, the biggest in the
United States. I listen to the story. I
said, "Look, quit eating sugar and
sweets. take about three grams a day of
vitamin C and 50 milligrams a day of B6.
If you don't feel better in a month,
call me.
You know, functional hypoglycemia is so
obvious. You know, I get the shakes and
I'm getting the rages and
functional glycemia. I mean, it's just
so you just know it from the tone of
voice. Okay.
All right. Those who are out for
spiritual seduction are equally clever
at the lower levels. But once you get
much higher, the seduction becomes more
subtle.
I've written about it in the book. I
the seduction is of the satanic and the
seduction is of the luciferic and I've
told you about the seduction of
uh the luciferic in the form of power.
Then there is that which distorts truth
and this is the hardest for the the real
spiritual student committed spiritual
student where the teacher has a grain of
truth in it and because of the grain of
truth you foil for it but what you get
don't get is that the context is out.
It's literally
plausible
but the context is out.
So other than fame, money and all the
rest that
seduce gurus and spiritually evolved
people, sexuality is another seduction.
The satanic takes the form of also
sexual seduction. And of course there's
quite a bit about that in the internet
right now. And
the way the seduction comes about is all
is holy, sex is holy, sex is holy. So
let's have holy sex around the clock.
You and I,
the leader will tell you that
for the good of your soul, the evolution
of your spirit.
So sexual seduction then falls into the
realm
There is a grain of truth. All is holy.
Yes, sexuality is holy. Of course, it
is.
There is the fallacy of
the spiritual and the
secular are one and the same.
I've had all these presented to me. So I
can tell you
the spiritual and the secular are one
and the same. From a certain degree of
abstraction that is so. But the intent
was
to okay
going after people for their money,
let's say, and signing them up for
courses and all. And I said, "But these
are not aligned with God. They're not
aligned with spiritual evolution.
They're just frankly these courses were
to make money. In fact, the course was
how to make money and they made money by
telling teaching you a course on how to
make money. So it was funny. I said, but
that's not spiritual. So the retort to
justify the materialism here was
the secular and the spiritual are one
and the same
which from a very abstract view from
that position is correct but not from
this position. So the error was one of
context.
The intention was how to get people's
money frankly and sign them up.
Therefore,
the kinesiologic test is a way we have
of affirming what we may suspect.
And I'll tell you, gentlemen, very often
the wife gets it before you do.
I think guru so and so is working you
for your money, honey. Oh, honey, how
can you think that? He's pure and holy.
I don't know. Just something in me just
tells me that.
Something in me just tells me that.
Let's see.
All right. I wanted to cover that.
All right. So, we covered it.
We were talking about the limitation of
the mind.
As spiritual work um progresses,
one is
interested in the quality, the
limitations, the structure of the ego in
in its form is mind.
Mind becomes
somebody's blocking our light here.
Here we go with the truth again.
All right.
As we get up here, see this is the level
in which democracy makes sense. You see,
I say it makes sense up here. A
civilization that's in the 400s,
educated, sophisticated, modern,
advanced society. It makes sense.
Doesn't make sense to these people down
here. And there's no point to kill them
to try and to get what you can only get
when you're in the 400s. You know what
I'm saying? But so reason becomes the
great
the great goal. Then reason itself
becomes the limitation. And we said how
the great geniuses of history
um characteristically car calibrate
around 499.
It's as though mind takes you as far as
it can go and now it has to move to a
different paradigm and it doesn't how to
move to a different paradigm of reality.
So the intellect, reason, logic, mind
which is really and science which are
the are what modern society worships.
Modern society wor does not worship God.
It worships
science, logic and reason.
I mean you try going like this in a
grocery store and see what happens to
you.
This is not a spiritual society.
$4.99 is a great block. All right. It's
because the person reaches the limits of
content and they try to stretch it as
far as they can. And if you look at
these conferences on science and
consciousness, you'll see they all
calibrate around 460 470 like that. The
most advanced one in the group will get
up to about 490 492 or something. And
it's you can just tell they're pushing
their mind to to cross that threshold.
And they figure the harder you push the
mind.
But you can't do it by pushing mind
because mind is only capable of knowing
about. It cannot know. The mind cannot
know. It does not have the capacity. It
is not an instrument of knowing.
The mind is capable of knowing about.
To know is one thing. To know about is
another.
The limitation of the intellect then is
it knows about something
that is still being extraneous to the
essence of that which you're trying to
describe.
The only way to know a thing is to be
it.
Only a bird knows
birdness.
You can know about birdness.
I got a straight A in ornithology.
So I know about birds
but I don't really know birdness.
So when you realize that then you you're
capable of humility
not as a spiritual pose.
Most most spiritual humility is a
spiritual pose
but it's the you know all humility comes
out of understanding the real.
When you really understand the
limitation of the intellect then you're
humble for that limitation. So the
really great scientists
of all time even though they hit 499 all
believed in God. Oh, Sir Isaac Newton,
all the great the great great scientific
geniuses of time all believed in God. So
when you realize so the mature intellect
realizes its own limitations. The
difficulty with science is it becomes
very arrogant. doesn't realize its own
limitations. It doesn't realize it's
really stupid intrinsically
which is hard to swallow for a scientist
that it's limited.
It can only know about but it cannot
take you across the threshold to 500.
How do you get how do you cross that
barrier? So the intellect attracts us to
spirituality. If as we become more
sophisticated and educated, we start
getting curious. So the reason reason
then is the curiosity factor and we
begin to read about spiritual things and
all and then the frustration sets in
because that which got us through
college and got us straight A's in
school
now is not helping.
I read this book and that book and you
know you've all got spiritual friends
and you yourself have got stacks of
books at home. You've read them all.
So therefore the true spiritual teacher
knows only by
identity with that which is spoken.
There is no external source. There is no
knowing about anything.
One knows
what birdness is because one is a bird.
So as the presence within
takes dominion takes dominion
then the knowingness begins to reveal
itself.
Knowingness is selfrevealing.
You remove the blocks. You remove the
barricades. You remove the impediments.
And then by devotion to the truth,
the way is opened and the truth reveals
itself.
Eventually then spiritual work goes
beyond knowing about.
Everybody here knows enough about to get
enlightened 100 million times.
Everybody's got enough info to go route.
No doubt.
What is the next step then? Because
further studying is not going to do it.
Although I will say spiritual
information which calibrates at a very
high level, the information itself is
liberating. Just to hear it
takes away a big chunk of the ego's
resistance.
Eventually knowing about the truth no
longer suffices.
At first it's exciting
to read all those books
to go all workshops etc.
But eventually it becomes its own
frustration
and that frustration then becomes the
driving force that drives you beyond the
400s.
It's that disillusionment and
dissatisfaction,
the frustration that the intellect won't
get you there. Jeez,
unfair.
I remember raging about it.
The harder I studied, the more elusive
it was. I realized that the the mind,
which is the only instrument I knew at
that time,
wouldn't get me there. Oh,
wow. What a frustration. What a sense of
loss.
No, now something else comes up. So, we
follow content as far as we can go. You
see the ego wants you to think that you
survived because of ego says
to yourself unc unconsciously
that
your survival is due to the fact that
I'm up and running and without me
disaster awaits.
So you owe your allegiance to the ego.
You become enamored of the mind and we
give it great importance.
Well, your reverence is the mind.
The unenlightened person thinks the mind
is the way to survival and salvation.
Then comes the great disillusionment.
No, the mind doesn't have the power. The
mind only calibrates in the 400. It's
not going to take you over 600 at all.
It only goes It only goes so far.
That street car only goes this far and
then you got to transfer to a bus. Oh,
all right. So, it's bus time. So,
the street car it will take you so far.
It's terrific. I'm not putting down
street cars. I love them.
Uh but the rest of the trip has to be by
bus. Okay. So
what are the tools?
IQ, intellect
won't help you anymore.
I have at home the
the great books of the western world
put out by the University of Chicago in
the 30s. Every great thinker that ever
lived, you know,
Aristotle and Plato and Uripides and
goes all the way down to Freud, stops at
Freud. So the work stops around 1900 or
so, but it calibrates at 475.
The greatest thinkers of all of history
calibrated at 475
with the exception of Aristotle
who was over 500.
So the intellect will only take you so
far for one reason. If you want to
follow the intellect of God, then study
epistemology.
Probably the nearest thing in philosophy
to spiritual reality
is epistemology. Because epistemology
takes you right to the door of how do
you know
the whole subject of epistemology
then takes the intellect as far as it
can get to spiritual truth and then a
jump has to be made. Mhm.
The techniques that we then follow are
not studying the written word
but taking what we got from the written
word and making it operative within
ourselves.
So we then come to
devotion,
respect,
the reverence for truth, the reverence
for the truth. It's not the teacher that
one reveres, but the truth.
One reverses the truth.
A reverence for the truth and a devotion
then carries you through the work that
it takes to go through the pathway of
non-duality.
The three great yogas, selfless service,
heart and mind are combined into one.
Huh.
Throughout the day, we look for no gain
from our work. We do it out of reverence
for life, out of reverence for our
existence.
the pathway of non-duality
which becomes very demanding as it
proceeds and we'll get into that this
afternoon
then requires devotion
the capacity
the devotion to the truth.
So one becomes devoted not to the
teacher but to the truth.
The teacher is only like a lighthouse.
The value of the lighthouse is not the
lighthouse. The value of the lighthouse
is the light going out to see. Not the
we don't worship the lighthouse. You
know what I'm saying?
Isn't the lighthouse is going to save
you? No. It's being able to see where
the light is to guide yourself back to
shore.
One becomes increasingly motivated
um to and desiring of the truth until
finally it almost becomes an obsession.
At first it's something you do now and
then.
Then you have runs of it. You do a
weekend
retreat etc.
Then you do another weekend retreat.
Meanwhile you read all the books, you go
to all the workshops
and gradually a sort of a momentum
builds within yourself
and then finally desire to reach the
truth becomes overwhelming. It becomes
the drivenness
and you will stop at nothing.
That's the time to tell your family
that your life is about to change
and they may think you've gone mad.
That's routine.
And people will walk out on everything.
It then becomes like an obsession,
a drivenness, a dedication.
There was an old movie
Lost Horizon.
>> Yeah. Who was it that plays in that with
me?
>> Land.
>> Huh?
>> Rival.
>> No.
>> Coleman. Yes.
Well, you remember I think I mentioned
it in five words this horse even
>> but having once experienced that high
energy I think we calibrated Shangerla
it I forget what it was it was quite
high but anyway once having experienced
it he tried going back into the world
and tried to function he was supposed to
have some job with the British
government or something
tried to be satisfied with that which is
less than what what he had experienced.
But he got caught by the spiritual
energy and now
through all obstacles
at the risk of death, physical death
itself
was driven to return to that state of
consciousness.
There's a number of people here in the
room who've had that same inner
experience.
They've had a sometimes after a
catastrophe in life, sometimes without
it, sometimes near-death experience,
whatever it is. There's a number of
people in the room and some I've seen
personally and they experience that
incredible state. And now, oh Lord, how
could you have deserted me? It is gone.
And I want to be back in that state
forever.
That's the beginning opening of the door
may open
and in the beginning it often closes
again.
Rarely does it stay a permanency.
Most usually it reveals itself. One
experiences the self in its full
one experiences the oneness with
divinity that that which you are
infinitely love infinite power beyond
all time
is not different than that which you are
exquisite unmistakable
always the same in everyone that it
happens to
no teacher has an exclus exclusive on
the truth. Anybody who's ever
experienced the self in its full
radiation has had exactly the same
experience throughout all of time in all
cultures.
Anything that varies from that is not
the truth.
The experience of the presence of God
has always been identical in all
cultures throughout thousands of years.
Not statistically frequent
but unmistakably identical.
There can be no other.
There is only the one and there can be
no other than the one.
Any description that varies from that
cannot be the truth because the truth is
always the same.
Once in a while it's comical somebody
will
I get such funny letters
you know infer that you are what
plagiarizing somebody because a sentence
sounds like something they read
somewhere else.
It better sound like something you read
somewhere else
because the experience of the truth is
always the same whether
the mood of Huda said that 600 BC or
what you know whether it's in the Vidas
or Christianity or Buddhism or whatever
that's all the cultural
trappings that go with
So that which is the absolute truth has
no cultural trappings.
I say what is your spiritual lineage?
Meaning I should trace teachers and
teachers back to the year something or
other walking around usually in the
Middle East in some place or India or
some strange foreign place.
Now the spirit of truth is the presence
of God within in this instant. It has
nothing to do with whatever happened in
history.
Whatever happened in history is totally
boring.
A curiosity perhaps when you first start
studying
whether anything or anyone ever
experienced before is totally
irrelevant.
It's the reality of no
be like asking a bird where did you hear
that you were a bird?
I just am a bird for God's sake. Anybody
can see that. So
all doubt is removed by
the experience of self as this infinite
presence.
Anything that is doubtful is coming from
the ego that is resisting its own
disillusion,
its own dissolution and is hoping it can
find a conundrum that will puzzle you so
it can go on. Gotcha there, duck.
All right.
There is nothing to argue about with the
truth because it is not arguable. The
reason is it takes no form. To argue
with something, it has to have form.
You see, context has no form. All form.
What's arguable about religion is when
it is expressed in dogma,
enthusiastic doctrine, then it can be
argued with.
But if you don't do that, you can't
argue with it.
You can only express a limitation
but that limitation that that religion
expresses is a limitation of its own
innate truth and power.
All right? So that which is truly
spiritual then
grants perfect freedom.
There is no dogma to be followed.
No excommunication is possible.
There is no membership that can be
revoked.
No titles that can be withdrawn, no
possessions that can be you know see
spirits of truth then is open and free.
There's nothing to join. There's no dues
to pay. There are no language to learn.
There's no reverence do anybody.
There is however a common devotion to
the truth. What holds a true spiritual
group group together
is all of us are profoundly devoted and
worship the truth.
The presence of God within
which expresses itself.
Oh thee I adore. Oh Lord,
a profound devotion
to
the radical truth.
So this is the pathway of radical
devotional
non-duality.
Actually
that's the pathway to mystic isn't it?
That is the pathway to mystic.
The truth is found within when all
barriers to it are removed.
The commonality in this group is
devotion to the innate truth of God
within
and
the recognition
and awareness that that reality can be
subjectively verified
if all the barriers to it are removed.
The purpose of the lectures then is how
to remove the barriers
so that that which is within shines
forth of its own.
The sun shines forth when the clouds are
removed from the sky.
You have reductions to truth.
So truth is not something one acquires
or gets. You don't get enlightened or
anything like that.
When all barriers are removed, the sun
shines forth
equally on all.
The energy of that truth is
what the teacher transmits
not to one's mental bodies
but to one's higher spiritual bodies.
It's the vibration of the higher
spiritual bodies that go get activated
by the frequency of that vibration which
comes of the certainty of the
absoluteness of the presence
for which I give thanks oh lord. Amen.
So
what unites a true spiritual group is
the absolute commitment to the pursuit
of truth
and we
support each other in that endeavor.
Sometimes it takes the strength and
conviction of others who have done it
and say yes that is the way to go.
This becomes very true
as I say the spiritual work eventually
takes you to a point where the spiritual
the power the spiritual inspiration now
forces you. You see it isn't that you're
choosing
it isn't your desiringness of a higher
state.
It begins to pull you up. You see,
it's like the
the density of the ocean becomes so
intense that you like a quirk are forced
up in it. You would like to congratulate
yourself that you've chosen to become
spiritual.
Fact is the other way around. It's
chosen you, brother.
I want you. And it begins to pull you.
And the closer you get to the magnet,
the more powerful
the iron filing is attracted until
finally it's undeniable.
If you remove enough barriers, you are
pulled to it whether you like it or not.
And
by transcending identification with the
mind, what you do
as each thing arises, one lets it go
until finally the mind is silent.
You notice that at all times you think
your mind is busy and you can't conquer
it and all this. Don't try and conquer
the mind. Just don't identify with it.
So where do you look? You look to that
which is just a priority to mind
at all times. The majority, the biggest
part of your mind is silent. Did you
ever know that
your mind is silent all the time?
A little bitty part of your mind is busy
thinking about this and that, but the
major portion of it is still in silent,
not saying anything.
You're only paying attention to the
noisy part here. At all times, your mind
is silent.
One way to notice how your mind is
silent is that although your intellect
is listening to what's being said, there
is within you the awareness of the
totality of this room and where we are
in Sedona and Arizona.
There's a silent part of you that just
accepts that the sky is here without
thinking sky.
Space is here. Silence is here.
But the ego wants you to focus on it so
it can survive. As you withdraw your
energy back from the in being entranced
and enamored of the mind and its going
on,
you become there is at all times the
majority of your mind is silent.
Even the thinkingness which is going on
here
does not interfere with the silence
because you cannot interfere with the
silence.
If you're out in the woods, the woods
are silent.
A bird makes a song.
Did the bird destroy the silence? No.
The silence is still there.
The bird sound is superimposed against
the background of the silence or else
you couldn't hear the bird.
But it is the silence which is so the
silence is
immune to interruption
just as the silent area of your mind is
always silent.
What is your mind doing when it's not
thinking? It's being silent.
People panic. Jesus, my mother suddenly
went dead. I didn't think of anything.
Doctor, do you think I'm well? Am I
getting Alzheimer's?
No, the silence is the presence within
on the level of consciousness.
And out of your consciousness comes the
awareness which is witnessing and
registering the thinkingness. But it's
all coming out of a silence.
This silence prevails right before the
thought arises.
You see the the mind thinks in linear
terms. So it thinks in the sentence the
cat is the dog is chasing the cat up the
tree that this is a linear sequence of
thoughts. The cat no the dog is chasing
the cat up the tree.
He sees a causal sequence.
Actually, if you study your mind through
introspective meditation,
you will see that the thoughts arise
this this way. The out of nothingness,
the dog is chasing the cat up the tree.
Every single thought arises from
nothingness.
Every single thought is an original
creation.
Superimposed upon that is a
contextualization
that we call reason or logic.
The Buddha said the space in which the
void by that he meant the infinite
presence of the self can be recognized
is between thoughts.
No, it's right prior to thoughts.
We've just discussed it endlessly,
Buddha and I.
I said he agreed. He said, "It's not
between thoughts. It's just prior
thoughts." No, it's the translation from
various languages and all. Besides, you
went there to hear the Buddha lecture.
Besides, he was that what he's trying to
convey is there's only one truth to
convey two truths. You see it isn't that
the space is between the thoughts or
between prior to the thoughts but in
both of course conditions.
So if you watch as your mind just starts
to think you'll see that just before the
instant that thought started there was
nothing there.
Every thought comes out of nothing.
You discover that you're close to being
home.
You begin to identify with the so silent
nothingness out of which each thought
arises.
That which is closest to your reality is
the silent field out of which the song
of the bird arises.
The silent mind is present within you at
all times. It's present right this
instant.
You're only listening with a little
bitty part of your mind. The majority of
your mind is silent.
Isn't that amazing?
>> Yeah.
>> One identifies progressively then with
with with the field
the context
that which you are is the context.
At a more advanced level, you see that
the context all include context includes
content as well. But at this point,
forget about content.
You're the context out of which
it all arises,
out of the energy of life.
So you become devoted to
M
the discernment of this quality of
silence within
by the letting go of everything that
stands in its way.
The mind becomes progressively silent
and then there comes a moment where the
only thing left
is you.
The only thing left to be surrendered
is the sense of self which you've always
identified as self
and you realize that you have to
surrender that also.
At the final doorway to enlightenment
then stands death.
Death as you understand it. Death as you
have experienced it.
Death as it is believed in. Because if
that which you think you are is
life itself,
to surrender that to God
means to die.
And at that point, the training you had
as a warrior and many a lifetime.
The willingness to die for a greater
cause now comes forth.
to have been able to commit Harry Kerry,
the willingness to die for one's belief.
And then comes the great terror of death
because all the times you've died in
previous lifetimes with a joke.
Whaml, you're out of body and life is
better than it was before. I'll tell
you.
So you've never experienced death.
Nobody has experienced that.
This is the one and only time you can
actually die.
There's the knowingness that what you
are facing is absolute death.
And then arises the terror of
nothingness.
If that which I believe and am committed
to as myself, if I surrender that, I
will become nothing.
There is the fear of death and the fear
of the void.
At that point, at that point, those who
have been through there, the energy of
those who have been through that point
will come to you
and you will remember,
walk straight ahead. No matter what, no
matter how severe the fear,
the greatest fear of all, walk through
it.
And so the terror lasts for an ungodly
minute
and one has made it through. So the
great beings that have walked through
there and when you're there, you'll see
who was there. You know who was there
and who turned back. The majority turned
back. 85% turned back.
Therefore, I want to make the
instruction clear.
In thy name, oh Lord,
at the moment of death,
die for God
and walk through the fear.
And then stands the glory unfolding,
a radiance so magnificent, so beyond all
comprehension,
beyond that which is humanly knowable
because at that point you stop being
human. You walk beyond humanness itself
in the presence of divinity.
There is one basic saying in Zen that
one can rely on completely
and that is to walk through all fear no
matter what.
Walk through all fear committed to
spiritual truth no matter what.
First of all make sure that's spiritual
truth.
Secondly, make sure
that you know this from the knowingness
of that which has accomplished it.
It better be a teacher who has been
there.
Know it with a concrete faith that that
within you which is dedicated to
reaching God is what's brought you to
the point of death.
And at that time then
one says
for thee oh Lord God do I lay down my
life.
So those words will be with you. Amen.
Thank you.
And um
therefore I have fulfilled my
role as a teacher.
I've told you the whole story.
Thank you. We'll break for lunch. We'll
be back in an hour.
Okay, we wanted all the staff, volunteer
office staff, uh we wanted all the
volunteer staff
and office staff
and those who have been of great
assistance to us, contribute
and Karen,
>> they shall remain anonymous.
And what would you like to do, my dear?
>> Um, the hungry.
>> Oh my goodness. Somebody could help you
do that. In fact,
>> yeah,
>> somebody could volunteer to help you.
Somebody could volunteer to help you.
Where's a volunteer? Take one out. Help
yourself, sweetheart.
>> That's what you can do. Just say help
yourself. Oh,
>> help yourself. That's the way you
volunteer
>> now. Don't you wish you'd volunteered?
>> Okay. Actually, so many people have
wanted to help and we are overwhelmed
with gratitude and some sit in the
audience who have made great
contributions and you should come up
ahead.
Yep. And you get one too.
Now we could take turns. We could all go
out in the audience and the whole
audience could come up here
because without you, who would we be?
Nobody, you know.
Oh, yes.
>> And what do we got there? Oh my
goodness. Don't we have to take these
things off?
24 hours a day, 7 days a week, 365 days
a year.
>> Thank you so much, my sweetheart.
>> Everyone's applause.
>> All right, you sit down. I'm going to
put him in here.
>> So, we want to thank you all from the
bottom of our heart.
You've all been of such wonderment to us
and we love you all and adore you.
So, I just wanted to acknowledge them
and
acknowledge all of you for being here
and making your contribution to us by
being here. Thank you.
Okay. So, we're resume. Thank you so
much.
Thanks to Sedona Creative Life Center
for, you know, supplying such a
beautiful place
and allowing us to meet here.
In the contract, it says we won't spray
perfume or drop flower petals around.
We did not mean to do that.
They did it of their own.