So
So to
So to some
So to some degree
So to some degree we
So to some degree we walk
So to some degree we walk near
So to some degree we walk near the
So to some degree we walk near the edge.
You
You push
So to some degree we walk near the edge.
You push your
You push your spiritual
So to some degree we walk near the edge.
You push your spiritual commitment
You push your spiritual commitment to
the
the edge.
And
And if
the edge.
And if you
And if you go
the edge.
And if you go over
And if you go over the
the edge.
And if you go over the edge,
And if you go over the edge, so
the edge.
And if you go over the edge, so you
And if you go over the edge, so you go
over
over the
over the edge.
So
So what?
So the
So the commitment
So the commitment is
So the commitment is a
So the commitment is a complete
So the commitment is a complete and
total
total commitment.
When
When I
When I say
When I say if
When I say if you
When I say if you can
When I say if you can find
When I say if you can find God
When I say if you can find God through
that
that music,
When I say if you can find God through
that music, that
that music, that ecstatic
When I say if you can find God through
that music, that ecstatic state,
don't
don't stop
don't stop playing
don't stop playing it.
round
round the
don't stop playing it.
round the clock
round the clock all
don't stop playing it.
round the clock all day,
round the clock all day, every
don't stop playing it.
round the clock all day, every day,
now
now and
now and forever.
And
And when
now and forever.
And when you've
And when you've transcended
now and forever.
And when you've transcended that
And when you've transcended that music,
you
you can
you can let
you can let it
you can let it go.
So
So there
you can let it go.
So there comes
So there comes that
you can let it go.
So there comes that time
So there comes that time when
you can let it go.
So there comes that time when you
So there comes that time when you make
you can let it go.
So there comes that time when you make a
run
run for
run for God.
There
There comes
run for God.
There comes the
There comes the time
run for God.
There comes the time when
There comes the time when your
run for God.
There comes the time when your spiritual
commitment,
commitment, you
commitment, you know
commitment, you know that
commitment, you know that this
commitment, you know that this is
commitment, you know that this is it,
that
that you're
commitment, you know that this is it,
that you're not
that you're not coming
commitment, you know that this is it,
that you're not coming back
that you're not coming back until
commitment, you know that this is it,
that you're not coming back until you
get
get there.
And
And then
get there.
And then you
And then you make
get there.
And then you make the
And then you make the final
get there.
And then you make the final run.
And then you make the final run. We'll
make
make the
make the we'll
make the we'll talk
make the we'll talk about
make the we'll talk about the
make the we'll talk about the final
make the we'll talk about the final run
the
the last
make the we'll talk about the final run
the last lecture
the last lecture otherwise
make the we'll talk about the final run
the last lecture otherwise nobody
the last lecture otherwise nobody will
be
be here
be here next
be here next next
be here next next time
loitating
loitating not
be here next next time
loitating not eating
loitating not eating and
be here next next time
loitating not eating and listening
loitating not eating and listening to
music
and
and their
music
and their families
and their families will
music
and their families will be
and their families will be calling
music
and their families will be calling the
police.
police. So
the
the doctor
police. So
the doctor made
the doctor made me
police. So
the doctor made me do
the doctor made me do it.
police. So
the doctor made me do it. I
the doctor made me do it. I went
police. So
the doctor made me do it. I went to
the doctor made me do it. I went to his
lecture
lecture and
along
along the
lecture and
along the way
along the way may
lecture and
along the way may one
along the way may one may
lecture and
along the way may one may also
along the way may one may also get
lecture and
along the way may one may also get a
along the way may one may also get a a
great
great number
great number of
great number of physical
great number of physical calamities
and
and aches
great number of physical calamities
and aches and
and aches and pains.
If
If you
If you look
If you look up
If you look up the
If you look up the mystic
If you look up the mystic in
encyclopedia,
we'll
we'll give
we'll give you
we'll give you quotes
we'll give you quotes going
we'll give you quotes going back
we'll give you quotes going back to
we'll give you quotes going back to the
12th,
12th, 13th,
we'll give you quotes going back to the
12th, 13th, 14th,
12th, 13th, 14th, 15th
we'll give you quotes going back to the
12th, 13th, 14th, 15th century
12th, 13th, 14th, 15th century of
various
various mystics
and
and their
various mystics
and their description
and their description of
various mystics
and their description of what
and their description of what they
various mystics
and their description of what they went
through.
One
One said,
through.
One said, "You'll
One said, "You'll spend
through.
One said, "You'll spend more
One said, "You'll spend more time
through.
One said, "You'll spend more time in
your
your sick
your sick bed
your sick bed than
your sick bed than you
your sick bed than you will
your sick bed than you will on
your sick bed than you will on your
knees."
that
that bringing
that bringing up
that bringing up negative
that bringing up negative energies
that bringing up negative energies and
what's
what's associated
that bringing up negative energies and
what's associated with
what's associated with them
that bringing up negative energies and
what's associated with them and
what's associated with them and the
karma
karma that's
karma that's associated
karma that's associated with
karma that's associated with them
karma that's associated with them may
put
put you
karma that's associated with them may
put you through
put you through all
karma that's associated with them may
put you through all kinds
put you through all kinds of
karma that's associated with them may
put you through all kinds of strange
wrecks
wrecks and
experiences
experiences that
wrecks and
experiences that really
experiences that really you
wrecks and
experiences that really you need
experiences that really you need um
people
people spiritually
people spiritually advanced
people spiritually advanced who've
people spiritually advanced who've been
through
through them
people spiritually advanced who've been
through them to
through them to reassure
people spiritually advanced who've been
through them to reassure you
through them to reassure you as
people spiritually advanced who've been
through them to reassure you as to
through them to reassure you as to what
they
they are
and
if
if they
if they seem
if they seem like
if they seem like a
if they seem like a calamity
if they seem like a calamity so
if they seem like a calamity so so
if they seem like a calamity so so it's
a
a calamity
I
I don't
I don't know
I don't know what
I don't know what percentage
I don't know what percentage of
I don't know what percentage of the
I don't know what percentage of the way
back
back to
I don't know what percentage of the way
back to God
back to God we
I don't know what percentage of the way
back to God we are.
Um
spending
spending time
Um
spending time in
spending time in the
Um
spending time in the presence
spending time in the presence of
Um
spending time in the presence of a
spending time in the presence of a of
Um
spending time in the presence of a of an
excellent
excellent teacher
excellent teacher does
excellent teacher does have
excellent teacher does have beneficial
effects.
effects. Yes,
excellent teacher does have beneficial
effects. Yes, we
effects. Yes, we said
excellent teacher does have beneficial
effects. Yes, we said that's
vibrational.
Um,
Um, how
vibrational.
Um, how do
Um, how do you
vibrational.
Um, how do you reconcile
Um, how do you reconcile the
vibrational.
Um, how do you reconcile the contention
that
that there
that there is
that there is no
that there is no causality
that there is no causality with
that there is no causality with the
assertion
assertion that
that there is no causality with the
assertion that one's
assertion that one's karma
that there is no causality with the
assertion that one's karma is
assertion that one's karma is the
consequence
consequence of
consequence of one's
consequence of one's past
consequence of one's past actions?
That's
That's an
consequence of one's past actions?
That's an easy
That's an easy question
consequence of one's past actions?
That's an easy question to
That's an easy question to see.
consequence of one's past actions?
That's an easy question to see. Um,
That's an easy question to see. Um, I
mean,
mean, it's
mean, it's easy
mean, it's easy to
mean, it's easy to see
mean, it's easy to see how
mean, it's easy to see how it
mean, it's easy to see how it would
arise
arise because
mean, it's easy to see how it would
arise because of
arise because of the
mean, it's easy to see how it would
arise because of the mind's
arise because of the mind's proclivity
to
to translate
to translate everything
to translate everything into
to translate everything into causality.
You
You see,
to translate everything into causality.
You see, one
You see, one thing
to translate everything into causality.
You see, one thing doesn't
You see, one thing doesn't cause
another.
But
But in
another.
But in the
But in the quantum
another.
But in the quantum reality,
what's
what's happening
what's happening is
what's happening is your
what's happening is your increasing
likelihoods
likelihoods of
what's happening is your increasing
likelihoods of potentialities.
This
This is
This is not
This is not causing
This is not causing that.
But
But under
This is not causing that.
But under this
But under this condition,
This is not causing that.
But under this condition, the
But under this condition, the likelihood
of
of this
of this happening
of this happening is
of this happening is increased.
However,
However, in
of this happening is increased.
However, in spiritual
However, in spiritual evolution,
of this happening is increased.
However, in spiritual evolution, freedom
of
of the
of the will
of the will is
of the will is everpresent.
Otherwise,
Otherwise, there
of the will is everpresent.
Otherwise, there would
Otherwise, there would be
of the will is everpresent.
Otherwise, there would be no
Otherwise, there would be no karmic
merit
merit possible,
nor
nor would
merit possible,
nor would there
nor would there be
merit possible,
nor would there be car
nor would there be car karmic
merit possible,
nor would there be car karmic demerit.
It's
It's because
It's because of
It's because of spiritual
It's because of spiritual will
It's because of spiritual will to
It's because of spiritual will to say
yes
yes to
It's because of spiritual will to say
yes to God.
yes to God. Apparently,
It's because of spiritual will to say
yes to God. Apparently, heaven
yes to God. Apparently, heaven is
populated
populated by
populated by people
populated by people who
populated by people who say
populated by people who say yes
populated by people who say yes to
populated by people who say yes to God.
You
You have
populated by people who say yes to God.
You have to
You have to say
populated by people who say yes to God.
You have to say yes
You have to say yes to
populated by people who say yes to God.
You have to say yes to God
You have to say yes to God to
populated by people who say yes to God.
You have to say yes to God to get
You have to say yes to God to get to
heaven.
heaven. That's
heaven. That's Is
heaven. That's Is that
heaven. That's Is that right?
You
You have
heaven. That's Is that right?
You have to
You have to want
heaven. That's Is that right?
You have to want to
You have to want to be
heaven. That's Is that right?
You have to want to be there.
You have to want to be there. God
doesn't
doesn't want
doesn't want anybody
who
who don't
doesn't want anybody
who don't want
who don't want to
doesn't want anybody
who don't want to be
who don't want to be there.
Who
Who hasn't
Who hasn't constant
Who hasn't constant consciously
Who hasn't constant consciously chosen
God?
God? That's
Who hasn't constant consciously chosen
God? That's something
God? That's something I
Who hasn't constant consciously chosen
God? That's something I never
God? That's something I never asked
before.
I
I have
before.
I have permission
I have permission to
before.
I have permission to ask
I have permission to ask and
before.
I have permission to ask and resist.
I have permission to ask and resist. And
that's
that's a
that's a fact.
that's a fact. Heaven
that's a fact. Heaven God
that's a fact. Heaven God doesn't
that's a fact. Heaven God doesn't want
anybody
anybody in
that's a fact. Heaven God doesn't want
anybody in heaven
anybody in heaven that
that's a fact. Heaven God doesn't want
anybody in heaven that doesn't
anybody in heaven that doesn't want
them.
them. Okay.
them. Okay. It's
them. Okay. It's simple
them. Okay. It's simple love.
So
So apparently
karmic
karmic mirror
karmic mirror comes
karmic mirror comes from
karmic mirror comes from having
karmic mirror comes from having had
karmic mirror comes from having had the
opportunity
opportunity to
karmic mirror comes from having had the
opportunity to choose
opportunity to choose either
karmic mirror comes from having had the
opportunity to choose either way
opportunity to choose either way and
karmic mirror comes from having had the
opportunity to choose either way and to
have
have chosen
have chosen this
have chosen this rather
have chosen this rather than
have chosen this rather than that.
have chosen this rather than that. So
all
all is
have chosen this rather than that. So
all is happening
all is happening by
have chosen this rather than that. So
all is happening by free
all is happening by free choice
not
not by
not by causal
not by causal determination.
You
You see
not by causal determination.
You see if
You see if things
not by causal determination.
You see if things were
You see if things were causal
there
there would
there would be
there would be no
there would be no karmic
there would be no karmic merit
there would be no karmic merit nor
demerit
demerit would
there would be no karmic merit nor
demerit would there?
demerit would there? You
there would be no karmic merit nor
demerit would there? You could
demerit would there? You could just
there would be no karmic merit nor
demerit would there? You could just say
everything's
everything's caused
everything's caused by
everything's caused by something
everything's caused by something else.
Well,
Well, this
everything's caused by something else.
Well, this c
Well, this c thought
everything's caused by something else.
Well, this c thought was
Well, this c thought was caused
everything's caused by something else.
Well, this c thought was caused by
Well, this c thought was caused by that
and
and that
and that was
and that was caused
and that was caused by
and that was caused by the
and that was caused by the NBC
and that was caused by the NBC news
and that was caused by the NBC news and
that
that was
and that was caused by the NBC news and
that was caused
that was caused by
and that was caused by the NBC news and
that was caused by the
that was caused by the paper
and that was caused by the NBC news and
that was caused by the paper and
that was caused by the paper and that
was
was caused
was caused by
was caused by what
was caused by what my
was caused by what my parents
was caused by what my parents did.
was caused by what my parents did. So
there's
there's no
was caused by what my parents did. So
there's no responsibility.
Neither
Neither is
Neither is there
Neither is there freedom.
Neither is there freedom. Neither
Neither is there freedom. Neither is
there
there merit
Neither is there freedom. Neither is
there merit nor
there merit nor is
Neither is there freedom. Neither is
there merit nor is there
there merit nor is there room
Neither is there freedom. Neither is
there merit nor is there room for
growth.
growth. It's
growth. It's only
growth. It's only because
growth. It's only because you
growth. It's only because you have
growth. It's only because you have the
option
option to
growth. It's only because you have the
option to say
option to say yes
growth. It's only because you have the
option to say yes or
option to say yes or no
growth. It's only because you have the
option to say yes or no that
option to say yes or no that one
growth. It's only because you have the
option to say yes or no that one by
saying
saying yes
saying yes automatically
saying yes automatically advances
oneself.
oneself. I
saying yes automatically advances
oneself. I don't
oneself. I don't know.
saying yes automatically advances
oneself. I don't know. I
oneself. I don't know. I didn't
saying yes automatically advances
oneself. I don't know. I didn't set
oneself. I don't know. I didn't set the
whole
whole deal
whole deal up.
whole deal up. Don't
whole deal up. Don't ask
whole deal up. Don't ask me
whole deal up. Don't ask me about
whole deal up. Don't ask me about it.
How
How can
whole deal up. Don't ask me about it.
How can we
How can we learn
whole deal up. Don't ask me about it.
How can we learn whether
How can we learn whether or
whole deal up. Don't ask me about it.
How can we learn whether or not
How can we learn whether or not we
whole deal up. Don't ask me about it.
How can we learn whether or not we had
past
past lives?
past lives? Well,
past lives? Well, I
past lives? Well, I suppose
past lives? Well, I suppose you
past lives? Well, I suppose you can
past lives? Well, I suppose you can just
ask.
Let's
Let's see
Let's see if
Let's see if we
Let's see if we have
Let's see if we have permission
Let's see if we have permission to
Let's see if we have permission to ask.
We
We have
Let's see if we have permission to ask.
We have permission
We have permission to
Let's see if we have permission to ask.
We have permission to ask.
We have permission to ask. We
Let's see if we have permission to ask.
We have permission to ask. We have
permission
permission to
permission to ask
permission to ask about
permission to ask about the
permission to ask about the person
permission to ask about the person who
wrote
wrote this.
permission to ask about the person who
wrote this. resist.
You
You want
You want to
You want to know
You want to know the
You want to know the answer?
>> Yes.
>> All
>> All right.
>> All right. This
>> All right. This person
>> All right. This person did
>> All right. This person did have
>> All right. This person did have past
human
human lifetimes.
>> All right. This person did have past
human lifetimes. Is
human lifetimes. Is this?
>> All right. This person did have past
human lifetimes. Is this? Yes.
You
You can
You can ask.
You can ask. That's
You can ask. That's the
You can ask. That's the easiest
You can ask. That's the easiest way.
See,
See, we
You can ask. That's the easiest way.
See, we said
See, we said the
You can ask. That's the easiest way.
See, we said the likelihood
See, we said the likelihood is
You can ask. That's the easiest way.
See, we said the likelihood is that
everybody
everybody in
everybody in the
everybody in the room
everybody in the room had
everybody in the room had what
everybody in the room had what do
everybody in the room had what do we
everybody in the room had what do we say
about
about 25
everybody in the room had what do we say
about 25 on
about 25 on an
everybody in the room had what do we say
about 25 on an average
about 25 on an average about
everybody in the room had what do we say
about 25 on an average about 25
lifetimes.
lifetimes. See,
lifetimes. See, when
lifetimes. See, when you
lifetimes. See, when you get
lifetimes. See, when you get to
lifetimes. See, when you get to a
certain
certain level,
lifetimes. See, when you get to a
certain level, you
certain level, you remember
lifetimes. See, when you get to a
certain level, you remember them.
certain level, you remember them. You
start
start to
start to remember
start to remember them.
start to remember them. You
start to remember them. You begin
start to remember them. You begin to
suspect
suspect them.
There
There are
There are people
There are people who
There are people who specialize
There are people who specialize in
There are people who specialize in past
life
life regression,
There are people who specialize in past
life regression, you
life regression, you know,
There are people who specialize in past
life regression, you know, that
life regression, you know, that can
There are people who specialize in past
life regression, you know, that can take
you
you back
you back there
you back there and
you back there and you
you back there and you reexperience
you back there and you reexperience it.
Um,
Um, people
you back there and you reexperience it.
Um, people get
Um, people get it
you back there and you reexperience it.
Um, people get it through
Um, people get it through dreams,
hallucinations,
and
and various
hallucinations,
and various other
and various other ways.
hallucinations,
and various other ways. You
and various other ways. You begin
hallucinations,
and various other ways. You begin to
suspect
suspect it.
I
I mean,
suspect it.
I mean, it's
I mean, it's not
suspect it.
I mean, it's not necessary
I mean, it's not necessary to
suspect it.
I mean, it's not necessary to know.
I mean, it's not necessary to know. It's
not
not necessary
not necessary to
not necessary to know.
not necessary to know. I
not necessary to know. I said
not necessary to know. I said you
not necessary to know. I said you could
skip
skip this
not necessary to know. I said you could
skip this whole
skip this whole lecture
not necessary to know. I said you could
skip this whole lecture and
skip this whole lecture and reach
not necessary to know. I said you could
skip this whole lecture and reach God
skip this whole lecture and reach God in
an
an instant
soon
soon as
an instant
soon as you
soon as you walk
an instant
soon as you walk out
soon as you walk out of
an instant
soon as you walk out of here.
Your
Your spouse
Your spouse will
Your spouse will know
Your spouse will know it
Your spouse will know it because
Your spouse will know it because you'll
say,
say, she'll
Your spouse will know it because you'll
say, she'll say,
say, she'll say, "Where
Your spouse will know it because you'll
say, she'll say, "Where am
say, she'll say, "Where am I?"
Your spouse will know it because you'll
say, she'll say, "Where am I?" Uh-oh.
God
God shock.
God shock. That
God shock. That was
God shock. That was another
God shock. That was another one
God shock. That was another one they
used
used to
God shock. That was another one they
used to bring
used to bring me.
God shock. That was another one they
used to bring me. Uh,
used to bring me. Uh, is
God shock. That was another one they
used to bring me. Uh, is this
used to bring me. Uh, is this monk
God shock. That was another one they
used to bring me. Uh, is this monk in
God
God shock?
God shock? It's
God shock? It's Godshock.
You
You hit
God shock? It's Godshock.
You hit um
You hit um unexpectedly
God shock? It's Godshock.
You hit um unexpectedly a
You hit um unexpectedly a high
God shock? It's Godshock.
You hit um unexpectedly a high sator
and
and it
and it totally
and it totally blows
and it totally blows you
and it totally blows you away.
Disoriented.
Disoriented. you
and it totally blows you away.
Disoriented. you don't
Disoriented. you don't know
and it totally blows you away.
Disoriented. you don't know how
Disoriented. you don't know how to
function
function in
function in the
function in the world.
function in the world. Uh
function in the world. Uh you're
confused,
confused, can't
function in the world. Uh you're
confused, can't think.
Um
there's
there's a
Um
there's a very
there's a very major
Um
there's a very major change
and
and there
and there is
and there is actually
and there is actually a
and there is actually a period
and there is actually a period of
and there is actually a period of time
when
when you
and there is actually a period of time
when you can't
when you can't function
and there is actually a period of time
when you can't function and
when you can't function and u
and there is actually a period of time
when you can't function and u so
when you can't function and u so have
and there is actually a period of time
when you can't function and u so have a
good
good place
good place to
good place to go
good place to go away
good place to go away when
good place to go away when you
good place to go away when you reach
that
that state.
good place to go away when you reach
that state. pick
that state. pick a
good place to go away when you reach
that state. pick a nice
that state. pick a nice place
good place to go away when you reach
that state. pick a nice place in
that state. pick a nice place in the
country.
country. They
country. They they
country. They they tell
country. They they tell them,
country. They they tell them, "If
country. They they tell them, "If I
country. They they tell them, "If I stop
talking,
talking, eating,
country. They they tell them, "If I stop
talking, eating, and
talking, eating, and looks
country. They they tell them, "If I stop
talking, eating, and looks have
talking, eating, and looks have a
country. They they tell them, "If I stop
talking, eating, and looks have a silly
grin
grin on
grin on my
grin on my face,
grin on my face, let's
grin on my face, let's just
grin on my face, let's just go
grin on my face, let's just go there
grin on my face, let's just go there and
we'll
we'll have
grin on my face, let's just go there and
we'll have chicken
we'll have chicken soup
grin on my face, let's just go there and
we'll have chicken soup once
we'll have chicken soup once a
grin on my face, let's just go there and
we'll have chicken soup once a week."
How
How can
How can we
How can we surrender
How can we surrender everything
How can we surrender everything to
How can we surrender everything to God?
The
The willingness
How can we surrender everything to God?
The willingness to
The willingness to surrender
How can we surrender everything to God?
The willingness to surrender to
The willingness to surrender to God
How can we surrender everything to God?
The willingness to surrender to God is
sort
sort of
sort of a
sort of a catch
sort of a catch 22
because
there
there is
there is a
there is a there
there is a there is
there is a there is a
there is a there is a love
there is a there is a love for
there is a there is a love for God
there is a there is a love for God that
is
is so
there is a there is a love for God that
is so deep
is so deep within
there is a there is a love for God that
is so deep within yourself,
is so deep within yourself, so
there is a there is a love for God that
is so deep within yourself, so profound,
so
so exquisitly
so exquisitly intense
that
that for
so exquisitly intense
that for God
that for God one
so exquisitly intense
that for God one would
that for God one would surrender
anything.
It's
It's something
anything.
It's something to
It's something to be
anything.
It's something to be discovered.
It's something to be discovered. It's
there.
there. That
there. That capacity,
there. That capacity, that
there. That capacity, that willingness
to
to surrender
there. That capacity, that willingness
to surrender everything
to surrender everything to
there. That capacity, that willingness
to surrender everything to God
to surrender everything to God is
there. That capacity, that willingness
to surrender everything to God is innate
within
within consciousness.
When
When you
within consciousness.
When you need
When you need it
within consciousness.
When you need it and
When you need it and call
within consciousness.
When you need it and call it
When you need it and call it forth,
within consciousness.
When you need it and call it forth, it's
there.
Would
Would I
there.
Would I be
Would I be willing
there.
Would I be willing to
Would I be willing to surrender
there.
Would I be willing to surrender this
Would I be willing to surrender this to
God?
God? Yes.
God? Yes. Then
God? Yes. Then you
God? Yes. Then you get
God? Yes. Then you get to
God? Yes. Then you get to a
God? Yes. Then you get to a tough
God? Yes. Then you get to a tough one.
So
So innate
God? Yes. Then you get to a tough one.
So innate to
So innate to the
God? Yes. Then you get to a tough one.
So innate to the pathway
So innate to the pathway of
God? Yes. Then you get to a tough one.
So innate to the pathway of non-duality
or
or the
or the Zen
or the Zen barebones
aesthetic
aesthetic root
aligned
aligned with
aligned with it
aligned with it is
aligned with it is the
aligned with it is the way
aligned with it is the way of
aligned with it is the way of the
aligned with it is the way of the heart.
It
It is
aligned with it is the way of the heart.
It is only
It is only out
aligned with it is the way of the heart.
It is only out of
It is only out of devotion
aligned with it is the way of the heart.
It is only out of devotion to
It is only out of devotion to God,
aligned with it is the way of the heart.
It is only out of devotion to God, out
of
of love
of love for
of love for God.
It
It is
of love for God.
It is only
It is only because
of love for God.
It is only because of
It is only because of the
of love for God.
It is only because of the heart
that
that you're
that you're willing
that you're willing to
that you're willing to follow
that you're willing to follow the
pathway
pathway of
that you're willing to follow the
pathway of negation.
pathway of negation. I'd
that you're willing to follow the
pathway of negation. I'd say
out
out of
out of your
out of your love
out of your love for
out of your love for God,
out of your love for God, you're
out of your love for God, you're willing
to
to let
out of your love for God, you're willing
to let go
to let go of
out of your love for God, you're willing
to let go of a
to let go of a positionality.
So
So one
So one lets
So one lets go
So one lets go of
the
the trit
So one lets go of
the trit ideas
the trit ideas of
So one lets go of
the trit ideas of right
the trit ideas of right and
So one lets go of
the trit ideas of right and wrong.
the trit ideas of right and wrong. War
is
is bad.
is bad. Peace
is bad. Peace is
is bad. Peace is good.
There's
There's more
is bad. Peace is good.
There's more crime
There's more crime goes
is bad. Peace is good.
There's more crime goes on
There's more crime goes on in
is bad. Peace is good.
There's more crime goes on in peaceful
times
times than
times than war.
times than war. War
times than war. War people
times than war. War people are
times than war. War people are too
times than war. War people are too busy
to
to commit
times than war. War people are too busy
to commit crimes.
When
When the
When the war
When the war is
When the war is over,
When the war is over, then
When the war is over, then they
When the war is over, then they go
When the war is over, then they go back
to
to it.
There's
There's a
There's a willingness
There's a willingness to
There's a willingness to surrender
There's a willingness to surrender all
presumptions
presumptions of
There's a willingness to surrender all
presumptions of the
presumptions of the mind
There's a willingness to surrender all
presumptions of the mind and
presumptions of the mind and ask
There's a willingness to surrender all
presumptions of the mind and ask God
presumptions of the mind and ask God for
revelation.
It's
It's like
revelation.
It's like one
It's like one holds
revelation.
It's like one holds one's
It's like one holds one's positionality
and
and ask
and ask God
and ask God to
and ask God to resolve
and ask God to resolve it
and ask God to resolve it out
and ask God to resolve it out of
and ask God to resolve it out of the
willingness
willingness to
and ask God to resolve it out of the
willingness to surrender
willingness to surrender it
and ask God to resolve it out of the
willingness to surrender it to
willingness to surrender it to God.
and ask God to resolve it out of the
willingness to surrender it to God. So
the
the willingness
the willingness to
the willingness to surrender
the willingness to surrender things
the willingness to surrender things to
God
God comes
the willingness to surrender things to
God comes out
God comes out of
the willingness to surrender things to
God comes out of devotion.
When
When you
When you get
When you get into
When you get into an
When you get into an really
When you get into an really incredibly
high
high place
When you get into an really incredibly
high place of
high place of beauty,
When you get into an really incredibly
high place of beauty, you'll
high place of beauty, you'll realize
When you get into an really incredibly
high place of beauty, you'll realize you
can
can get
can get in
can get in touch
can get in touch with
can get in touch with it
can get in touch with it there.
In
In the
can get in touch with it there.
In the state
In the state that
can get in touch with it there.
In the state that you're
In the state that you're in,
can get in touch with it there.
In the state that you're in, you'd
In the state that you're in, you'd be
willing
willing to
willing to surrender
anything
anything to
willing to surrender
anything to God,
anything to God, everything
willing to surrender
anything to God, everything to
anything to God, everything to God,
willing to surrender
anything to God, everything to God, life
itself.
And
And in
itself.
And in the
And in the last
itself.
And in the last instant
And in the last instant that
itself.
And in the last instant that is
And in the last instant that is what
itself.
And in the last instant that is what is
asked
asked for
are
are you
asked for
are you willing
are you willing to
asked for
are you willing to surrender
are you willing to surrender your
asked for
are you willing to surrender your life
itself
itself to
itself to God.
So
So the
itself to God.
So the more
So the more you
itself to God.
So the more you clear
So the more you clear away
itself to God.
So the more you clear away the
So the more you clear away the ego
through
through let's
through let's say
through let's say the
through let's say the Buddhism
through let's say the Buddhism side
through let's say the Buddhism side of
spirituality
spirituality or
through let's say the Buddhism side of
spirituality or the
uh
uh advide
uh advide the
uh advide the side
uh advide the side of
uh advide the side of non-duality
it
strengthens
strengthens the
strengthens the way
strengthens the way of
strengthens the way of the
strengthens the way of the heart
strengthens the way of the heart the
traditional
traditional Christian
strengthens the way of the heart the
traditional Christian way
traditional Christian way let's
strengthens the way of the heart the
traditional Christian way let's say
through
through the
through the heart
through the heart the
through the heart the more
through the heart the more you
through the heart the more you evolve
through
through the
through the heart the more you evolve
through the heart
through the heart the
through the heart the more you evolve
through the heart the greater
through the heart the greater power
through the heart the more you evolve
through the heart the greater power you
have
have to
have to let
have to let go
have to let go positionalities
have to let go positionalities that
have to let go positionalities that are
deeply
deeply ingrained.
So
So each
So each one
So each one assists
So each one assists the
So each one assists the other
So each one assists the other to
So each one assists the other to be
devoted
to
to one
to one spiritual
to one spiritual work.
to one spiritual work. You're
to one spiritual work. You're doing
to one spiritual work. You're doing that
out
out of
to one spiritual work. You're doing that
out of your
out of your love
to one spiritual work. You're doing that
out of your love for
out of your love for God.
The
The reason
The reason to
The reason to become
The reason to become enlightened
The reason to become enlightened is
The reason to become enlightened is out
of
of your
The reason to become enlightened is out
of your love
of your love for
The reason to become enlightened is out
of your love for God.
of your love for God. That's
The reason to become enlightened is out
of your love for God. That's the
of your love for God. That's the reason.
It
It is
It is out
It is out of
It is out of my
It is out of my love
It is out of my love for
It is out of my love for thee,
It is out of my love for thee, oh
It is out of my love for thee, oh Lord,
that
that I
It is out of my love for thee, oh Lord,
that I do
that I do surrender
It is out of my love for thee, oh Lord,
that I do surrender all
that I do surrender all that
It is out of my love for thee, oh Lord,
that I do surrender all that I
that I do surrender all that I think
It is out of my love for thee, oh Lord,
that I do surrender all that I think and
believe
believe that
believe that I
believe that I am,
believe that I am, including
believe that I am, including life
itself.
To
To thee,
To thee, oh
To thee, oh Lord,
To thee, oh Lord, do
To thee, oh Lord, do I
To thee, oh Lord, do I surrender
To thee, oh Lord, do I surrender my
being.
That's
That's an
That's an act
That's an act of
That's an act of the
That's an act of the spiritual
That's an act of the spiritual will.
comes
comes from
That's an act of the spiritual will.
comes from the
comes from the heart
That's an act of the spiritual will.
comes from the heart of
comes from the heart of the
That's an act of the spiritual will.
comes from the heart of the spiritual
will.
It
It comes
will.
It comes out
It comes out of
will.
It comes out of connecting
It comes out of connecting with
will.
It comes out of connecting with the
inner
inner joy.
When
When you
inner joy.
When you connect
When you connect with
inner joy.
When you connect with the
When you connect with the inner
inner joy.
When you connect with the inner joy,
When you connect with the inner joy, it
gives
gives you
gives you the
gives you the spiritual
gives you the spiritual power
gives you the spiritual power to
surrender
surrender anything
gives you the spiritual power to
surrender anything else
surrender anything else except
gives you the spiritual power to
surrender anything else except truth
surrender anything else except truth to
the
the Lord,
the Lord, you
the Lord, you know.
also
divinity
divinity respond
divinity respond let's
divinity respond let's say
divinity respond let's say no
divinity respond let's say no I
divinity respond let's say no I can't
put
put it
divinity respond let's say no I can't
put it that
put it that way
the
the worship
the worship of
the worship of God
the worship of God the
the worship of God the love
the worship of God the love for
the worship of God the love for God
the worship of God the love for God the
devotion
devotion to
the worship of God the love for God the
devotion to God
the
the love
the love and
the love and devotion
the love and devotion to
the love and devotion to spiritual
the love and devotion to spiritual work
itself
itself is
the love and devotion to spiritual work
itself is a
itself is a sacrifice
the love and devotion to spiritual work
itself is a sacrifice and
itself is a sacrifice and a
the love and devotion to spiritual work
itself is a sacrifice and a gift
itself is a sacrifice and a gift to
the love and devotion to spiritual work
itself is a sacrifice and a gift to God
who
who doesn't
who doesn't need
who doesn't need any
who doesn't need any gifts
it's
it's Just
who doesn't need any gifts
it's Just a
it's Just a silent
who doesn't need any gifts
it's Just a silent speech.
It's
It's a
It's a gift
It's a gift of
It's a gift of love
It's a gift of love is
It's a gift of love is a
It's a gift of love is a gift
It's a gift of love is a gift of
It's a gift of love is a gift of love
and
and it
It's a gift of love is a gift of love
and it is
and it is its
It's a gift of love is a gift of love
and it is its own
and it is its own reward.
Just
Just like
you
you follow
Just like
you follow something
you follow something that
Just like
you follow something that brings
you follow something that brings you
great
great joy
great joy and
great joy and ecstasy
great joy and ecstasy and
great joy and ecstasy and you
great joy and ecstasy and you tell
somebody
somebody about
great joy and ecstasy and you tell
somebody about it
somebody about it and
great joy and ecstasy and you tell
somebody about it and then
somebody about it and then one
great joy and ecstasy and you tell
somebody about it and then one day
somebody about it and then one day you
can
can just
can just tell
can just tell by
can just tell by the
can just tell by the look
can just tell by the look on
can just tell by the look on their
can just tell by the look on their face
that
that they
can just tell by the look on their face
that they got
that they got it.
can just tell by the look on their face
that they got it. The
that they got it. The look
can just tell by the look on their face
that they got it. The look on
that they got it. The look on their
can just tell by the look on their face
that they got it. The look on their face
that
that they
that they got
that they got it
that they got it brings
that they got it brings you
that they got it brings you such
that they got it brings you such joy.
It's
It's its
that they got it brings you such joy.
It's its own
It's its own reward.
that they got it brings you such joy.
It's its own reward. It's
self-fulfilling.
self-fulfilling. Nothing
self-fulfilling. Nothing more
self-fulfilling. Nothing more is
self-fulfilling. Nothing more is needed.
Compassion
Compassion for
self-fulfilling. Nothing more is needed.
Compassion for oneself
arises
arises out
arises out of
arises out of seeing
arises out of seeing one's
arises out of seeing one's own
innocence.
innocence. Intrinsically
the
the innate
that
that which
the innate
that which is
that which is within
the innate
that which is within oneself
that which is within oneself is
innocent.
Out
Out of
innocent.
Out of the
Out of the unmanifest
innocent.
Out of the unmanifest arises
Out of the unmanifest arises the
manifest.
manifest. Out
manifest. Out of
manifest. Out of the
manifest. Out of the manifest
manifest. Out of the manifest arises
consciousness.
And
And the
And the spirit
And the spirit of
And the spirit of God
And the spirit of God is
And the spirit of God is life.
Life
Life itself
And the spirit of God is life.
Life itself is
Life itself is innocent.
It
It takes
It takes whatever
It takes whatever form.
It
It stays
It takes whatever form.
It stays life.
It stays life. It
It takes whatever form.
It stays life. It does
It stays life. It does not
It takes whatever form.
It stays life. It does not change
It stays life. It does not change with
the
the form.
the form. Huh?
To
To truly
the form. Huh?
To truly love
To truly love oneself,
the form. Huh?
To truly love oneself, then
To truly love oneself, then it's
necessary
necessary to
necessary to love
necessary to love God.
necessary to love God. And
necessary to love God. And to
necessary to love God. And to love
necessary to love God. And to love God,
it's
it's really
necessary to love God. And to love God,
it's really necessary
it's really necessary to
necessary to love God. And to love God,
it's really necessary to love
it's really necessary to love oneself.
So
So we
So we constantly
So we constantly let
So we constantly let go
So we constantly let go any
So we constantly let go any blocks
So we constantly let go any blocks to
the
the realization
So we constantly let go any blocks to
the realization of
the realization of the
So we constantly let go any blocks to
the realization of the truth
the realization of the truth of
So we constantly let go any blocks to
the realization of the truth of that,
the
the willingness
the willingness to
the willingness to be
the willingness to be compassionate,
the willingness to be compassionate, the
willingness
willingness to
the willingness to be compassionate, the
willingness to surrender
willingness to surrender all
the willingness to be compassionate, the
willingness to surrender all to
willingness to surrender all to God.
the willingness to be compassionate, the
willingness to surrender all to God. In
the
the end,
the end, it's
the end, it's a
the end, it's a matter
the end, it's a matter of
the end, it's a matter of trust
the end, it's a matter of trust and
faith.
faith. In
the end, it's a matter of trust and
faith. In the
faith. In the in
the end, it's a matter of trust and
faith. In the in the
faith. In the in the end
the end, it's a matter of trust and
faith. In the in the end when
faith. In the in the end when you
the end, it's a matter of trust and
faith. In the in the end when you are
asked
asked to
asked to walk
asked to walk off
asked to walk off the
asked to walk off the cliff
asked to walk off the cliff in
asked to walk off the cliff in the
asked to walk off the cliff in the end
you're
you're walking
asked to walk off the cliff in the end
you're walking off
you're walking off you're
asked to walk off the cliff in the end
you're walking off you're going
you're walking off you're going to
asked to walk off the cliff in the end
you're walking off you're going to walk
off
off the
off the cliff
and
and it's
off the cliff
and it's the
and it's the faith
off the cliff
and it's the faith and
and it's the faith and trust
off the cliff
and it's the faith and trust and
and it's the faith and trust and the
teachers
the
the veracity
teachers
the veracity of
the veracity of the
teachers
the veracity of the teachers
the veracity of the teachers the
teachers
the veracity of the teachers the energy
field
field of
field of the
field of the reverberation
the
the um
field of the reverberation
the um absolute
the um absolute conviction
um
um of
um of the
um of the truth
um of the truth of
um of the truth of the
um of the truth of the Buddha
um of the truth of the Buddha and
um of the truth of the Buddha and all
the
the great
um of the truth of the Buddha and all
the great avatars.
So
So the
So the last
So the last moment
So the last moment when
So the last moment when one
So the last moment when one is
So the last moment when one is asked
So the last moment when one is asked to
give
give up
So the last moment when one is asked to
give up the
give up the self
So the last moment when one is asked to
give up the self life
give up the self life and
So the last moment when one is asked to
give up the self life and all
give up the self life and all that
So the last moment when one is asked to
give up the self life and all that you
know
know exists
then
then up
know exists
then up comes
then up comes that
devotion
of
of enormous
devotion
of enormous power.
One
One would
One would let
One would let oneself
One would let oneself be
One would let oneself be eaten
One would let oneself be eaten alive
One would let oneself be eaten alive if
God
God asked
One would let oneself be eaten alive if
God asked you
God asked you to.
For
For thee,
For thee, oh
For thee, oh Lord,
For thee, oh Lord, do
For thee, oh Lord, do I
For thee, oh Lord, do I give
For thee, oh Lord, do I give myself.
You
You surrender
For thee, oh Lord, do I give myself.
You surrender even
You surrender even life
For thee, oh Lord, do I give myself.
You surrender even life itself
You surrender even life itself to
For thee, oh Lord, do I give myself.
You surrender even life itself to thee,
oh
oh Lord.
Um
the
the juices
the juices of
the juices of illness
the juices of illness and
the juices of illness and negativity
the juices of illness and negativity and
suffering
are
the
the suffering
are
the suffering itself.
the suffering itself. In
are
the suffering itself. In other
the suffering itself. In other words,
people
people look
people look for
people look for psychological
people look for psychological reasons.
There's
There's a
people look for psychological reasons.
There's a naive
There's a naive you
people look for psychological reasons.
There's a naive you see.
There's a naive you see. You
people look for psychological reasons.
There's a naive you see. You see
There's a naive you see. You see it
every
every night
every night on
every night on television.
Sort
Sort of
every night on television.
Sort of pop
Sort of pop psychology.
Oh,
Oh, this
Oh, this guy
Oh, this guy just
Oh, this guy just shot
Oh, this guy just shot 14
Oh, this guy just shot 14 strangers
Oh, this guy just shot 14 strangers in
Oh, this guy just shot 14 strangers in a
row.
row. What
Oh, this guy just shot 14 strangers in a
row. What do
row. What do you
Oh, this guy just shot 14 strangers in a
row. What do you suppose
row. What do you suppose happened
Oh, this guy just shot 14 strangers in a
row. What do you suppose happened in
row. What do you suppose happened in his
childhood?
childhood? That's
childhood? That's the
childhood? That's the first
childhood? That's the first thing.
childhood? That's the first thing. You
know,
nothing.
Nothing
Nothing that
nothing.
Nothing that happened
Nothing that happened in
nothing.
Nothing that happened in his
Nothing that happened in his childhood
has
has got
has got anything
has got anything to
has got anything to do
has got anything to do with
has got anything to do with what
has got anything to do with what he's
doing
doing now.
That's
That's just
That's just a
That's just a plausible
That's just a plausible rationalization
because
because we
That's just a plausible rationalization
because we like
because we like to
That's just a plausible rationalization
because we like to psychize
because we like to psychize things
because
because that
because that gives
because that gives us
because that gives us a
because that gives us a superior
because that gives us a superior feeling
that
that we
because that gives us a superior feeling
that we understand
that we understand them
because that gives us a superior feeling
that we understand them and
that we understand them and can
because that gives us a superior feeling
that we understand them and can explain
them
them when
them when the
them when the truth
them when the truth is
all
all these
them when the truth is
all these explanations
all these explanations are
them when the truth is
all these explanations are nonsensical.
Have
Have nothing
Have nothing to
Have nothing to do
Have nothing to do with
Have nothing to do with it.
You
You know
Have nothing to do with it.
You know why
You know why I
Have nothing to do with it.
You know why I like
You know why I like shooting
Have nothing to do with it.
You know why I like shooting people?
Because
Because I
Because I like
Because I like shooting
Because I like shooting people.
Because I like shooting people. You
understand?
understand? The
Because I like shooting people. You
understand? The payoff
understand? The payoff is
Because I like shooting people. You
understand? The payoff is the
understand? The payoff is the experience
itself.
Not
Not because
itself.
Not because I'm
Not because I'm getting
itself.
Not because I'm getting even
Not because I'm getting even with
itself.
Not because I'm getting even with my
father
father from
father from childhood
father from childhood when
father from childhood when he
father from childhood when he abused
father from childhood when he abused me
and
and all
father from childhood when he abused me
and all that.
Because
Because even
Because even if
Because even if that's
Because even if that's a
Because even if that's a fact,
Because even if that's a fact, it's
still
still got
Because even if that's a fact, it's
still got nothing
still got nothing to
Because even if that's a fact, it's
still got nothing to do
still got nothing to do with
Because even if that's a fact, it's
still got nothing to do with why
still got nothing to do with why you're
doing
doing what
doing what you
doing what you do
doing what you do now.
doing what you do now. You
doing what you do now. You do
doing what you do now. You do what
doing what you do now. You do what you
do
do now
doing what you do now. You do what you
do now because
do now because the
doing what you do now. You do what you
do now because the experience
do now because the experience itself
doing what you do now. You do what you
do now because the experience itself is
the
the payoff.
The
The experience
the payoff.
The experience itself
The experience itself is
the payoff.
The experience itself is what
The experience itself is what is
the payoff.
The experience itself is what is sought.
Once
Once we
Once we seek
Once we seek to
Once we seek to feel
Once we seek to feel sorry
Once we seek to feel sorry for
Once we seek to feel sorry for ourself,
we
we seek
Once we seek to feel sorry for ourself,
we seek to
we seek to feel
Once we seek to feel sorry for ourself,
we seek to feel resentments
we seek to feel resentments and
Once we seek to feel sorry for ourself,
we seek to feel resentments and revenge.
We
We love
We love to
We love to see
We love to see with
We love to see with rage
We love to see with rage and
indignation.
Ain't
Ain't that
Ain't that fun?
Just
Just see,
Ain't that fun?
Just see, oh,
Just see, oh, we
Ain't that fun?
Just see, oh, we hate
Just see, oh, we hate them.
We
We just
We just have
We just have a
We just have a hate
We just have a hate parade.
We just have a hate parade. I
We just have a hate parade. I mean,
people
people just
We just have a hate parade. I mean,
people just dig
people just dig hate.
We just have a hate parade. I mean,
people just dig hate. You
people just dig hate. You know,
We just have a hate parade. I mean,
people just dig hate. You know, you
watch
watch those
watch those uh
news
news broadcasts
watch those uh
news broadcasts from
news broadcasts from the
watch those uh
news broadcasts from the Middle
news broadcasts from the Middle East,
watch those uh
news broadcasts from the Middle East, as
I've
I've spoken
I've spoken before,
I've spoken before, and
I've spoken before, and you
I've spoken before, and you watch
I've spoken before, and you watch how
watch
watch the
I've spoken before, and you watch how
watch the expression
watch the expression on
I've spoken before, and you watch how
watch the expression on their
watch the expression on their face
I've spoken before, and you watch how
watch the expression on their face as
they
they throw
they throw rocks
they throw rocks at
they throw rocks at each
they throw rocks at each other,
they throw rocks at each other, man.
They're
They're really
they throw rocks at each other, man.
They're really getting
They're really getting off
they throw rocks at each other, man.
They're really getting off on
They're really getting off on it.
they throw rocks at each other, man.
They're really getting off on it. I
mean,
mean, they're
mean, they're having
mean, they're having a
mean, they're having a ball
pop.
pop. I
mean, they're having a ball
pop. I mean,
pop. I mean, they
mean, they're having a ball
pop. I mean, they just
pop. I mean, they just love
mean, they're having a ball
pop. I mean, they just love it,
pop. I mean, they just love it, you
know?
know? And
know? And you
know? And you want
know? And you want to
know? And you want to get
know? And you want to get in
know? And you want to get in there
know? And you want to get in there with
a
a peace
know? And you want to get in there with
a peace sign,
a peace sign, get
know? And you want to get in there with
a peace sign, get out
a peace sign, get out of
know? And you want to get in there with
a peace sign, get out of there.
Who
Who wants
Who wants peace?
be
be in
Who wants peace?
be in the
be in the middle
Who wants peace?
be in the middle of
be in the middle of a
Who wants peace?
be in the middle of a prize
be in the middle of a prize fight.
Who wants peace?
be in the middle of a prize fight. Some
idiot
idiot runs
idiot runs out
idiot runs out there.
idiot runs out there. Peas,
give
give us
idiot runs out there. Peas,
give us a
give us a break.
How
How does
How does one
How does one surrender
How does one surrender the
How does one surrender the will
How does one surrender the will to
think?
think? That
How does one surrender the will to
think? That is
think? That is sort
How does one surrender the will to
think? That is sort of
think? That is sort of a
How does one surrender the will to
think? That is sort of a tricky
think? That is sort of a tricky one.
How does one surrender the will to
think? That is sort of a tricky one. And
we've
we've said
we've said that
we've said that thinkingness
we've said that thinkingness is
we've said that thinkingness is its
we've said that thinkingness is its own
reward.
We
We just
We just got
We just got through
We just got through saying
We just got through saying that
We just got through saying that the
reason
reason behind
We just got through saying that the
reason behind you
reason behind you see
We just got through saying that the
reason behind you see because
reason behind you see because that's
based
based on
based on causality
based on causality and
based on causality and there
based on causality and there is
based on causality and there is no
based on causality and there is no such
thing
thing as
based on causality and there is no such
thing as causality.
thing as causality. So
based on causality and there is no such
thing as causality. So looking
thing as causality. So looking for
based on causality and there is no such
thing as causality. So looking for the
cause
cause of
cause of something
cause of something you
cause of something you always
cause of something you always end
cause of something you always end up
with
with a
cause of something you always end up
with a tautology
with a tautology chasing
cause of something you always end up
with a tautology chasing your
with a tautology chasing your tail.
The
The payoff
The payoff of
The payoff of an
The payoff of an experience
The payoff of an experience is
The payoff of an experience is the
The payoff of an experience is the is
the
the experience.
That
That is
That is the
That is the payoff.
The
The payoff
That is the payoff.
The payoff of
The payoff of hating
That is the payoff.
The payoff of hating is
The payoff of hating is to
That is the payoff.
The payoff of hating is to get
The payoff of hating is to get to
experience
experience hating.
One
One can
experience hating.
One can rec
One can rec retrospectively
experience hating.
One can rec retrospectively justify
One can rec retrospectively justify it.
My
My father
My father was
My father was brutal
My father was brutal to
My father was brutal to me,
My father was brutal to me, etc.
My father was brutal to me, etc. But
that
that frankly
My father was brutal to me, etc. But
that frankly is
that frankly is not
My father was brutal to me, etc. But
that frankly is not why
that frankly is not why you're
My father was brutal to me, etc. But
that frankly is not why you're doing
what
what you're
what you're doing
what you're doing now.
what you're doing now. Because
what you're doing now. Because you're
not
not 5
what you're doing now. Because you're
not 5 years
not 5 years old.
what you're doing now. Because you're
not 5 years old. That's
not 5 years old. That's not
what you're doing now. Because you're
not 5 years old. That's not your
not 5 years old. That's not your father.
It's
It's got
It's got nothing
It's got nothing to
It's got nothing to do
It's got nothing to do with
It's got nothing to do with it.
You're
You're violent
It's got nothing to do with it.
You're violent right
You're violent right now
It's got nothing to do with it.
You're violent right now because
You're violent right now because you
enjoy
enjoy being
enjoy being violent.
I've
I've got
enjoy being violent.
I've got 50
I've got 50 girls,
enjoy being violent.
I've got 50 girls, many
I've got 50 girls, many of
enjoy being violent.
I've got 50 girls, many of whom
I've got 50 girls, many of whom just
enjoy
enjoy being
enjoy being violent.
They
They like
enjoy being violent.
They like to
They like to hit
enjoy being violent.
They like to hit cement
They like to hit cement walls
enjoy being violent.
They like to hit cement walls with
They like to hit cement walls with their
fists
fists and
fists and fracture
fists and fracture their
fists and fracture their bones.
Is
Is logic
fists and fracture their bones.
Is logic or
Is logic or reason
fists and fracture their bones.
Is logic or reason or
Is logic or reason or psychology
fists and fracture their bones.
Is logic or reason or psychology going
to
to find
to find a
to find a reason?
to find a reason? Pathetic.
to find a reason? Pathetic. Now
to find a reason? Pathetic. Now you
to find a reason? Pathetic. Now you hear
them
them try
to find a reason? Pathetic. Now you hear
them try to
them try to find
to find a reason? Pathetic. Now you hear
them try to find it.
And
And I
And I humor
And I humor them
And I humor them and
And I humor them and say,
And I humor them and say, "Uh-huh.
You
You hit
And I humor them and say, "Uh-huh.
You hit your
You hit your fist
And I humor them and say, "Uh-huh.
You hit your fist against
You hit your fist against the
And I humor them and say, "Uh-huh.
You hit your fist against the cement
You hit your fist against the cement so
you
you can
you can break
you can break your
you can break your fist
you can break your fist and
you can break your fist and say,
you can break your fist and say, "Look,
I
I broke
you can break your fist and say, "Look,
I broke my
I broke my fist
you can break your fist and say, "Look,
I broke my fist against
I broke my fist against the
you can break your fist and say, "Look,
I broke my fist against the cement
I broke my fist against the cement wall.
See
See how
See how crazy
See how crazy I
See how crazy I am."
I
I say,
See how crazy I am."
I say, "Look,
I say, "Look, I
See how crazy I am."
I say, "Look, I know
I say, "Look, I know you're
See how crazy I am."
I say, "Look, I know you're crazy.
I say, "Look, I know you're crazy. You
don't
don't have
don't have to
don't have to prove
don't have to prove it.
You
You have
don't have to prove it.
You have to
You have to break
don't have to prove it.
You have to break bones
You have to break bones to
don't have to prove it.
You have to break bones to tell
You have to break bones to tell me
you're
you're crazy."
But
But what
you're crazy."
But what she's
But what she's saying
you're crazy."
But what she's saying to
But what she's saying to me
you're crazy."
But what she's saying to me is,
But what she's saying to me is, "I
you're crazy."
But what she's saying to me is, "I am
that
that crazy.
I
I am
that crazy.
I am so
I am so crazy
that crazy.
I am so crazy that
I am so crazy that I'll
that crazy.
I am so crazy that I'll actually
I am so crazy that I'll actually break
my
my bones
my bones against
my bones against cement
my bones against cement walls."
my bones against cement walls." So
my bones against cement walls." So I
said
said to
my bones against cement walls." So I
said to her,
said to her, you
my bones against cement walls." So I
said to her, you know,
said to her, you know, I
my bones against cement walls." So I
said to her, you know, I get
said to her, you know, I get it.
my bones against cement walls." So I
said to her, you know, I get it. I
said to her, you know, I get it. I get
it.
Yes,
Yes, you
it.
Yes, you are
Yes, you are that
it.
Yes, you are that crazy.
Oh
Oh dear.
The
The payoff
Oh dear.
The payoff of
The payoff of an
Oh dear.
The payoff of an experience
The payoff of an experience is
Oh dear.
The payoff of an experience is the
experience
experience itself.
experience itself. Therefore,
experience itself. Therefore, the
experience itself. Therefore, the only
thing
thing you
experience itself. Therefore, the only
thing you have
thing you have to
experience itself. Therefore, the only
thing you have to experience
thing you have to experience sacrifice
is
is your
is your desire
is your desire for
is your desire for that
is your desire for that experience.
We
We indulge
is your desire for that experience.
We indulge in
We indulge in certain
is your desire for that experience.
We indulge in certain fantasies
We indulge in certain fantasies and
feelings
feelings and
feelings and recollections
feelings and recollections and
feelings and recollections and memories
because
because of
feelings and recollections and memories
because of that
because of that which
feelings and recollections and memories
because of that which it
because of that which it brings
feelings and recollections and memories
because of that which it brings up.
because of that which it brings up. And
we're
we're doing
we're doing it
we're doing it for
we're doing it for the
we're doing it for the sake
we're doing it for the sake of
we're doing it for the sake of that
which
which it
we're doing it for the sake of that
which it brings
which it brings up
and
and thereby
and thereby the
and thereby the ego
and thereby the ego ensures
and thereby the ego ensures its
and thereby the ego ensures its own
survival
survival through
and thereby the ego ensures its own
survival through repetition.
We
We get
We get addicted
We get addicted to
We get addicted to being
We get addicted to being addicting.
We get addicted to being addicting. One
of
of the
We get addicted to being addicting. One
of the things
of the things you
We get addicted to being addicting. One
of the things you got
of the things you got to
We get addicted to being addicting. One
of the things you got to let
of the things you got to let go
We get addicted to being addicting. One
of the things you got to let go of
of the things you got to let go of is
wanting
wanting to
wanting to become
wanting to become addicted.
We're
We're addicted
wanting to become addicted.
We're addicted to
We're addicted to thinking.
wanting to become addicted.
We're addicted to thinking. We're
addicted
addicted to
addicted to suffering.
addicted to suffering. We're
addicted to suffering. We're addicted
addicted to suffering. We're addicted to
guilt.
guilt. We're
addicted to suffering. We're addicted to
guilt. We're addicted.
One
One of
One of the
One of the things
One of the things you
One of the things you have
One of the things you have to
One of the things you have to detach
from
from is
One of the things you have to detach
from is a
from is a desire
One of the things you have to detach
from is a desire to
from is a desire to become
One of the things you have to detach
from is a desire to become addicted
from is a desire to become addicted to
things.
Not
Not addicted
things.
Not addicted to
Not addicted to this,
things.
Not addicted to this, not
Not addicted to this, not addicted
things.
Not addicted to this, not addicted to
that,
that, but
becoming
becoming addicted
that, but
becoming addicted to
addiction
addiction itself.
becoming
becoming attached
addiction itself.
becoming attached to
becoming attached to attachment
addiction itself.
becoming attached to attachment itself.
Some
Some people
Some people become
Some people become attached
Some people become attached to
everything
everything constantly.
Some people become attached to
everything constantly. They're
everything constantly. They're just
attached
attached to
attached to everything.
attached to everything. And
attached to everything. And you
attached to everything. And you just
watch
watch them.
attached to everything. And you just
watch them. They're
watch them. They're attached
attached to everything. And you just
watch them. They're attached to
watch them. They're attached to this.
They're
They're attached
They're attached to
They're attached to that.
They're attached to that. Attached
They're attached to that. Attached to
their
their thoughts,
They're attached to that. Attached to
their thoughts, attached
their thoughts, attached to
They're attached to that. Attached to
their thoughts, attached to their
habits.
habits. They're
habits. They're attached
habits. They're attached to
habits. They're attached to everything.
Attached
Attached to
habits. They're attached to everything.
Attached to their
Attached to their possessions.
You
You have
You have to
You have to let
You have to let go.
You have to let go. Not
You have to let go. Not being
You have to let go. Not being attached
to
to money,
You have to let go. Not being attached
to money, attached
to money, attached to
You have to let go. Not being attached
to money, attached to greed,
to money, attached to greed, attached
You have to let go. Not being attached
to money, attached to greed, attached to
six,
six, whatever.
six, whatever. You
six, whatever. You have
six, whatever. You have to
six, whatever. You have to let
six, whatever. You have to let go
wanting
wanting to
six, whatever. You have to let go
wanting to be
wanting to be attached
six, whatever. You have to let go
wanting to be attached period.
wanting to be attached period. What
six, whatever. You have to let go
wanting to be attached period. What do
wanting to be attached period. What do I
get
get out
get out of
get out of feeling
get out of feeling attached
get out of feeling attached to
get out of feeling attached to things
whatever
whatever they
get out of feeling attached to things
whatever they might
whatever they might be?
Attachment
Attachment itself
Attachment itself then
Attachment itself then is
Attachment itself then is some
Attachment itself then is some kind
Attachment itself then is some kind of
Attachment itself then is some kind of a
security
security operation
Attachment itself then is some kind of a
security operation operating
security operation operating out
Attachment itself then is some kind of a
security operation operating out of
illusion.
illusion. So
illusion. So in
illusion. So in spiritual
illusion. So in spiritual work
illusion. So in spiritual work you
illusion. So in spiritual work you you
try
try to
illusion. So in spiritual work you you
try to find
try to find the
illusion. So in spiritual work you you
try to find the common
try to find the common denominator
illusion. So in spiritual work you you
try to find the common denominator so
that
that when
that when you
that when you let
that when you let go
that when you let go of
that when you let go of this
that when you let go of this down
that when you let go of this down here
it
it lets
that when you let go of this down here
it lets go
it lets go a
that when you let go of this down here
it lets go a whole
it lets go a whole lot
that when you let go of this down here
it lets go a whole lot of
it lets go a whole lot of things
that when you let go of this down here
it lets go a whole lot of things because
you
you don't
you don't have
you don't have enough
you don't have enough time
you don't have enough time to
you don't have enough time to let
you don't have enough time to let go
you don't have enough time to let go all
the
the blocks
you don't have enough time to let go all
the blocks and
the blocks and impediments.
you don't have enough time to let go all
the blocks and impediments. What
the blocks and impediments. What you
you don't have enough time to let go all
the blocks and impediments. What you can
find
find is
find is a
find is a commonality.
Uh
Uh diffuse
find is a commonality.
Uh diffuse that
Uh diffuse that commonality
find is a commonality.
Uh diffuse that commonality and
Uh diffuse that commonality and now
whole
whole rafts
whole rafts of
whole rafts of things
whole rafts of things leave
whole rafts of things leave your
whole rafts of things leave your mind
and
and just
whole rafts of things leave your mind
and just never
and just never come
whole rafts of things leave your mind
and just never come back
and just never come back there
whole rafts of things leave your mind
and just never come back there anymore.
People
have
have good
People
have good and
have good and kindly
People
have good and kindly thoughts
have good and kindly thoughts about
People
have good and kindly thoughts about God
and
and they
and they their
and they their heart
and they their heart they
and they their heart they touch
and they their heart they touch their
heart
heart but
God
God is
God is not
God is not a
God is not a sweet
God is not a sweet old
God is not a sweet old lady.
God is not a sweet old lady. No,
there
there is
God is not a sweet old lady. No,
there is a
there is a certain
God is not a sweet old lady. No,
there is a certain parallelism
there is a certain parallelism between
the
the nonlinear
the nonlinear and
the nonlinear and the
the nonlinear and the linear
the nonlinear and the linear domain
between
between spirituality
the nonlinear and the linear domain
between spirituality and
between spirituality and physicality.
Therefore,
Therefore, that
Therefore, that which
Therefore, that which is
Therefore, that which is legitimate
legitimately
legitimately spiritual
Therefore, that which is legitimate
legitimately spiritual may
legitimately spiritual may also
Therefore, that which is legitimate
legitimately spiritual may also have
legitimately spiritual may also have its
parallel
parallel within
parallel within the
parallel within the physical
parallel within the physical domain.
The
The fact
parallel within the physical domain.
The fact that
The fact that there
parallel within the physical domain.
The fact that there is
The fact that there is a
parallel within the physical domain.
The fact that there is a parallel
The fact that there is a parallel in
which
which you
which you can
which you can imitate
which you can imitate the
which you can imitate the spiritual
which you can imitate the spiritual by
physical
physical manipulation.
It's
It's a
It's a nonssetor
It's a nonssetor to
It's a nonssetor to conclude
It's a nonssetor to conclude therefore
that
that the
It's a nonssetor to conclude therefore
that the spiritual
that the spiritual is
It's a nonssetor to conclude therefore
that the spiritual is unreal
that the spiritual is unreal because
It's a nonssetor to conclude therefore
that the spiritual is unreal because it
can
can be
can be imitated
can be imitated within
can be imitated within the
can be imitated within the physical.
All
All kinds
can be imitated within the physical.
All kinds of
All kinds of per
can be imitated within the physical.
All kinds of per of
All kinds of per of experiences
can be imitated within the physical.
All kinds of per of experiences can
All kinds of per of experiences can be
imitated
imitated by
imitated by poking
imitated by poking various
imitated by poking various parts
imitated by poking various parts of
imitated by poking various parts of the
brain.
All
All kinds
All kinds of
All kinds of events
All kinds of events can
All kinds of events can be
All kinds of events can be uh
All kinds of events can be uh imitated
spiriously
spiriously created
and
and I
and I suppose
and I suppose Indian
and I suppose Indian rope
and I suppose Indian rope tricks
and I suppose Indian rope tricks can
and I suppose Indian rope tricks can be
performed.
There
There is
There is a
There is a limited
There is a limited parallelism
There is a limited parallelism in
There is a limited parallelism in which
that
that which
There is a limited parallelism in which
that which is
that which is the
There is a limited parallelism in which
that which is the imitation
that which is the imitation within
There is a limited parallelism in which
that which is the imitation within the
physical
physical domain
physical domain has
physical domain has to
physical domain has to the
unsophisticated
unsophisticated a
physical domain has to the
unsophisticated a superficial
unsophisticated a superficial appearance
to
to the
to the real.
One
One way
to the real.
One way to
One way to differentiate
to the real.
One way to differentiate the
One way to differentiate the truth
to the real.
One way to differentiate the truth of
the
the two
the two is
the two is by
the two is by calibration.
We
We said
the two is by calibration.
We said that
We said that out
the two is by calibration.
We said that out of
We said that out of body
the two is by calibration.
We said that out of body experiences
We said that out of body experiences for
for
for instance
are
are quite
for instance
are quite amazing
and
and uh
and uh fun.
and uh fun. Besides,
how
how many
and uh fun. Besides,
how many here
how many here have
and uh fun. Besides,
how many here have had
how many here have had out
and uh fun. Besides,
how many here have had out of the
how many here have had out of the body
experience?
experience? Yeah.
experience? Yeah. Okay.
experience? Yeah. Okay. All
experience? Yeah. Okay. All right.
experience? Yeah. Okay. All right. If
experience? Yeah. Okay. All right. If we
calibrate
calibrate the
experience? Yeah. Okay. All right. If we
calibrate the energy
calibrate the energy of
experience? Yeah. Okay. All right. If we
calibrate the energy of the
calibrate the energy of the entity,
experience? Yeah. Okay. All right. If we
calibrate the energy of the entity, the
entity.
entity. How
entity. How do
entity. How do you
entity. How do you like
entity. How do you like that?
entity. How do you like that? What?
entity. How do you like that? What? What
technical
technical talking?
entity. How do you like that? What? What
technical talking? The
technical talking? The person
entity. How do you like that? What? What
technical talking? The person before
technical talking? The person before and
after.
We
We said
after.
We said I
We said I think
after.
We said I think we've
We said I think we've done
after.
We said I think we've done this
We said I think we've done this before.
Uh
Uh out
Uh out of
Uh out of body
Uh out of body experience,
Uh out of body experience, the
Uh out of body experience, the person's
calibration
calibration does
Uh out of body experience, the person's
calibration does not
calibration does not uh
Uh out of body experience, the person's
calibration does not uh really
calibration does not uh really change
significantly.
significantly. We
significantly. We have
significantly. We have permission
significantly. We have permission to
significantly. We have permission to ask
that.
that. It
significantly. We have permission to ask
that. It it
that. It it remains
significantly. We have permission to ask
that. It it remains about
that. It it remains about the
significantly. We have permission to ask
that. It it remains about the same
resistance.
But
But you
resistance.
But you do
But you do learn
resistance.
But you do learn something.
But you do learn something. You
resistance.
But you do learn something. You learn
that
that you're
that you're more
that you're more than
that you're more than just
that you're more than just a
that you're more than just a physical
body
body resist.
that you're more than just a physical
body resist. Now,
body resist. Now, how
that you're more than just a physical
body resist. Now, how come
body resist. Now, how come your
that you're more than just a physical
body resist. Now, how come your level
body resist. Now, how come your level of
consciousness
consciousness doesn't
consciousness doesn't jump
consciousness doesn't jump when
consciousness doesn't jump when you
realize
realize that?
consciousness doesn't jump when you
realize that? Huh?
realize that? Huh? Why
consciousness doesn't jump when you
realize that? Huh? Why is
realize that? Huh? Why is that?
All
All of
All of a
All of a sudden,
where
where was
All of a sudden,
where was it?
where was it? I
All of a sudden,
where was it? I was
where was it? I was Oh,
All of a sudden,
where was it? I was Oh, I'll
where was it? I was Oh, I'll recall
All of a sudden,
where was it? I was Oh, I'll recall my
own
own experience.
own experience. You
own experience. You know,
own experience. You know, ser
own experience. You know, ser your
deathbed,
deathbed, severely
own experience. You know, ser your
deathbed, severely ill,
deathbed, severely ill, critically
own experience. You know, ser your
deathbed, severely ill, critically ill,
gravely
gravely ill,
never
never even
gravely ill,
never even heard
never even heard out
gravely ill,
never even heard out of
never even heard out of body
gravely ill,
never even heard out of body experience.
Next
Next thing
Next thing you
Next thing you know,
Next thing you know, you're
Next thing you know, you're 6
Next thing you know, you're 6 feet
Next thing you know, you're 6 feet in
the
the air,
Next thing you know, you're 6 feet in
the air, weightless,
the air, weightless, invisible.
Fantastic.
Fantastic. Free
Fantastic. Free as
Fantastic. Free as a
Fantastic. Free as a bird.
If
If you
Fantastic. Free as a bird.
If you think
If you think over
Fantastic. Free as a bird.
If you think over there,
If you think over there, you're
Fantastic. Free as a bird.
If you think over there, you're over
there.
there. You
there. You think
there. You think here,
there. You think here, you're
there. You think here, you're there.
Great.
Great. No
there. You think here, you're there.
Great. No time
Great. No time wasted
there. You think here, you're there.
Great. No time wasted in
Great. No time wasted in traveling.
Um,
Um, this
Um, this consciousness
Um, this consciousness advanced
Um, this consciousness advanced as
Um, this consciousness advanced as a
result
result of
Um, this consciousness advanced as a
result of that
result of that experience.
Um, this consciousness advanced as a
result of that experience. Resist.
result of that experience. Resist. No.
Why
Why not?
Why not? That's
Why not? That's curious.
Oh,
Oh, I
Why not? That's curious.
Oh, I see.
Oh, I see. The
Why not? That's curious.
Oh, I see. The mind
Oh, I see. The mind discards
Why not? That's curious.
Oh, I see. The mind discards it
Oh, I see. The mind discards it as
Why not? That's curious.
Oh, I see. The mind discards it as being
unreal.
unreal. Resist.
unreal. Resist. Oh,
unreal. Resist. Oh, I
unreal. Resist. Oh, I see.
unreal. Resist. Oh, I see. Okay.
unreal. Resist. Oh, I see. Okay. The
reason
reason we
unreal. Resist. Oh, I see. Okay. The
reason we don't
reason we don't really
unreal. Resist. Oh, I see. Okay. The
reason we don't really grow
reason we don't really grow from
unreal. Resist. Oh, I see. Okay. The
reason we don't really grow from it,
reason we don't really grow from it, the
the
the mind
the mind doesn't
the mind doesn't really
the mind doesn't really believe
the mind doesn't really believe it.
the mind doesn't really believe it. It
discards
discards it.
the mind doesn't really believe it. It
discards it. Even
discards it. Even when
the mind doesn't really believe it. It
discards it. Even when it's
discards it. Even when it's going
the mind doesn't really believe it. It
discards it. Even when it's going on,
you
you don't
you don't believe
you don't believe it.
Out
Out of
you don't believe it.
Out of body
Out of body is
you don't believe it.
Out of body is strange,
Out of body is strange, isn't
you don't believe it.
Out of body is strange, isn't it?
Out of body is strange, isn't it? Near
death
death is
death is something
death is something else.
death is something else. Again,
death is something else. Again, that's
transformative
transformative and
death is something else. Again, that's
transformative and the
transformative and the person's
death is something else. Again, that's
transformative and the person's level
transformative and the person's level of
consciousness
after
near-death
near-death experience
near-death experience shows
near-death experience shows rather
dramatic
dramatic increase.
near-death experience shows rather
dramatic increase. Many
dramatic increase. Many people's
near-death experience shows rather
dramatic increase. Many people's lives
changed
incredibly.
incredibly. There's
changed
incredibly. There's a
incredibly. There's a number
changed
incredibly. There's a number of
well-known
well-known authors
well-known authors who
well-known authors who had
well-known authors who had near-death
experiences
experiences described
well-known authors who had near-death
experiences described of
experiences described of total
transformation
transformation that
transformation that occurred
transformation that occurred to
transformation that occurred to them
transformation that occurred to them as
a
a result
transformation that occurred to them as
a result of
a result of those
transformation that occurred to them as
a result of those kinds
a result of those kinds of
transformation that occurred to them as
a result of those kinds of experiences.
And
And um
And um so
And um so that
And um so that which
And um so that which imitates
And um so that which imitates the
spiritual
spiritual uh
And um so that which imitates the
spiritual uh does
spiritual uh does not
And um so that which imitates the
spiritual uh does not show.
spiritual uh does not show. So
And um so that which imitates the
spiritual uh does not show. So that
which
which imitates
which imitates a
which imitates a miracle
which imitates a miracle the
which imitates a miracle the calibrated
consciousness
consciousness of
which imitates a miracle the calibrated
consciousness of it
consciousness of it is
which imitates a miracle the calibrated
consciousness of it is let's
consciousness of it is let's say
which imitates a miracle the calibrated
consciousness of it is let's say uh
consciousness of it is let's say uh 190.
very
very often
very often people
very often people want
very often people want to
very often people want to disprove
very often people want to disprove the
reality
reality of
very often people want to disprove the
reality of spirituality
are
are people
are people who
are people who hate
are people who hate God
are people who hate God and
are people who hate God and they
are people who hate God and they really
come
come from
are people who hate God and they really
come from very
come from very low
are people who hate God and they really
come from very low numbers
come from very low numbers and
are people who hate God and they really
come from very low numbers and um
come from very low numbers and um so
that
that which
that which imitates
that which imitates a
that which imitates a miracle
that which imitates a miracle doesn't
that which imitates a miracle doesn't ne
negate
negate the
that which imitates a miracle doesn't ne
negate the fact
negate the fact that
that which imitates a miracle doesn't ne
negate the fact that the
negate the fact that the miraculous
occurs
occurs not
occurs not only
occurs not only does
occurs not only does it
occurs not only does it occur
occurs not only does it occur but
occurs not only does it occur but it
occurs
very
very uh
very uh frequently
very uh frequently and
very uh frequently and commonly
it's
it's just
very uh frequently and commonly
it's just that
it's just that ordinary
very uh frequently and commonly
it's just that ordinary perception
doesn't
doesn't read
doesn't read it
doesn't read it because
doesn't read it because it's
doesn't read it because it's outside
doesn't read it because it's outside its
paradigm
paradigm of
doesn't read it because it's outside its
paradigm of reality
and
and I
and I used
and I used to
and I used to be
and I used to be the
and I used to be the in
and I used to be the in the
and I used to be the in the presence
and I used to be the in the presence of
the
the miraculous
and I used to be the in the presence of
the miraculous all
the miraculous all the
and I used to be the in the presence of
the miraculous all the time.
the miraculous all the time. There
and I used to be the in the presence of
the miraculous all the time. There was
the miraculous all the time. There was a
period
period of
period of time
period of time in
period of time in which
period of time in which the
period of time in which the miraculous
was
was continuous
period of time in which the miraculous
was continuous and
was continuous and people
period of time in which the miraculous
was continuous and people would
was continuous and people would sit
period of time in which the miraculous
was continuous and people would sit down
in
in that
in that field
in that field and
in that field and walk
in that field and walk uphill
in that field and walk uphill and
in that field and walk uphill and and
in that field and walk uphill and and um
and
and you
in that field and walk uphill and and um
and you would
and you would see
in that field and walk uphill and and um
and you would see a
and you would see a relative
uh
uh saying,
uh saying, "Well,
uh
uh saying, "Well, I
uh saying, "Well, I told
uh
uh saying, "Well, I told you
uh saying, "Well, I told you how
uh
uh saying, "Well, I told you how long
you
you didn't
you didn't need
you didn't need that
you didn't need that cane."
The
The lady
you didn't need that cane."
The lady could
The lady could now
you didn't need that cane."
The lady could now walk
The lady could now walk and
you didn't need that cane."
The lady could now walk and she
The lady could now walk and she couldn't
walk
walk before.
walk before. See,
walk before. See, but
walk before. See, but but
walk before. See, but but ordinary
consciousness
consciousness didn't
walk before. See, but but ordinary
consciousness didn't even
consciousness didn't even read
walk before. See, but but ordinary
consciousness didn't even read what
consciousness didn't even read what it
was.
was. This
was. This lady
was. This lady was
was. This lady was suddenly
was. This lady was suddenly able
was. This lady was suddenly able to
was. This lady was suddenly able to walk
and
and perfectly
was. This lady was suddenly able to walk
and perfectly fine.
and perfectly fine. you
was. This lady was suddenly able to walk
and perfectly fine. you know,
and perfectly fine. you know, you
was. This lady was suddenly able to walk
and perfectly fine. you know, you just
watch
watch you
watch you witness
watch you witness the
watch you witness the miraculous.
People
People that
watch you witness the miraculous.
People that that
People that that uh
watch you witness the miraculous.
People that that uh are
People that that uh are sort
watch you witness the miraculous.
People that that uh are sort of
People that that uh are sort of not
aligned
aligned with
aligned with God
aligned with God don't
aligned with God don't they
aligned with God don't they they
aligned with God don't they they they
don't
don't even
aligned with God don't they they they
don't even see
don't even see it.
aligned with God don't they they they
don't even see it. They
don't even see it. They don't
aligned with God don't they they they
don't even see it. They don't see
don't even see it. They don't see it
aligned with God don't they they they
don't even see it. They don't see it for
what
what it
what it is.
what it is. But
what it is. But anyway,
what it is. But anyway, there's
what it is. But anyway, there's a
what it is. But anyway, there's a lot
what it is. But anyway, there's a lot of
programs
programs on
what it is. But anyway, there's a lot of
programs on TV
programs on TV in
what it is. But anyway, there's a lot of
programs on TV in which
programs on TV in which u
what it is. But anyway, there's a lot of
programs on TV in which u professional
debunkers
debunkers love
debunkers love to
debunkers love to try
debunkers love to try to
debunkers love to try to disprove
debunkers love to try to disprove uh
debunkers love to try to disprove uh the
reality
reality of
debunkers love to try to disprove uh the
reality of spiritual
reality of spiritual phenomena.
I'm
I'm not
I'm not talking
I'm not talking about
I'm not talking about occult.
I'm not talking about occult. Occult
I'm not talking about occult. Occult is
something
something else.
I'm not talking about occult. Occult is
something else. And
something else. And uh
I'm not talking about occult. Occult is
something else. And uh generally
something else. And uh generally we
advise
advise people
advise people to
advise people to avoid
advise people to avoid the
advise people to avoid the supernatural,
the
the occult,
advise people to avoid the supernatural,
the occult, the
the occult, the weird,
advise people to avoid the supernatural,
the occult, the weird, the
the occult, the weird, the strange
advise people to avoid the supernatural,
the occult, the weird, the strange uh
channeling,
channeling, strange
channeling, strange chantings
channeling, strange chantings of
channeling, strange chantings of Baba
this
this and
channeling, strange chantings of Baba
this and Baba
this and Baba that
channeling, strange chantings of Baba
this and Baba that on
this and Baba that on the
channeling, strange chantings of Baba
this and Baba that on the other
this and Baba that on the other side.
And
And people
And people will
And people will do
And people will do all
And people will do all kinds
And people will do all kinds of
And people will do all kinds of astral
tricks.
tricks. It's
And people will do all kinds of astral
tricks. It's best
tricks. It's best to
And people will do all kinds of astral
tricks. It's best to avoid
tricks. It's best to avoid them
And people will do all kinds of astral
tricks. It's best to avoid them to
tricks. It's best to avoid them to stick
with
with that
with that which
with that which is
with that which is tried
with that which is tried and
with that which is tried and true.
Spiritual
Spiritual truth
with that which is tried and true.
Spiritual truth is
Spiritual truth is clear
with that which is tried and true.
Spiritual truth is clear and
Spiritual truth is clear and obvious.
You
You don't
You don't really
You don't really have
You don't really have to
You don't really have to study
You don't really have to study it.
You don't really have to study it. That
which
which is
Peace
Peace and
Peace and love
Peace and love committed
Peace and love committed to
Peace and love committed to truth,
integrity,
surrendering
surrendering all
surrendering all to
surrendering all to God
is
is the
surrendering all to God
is the same
is the same in
surrendering all to God
is the same in throughout
is the same in throughout all
surrendering all to God
is the same in throughout all time
is the same in throughout all time and
all
all religions
all religions and
all religions and nothing
all religions and nothing else
all religions and nothing else is
all religions and nothing else is really
needed.
All
All a
All a teacher
All a teacher can
All a teacher can do
All a teacher can do is
All a teacher can do is be
All a teacher can do is be like
All a teacher can do is be like a
All a teacher can do is be like a coach.
See
coach
coach to
coach to affirm
coach to affirm the
coach to affirm the validity
coach to affirm the validity of
coach to affirm the validity of the
teaching.
teaching. Anything
coach to affirm the validity of the
teaching. Anything that
teaching. Anything that varies
coach to affirm the validity of the
teaching. Anything that varies from
teaching. Anything that varies from that
is
is not
is not of
is not of God.
is not of God. Anything
is not of God. Anything that
is not of God. Anything that tells
is not of God. Anything that tells you
kill
kill infidels
is not of God. Anything that tells you
kill infidels for
kill infidels for God
is not of God. Anything that tells you
kill infidels for God is
kill infidels for God is not
is not of God. Anything that tells you
kill infidels for God is not of
kill infidels for God is not of God.
is not of God. Anything that tells you
kill infidels for God is not of God. Not
of
of that
of that other
of that other than
of that other than so
of that other than so besides
of that other than so besides that
of that other than so besides that you
don't
don't really
of that other than so besides that you
don't really to
don't really to know
of that other than so besides that you
don't really to know need
don't really to know need to
of that other than so besides that you
don't really to know need to really
don't really to know need to really know
anything.
uh
the
the false
the false teachers
the false teachers we've
the false teachers we've advised
the false teachers we've advised about
that
that too.
the false teachers we've advised about
that too. That's
that too. That's another
the false teachers we've advised about
that too. That's another responsibility
of
of a
of a teacher.
of a teacher. Two
of a teacher. Two teachers
of a teacher. Two teachers not
interested
interested in
of a teacher. Two teachers not
interested in money,
interested in money, position,
trappings,
trappings, ownership,
trappings, ownership, possessions,
organizations,
organizations, hierarchies,
trappings, ownership, possessions,
organizations, hierarchies, titles,
organizations,
treasuries,
the
the owning
the owning of
the owning of anything,
the owning of anything, the
the owning of anything, the possession
of
of anything,
the
the proclaiming
the proclaiming of
the proclaiming of anything.
the proclaiming of anything. There
the proclaiming of anything. There is
only
only the
the proclaiming of anything. There is
only the speaking
only the speaking of
the proclaiming of anything. There is
only the speaking of the
only the speaking of the truth
the proclaiming of anything. There is
only the speaking of the truth as
only the speaking of the truth as one
has
has come
has come to
has come to know
has come to know it
has come to know it through
has come to know it through one's
has come to know it through one's own
inner
inner experience.
to
to share
to share that
to share that which
to share that which has
to share that which has been
to share that which has been validated
through
one's
one's own
one's own consciousness.
Anything
Anything else
one's own consciousness.
Anything else is
Anything else is an
one's own consciousness.
Anything else is an artifice.
This
This willingness
This willingness to
This willingness to turn
This willingness to turn things
This willingness to turn things over
This willingness to turn things over to
God's
God's will
This willingness to turn things over to
God's will is
God's will is partly
This willingness to turn things over to
God's will is partly is
God's will is partly is a
This willingness to turn things over to
God's will is partly is a result
God's will is partly is a result you
This willingness to turn things over to
God's will is partly is a result you see
of
of your
of your own
of your own spiritual
of your own spiritual will.
of your own spiritual will. We're
of your own spiritual will. We're going
to
to stop
of your own spiritual will. We're going
to stop for
to stop for a
of your own spiritual will. We're going
to stop for a break
to stop for a break after
of your own spiritual will. We're going
to stop for a break after this.
to stop for a break after this. And
of your own spiritual will. We're going
to stop for a break after this. And we
described
described the
described the technique
described the technique where
described the technique where anything
and
and everything
described the technique where anything
and everything that
and everything that happens
described the technique where anything
and everything that happens no
and everything that happens no no
described the technique where anything
and everything that happens no no matter
what
what you
what you stop
what you stop resisting
what you stop resisting it
what you stop resisting it and
what you stop resisting it and you
surrender
surrender it
what you stop resisting it and you
surrender it to
surrender it to God.
what you stop resisting it and you
surrender it to God. The
surrender it to God. The news
what you stop resisting it and you
surrender it to God. The news says
surrender it to God. The news says we're
all
all going
all going to
all going to war.
all going to war. So
all going to war. So you
all going to war. So you surrender
all going to war. So you surrender it
all going to war. So you surrender it to
God.
God. No
all going to war. So you surrender it to
God. No God,
God. No God, we
all going to war. So you surrender it to
God. No God, we don't
God. No God, we don't want
all going to war. So you surrender it to
God. No God, we don't want war.
God. No God, we don't want war. Where's
my
my peace
my peace sign?
my peace sign? Mother,
get
get off
my peace sign? Mother,
get off it.
get off it. Without
my peace sign? Mother,
get off it. Without war,
get off it. Without war, how
my peace sign? Mother,
get off it. Without war, how are
get off it. Without war, how are people
ever
ever going
ever going to
ever going to get
ever going to get beyond
ever going to get beyond war?
ever going to get beyond war? The
ever going to get beyond war? The only
way
way to
ever going to get beyond war? The only
way to get
way to get beyond
ever going to get beyond war? The only
way to get beyond war
way to get beyond war is
ever going to get beyond war? The only
way to get beyond war is to
way to get beyond war is to get
ever going to get beyond war? The only
way to get beyond war is to get beyond
war.
You
You can't
war.
You can't just
You can't just do
war.
You can't just do it
You can't just do it out
war.
You can't just do it out of
You can't just do it out of a
war.
You can't just do it out of a textbook
in
in fourth
in fourth grade.
in fourth grade. War
in fourth grade. War is
in fourth grade. War is bad
in fourth grade. War is bad for
in fourth grade. War is bad for people.
That
That should
in fourth grade. War is bad for people.
That should end
That should end war,
in fourth grade. War is bad for people.
That should end war, shouldn't
That should end war, shouldn't it?
in fourth grade. War is bad for people.
That should end war, shouldn't it? If
that
that ended
that ended war,
that ended war, there
that ended war, there wouldn't
that ended war, there wouldn't be
that ended war, there wouldn't be any
war.
war. No,
that ended war, there wouldn't be any
war. No, people
war. No, people have
that ended war, there wouldn't be any
war. No, people have to
war. No, people have to go
that ended war, there wouldn't be any
war. No, people have to go through
war. No, people have to go through the
the
the gut-wrenching,
the gut-wrenching, ripping
the gut-wrenching, ripping experience
the gut-wrenching, ripping experience of
devastation.
What
What amazes
What amazes me
What amazes me is
What amazes me is the
What amazes me is the extent
What amazes me is the extent to
What amazes me is the extent to which
the
the ego
What amazes me is the extent to which
the ego has
the ego has to
What amazes me is the extent to which
the ego has to go
the ego has to go before
What amazes me is the extent to which
the ego has to go before it
the ego has to go before it relents.
It's
It's just
It's just amazing
It's just amazing the
It's just amazing the degree,
It's just amazing the degree, the
It's just amazing the degree, the extent
to
to which
It's just amazing the degree, the extent
to which the
to which the ego
It's just amazing the degree, the extent
to which the ego will
to which the ego will go,
It's just amazing the degree, the extent
to which the ego will go, the
to which the ego will go, the extremes,
barbaric,
barbaric, insane,
barbaric, insane, psychotic
barbaric, insane, psychotic degrees
before
before it
barbaric, insane, psychotic degrees
before it finally
before it finally lets
barbaric, insane, psychotic degrees
before it finally lets go
before it finally lets go of
barbaric, insane, psychotic degrees
before it finally lets go of a
before it finally lets go of a thing.
barbaric, insane, psychotic degrees
before it finally lets go of a thing. If
there's
there's anything
there's anything I'm
there's anything I'm dismayed
there's anything I'm dismayed about
there's anything I'm dismayed about the
human
human condition,
there's anything I'm dismayed about the
human condition, that
human condition, that is
there's anything I'm dismayed about the
human condition, that is what
human condition, that is what it
there's anything I'm dismayed about the
human condition, that is what it is.
human condition, that is what it is. I'm
dismayed
dismayed that
dismayed that it
dismayed that it takes
dismayed that it takes so
dismayed that it takes so much
dismayed that it takes so much to
dismayed that it takes so much to let
the
the to
dismayed that it takes so much to let
the to bring
the to bring the
dismayed that it takes so much to let
the to bring the ego
the to bring the ego to
dismayed that it takes so much to let
the to bring the ego to the
the to bring the ego to the level
dismayed that it takes so much to let
the to bring the ego to the level of
letting
letting go.
letting go. Why
letting go. Why does
letting go. Why does it
letting go. Why does it have
letting go. Why does it have to
letting go. Why does it have to be
letting go. Why does it have to be so
extreme?
That
That distresses
That distresses me
That distresses me still.
That distresses me still. So
That distresses me still. So that
That distresses me still. So that is
something
something I'll
That distresses me still. So that is
something I'll have
something I'll have to
That distresses me still. So that is
something I'll have to let
something I'll have to let go
That distresses me still. So that is
something I'll have to let go in
something I'll have to let go in myself.
That
That identification
That identification with
That identification with the
That identification with the human
condition.
Why
Why it
Why it should
Why it should go
Why it should go to
Why it should go to such
Why it should go to such extremes?
Why
Why does
Why it should go to such extremes?
Why does it
Why does it have
Why it should go to such extremes?
Why does it have to
Why does it have to go
Why it should go to such extremes?
Why does it have to go so
Why does it have to go so far?
Why it should go to such extremes?
Why does it have to go so far? Why
Why does it have to go so far? Why does
the
the pain
the pain have
the pain have to
the pain have to be
the pain have to be so
the pain have to be so bad?
the pain have to be so bad? Why
the pain have to be so bad? Why does
the pain have to be so bad? Why does it
have
have to
the pain have to be so bad? Why does it
have to reach?
have to reach? Why
the pain have to be so bad? Why does it
have to reach? Why does
have to reach? Why does agony
the pain have to be so bad? Why does it
have to reach? Why does agony have
have to reach? Why does agony have to
take
take you
take you to
take you to the
take you to the pit
take you to the pit beyond
take you to the pit beyond which
take you to the pit beyond which no
take you to the pit beyond which no more
agony
agony is
take you to the pit beyond which no more
agony is bearable
agony is bearable and
take you to the pit beyond which no more
agony is bearable and yet
agony is bearable and yet you
take you to the pit beyond which no more
agony is bearable and yet you have
agony is bearable and yet you have to
experience
experience more?
Why
Why is
experience more?
Why is it
Why is it so
experience more?
Why is it so extreme?
I
I don't
I don't know.
I don't know. I
I don't know. I asked
I don't know. I asked the
I don't know. I asked the question
today.
today. So
I don't know. I asked the question
today. So that's
today. So that's my
I don't know. I asked the question
today. So that's my question
today. So that's my question for
I don't know. I asked the question
today. So that's my question for the
day.
day. Why
day. Why does
day. Why does it
day. Why does it have
day. Why does it have to
day. Why does it have to be
day. Why does it have to be so
day. Why does it have to be so extreme?
Why
Why does
day. Why does it have to be so extreme?
Why does human
Why does human suffering
day. Why does it have to be so extreme?
Why does human suffering have
Why does human suffering have to
day. Why does it have to be so extreme?
Why does human suffering have to be
Why does human suffering have to be so
enormous?
Why
Why does
enormous?
Why does it
Why does it take
enormous?
Why does it take 70
Why does it take 70 million
enormous?
Why does it take 70 million people
ripped
ripped to
ripped to death
ripped to death by
ripped to death by bullets
ripped to death by bullets and
ripped to death by bullets and guns
ripped to death by bullets and guns and
savage
savage wounds
ripped to death by bullets and guns and
savage wounds and
savage wounds and their
ripped to death by bullets and guns and
savage wounds and their arms
savage wounds and their arms and
ripped to death by bullets and guns and
savage wounds and their arms and legs
being
being ripped
being ripped off
being ripped off and
being ripped off and exploded
being ripped off and exploded into
nothingness?
Not
Not once,
Not once, but
Not once, but over
Not once, but over and
Not once, but over and over
Not once, but over and over again.
Not once, but over and over again. 70
million
million in
Not once, but over and over again. 70
million in one
million in one war.
Not once, but over and over again. 70
million in one war. 20
million in one war. 20 years
Not once, but over and over again. 70
million in one war. 20 years later,
million in one war. 20 years later, you
got
got 70
got 70 million
got 70 million going
got 70 million going in
got 70 million going in another
got 70 million going in another war.
Every
Every 10
got 70 million going in another war.
Every 10 or
Every 10 or 20
got 70 million going in another war.
Every 10 or 20 years,
Every 10 or 20 years, another
got 70 million going in another war.
Every 10 or 20 years, another 10,
Every 10 or 20 years, another 10, 20,
30,
30, 50,
30, 50, 40,
30, 50, 40, 70
30, 50, 40, 70 million
30, 50, 40, 70 million people
30, 50, 40, 70 million people go.
30, 50, 40, 70 million people go. Why
does
does it
30, 50, 40, 70 million people go. Why
does it take
does it take such
30, 50, 40, 70 million people go. Why
does it take such an
does it take such an extreme?
30, 50, 40, 70 million people go. Why
does it take such an extreme? Why
does it take such an extreme? Why is
30, 50, 40, 70 million people go. Why
does it take such an extreme? Why is it
so
so severe?
What
What does
so severe?
What does it
What does it take
so severe?
What does it take for
What does it take for people
so severe?
What does it take for people to
What does it take for people to wake
so severe?
What does it take for people to wake up
and
and and
and and recognize
and and recognize a
and and recognize a megalomaniac
and and recognize a megalomaniac when
he's
he's staring
and and recognize a megalomaniac when
he's staring you
he's staring you right
and and recognize a megalomaniac when
he's staring you right in
he's staring you right in the
and and recognize a megalomaniac when
he's staring you right in the face
over
over and
over and over
over and over over
over and over over again?
over and over over again? Whole
over and over over again? Whole nations
march
to
to some
to some megalomaniac's
to some megalomaniac's maniac
to some megalomaniac's maniac ego
to some megalomaniac's maniac ego and
they
they don't
to some megalomaniac's maniac ego and
they don't recognize
they don't recognize it
to some megalomaniac's maniac ego and
they don't recognize it for
they don't recognize it for what
to some megalomaniac's maniac ego and
they don't recognize it for what it
they don't recognize it for what it is.
Why
Why is
Why is that?
It's
It's presented
Why is that?
It's presented to
It's presented to them
Why is that?
It's presented to them over
It's presented to them over and
Why is that?
It's presented to them over and over
again
again within
again within one
again within one lifetime.
again within one lifetime. They
again within one lifetime. They fall
again within one lifetime. They fall for
it
it one
again within one lifetime. They fall for
it one time,
it one time, 20
again within one lifetime. They fall for
it one time, 20 years
it one time, 20 years later
again within one lifetime. They fall for
it one time, 20 years later they
it one time, 20 years later they fall
for
for it
for it again.
for it again. 10
for it again. 10 years
for it again. 10 years later
for it again. 10 years later they
for it again. 10 years later they fall
for
for it
for it again. 10 years later they fall
for it again.
Innately,
Innately, innately
Innately, innately stupid.
Innately, innately stupid. Well,
Innately, innately stupid. Well, I
Innately, innately stupid. Well, I guess
we
we say
Innately, innately stupid. Well, I guess
we say the
we say the ego
Innately, innately stupid. Well, I guess
we say the ego is
we say the ego is innately
Innately, innately stupid. Well, I guess
we say the ego is innately stupid.
It
It really
It really is
It really is dumb,
It really is dumb, isn't
It really is dumb, isn't it?
It
It really
It really is dumb, isn't it?
It really is
It really is dumb.
So,
So, that's
So, that's the
So, that's the answer.
So, that's the answer. Thank
So, that's the answer. Thank you,
So, that's the answer. Thank you, Lord.
People
People are
So, that's the answer. Thank you, Lord.
People are just
People are just stupid.
So, that's the answer. Thank you, Lord.
People are just stupid. Oh,
People are just stupid. Oh, okay.
That's
That's true.
I
I guess
That's true.
I guess we
I guess we are
That's true.
I guess we are dumb
I guess we are dumb lord.
Well,
all
all right.
Well,
all right. So,
all right. So, that's
Well,
all right. So, that's why
all right. So, that's why the
Well,
all right. So, that's why the Buddha
said
said to
said to become
said to become enlightened
said to become enlightened so
said to become enlightened so that
you're
you're not
said to become enlightened so that
you're not caught.
you're not caught. Oh,
said to become enlightened so that
you're not caught. Oh, I
you're not caught. Oh, I see.
said to become enlightened so that
you're not caught. Oh, I see. Unless
you're not caught. Oh, I see. Unless you
grow,
grow, you
grow, you go
grow, you go around
grow, you go around and
grow, you go around and around
grow, you go around and around endlessly
in
in this
grow, you go around and around endlessly
in this karmic
in this karmic cycle.
grow, you go around and around endlessly
in this karmic cycle. Right.
in this karmic cycle. Right. Question
here
here is,
here is, if
here is, if you
here is, if you reach
here is, if you reach enlightenment,
here is, if you reach enlightenment, is
it
it true
here is, if you reach enlightenment, is
it true you
it true you don't
here is, if you reach enlightenment, is
it true you don't have
it true you don't have to
here is, if you reach enlightenment, is
it true you don't have to reincarnate?
As
As far
As far as
As far as I
As far as I know,
As far as I know, that's
As far as I know, that's true.
As far as I know, that's true. Yes.
As far as I know, that's true. Yes. If
you
you transcend
As far as I know, that's true. Yes. If
you transcend personal
you transcend personal karma,
As far as I know, that's true. Yes. If
you transcend personal karma, but
you transcend personal karma, but don't
forget
forget one
forget one does
forget one does not
forget one does not transcend
forget one does not transcend the
forget one does not transcend the karmic
reality
reality of
forget one does not transcend the karmic
reality of divinity.
That
That that
That that which
That that which is
That that which is God
That that which is God is
That that which is God is the
That that which is God is the totality
of
of all
That that which is God is the totality
of all that
of all that exists.
And
And you
And you may
And you may escape
And you may escape your
And you may escape your own
And you may escape your own personal
karma,
karma, go
And you may escape your own personal
karma, go into
karma, go into a
And you may escape your own personal
karma, go into a very
karma, go into a very neat
And you may escape your own personal
karma, go into a very neat place,
karma, go into a very neat place, but
you
you still
you still have
you still have not
you still have not escaped,
let's
let's say,
the
the reality.
the reality. The
the reality. The allness
the reality. The allness that
the reality. The allness that exists
is
is the
the reality. The allness that exists
is the karmic
is the karmic unity
the reality. The allness that exists
is the karmic unity of
is the karmic unity of God.
the reality. The allness that exists
is the karmic unity of God. So
is the karmic unity of God. So I
the reality. The allness that exists
is the karmic unity of God. So I told
you
you about
you about that
you about that luciferic
you about that luciferic trap
you about that luciferic trap that
you about that luciferic trap that you
hit
hit when
you about that luciferic trap that you
hit when you
hit when you get
you about that luciferic trap that you
hit when you get into
hit when you get into a
you about that luciferic trap that you
hit when you get into a very
hit when you get into a very high
you about that luciferic trap that you
hit when you get into a very high place
where
where you
where you know
where you know you're
where you know you're beyond
where you know you're beyond personal
karma.
And
And then
And then this
And then this luciferic
And then this luciferic knowingness
comes
comes to
And then this luciferic knowingness
comes to you.
comes to you. It's
And then this luciferic knowingness
comes to you. It's non-verbal.
Now
Now that
Now that you're
Now that you're beyond
Now that you're beyond personal
Now that you're beyond personal karma,
you
you know
Now that you're beyond personal karma,
you know there
you know there is
Now that you're beyond personal karma,
you know there is no
you know there is no god
Now that you're beyond personal karma,
you know there is no god to
you know there is no god to answer
Now that you're beyond personal karma,
you know there is no god to answer for.
answer
answer to.
answer to. There
answer to. There are
answer to. There are nothing
answer to. There are nothing and
answer to. There are nothing and no
answer to. There are nothing and no one
to
to answer
answer to. There are nothing and no one
to answer to
to answer to for
answer to. There are nothing and no one
to answer to for anything.
to answer to for anything. Nor
answer to. There are nothing and no one
to answer to for anything. Nor are
to answer to for anything. Nor are you
accountable
because
because there
accountable
because there is
because there is no
accountable
because there is no personal
because there is no personal self
accountable
because there is no personal self that
could
could be
could be accountable
on
on a
could be accountable
on a certain
on a certain level
could be accountable
on a certain level of
on a certain level of understanding.
That
That certainly
That certainly sounds
That certainly sounds true.
That certainly sounds true. If
That certainly sounds true. If there's
no
no personal
That certainly sounds true. If there's
no personal self,
no personal self, then
That certainly sounds true. If there's
no personal self, then what
no personal self, then what would
That certainly sounds true. If there's
no personal self, then what would be
accountable
accountable and
accountable and to
accountable and to whom?
when
when it's
accountable and to whom?
when it's free
when it's free of
accountable and to whom?
when it's free of all
when it's free of all accountability
and
and that
and that is
and that is the
and that is the luciferic
and that is the luciferic temptation
and that is the luciferic temptation at
that
that level
and that is the luciferic temptation at
that level about
that level about 840
and that is the luciferic temptation at
that level about 840 or
that level about 840 or something
own
own that
and
and you
own that
and you have
and you have unlimited
own that
and you have unlimited power
and you have unlimited power over
everyone
you
you have
everyone
you have unlimited
you have unlimited power
everyone
you have unlimited power over
you have unlimited power over the
everyone
you have unlimited power over the world
that's
that's the
that's the luciferic
that's the luciferic temptation
that's the luciferic temptation now
that's the luciferic temptation now that
you're
you're beyond
that's the luciferic temptation now that
you're beyond all
you're beyond all personal
that's the luciferic temptation now that
you're beyond all personal karma
you're beyond all personal karma and
accountability
accountability and
accountability and there
accountability and there is
accountability and there is no
accountability and there is no awful
accountability and there is no awful god
to
to punish
accountability and there is no awful god
to punish you
to punish you for
accountability and there is no awful god
to punish you for anything
to punish you for anything anyway
accountability and there is no awful god
to punish you for anything anyway that
was
was all
was all just
was all just an
was all just an imagination
was all just an imagination in
was all just an imagination in your
ego's
ego's brain
was all just an imagination in your
ego's brain which
ego's brain which you've
was all just an imagination in your
ego's brain which you've now
ego's brain which you've now let
was all just an imagination in your
ego's brain which you've now let go
ego's brain which you've now let go of.
All
All power
All power is
All power is yours.
That's
That's the
All power is yours.
That's the luciferic
That's the luciferic temptation.
And
And you're
And you're all
And you're all destined
And you're all destined for
And you're all destined for the
ultimate.
ultimate. So
And you're all destined for the
ultimate. So it'll
ultimate. So it'll come
And you're all destined for the
ultimate. So it'll come to
ultimate. So it'll come to you
And you're all destined for the
ultimate. So it'll come to you too.
Don't
Don't say
Don't say I
Don't say I didn't
Don't say I didn't warn
Don't say I didn't warn you.
Hey,
Hey, I
Don't say I didn't warn you.
Hey, I want
Hey, I want my
Don't say I didn't warn you.
Hey, I want my money
Hey, I want my money back.
Don't say I didn't warn you.
Hey, I want my money back. You
Hey, I want my money back. You didn't
tell
tell me
tell me about
tell me about that.
tell me about that. I'll
tell me about that. I'll tell
tell me about that. I'll tell you
tell me about that. I'll tell you now.
It's
It's interesting.
tell me about that. I'll tell you now.
It's interesting. But
It's interesting. But the
tell me about that. I'll tell you now.
It's interesting. But the truth
It's interesting. But the truth that
you've
you've heard
you've heard from
you've heard from gurus
you've heard from gurus Krishna
you've heard from gurus Krishna or
whoever
walks
walks into
walks into that
walks into that space
walks into that space there's
walks into that space there's a
knowingness
knowingness not
walks into that space there's a
knowingness not not
knowingness not not a
walks into that space there's a
knowingness not not a voice
knowingness not not a voice no
walks into that space there's a
knowingness not not a voice no script
nothing
nothing there's
nothing there's a
nothing there's a knowingness
nothing there's a knowingness that
nothing there's a knowingness that that
temptation
temptation is
nothing there's a knowingness that that
temptation is an
temptation is an error
nothing there's a knowingness that that
temptation is an error it's
temptation is an error it's an
nothing there's a knowingness that that
temptation is an error it's an error
temptation is an error it's an error of
context
context at
context at the
context at the time
context at the time you're
context at the time you're not
consciously
consciously aware
context at the time you're not
consciously aware of
consciously aware of what
context at the time you're not
consciously aware of what the
consciously aware of what the error
context at the time you're not
consciously aware of what the error is
but
but there
but there is
but there is a
but there is a refusal
but there is a refusal there's
but there is a refusal there's a
but there is a refusal there's a refusal
and
and then
but there is a refusal there's a refusal
and then one
and then one passes
but there is a refusal there's a refusal
and then one passes those
and then one passes those gates
but there is a refusal there's a refusal
and then one passes those gates So
and then one passes those gates So the
levels
levels that
levels that we
levels that we see
levels that we see on
levels that we see on the
levels that we see on the board
levels that we see on the board of
levels that we see on the board of the
higher
higher levels
levels that we see on the board of the
higher levels are
higher levels are guarded
levels that we see on the board of the
higher levels are guarded by
higher levels are guarded by gates
levels that we see on the board of the
higher levels are guarded by gates and
each
each gate
each gate there's
each gate there's a
each gate there's a question
and
and so
each gate there's a question
and so I
and so I want
each gate there's a question
and so I want everybody
and so I want everybody to
each gate there's a question
and so I want everybody to know
and so I want everybody to know the
right
right answers.
God
God looks
right answers.
God looks at
God looks at your
right answers.
God looks at your report
God looks at your report card
right answers.
God looks at your report card and
God looks at your report card and he
says
says you
says you got
says you got that
says you got that one
says you got that one right.
Power
Power over
says you got that one right.
Power over everybody.
Power over everybody. That's
says you got that one right.
Power over everybody. That's a
Power over everybody. That's a sucker's
game.
Oh
Oh lordy.
Um,
Um, some
Um, some of
Um, some of these
Um, some of these things
Um, some of these things are
Um, some of these things are beyond
Um, some of these things are beyond me.
It's
It's just
Um, some of these things are beyond me.
It's just that
It's just that they're
Um, some of these things are beyond me.
It's just that they're two
It's just that they're two circum
religion
religion is
religion is a
religion is a fascinating
religion is a fascinating subject
religion is a fascinating subject and
religion is a fascinating subject and of
course
course I
religion is a fascinating subject and of
course I look
course I look into
religion is a fascinating subject and of
course I look into various
course I look into various aspects
religion is a fascinating subject and of
course I look into various aspects of
course I look into various aspects of it
in
in the
in the study
in the study of
in the study of consciousness
in the study of consciousness itself
in the study of consciousness itself how
it
it evolved
in the study of consciousness itself how
it evolved in
it evolved in the
in the study of consciousness itself how
it evolved in the form
it evolved in the form of
in the study of consciousness itself how
it evolved in the form of religion
it evolved in the form of religion and
the
the difficulties
the difficulties that
the difficulties that religions
the difficulties that religions present.
I
I think
the difficulties that religions present.
I think the
I think the purest
the difficulties that religions present.
I think the purest purest
I think the purest purest the
the difficulties that religions present.
I think the purest purest the purest
spiritual
spiritual pathway
spiritual pathway is
spiritual pathway is the
spiritual pathway is the fastest
spiritual pathway is the fastest way
spiritual pathway is the fastest way to
God
and
and religions
and religions can
and religions can offer
and religions can offer a
and religions can offer a great
and religions can offer a great deal
and religions can offer a great deal of
help
help along
and religions can offer a great deal of
help along the
help along the way.
and religions can offer a great deal of
help along the way. That
help along the way. That which
and religions can offer a great deal of
help along the way. That which is
positive
positive about
positive about the
positive about the religion,
positive about the religion, the
fellowship,
the
the beauty,
um
um the
the beauty,
um the love,
um the love, the
the beauty,
um the love, the lovingness
um the love, the lovingness of
the beauty,
um the love, the lovingness of the
group,
group, the
group, the integrity
group, the integrity of
group, the integrity of the
group, the integrity of the teacher
and
and I
group, the integrity of the teacher
and I myself
and I myself love
group, the integrity of the teacher
and I myself love going
and I myself love going to
group, the integrity of the teacher
and I myself love going to church.
We
We say
We say when
We say when a
We say when a person
declares
declares a
We say when a person
declares a spiritual
declares a spiritual intention,
We say when a person
declares a spiritual intention, is
declares a spiritual intention, is there
a
a counterforce?
a counterforce? And
a counterforce? And then
a counterforce? And then we'll
a counterforce? And then we'll stop
after
after this
a counterforce? And then we'll stop
after this and
after this and take
a counterforce? And then we'll stop
after this and take a
after this and take a break
a counterforce? And then we'll stop
after this and take a break and
after this and take a break and then
we'll
we'll finish
we'll finish up
we'll finish up uh
we'll finish up uh after
we'll finish up uh after a
we'll finish up uh after a break.
we'll finish up uh after a break. Is
there
there a
we'll finish up uh after a break. Is
there a counter
there a counter force?
we'll finish up uh after a break. Is
there a counter force? I'm
there a counter force? I'm glad
we'll finish up uh after a break. Is
there a counter force? I'm glad you
asked
asked that.
asked that. Yes,
asked that. Yes, there
asked that. Yes, there is
asked that. Yes, there is a
counterforce.
There
There is
There is a
There is a counter
There is a counter force.
There is a counter force. Um,
and
and it's
There is a counter force. Um,
and it's imperative
and it's imperative to
There is a counter force. Um,
and it's imperative to discover
and it's imperative to discover what
There is a counter force. Um,
and it's imperative to discover what is
the
the counterforce.
You
You the
the counterforce.
You the counterforce
You the counterforce can
the counterforce.
You the counterforce can be
You the counterforce can be quite
operative,
operative, quite
operative, quite effective,
operative, quite effective, and
operative, quite effective, and yet
operative, quite effective, and yet in
and
and of
operative, quite effective, and yet in
and of itself
and of itself be
operative, quite effective, and yet in
and of itself be a
and of itself be a snap
operative, quite effective, and yet in
and of itself be a snap to
and of itself be a snap to let
operative, quite effective, and yet in
and of itself be a snap to let go
and of itself be a snap to let go of
once
once you
once you find
once you find it.
You
You can
once you find it.
You can hold
You can hold the
once you find it.
You can hold the back
You can hold the back a
once you find it.
You can hold the back a whole
locomotive,
locomotive, you
locomotive, you know,
locomotive, you know, with
locomotive, you know, with your
locomotive, you know, with your finger
on
on this
locomotive, you know, with your finger
on this button
on this button here.
4,000
4,000 tons
4,000 tons of
4,000 tons of locomotive
4,000 tons of locomotive can't
4,000 tons of locomotive can't move.
4,000 tons of locomotive can't move. One
little
little finger,
4,000 tons of locomotive can't move. One
little finger, half
little finger, half an
4,000 tons of locomotive can't move. One
little finger, half an ounce.
little finger, half an ounce. Locomotive
can't
can't move.
Immobilize
Immobilize the
can't move.
Immobilize the whole
Immobilize the whole steam
can't move.
Immobilize the whole steam engine
Immobilize the whole steam engine with
one
one little
one little finger.
So
So that's
one little finger.
So that's not
So that's not power.
one little finger.
So that's not power. You
So that's not power. You see?
I
I mean,
I mean, that's
I mean, that's not
I mean, that's not force.
It's
It's the
I mean, that's not force.
It's the the
It's the the knowingness.
I mean, that's not force.
It's the the knowingness. So
It's the the knowingness. So you
I mean, that's not force.
It's the the knowingness. So you may
discover
discover something
discover something in
discover something in yourself
discover something in yourself that's
really
really driving
discover something in yourself that's
really driving you
really driving you crazy
discover something in yourself that's
really driving you crazy and
really driving you crazy and it's
discover something in yourself that's
really driving you crazy and it's really
countered
countered by
countered by a
countered by a very
countered by a very small
um
um understanding
countered by a very small
um understanding that
um understanding that little
countered by a very small
um understanding that little subtle
understanding.
understanding. Once
understanding. Once you
understanding. Once you get
understanding. Once you get that
understanding. Once you get that the
whole
whole thing
understanding. Once you get that the
whole thing clears
whole thing clears away
understanding. Once you get that the
whole thing clears away of
whole thing clears away of its
understanding. Once you get that the
whole thing clears away of its own.
whole thing clears away of its own. So
don't
don't be
don't be impressed
don't be impressed by
don't be impressed by how
don't be impressed by how difficult
don't be impressed by how difficult the
problem
problem seems
don't be impressed by how difficult the
problem seems to
problem seems to be
don't be impressed by how difficult the
problem seems to be because
problem seems to be because its
don't be impressed by how difficult the
problem seems to be because its answer
is
is usually
is usually very
is usually very simple.
the
the light
is usually very simple.
the light switch
the light switch is
is usually very simple.
the light switch is on
the light switch is on this
is usually very simple.
the light switch is on this side,
the light switch is on this side, not
that
that side.
that side. You
that side. You go,
that side. You go, "Oh,
that's
that's all
that side. You go, "Oh,
that's all it
that's all it was."
that side. You go, "Oh,
that's all it was." Many
that's all it was." Many of
that side. You go, "Oh,
that's all it was." Many of the
that's all it was." Many of the major
ones
ones that
ones that I
ones that I could
ones that I could bypass
ones that I could bypass in
ones that I could bypass in my
ones that I could bypass in my life
ones that I could bypass in my life were
really
really that
ones that I could bypass in my life were
really that simple.
really that simple. But
ones that I could bypass in my life were
really that simple. But what
really that simple. But what they
depended
depended on
depended on was
depended on was a
depended on was a willingness
depended on was a willingness to
depended on was a willingness to trust.
A
A willingness
depended on was a willingness to trust.
A willingness to
A willingness to trust,
depended on was a willingness to trust.
A willingness to trust, to
A willingness to trust, to let
depended on was a willingness to trust.
A willingness to trust, to let go
A willingness to trust, to let go of
what
what you
what you think
what you think you've
what you think you've got
what you think you've got for
what you think you've got for what
you're
you're told
what you think you've got for what
you're told will
you're told will work.
what you think you've got for what
you're told will work. You
you're told will work. You see,
what you think you've got for what
you're told will work. You see, so
there's
there's a
there's a certain
there's a certain amount
there's a certain amount of
there's a certain amount of trust
there's a certain amount of trust in
letting
letting go.
there's a certain amount of trust in
letting go. But
letting go. But you're
there's a certain amount of trust in
letting go. But you're right.
letting go. But you're right. Whatever
commitment
commitment there
commitment there is
commitment there is to
commitment there is to move
commitment there is to move in
commitment there is to move in this
direction.
direction. It
commitment there is to move in this
direction. It does
direction. It does tend
commitment there is to move in this
direction. It does tend to
direction. It does tend to set
commitment there is to move in this
direction. It does tend to set up.
direction. It does tend to set up. We
commitment there is to move in this
direction. It does tend to set up. We we
tried
tried to
tried to cover
tried to cover that
tried to cover that in
tried to cover that in the
tried to cover that in the when
tried to cover that in the when we
covered
covered the
tried to cover that in the when we
covered the structure
covered the structure of
tried to cover that in the when we
covered the structure of the
covered the structure of the ego
tried to cover that in the when we
covered the structure of the ego when
covered the structure of the ego when we
talked
talked about
talked about the
talked about the alternative
alternatives
alternatives and
talked about the alternative
alternatives and the
alternatives and the contraries
talked about the alternative
alternatives and the contraries and
alternatives and the contraries and the
opposites
that
that within
opposites
that within yourself
that within yourself there
opposites
that within yourself there things
that within yourself there things are
set
set up
set up as
set up as opposites.
That's
That's why
set up as opposites.
That's why people
That's why people feel
set up as opposites.
That's why people feel like
That's why people feel like they
set up as opposites.
That's why people feel like they may
That's why people feel like they may I
have
have a
have a lot
have a lot of
have a lot of patients.
have a lot of patients. I'm
have a lot of patients. I'm afraid
have a lot of patients. I'm afraid that
they
they may
have a lot of patients. I'm afraid that
they may burst
they may burst out
have a lot of patients. I'm afraid that
they may burst out in
they may burst out in the
have a lot of patients. I'm afraid that
they may burst out in the middle
they may burst out in the middle of
church
church with
church with a
church with a curse
church with a curse or
church with a curse or a
church with a curse or a vulgar
church with a curse or a vulgar word.
That's
That's a
church with a curse or a vulgar word.
That's a very
That's a very frequent
church with a curse or a vulgar word.
That's a very frequent obsession
That's a very frequent obsession with
obsessives.
obsessives. They're
obsessives. They're afraid
obsessives. They're afraid that
obsessives. They're afraid that in
church
church they're
obsessives. They're afraid that in
church they're going
church they're going to
obsessives. They're afraid that in
church they're going to suddenly
church they're going to suddenly blurt
out
out a
out a four-letter
out a four-letter word
out a four-letter word right
out a four-letter word right in
out a four-letter word right in the
middle
middle of
out a four-letter word right in the
middle of mass.
So
So that
So that which
So that which is
So that which is holy
So that which is holy and
So that which is holy and sacred
So that which is holy and sacred then
brings
brings forward
So that which is holy and sacred then
brings forward this
brings forward this opposite
So that which is holy and sacred then
brings forward this opposite of
brings forward this opposite of that
which
which is
anti-sacred
anti-sacred or
which is
anti-sacred or whatever
anti-sacred or whatever you
which is
anti-sacred or whatever you would
anti-sacred or whatever you would call
it,
it, a
it, a blasphemy
it, a blasphemy or
it, a blasphemy or something.
it, a blasphemy or something. They'll
suddenly
suddenly blurt
it, a blasphemy or something. They'll
suddenly blurt out
suddenly blurt out something
it, a blasphemy or something. They'll
suddenly blurt out something horrible
suddenly blurt out something horrible in
the
the middle
the middle of
the middle of church.
So
So I
the middle of church.
So I suppose
So I suppose we
the middle of church.
So I suppose we should
So I suppose we should have
the middle of church.
So I suppose we should have a
So I suppose we should have a special
service
service for
service for them
service for them some
service for them some Sunday
service for them some Sunday morning
in
in which
service for them some Sunday morning
in which they
in which they are
service for them some Sunday morning
in which they are free
in which they are free to
service for them some Sunday morning
in which they are free to express
themselves
themselves and
themselves and we
themselves and we will
themselves and we will all
themselves and we will all clap
themselves and we will all clap and
parade
parade and
themselves and we will all clap and
parade and thank
parade and thank them
themselves and we will all clap and
parade and thank them for
parade and thank them for their
themselves and we will all clap and
parade and thank them for their honesty
and
and forthrightness
and forthrightness and
and forthrightness and the
and forthrightness and the willingness
to
to share.
So
So we'll
So we'll take
So we'll take a
So we'll take a break
So we'll take a break and
So we'll take a break and then
So we'll take a break and then we'll
conclude
conclude with
So we'll take a break and then we'll
conclude with some
conclude with some more
So we'll take a break and then we'll
conclude with some more questions
afterwards.
Yes,
Yes, without
afterwards.
Yes, without love,
Yes, without love, where
afterwards.
Yes, without love, where would
Yes, without love, where would we
afterwards.
Yes, without love, where would we be?
Yes, without love, where would we be? At
the
the bottom
the bottom of
the bottom of the
the bottom of the sea,
it
it takes,
the bottom of the sea,
it takes, you
it takes, you know,
the bottom of the sea,
it takes, you know, a
it takes, you know, a whole
the bottom of the sea,
it takes, you know, a whole slew
it takes, you know, a whole slew of
people
people to
people to make
people to make these
people to make these events
people to make these events happen.
We
We keep
people to make these events happen.
We keep them
We keep them secret.
people to make these events happen.
We keep them secret. However,
such
such pearls
such pearls are
such pearls are hard
such pearls are hard to
such pearls are hard to find.
such pearls are hard to find. We
such pearls are hard to find. We will
not
not reveal
such pearls are hard to find. We will
not reveal them
not reveal them until
such pearls are hard to find. We will
not reveal them until the
not reveal them until the last
such pearls are hard to find. We will
not reveal them until the last lecture.
But
But it
But it takes
But it takes 12
But it takes 12 or
But it takes 12 or 15
But it takes 12 or 15 people
But it takes 12 or 15 people working
around
around the
But it takes 12 or 15 people working
around the clock.
around the clock. I
But it takes 12 or 15 people working
around the clock. I mean,
around the clock. I mean, enormous
amount
amount of
amount of energy
amount of energy and
amount of energy and work
amount of energy and work to
amount of energy and work to bring
together
together the
amount of energy and work to bring
together the communications
together the communications from
amount of energy and work to bring
together the communications from so
together the communications from so many
people
to
to try
people
to try to
to try to put
people
to try to put what
to try to put what we
people
to try to put what we say
to try to put what we say into
people
to try to put what we say into a
to try to put what we say into a form
available
available to
available to others,
distribute
distribute them
available to others,
distribute them around
distribute them around the
available to others,
distribute them around the world,
distribute them around the world, and
it's
it's a
it's a great
it's a great deal
it's a great deal of
it's a great deal of work
it's a great deal of work and
it's a great deal of work and energy.
And
And uh,
it's a great deal of work and energy.
And uh, as
And uh, as I
it's a great deal of work and energy.
And uh, as I say,
And uh, as I say, I'm
it's a great deal of work and energy.
And uh, as I say, I'm going
And uh, as I say, I'm going to
it's a great deal of work and energy.
And uh, as I say, I'm going to keep
And uh, as I say, I'm going to keep them
secret
secret until
secret until the
secret until the last
secret until the last session.
Uh
Uh I
secret until the last session.
Uh I wanted
Uh I wanted to
secret until the last session.
Uh I wanted to say
Uh I wanted to say a
secret until the last session.
Uh I wanted to say a few
Uh I wanted to say a few things
secret until the last session.
Uh I wanted to say a few things about
kinesiology
kinesiology itself
kinesiology itself not
kinesiology itself not to
kinesiology itself not to get
kinesiology itself not to get carried
away
away with
kinesiology itself not to get carried
away with it
away with it you
kinesiology itself not to get carried
away with it you know
away with it you know kinesiology
kinesiology itself not to get carried
away with it you know kinesiology is
away with it you know kinesiology is a
tool
tool it's
tool it's useful
tool it's useful thing
tool it's useful thing and
tool it's useful thing and uh
tool it's useful thing and uh a
tool it's useful thing and uh a lot
tool it's useful thing and uh a lot of
times
times we
tool it's useful thing and uh a lot of
times we use
times we use it
tool it's useful thing and uh a lot of
times we use it more
times we use it more for
tool it's useful thing and uh a lot of
times we use it more for curiosity
times we use it more for curiosity than
for
for you
for you know
for you know anything
for you know anything really
for you know anything really genuine
u
you
you know
you know people
you know people ask
you know people ask about
you know people ask about other
you know people ask about other realms
and
and all
you know people ask about other realms
and all I
and all I mean
you know people ask about other realms
and all I mean it's
and all I mean it's got
you know people ask about other realms
and all I mean it's got nothing
and all I mean it's got nothing to
you know people ask about other realms
and all I mean it's got nothing to do
with
with your
with your enlightenment
with your enlightenment you
with your enlightenment you know what
with your enlightenment you know what I
mean
mean it's
with your enlightenment you know what I
mean it's just
mean it's just spiritual
with your enlightenment you know what I
mean it's just spiritual wandering
mean it's just spiritual wandering you
know
know and
know and um
know and um so
know and um so you
know and um so you stick
know and um so you stick to
know and um so you stick to your
know and um so you stick to your own
know and um so you stick to your own uh
straightforwardness.
All
All that
All that you
All that you know
All that you know has
All that you know has already
All that you know has already been
spoken
spoken and
All that you know has already been
spoken and revealed.
spoken and revealed. It
All that you know has already been
spoken and revealed. It hasn't
spoken and revealed. It hasn't changed
since
it
it hasn't
since
it hasn't changed
it hasn't changed for
since
it hasn't changed for thousands
it hasn't changed for thousands of
years.
That
That which
years.
That which was
That which was said
years.
That which was said today,
That which was said today, that
years.
That which was said today, that which
Christ
Christ taught,
Christ taught, they're
Christ taught, they're all
Christ taught, they're all the
Christ taught, they're all the same.
Because
Because anybody
Christ taught, they're all the same.
Because anybody who's
Because anybody who's ever
Christ taught, they're all the same.
Because anybody who's ever experienced
the
the truth,
the truth, it
the truth, it always
the truth, it always comes
the truth, it always comes back
the truth, it always comes back forth
exactly
exactly the
the truth, it always comes back forth
exactly the same
exactly the same because
the truth, it always comes back forth
exactly the same because there
exactly the same because there is
the truth, it always comes back forth
exactly the same because there is only
one
one truth.
one truth. and
one truth. and unmbellished
one truth. and unmbellished by
thinking
thinking this
one truth. and unmbellished by
thinking this the
thinking this the experience
one truth. and unmbellished by
thinking this the experience is
thinking this the experience is always
the
the same.
the same. It
the same. It manifests
the same. It manifests itself
the same. It manifests itself in
the same. It manifests itself in the
same
same way.
the same. It manifests itself in the
same way. It
same way. It speaks
the same. It manifests itself in the
same way. It speaks in
same way. It speaks in the
the same. It manifests itself in the
same way. It speaks in the same
same way. It speaks in the same way
the same. It manifests itself in the
same way. It speaks in the same way and
one
one can
one can tell
one can tell at
one can tell at a
one can tell at a glance
one can tell at a glance at
one can tell at a glance at a
one can tell at a glance at a sentence
or
or two
one can tell at a glance at a sentence
or two by
or two by of
one can tell at a glance at a sentence
or two by of a
or two by of a book
one can tell at a glance at a sentence
or two by of a book written
or two by of a book written by
one can tell at a glance at a sentence
or two by of a book written by somebody
whe
whe they've
whe they've experienced
whe they've experienced it
whe they've experienced it or
whe they've experienced it or not.
whe they've experienced it or not. It's
just
just in
whe they've experienced it or not. It's
just in the
just in the energy
whe they've experienced it or not. It's
just in the energy of
just in the energy of the
whe they've experienced it or not. It's
just in the energy of the sentence
itself.
itself. It's
itself. It's a
itself. It's a way
itself. It's a way of
itself. It's a way of being
itself. It's a way of being with
itself. It's a way of being with it.
There's
There's a
itself. It's a way of being with it.
There's a conviction
There's a conviction that
itself. It's a way of being with it.
There's a conviction that comes
There's a conviction that comes only
from
from the
from the validity
from the validity of
from the validity of the
from the validity of the experience
itself.
So
So the
So the ultimate
So the ultimate truth
So the ultimate truth is
So the ultimate truth is the
So the ultimate truth is the ultimate
beyond
beyond even
So the ultimate truth is the ultimate
beyond even experiencing.
We
We said
We said that
We said that there's
We said that there's thinkingness.
There's
There's that
We said that there's thinkingness.
There's that which
There's that which witnesses
We said that there's thinkingness.
There's that which witnesses the
thinkingness.
thinkingness. There's
thinkingness. There's what
thinkingness. There's what that
thinkingness. There's what that which
experiences
experiences the
thinkingness. There's what that which
experiences the witnessing
experiences the witnessing of
thinkingness. There's what that which
experiences the witnessing of the
thinkingness
thinkingness until
thinkingness until finally
thinkingness until finally one
thinkingness until finally one gets
thinkingness until finally one gets to
the
the substrate
which
which is
which is consciousness
which is consciousness itself.
And
And then
which is consciousness itself.
And then if
And then if karmically
which is consciousness itself.
And then if karmically destined,
And then if karmically destined, one
goes
goes even
goes even beyond
goes even beyond consciousness
goes even beyond consciousness itself.
Out
Out of
goes even beyond consciousness itself.
Out of that
Out of that which
goes even beyond consciousness itself.
Out of that which you
Out of that which you are
goes even beyond consciousness itself.
Out of that which you are arises
consciousness.
So
So the
consciousness.
So the truth,
So the truth, the
consciousness.
So the truth, the absolute
So the truth, the absolute ultimate
truth
truth of
truth of that
truth of that which
truth of that which you
truth of that which you are
truth of that which you are is
truth of that which you are is beyond
even
even consciousness
truth of that which you are is beyond
even consciousness itself.
So
So there's
So there's no
So there's no point
So there's no point to
So there's no point to getting
So there's no point to getting wrapped
up
up in
So there's no point to getting wrapped
up in kinesiology
up in kinesiology and
So there's no point to getting wrapped
up in kinesiology and making
up in kinesiology and making it
So there's no point to getting wrapped
up in kinesiology and making it a
up in kinesiology and making it a new
obsess
obsess obsessive
obsess obsessive compulsive
obsess obsessive compulsive device
obsess obsessive compulsive device to
avoid
avoid reaching
obsess obsessive compulsive device to
avoid reaching enlightenment.
You
You don't
You don't have
You don't have to
You don't have to calibrate
You don't have to calibrate everything
on
on the
You don't have to calibrate everything
on the planet.
on the planet. It
You don't have to calibrate everything
on the planet. It is
on the planet. It is fun
You don't have to calibrate everything
on the planet. It is fun however
on the planet. It is fun however and
You don't have to calibrate everything
on the planet. It is fun however and of
course
course we
course we did
course we did it
course we did it already.
course we did it already. We
course we did it already. We did
thousands
thousands and
course we did it already. We did
thousands and we
thousands and we routinely
course we did it already. We did
thousands and we routinely do
thousands and we routinely do a
course we did it already. We did
thousands and we routinely do a thousand
or
or two
or two two
or two two a
or two two a year
or two two a year just
or two two a year just routinely
or two two a year just routinely just
walking
walking through
or two two a year just routinely just
walking through the
walking through the house
or two two a year just routinely just
walking through the house various
walking through the house various things
arise.
arise. partly
arise. partly because
arise. partly because we
arise. partly because we get
arise. partly because we get such
arise. partly because we get such a
arise. partly because we get such a an
enormous
enormous amount
arise. partly because we get such a an
enormous amount of
enormous amount of communication
arise. partly because we get such a an
enormous amount of communication from
all
all over
all over you
all over you know
all over you know all
all over you know all different
countries
countries around
all over you know all different
countries around the
countries around the clock
all over you know all different
countries around the clock all
countries around the clock all different
propositions
propositions questions
um
um would
propositions questions
um would you
um would you go
propositions questions
um would you go here
um would you go here do
propositions questions
um would you go here do this
um would you go here do this etc.
propositions questions
um would you go here do this etc. So
the
the difficulty
the difficulty with
the difficulty with physicality
the difficulty with physicality is
the difficulty with physicality is um
that
that you're
the difficulty with physicality is um
that you're limited
that you're limited to
the difficulty with physicality is um
that you're limited to um
that you're limited to um the
temporality
temporality of
temporality of here
temporality of here and
temporality of here and now.
temporality of here and now. You
temporality of here and now. You see
uh
uh with
temporality of here and now. You see
uh with the
uh with the physical
temporality of here and now. You see
uh with the physical self.
uh with the physical self. Therefore
temporality of here and now. You see
uh with the physical self. Therefore I
never
never like
never like the
never like the physical
never like the physical self
never like the physical self much
because
because it's
never like the physical self much
because it's an
because it's an impediment.
never like the physical self much
because it's an impediment. It's
because it's an impediment. It's always
in
in the
in the way.
in the way. When
in the way. When you
in the way. When you want
in the way. When you want to
in the way. When you want to go
someplace
someplace or
in the way. When you want to go
someplace or do
someplace or do something,
in the way. When you want to go
someplace or do something, you
someplace or do something, you got
in the way. When you want to go
someplace or do something, you got to
drag
drag this
drag this around
drag this around and
drag this around and that
drag this around and that can
drag this around and that can take
drag this around and that can take hours
and
and days
drag this around and that can take hours
and days and
and days and it's
drag this around and that can take hours
and days and it's a
and days and it's a drag.
So
So I
So I just
So I just wanted
So I just wanted to
So I just wanted to say
So I just wanted to say don't
So I just wanted to say don't make
kinesiology
kinesiology itself
So I just wanted to say don't make
kinesiology itself an
kinesiology itself an obsession
So I just wanted to say don't make
kinesiology itself an obsession or
kinesiology itself an obsession or a
compulsion.
That
That which
compulsion.
That which is
That which is necessary
compulsion.
That which is necessary to
That which is necessary to know
compulsion.
That which is necessary to know has
already
already been
already been spoken,
already been spoken, has
already been spoken, has already
already been spoken, has already been
shared,
shared, has
already been spoken, has already been
shared, has already
shared, has already been
already been spoken, has already been
shared, has already been taught.
shared, has already been taught. It's
the
the same
the same throughout
the same throughout all
the same throughout all of
the same throughout all of time.
Anything
Anything that
the same throughout all of time.
Anything that varies
Anything that varies from
the same throughout all of time.
Anything that varies from that
Anything that varies from that which
the same throughout all of time.
Anything that varies from that which has
been
taught
taught throughout
been
taught throughout time
taught throughout time is
been
taught throughout time is a
taught throughout time is a variance
from
from the
from the truth.
from the truth. The
from the truth. The truth
from the truth. The truth is
from the truth. The truth is always
from the truth. The truth is always the
same.
there's
there's no
there's no variation
there's no variation from
there's no variation from the
there's no variation from the tooth.
there's no variation from the tooth. So
there's
there's fancy
there's no variation from the tooth. So
there's fancy side
there's fancy side trips
there's no variation from the tooth. So
there's fancy side trips often
there's fancy side trips often to
there's no variation from the tooth. So
there's fancy side trips often to other
domains
and
and um
domains
and um the
and um the lure
domains
and um the lure the
and um the lure the siren
domains
and um the lure the siren song
and um the lure the siren song of
specialness
specialness coming
specialness coming from
specialness coming from various
dimensions.
dimensions. These
specialness coming from various
dimensions. These are
dimensions. These are all
specialness coming from various
dimensions. These are all lures
dimensions. These are all lures to
specialness coming from various
dimensions. These are all lures to pull
you
you off
you off the
you off the straight
you off the straight and
you off the straight and narrow.
you off the straight and narrow. All
lures
lures to
you off the straight and narrow. All
lures to pull
lures to pull you
you off the straight and narrow. All
lures to pull you off
lures to pull you off the
you off the straight and narrow. All
lures to pull you off the straight
lures to pull you off the straight and
narrow
narrow and
narrow and test
narrow and test your
narrow and test your your
narrow and test your your conviction
narrow and test your your conviction of
your
your convictions.
Don't
Don't allow
Don't allow yourself
Don't allow yourself to
Don't allow yourself to be
Don't allow yourself to be pulled
Don't allow yourself to be pulled off.
the
the central
Don't allow yourself to be pulled off.
the central path.
So
So now
So now not
So now not all
So now not all questions
So now not all questions can
So now not all questions can be
answered.
answered. Not
So now not all questions can be
answered. Not all
answered. Not all questions
So now not all questions can be
answered. Not all questions are
necessary
necessary to
necessary to answer.
And
And many
necessary to answer.
And many questions
And many questions what
necessary to answer.
And many questions what you
And many questions what you do
necessary to answer.
And many questions what you do is
And many questions what you do is you
pose
pose them
pose them as
pose them as a
pose them as a meditation
pose them as a meditation and
pose them as a meditation and you
pose them as a meditation and you simply
surrender
surrender them
pose them as a meditation and you simply
surrender them to
surrender them to God.
See
See because
See because otherwise
See because otherwise the
See because otherwise the ego
See because otherwise the ego just
See because otherwise the ego just uses
it
it as
See because otherwise the ego just uses
it as another
it as another way
See because otherwise the ego just uses
it as another way of
it as another way of maintaining
See because otherwise the ego just uses
it as another way of maintaining its
dominance
dominance over
dominance over your
dominance over your consciousness.
like
like I
dominance over your consciousness.
like I have
like I have to
dominance over your consciousness.
like I have to know
like I have to know if
dominance over your consciousness.
like I have to know if I
like I have to know if I had
dominance over your consciousness.
like I have to know if I had pre
like I have to know if I had pre past
lives
lives or
lives or not.
lives or not. You
lives or not. You don't
lives or not. You don't have
lives or not. You don't have to
lives or not. You don't have to know
that.
that. I
lives or not. You don't have to know
that. I mean,
that. I mean, what
lives or not. You don't have to know
that. I mean, what does
that. I mean, what does that
lives or not. You don't have to know
that. I mean, what does that got
that. I mean, what does that got to
lives or not. You don't have to know
that. I mean, what does that got to do
with
with totally
with totally surrendering
with totally surrendering to
with totally surrendering to God?
with totally surrendering to God? You
know,
it's
it's helpful.
it's helpful. So,
it's helpful. So, a
it's helpful. So, a lot
it's helpful. So, a lot of
it's helpful. So, a lot of these
it's helpful. So, a lot of these things
that
that we've
it's helpful. So, a lot of these things
that we've mentioned
that we've mentioned are
it's helpful. So, a lot of these things
that we've mentioned are helpful
that we've mentioned are helpful to
it's helpful. So, a lot of these things
that we've mentioned are helpful to know
at
at various
at various places
at various places and
at various places and it's
at various places and it's a
at various places and it's a subtlety
at various places and it's a subtlety of
spiritual
spiritual discernment
at various places and it's a subtlety of
spiritual discernment to
spiritual discernment to know
at various places and it's a subtlety of
spiritual discernment to know when
spiritual discernment to know when a
thing
thing is
thing is a
thing is a distraction
thing is a distraction or
thing is a distraction or it's
thing is a distraction or it's really
significant
significant and
thing is a distraction or it's really
significant and worthy
significant and worthy of
thing is a distraction or it's really
significant and worthy of um
significant and worthy of um looking
thing is a distraction or it's really
significant and worthy of um looking at.
Almost
Almost all
Almost all things
Almost all things resolve
Almost all things resolve themselves
Almost all things resolve themselves by
simply
simply asking
Almost all things resolve themselves by
simply asking and
simply asking and then
Almost all things resolve themselves by
simply asking and then waiting.
simply asking and then waiting. To
simply
simply ask
simply ask what
simply ask what is
simply ask what is the
simply ask what is the answer
simply ask what is the answer to
simply ask what is the answer to this?
What
What is
simply ask what is the answer to this?
What is the
What is the meaning
simply ask what is the answer to this?
What is the meaning of
What is the meaning of that?
simply ask what is the answer to this?
What is the meaning of that? Does
What is the meaning of that? Does this
pertain
pertain to
pertain to me?
Then
Then the
pertain to me?
Then the answer
Then the answer presents
pertain to me?
Then the answer presents itself
Then the answer presents itself in
pertain to me?
Then the answer presents itself in due
time.
time. You
time. You see,
time. You see, we
time. You see, we look
time. You see, we look at
time. You see, we look at we
time. You see, we look at we said
time. You see, we look at we said the
question
question here.
time. You see, we look at we said the
question here. Now
question here. Now we
time. You see, we look at we said the
question here. Now we waited
question here. Now we waited three
minutes
minutes and
minutes and we
minutes and we ain't
minutes and we ain't got
minutes and we ain't got an
minutes and we ain't got an answer
minutes and we ain't got an answer yet.
I
I mean,
I'm
I'm waiting
I'm waiting for
I'm waiting for the
I'm waiting for the phone
I'm waiting for the phone to
I'm waiting for the phone to ring
I'm waiting for the phone to ring on.
Yeah.
when
when we
when we ask
when we ask a
when we ask a question
when we ask a question may
when we ask a question may we
when we ask a question may we mean
when we ask a question may we mean like
right
right now
when we ask a question may we mean like
right now you
right now you know
when we ask a question may we mean like
right now you know what
right now you know what I'm
when we ask a question may we mean like
right now you know what I'm saying
just
just know
just know that
just know that it's
just know that it's heard
just know that it's heard and
just know that it's heard and when
just know that it's heard and when the
time
time is
just know that it's heard and when the
time is appropriate
see
see because
see because spiritual
see because spiritual work
see because spiritual work is
see because spiritual work is really
extremely
extremely subtle
see because spiritual work is really
extremely subtle extremely
extremely subtle extremely subtle
see because spiritual work is really
extremely subtle extremely subtle this
the
the slightest
the slightest move
the slightest move of
the slightest move of an
the slightest move of an energy
the slightest move of an energy like
this
this reveals
the slightest move of an energy like
this reveals an
this reveals an entire
the slightest move of an energy like
this reveals an entire field
this reveals an entire field like
the slightest move of an energy like
this reveals an entire field like that
that
that illuminates
that illuminates this
that illuminates this entire
that illuminates this entire landscape
it's
it's not
that illuminates this entire landscape
it's not a
it's not a linear
that illuminates this entire landscape
it's not a linear what
it's not a linear what is
that illuminates this entire landscape
it's not a linear what is the
it's not a linear what is the answer
that illuminates this entire landscape
it's not a linear what is the answer to
this
this question
this question and
this question and if
this question and if I
this question and if I get
this question and if I get the
this question and if I get the answer
then
then I'm
this question and if I get the answer
then I'm going
then I'm going to
this question and if I get the answer
then I'm going to move
then I'm going to move from
this question and if I get the answer
then I'm going to move from here
then I'm going to move from here to
there.
It's
It's more
there.
It's more a
It's more a way
there.
It's more a way of
It's more a way of being
there.
It's more a way of being in
It's more a way of being in the
there.
It's more a way of being in the world.
It's
It's it's
It's it's more
It's it's more of
It's it's more of a
It's it's more of a contemplative
It's it's more of a contemplative way
It's it's more of a contemplative way of
being
being in
It's it's more of a contemplative way of
being in the
being in the world.
It's it's more of a contemplative way of
being in the world. It's
being in the world. It's more
It's it's more of a contemplative way of
being in the world. It's more a
being in the world. It's more a way
It's it's more of a contemplative way of
being in the world. It's more a way of
relating
relating to
relating to the
relating to the context
relating to the context of
relating to the context of life
relating to the context of life and
relating to the context of life and of
your
your life
relating to the context of life and of
your life and
your life and of
relating to the context of life and of
your life and of all
your life and of all of
relating to the context of life and of
your life and of all of life
your life and of all of life and
relating to the context of life and of
your life and of all of life and of
human
human life.
It's
It's more
human life.
It's more a
It's more a way
human life.
It's more a way of
It's more a way of relating
human life.
It's more a way of relating to
It's more a way of relating to context
than
than it
than it is
than it is focusing
than it is focusing on
than it is focusing on content.
The
The content
than it is focusing on content.
The content comes
The content comes forth
than it is focusing on content.
The content comes forth in
The content comes forth in due
than it is focusing on content.
The content comes forth in due time.
So
So to
So to po
So to po the
So to po the way
So to po the way to
So to po the way to get
So to po the way to get an
So to po the way to get an answer
So to po the way to get an answer is
So to po the way to get an answer is to
pose
pose the
So to po the way to get an answer is to
pose the question,
pose the question, meditate
So to po the way to get an answer is to
pose the question, meditate on
pose the question, meditate on it,
So to po the way to get an answer is to
pose the question, meditate on it, turn
it
it over
it over to
it over to God
it over to God and
it over to God and ask
it over to God and ask God
it over to God and ask God to
it over to God and ask God to help
it over to God and ask God to help you
understand.
understand. Ask
it over to God and ask God to help you
understand. Ask the
understand. Ask the Holy
it over to God and ask God to help you
understand. Ask the Holy Spirit.
understand. Ask the Holy Spirit. You
it over to God and ask God to help you
understand. Ask the Holy Spirit. You can
pester
pester the
pester the Holy
pester the Holy Spirit
pester the Holy Spirit who
pester the Holy Spirit who doesn't
pester the Holy Spirit who doesn't seem
to
to mind
pester the Holy Spirit who doesn't seem
to mind at
to mind at all.
Why
Why doesn't
Why doesn't my
Why doesn't my ignition
Why doesn't my ignition turn
Why doesn't my ignition turn on?
It's
It's not
Why doesn't my ignition turn on?
It's not turning
It's not turning on.
Why doesn't my ignition turn on?
It's not turning on. The
It's not turning on. The Holy
Why doesn't my ignition turn on?
It's not turning on. The Holy Spirit
It's not turning on. The Holy Spirit is
very
very helpful
very helpful about
very helpful about such
very helpful about such things.
very helpful about such things. seems
very helpful about such things. seems to
have
have a
very helpful about such things. seems to
have a whole
have a whole bunch
very helpful about such things. seems to
have a whole bunch of
have a whole bunch of experts
very helpful about such things. seems to
have a whole bunch of experts on
have a whole bunch of experts on the
other
other side.
other side. Electricians,
other side. Electricians, mechanics,
other side. Electricians, mechanics, all
kinds
kinds of
other side. Electricians, mechanics, all
kinds of people,
kinds of people, map
other side. Electricians, mechanics, all
kinds of people, map readers.
I
I found
I found that
yeah,
yeah, very
I found that
yeah, very helpful.
yeah, very helpful. So
I found that
yeah, very helpful. So it
yeah, very helpful. So it it
I found that
yeah, very helpful. So it it doesn't
have
have to
have to be
have to be airy
have to be airy fairy
have to be airy fairy and
have to be airy fairy and sound
have to be airy fairy and sound very
grandiose
and
and very
and very splendid
and very splendid in
and very splendid in order
and very splendid in order to
and very splendid in order to ask
and very splendid in order to ask God
and very splendid in order to ask God a
question
question because
and very splendid in order to ask God a
question because the
question because the simplest
and very splendid in order to ask God a
question because the simplest things
question because the simplest things may
be
be quite
be quite distressing
be quite distressing and
be quite distressing and you
be quite distressing and you you
be quite distressing and you you have
be quite distressing and you you have to
surrender
surrender your
be quite distressing and you you have to
surrender your distress
surrender your distress to
be quite distressing and you you have to
surrender your distress to God
surrender your distress to God and
be quite distressing and you you have to
surrender your distress to God and and
ask
ask for
ask for help
ask for help with
ask for help with it.
We
We wanted
ask for help with it.
We wanted to
We wanted to answer
ask for help with it.
We wanted to answer a
We wanted to answer a few
ask for help with it.
We wanted to answer a few more
We wanted to answer a few more questions
and
what
what else
and
what else were
what else were we
and
what else were we going
what else were we going to
and
what else were we going to say
what else were we going to say today?
and
what else were we going to say today? I
just
just wanted
just wanted to
just wanted to explain
just wanted to explain about
just wanted to explain about the
correspondence
correspondence about
just wanted to explain about the
correspondence about the
correspondence about the kinesiology.
The
The other
The other thing
The other thing about
The other thing about kinesiology
because
because we
The other thing about kinesiology
because we get
because we get a
The other thing about kinesiology
because we get a lot
because we get a lot of
The other thing about kinesiology
because we get a lot of correspondence
about
about that.
about that. I
about that. I wish
about that. I wish I'd
about that. I wish I'd never
about that. I wish I'd never written
about
about it.
I'm
I'm like
I'm like Galileo
I'm like Galileo and
I'm like Galileo and he
I'm like Galileo and he keeps
I'm like Galileo and he keeps getting
letters
letters about
I'm like Galileo and he keeps getting
letters about telescopes.
letters about telescopes. He
I'm like Galileo and he keeps getting
letters about telescopes. He doesn't
know
know about
know about telescopes.
know about telescopes. You
know about telescopes. You know,
know about telescopes. You know, friend
said,
said, "You
know about telescopes. You know, friend
said, "You put
said, "You put this
know about telescopes. You know, friend
said, "You put this glass
said, "You put this glass here,
know about telescopes. You know, friend
said, "You put this glass here, you
said, "You put this glass here, you put
this
this glass,
this glass, you
this glass, you look
this glass, you look through
this glass, you look through here."
this glass, you look through here." And
he
he says,
this glass, you look through here." And
he says, "Wow,
he says, "Wow, man.
this glass, you look through here." And
he says, "Wow, man. There's
he says, "Wow, man. There's stars
this glass, you look through here." And
he says, "Wow, man. There's stars out
there."
there." I
there." I mean,
they
they keep
there." I mean,
they keep writing
they keep writing me
there." I mean,
they keep writing me about
they keep writing me about telescopes.
there." I mean,
they keep writing me about telescopes. I
don't
don't know.
don't know. So
don't know. So there's
don't know. So there's experts
don't know. So there's experts that
don't know. So there's experts that do
kinesiology
kinesiology all
don't know. So there's experts that do
kinesiology all day
kinesiology all day every
don't know. So there's experts that do
kinesiology all day every day
kinesiology all day every day and
don't know. So there's experts that do
kinesiology all day every day and it's
their
their whole
their whole thing
their whole thing and
their whole thing and we
their whole thing and we try
their whole thing and we try to
their whole thing and we try to send
their whole thing and we try to send out
a
a list
their whole thing and we try to send out
a list of
a list of people
their whole thing and we try to send out
a list of people we
a list of people we know
their whole thing and we try to send out
a list of people we know have
demonstration
demonstration tapes
demonstration tapes and
demonstration tapes and explanations
demonstration tapes and explanations of
it
it at
demonstration tapes and explanations of
it at all.
it at all. It's
demonstration tapes and explanations of
it at all. It's it's
it at all. It's it's just
demonstration tapes and explanations of
it at all. It's it's just a
it at all. It's it's just a simple
demonstration tapes and explanations of
it at all. It's it's just a simple way
of
of discerning
of discerning the
of discerning the truth
of discerning the truth or
of discerning the truth or false
of discerning the truth or false of
of discerning the truth or false of a
single
single statement
and
and it's
and it's nothing
and it's nothing more
and it's nothing more than
and it's nothing more than that.
and it's nothing more than that. It's
just
just a
and it's nothing more than that. It's
just a it's
just a it's an
and it's nothing more than that. It's
just a it's an assist.
just a it's an assist. It's
and it's nothing more than that. It's
just a it's an assist. It's useful.
just a it's an assist. It's useful. Its
primary
primary use
primary use is
primary use is really
primary use is really in
primary use is really in doing
primary use is really in doing research.
the
the kind
primary use is really in doing research.
the kind of
the kind of research
primary use is really in doing research.
the kind of research we
the kind of research we did
primary use is really in doing research.
the kind of research we did that
the kind of research we did that went
into
into power
into power versus
into power versus force
into power versus force etc
there
there it
into power versus force etc
there it serves
there it serves a
into power versus force etc
there it serves a very
there it serves a very useful
into power versus force etc
there it serves a very useful research
purpose
purpose and
purpose and in
purpose and in getting
purpose and in getting question
purpose and in getting question answers
to
to the
purpose and in getting question answers
to the unanswerable
to the unanswerable because
purpose and in getting question answers
to the unanswerable because they're
outside
outside of
outside of the
outside of the linear
outside of the linear domain.
outside of the linear domain. So
outside of the linear domain. So it's
useful
useful in
outside of the linear domain. So it's
useful in exploring
useful in exploring the
outside of the linear domain. So it's
useful in exploring the realities
useful in exploring the realities the
the
the nonlinear
the nonlinear domain.
If
If you're
the nonlinear domain.
If you're going
If you're going to
the nonlinear domain.
If you're going to explore
If you're going to explore the
the nonlinear domain.
If you're going to explore the linear
domain,
domain, it's
domain, it's better
domain, it's better to
domain, it's better to get
domain, it's better to get a
domain, it's better to get a computer.
Uh,
what
what is
what is the
what is the conscious
what is the conscious level
what is the conscious level of
what is the conscious level of people
what is the conscious level of people in
Iraq
Iraq and
what is the conscious level of people in
Iraq and Saddam?
Iraq and Saddam? I
what is the conscious level of people in
Iraq and Saddam? I think
Iraq and Saddam? I think we
what is the conscious level of people in
Iraq and Saddam? I think we already
Iraq and Saddam? I think we already did
them.
them. I
them. I think
them. I think they're
them. I think they're around
them. I think they're around 70
them. I think they're around 70 or
them. I think they're around 70 or 90.
They're
They're not
them. I think they're around 70 or 90.
They're not very
They're not very good.
them. I think they're around 70 or 90.
They're not very good. Oh,
They're not very good. Oh, Saddam
Hussein.
Hussein. No,
Hussein. No, we
Hussein. No, we never
Hussein. No, we never did
Hussein. No, we never did him.
Hussein. No, we never did him. Do
Hussein. No, we never did him. Do we
have
have permission
Hussein. No, we never did him. Do we
have permission to
have permission to do
Hussein. No, we never did him. Do we
have permission to do Saddam
have permission to do Saddam Hussein?
He's
He's over
He's over 200
He's over 200 resistant.
He's over 200 resistant. He's
He's over 200 resistant. He's not
He's over 200 resistant. He's not over
200.
200. I
He's over 200 resistant. He's not over
200. I don't
200. I don't like
He's over 200 resistant. He's not over
200. I don't like to
200. I don't like to say
He's over 200 resistant. He's not over
200. I don't like to say how
200. I don't like to say how low
He's over 200 resistant. He's not over
200. I don't like to say how low people
are.
are. I
are. I mean,
are. I mean, if
are. I mean, if you're
are. I mean, if you're either
are. I mean, if you're either either
over
over 200
are. I mean, if you're either either
over 200 or
over 200 or you're
are. I mean, if you're either either
over 200 or you're under
over 200 or you're under 200,
are. I mean, if you're either either
over 200 or you're under 200, you're
either
either committed
either committed to
either committed to integrity
either committed to integrity and
either committed to integrity and truth
or
or you're
either committed to integrity and truth
or you're into
or you're into grandiosity,
either committed to integrity and truth
or you're into grandiosity, megalomania,
and
and and
and and really
and and really a
and and really a hatred
and and really a hatred for
and and really a hatred for people.
and and really a hatred for people. Can
you
you imagine
and and really a hatred for people. Can
you imagine a
you imagine a person
and and really a hatred for people. Can
you imagine a person who
you imagine a person who defends
and and really a hatred for people. Can
you imagine a person who defends himself
by
by surrounding
by surrounding his
by surrounding his military
by surrounding his military compound
with
with children?
So,
So, if
So, if you
So, if you bomb
So, if you bomb his
So, if you bomb his military
So, if you bomb his military compound,
you
you now
So, if you bomb his military compound,
you now he's
you now he's he's
So, if you bomb his military compound,
you now he's he's got
you now he's he's got you
So, if you bomb his military compound,
you now he's he's got you right
you now he's he's got you right in
So, if you bomb his military compound,
you now he's he's got you right in the
gut,
gut, right
gut, right in
gut, right in the
gut, right in the spleen,
gut, right in the spleen, right
gut, right in the spleen, right into
gut, right in the spleen, right into the
old
old guilt
gut, right in the spleen, right into the
old guilt complex
old guilt complex that
gut, right in the spleen, right into the
old guilt complex that you
old guilt complex that you got
gut, right in the spleen, right into the
old guilt complex that you got to
old guilt complex that you got to kill
children.
children. A
children. A man
children. A man who
children. A man who hides
children. A man who hides behind
children.
children. I
children. A man who hides behind
children. I don't
children. I don't know.
children. A man who hides behind
children. I don't know. I
children. I don't know. I can't
children. A man who hides behind
children. I don't know. I can't say
children. I don't know. I can't say much
of
of him.
I'll
I'll tell
of him.
I'll tell you
I'll tell you what
of him.
I'll tell you what my
I'll tell you what my macho
of him.
I'll tell you what my macho man
I'll tell you what my macho man thinks
of
of him,
of him, but
of him, but that
of him, but that wouldn't
of him, but that wouldn't be
of him, but that wouldn't be good
of him, but that wouldn't be good for
recording.
Few
Few rounds
Few rounds in
Few rounds in the
Few rounds in the gun
Few rounds in the gun tub
Few rounds in the gun tub and
Few rounds in the gun tub and I'd
straighten
straighten out
Few rounds in the gun tub and I'd
straighten out his
straighten out his understanding
Few rounds in the gun tub and I'd
straighten out his understanding of
things.
I
I tell
things.
I tell you
I tell you when
things.
I tell you when I
I tell you when I when
things.
I tell you when I when I
I tell you when I when I was
things.
I tell you when I when I was in
I tell you when I when I was in the
Navy,
Navy, you
Navy, you know,
Navy, you know, I
Navy, you know, I got
Navy, you know, I got put
Navy, you know, I got put on
Navy, you know, I got put on hazardous
duty
duty and
Navy, you know, I got put on hazardous
duty and I
duty and I go
Navy, you know, I got put on hazardous
duty and I go aboard
duty and I go aboard this
Navy, you know, I got put on hazardous
duty and I go aboard this mind
duty and I go aboard this mind sweeper
and
and here's
and here's these
and here's these grizzled
and here's these grizzled little
and here's these grizzled little guys
have
have been
and here's these grizzled little guys
have been out
have been out to
and here's these grizzled little guys
have been out to sea
have been out to sea with
and here's these grizzled little guys
have been out to sea with tattoos
have been out to sea with tattoos and
rings
rings in
rings in their
rings in their ears
rings in their ears and
rings in their ears and parrots
rings in their ears and parrots on
rings in their ears and parrots on their
shoulder.
shoulder. I
rings in their ears and parrots on their
shoulder. I mean,
shoulder. I mean, you
rings in their ears and parrots on their
shoulder. I mean, you know,
and
and so
and so the
and so the first
and so the first guy,
and so the first guy, this
and so the first guy, this guy
and so the first guy, this guy says
and so the first guy, this guy says to
me,
me, "Hey,
and so the first guy, this guy says to
me, "Hey, shorty."
me, "Hey, shorty." That
and so the first guy, this guy says to
me, "Hey, shorty." That was
me, "Hey, shorty." That was my
and so the first guy, this guy says to
me, "Hey, shorty." That was my name
me, "Hey, shorty." That was my name ever
after.
after. Shorty,
after. Shorty, he
after. Shorty, he says,
after. Shorty, he says, "You
after. Shorty, he says, "You box?"
after. Shorty, he says, "You box?" And
after. Shorty, he says, "You box?" And I
said, "Well,
said, "Well, I
after. Shorty, he says, "You box?" And I
said, "Well, I took
said, "Well, I took lessons
after. Shorty, he says, "You box?" And I
said, "Well, I took lessons from
said, "Well, I took lessons from Richie
Mitchell."
Mitchell." He
Mitchell." He says,
Mitchell." He says, "What
Mitchell." He says, "What weight
Mitchell." He says, "What weight were
you?"
you?" I
Mitchell." He says, "What weight were
you?" I says,
you?" I says, "I
Mitchell." He says, "What weight were
you?" I says, "I was
you?" I says, "I was mosquito
Mitchell." He says, "What weight were
you?" I says, "I was mosquito weight.
He
He said,
He said, "Well,
He said, "Well, how
He said, "Well, how about
He said, "Well, how about going
He said, "Well, how about going a
He said, "Well, how about going a few
rounds
rounds as
He said, "Well, how about going a few
rounds as a
rounds as a spar
He said, "Well, how about going a few
rounds as a spar partner
rounds as a spar partner in
He said, "Well, how about going a few
rounds as a spar partner in the
rounds as a spar partner in the gun
tub?"
tub?" I
tub?" I says,
tub?" I says, "Okay."
tub?" I says, "Okay." So,
tub?" I says, "Okay." So, we
tub?" I says, "Okay." So, we put
tub?" I says, "Okay." So, we put on
these
these big
tub?" I says, "Okay." So, we put on
these big mits.
these big mits. I
tub?" I says, "Okay." So, we put on
these big mits. I almost
these big mits. I almost fell
tub?" I says, "Okay." So, we put on
these big mits. I almost fell over
these big mits. I almost fell over with
him.
him. And
him. And we
him. And we go
him. And we go up
him. And we go up in
him. And we go up in the
him. And we go up in the gun
him. And we go up in the gun tub.
him. And we go up in the gun tub. We
spired
spired off
him. And we go up in the gun tub. We
spired off and
spired off and he
him. And we go up in the gun tub. We
spired off and he knocked
spired off and he knocked me
him. And we go up in the gun tub. We
spired off and he knocked me cold
spired off and he knocked me cold with
one
one shot.
I
I told
one shot.
I told you
I told you that
one shot.
I told you that story
I told you that story before,
>> did
>> did I?
>> did I? Then
>> did I? Then I
>> did I? Then I told
>> did I? Then I told find
>> did I? Then I told find out
>> did I? Then I told find out later
>> did I? Then I told find out later he
>> did I? Then I told find out later he was
the
the champion
>> did I? Then I told find out later he was
the champion of
the champion of the
>> did I? Then I told find out later he was
the champion of the third
the champion of the third fleet.
>> did I? Then I told find out later he was
the champion of the third fleet. Yeah.
And
And we're
And we're still
And we're still friends
And we're still friends to
And we're still friends to this
And we're still friends to this day.
And we're still friends to this day. you
know,
know, he
And we're still friends to this day. you
know, he uh
know, he uh writes
And we're still friends to this day. you
know, he uh writes me
know, he uh writes me and
And we're still friends to this day. you
know, he uh writes me and uh
know, he uh writes me and uh he's
getting
getting he's
getting he's getting
getting he's getting on
getting he's getting on now.
He's
He's not
getting he's getting on now.
He's not all
He's not all there
getting he's getting on now.
He's not all there and
He's not all there and he's
getting he's getting on now.
He's not all there and he's always
telling
telling me
telling me he
telling me he quit
telling me he quit drinking
telling me he quit drinking too
telling me he quit drinking too late
anyway.
Is
Is it
Is it within
Is it within God's
Is it within God's wish
Is it within God's wish for
Is it within God's wish for you
Is it within God's wish for you to
Is it within God's wish for you to teach
us
us all
Is it within God's wish for you to teach
us all muscle
us all muscle testing
Is it within God's wish for you to teach
us all muscle testing today?
That's
That's hysterical.
But
But make
That's hysterical.
But make it
But make it brief,
That's hysterical.
But make it brief, he
But make it brief, he said.
That's hysterical.
But make it brief, he said. Okay.
We
We do
We do recapitulate
We do recapitulate this
We do recapitulate this because
We do recapitulate this because no
matter
matter how
We do recapitulate this because no
matter how many
matter how many tapes,
We do recapitulate this because no
matter how many tapes, videos
matter how many tapes, videos and
lectures
lectures we
lectures we give,
lectures we give, for
lectures we give, for some
lectures we give, for some reason
lectures we give, for some reason some
people
people be
lectures we give, for some reason some
people be are
people be are up
lectures we give, for some reason some
people be are up against
people be are up against it
lectures we give, for some reason some
people be are up against it with
people be are up against it with muscle
testing.
testing. The
testing. The reason
testing. The reason they
testing. The reason they have
testing. The reason they have a
testing. The reason they have a problem
with
with it
testing. The reason they have a problem
with it is
with it is because
testing. The reason they have a problem
with it is because it's
with it is because it's so
testing. The reason they have a problem
with it is because it's so simple.
with it is because it's so simple. I
find
find the
find the things
find the things that
find the things that are
find the things that are very
find the things that are very are
find the things that are very are simple
are
are very
find the things that are very are simple
are very difficult
are very difficult to
find the things that are very are simple
are very difficult to explain.
You
You say
You say just
You say just put
You say just put it
You say just put it here.
You say just put it here. Nobody
You say just put it here. Nobody gets
that.
Where
Where should
Where should I
Where should I put
Where should I put this?
Where should I put this? Just
Where should I put this? Just put
Where should I put this? Just put it
here.
here. Well,
Where should I put this? Just put it
here. Well, what
here. Well, what do
Where should I put this? Just put it
here. Well, what do you
here. Well, what do you mean
Where should I put this? Just put it
here. Well, what do you mean by
here. Well, what do you mean by here?
When
When now
When now you
When now you mean
When now you mean this
When now you mean this way,
When now you mean this way, that
When now you mean this way, that I
When now you mean this way, that I mean
Christ,
Christ, they
When now you mean this way, that I mean
Christ, they got
Christ, they got to
When now you mean this way, that I mean
Christ, they got to complicate
everything.
everything. Just
everything. Just put
everything. Just put it
everything. Just put it here,
everything. Just put it here, man.
everything. Just put it here, man. Just
is
is it
everything. Just put it here, man. Just
is it God's
is it God's will
everything. Just put it here, man. Just
is it God's will that
is it God's will that for
we
we know
we know that
we know that God's
we know that God's will
we know that God's will doesn't
we know that God's will doesn't have
we know that God's will doesn't have its
specifics
specifics like
we know that God's will doesn't have its
specifics like whether
specifics like whether I
we know that God's will doesn't have its
specifics like whether I should
specifics like whether I should teach
we know that God's will doesn't have its
specifics like whether I should teach it
or
or not.
or not. It's
or not. It's ridiculous.
Anyway,
Anyway, it's
or not. It's ridiculous.
Anyway, it's my
Anyway, it's my will
or not. It's ridiculous.
Anyway, it's my will to
Anyway, it's my will to teach
or not. It's ridiculous.
Anyway, it's my will to teach it.
All right.
All right. I
All right. I did
All right. I did want
All right. I did want to
All right. I did want to go
All right. I did want to go over
All right. I did want to go over just
people
people are
All right. I did want to go over just
people are getting
people are getting calibrations
All right. I did want to go over just
people are getting calibrations that
people are getting calibrations that are
too
too high
too high by
too high by virtue
too high by virtue of
too high by virtue of the
too high by virtue of the fact
too high by virtue of the fact that
too high by virtue of the fact that they
resist.
It's
It's a
It's a very
It's a very fast
It's a very fast subtle
It's a very fast subtle energy.
It's a very fast subtle energy. Okay?
It's
It's a
It's a very fast subtle energy. Okay?
It's a very
It's a very fast
It's a very fast subtle energy. Okay?
It's a very fast subtle
It's a very fast subtle energy.
It's a very fast subtle energy. Okay?
It's a very fast subtle energy. Really?
You
You see
You see it's
You see it's very
You see it's very quick.
You see it's very quick. So
You see it's very quick. So when
You see it's very quick. So when I
You see it's very quick. So when I hold
something
something negative
You see it's very quick. So when I hold
something negative in
something negative in mind,
You see it's very quick. So when I hold
something negative in mind, it
something negative in mind, it shoots
down
down that
down that fast.
down that fast. That's
down that fast. That's when
down that fast. That's when you
down that fast. That's when you go
down that fast. That's when you go weak.
Then
Then the
down that fast. That's when you go weak.
Then the primate
Then the primate within
down that fast. That's when you go weak.
Then the primate within us,
Then the primate within us, the
down that fast. That's when you go weak.
Then the primate within us, the old
primate
primate out
primate out of
primate out of evolution
primate out of evolution thinks
primate out of evolution thinks it's
falling
falling out
primate out of evolution thinks it's
falling out of
falling out of a
primate out of evolution thinks it's
falling out of a tree
falling out of a tree and
primate out of evolution thinks it's
falling out of a tree and it's
anti-gravity
anti-gravity muscles
anti-gravity muscles resist.
anti-gravity muscles resist. See?
anti-gravity muscles resist. See? So
what
what we've
anti-gravity muscles resist. See? So
what we've noticed
what we've noticed this
anti-gravity muscles resist. See? So
what we've noticed this all
what we've noticed this all around
anti-gravity muscles resist. See? So
what we've noticed this all around the
world.
world. The
world. The minute
world. The minute the
world. The minute the person
world. The minute the person goes
world. The minute the person goes weak,
I
I say
world. The minute the person goes weak,
I say hold
I say hold hold
world. The minute the person goes weak,
I say hold hold been
I say hold hold been loud
world. The minute the person goes weak,
I say hold hold been loud in
I say hold hold been loud in your
world. The minute the person goes weak,
I say hold hold been loud in your mind.
They
They start
They start to
They start to go
They start to go weak
They start to go weak and
They start to go weak and what
They start to go weak and what happens
then
then is
They start to go weak and what happens
then is they
then is they resist.
They start to go weak and what happens
then is they resist. You
then is they resist. You can't
They start to go weak and what happens
then is they resist. You can't resist.
It's
It's very
It's very very
It's very very fast.
It's very very fast. So
It's very very fast. So what
It's very very fast. So what you
It's very very fast. So what you do
It's very very fast. So what you do is
you
you surrender.
It's very very fast. So what you do is
you surrender. So
you surrender. So it's
It's very very fast. So what you do is
you surrender. So it's a
you surrender. So it's a partly
It's very very fast. So what you do is
you surrender. So it's a partly a
willingness
willingness to
willingness to surrender
willingness to surrender to
willingness to surrender to weakness
which
which sets
willingness to surrender to weakness
which sets the
which sets the monkey
willingness to surrender to weakness
which sets the monkey and
which sets the monkey and your
unconscious
unconscious into
unconscious into franics
unconscious into franics that
unconscious into franics that he's
unconscious into franics that he's going
to
to fall
unconscious into franics that he's going
to fall out
to fall out of
unconscious into franics that he's going
to fall out of the
to fall out of the tree.
unconscious into franics that he's going
to fall out of the tree. So
to fall out of the tree. So you've
unconscious into franics that he's going
to fall out of the tree. So you've got
to
to retrain
to retrain the
to retrain the monkey
to retrain the monkey that
to retrain the monkey that he's
to retrain the monkey that he's he's
okay
okay to
to retrain the monkey that he's he's
okay to fall
okay to fall out
to retrain the monkey that he's he's
okay to fall out of
okay to fall out of the
to retrain the monkey that he's he's
okay to fall out of the tree.
okay to fall out of the tree. Most
people
people overly
people overly resist.
people overly resist. Therefore,
people overly resist. Therefore, they
get
get calibrations
people overly resist. Therefore, they
get calibrations that
get calibrations that are
people overly resist. Therefore, they
get calibrations that are way
get calibrations that are way too
people overly resist. Therefore, they
get calibrations that are way too high.
Exist.
Exist. Okay.
Exist. Okay. All right.
Exist. Okay. All right. So,
Exist. Okay. All right. So, the
Exist. Okay. All right. So, the thing
Exist. Okay. All right. So, the thing is
you
you have
Exist. Okay. All right. So, the thing is
you have to
you have to let
Exist. Okay. All right. So, the thing is
you have to let go
you have to let go instantly.
Exist. Okay. All right. So, the thing is
you have to let go instantly. It's
you have to let go instantly. It's a
subtlety.
Anybody
Anybody can
subtlety.
Anybody can totally
Anybody can totally resist
subtlety.
Anybody can totally resist and
Anybody can totally resist and you
subtlety.
Anybody can totally resist and you would
never
never get
never get a
never get a no
never get a no because
no
no matter
never get a no because
no matter how
no matter how hard
never get a no because
no matter how hard you
no matter how hard you push,
never get a no because
no matter how hard you push, I
no matter how hard you push, I can
never get a no because
no matter how hard you push, I can push
harder.
harder. You
harder. You understand?
harder. You understand? So,
harder. You understand? So, it's
harder. You understand? So, it's not
harder. You understand? So, it's not a
test
test of
harder. You understand? So, it's not a
test of strength.
test of strength. It's
harder. You understand? So, it's not a
test of strength. It's a
test of strength. It's a test.
harder. You understand? So, it's not a
test of strength. It's a test. It's
test of strength. It's a test. It's a
fast
fast test
fast test like
fast test like that.
fast test like that. Instantaneous
fast test like that. Instantaneous test.
I'm
I'm holding
fast test like that. Instantaneous test.
I'm holding something
I'm holding something in
fast test like that. Instantaneous test.
I'm holding something in mind.
I'm holding something in mind. Resist.
I'm
I'm holding
I'm holding something
I'm holding something in
I'm holding something in mind.
I'm holding something in mind. Resist.
All right.
All right. First
I'm holding something in mind. Resist.
All right. First time
All right. First time was
I'm holding something in mind. Resist.
All right. First time was Jesus
All right. First time was Jesus Christ.
The
The second
The second time
The second time was
The second time was bin
The second time was bin L.
The second time was bin L. You
The second time was bin L. You see
The second time was bin L. You see how
fast
fast it
The second time was bin L. You see how
fast it went?
fast it went? Now,
The second time was bin L. You see how
fast it went? Now, the
fast it went? Now, the other
The second time was bin L. You see how
fast it went? Now, the other question
that
that comes
that comes up
that comes up is,
that comes up is, doesn't
that comes up is, doesn't the
that comes up is, doesn't the other
person's
person's belief
that comes up is, doesn't the other
person's belief system
person's belief system affect
that comes up is, doesn't the other
person's belief system affect the
result?
result? No.
result? No. Because
result? No. Because she
result? No. Because she doesn't
result? No. Because she doesn't know
what
what I
result? No. Because she doesn't know
what I was
what I was thinking.
result? No. Because she doesn't know
what I was thinking. She
what I was thinking. She had
result? No. Because she doesn't know
what I was thinking. She had no
what I was thinking. She had no belief
system.
system. She
system. She has
system. She has no
system. She has no belief
system. She has no belief system
system. She has no belief system what
I'm
I'm thinking
system. She has no belief system what
I'm thinking because
I'm thinking because she
system. She has no belief system what
I'm thinking because she doesn't
I'm thinking because she doesn't know
what
what I'm
what I'm thinking.
what I'm thinking. I
what I'm thinking. I was
what I'm thinking. I was holding
>> I
>> I thought
what I'm thinking. I was holding
>> I thought it
>> I thought it was
what I'm thinking. I was holding
>> I thought it was cuz
>> I thought it was cuz I
what I'm thinking. I was holding
>> I thought it was cuz I was
>> I thought it was cuz I was blonde.
She
She said,
"It's
"It's funny.
She said,
"It's funny. A
"It's funny. A funny
She said,
"It's funny. A funny joke.
"It's funny. A funny joke. She
She said,
"It's funny. A funny joke. She just
"It's funny. A funny joke. She just made
up
up a
up a blonde
up a blonde joke."
up a blonde joke." She
up a blonde joke." She said, "I
up a blonde joke." She said, "I thought
it's
it's cuz
up a blonde joke." She said, "I thought
it's cuz I
it's cuz I was
up a blonde joke." She said, "I thought
it's cuz I was blonde."
Okay.
Okay. So,
Okay. So, the
the
the answer
Okay. So, the
the answer the
the answer the answer
Okay. So, the
the answer the answer is
the answer the answer is very
Okay. So, the
the answer the answer is very very
rapid.
rapid. Consciousness
rapid. Consciousness instantly
rapid. Consciousness instantly detects
that
that which
rapid. Consciousness instantly detects
that which is
that which is dilotious
rapid. Consciousness instantly detects
that which is dilotious to
that which is dilotious to it
rapid. Consciousness instantly detects
that which is dilotious to it and
instantly
instantly detects
instantly detects that
instantly detects that which
instantly detects that which is
instantly detects that which is friendly
to
to it.
instantly detects that which is friendly
to it. extremely
to it. extremely rapid,
instantly detects that which is friendly
to it. extremely rapid, probably
to it. extremely rapid, probably a
instantly detects that which is friendly
to it. extremely rapid, probably a tenth
of
of a
of a second.
of a second. Let's
of a second. Let's see
of a second. Let's see how
of a second. Let's see how fast
of a second. Let's see how fast it
of a second. Let's see how fast it is.
I've
I've never
of a second. Let's see how fast it is.
I've never did
I've never did measure
of a second. Let's see how fast it is.
I've never did measure it.
I've never did measure it. Come
of a second. Let's see how fast it is.
I've never did measure it. Come to
I've never did measure it. Come to think
of
of it.
of it. Um,
of it. Um, we
of it. Um, we have
of it. Um, we have permission
of it. Um, we have permission to
of it. Um, we have permission to measure
this
this right
of it. Um, we have permission to measure
this right here.
this right here. Now,
of it. Um, we have permission to measure
this right here. Now, this
this right here. Now, this um
of it. Um, we have permission to measure
this right here. Now, this um this
this right here. Now, this um this uh
discharge
discharge is
discharge is uh
discharge is uh longer
discharge is uh longer than
discharge is uh longer than a
discharge is uh longer than a hundth
discharge is uh longer than a hundth of
a
a second.
It's
It's longer
It's longer than
It's longer than a
It's longer than a 1,000th
It's longer than a 1,000th of
It's longer than a 1,000th of a
It's longer than a 1,000th of a second.
It's
It's 1
It's longer than a 1,000th of a second.
It's 1 10,000th
It's 1 10,000th of
It's longer than a 1,000th of a second.
It's 1 10,000th of a
It's 1 10,000th of a second.
Approximately
Approximately 110,000
Approximately 110,000 of
Approximately 110,000 of a
Approximately 110,000 of a second.
Approximately 110,000 of a second. So,
um
it's
it's something
it's something you
it's something you get
it's something you get just
it's something you get just by
it's something you get just by practice.
Um
Um it's
it's something you get just by practice.
Um it's more
Um it's more like
it's something you get just by practice.
Um it's more like when
Um it's more like when you
it's something you get just by practice.
Um it's more like when you walk
Um it's more like when you walk into
it's something you get just by practice.
Um it's more like when you walk into a
room,
room, you've
room, you've already
room, you've already got
room, you've already got the
room, you've already got the energy
room, you've already got the energy of
all
all that.
room, you've already got the energy of
all that. You've
all that. You've already
room, you've already got the energy of
all that. You've already got
all that. You've already got the
room, you've already got the energy of
all that. You've already got the energy
of
of that
of that room
of that room and
of that room and and
of that room and and the
of that room and and the context
of that room and and the context of
of that room and and the context of that
room.
room. It's
of that room and and the context of that
room. It's very
room. It's very fast,
of that room and and the context of that
room. It's very fast, very
room. It's very fast, very quick.
of that room and and the context of that
room. It's very fast, very quick. Uh
with
with practice,
with practice, you
with practice, you get
with practice, you get it.
Um
Um people
with practice, you get it.
Um people who
Um people who practice
with practice, you get it.
Um people who practice by
Um people who practice by themselves
like
like this
like this are
like this are the
like this are the most
like this are the most prone
like this are the most prone to
like this are the most prone to get
like this are the most prone to get high
calibrations.
Um
Um because
Um because again
Um because again you
Um because again you have
Um because again you have to
Um because again you have to develop
Um because again you have to develop the
sensitivity
and
and it's
and it's probably
and it's probably better
and it's probably better to
and it's probably better to use
and it's probably better to use these
two
two fingers
and it's probably better to use these
two fingers than
two fingers than the
and it's probably better to use these
two fingers than the ring
two fingers than the ring than
and it's probably better to use these
two fingers than the ring than than
these
these two
these two fingers.
these two fingers. These
these two fingers. These are
these two fingers. These are very
strong.
strong. If
these two fingers. These are very
strong. If I
strong. If I make
these two fingers. These are very
strong. If I make up
strong. If I make up my
these two fingers. These are very
strong. If I make up my mind
strong. If I make up my mind it's
these two fingers. These are very
strong. If I make up my mind it's going
to
to be
to be practically
to be practically impossible
to be practically impossible to
to be practically impossible to pull
them
them apart.
to be practically impossible to pull
them apart. You
them apart. You understand?
to be practically impossible to pull
them apart. You understand? So
them apart. You understand? So the
tendency
tendency is
tendency is to
tendency is to resist
tendency is to resist and
tendency is to resist and get
calibrations
calibrations that
tendency is to resist and get
calibrations that are
calibrations that are way
tendency is to resist and get
calibrations that are way too
calibrations that are way too high.
um
um these
um these two
um these two fingers
um these two fingers here
um these two fingers here do
um these two fingers here do not
um these two fingers here do not have
that
that much
um these two fingers here do not have
that much strength
that much strength and
um these two fingers here do not have
that much strength and therefore
that much strength and therefore to
um these two fingers here do not have
that much strength and therefore to use
these
these two
these two fingers
these two fingers here
these two fingers here the
these two fingers here the relative
strength
strength between
these two fingers here the relative
strength between truth
strength between truth and
these two fingers here the relative
strength between truth and false
strength between truth and false is
these two fingers here the relative
strength between truth and false is much
more
more easily
more easily perceived
more easily perceived this
more easily perceived this way
more easily perceived this way as
more easily perceived this way as you
notice
notice trying
more easily perceived this way as you
notice trying to
notice trying to keep
more easily perceived this way as you
notice trying to keep these
notice trying to keep these two
more easily perceived this way as you
notice trying to keep these two fingers
apart
apart you
apart you really
apart you really don't
apart you really don't have
apart you really don't have much
strength
if
if you
if you try
if you try to
if you try to keep
if you try to keep these
if you try to keep these two
if you try to keep these two fingers
if you try to keep these two fingers now
if
if I
if you try to keep these two fingers now
if I try
if I try to
if you try to keep these two fingers now
if I try to part
if I try to part them
if you try to keep these two fingers now
if I try to part them you'll
if I try to part them you'll notice
they're
they're quite
they're quite weak
they're quite weak I
they're quite weak I can't
they're quite weak I can't really
they're quite weak I can't really part
them
them because
they're quite weak I can't really part
them because they're
them because they're very
they're quite weak I can't really part
them because they're very very
them because they're very very weak
they're quite weak I can't really part
them because they're very very weak So
using
using these
using these two
using these two muscles,
using these two muscles, these
using these two muscles, these two
fingers
fingers here
using these two muscles, these two
fingers here is
fingers here is quicker
using these two muscles, these two
fingers here is quicker and
fingers here is quicker and more
sensitive
sensitive because
sensitive because they're
sensitive because they're much
sensitive because they're much weaker
and
and I
sensitive because they're much weaker
and I can
and I can overpower
sensitive because they're much weaker
and I can overpower them
and I can overpower them any
sensitive because they're much weaker
and I can overpower them any time.
and I can overpower them any time. You
see,
see, because
see, because they
see, because they don't
see, because they don't have
see, because they don't have that
see, because they don't have that much
strength.
strength. So
see, because they don't have that much
strength. So you're
strength. So you're not
see, because they don't have that much
strength. So you're not as
strength. So you're not as likely
see, because they don't have that much
strength. So you're not as likely to
strength. So you're not as likely to get
a
a false
a false positive.
Most
Most things
a false positive.
Most things that
Most things that are
a false positive.
Most things that are are
Most things that are are necessary
a false positive.
Most things that are are necessary to
know,
know, you
know, you know,
know, you know, we
know, you know, we have
know, you know, we have already
know, you know, we have already been
discussed
discussed and
know, you know, we have already been
discussed and demonstrated.
discussed and demonstrated. We
know, you know, we have already been
discussed and demonstrated. We are
working
working on
working on a
working on a book
working on a book where
working on a book where we're
working on a book where we're doing
working on a book where we're doing a
thousand
thousand calibrations
and
and as
and as soon
and as soon as
and as soon as we
and as soon as we finish
and as soon as we finish the
and as soon as we finish the book
and as soon as we finish the book I
which
Sonia
Sonia just
Sonia just finished
Sonia just finished the
Sonia just finished the last
Sonia just finished the last the
Sonia just finished the last the last
uh
uh manuscript
um
um the
um the next
um the next one
um the next one we're
um the next one we're halfway
um the next one we're halfway I've
um the next one we're halfway I've got
halfway
halfway through.
So
So I'm
So I'm trying
So I'm trying to
So I'm trying to make
So I'm trying to make a
So I'm trying to make a reference
So I'm trying to make a reference book
because
because lots
So I'm trying to make a reference book
because lots of
because lots of people
So I'm trying to make a reference book
because lots of people will
because lots of people will have
So I'm trying to make a reference book
because lots of people will have many
questions
questions and
questions and they
questions and they can't
questions and they can't really
questions and they can't really do
questions and they can't really do it
themselves
themselves or
questions and they can't really do it
themselves or they
themselves or they don't
questions and they can't really do it
themselves or they don't have
themselves or they don't have a
questions and they can't really do it
themselves or they don't have a partner
they
they can
they can do
they can do it
they can do it with
they can do it with themselves
they can do it with themselves and
they can do it with themselves and be
just
just uh
they can do it with themselves and be
just uh you
just uh you know
they can do it with themselves and be
just uh you know sort
just uh you know sort of
they can do it with themselves and be
just uh you know sort of easy
just uh you know sort of easy to
they can do it with themselves and be
just uh you know sort of easy to be
just uh you know sort of easy to be able
to
to look
to look up
to look up you
to look up you know
to look up you know very
to look up you know very spiritual
authors
authors in
to look up you know very spiritual
authors in history
authors in history you
to look up you know very spiritual
authors in history you know
authors in history you know what
to look up you know very spiritual
authors in history you know what what
level
level of
level of consciousness
level of consciousness you
level of consciousness you see
level of consciousness you see in
level of consciousness you see in the
levels
levels of
level of consciousness you see in the
levels of consciousness
levels of consciousness is
level of consciousness you see in the
levels of consciousness is not
levels of consciousness is not better
than
than see
than see the
than see the ego
than see the ego tends
than see the ego tends to
than see the ego tends to think
than see the ego tends to think of
better
better than
than see the ego tends to think of
better than or
better than or less
than see the ego tends to think of
better than or less than
better than or less than or
um
no
no it's
um
no it's what
no it's what level
um
no it's what level of
no it's what level of truth
um
no it's what level of truth are
no it's what level of truth are they
talking
talking about
talking about there
talking about there are
talking about there are many
talking about there are many terrific
teachers
teachers in
talking about there are many terrific
teachers in the
teachers in the high
talking about there are many terrific
teachers in the high 200s.
Um
Um I
Um I mean
Um I mean the
Um I mean the basics
Um I mean the basics of
Um I mean the basics of spirituality
Um I mean the basics of spirituality you
don't
don't have
Um I mean the basics of spirituality you
don't have to
don't have to be
Um I mean the basics of spirituality you
don't have to be a
don't have to be a rocket
Um I mean the basics of spirituality you
don't have to be a rocket scientist
to
to be
to be kind
to be kind loving
to be kind loving forgiving
to be kind loving forgiving uh
to be kind loving forgiving uh unselfish
to
to be
to be kind loving forgiving uh unselfish
to be of
to be of service
to be kind loving forgiving uh unselfish
to be of service to
to be of service to others
to
to see
to see the
to see the value
to see the value of
to see the value of worship
to see the value of worship and
to see the value of worship and prayer
and
and dedication
to see the value of worship and prayer
and dedication of
and dedication of surrendering
to see the value of worship and prayer
and dedication of surrendering all
and dedication of surrendering all one's
service
service and
service and efforts
service and efforts to
service and efforts to God
service and efforts to God to
service and efforts to God to stop
looking
looking for
service and efforts to God to stop
looking for stop
looking for stop looking
service and efforts to God to stop
looking for stop looking for
looking for stop looking for rewards
from
from the
from the world
from the world and
from the world and do
from the world and do them
from the world and do them for
from the world and do them for their
from the world and do them for their own
sake
sake out
from the world and do them for their own
sake out of
one's
one's love
one's love for
one's love for God
one's love for God and
one's love for God and one's
one's love for God and one's fellow
one's love for God and one's fellow man.
Those
Those things
one's love for God and one's fellow man.
Those things are
Those things are very
one's love for God and one's fellow man.
Those things are very simple
Those things are very simple and
one's love for God and one's fellow man.
Those things are very simple and also
very
very difficult,
very difficult
very difficult as
very difficult,
very difficult as we
very difficult as we all
very difficult,
very difficult as we all know.
very difficult as we all know. Uh
very difficult,
very difficult as we all know. Uh and
very difficult as we all know. Uh and it
takes
takes years
takes years of
takes years of practice
takes years of practice before
takes years of practice before one
takes years of practice before one goes
on
on and
takes years of practice before one goes
on and needs
on and needs more
takes years of practice before one goes
on and needs more advanced
on and needs more advanced spiritual
techniques.
techniques. The
techniques. The desire
techniques. The desire for
techniques. The desire for we,
techniques. The desire for we, as
techniques. The desire for we, as we
said,
said, salvation
techniques. The desire for we, as we
said, salvation is
said, salvation is one
techniques. The desire for we, as we
said, salvation is one thing,
enlightenment
enlightenment is
enlightenment is another.
Enlightenment
Enlightenment is
enlightenment is another.
Enlightenment is far
Enlightenment is far more
enlightenment is another.
Enlightenment is far more demanding,
more
more strict,
more radical.
Radical.
You
You got
Radical.
You got to
You got to be
Radical.
You got to be actually
You got to be actually willing
Radical.
You got to be actually willing to
You got to be actually willing to get
riddled
riddled with
riddled with bullets.
riddled with bullets. That's
riddled with bullets. That's what
riddled with bullets. That's what it
takes
takes to
riddled with bullets. That's what it
takes to walk
takes to walk beyond
riddled with bullets. That's what it
takes to walk beyond identifying
yourself
yourself as
yourself as the
yourself as the physic
yourself as the physic as
yourself as the physic as a
yourself as the physic as a physical
body
and
and giving
and giving in
and giving in and
and giving in and giving
and giving in and giving power
and giving in and giving power to
and giving in and giving power to fear.
So
So it's
and giving in and giving power to fear.
So it's extremely
So it's extremely radical
and giving in and giving power to fear.
So it's extremely radical to
So it's extremely radical to reach
enlightenment
enlightenment is
enlightenment is extremely
enlightenment is extremely demanding
enlightenment is extremely demanding and
you
you can
enlightenment is extremely demanding and
you can be
you can be asked
enlightenment is extremely demanding and
you can be asked to
you can be asked to give
enlightenment is extremely demanding and
you can be asked to give up
you can be asked to give up anything
enlightenment is extremely demanding and
you can be asked to give up anything and
you
you have
you have to
you have to be
you have to be willing
you have to be willing to
you have to be willing to surrender
anything
anything and
you have to be willing to surrender
anything and everything.
anything and everything. When
you have to be willing to surrender
anything and everything. When I
anything and everything. When I said
you have to be willing to surrender
anything and everything. When I said if
that
that music
that music puts
that music puts you
that music puts you in
that music puts you in that
that music puts you in that very
that music puts you in that very unique
divine
divine space
then
then I
then I would
then I would just
then I would just stay
then I would just stay in
then I would just stay in that
then I would just stay in that space.
then I would just stay in that space. I
would
would never
then I would just stay in that space. I
would never do
would never do anything
then I would just stay in that space. I
would never do anything but
would never do anything but play
then I would just stay in that space. I
would never do anything but play the
music
music month
music month after
music month after month
music month after month after
music month after month after month
after
after month.
year
year after
year after year
till
till finally
year after year
till finally one's
till finally one's willing
year after year
till finally one's willing to
till finally one's willing to do
year after year
till finally one's willing to do it
forever.
Instantly
you're
you're into
you're into that
you're into that forever.
So
those
those which
those which are
those which are great
those which are great gains
those which are great gains sometimes
require
require great
those which are great gains sometimes
require great um
require great um commitments
those which are great gains sometimes
require great um commitments and
require great um commitments and great
sacrifices.
So
So when
sacrifices.
So when one
So when one reaches
sacrifices.
So when one reaches a
So when one reaches a certain
sacrifices.
So when one reaches a certain stage
So when one reaches a certain stage you
like
like know
like know it
like know it like
like know it like that
like know it like that like
like know it like that like one
like know it like that like one is
almost
almost compelled
like know it like that like one is
almost compelled to
leave
leave everything
leave everything devote
leave everything devote oneself
leave everything devote oneself to
leave everything devote oneself to a
very
very intense
leave everything devote oneself to a
very intense spirituality
and
and that's
and that's the
and that's the call
and that's the call and
and that's the call and you
and that's the call and you say
and that's the call and you say yes
and that's the call and you say yes to
it
it and
and that's the call and you say yes to
it and then
it and then you
and that's the call and you say yes to
it and then you go
it and then you go for
and that's the call and you say yes to
it and then you go for it
it and then you go for it and
and that's the call and you say yes to
it and then you go for it and you
it and then you go for it and you make
what
what I
what I call
what I call the
what I call the run
what I call the run you
what I call the run you make
what I call the run you make the
what I call the run you make the final
run
run where
what I call the run you make the final
run where nothing
run where nothing stops
what I call the run you make the final
run where nothing stops you
run where nothing stops you nothing
what I call the run you make the final
run where nothing stops you nothing gets
in
in your
in your way
you
you sacrifice
in your way
you sacrifice and
you sacrifice and surrender
in your way
you sacrifice and surrender anything
you sacrifice and surrender anything and
everything
everything that
everything that stands
everything that stands in
everything that stands in the
everything that stands in the way.
everything that stands in the way. The
willingness
willingness to
everything that stands in the way. The
willingness to leave
willingness to leave the
everything that stands in the way. The
willingness to leave the world
willingness to leave the world and
everything
everything in
everything in it,
titles,
titles, the
everything in it,
titles, the riches,
titles, the riches, the
everything in it,
titles, the riches, the family
titles, the riches, the family members,
whatever
whatever it
whatever it takes,
whatever it takes, you
whatever it takes, you walk
whatever it takes, you walk out,
whatever it takes, you walk out, walk
away.
away. Whatever
whatever it takes, you walk out, walk
away. Whatever you
away. Whatever you have
whatever it takes, you walk out, walk
away. Whatever you have to
away. Whatever you have to do,
whatever it takes, you walk out, walk
away. Whatever you have to do, you
away. Whatever you have to do, you have
to
to do.
So
So those
to do.
So those are
So those are the
to do.
So those are the things
So those are the things that
to do.
So those are the things that that
So those are the things that that come
up
up later.
up later. Not
up later. Not this
up later. Not this morning.
You
You don't
up later. Not this morning.
You don't have
You don't have to
up later. Not this morning.
You don't have to leave
You don't have to leave your
up later. Not this morning.
You don't have to leave your car
You don't have to leave your car and
take
take the
take the bus
take the bus today.
take the bus today. No.
the
the collective
take the bus today. No.
the collective consciousness.
the collective consciousness. What
take the bus today. No.
the collective consciousness. What is
the
the effect
the effect of
the effect of the
the effect of the terrorist
the effect of the terrorist attacks?
the effect of the terrorist attacks? I
think
think the
the effect of the terrorist attacks? I
think the effect
think the effect of
the effect of the terrorist attacks? I
think the effect of the
think the effect of the terrorist
attacks
attacks is
attacks is actually
attacks is actually to
attacks is actually to elevate
consciousness.
consciousness. I
attacks is actually to elevate
consciousness. I think
consciousness. I think that
attacks is actually to elevate
consciousness. I think that um
consciousness. I think that um following
that
that we
that we all
that we all became
that we all became more
that we all became more spiritual,
that we all became more spiritual, more
committed
committed to
that we all became more spiritual, more
committed to integrity,
committed to integrity, more
that we all became more spiritual, more
committed to integrity, more to
questioning.
questioning. Um
questioning. Um look
questioning. Um look at
questioning. Um look at the
questioning. Um look at the agonizing
questioning. Um look at the agonizing we
go
go over
questioning. Um look at the agonizing we
go over the
go over the moral
questioning. Um look at the agonizing we
go over the moral agonizing
go over the moral agonizing about
questioning. Um look at the agonizing we
go over the moral agonizing about what
should
should be
should be the
should be the response
should be the response to
should be the response to it.
should be the response to it. Uh
should be the response to it. Uh what
does
does it
should be the response to it. Uh what
does it mean
does it mean to
should be the response to it. Uh what
does it mean to be
does it mean to be patriotic?
should be the response to it. Uh what
does it mean to be patriotic? Um,
does it mean to be patriotic? Um, should
we
we have
we have go
we have go and
we have go and God
we have go and God we
we have go and God we trust
we have go and God we trust on
we have go and God we trust on our
money?
I
I always
I always think
I always think that's
I always think that's so
I always think that's so funny.
I always think that's so funny. It's
I always think that's so funny. It's on
money.
God
God we
God we trust
God we trust on
God we trust on a
God we trust on a dollar
God we trust on a dollar bill.
God we trust on a dollar bill. I
God we trust on a dollar bill. I mean,
there's
there's God
God we trust on a dollar bill. I mean,
there's God in
there's God in money,
God we trust on a dollar bill. I mean,
there's God in money, you
there's God in money, you know,
which
which is
which is more
which is more important.
which is more important. It's
which is more important. It's hard
which is more important. It's hard to
say,
say, man.
which is more important. It's hard to
say, man. Should
say, man. Should we
which is more important. It's hard to
say, man. Should we take
say, man. Should we take God
which is more important. It's hard to
say, man. Should we take God off
say, man. Should we take God off of
which is more important. It's hard to
say, man. Should we take God off of the
money?
Uh
Uh so
money?
Uh so the
Uh so the question
money?
Uh so the question of
Uh so the question of should
money?
Uh so the question of should we
Uh so the question of should we even
allow
allow God
allow God to
allow God to be
allow God to be a
allow God to be a legitimate
allow God to be a legitimate um
expression
expression of
allow God to be a legitimate um
expression of what
expression of what is
allow God to be a legitimate um
expression of what is the
expression of what is the difference
between
between national
between national being
between national being nationalistic
between national being nationalistic and
and
and um
what
what should
what should one's
what should one's relationship
what should one's relationship to
what should one's relationship to one's
country
country be
what should one's relationship to one's
country be and
country be and to
what should one's relationship to one's
country be and to what
country be and to what degree
what should one's relationship to one's
country be and to what degree and
country be and to what degree and in
what
what context.
what context. So
what context. So I
what context. So I think
what context. So I think there's
what context. So I think there's a
what context. So I think there's a great
deal
deal of
what context. So I think there's a great
deal of of
deal of of benefit
what context. So I think there's a great
deal of of benefit to
deal of of benefit to the
what context. So I think there's a great
deal of of benefit to the country.
deal of of benefit to the country. is
what context. So I think there's a great
deal of of benefit to the country. is a
real
real live
real live awakening
real live awakening to
real live awakening to uh
real live awakening to uh the
real live awakening to uh the reality
real live awakening to uh the reality of
spiritual
spiritual and
real live awakening to uh the reality of
spiritual and and
spiritual and and theological
real live awakening to uh the reality of
spiritual and and theological questions
and
and uh
and uh unfortunately
and uh unfortunately those
and uh unfortunately those who
and uh unfortunately those who do
and uh unfortunately those who do the
voting
voting and
and uh unfortunately those who do the
voting and talking
voting and talking most
and uh unfortunately those who do the
voting and talking most of
voting and talking most of the
and uh unfortunately those who do the
voting and talking most of the time
don't
don't know
don't know the
don't know the difference
don't know the difference between
religion
religion and
don't know the difference between
religion and spirituality
religion and spirituality that's
don't know the difference between
religion and spirituality that's the
difficulty
difficulty their
difficulty their difficulty
difficulty their difficulty is
difficulty their difficulty is they
don't
don't understand
difficulty their difficulty is they
don't understand the
don't understand the constitution
difficulty their difficulty is they
don't understand the constitution to
don't understand the constitution to get
elected
elected to
elected to the
elected to the congress
elected to the congress you
elected to the congress you don't
elected to the congress you don't have
to
to understand
elected to the congress you don't have
to understand the
to understand the constitution
I
I myself
I myself would
I myself would make
I myself would make them
I myself would make them all
I myself would make them all pass
I myself would make them all pass a
I myself would make them all pass a test
of
of whether
I myself would make them all pass a test
of whether they
of whether they understand
I myself would make them all pass a test
of whether they understand the
constitution
constitution of
constitution of the
constitution of the United
constitution of the United States
constitution of the United States before
they
they swear
constitution of the United States before
they swear to
they swear to uphold
constitution of the United States before
they swear to uphold it.
Uphold
Uphold what
Uphold what idiot?
Uphold what idiot? You
Uphold what idiot? You don't
Uphold what idiot? You don't know
Uphold what idiot? You don't know the
difference
difference between
Uphold what idiot? You don't know the
difference between the
difference between the religion
Uphold what idiot? You don't know the
difference between the religion of
spirituality.
It
It cal
spirituality.
It cal kind
It cal kind of
spirituality.
It cal kind of you
It cal kind of you know
spirituality.
It cal kind of you know the
It cal kind of you know the the
spirituality.
It cal kind of you know the the uh
constitution
constitution United
constitution United States
constitution United States calibrates
and
and in
constitution United States calibrates
and in the
and in the 700s
constitution United States calibrates
and in the 700s it
and in the 700s it says
constitution United States calibrates
and in the 700s it says that
by
by virtue
by virtue of
by virtue of the
by virtue of the divinity
by virtue of the divinity of
by virtue of the divinity of our
by virtue of the divinity of our origin
that
that is
by virtue of the divinity of our origin
that is the
that is the source
by virtue of the divinity of our origin
that is the source of
that is the source of our
by virtue of the divinity of our origin
that is the source of our equality
and
and out
and out of
and out of that
and out of that equality
then
then we
and out of that equality
then we acknowledge
then we acknowledge God
and out of that equality
then we acknowledge God as
then we acknowledge God as our
and out of that equality
then we acknowledge God as our source
and
and out
and out of
and out of acknowledging
and out of acknowledging our
and out of acknowledging our God
and out of acknowledging our God as
and out of acknowledging our God as as
source
Therefore,
Therefore, we
Therefore, we establish
Therefore, we establish no
Therefore, we establish no religion.
It's
It's because
Therefore, we establish no religion.
It's because of
It's because of the
Therefore, we establish no religion.
It's because of the powerful
It's because of the powerful truth
Therefore, we establish no religion.
It's because of the powerful truth of
spirituality
that
that the
spirituality
that the state
that the state shall
spirituality
that the state shall establish
that the state shall establish no
religion.
religion. And
religion. And in
religion. And in enforcing
religion. And in enforcing the
spiritual
spiritual truth,
religion. And in enforcing the
spiritual truth, then
spiritual truth, then it
religion. And in enforcing the
spiritual truth, then it guarantees
spiritual truth, then it guarantees the
freedom
freedom of
freedom of religion
freedom of religion because
freedom of religion because the
freedom of religion because the the
government
government shall
freedom of religion because the the
government shall neither
government shall neither prohibit
freedom of religion because the the
government shall neither prohibit nor
establish
establish a
establish a religion.
establish a religion. In
establish a religion. In other
establish a religion. In other words,
the
the government
because
because its
because its source
because its source is
because its source is spiritual
because its source is spiritual truth
keeps
keeps its
because its source is spiritual truth
keeps its hand
keeps its hand off
because its source is spiritual truth
keeps its hand off all
keeps its hand off all religions
neither.
So
So the
neither.
So the word
So the word God
neither.
So the word God is
So the word God is merely
neither.
So the word God is merely a
So the word God is merely a word
neither.
So the word God is merely a word is
merely
merely a
merely a word
merely a word and
merely a word and to
merely a word and to say
to
to reiterate
merely a word and to say
to reiterate the
to reiterate the source
merely a word and to say
to reiterate the source of
to reiterate the source of the
merely a word and to say
to reiterate the source of the power
to reiterate the source of the power of
the
the constitution
does
does not
the constitution
does not establish
does not establish religion.
the constitution
does not establish religion. So
does not establish religion. So the
objection
objection to
objection to it
objection to it was
first
first of
objection to it was
first of all
first of all it
objection to it was
first of all it does
first of all it does not
objection to it was
first of all it does not say
first of all it does not say in
objection to it was
first of all it does not say in it
first of all it does not say in it that
um
so
so the
um
so the political
so the political opposition
um
so the political opposition to
so the political opposition to it
um
so the political opposition to it was
confusing.
confusing. Oh
confusing. Oh that
confusing. Oh that that
confusing. Oh that that uh
confusing. Oh that that uh government
shall
shall not
confusing. Oh that that uh government
shall not establish
shall not establish a
confusing. Oh that that uh government
shall not establish a religion.
shall not establish a religion. See
confusing. Oh that that uh government
shall not establish a religion. See but
to
to mention
to mention the
to mention the word
to mention the word God
to mention the word God as
to mention the word God as the
to mention the word God as the source
to mention the word God as the source of
man's
man's origin
to mention the word God as the source of
man's origin is
man's origin is not
to mention the word God as the source of
man's origin is not a
man's origin is not a religion.
to mention the word God as the source of
man's origin is not a religion. That
man's origin is not a religion. That is
not
not a
not a religion.
So
So one
not a religion.
So one is
So one is free
not a religion.
So one is free to
So one is free to talk
not a religion.
So one is free to talk about
So one is free to talk about Satan
not a religion.
So one is free to talk about Satan in
colleges.
colleges. Is
colleges. Is it
colleges. Is it college?
colleges. Is it college? You
colleges. Is it college? You just
established
established the
colleges. Is it college? You just
established the Satan
established the Satan club.
Would
Would you
Would you believe
Would you believe a
Would you believe a Satan
Would you believe a Satan club?
And
And uh
Would you believe a Satan club?
And uh goes
And uh goes with
Would you believe a Satan club?
And uh goes with a
And uh goes with a lot
Would you believe a Satan club?
And uh goes with a lot of
And uh goes with a lot of music
Would you believe a Satan club?
And uh goes with a lot of music that
And uh goes with a lot of music that we
hear
hear in
hear in the
hear in the MTV
hear in the MTV and
hear in the MTV and all.
hear in the MTV and all. Guess
hear in the MTV and all. Guess that's
the
the music
hear in the MTV and all. Guess that's
the music goes
the music goes with
hear in the MTV and all. Guess that's
the music goes with the
the music goes with the saint
hear in the MTV and all. Guess that's
the music goes with the saint club.
the music goes with the saint club. So
it's
it's it's
it's it's an
it's it's an odd
it's it's an odd paradox.
that
that it's
it's it's an odd paradox.
that it's okay
that it's okay to
it's it's an odd paradox.
that it's okay to establish
that it's okay to establish a
it's it's an odd paradox.
that it's okay to establish a Satan
club,
club, but
club, but it
club, but it is
club, but it is not
club, but it is not okay
club, but it is not okay to
club, but it is not okay to mention
club, but it is not okay to mention God.
So
So that's
club, but it is not okay to mention God.
So that's a
So that's a peculiar
club, but it is not okay to mention God.
So that's a peculiar perversion
So that's a peculiar perversion of
truth,
truth, which
truth, which which
truth, which which is
truth, which which is based
truth, which which is based on
truth, which which is based on a
luciferic
luciferic energy.
truth, which which is based on a
luciferic energy. The
luciferic energy. The luciferic
truth, which which is based on a
luciferic energy. The luciferic likes
luciferic energy. The luciferic likes to
turn
turn things
turn things into
turn things into their
turn things into their opposites
turn things into their opposites so
turn things into their opposites so that
you
you become
turn things into their opposites so that
you become the
you become the defender
turn things into their opposites so that
you become the defender of
you become the defender of evil
turn things into their opposites so that
you become the defender of evil in
you become the defender of evil in the
name
name of
name of truth.
When
When Bin
name of truth.
When Bin Laden's
When Bin Laden's last
name of truth.
When Bin Laden's last days
When Bin Laden's last days arise,
name of truth.
When Bin Laden's last days arise, you
can
can be
can be sure
can be sure they'll
can be sure they'll all
can be sure they'll all be
can be sure they'll all be out
can be sure they'll all be out there
with
with the
can be sure they'll all be out there
with the plaque
with the plaque cards.
can be sure they'll all be out there
with the plaque cards. Spin
with the plaque cards. Spin Roden's
rights
rights are
rights are being
rights are being violated.
We
We got
rights are being violated.
We got the
We got the 3,000
rights are being violated.
We got the 3,000 people
We got the 3,000 people in
rights are being violated.
We got the 3,000 people in their
families
families and
families and all
families and all the
families and all the rest
families and all the rest of
families and all the rest of us
families and all the rest of us sitting
around
around in
families and all the rest of us sitting
around in the
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So that
All right. So that confusion
All right. So that confusion of
All right. So that confusion of truth
then
then the
All right. So that confusion of truth
then the luciferic
then the luciferic energy
All right. So that confusion of truth
then the luciferic energy tries
then the luciferic energy tries to
reverse
reverse good
reverse good and
reverse good and evil
reverse good and evil and
reverse good and evil and make
reverse good and evil and make and
reverse good and evil and make and make
them
them look
reverse good and evil and make and make
them look look
them look look like
reverse good and evil and make and make
them look look like they're
them look look like they're opposites.
So
So I
So I think
So I think the
So I think the country
So I think the country is
So I think the country is looking
So I think the country is looking at
that
that you
So I think the country is looking at
that you know
that you know is
So I think the country is looking at
that you know is confronted
that you know is confronted with
So I think the country is looking at
that you know is confronted with what
that you know is confronted with what is
religion
religion what
religion what is
religion what is spirituality
religion what is spirituality what
religion what is spirituality what is
integrity
what
what is
what is truth
what is truth what
what is truth what is
what is truth what is our
what is truth what is our commitment
what's
what's the
what is truth what is our commitment
what's the difference
what's the difference between
nationalism
nationalism and
nationalism and patriotism
people
people don't
nationalism and patriotism
people don't even
people don't even get
nationalism and patriotism
people don't even get that
people don't even get that they
nationalism and patriotism
people don't even get that they discuss
it
it and
it and they
it and they don't
it and they don't even
it and they don't even know
it and they don't even know the
difference
difference because
it and they don't even know the
difference because nationalism
difference because nationalism is
it and they don't even know the
difference because nationalism is bad
therefore
therefore we
therefore we should
therefore we should not
therefore we should not be
therefore we should not be patriotic
that's
that's confusing
therefore we should not be patriotic
that's confusing two
that's confusing two things
therefore we should not be patriotic
that's confusing two things alto
together
together they're
together they're two
together they're two different
together they're two different domains.
Patriotism
Patriotism comes
together they're two different domains.
Patriotism comes from
Patriotism comes from the
together they're two different domains.
Patriotism comes from the heart.
Nationalism
Nationalism is
Nationalism is a
Nationalism is a political
Nationalism is a political control
technique.
technique. You
Nationalism is a political control
technique. You know,
technique. You know, they're
Nationalism is a political control
technique. You know, they're not
technique. You know, they're not the
same
same thing.
same thing. So,
same thing. So, there's
same thing. So, there's big
same thing. So, there's big mistakes
made
made just
same thing. So, there's big mistakes
made just due
made just due to
same thing. So, there's big mistakes
made just due to ignorance
made just due to ignorance of
same thing. So, there's big mistakes
made just due to ignorance of not
knowing
knowing the
knowing the difference
knowing the difference between
knowing the difference between religion
and
and spirituality,
knowing the difference between religion
and spirituality, not
and spirituality, not knowing
knowing the difference between religion
and spirituality, not knowing the
difference
difference between
difference between patriotism
difference between patriotism and
nationalism.
In
In Nazi
In Nazi Germany,
In Nazi Germany, we
In Nazi Germany, we see
In Nazi Germany, we see the
In Nazi Germany, we see the apex
In Nazi Germany, we see the apex of
nationalism,
nationalism, Deutsland
In Nazi Germany, we see the apex of
nationalism, Deutsland Uber,
nationalism, Deutsland Uber, Alice
and
and and
and and its
and and its appeal.
and and its appeal. So
and and its appeal. So you
and and its appeal. So you can
and and its appeal. So you can see
and and its appeal. So you can see how
people
people would
and and its appeal. So you can see how
people would later
people would later mistrust
and and its appeal. So you can see how
people would later mistrust that.
Patriotism
Patriotism is
Patriotism is love
Patriotism is love for
Patriotism is love for one's
Patriotism is love for one's country.
Love
Love for
Patriotism is love for one's country.
Love for one's
Love for one's country.
Patriotism is love for one's country.
Love for one's country. When
Love for one's country. When you
Patriotism is love for one's country.
Love for one's country. When you love
your
your country,
your country, it
your country, it doesn't
your country, it doesn't have
your country, it doesn't have to
dominate
dominate anybody
your country, it doesn't have to
dominate anybody else.
dominate anybody else. You
your country, it doesn't have to
dominate anybody else. You know,
dominate anybody else. You know, we
don't
don't see
don't see America
don't see America invading
don't see America invading Canada,
invading
invading Mexico,
don't see America invading Canada,
invading Mexico, taking
invading Mexico, taking over
don't see America invading Canada,
invading Mexico, taking over the
Caribbean.
Caribbean. You
Caribbean. You see
Caribbean. You see what
Caribbean. You see what I'm
Caribbean. You see what I'm saying?
Caribbean. You see what I'm saying? It's
sufficient
sufficient unto
Caribbean. You see what I'm saying? It's
sufficient unto itself
sufficient unto itself to
Caribbean. You see what I'm saying? It's
sufficient unto itself to love
sufficient unto itself to love one's
country
country is
country is to
country is to love
country is to love one's
country is to love one's fellow
country is to love one's fellow man.
Mhm.
As
As far
As far as
As far as walk-ins
and
and soul
As far as walk-ins
and soul exchangers,
that's
that's an
that's an illusion.
that's an illusion. Just
that's an illusion. Just Yeah,
that's an illusion. Just Yeah, that's
that's an illusion. Just Yeah, that's an
illusion.
illusion. That's
that's an illusion. Just Yeah, that's an
illusion. That's some
illusion. That's some kind
that's an illusion. Just Yeah, that's an
illusion. That's some kind of
illusion. That's some kind of a
that's an illusion. Just Yeah, that's an
illusion. That's some kind of a pop
spirituality
spirituality concept
spirituality concept that
spirituality concept that there's
walk-ins
walk-ins and
spirituality concept that there's
walk-ins and then
walk-ins and then there
spirituality concept that there's
walk-ins and then there were
walk-ins and then there were people
spirituality concept that there's
walk-ins and then there were people with
the
the tailbones
the tailbones missing
the tailbones missing and
the tailbones missing and there
the tailbones missing and there were
the tailbones missing and there were the
they're
they're all
the tailbones missing and there were the
they're all there's
they're all there's all
the tailbones missing and there were the
they're all there's all the
they're all there's all the they're
the tailbones missing and there were the
they're all there's all the they're all
looking
looking for
looking for specialness.
looking for specialness. It's
looking for specialness. It's all
looking
looking for
looking for specialness. It's all
looking for a
looking for a specialness.
Um
looking
looking for
Um
looking for a
looking for a specialist
specialist
to
to be
specialist
to be special.
to be special. Um
specialist
to be special. Um one
to be special. Um one doesn't
specialist
to be special. Um one doesn't need
to be special. Um one doesn't need to
specialist
to be special. Um one doesn't need to be
special.
special. You
special. You see
special. You see when
special. You see when you
special. You see when you surrender
special. You see when you surrender all
to
to God,
special. You see when you surrender all
to God, humility
to God, humility means
special. You see when you surrender all
to God, humility means there's
to God, humility means there's no
special. You see when you surrender all
to God, humility means there's no need
to
to be
to be special.
to be special. There's
to be special. There's no
to be special. There's no need
to be special. There's no need for
recognition.
recognition. There's
to be special. There's no need for
recognition. There's no
recognition. There's no need
to be special. There's no need for
recognition. There's no need for
recognition. There's no need for titles,
possessions,
possessions, control.
possessions, control. One
possessions, control. One doesn't
possessions, control. One doesn't want
followers,
followers, money,
possessions, control. One doesn't want
followers, money, don't
followers, money, don't have
possessions, control. One doesn't want
followers, money, don't have to
followers, money, don't have to have
possessions, control. One doesn't want
followers, money, don't have to have uh
membership.
membership. People
membership. People don't
membership. People don't have
membership. People don't have to
membership. People don't have to sign
up.
up. You
membership. People don't have to sign
up. You don't
up. You don't have
membership. People don't have to sign
up. You don't have to
up. You don't have to remember
membership. People don't have to sign
up. You don't have to remember the
up. You don't have to remember the club.
You
You don't
You don't have
You don't have to
You don't have to go
You don't have to go through
You don't have to go through initiation.
We
We don't
You don't have to go through initiation.
We don't put
We don't put a
You don't have to go through initiation.
We don't put a rattlesnake
We don't put a rattlesnake in
You don't have to go through initiation.
We don't put a rattlesnake in your
mailbox
mailbox if
mailbox if you
mailbox if you decide
mailbox if you decide to
mailbox if you decide to leave.
No.
No. Spirituality
mailbox if you decide to leave.
No. Spirituality means
No. Spirituality means freedom
mailbox if you decide to leave.
No. Spirituality means freedom to
No. Spirituality means freedom to u
mailbox if you decide to leave.
No. Spirituality means freedom to u be
where
where you
where you want
where you want to
where you want to be
where you want to be for
where you want to be for the
where you want to be for the benefit
where you want to be for the benefit of
being
being there
because
because the
because the karmic
because the karmic merit
because the karmic merit is
because the karmic merit is your
because the karmic merit is your own
decision
decision to
because the karmic merit is your own
decision to be
decision to be there
because the karmic merit is your own
decision to be there for
decision to be there for its
because the karmic merit is your own
decision to be there for its own
decision to be there for its own sake.
If
If you're
If you're going
If you're going to
If you're going to church
If you're going to church because
If you're going to church because you'll
go
go to
If you're going to church because you'll
go to hell
go to hell if
If you're going to church because you'll
go to hell if you
go to hell if you don't
If you're going to church because you'll
go to hell if you don't go
go to hell if you don't go to
If you're going to church because you'll
go to hell if you don't go to church,
what
what is
what is the
what is the karmic
what is the karmic merit
what is the karmic merit in
what is the karmic merit in that?
Spiritual
Spiritual growth
what is the karmic merit in that?
Spiritual growth comes
Spiritual growth comes from
what is the karmic merit in that?
Spiritual growth comes from saying
Spiritual growth comes from saying yes
to
to that
to that which
to that which is
to that which is positive,
to that which is positive, seeking
to that which is positive, seeking that
which
which you
to that which is positive, seeking that
which you feel
which you feel beneficial
and
and and
and and and
and and and not
and and and not avoiding
and and and not avoiding the
and and and not avoiding the negative
but
but choosing
and and and not avoiding the negative
but choosing the
but choosing the positive.
and and and not avoiding the negative
but choosing the positive. So
but choosing the positive. So the
and and and not avoiding the negative
but choosing the positive. So the way
out
out of
out of the
out of the duality
out of the duality of
out of the duality of good
out of the duality of good and
out of the duality of good and evil
out of the duality of good and evil and
good
good and
out of the duality of good and evil and
good and bad
good and bad is
out of the duality of good and evil and
good and bad is to
good and bad is to choose
out of the duality of good and evil and
good and bad is to choose choose
good and bad is to choose choose the
good.
good. Choose
good. Choose the
good. Choose the positive.
good. Choose the positive. There's
good. Choose the positive. There's no
point
point in
good. Choose the positive. There's no
point in battling
point in battling evil
good. Choose the positive. There's no
point in battling evil and
point in battling evil and because
good. Choose the positive. There's no
point in battling evil and because you
then
then just
then just give
then just give it
then just give it some
then just give it some kind
then just give it some kind of
then just give it some kind of reality
and
and energy
then just give it some kind of reality
and energy of
and energy of reality.
then just give it some kind of reality
and energy of reality. No,
and energy of reality. No, what
then just give it some kind of reality
and energy of reality. No, what you
and energy of reality. No, what you do
is
is you
is you you
is you you choose
is you you choose uh
is you you choose uh the
is you you choose uh the way
is you you choose uh the way out
is you you choose uh the way out of
is you you choose uh the way out of that
one
one is
is you you choose uh the way out of that
one is you
one is you merely
is you you choose uh the way out of that
one is you merely choose
one is you merely choose the
is you you choose uh the way out of that
one is you merely choose the good.
one is you merely choose the good. You
might
might say
might say you
choose
choose truth
might say you
choose truth over
choose truth over falsehood.
uh
can
can well
uh
can well it's
can well it's true
uh
can well it's true that
can well it's true that with
uh
can well it's true that with kinesiology
and
and with
and with karmic
and with karmic research
and with karmic research you
and with karmic research you can
discover
discover the
and with karmic research you can
discover the source
discover the source of
and with karmic research you can
discover the source of a
discover the source of a lot
and with karmic research you can
discover the source of a lot of
discover the source of a lot of things
now
now there
now there a
now there a lot
now there a lot of
now there a lot of people
now there a lot of people that
now there a lot of people that write
books
books on
now there a lot of people that write
books on past
books on past life
now there a lot of people that write
books on past life research
books on past life research I
now there a lot of people that write
books on past life research I don't
books on past life research I don't know
all
all their
all their names
all their names uh
all their names uh but
all their names uh but there
all their names uh but there are
specialists
specialists in
all their names uh but there are
specialists in it
specialists in it and
there
there are
there are very
there are very various
there are very various techniques
there's
there's simple
there are very various techniques
there's simple hypnotic
there's simple hypnotic techniques
there are very various techniques
there's simple hypnotic techniques where
you
you count
you count back
you count back and
you count back and you
you count back and you go
you count back and you go to
you count back and you go to a
you count back and you go to a certain
time
time and
you count back and you go to a certain
time and you
time and you come
you count back and you go to a certain
time and you come up
time and you come up the
you count back and you go to a certain
time and you come up the elevator
time and you come up the elevator and
you
you step
you step out
you step out and
you step out and then
you step out and then the
you step out and then the whole
you step out and then the whole panoram
begins
begins to
you step out and then the whole panoram
begins to to
begins to to present
you step out and then the whole panoram
begins to to present itself
and
and u
and u with
and u with that
and u with that there's
and u with that there's often
and u with that there's often a
recognition.
recognition. A
and u with that there's often a
recognition. A lot
recognition. A lot of
and u with that there's often a
recognition. A lot of times
recognition. A lot of times you
and u with that there's often a
recognition. A lot of times you suddenly
remember
remember if
remember if it's
remember if it's valid
remember if it's valid you'll
remember if it's valid you'll remember
it.
it. It's
remember if it's valid you'll remember
it. It's not
it. It's not just
remember if it's valid you'll remember
it. It's not just uh
it. It's not just uh a
remember if it's valid you'll remember
it. It's not just uh a recall
it. It's not just uh a recall in
remember if it's valid you'll remember
it. It's not just uh a recall in sort
it. It's not just uh a recall in sort of
a
a trance
a trance state.
a trance state. You
a trance state. You frankly
a trance state. You frankly remember
a trance state. You frankly remember it
and
and uh
a trance state. You frankly remember it
and uh you
and uh you remember
a trance state. You frankly remember it
and uh you remember the
and uh you remember the circumstances
sometimes
sometimes you
sometimes you wish
sometimes you wish you
sometimes you wish you didn't.
You
You remember
sometimes you wish you didn't.
You remember the
You remember the circumstances
sometimes you wish you didn't.
You remember the circumstances right
You remember the circumstances right and
that
that may
that may start
that may start a
that may start a train
that may start a train of
that may start a train of them
that may start a train of them in
that may start a train of them in which
you
you can
that may start a train of them in which
you can remember
you can remember quite
that may start a train of them in which
you can remember quite a
you can remember quite a few
that may start a train of them in which
you can remember quite a few lifetimes.
You
You know
You know you
You know you can
You know you can without
You know you can without much
You know you can without much difficulty
remember
remember really
You know you can without much difficulty
remember really quite
remember really quite a
You know you can without much difficulty
remember really quite a few
remember really quite a few lifetimes.
Uh-huh.
Uh-huh. And
Uh-huh. And then
Uh-huh. And then at
Uh-huh. And then at a
Uh-huh. And then at a certain
Uh-huh. And then at a certain level
Uh-huh. And then at a certain level of
consciousness
um
um because
um because you
um because you don't
um because you don't identify
um because you don't identify with
um because you don't identify with this
physicality
uh
uh you
uh you identify
uh you identify more
uh you identify more with
uh you identify more with the
uh you identify more with the evolution
of
of consciousness
um
um back
um back through
um back through time.
um back through time. And
um back through time. And then
um back through time. And then there's
the
the recall
um back through time. And then there's
the recall and
the recall and awareness
um back through time. And then there's
the recall and awareness of
the recall and awareness of all
um back through time. And then there's
the recall and awareness of all kinds
the recall and awareness of all kinds of
lifetimes.
and
and usually
lifetimes.
and usually with
and usually with an
lifetimes.
and usually with an awareness
and usually with an awareness of
lifetimes.
and usually with an awareness of what
what
what the
what the uh
what the uh purpose
what the uh purpose of
what the uh purpose of that
what the uh purpose of that encounter
was.
Uh
Uh can
Uh can you
Uh can you find
Uh can you find out
Uh can you find out spiritual
Uh can you find out spiritual truths
Uh can you find out spiritual truths for
a
a third
Uh can you find out spiritual truths for
a third person?
a third person? Yes,
Uh can you find out spiritual truths for
a third person? Yes, you
a third person? Yes, you can
Uh can you find out spiritual truths for
a third person? Yes, you can do
a third person? Yes, you can do that.
And
And uh
And uh a
And uh a lot
And uh a lot of
And uh a lot of times,
And uh a lot of times, you
And uh a lot of times, you know,
And uh a lot of times, you know, we
And uh a lot of times, you know, we do
do
do it
And uh a lot of times, you know, we do
do it once
do it once in
And uh a lot of times, you know, we do
do it once in a
do it once in a while
And uh a lot of times, you know, we do
do it once in a while uh
do it once in a while uh on
And uh a lot of times, you know, we do
do it once in a while uh on behalf
do it once in a while uh on behalf of
someone
someone else
someone else at
someone else at their
someone else at their request
u
u because
someone else at their request
u because they
u because they don't
someone else at their request
u because they don't have
u because they don't have a
someone else at their request
u because they don't have a partner
u because they don't have a partner to
do
do it
do it and
do it and etc.
do it and etc. and
do it and etc. and they'll
do it and etc. and they'll say
do it and etc. and they'll say um
do it and etc. and they'll say um you
know
know could
do it and etc. and they'll say um you
know could you
know could you ask
do it and etc. and they'll say um you
know could you ask this
know could you ask this or
do it and etc. and they'll say um you
know could you ask this or that
know could you ask this or that for
do it and etc. and they'll say um you
know could you ask this or that for me?
So
So there
So there you
So there you have
So there you have to
So there you have to get
So there you have to get karmic
permission.
permission. You
So there you have to get karmic
permission. You have
permission. You have to
So there you have to get karmic
permission. You have to get
permission. You have to get their
permission
permission and
permission and you
permission and you also
permission and you also have
permission and you also have to
permission and you also have to ask
because
because sometimes
permission and you also have to ask
because sometimes it's
because sometimes it's a
permission and you also have to ask
because sometimes it's a merely
because sometimes it's a merely a
permission and you also have to ask
because sometimes it's a merely a way
the
the person's
the person's bypassing
the person's bypassing facing
the person's bypassing facing a
spiritual
spiritual task
the person's bypassing facing a
spiritual task that
spiritual task that they've
the person's bypassing facing a
spiritual task that they've got
spiritual task that they've got to
handle
handle with
handle with themsel
handle with themsel you
handle with themsel you know.
handle with themsel you know. So
sometimes
sometimes kinesiology
handle with themsel you know. So
sometimes kinesiology can
sometimes kinesiology can be
handle with themsel you know. So
sometimes kinesiology can be used
sometimes kinesiology can be used more
to
to escape
to escape spiritual
to escape spiritual responsibility
rather
rather than
to escape spiritual responsibility
rather than than
rather than than um
to escape spiritual responsibility
rather than than um actually
rather than than um actually advance
your
your own
your own consciousness.
Um,
well,
well, this
well, this is
well, this is a
well, this is a good
well, this is a good one.
well, this is a good one. Now
well, this is a good one. Now that
well, this is a good one. Now that we
know
know causality,
well, this is a good one. Now that we
know causality, what
know causality, what now
well, this is a good one. Now that we
know causality, what now that
know causality, what now that we
well, this is a good one. Now that we
know causality, what now that we know
causality,
causality, now
causality, now that
causality, now that we
causality, now that we don't
causality, now that we don't know
causality,
causality, what
causality, now that we don't know
causality, what does
causality, what does it
causality, now that we don't know
causality, what does it mean
causality, what does it mean when
causality, now that we don't know
causality, what does it mean when you
think
think you
think you are
think you are making
think you are making progress
in
in your
think you are making progress
in your spiritual
in your spiritual work
think you are making progress
in your spiritual work and
in your spiritual work and all
think you are making progress
in your spiritual work and all of a
sudden
sudden it
sudden it all
sudden it all goes
sudden it all goes down
sudden it all goes down the
sudden it all goes down the drain?
Sudden
Sudden severe
sudden it all goes down the drain?
Sudden severe storm.
Sudden severe storm. Everything
sudden it all goes down the drain?
Sudden severe storm. Everything is
Sudden severe storm. Everything is in
chaos
chaos and
chaos and all
chaos and all the
chaos and all the garbage
chaos and all the garbage of
chaos and all the garbage of your
chaos and all the garbage of your life
comes
comes out.
chaos and all the garbage of your life
comes out. Oh,
comes out. Oh, it
chaos and all the garbage of your life
comes out. Oh, it means
comes out. Oh, it means you're
chaos and all the garbage of your life
comes out. Oh, it means you're making
fantastic
fantastic progress.
When
When you're
fantastic progress.
When you're BSing
When you're BSing around
fantastic progress.
When you're BSing around in
When you're BSing around in your
fantastic progress.
When you're BSing around in your head
and
and thinking
and thinking you're
and thinking you're doing
and thinking you're doing spirituality,
nothing
nothing really
and thinking you're doing spirituality,
nothing really much
nothing really much happens.
and thinking you're doing spirituality,
nothing really much happens. When
nothing really much happens. When you
get
get serious
get serious about
get serious about it,
get serious about it, all
get serious about it, all kinds
get serious about it, all kinds of
get serious about it, all kinds of stuff
can
can come
get serious about it, all kinds of stuff
can come out
can come out of
get serious about it, all kinds of stuff
can come out of the
can come out of the woodwork.
get serious about it, all kinds of stuff
can come out of the woodwork. And
can come out of the woodwork. And uh
that's
that's quite
that's quite true.
that's quite true. So
that's quite true. So the
that's quite true. So the lives
that's quite true. So the lives of
spiritual
spiritual seekers
that's quite true. So the lives of
spiritual seekers is
spiritual seekers is often
that's quite true. So the lives of
spiritual seekers is often quite
turbulent,
turbulent, quite
turbulent, quite turbulent
because
because uh
turbulent, quite turbulent
because uh it
because uh it tends
turbulent, quite turbulent
because uh it tends to
because uh it tends to bring
turbulent, quite turbulent
because uh it tends to bring up
uh
the
the calibration
uh
the calibration of
the calibration of various
uh
the calibration of various spiritual
teachers
teachers um
teachers um is
teachers um is somewhat
teachers um is somewhat difficult
teachers um is somewhat difficult to
explain.
Many
Many people
Many people spiritual
Many people spiritual teachers
Many people spiritual teachers and
otherwise
otherwise calibrate
Many people spiritual teachers and
otherwise calibrate quite
otherwise calibrate quite high
Many people spiritual teachers and
otherwise calibrate quite high do
otherwise calibrate quite high do good
very
very very
very very good
very very good work
very very good work in
very very good work in the
very very good work in the world
very very good work in the world attain
recognition
recognition power
very very good work in the world attain
recognition power financial
recognition power financial gain
very very good work in the world attain
recognition power financial gain etc
recognition power financial gain etc etc
elected
elected the
elected the elected
elected the elected president
elected the elected president of
elected the elected president of their
country
country and
elected the elected president of their
country and then
country and then and
elected the elected president of their
country and then and then
they
they crash
they crash then
they crash then it
they crash then it goes
they crash then it goes to
they crash then it goes to their
they crash then it goes to their head
you
you might
they crash then it goes to their head
you might say
you might say the
they crash then it goes to their head
you might say the luciferic
you might say the luciferic energy
they crash then it goes to their head
you might say the luciferic energy of
power
power money
power money control
power money control so
power money control so we
power money control so we see
power money control so we see a
power money control so we see a lot
power money control so we see a lot of
people
people not
power money control so we see a lot of
people not just
people not just gurus
power money control so we see a lot of
people not just gurus who
people not just gurus who write
power money control so we see a lot of
people not just gurus who write their
let's
let's say
let's say there's
let's say there's gurus
let's say there's gurus that
let's say there's gurus that write
let's say there's gurus that write books
that
that are
let's say there's gurus that write books
that are in
that are in They're
let's say there's gurus that write books
that are in They're usually
that are in They're usually in
let's say there's gurus that write books
that are in They're usually in the
that are in They're usually in the high
500s.
500s. They
500s. They gain
500s. They gain a
500s. They gain a lot
500s. They gain a lot of
500s. They gain a lot of followers.
500s. They gain a lot of followers. Then
somehow
somehow the
500s. They gain a lot of followers. Then
somehow the ego
somehow the ego gets
uh
uh pulled
uh pulled into
uh pulled into it
uh pulled into it and
uh pulled into it and they
uh pulled into it and they succumb
uh pulled into it and they succumb to
the
the glamour,
uh pulled into it and they succumb to
the glamour, I
the glamour, I guess,
uh pulled into it and they succumb to
the glamour, I guess, the
the glamour, I guess, the glamour
uh pulled into it and they succumb to
the glamour, I guess, the glamour of
the glamour, I guess, the glamour of all
that.
that. And
that. And then
that. And then you
that. And then you see
that. And then you see that
that. And then you see that suddenly
their
their calibration
that. And then you see that suddenly
their calibration goes
their calibration goes way
that. And then you see that suddenly
their calibration goes way down.
their calibration goes way down. The
book
book they
book they wrote
book they wrote in
book they wrote in the
book they wrote in the 500s
book they wrote in the 500s may
book they wrote in the 500s may still
book they wrote in the 500s may still be
in
in the
book they wrote in the 500s may still be
in the 500s.
in the 500s. They
book they wrote in the 500s may still be
in the 500s. They as
in the 500s. They as a
book they wrote in the 500s may still be
in the 500s. They as a person,
in the 500s. They as a person, as
book they wrote in the 500s may still be
in the 500s. They as a person, as an
entity
entity right
entity right now,
entity right now, may
entity right now, may calibrate
entity right now, may calibrate quite
low.
low. It
entity right now, may calibrate quite
low. It happened
low. It happened with
entity right now, may calibrate quite
low. It happened with Napoleon.
low. It happened with Napoleon. It
happened
happened with
happened with Hitler.
happened with Hitler. Let's
happened with Hitler. Let's just
happened with Hitler. Let's just do
happened with Hitler. Let's just do I
happened with Hitler. Let's just do I so
it's
it's not
happened with Hitler. Let's just do I so
it's not just
it's not just gurus
we
we have
we have uh
we have uh permission
we have uh permission to
we have uh permission to do
we have uh permission to do Napoleon
Napoleon
Napoleon on
we have uh permission to do Napoleon
Napoleon on his
Napoleon on his rise
we have uh permission to do Napoleon
Napoleon on his rise was
Napoleon on his rise was over
we have uh permission to do Napoleon
Napoleon on his rise was over 450
Napoleon on his rise was over 450 460
470 480
470 480 he
470 480 he was
470 480 he was a
470 480 he was a brilliant
470 480 he was a brilliant man
470 480 he was a brilliant man yeah
470 480 he was a brilliant man yeah he
calibrates
calibrates at
470 480 he was a brilliant man yeah he
calibrates at 480
calibrates at 480 that's
470 480 he was a brilliant man yeah he
calibrates at 480 that's very
calibrates at 480 that's very high
intelligence
intelligence he
intelligence he was
intelligence he was probably
intelligence he was probably very
intelligence he was probably very uh
brilliant
brilliant u
intelligence he was probably very uh
brilliant u military
brilliant u military strategist
intelligence he was probably very uh
brilliant u military strategist and
brilliant u military strategist and uh
uh
uh Napoleon
uh Napoleon Okay.
uh Napoleon Okay. Um
uh Napoleon Okay. Um later
uh Napoleon Okay. Um later before
uh Napoleon Okay. Um later before he
died,
died, Napoleon
uh Napoleon Okay. Um later before he
died, Napoleon calibrated
died, Napoleon calibrated over
uh Napoleon Okay. Um later before he
died, Napoleon calibrated over 200
resistance.
See,
See, Napoleon
resistance.
See, Napoleon was
See, Napoleon was 480.
resistance.
See, Napoleon was 480. That's
See, Napoleon was 480. That's really
resistance.
See, Napoleon was 480. That's really way
up
up there.
up there. And
up there. And then
up there. And then somehow
up there. And then somehow being
emperor,
emperor, being
up there. And then somehow being
emperor, being commander,
maybe
maybe the
maybe the maybe
maybe the maybe the
maybe the maybe the accumulated
maybe the maybe the accumulated karma
maybe the maybe the accumulated karma of
killing
killing many
maybe the maybe the accumulated karma of
killing many innocent
killing many innocent people.
maybe the maybe the accumulated karma of
killing many innocent people. Oh,
killing many innocent people. Oh, that
could
could be
could be it.
could be it. I
could be it. I don't
could be it. I don't want
could be it. I don't want to
could be it. I don't want to know
could be it. I don't want to know that.
Anyway,
so
so it
so it can
so it can happen.
so it can happen. I
so it can happen. I think
so it can happen. I think Adolf
so it can happen. I think Adolf Hitler,
we
we have
so it can happen. I think Adolf Hitler,
we have permission
we have permission to
so it can happen. I think Adolf Hitler,
we have permission to ask
we have permission to ask about
so it can happen. I think Adolf Hitler,
we have permission to ask about Adolf
Hitler
Hitler when
Hitler when he
Hitler when he wrote
Hitler when he wrote mine
Hitler when he wrote mine comp
Hitler when he wrote mine comp was
Hitler when he wrote mine comp was over
400,
400, 450,
440,
440, 445.
So
So Hitler
was
was a
was a politician.
was a politician. He
was a politician. He uh
was a politician. He uh stood
was a politician. He uh stood for
was a politician. He uh stood for what
was
was it?
was a politician. He uh stood for what
was it? National
was it? National Socialism
was a politician. He uh stood for what
was it? National Socialism or
was it? National Socialism or something.
And
And he
And he wrote
And he wrote his
And he wrote his political
And he wrote his political treatise
And he wrote his political treatise in
prison.
prison. And
And he wrote his political treatise in
prison. And uh
prison. And uh after
And he wrote his political treatise in
prison. And uh after the
prison. And uh after the push
And he wrote his political treatise in
prison. And uh after the push failed,
he
he was
he was over
he was over 450
he was over 450 at
he was over 450 at the
he was over 450 at the time.
he was over 450 at the time. Uh
he was over 450 at the time. Uh before
he
he died,
he was over 450 at the time. Uh before
he died, Adolf
he died, Adolf Hitler
he was over 450 at the time. Uh before
he died, Adolf Hitler was
he died, Adolf Hitler was over
he was over 450 at the time. Uh before
he died, Adolf Hitler was over 200.
he died, Adolf Hitler was over 200. I
don't
don't want
don't want to
don't want to tell
don't want to tell you
don't want to tell you how
don't want to tell you how low
don't want to tell you how low he
don't want to tell you how low he was,
but
but uh
don't want to tell you how low he was,
but uh so
but uh so you
don't want to tell you how low he was,
but uh so you see,
but uh so you see, it's
don't want to tell you how low he was,
but uh so you see, it's not
but uh so you see, it's not just
don't want to tell you how low he was,
but uh so you see, it's not just gurus,
but
but um
but um the
but um the the
but um the the most
but um the the most startling
but um the the most startling I
but um the the most startling I have
permission
permission to
but um the the most startling I have
permission to share
permission to share this
but um the the most startling I have
permission to share this with
permission to share this with this
group.
group. No,
group. No, resist
group. No, resist to
group. No, resist to share
group. No, resist to share the
group. No, resist to share the most
startling
startling example.
group. No, resist to share the most
startling example. Resist.
I
I have
I have permission
I have permission to
I have permission to share
I have permission to share the
I have permission to share the more
I have permission to share the more the
one
one I'm
I have permission to share the more the
one I'm holding
one I'm holding in
I have permission to share the more the
one I'm holding in mind.
one I'm holding in mind. Resist.
I have permission to share the more the
one I'm holding in mind. Resist. Okay.
There's
There's far
There's far more
There's far more dramatic
There's far more dramatic examples.
All
All right.
You
You get
You get a
You get a no.
You get a no. Sometimes
You get a no. Sometimes the
You get a no. Sometimes the no
You get a no. Sometimes the no can
You get a no. Sometimes the no can be
because
because of
You get a no. Sometimes the no can be
because of the
because of the setting,
You get a no. Sometimes the no can be
because of the setting, because
because of the setting, because of
You get a no. Sometimes the no can be
because of the setting, because of the
way
way the
way the questions
way the questions asked,
way the questions asked, because
way the questions asked, because of
way the questions asked, because of your
intention.
So
So we'll
So we'll have
So we'll have to
So we'll have to re
So we'll have to re search
So we'll have to re search out
So we'll have to re search out later
So we'll have to re search out later why
we
we got
So we'll have to re search out later why
we got the
we got the no.
So we'll have to re search out later why
we got the no. We
we got the no. We don't
So we'll have to re search out later why
we got the no. We don't have
we got the no. We don't have time
So we'll have to re search out later why
we got the no. We don't have time now.
Sometimes
Sometimes you
Sometimes you get
Sometimes you get it
Sometimes you get it because
Sometimes you get it because an
Sometimes you get it because an audience
and
and a
Sometimes you get it because an audience
and a certain
and a certain percentage
Sometimes you get it because an audience
and a certain percentage of
and a certain percentage of the
Sometimes you get it because an audience
and a certain percentage of the audience
may
may get
may get upset
may get upset by
may get upset by the
may get upset by the answer
may get upset by the answer or
may get upset by the answer or something
like
like this.
may get upset by the answer or something
like this. So
like this. So anyhow
may get upset by the answer or something
like this. So anyhow um
it
it can
it can happen
it can happen to
it can happen to anyone
a
a person
it can happen to anyone
a person like
a person like that
it can happen to anyone
a person like that will
a person like that will retain
it can happen to anyone
a person like that will retain the
a person like that will retain the image
of
of what
of what they
of what they were
of what they were when
of what they were when they
of what they were when they were
of what they were when they were in
their
their higher
of what they were when they were in
their higher state
their higher state and
of what they were when they were in
their higher state and people
their higher state and people relate
of what they were when they were in
their higher state and people relate to
that
that image.
Even
Even at
that image.
Even at the
Even at the end
that image.
Even at the end of
Even at the end of the
that image.
Even at the end of the war
Even at the end of the war I'm
that image.
Even at the end of the war I'm sure
there
there were
there were a
there were a lot
there were a lot of
there were a lot of people
there were a lot of people that
there were a lot of people that believed
in
in Hitler.
there were a lot of people that believed
in Hitler. They
in Hitler. They believed
there were a lot of people that believed
in Hitler. They believed in
in Hitler. They believed in him
there were a lot of people that believed
in Hitler. They believed in him still
even
even though
even though he
even though he led
even though he led the
even though he led the country
even though he led the country down
even though he led the country down to
disaster
disaster and
even though he led the country down to
disaster and destruction
disaster and destruction and
even though he led the country down to
disaster and destruction and the
disaster and destruction and the the
destruction
destruction of
destruction of the
destruction of the cologne.
destruction of the cologne. I
destruction of the cologne. I mean
destruction of the cologne. I mean the
beautiful
beautiful cities
destruction of the cologne. I mean the
beautiful cities dri
beautiful cities dri incredible
destruction of the cologne. I mean the
beautiful cities dri incredible beauty
that
that was
that was destroyed
that was destroyed in
that was destroyed in the
that was destroyed in the name
that was destroyed in the name of
that was destroyed in the name of war
that
that in
that was destroyed in the name of war
that in itself
that in itself must
that was destroyed in the name of war
that in itself must have
that in itself must have a
that was destroyed in the name of war
that in itself must have a bad
that in itself must have a bad karmic
consequence
consequence to
consequence to destroy
consequence to destroy so
consequence to destroy so much
consequence to destroy so much beauty.
consequence to destroy so much beauty. U
but
but I'm
consequence to destroy so much beauty. U
but I'm sure
but I'm sure there
consequence to destroy so much beauty. U
but I'm sure there were
but I'm sure there were still
consequence to destroy so much beauty. U
but I'm sure there were still people
that
that believed
that believed in
that believed in him.
that believed in him. So
that believed in him. So the
that believed in him. So the image
that believed in him. So the image may
outlast
outlast the
that believed in him. So the image may
outlast the reality.
outlast the reality. The
that believed in him. So the image may
outlast the reality. The image
outlast the reality. The image outlasts
the
the reality.
the reality. What
the reality. What the
the reality. What the person
the reality. What the person was
the reality. What the person was is
still
still being
the reality. What the person was is
still being glorified
still being glorified or
the reality. What the person was is
still being glorified or respected
and
and they
and they don't
and they don't see
and they don't see what
and they don't see what the
and they don't see what the person
and they don't see what the person is
now.
now. They
and they don't see what the person is
now. They only
now. They only see
and they don't see what the person is
now. They only see what
now. They only see what the
and they don't see what the person is
now. They only see what the person
now. They only see what the person was
at
at their
at their highest
at their highest level
at their highest level of
at their highest level of functioning.
So
So it
at their highest level of functioning.
So it happens
So it happens even
at their highest level of functioning.
So it happens even to
So it happens even to military
commanders
commanders and
commanders and it
commanders and it happens
commanders and it happens to
commanders and it happens to politicians
all
all the
commanders and it happens to politicians
all the time
all the time and
commanders and it happens to politicians
all the time and celebrities
all the time and celebrities of
commanders and it happens to politicians
all the time and celebrities of course.
It
It happens
It happens to
It happens to celebrities
It happens to celebrities uh
It happens to celebrities uh once
It happens to celebrities uh once they
get
get in
It happens to celebrities uh once they
get in the
get in the eye
It happens to celebrities uh once they
get in the eye of
get in the eye of the
um
popularity
popularity and
um
popularity and all
popularity and all the
um
popularity and all the paparazzi
popularity and all the paparazzi are
after
after them
after them etc.
after them etc. Uh
after them etc. Uh it's
after them etc. Uh it's very
after them etc. Uh it's very hard
after them etc. Uh it's very hard for
them
them not
after them etc. Uh it's very hard for
them not to
them not to crash.
after them etc. Uh it's very hard for
them not to crash. I
them not to crash. I feel
after them etc. Uh it's very hard for
them not to crash. I feel sorry
them not to crash. I feel sorry for
them.
them. And
them. And of
them. And of course
them. And of course many
them. And of course many great
them. And of course many great rock
stars
stars and
them. And of course many great rock
stars and all
stars and all we
them. And of course many great rock
stars and all we saw
stars and all we saw them
them. And of course many great rock
stars and all we saw them start
stars and all we saw them start out
humbly
humbly and
humbly and full
humbly and full of
humbly and full of joy
humbly and full of joy and
humbly and full of joy and then
humbly and full of joy and then end
humbly and full of joy and then end up
crashing
crashing and
humbly and full of joy and then end up
crashing and committing
crashing and committing suicide
humbly and full of joy and then end up
crashing and committing suicide and
dying
dying of
dying of drugs
dying of drugs etc.
dying of drugs etc. So
dying of drugs etc. So to
dying of drugs etc. So to take
dying of drugs etc. So to take that
onslaught
onslaught of
dying of drugs etc. So to take that
onslaught of popularity
onslaught of popularity and
dying of drugs etc. So to take that
onslaught of popularity and the
onslaught of popularity and the media,
the
the spotlight
the spotlight of
the spotlight of the
the spotlight of the media,
the spotlight of the media, money,
prestige,
prestige, followers,
the spotlight of the media, money,
prestige, followers, um
prestige, followers, um can
the spotlight of the media, money,
prestige, followers, um can imagine
putting
putting on
putting on a
putting on a concert
putting on a concert and
putting on a concert and having
putting on a concert and having what
putting on a concert and having what do
they
they have
putting on a concert and having what do
they have like
they have like 10,000
putting on a concert and having what do
they have like 10,000 people
they have like 10,000 people out
putting on a concert and having what do
they have like 10,000 people out there?
30,000
30,000 or
30,000 or something.
30,000 or something. It
30,000 or something. It must
30,000 or something. It must be
staggering
staggering for
30,000 or something. It must be
staggering for their
staggering for their ego
30,000 or something. It must be
staggering for their ego to
staggering for their ego to handle
30,000 or something. It must be
staggering for their ego to handle that
and
and not
and not become
and not become grandiose
and not become grandiose and
and not become grandiose and sucked
and not become grandiose and sucked in
by
by the
and not become grandiose and sucked in
by the glamour.
by the glamour. Sucked
and not become grandiose and sucked in
by the glamour. Sucked in
by the glamour. Sucked in by
and not become grandiose and sucked in
by the glamour. Sucked in by the
by the glamour. Sucked in by the glamour
of
of it.
of it. So
of it. So one
of it. So one of
of it. So one of the
of it. So one of the great
of it. So one of the great seducers
of it. So one of the great seducers then
is
is glamour.
of it. So one of the great seducers then
is glamour. One
is glamour. One of
of it. So one of the great seducers then
is glamour. One of the
is glamour. One of the great
of it. So one of the great seducers then
is glamour. One of the great seducers
is glamour. One of the great seducers is
glamour.
glamour. Is
glamour. Is this
glamour. Is this the
glamour. Is this the glamour
glamour. Is this the glamour of
glamour. Is this the glamour of success?
The
The glamour
glamour. Is this the glamour of success?
The glamour of
The glamour of prestige.
Oh
Oh yeah.
Oh yeah. So
Oh yeah. So it
Oh yeah. So it isn't
Oh yeah. So it isn't just
Oh yeah. So it isn't just the
Oh yeah. So it isn't just the prestige
and
and the
Oh yeah. So it isn't just the prestige
and the power.
and the power. It's
Oh yeah. So it isn't just the prestige
and the power. It's the
and the power. It's the glamour
Oh yeah. So it isn't just the prestige
and the power. It's the glamour of
and the power. It's the glamour of it.
There
There was
There was I
There was I think
There was I think a
There was I think a book
There was I think a book written
There was I think a book written by
about
about glamour
There was I think a book written by
about glamour as
about glamour as a
There was I think a book written by
about glamour as a specific
about glamour as a specific energy
written
written by
written by a
written by a member
written by a member of
written by a member of the
written by a member of the white
brotherhood
brotherhood channel
written by a member of the white
brotherhood channel on
brotherhood channel on from
>> Alice.
>> Alice
>> Alice Bailey,
>> Alice.
>> Alice Bailey, right?
>> Alice Bailey, right? Yes.
>> Alice.
>> Alice Bailey, right? Yes. I
>> Alice Bailey, right? Yes. I always
thought
thought the
thought the book
thought the book on
thought the book on glamour
thought the book on glamour was
thought the book on glamour was probably
the
the best
thought the book on glamour was probably
the best of
the best of all
thought the book on glamour was probably
the best of all of
the best of all of them.
thought the book on glamour was probably
the best of all of them. Uh
the best of all of them. Uh that
thought the book on glamour was probably
the best of all of them. Uh that it
the best of all of them. Uh that it is
thought the book on glamour was probably
the best of all of them. Uh that it is a
very
very spec
very spec actually
very spec actually a
very spec actually a specific
very spec actually a specific energy.
Glamour
Glamour we
very spec actually a specific energy.
Glamour we have
Glamour we have permission
very spec actually a specific energy.
Glamour we have permission to
Glamour we have permission to ask
very spec actually a specific energy.
Glamour we have permission to ask that
is
is a
is a specific
is a specific energy.
is a specific energy. You
is a specific energy. You just
is a specific energy. You just know
is a specific energy. You just know it
is
is a
is a specific energy. You just know it
is a specific
is a specific energy.
So
So that's
So that's an
So that's an interesting
So that's an interesting thing
So that's an interesting thing to
So that's an interesting thing to know
that
that certain
So that's an interesting thing to know
that certain accomplishments
that certain accomplishments then
So that's an interesting thing to know
that certain accomplishments then will
attract
attract that
attract that energy
attract that energy of
attract that energy of glamour
attract that energy of glamour which
itself
would
would could
would could lead
would could lead to
would could lead to your
would could lead to your downfall.
You
You become
would could lead to your downfall.
You become captured
You become captured by
would could lead to your downfall.
You become captured by that.
You become captured by that. So
would could lead to your downfall.
You become captured by that. So one
becomes
um
um captured
becomes
um captured by
um captured by that
becomes
um captured by that energy
um captured by that energy of
becomes
um captured by that energy of glamour,
seduced
seduced by
seduced by it.
seduced by it. Resist
seduced by it. Resist captivated
seduced by it. Resist captivated by
seduced by it. Resist captivated by it.
Oh
Oh and
seduced by it. Resist captivated by it.
Oh and enslaved
Oh and enslaved by
seduced by it. Resist captivated by it.
Oh and enslaved by it.
Oh and enslaved by it. Uh
seduced by it. Resist captivated by it.
Oh and enslaved by it. Uh oh
Oh and enslaved by it. Uh oh becomes
enslaved
enslaved by
enslaved by it.
enslaved by it. Uhhuh.
So
So that
enslaved by it. Uhhuh.
So that would
So that would explain
enslaved by it. Uhhuh.
So that would explain then
So that would explain then the
enslaved by it. Uhhuh.
So that would explain then the fall
So that would explain then the fall of
many
many u
many u the
many u the glamour.
All
All right.
many u the glamour.
All right. So
All right. So I
many u the glamour.
All right. So I hope
All right. So I hope we've
many u the glamour.
All right. So I hope we've asked
answered
answered most
answered most of
answered most of the
answered most of the questions.
answered most of the questions. Is
answered most of the questions. Is there
any
any more
answered most of the questions. Is there
any more that
any more that we
answered most of the questions. Is there
any more that we want
any more that we want to
answered most of the questions. Is there
any more that we want to answer
any more that we want to answer before
we
we go?
we go? We're
we go? We're going
we go? We're going to
we go? We're going to quit
we go? We're going to quit a
we go? We're going to quit a little
we go? We're going to quit a little a
little
little early
we go? We're going to quit a little a
little early tonight
little early tonight because
we go? We're going to quit a little a
little early tonight because I
little early tonight because I still
want
want to
want to say
want to say uh
want to say uh I
want to say uh I want
want to say uh I want to
want to say uh I want to sign
want to say uh I want to sign books
want to say uh I want to sign books and
greet
greet people
want to say uh I want to sign books and
greet people and
greet people and shake
want to say uh I want to sign books and
greet people and shake hands
greet people and shake hands and
want to say uh I want to sign books and
greet people and shake hands and all.
And
And uh
And uh today
And uh today we're
And uh today we're going
And uh today we're going to
And uh today we're going to escape
And uh today we're going to escape a
little
little early
And uh today we're going to escape a
little early but
little early but not
And uh today we're going to escape a
little early but not too
little early but not too early.
Any
Any other
Any other questions
Any other questions you
Any other questions you really
Any other questions you really need
asked?
>> Gratitude.
>> Gratitude. Yes,
>> Gratitude. Yes, gratitude
>> Gratitude.
>> Gratitude. Yes, gratitude is
>> Gratitude. Yes, gratitude is is
>> Gratitude.
>> Gratitude. Yes, gratitude is is uh
>> Gratitude. Yes, gratitude is is uh one
of
of the
of the most
of the most wonderful
of the most wonderful things
of the most wonderful things and
of the most wonderful things and helpful
spiritually.
spiritually. Um
gratitude
gratitude is
gratitude is over
gratitude is over um
gratitude is over um 500
gratitude is over um 500 resist
gratitude is over um 500 resist 510
gratitude is over um 500 resist 510 520
20 53.
20 53. Yeah.
20 53. Yeah. It's
20 53. Yeah. It's just
20 53. Yeah. It's just the
20 53. Yeah. It's just the way
20 53. Yeah. It's just the way of
20 53. Yeah. It's just the way of the
heart.
heart. Gratitude
20 53. Yeah. It's just the way of the
heart. Gratitude is
heart. Gratitude is a
20 53. Yeah. It's just the way of the
heart. Gratitude is a way
heart. Gratitude is a way of
20 53. Yeah. It's just the way of the
heart. Gratitude is a way of the
heart. Gratitude is a way of the heart.
Thankfulness
Thankfulness and
Thankfulness and gratitude.
Um,
and
and it's
and it's very
and it's very important
and it's very important in
and it's very important in many
spiritual
spiritual pathways.
and it's very important in many
spiritual pathways. It's
spiritual pathways. It's certainly
and it's very important in many
spiritual pathways. It's certainly in
the
the 12step
the 12step programs.
the 12step programs. It's
the 12step programs. It's a
the 12step programs. It's a very
the 12step programs. It's a very very
big
big piece
the 12step programs. It's a very very
big piece of
big piece of the
the 12step programs. It's a very very
big piece of the program
big piece of the program instead
the 12step programs. It's a very very
big piece of the program instead of
resentments
resentments to
resentments to have
resentments to have be
resentments to have be grateful
resentments to have be grateful for
resentments to have be grateful for what
you
you have
resentments to have be grateful for what
you have instead
you have instead of
resentments to have be grateful for what
you have instead of resentful
you have instead of resentful about
resentments to have be grateful for what
you have instead of resentful about what
you
you don't
you don't have
you don't have because
the
the way
you don't have because
the way of
the way of the
you don't have because
the way of the heart.
the way of the heart. Then
you don't have because
the way of the heart. Then so
the way of the heart. Then so the
you don't have because
the way of the heart. Then so the 12
step
step groups
step groups are
step groups are a
step groups are a way
step groups are a way of
step groups are a way of the
step groups are a way of the heart,
step groups are a way of the heart, the
way
way of
step groups are a way of the heart, the
way of surrendering.
way of surrendering. And
step groups are a way of the heart, the
way of surrendering. And through
way of surrendering. And through the
third
third step,
third step, one
third step, one surrenders
third step, one surrenders one
third step, one surrenders one will
third step, one surrenders one will to
God
God and
third step, one surrenders one will to
God and is
God and is grateful
third step, one surrenders one will to
God and is grateful for
God and is grateful for all
third step, one surrenders one will to
God and is grateful for all o
God and is grateful for all o all
experiences
experiences because
experiences because as
experiences because as someone
experiences because as someone said
experiences because as someone said to
me
me the
experiences because as someone said to
me the other
me the other day,
experiences because as someone said to
me the other day, you
me the other day, you get
experiences because as someone said to
me the other day, you get the
experiences
experiences that
experiences that you
experiences that you need.
You
You can't
experiences that you need.
You can't get
You can't get from
experiences that you need.
You can't get from here
You can't get from here to
experiences that you need.
You can't get from here to there
You can't get from here to there without
going
going through
going through here.
going through here. You
going through here. You understand?
going through here. You understand? So
that
that would
going through here. You understand? So
that would explain
that would explain why
going through here. You understand? So
that would explain why the
that would explain why the world
going through here. You understand? So
that would explain why the world appears
as
as it
as it as
as it as it
as it as it does
as it as it does because
as it as it does because it
as it as it does because it requires
as it as it does because it requires to
grow
grow spiritually
many
many opportunities
many opportunities which
many opportunities which this
many opportunities which this world
provides.
This
This world
This world in
This world in other
This world in other words
This world in other words if
This world in other words if you're
This world in other words if you're in
This world in other words if you're in a
beautiful
beautiful monastery
This world in other words if you're in a
beautiful monastery where
beautiful monastery where everybody
This world in other words if you're in a
beautiful monastery where everybody is
unconditionally
unconditionally loving
unconditionally loving and
unconditionally loving and you
unconditionally loving and you do
nothing
nothing but
unconditionally loving and you do
nothing but listen
nothing but listen to
unconditionally loving and you do
nothing but listen to birds
nothing but listen to birds and
unconditionally loving and you do
nothing but listen to birds and garden
all
all day
there's
there's a
all day
there's a limited
there's a limited amount
all day
there's a limited amount of
there's a limited amount of karmic
possibilities
possibilities there.
possibilities there. Correct.
Give
Give up
possibilities there. Correct.
Give up sex
Give up sex maybe.
possibilities there. Correct.
Give up sex maybe. Okay.
75 years
75 years in
75 years in a
75 years in a monastery
75 years in a monastery and
75 years in a monastery and out
75 years in a monastery and out of
75 years in a monastery and out of that
lifetime
lifetime you
75 years in a monastery and out of that
lifetime you learn
lifetime you learn to
75 years in a monastery and out of that
lifetime you learn to let
lifetime you learn to let sex
75 years in a monastery and out of that
lifetime you learn to let sex go.
lifetime you learn to let sex go. You
know
I
I can
know
I can be
I can be happy
know
I can be happy without
I can be happy without sex.
know
I can be happy without sex. Okay.
I can be happy without sex. Okay. Take
if
if you
if you can
if you can do
if you can do that
if you can do that one
if you can do that one in
if you can do that one in one
if you can do that one in one lifetime
that's
that's pretty
if you can do that one in one lifetime
that's pretty good.
Now
Now in
Now in the
Now in the world
Now in the world which
Now in the world which most
Now in the world which most of
Now in the world which most of us
Now in the world which most of us live
the
the opportunities
Now in the world which most of us live
the opportunities are
the opportunities are complex
multitudinous
and
and constantly
multitudinous
and constantly presenting
and constantly presenting themsel.
multitudinous
and constantly presenting themsel. So
and constantly presenting themsel. So if
you
you want
you want to
you want to evolve
you want to evolve rapidly
you want to evolve rapidly it
you want to evolve rapidly it seems
you want to evolve rapidly it seems to
me
me this
you want to evolve rapidly it seems to
me this world
me this world would
you want to evolve rapidly it seems to
me this world would be
me this world would be the
you want to evolve rapidly it seems to
me this world would be the ideal
me this world would be the ideal place.
This
This is
This is a
This is a wonderful
This is a wonderful place.
This is a wonderful place. All
This is a wonderful place. All you
This is a wonderful place. All you have
to
to do
This is a wonderful place. All you have
to do is
to do is turn
This is a wonderful place. All you have
to do is turn on
to do is turn on the
This is a wonderful place. All you have
to do is turn on the TV.
to do is turn on the TV. You
This is a wonderful place. All you have
to do is turn on the TV. You got
to do is turn on the TV. You got an
opportunity
opportunity to
opportunity to let
opportunity to let go
opportunity to let go of
opportunity to let go of hate.
opportunity to let go of hate. Let
opportunity to let go of hate. Let go
opportunity to let go of hate. Let go of
fear.
fear. Let
opportunity to let go of hate. Let go of
fear. Let go
fear. Let go of
opportunity to let go of hate. Let go of
fear. Let go of greed.
fear. Let go of greed. Let
opportunity to let go of hate. Let go of
fear. Let go of greed. Let go
fear. Let go of greed. Let go of
opportunity to let go of hate. Let go of
fear. Let go of greed. Let go of lust.
avarice
avarice as
avarice as they
avarice as they shake
avarice as they shake as
avarice as they shake as they
avarice as they shake as they shake
avarice as they shake as they shake on
the
the screen
avarice as they shake as they shake on
the screen and
the screen and invite
avarice as they shake as they shake on
the screen and invite you
the screen and invite you to
avarice as they shake as they shake on
the screen and invite you to try
the screen and invite you to try this
which
which will
which will turn
which will turn you
which will turn you into
which will turn you into more
which will turn you into more of
which will turn you into more of a
which will turn you into more of a man
and
and no
which will turn you into more of a man
and no your
and no your money
which will turn you into more of a man
and no your money back
and no your money back and
which will turn you into more of a man
and no your money back and I
and no your money back and I mean
which will turn you into more of a man
and no your money back and I mean the
seductions
seductions and
seductions and the
seductions and the presentations
seductions and the presentations and
and
and the
seductions and the presentations and
and the latest
and the latest person
seductions and the presentations and
and the latest person to
and the latest person to hate
seductions and the presentations and
and the latest person to hate and
and the latest person to hate and the
latest
latest person
latest person to
latest person to fear
latest person to fear the
latest person to fear the latest
political
political shenanigan
latest person to fear the latest
political shenanigan to
political shenanigan to twist
latest person to fear the latest
political shenanigan to twist your
political shenanigan to twist your mind
with
um
um the
with
um the appeal
um the appeal to
with
um the appeal to all
um the appeal to all the
with
um the appeal to all the vanities
um the appeal to all the vanities to
appearance
appearance to
appearance to glamour
appearance to glamour it's
appearance to glamour it's just
appearance to glamour it's just an
endless
endless barrage
appearance to glamour it's just an
endless barrage So
endless barrage So if
appearance to glamour it's just an
endless barrage So if you
endless barrage So if you have
appearance to glamour it's just an
endless barrage So if you have to
endless barrage So if you have to pick
appearance to glamour it's just an
endless barrage So if you have to pick a
world
world for
world for rapid
world for rapid spiritual
world for rapid spiritual evolution,
world for rapid spiritual evolution, I
think
think this
world for rapid spiritual evolution, I
think this is
think this is the
world for rapid spiritual evolution, I
think this is the ultimate.
That's
That's true.
That's true. This
That's true. This is
That's true. This is almost
That's true. This is almost the
That's true. This is almost the ultimate
opportunity.
opportunity. Resist.
That's true. This is almost the ultimate
opportunity. Resist. And
opportunity. Resist. And that's
That's true. This is almost the ultimate
opportunity. Resist. And that's why
opportunity. Resist. And that's why it
is
is a
is a gift
is a gift to
is a gift to be
is a gift to be born
is a gift to be born a
is a gift to be born a human,
is a gift to be born a human, which
is a gift to be born a human, which is
what
what the
is a gift to be born a human, which is
what the Buddha
what the Buddha meant.
is a gift to be born a human, which is
what the Buddha meant. Resist.
what the Buddha meant. Resist. So
is a gift to be born a human, which is
what the Buddha meant. Resist. So the
Buddha
Buddha was
Buddha was right
Buddha was right to
Buddha was right to say
Buddha was right to say it's
Buddha was right to say it's a
Buddha was right to say it's a great
gift
gift to
Buddha was right to say it's a great
gift to be
gift to be born
Buddha was right to say it's a great
gift to be born a
gift to be born a human.
Buddha was right to say it's a great
gift to be born a human. and
gift to be born a human. and the
Buddha was right to say it's a great
gift to be born a human. and the chance
that
that because
that because it
that because it opens
that because it opens the
that because it opens the chance
that because it opens the chance to
evolve
evolve all
that because it opens the chance to
evolve all the
evolve all the way
that because it opens the chance to
evolve all the way to
evolve all the way to enlightenment
uh
uh just
uh just in
uh just in one
uh just in one lifetime.
uh just in one lifetime. So
we're
we're grateful
uh just in one lifetime. So
we're grateful to
we're grateful to be
uh just in one lifetime. So
we're grateful to be here.
We're
We're grateful
We're grateful to
We're grateful to be
We're grateful to be here,
We're grateful to be here, oh
We're grateful to be here, oh Lord.
We're grateful to be here, oh Lord. We
give
give thanks
We're grateful to be here, oh Lord. We
give thanks for
give thanks for this
We're grateful to be here, oh Lord. We
give thanks for this world
give thanks for this world and
We're grateful to be here, oh Lord. We
give thanks for this world and the
multitudinous
multitudinous opportunities
multitudinous opportunities it
multitudinous opportunities it presents.
And
And prayerfully,
multitudinous opportunities it presents.
And prayerfully, we
And prayerfully, we are
multitudinous opportunities it presents.
And prayerfully, we are grateful
And prayerfully, we are grateful and
thankful
thankful for
thankful for this
thankful for this lifetime.
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
the
the audience
the audience as
the audience as we
the audience as we were
the audience as we were as
the audience as we were as we
the audience as we were as we are
the audience as we were as we are now.
>> We
>> We never
the audience as we were as we are now.
>> We never get
>> We never get away
the audience as we were as we are now.
>> We never get away with
>> We never get away with it,
the audience as we were as we are now.
>> We never get away with it, do
>> We never get away with it, do we?
>> Uh,
>> Uh, we
>> Uh, we have
>> Uh, we have permission
>> Uh, we have permission to
>> Uh, we have permission to ask
>> Uh, we have permission to ask this.
>> Uh, we have permission to ask this. They
went
went up
>> Uh, we have permission to ask this. They
went up over
went up over eight
>> Uh, we have permission to ask this. They
went up over eight points,
went up over eight points, nine
>> Uh, we have permission to ask this. They
went up over eight points, nine points,
10 points,
10 points, 11
10 points, 11 points.
10 points, 11 points. Oo,
10 points, 11 points. Oo, 11
10 points, 11 points. Oo, 11 points
today.
today. Yeah,
>> they
>> they went
>> they went over
>> they went over 11
>> they went over 11 points,
>> they went over 11 points, 12
>> they went over 11 points, 12 points.
Okay,
Okay, some
>> they went over 11 points, 12 points.
Okay, some people
Okay, some people went
>> they went over 11 points, 12 points.
Okay, some people went over
Okay, some people went over 50
>> they went over 11 points, 12 points.
Okay, some people went over 50 points.
Resist,
Resist, you
Resist, you know,
Resist, you know, the
Resist, you know, the average,
Resist, you know, the average, the
Resist, you know, the average, the group
as
as an
Resist, you know, the average, the group
as an average
as an average went
Resist, you know, the average, the group
as an average went up
as an average went up 11
Resist, you know, the average, the group
as an average went up 11 points.
as an average went up 11 points. Some
people
people went
people went 50
people went 50 to
people went 50 to 100,
people went 50 to 100, you
people went 50 to 100, you know,
individually.
Some
Some went
Some went over
Some went over 100
Some went over 100 points,
Some went over 100 points, 150.
Some went over 100 points, 150. Some
people
people went
Some went over 100 points, 150. Some
people went over
people went over 100
Some went over 100 points, 150. Some
people went over 100 points
people went over 100 points just
Some went over 100 points, 150. Some
people went over 100 points just during
the
the course
the course of the
the course of the lecture.
the course of the lecture. So,
the course of the lecture. So, it's
the course of the lecture. So, it's like
if
if you're
the course of the lecture. So, it's like
if you're poised
if you're poised on
the course of the lecture. So, it's like
if you're poised on the
if you're poised on the on
the course of the lecture. So, it's like
if you're poised on the on the
if you're poised on the on the edge
the course of the lecture. So, it's like
if you're poised on the on the edge of
something,
something, wham,
something, wham, you
something, wham, you just
something, wham, you just shoot
something, wham, you just shoot ahead,
you
you know,
something, wham, you just shoot ahead,
you know, because
you know, because you're
something, wham, you just shoot ahead,
you know, because you're you
you know, because you're you were
something, wham, you just shoot ahead,
you know, because you're you were just
poised
poised for
poised for that.
poised for that. But
poised for that. But the
poised for that. But the average
poised for that. But the average of
poised for that. But the average of all
is
is 11.
poised for that. But the average of all
is 11. When
is 11. When you
poised for that. But the average of all
is 11. When you consider
is 11. When you consider that
poised for that. But the average of all
is 11. When you consider that five
points
points in
points in a
points in a lifetime
points in a lifetime is
points in a lifetime is the
points in a lifetime is the average
points in a lifetime is the average to
do
do 11
points in a lifetime is the average to
do 11 in
do 11 in an
points in a lifetime is the average to
do 11 in an afternoon
plus
plus free
plus free lunch.
Great
Great for
plus free lunch.
Great for us.
Great for us. We're
plus free lunch.
Great for us. We're wonderful.
That's
That's to
That's to put
That's to put the
That's to put the dark
That's to put the dark forces
That's to put the dark forces on
That's to put the dark forces on guard.
Thank
Thank you.
That's to put the dark forces on guard.
Thank you. I
Thank you. I guess
That's to put the dark forces on guard.
Thank you. I guess that
Thank you. I guess that will
That's to put the dark forces on guard.
Thank you. I guess that will show
Thank you. I guess that will show them.