Welcome to Dr. David Hawkins Sedona 2002
series, The Way to God.
Lecture 4:
Phosality and Duality.
Originally presented in April of 2002 at
the Sedona Creative Life Center.
The reason we meet is uh to share what
we've learned about uh our
investigations about the nature of
consciousness.
It's the only place I know of that is
actually doing
spiritual research.
As amazing as that may sound, there's
archaeologic research on religious
history.
And for that, you need a little pick and
and a pith hat and you go out in the
desert and you hope to find something.
But that doesn't really advance human
knowledge, you see, really.
So
what's unique about uh these talks is
that we've um discovered a means of
investigating
the nonlinear domain.
We found a means of investigating that
which is unknowable by ordinary means.
And I share with you my own
experiences as consciousness advance
throughout this lifetime
and my own awareness of reality as I
experience it.
So it's both subjective and in terms of
the world objective and that we have
um discovered a means of verifying truth
uh that's never been discovered before
which makes it very useful tool.
And of course everybody here is pretty
aware that we discovered that
kinesiology itself made a very
uh incredible tool available to almost
everyone if they calibrate over 200 and
their partner does and their question is
over 200 the results are valid.
uh we didn't even know that when we
wrote power versus force we said we
thought anybody could do it and then I
would get letters from people
uh that they were unable to make it work
and they were trying to find out how to
get even with their mother-in-law make
money on the stock market and it could
be the intention behind those things I
don't know but I began to suspect that
and then we discovered that um
if if the uh the question needs to be
integris the intention
uh is what really sets the calibrable
level of consciousness.
The the two people involved both need to
be above 200. So it works therefore only
for about 15% of the population which I
didn't know when I wrote power versus
force I think when I revised it for Hay
House. So I did put that in there. The
caveat that uh
the the purpose has to be integrous.
The discovery was that chinesiology was
asking a question of the field of
consciousness.
Consciousness registers only that which
is
consequently
the other error in power versus force is
I said it was true versus false.
The correct the correct u explanation of
the phenomena is it's either true or not
true.
Uh so because that which is real exists
then that which is real registers within
the field of consciousness.
That which is unreal, that which the
world calls false has no independent
existence.
does not register in consciousness and
therefore gives you a weak response
and in terms of the world unknow.
We said it's more analogous to
an electricity going down a wire. When
electricity is there, it's on. When
electricity is off,
it's not on.
But there is no independent existent
thing such as offness.
That's an important point to get. There
is no such thing as offness. And we'll
get to that more later in the lecture
because the lecture is supposed to be
about
uh supposed to be about what's it about
today?
>> Yes. Well, anyway,
whatever it's about, uh it's it's
extremely important to realize this
essential truth
that there is no such thing as offness.
We'll expand upon that later. Yes, today
we're talking about positionality and uh
how to transcend positionality because
the undoing of the ego, the ego is based
on
uh a whole series of positionalities of
increasing elaboration.
So we'll talk about the structure of the
ego, its origin and how it expresses
itself in the human domain
and how to therefore to transcend it. A
great a great deal of information itself
is transformational.
To merely hear certain things already
resolves the problem.
It's not going to rain today. That takes
care of that one right there. You see
what I'm saying?
One worry just got eliminated. You know
what I mean? So certain information
itself is transformational because it's
so powerful. And if you calibrate the
level of certain pieces of information,
you'll see why they are so powerful.
Everything occurs uh we could start with
a paradigm
of context and content. It's crucially
important to understand
that what the ego
experiences is content
and what enlightenment is concerned with
is context.
that God is the ultimate infinite
context
and that all that all of existence is
then content.
All that exists is content
and nothing comes into existence except
for context.
Therefore, God is the source of all
existence.
All that exists arises solely as a
specific creation of God. You know,
we spoke about that when we were
differentiating uh evolution from
creation
that contrary um to the ego's thought
that causality works like a series of
billyard balls. On the contrary, every
single moment because of creation, all
that exists, its existence is because
it is simultaneously and in every moment
being created by God. So God doesn't hit
ball A and then then go through all the
next 14 balls until it comes out at the
end, which is the traditional idea of
the evolution of of evolution.
On the contrary, each and every movement
of each and every ball is an individual
creation of God. God creates this. God
creates this. This God creates this. God
creates this. God creates this. So that
the creator is continuously present. So
that all that is happening is a
continuous creation which seems to be
sequential because it's perceived
sequentially.
But perception is not causality.
So to start out uh help you digest your
breakfast, I thought we'd start out with
this
which will take us uh
uh from the Buddha nature right down to
breakfast.
I thought we'd start with an easy one.
So we start with the simple awareness
that the unmanifest is the godhead. In
other words, out of apparent
nothingness, the Buddha's void,
um the Buddha nature, he has the
unmanifest having no form.
Let's see if the unmanifest is the
Buddha nature. Yes,
we have permission to ask this resist.
The unmanifest and the Buddha nature,
one in the same resistance. Yeah. So
this is what the Buddha is speaking of
then
because in the enlightened state there
is no form, there is no thingness,
there is no positionality, there is no
time, space or any point of reference.
So it seems void. But the ultimate
reality is not nothingness.
The error which I spoke about previously
and which I wrote about more extensively
in the book I'm finishing now
is not to confuse the Buddha's void with
nothingness
because as we said no there is no such
thing as offness neither can nothingness
exist
one branch of Buddhism leads you into
the void and I've been there it's very
very impressive
is extremely impressive
and one is certain this is what the
Buddha spoke of.
However, it is not.
Nothingness cannot exist. And um any
more than offness can exist.
Uh
if we have something here, we say
there's something here. If we take it
away, you have nothingness. But you
can't give me a piece of nothingness
because it doesn't exist. All right.
Okay. So the unmanifest then is that
which is prior you might say prior to
the universe which is just a way of
languaging it. Yeah.
The next realization is that one is all
that is.
Um so I forget the calibrated levels of
these. I think I've got it somewhere
else later this morning. Each one of
these you can calibrate these levels of
awareness. This would be a thousand and
up manifest.
As the ego disappears,
there's like an agonizing shock, a
feeling of literally dying.
People worry about physically dying. You
can forget about worrying about
physically dying. There's nothing to
physically dying. It's a snap. You're
out of the body. It's fantastic. You
wonder why you ever hung out with that
stupid thing?
And don't forget 99% of your fears and
worries have to do with the body,
survival, money, health, uh,
transportation, food, eating, breathing.
I mean, my god, it's a really drag. So,
the minute you're out of it, you say,
"Oh, this is fantastic." And then
somebody shakes your knee and it's your
father and you can see he thinks you're
you're dead. Oh,
He believes in death. You see, he
believes in death. And if you don't go
back in the body and breathe again, he's
going to grieve.
Well, if I'd been a true Buddha at that
m moment, I would have left it. It was
his problem.
But I wasn't a true Buddha. It was just
an enlightened state, but uh not the not
the ultimate. So,
one then reluctantly re-energizes the
body, which is a terrible mistake, but
anyway, you do it.
That was very codependent, right? We
call it codependent.
You agree to stay alive so your father
won't grieve over your death. I mean
that's really neurotic, you know,
but that's what happened. And more than
once, more than once. All right. So
in that state, in that state, one is all
that is
the everythingness of allness.
This is self. The the awareness of
reality as
as allness, the oneness and allness,
complete totality,
infinitude beyond beginnings or endings.
And in that state, one knows that that
which I am has always existed before
this universe, before other universes,
when all universes have come and gone,
that which I am
um is continuous because one that's
experiencing God as allness.
The state prior to that is the awareness
that the these are states you can reach
through meditation and we'll get into
that in in another lecture.
Uh
when you when you when you you in
meditation get to identify with the
observer witness rather than the content
of consciousness. I should have started
from the other end.
We should start with the dog here. The
dog is barking and my leg is hurting and
my name is George
and you are stuck with form.
As you begin to meditate, you see that
all this is going through your mind and
you say this is hopeless. I cannot stop
the mind. It's uh relentless. It's
thinking all the time, feeling all the
time, imagining things, remembering
things. It's a cacony. It just goes on
and on. So at this point, the ordinary
person as they walk around in the
universe, 99.9% of people identify with
form and that's why they're so
preoccupied with health and wealth and
death and all that kind of thing.
Uh because they are form and they
identify life as form
and this is I am the body and I am the
content of the mind.
The person as they start to get involved
in spiritual work begins to realize that
there's a step beyond that that the mind
is somehow registering somewhere. I say
to people say I can't stop my mind. I
can't do this and that. I say well how
do you know what your mind is doing?
You're complaining. What are you
complaining about?
Well, you must be aware of what the mind
is doing. So it's registering somewhere.
So this begins to pull you back from the
identification with content and you see
that something is registering what's
going on in the mind
and that something is recognizing the
registration of form and then you come
to the watcher
before you get to the watcher you get to
the experiences so here is the form I am
George and I'm 14 years old or whatever
and my dog is here And you say, well,
this is registering in something and I'm
because I'm recognizing it and I'm
experiencing it. And you begin to
realize that there's a watcher of all
this. There's a knower of all this.
Somehow there's a spotlight, there's a
lens, something is aware and you realize
that there is awareness going on of the
observer and the witness.
As you go beyond the observer and the
witness, you wonder how does light.
First of all, you begin to realize these
are impersonal. You realize that
observing and witnessing are happening
of their own. There is no you that is
watching and witnessing. Although in the
beginning you have the illusion that's
you that's watching and observing.
Except that you then begin to notice it
does it all the time without being
asked. So if it was you, you could
control it. You could stop witnessing.
You could stop watching. You could stop
observing. But you begin to realize that
this is happening of its own and you
disidentify that with it with with that
and you see that that is coming out of
consciousness itself.
And so you as you see you progressively
let go identifying with content and you
progressively expanding and identifying
with context.
So this is very very limited. This is
very specific, very restricting
and this is completely content when
you're just you're ignoring the con
context altogether. Here you're ignoring
context.
As you move up, you begin to relinquish
your identification with content and you
begin to realize that that which you are
is context. It is because of
consciousness that any of the lower
states can occur in the first place.
The reason you realize they're not you
is because you have no control of them
and you see they're happening
spontaneously.
Consciousness is there in and of itself
without being asked.
You can become unconscious of
consciousness when you go to sleep.
And that's the oblivion.
That's not the void. That's oblivion.
And many people like oblivion.
And why do they like oblivion?
Because it's so peaceful and happy. How
do you know it's peaceful and happy? So
you weren't oblivious. You were aware
that it was peaceful and happy. And you
said it to everybody how well you slept
last night. So something is aware
anyway. And so
we move up these levels
and realize that that's where we are at
the top.
Everybody realizes now that you're the
unmanifest, right?
We wanted to demonstrate for the
doubting Thomas' here.
Stand up. Ding Thomas', where are you?
Let me just ask if we can do this.
Uh, this is a valid piece of paper.
Resist.
This is a This is a bounce check, by the
way.
For those who doubt the accuracy of
kinesiology, I think it's always fun to
have a bounce check. So, we do that at
every lecture too for fun because so far
the person's obviously not deposited the
money because it's still it still
bounces every time we check it out.
All right. Right. So the value of
kinesiology then is that it affirms that
which has existence, that which is true.
And for the first time in human history
gives us a means of differentiating
truth from falsehood.
The discovery that you can differentiate
truth from falsehood anywhere in time
about anything
is so mind-boggling that I don't think
anybody on the planet has
grasped the significance of it
including myself.
it uh sort of blew me away for some
years and uh number of people when they
first read the the prior the manuscript
manuscript of art versus went to Europe
for a couple of weeks and to just
recover from the shock of discovery
that for the first time in human history
mankind has
some means of navigation
other than
credility. In other words, other than
faith in others,
mankind has some means of telling truth
from falsehood.
Well, when you look at the history of
mankind, it's a disaster.
The history of mankind is really a
disaster. If you don't think so, you
watch the History Channel a couple of
nights and it'll change your mind.
Well, the consciousness of mankind, you
know, was was about 190 for many many
centuries
and um
87% of the population or 85%
calibrated below 200
and therefore such things as the current
the current situation in the Middle East
is the way the whole world has been
not just the Middle East, the whole
world's been that way. All of Europe was
ravaged by one horde after another. All
of Asia was ravaged by one horde after
another. It was just one civilization
plundering and savaging another
civilization
continuously.
And it goes on right up to this very
day. Hasn't changed at all. If we
calibrate the energy of the Middle East
right now, it'll be about the same as
the dinosaurs, I would imagine.
Can we have permission to do the Middle
East resist? Middle East is over 65.
Oh, Middle East is over 60. 65.
Jeez, it was 70. It's gone down.
We have permission to ask about Mr. Bin
Lowden. Resist. He's over 65. Resist.
No. So, you see
the Let's do the dinosaurs.
The dinosaurs are over 30, 35, 40, 45,
50, 55, 60, 65.
Hm. Very interesting, isn't it?
So, we see the evolution of life.
So we'll have to in in the book I I'm
finishing up trying to track the
evolution of consciousness as it
appeared on the planet and then evolved
throughout time
on up to the present day.
I'm trying to recapitulate
life and all of its expressions,
especially as consciousness and as all
of life throughout all of time as it
evolved on this planet. I thought I'd do
that before lunch.
It makes me warm just to think of it. So
anyway, that's what we're doing. And uh
but you see that life then appeared.
What happened to our diagram? Oh,
anyway, it
it appeared out of the unmanifest
becoming manifest and the light of
consciousness then shone forth.
Um, and creation arose out of the man
unmanifest as the manifest. So God as
unmanifest is infinite potentiality.
>> That's the one.
Ah, so this is infinite potentiality.
Infinite potentiality.
Therefore, the infinite context
of all of creation is unmanifest. The
context
is infinite.
The capacity of the unmanifest is beyond
man's imagination. And no writer has
really touched
has really gotten what it is.
The
unmanifest
has the capacity for creativity. It's
innate to its nature
and all that it creates has within it
the nature of that which created it.
So that
creation
is continuous and infinite.
Therefore,
we tend to think of the creator as
creating this world. More sophisticated
person thinks of the creator as creating
our universe,
the infinite universe.
But beyond this universe is an infinite
universe of universes,
each of which is at faster than the
speed of light, creating an infinite
series of universes.
Yeah. Is that so?
That's not resistant. That is so
resistant.
Out of an infinite series of infinite
universes
are arising simultaneously faster than
the speed of light.
Infinite universes continuously.
Therefore, that sort of expands
one's concept of the creator.
Nothing comes into existence without
having come from God.
Nothing within the physical domain
has within it power. It has within
itself
only that expression in form that we
call force.
Nothing that exists has the power to
create its own existence.
Nothing that exists has within it the
power to create its own existence.
All that exists arises from God.
All right.
So this
out of the unmanifest arises the light,
the light of consciousness where this
infinite power
interacting with matter
and we have life united with matter.
And creation as we know it then is the
lighting of matter by the light of
consciousness as life. The life then
evolved on this planet through very
rudimentary forms.
It did not occur spontaneously as a
happy accidental combination of
chemicals as
uh sort of pedestrian science would have
you think. Don't forget science is on
different levels too. And what people
think of as science varies all the way
from the somewhat stupid to the
brilliant.
Just because it's labeled science
doesn't think it mean that it's highly
intelligent. Very often it isn't. And uh
anyway it it the lowest levels of
science then are concretism concretism
literalism
and reductive materialism.
So anyway according to that theory of
evolution then there was a happy
combination of chemicals that began to
breathe and think which is you know
unlikely.
Why is it unlikely? because you're
mixing categories. There are two two
different categories of existence.
Materiality has no capacity for
consciousness.
It's very obvious to to anybody that
thinks about it. That for anything to
evolve has to have a pattern. And where
would this pattern arise? Well, the
pattern arises in consciousness. And
then it manifests in the physical
domain. Huh?
So all power is within the field of
consciousness. And what we see is the
evolution of form. But the evolution of
form is only a result, a consequence of
that which is evolving in consciousness.
How can we say that is? Because we see
the progression of complexity and
function throughout the evolution of
life on this planet. the smallest little
bacteria
at the bottom of the sea.
The small little bacteria begins to
multiply and begins to learn. So we see
qualities of consciousness now
accompanying materiality and physicality
because learning is not something that
chemicals and molecules do.
So
the evolution of consciousness then and
as it manifests in form we see is the
evolution to higher and higher forms
and we see the complexity of form
increasing we see not only complexity of
form but we see aesthetics. We see
aesthetics the incredible beauty. If you
watch the Nature Channel long enough,
you're stunned by the incredible beauty
and the complexity of the design and the
discoveries uh made within the physical
domain. The fish at the bottom of the
sea that know how to produce
electricity, they knew how to do that
500 million years ago, long before we
discovered electricity, phosphoresence
and electric eel. In the days of ancient
Greek, they used to treat depression by
taking electric eel and shocking you
with a nuke.
certain number of people now they
recovered probably just so you go don't
get hit by the electric fish again if
nothing else
but anyway as we see the evolution of
evolution you see the be you see the
evolution what you're really seeing is
the evolution of learning and the
capacity to store learning so you needed
a brain then to store the learning in
the physical domain we see the evolution
of life
becoming more and more complex
But you see sort of two trains of life.
You see the train of life which lives at
the cost of other life and it reaches
its maximum at the level of the
dinosaur.
The dinosaur which from aesthetic
viewpoint
is a badl looking ombre lives by
chewing you up. Anything that's smaller
and weaker, it eats you.
So it maintains its life at the cost of
the life of the other. We might say that
the
that it's the height of egoentricity.
The reptilian world, the world of the
dinosaur is the ultimate me.
Fulfill my wants.
If you want to mate, you knock the
female down and you mate her. And if you
want to eat something, you kill it and
eat it. If something is in your way, you
knock it over.
Very much like preschool.
In In preschool, you're not allowed to
eat your other children.
We train them to eat cookies
unless you get to be a famous boxer in
which you can go back to eating people
again or their ears anyway.
I don't know. I didn't know how to hold
that. Whether it's humor or ridiculous,
I don't know. Bite the guy's ear off.
Well, it's a great publicity stunt.
All right. So, you see, the evolution of
this level of consciousness is all
egocentricity.
So, when we calibrate 65, we were just
calibrating extreme selfishness. Huh? Is
that what we got?
65 is really extreme selfishness. Resist
the absolute um the ego as God. Resist.
Yeah. Right. That's the level of
consciousness of the serial killer
of um the shoe bomber.
Can you believe there is such a thing as
a shoe bomber? Do we can we do the shoe
bomber? Is that guy over? That guy's
over 70. Where's he? 75. He's 75. Well,
he's a little bit beyond Tyrannosaurus.
Rex.
He probably uses the bathroom. You know
what I mean? Tyrannosaurus
Rex didn't. So, he goes from 60 to 70.
60 to 70. All right. So,
see, because we're trying to
differentiate good from evil, too. Here
you see when you recontextualize it, you
see it what it is. So, the dinosaur then
is only interested in me. That's Bin
Lden. Bin Lden only cares about
expressing his political views and um
dramatizing them.
It's all me. So you might say evil is
nothing but ex the extremity of the ego.
The ego is God. And you certainly see it
in who's that? Melissovich,
Stalin, Hitler. You see you see it in
all these people that don't mind killing
70 million people out there.
um because they don't deserve to live.
They have no rights. There's only me.
The dinosaur is not concerned
with the life of anything else except
its own jaws.
So you see that evolution of life then
coming up as rapacious, victimizing
others.
Um it has no concern for anything other
than its own self.
So you might say the dinosaur is the
epitome of the ego egoomaniac the
megalomania which characterizes people
like Stalin and Hitler and Mallovvich
and Nero and various people.
In another book I'm working on we we're
doing about a thousand calibrations.
We're doing all the famous people of
history etc. And it's sort of
interesting to go through uh the ancient
Rome and calibrate the levels of
consciousness of all the Caesars and the
various
uh people that have been on the planet.
All right. So that level of conscious
then is rapacious.
It reached its height at the level uh of
expression in the level of the dinosaur.
And then the dinosaur went down and we
saw the evolution of something else on
the planet. We saw the evolution of the
mamlon. We saw the evolution of that
which lives without destroying other
life. We see the sheep munching on the
grass. We see the cow and all the
domestic animals and the horse and all.
It eats that which is the product of uh
light plus chlorophyll and minerals. And
then in doing that refertilizes the
ground which makes more grass. So, it
not only does not kill other life, it
takes the top off the grass, but it
doesn't pull up its roots. And the grass
comes back better than ever, having been
fertilized with all kinds of manure.
So, you see that which lives
at the price of the life of others, and
you see that which lives in a mutual
mutuality with other life in which the
give and take is equal. So the grass
benefits from
from the cow and the cow benefits from
the grass.
So you might say there's two different
evolutionary lines. One rapacious.
So in
these biologic expressions then um we
see in the human ego people feel guilt
about the ego. See we're today our
lecture is about transcending the
opposites. I remember what it was. Huh?
And positionality. Yeah, they got there.
So,
you see the evolution then of animal
life. What is the animal concerned
about? The animal's concerned about
survival. It It's concerned about ter
territoriality.
It's concerned about right and wrong.
It's concerned with being a member, an
accepted member of the family or the
group.
Um
and we see that
uh m you see the evolution of
consciousness. Monkeys are smart enough
to know that when another tribe of
monkeys has beaten them, they retreat.
They retreat. Monkeys retreat.
H Let's see.
Monkey Island is the monkeys in the zoo.
Their civilization calibrates over 125,
130, 135,
135, 140.
Oh, in the wild they're over 130, 135,
140. Oh, they're still 140. All right.
So, wow.
The monkeys calibrate at 135 or 140. We
just said that the Middle East
calibrates at 70.
When a monkey tribe is being vanquished
by the invaders, it retreats.
Huh? It retreats.
Well, the Germans didn't do that at the
end of World War II. It was vanquished
and it went ahead and killed a few more
million of
Russians and had a few more million of
itself killed. Japan didn't see that at
the end of World War II. It took two
atomic bombs to get it through their
thick skull. I mean, that's really dumb.
If you're not very bright, you don't get
it the first time. So hundreds of
thousands more had to go.
All right? So
that gives us some idea then how the ego
arose so we can stop feeling guilty. The
ego is not your enemy. It's not evil.
And
um
you have to understand it.
It's hard to disassemble the ego without
understanding it. Me many people try to
do it. They go into a nice elated
spiritual state and then they fall back
again and they don't know why they keep
falling back again.
To stay there, you have to disassemble
the ego. And a disassemble it is to
merely understand it. To merely
understand it is already to disassemble
it. But as you understand the ego is
already getting weaker. By noon your ego
is going to be weaker.
We forgot to calibrate the audience.
Darn it.
Let's do uh we can do the audience as
they came in this morning. Resist.
They're over 410. 420 425 430
431 432 432 That's good. 432 is great to
talk to.
200 is too stupid.
432 is the world of America. That's
pretty much the consciousness of
America. 431. You know, that's a
meritocracy that emphasizes education,
intelligence, logic, reason,
understanding, study.
Um,
it's the springboard.
Yeah. All right. Springboard of
civilization,
advanced civilization, civil civilized
civilization like America.
All right. So we see the origin then of
how consciousness then begins to express
itself in the animal world on one level
as the voracious killer.
On the other hand, it's also the
benevolent mother. We don't you don't
see any love. There's no love amongst
dinosaurs.
Dinosaurs don't love anything. Even when
they lay an egg, they walk away from it.
They think it's disgusting and take off.
You're on your own, kid. And
frogs do the same. The lower lies, they
have no no capacity for maternal
instinct. All right. So, as this um
consciousness evolves, then
what happens is structure begins to
accommodate itself to the continuation
of this form. And you have the evolution
of the nervous system. You didn't need a
brain until
physicality doesn't need a brain.
Consciousness needs a brain in which you
store data. So as consciousness evolves,
it learns. When you learn, you got to
store data. So little computers. So the
brain and the neurons as they grow, they
grow according to the function. And
you see that the ego is really the
evolution of the animal.
Everything that you see on the
playground, everything that you see in
Monkey Island, everything you see on the
TV news is not different than the
animal.
The animal is interested in survival,
mating, protecting boundaries,
territoriality, possession,
grabbing things, hoarding things,
pridefulness, bragging,
and
gets out there,
brags, and gets mad, gets angry, and
then it finds it. But getting angry, it
scares people.
You see that on the playground, right?
There's the ego for you.
Preschool, Monkey Island, Middle East.
There it is.
5:30 News on Channel 15.
It learns that it can instead of
physically doing it, it can emotionally
express it. It can blubber and cry and
drag people all over and all this. All
right. So what what happens then is the
forebrain
see the intellect then
the human intelligence didn't come in as
a new different kind of brain. No, not
at all.
The end man's brain got better and
homoerectus got better. The homminid as
it evolved, you know, got better and
better. So what happened is we just
added a forebrain to the old animal
brain. We didn't eliminate the old
animal brain. The amydala and all these
deep uh things that make you hate the
guy who cuts in front of you in traffic
is still very active. Right?
Flash up comes the rage and the
adrenaline before you even had a chance
to think about it. And
so the brain is structured to serve the
animal.
It's set to trigger. The anger comes up.
The amygdala shoots up before your
frontal cortex even gets a chance.
All right? So the ego then is it's
selfishness, self-centered.
Um
and the animal instincts become
elaborated through the intellect. Now
man has an intellect. So he can extend
his animal nature now in more
sophisticated ex extensive means.
He becomes more sophisticated in in its
expression. But it's still nothing but
the animal instinct out there.
convenience, satisfaction, storage, all
these things now become
more advanced in their expression. But
the motivation is still that of the
animal to be better than another. Uh
to be able to beat them, to be richer,
to be more admired, to be the alpha
male, the alpha female in the pack.
that juggling for a position in small
groups.
This one wants to be right so they can
make this one wrong. Nah, there you
preschool, right? Preschool.
It's the animal. It's
It's the zoo. All right. So, your ego is
the zoo. A living zoo.
There you go. Of course it wants to kill
people that pull in front of it in
traffic. Of course it does.
They deserve to die.
See the difficulty of spiritual work.
You know, as a teacher, I'm trying to
jump the the pitfalls to recontextualize
the ego to see its true nature and how
it arose. You don't have to feel guilty
about it. You don't have to crush
yourself because how could I have said
that or made that mistake? How could I
have been so cruel
because you're a vicious little dinosaur
inside me?
You'd like to chew her rotten little
tail off and place her right in the eye,
wouldn't you? That's the truth of it.
Okay.
All right. So, you got to own your
animal. You own your animal. And the
animal is called the ego.
All right. So, the the the ego is
trained to think in terms of form. When
the animal wants to eat something, it
has to perceive. So, the ego's primary
mode is perception. If I'm going to eat
this critter over here, I have to me
estimate the time it takes to get there
in my strength as compared to that
animal etc. So the animal now lives in a
world of
uh physicality
and a concrete literality which takes
its expression in the lower levels of
science.
Nothing is real unless it can be
measured. Yeah, that is the lowest level
of science.
Nothing is real unless it can be
measured. And in fact, there's a
definition in the idiot side of science
called nothing nothing exists unless
it's measurable. Okay.
All right. That's that pretty much clips
its wings as far as becoming
enlightened. So
because as science advances it realizes
that kind of thinking is why it can't
get any further and it has to look to
consciousness itself. That's why we have
conferences on science and
consciousness.
The more sophisticated, the high end of
the intellect in science of course is
aware of advanced theoretical physics,
subatomic subparticle physics and the
quantum reality.
How does consciousness then interface
with the physicality of the world? And
that takes us to quantum mechanics.
quantum mechanics
which reached its height in I would say
the 30s and even those who don't know
about quantum mechanics
uh I would give you a lecture on it
complete with all the
um
with all the mathematics but it would
put you to sleep
to prove it. You don't need to prove it
any more than you need to prove uh that
when you turn the key in the ignition,
the car goes on.
But everybody who has ever heard of
quantum mechanics realizes that there is
a microscopic reality beyond the
microscopic microscopic world. The world
of observation, the world of the ego is
microscopic.
However, there's something else going on
in the universe. And
everybody has heard of the Heisenberg
uncertainty principle. So we'll just
state one or two things about it that's
significant.
Smaller than the smallest atom, smaller
than the smallest particle, smaller than
the electron, smaller than the photon
is a reality which
has as a basic principle uncertainty.
So Heisenberg's uncertainty principle is
stated things can exist either as a
particle or as a wave
all exists as a potentiality
and the potentiality is influenced by
consciousness because the startling
thing about Heisenberg's discovery
was an observation the second time you
make it has changed. The fact that
you've observed the phenomena has
already changed the phenomena. You
cannot observe the same phenomena in
quantum mechanics twice. The mere act of
observation has already changed its
potentiality and its innate energy
potentiality as well as its position.
Its position already changes.
We all know that intention changes
results. We all know that what you hold
in mind tends to potentiate,
tends to materialize. Sorry. What you
hold in mind tends to materialize.
We know that prayer is effective. Not
always what kind of prayer you want. Oh,
dear God, please keep the hold the bus
so I won't be leaving my violin lesson.
But we know that a a maintained
intention has a very powerful effect
and it's the most important thing
karmically. It's the most important
thing that determines the level of
consciousness is intention.
You might say that which we're
accountable for
is intention, not results. Let's see if
that's true or not.
We're responsible for intention. Resist.
It's the spiritual attention, the
spiritual will that determines karma.
Resist. Right?
So that keeps us from worrying about
every little
time we say damn and then feel guilty
about oh lord I didn't mean to say that
it's the overall intention the alignment
it's not every little wave that hits the
prow of the ship it's that you set the
compass in this degree this is what's
going to determine
where you go eventually
and where you're at now
because it's it's all one.
So we were tracking the origin of the
ego in order to disassemble it. We
noticed uh that it originates from its
main purpose is survival within the
animal world.
And we don't see love evolve until the
maternal. The really the first you see
two emergencies of love. You see the the
bonding of male to male in the hunting
pack and you see the maternal and then
you see the bonding of the maternal as
nurturance. The mother elephants
uh and the aunts and the grandmothers
will all nurture the so they they bond
like men bond. Uh so the women bond in
maternal functioning.
As far as love between men and women,
that is a very recent thing.
Couple hundred years old. Romantic love
is just born on the planet. And men went
off and hunted. Women stayed home, made
babies, and they didn't hang out with
each other.
What are you going to talk about? You
know what I mean?
Romantic love only arose a couple
hundred years ago. You really in the
feudal feudal era era where the idea of
a flower to the lady of the house and
and all this women were to mate with and
men were to bond with. See to a man men
bond with other men and they mate with
women but they don't necessarily bond
with women
as we know from the divorce rate.
Women come and go. Yeah. But your
buddies are your buddies. You know what
I mean?
Your buddies are your buddies. Women
come and go. Yeah. And women at the same
time also hang together for the sake of
the clan and the children and the
growing growing up of the young ones.
But romantic love is really very very
recent
on a romantic level. However, we do see
love evolving as companionship and
friendship in play even in the early
Mamlian kingdom. And anybody who watches
the Animal Channel sees that. Last night
there was a very funny one about a
parrot and a cat I think that that
bonded with each other and they played
with each other endlessly and rolled
around them. So you see the evolution of
love. We didn't see it in the dinosaur.
The dinosaurs don't really kid around.
But we do see the evolution.
So the capacity for play which then
evolves through the intellect is humor.
And one of the most healing modalities
and useful in spiritual work is a sense
of humor. And I would say never trust a
person who doesn't have a sense of
humor. They'll turn you in.
They're deadly. Yeah. Every
whistleblower is grim. Uh we wanted to
ask about the uh the elephants.
Elephants a group of elephants
calibrates over 180 185 190 192.
Elephants are what? 192.
Very interesting. They have a lot of
awareness and uh nonverbal
non
nonstructured awareness. There's an
awareness of uh that they are. So let's
see what that says.
The elephant is realizes it is resist.
H it realizes that others are resist.
Capacity to recognize existence. Huh?
Capacity to recognize existence.
So that awareness is uh why I can't uh
hunt and I can't see anybody really
hunting who who's conscious because
uh I remember my father saying that uh
one time to be one of the boys he went
hunting with a 30 caliber deer rifle
and he finally discovered this deer in
the woods and he looked in the deer's
eyes and in that instant he couldn't
kill it. He saw what it was. He saw the
consciousness shining out of the deer.
The deer loves its life and is aware of
its existence the same as you. No
different at all. It just doesn't call
itself deer. But he saw that it was
really existence itself coming forth as
awareness of existence and he couldn't
kill it. And uh so he never killed
anything. I've never killed anything
either.
Uh, it's just because you're aware that
it loves its life.
All that exists loves its life to the
same degree that you love your life.
Let's see if that's so.
The deer loves its life to the same
degree that we love ours. Just wow. Huh.
It loves its life to the same degree you
love yours. Huh?
M. So
that makes the Middle East look a little
worse than it did this morning.
All those people love their life. I
don't know why that didn't cross the
mind of the shoe bomber on that. The
shoe bomber to me is the ultimate. I
don't know. There's something about that
guy. When I look at this picture, even I
say I don't believe this guy
getting on a plane with your shoes full
of bombs to blow yourself and everybody
on the plane up. I mean, it is so
bizarre.
It's bizarre and you know it's funny.
It's humorous.
As you evolve spiritually, then what
happens is you get away from good and
evil and you see things as ridiculous,
absurd, you nonsensical,
childish, immature.
Uh,
I mean the cowboys and Indians games, we
shoot six of them and the next day they
come back and shoot six of us. The next
day we go back and shoot six of them.
I mean, is this or what?
So, you see the Buddhist said and so did
Jesus.
You know that the basic problem is the
only basic problem is ignorance.
See, we're trying to transcend good and
evil. By understanding that ego, how it
arose, how it functions, how it
expresses itself, you have seed the
absurdity of life
in its various self-dest apparently
self-destructive
expressions.
Now, we want to get beyond
positionality. This is from a book I'm
working on now.
Ah, all right.
So we said what the ego does then it
takes a positionality. It says
everything on this side is good
everything on this side is bad and it
but it changes its positionality. So
what's good or what's evil then
doesn't exist independently of itself
any more than offness exists in a war in
a wire or that falseness exists.
It's very obvious that non-existence
doesn't exist.
That may sound superficial but it's very
profound. Yeah.
I think it's profound.
All right. So let's see how this works.
Um you can see that we can take a point
anywhere here.
Uh this is uh light.
We can say that light is either there
or it is not there.
languaging however takes a point here
and says well this is light and this is
dark and they're opposites
as you can see they are not opposites
they're only a matter of degree
and the only thing I really want you to
get out of the this today is
there's only one variable in reality
only one the mistake of the ego is to
think there's two two and those two are
opposites and that you have to choose
between the opposites good and evil and
right and wrong and all
there is many varying degrees
light is profoundly present or it
diminishes less and less
and when it's completely absent we call
that darkness.
Then in languaging in the dualistic
style of the ego we say there are the
opposites of light and dark. opposites
of light and dark. As you can see,
there's no they're not opposite.
Light is either present or not present,
and it's present to a varying degree.
When we go, we'll go go back briefly
over the levels of consciousness and and
see again how that that works.
We can take things as far as their
desiraability
and we'd say, "Wow, this is heavenly.
This is very good. This is sort of okay.
This is fair to middling.
This is sort of lousy. This is horrible.
This is
terrible.
Right? That's degrees of desiraability.
But again, you see, there's no really
good versus bad. There's only a matter
of degrees. A matter of degrees. And
then conventionally in human society we
sort of mutually
agree that we will call this level of
light dimness. We will call you know so
we label it
but the label doesn't have any actual
positionality. It's so we see the old
definitions then then are optional
definitions
for pragmatic uh usefulness.
But there is no there are no opposites.
To merely see that takes you beyond the
polarity of the opposites which is one
of the great blocks to the evolution of
consciousness and spiritual work.
To label anything near the bottom is
bad, awful. You should indulge. You see,
if you label a thing at this side down,
you're going to call it bad, evil,
wicked. We should kill it. I should do
penance. I should beat myself or commit
suicide maybe. Or you should.
Why don't you kill yourself and get it
over with?
Do me a favor and kill yourself, will
you? So
we want to just recapitulate how this uh
oh that's wrong one here it is we want
to recapitulate then how this translates
you see because this is the conventional
map of consciousness
uh power versus force but you see that
here again you don't have goodness
versus evil these are descriptive terms
that they are not opposites are all
matters of degree matters of degree of
what? They're all matters of degree of
the presence of God as love. Yeah. That
which is beyond all form.
The context out of which we all arise is
is over a thousand. But when it hits
human consciousness,
usually we calibrate about a thousand.
So this is either the presence or the
absence of love. Huh. Down here we get
more to the dinosaur. What's sort what's
so sad about the dinosaur
is in human expression it takes disdain
for others disdain for others. You know
Hitler said that at the end of the World
War II all the Germans deserve to die
because they lost the war.
In fact, he was going to burn down all
of Germany and only a few remaining
generals that he that he hadn't
assassinated.
There are few left refused to carry out
his order. He was also going to burn
down Paris and destroy the Eiffel Tower.
And uh again, his generals refused. So
there were a few sane people that
realized that he was quite psychotic.
Uh all right.
So there was a walking dinosaur in human
form. Huh? All right. So
we see there are no such things as
opposites. That an opposite is an
artifact created by an arbitrary
positionality.
You can choose to call this level rich,
this level poor. That's why government
statistics, you know, the percentage of
poor below below the poverty level.
Well, it depends on what you set the
poverty level at. You know what I mean?
Uh,
and those are a matter of many
gradations, expectations, and uh,
what you set the poverty level at. then
decides on what percentage of the
population is uh you know when I first
came out to Sedona I had a truck full of
my old tools for my tool room
and uh and I went to the dime store and
I bought a cot and then I found an old
box that was the table and I put a
candle on there and a book and I was
home and I lived that way. I never even
closed the doors. animals and birds blew
in and out and
you know was I poor? I don't know. If I
needed two candles and only had one,
then I'd be poor, right?
So you and I got silverware. I went to
garage sales. So I got silverware for
like 50 cents and plates for a dollar
and I lived that way for a long time.
Don't need anything. Therefore, you
don't have any shortage. And if you
don't have any needs, you don't have any
shortage, you can't experience your
experience poverty, right?
All right. So there I was with nothing
at all and rich.
Then I needed some cash for something I
forgot. So I had my old truck and Sedona
at that time. This is the mid70s, late
'7s. Uh people were into gardening, but
there was no manure.
I discovered down in um a nearby town
eight miles away there was a dairy farm
with 600 head of cattle. Boy, they had a
lot of manure.
They heaped it up with big m things that
this and then it dried and there was
they had tons of manure. For 10 bucks
they would take this thing, lift it up,
dump it in the back of your truck. Boom.
I had a whole truckload. The back of the
truck go down for 10 bucks. I had a
whole load of manure and I drove it to
Sedona and sold for $55.
45 bucks cash profit minus the gas rate
miles.
So now I was well fixed before I wasn't
in poverty but now I was pretty well
fixed $45.
All right. So you see definition then
definition.
On the other hand back east I can
remember a time when if I didn't have
like 25,000 by Monday I was going to
lose this and that. So you see it's just
all where is poverty? I don't know. It's
where we want it to be.
Uh but there is an important point
there. These are not opposites. These
are not the opposites of good and evil.
But there is an important point. We
notice if we take the temperature of
water. So we need my temperature graph
here degrees Fahrenheit. Okay.
We notice there is something important.
However,
if
again here's either the presence of heat
or its absence. Heat and cold are not
opposites. Cold is not the opposite of
heat.
You could call all this hot. You can
call it hot down as far as you want. You
know, minus50° and Eskimo might say,
"Boy, it's hot today."
In Antarctica, this would be warm,
wouldn't it? Minus 50. that we begin to
notice something different happens and
that is a change of quality.
So if this is um centigrade, if this
were centigrade, we notice at this point
water turns into ice. So that now we did
find out something important
there. You got that.
Now you think that's upside down, don't
you?
That's because you're not standing on
your head.
>> You stood on your head.
>> If you were standing on your head, you'd
say it's upside down.
All right. But we do notice something
critical here which is the same as when
water is 0 degrees centigrade or 30° 32
degrees Fahrenheit and that is that it
changes quality. They're not opposites
but there is a major shift of quality.
Here at 200 we notice above 200 you go
strong with kinesiology. Below 200 you
go weak. Above 200
you nurture life. Below 200 you destroy
it.
Ah so they're not opposites but there
certainly is a major change of quality.
That is the error of the spiritually of
the politically correct person is they
don't get that because of a shift of
context. Now the context is different.
Content the meaning of content depends
on context.
What's acceptable legal procedure during
peace time changes marketkedly the
minute
the incident after Pearl Harbor. All of
it changed.
So the context then changes the meaning
of content. what's appropriate.
You have to change content then because
it mean its meaning is dependent on
context. All right, context.
It's politically naive to pretend that
content does not change with context.
Context is what gives content its
meaning in the first place. up.
So we notice here on this calibrated
level that at 200 there is a change of
quality
water at 32°. So if we take water and
below 32° F it's a solid above 32 it
turns into water. Above 212 it turns
into a gas. Those are very profound
changes due to shift of context.
Technically, the content hasn't changed.
It's still H2O.
It's still H2O. But you can't pretend
H2O at
minus30° is the same as H2O at 32°. And
you can't pre pretend it's the same at
212 just because it's still H2O. So that
is the basis of political naive and
philosophical ignorance of and really
sort of academic sophistry is the
failure to realize that the quality
changes and the quality is profoundly
important in a world of form.
So here at 200 then we have a critical
shift of quality
that is occurring without there becoming
opposites.
The fact that there's a shift to quality
does not mean that they're opposites.
H2O is still H2O whether it's solid,
liquid, or gas.
So we can't say the dinosaur is evil. We
can't say that bin Laden is evil. We
can't say that the Middle East is evil.
They calibrate down here. Their quality
is considerably different once because
they're below the line.
That which is above the line nurtures
and supports life. That which is below
the line is destructive of life.
To see that all discernment then is a
matter of positionality. All description
is arbitrary.
No such thing exists in and of itself.
It gets you out of the hook of good
versus evil. I mean, good versus bad,
good versus evil.
It's the way out of guilt about
the content of your own consciousness.
It's the way out of hating the content
of other people's consciousness.
Do I hate bin Laden? No, I don't hate
Bin Laden.
Uh why would I bother hating Bin Laden?
I mean, the guy is sort of mental,
right?
He belongs in a ward someplace, you
know, it he's not responsible. Not
responsible to himself, to his fellow
human beings.
And he said, and there he is trotting
the glee that he killed 3,000 Americans.
He's going to kill Americans. So, the
whole idea of killing Americans is, you
know, they forget, you know, they've got
280 million more to go.
If you're going to kill Americans, you
better get busy. You better kill them
round the clock. And you better do more
than 3,000 at a time because they
propagate faster than that. By the time
you kill 3,000, there'll be 18,000
babies born already. So, you better
increase the speed of So, I mean, you
know, it's not only feudal and stupid,
you know, and you worry about the
vicinity of his soul. Well, I guess I
shouldn't worry about it
anyway.
All right. So we begin to see then
things as nonsensical, idiotic, uh
ludicrous, ridiculous,
uh
and that which is ludicrous and
ridiculous is very close to that which
is funny. You know, like the joke, I
don't know whether to commit suicide
today or go to a movie.
Why is that funny? because
it's it's
ex it's extremely funny.
You see Bin Laden saying, "I don't know
whether to kill 3,000 Americans today or
uh go for a camel ride." Well,
I don't recommend camel rides myself. I
would never make a very good Arab.
I was over there and when you're on top
of a camel, let me tell you, you're way
up in the air. You're not like a horse
at all. I mean, you're like up there.
And I had to bigg the camel driver to
get me down. And uh he wanted 10 bucks.
So help me God. He would not, hey, rich
American, you give me money. I said,
listen, I paid for this camel ride
already. You got plenty of money. You
American. Give me money. Give me You
wanted $10 to get out this camel.
I said, "It's either that or I'm going
to sit out in the hot sun often." And so
I gave him 10 bucks. And then he had the
camel sit down.
I understand camels completely, you
know. And the older you get, the older a
man gets, I think, the more he
understands camels. And
Yeah. And the camel
poor old camel like his arthritis is
killing him.
He's got this mean trainer. They're mean
over there. They got this whip and if
the camel doesn't behave, they whip
their front legs. Camel.
So that did not uh make me happy with
that culture at that time. Anyway,
all right. So, you see how then life is
evolving in varying degrees. We see that
consciousness is really the appearance
of love and the evolution of love
and um
you see almost the resistance to the
lower energies their dominance of life
on this planet uh almost in conflict
with those that have a higher energy.
It's almost like a battle
uh to see who's going to dominate the
planet. And then of course in 1986 what
we discovered was that the consciousness
level of mankind for the first time went
over 200. And the prognosis then for
mankind is considerably different.
190 means that eventually man would
destroy himself.
My prediction was the man was
uh going to destroy himself. It was
almost inevitable. In fact the mechanism
was already in place. You remember the
Russian super bomb that if they lost the
war would destroy destroy all of life on
this planet for thousands of years and
millennia to come. So the megalomaniac
almost won this planet came very close
very close and uh but then what happened
is consciousness went over 200 and I
think it's currently still at 207.
Somebody asked me has it changed since
uh uh 911. I don't think so.
consciousness level of mankind. We have
permission to ask that in the public
resist. It's over 206 207 208
still 207. All right. It stayed very
very low for
thousands of years and then suddenly
jumped to 207. The prognosis for mankind
is completely different. 207 is a whole
different universe than 190.
190 what Hitler did is acceptable.
190 the Middle East would be acceptable.
Um
190 devastation and disease and ravaging
others and rape and pillillage
uh is acceptable. Over over 200 is no
longer acceptable. It still goes on. It
still goes on because the evolution of
consciousness seems to evolve in certain
places on the planet.
Uh the western world as we know it tends
to calibrate in the 400s.
Uh there's places whole continents that
calibrate maybe 70. Uh the whole African
continent calibrates maybe 75 or 80
which disease and death and all such
things are prevalent and the average uh
age of death is 26 or 29 or 30 or
whatever.
So we see consciousness then breaking
forth in greater evolution in in
primarily in spots on the planet. Uh
America is about 431
I think isn't it?
Um, America as we know it is over 400,
420, 430, 431, 432, 431 is right on uh
where America is. That's quite a
contrast with uh 70. You understand?
It's a different world. We cannot judge
the Middle East, which calibrates at 70,
when we're at 431,
right? You understand? It's a different
world. It would be like saying
alligators are wrong to eat other living
things in the swamp. That which lives in
the swamp lives in the swamp and lives
by the laws of the swamp.
You understand how we're transcending
good and evil, good and bad, wicked. And
so we're trying to do this morning is
transcend that positionality. The most
difficult one for most people in
spiritual work is good versus evil. Mhm.
That's the one that people get hooked on
either in condemning others which then
puts them in the same point of self
judgment or in judging themsel which
they then project onto the world and
judge the world. So, it's hard to watch
the evening news without good and evil
coming up. And the president of the
United States, of course, has a very
black and white idea of good and bad.
And it it has, you know, pragmatically
he's, you know, pragmatically it works.
Pragmatically,
pragmatically,
um, when you're out in nature, there's
certain things you better avoid and then
there's other things that that are
useful, right? So a workable pragmatism
then but he's not you know for our
purposes then good and evil are
different than what the president is
saying. He's saying from a political
point of view.
He's also probably personally quite
moralistic about it too. He probably
believes that. But the spiritual aspirin
has to forgo that convenience. It's just
a convenience. It' be neat to just
classify everything above as good and
everything below as as bad. You see, but
it doesn't.
The backfire of that is that you then
get stuck in that duality yourself.
And spiritual work means giving up
judgmentalism. Judgmentalism means to
transcend perception.
And what that means is that you have to
see it differently. You have to context
that means you have to contextualize it
differently. So what we've been trying
to do this morning is recontextualize
all of life as it evolved throughout all
of time. how it presents itself
in various gradations so as to transcend
the positionality so you don't get stuck
in the duality of the opposites.
That's good enough for the moment.
Should we take a break?
>> Okay.
Thank you so much.
You can tell a true spiritual teacher
they always wear white socks.
Why do they wear white socks? I don't
know.
>> Cuz they can't be bothered trying to
find a pair that matches. I guess that's
what
somebody asked how does spirit energize
the body. There is a disinterest in the
body as you dis uh you know as you
disidentify with the body which can
happen very rapidly. Uh I always tell
people if you're into serious spiritual
work,
make sure that some other people know
about that, you know, because uh people
can think they're far from the truth and
then suddenly without warning, it comes
on without warning.
You're in a completely different
dimension
and the physicality is actually of no
interest whatsoever.
Um
maybe it's advisable not that people
know what you're up to. I don't know
when I think about it.
Without other people, the physical body
would be uh would uh you'd never bother
with it. It would just topple over
eventually.
So happily, if you have people in your
life that care about the continuence of
that physicality, they remind you to eat
and all the things that you need to do
to keep it going, but left to your own
devices, you'd never bother with it.
Uh
well, we're out and back talking about
all kinds of interesting things, but I
forgot what they were.
>> Things I said I was going to be sure and
mention, and I don't remember what I was
going to mention.
>> Huh?
>> Ask her to ask the question again
as you whatever question.
>> Oh, she asked me about karma. Yeah.
Yeah, that's right. I started it off.
Uh
anyway, we said that
what to worry about as a spiritual
aspirant.
Um then nothing to worry about because
once you're a spiritual aspirant, you
already committed to
we said the spiritual will
in in meditation and all spiritual work.
Um the field seems to be scattered. You
look at the content of consciousness,
you look at the mind and the events of
the world and sort of your life seems
sort of scattered and sort of that's
sort of worrisome.
Yeah. First I'm reading this book, then
I'm reading this book, then I'm hearing
this guru, then I'm going to that
lecture.
Uh but one's spiritual commitment. So
the decision of the spiritual will is
what determines karma karmic
consequences
and determines uh the fate of the
spirit.
People she was asking me what you know
what is the significance of it and that
and I was explaining that the uni the
universe the entire universe is one
karmic unity.
Everything within this universe is
related to everything else within this
universe
based on the laws which
are of the nature of the creator because
of because the entire universe comes
from one creation. Therefore the entire
universe is one karmic unity. Nothing is
beyond the karmic
oneness of all of creation.
Consequently, whether people believe it
or not is irrelevant. That one's destiny
is already karmically dis determined.
Even if when you die, you go into
oblivion. There's nothing more. That's
already karmically determined, isn't it?
You didn't determine that. So, even
though people deny karma,
that's just a conceptual thing that
they're talking about. What they mean by
karma. When people deny karma, what they
mean is reincarnation. Well,
reincarnation is one thing. Karma is
another. Well, we're going to do a
lecture on that, so I won't go into it
extensively. But as we demonstrated, I
think in a previous lecture, Jesus
Christ never had any previous physical
lifetimes.
He never spoke of any previous
lifetimes. One reason is he never had
any.
Interesting, eh? The Buddha on the other
hand had many previous lifetimes and the
Buddha spoke of it extensively. Buddha
remembered many previous lifetimes. I
myself remember
uh many many lifetimes in great detail.
Let's just ascertain the truth of that.
Jesus Christ uh never had any previous
physical incarnations. Resist. That's
correct. The Buddha had many. Resist.
Right. So Jesus, one reason he didn't
speak about previous lifetimes and
reincarnations, he never had any.
And by questioning we got that Christ
did come down from heaven that that
dominion that domain and did our
incarnate and did never had a previous
physical lifetime. The Buddha on the
other hand evolved through countless
lifetimes and so their teaches teachings
are different. Christ came for
salvation. The Bu Christ teaches
salvation. And Buddha teaches
enlightenment. Again, don't confuse the
two. They're two different things.
Enlightenment is one thing. Salvation is
another.
How does spirit function practically in
the physical body?
Well, spirit doesn't really function.
Spirit is like uh like the electricity
in the wire. And uh doesn't the
electricity doesn't care what form it go
flows into. It could be a toaster oven.
It could be a microwave. It doesn't
really care because it only is what it
is. It doesn't change function.
Uh so the spirit then is you might say
is the energy of life itself. The energy
of life itself
manifests depending on the form in which
it finds itself.
How do you calibrate truth versus
non-truth if you don't have a partner to
do kinesiology? That's a frequent
question. And a lot of people know um th
this this particular technique where the
truth makes you go strong and you can't
break the ring and bin Laden
thought that guy again. I don't know he
makes you go weak. So that's one
technique you can use on your own. Uh
there's many people know how to do it
there. If you go on the internet under
kinesiology, there's quite a list of uh
resources.
Also, from the levels of consciousness,
you can pretty much guess where you're
at and where everybody else is. If this
is a meritocracy where a college
education, intelligence, reason, and
logic, and science, the new god of the
world is not religion, but science, then
you can pretty much know, you can guess
America's in the 400s. You don't really
have to calibrate it. And so if you're
if you merely look at the levels of
consciousness to see what prevails, uh
you can pretty much guess the level of
consciousness.
Um any phys any
difficulty
this question here really relates to to
healing. This really relates to healing.
Um the letting go of negativity in all
the forms in which you can tends in and
of itself to have a healing effect. Uh
the letting go of judgmentalism. The
course of miracles I always tell
everybody in the office who has any kind
of an affliction. If you haven't done
the course of miracles, you ought to do
it before you die from what you got. You
know, didn't want you to worry about
your hypertension, but
you got a year to do the course of
miracles. Anyway, Course of Miracles is
very, very practical.
If you got cancer, high blood pressure,
whatever ills you
miracles
and uh I did original research on them
and they they first came out, you know,
and I knew the Kushes and I knew Helen
and Bill and all those people and we had
a attitudinal healing center at my
clinic back east. We had the second one.
Jerry Jolsky started the first one in
Tiviron. Then he and his uh crew came
out and stayed at my house back east. I
had a very large house and we spent the
weekend and u we started the second
attitudinal healing center. The purpose
of the attitudinal healing center was to
practice the principles of the course of
miracles no matter what the ailment was.
So we had people with multiple scerosis
all kinds of illnesses. I've seen every
kind of illness that walks the planet
remit, go into remission and heal
itself. And the institute institute of
nuetic sciences has records proven
medical records of something like 86,000
uh miraculous cures and healings from
every affliction known to mankind.
We notice that uh beyond uh I won't even
say what that number is because people
jump to that number and read that lesson
and skip the ones that precede it. But
when you get to a certain level of those
lessons, you're only subject to what you
hold in mind. And you can begin to deny,
refuse, and release it and recover from
it. And all the ailments I had when I
took the course of miracles all
disappeared.
I got new ones later, but
I'm working on them. No, they're not
actually illnesses. Yeah. Anyway, the
course of miracles. So, I always tell
everybody if you've got a physical
ailment, no matter what other spiritual
work you're doing, uh, do the course of
miracles because first of all, it's
hysterically fun. I mean, I'll never
forget the first lesson here. I'm a
psychiatrist and the lesson is uh,
nothing your mind your mind thinks means
anything.
I almost fell off the toilet. It was
hysterical.
I mean, I recognized the genius. I said,
"This is genius." Instantly, I saw the
genius of it. Nothing your mind thinks
means anything. Whoa. I knew this course
is for me.
So the course is beautiful and um
you know science of mind u the 12step
groups and u
course of miracles are all beautiful
ways of transcending the negatives and
putting you in a very good place. All of
them will take you in the high 500s.
Alcoholic synonymous calibrates at 540.
Of course, a miracle calibrates at 600.
Uh so to get out of the bottom of the
box and uh transcend to higher levels.
Um the the purpose of Christianity is
really to reach 540. I mean, what Jesus
Christ taught was
designed to get you to 540,
which is unconditional love,
to pray for your enemies, to turn the
other cheek, etc. Uh to give up hatred
and pray for them, to see them as
ignorant rather than evil. That's all
designed to get you to 540. And from 540
on, anybody who reaches 540 has no
worries in this universe because 540 is
heaven and beyond. And uh 540 is also I
think lotus the lotus land of Buddhism.
I never calibrated lotus land but I
think cal calibrated would be about the
same lotus land is about 540 resist.
Okay. So the Buddha you see Buddhism uh
has various schools also and lotus land
Buddhism envisions the Buddha who then
has a different name because his
function is different as the Buddha of
salvation that you're not
that there is a certain understanding
that the negativity of this world is so
severe that the average human is
unlikely to reach enlightenment from
this plane that it's like the gravity
here is so strong that to transcend the
level of gravity of the consciousness of
this world is so unlikely that it's
better to be practical. Aim for 540
which is heaven and from heaven you
don't have to worry because heaven at
540 is beyond the tremendous gravity of
so much negativity
and uh so in that function the Buddha
stands for the savior. Um he's the
Buddha of salvation and the Buddha of
lotus land Buddhism. So bu Buddhism and
Christian lotus land Buddhism and
Christianity are very practical very
practical.
Reach 540 and you don't have to worry
because from there on uh the great
beings will lift you and uh and you'll
be okay. So I don't worry about anybody
once they reach 540. I don't really
worry about anybody once they get to
500.
Um,
and I really don't worry about anybody
when they were in the 400s or even the
high 300s.
We uh, you know, I did Walmart power
versus force. We calibrated Walmart and
Sam Walton and I corresponded back and
forth. I approved to Sam Walton because
he stood for integrity, integrity. And
he liked the book and uh,
uh, anyway, I think we calibrated
Walmart in those days was like 380 or
something. Well, 350 and up is uh
willingness.
So Walmart, when you walk into Walmart,
their attitude is, "How can I help you?"
Right? That's willingness. And um we
have friends that if you're carrying
packages out to the truck, they run over
and say, "Can I help you? How can I help
you?" So that's a very positive uh
level. You know, when the world at the
time was 190
and here's Walmart at 370 or something.
So anyway, we predicted that Walmart
would do well
and um but two weeks ago I think it was
announced Walmart has become the largest
most successful corporation in the world
in the entire world. So 350 or 360
is a lot different than Enron
to be helpful to to be uh integrous to
give you a good product made in America
all those things are uh integris. So I
just thought it was interesting in '95
cuz I calibrated Walmart. I think it
must have been in '94 cuz I did power
versus in 95 in 94 you know we already
knew that Walmart was going to do well.
Um
so integrity in the long run takes you a
long way.
Uh this question was about blood
pressure. We wandered off the subject.
Um, the course of miracles I think is
based on, you know, what we were talking
about this morning. In other words, to
let it go of a positionality
which creates a duality which puts you
in good versus evil and
and puts you into a polarized dualistic
uh belief system.
So the course of miracles is designed to
transcend that belief system, take you
out of perception
uh through a nonjudgmentalism.
All right? Non-judgmentalism. So the
course of miracles then is based on
forgiveness. In order to forgive, you
have to have already made a judgment. To
have made a judgment, you've had to
adopt a positionality. So our purpose
this morning is in a way the same as the
course of miracles to transcend
positionality. Stop seeing it as good
and evil. We don't have to hate Bin
Laden. We don't have to hate dinosaurs.
Don't have to hate them.
I wouldn't hang out with them though
because they'll eat you alive. But uh
uh
it doesn't mean you have to become
stupid. It just means that you have to
comprehend
that which you experience from a
different
context. And spiritual work is really
one of identifying with a with a more
and more diffuse context getting away
from the specifics of content.
We we're going to do a lecture later on
meditative techniques and um there's a
meditative technique in which um one
focuses primarily on peripheral vision
which anybody can do.
It's working in the same direction as
the course of miracles or consciousness
research that we're such as we're doing.
As you walk about the world, instead of
focusing on the content and the itty
bitty nitty-gritties,
you you you focus on the context,
the overall space in which you are, the
overall space and the intention for
which you're in this space.
In other words, you identify with the
context out of which life arises and
then of course at this moment is taking
this form. But your identification
becomes progressively
less with this body and this table and
this particular audience and it
eventually takes you to existence
itself. So as you let go identifying
with and focusing on content,
you become you realize that you are the
context.
You thought you were the content and you
realize, oh, I'm the context in which
it's all happening. I'm the theater. I
thought I was the play. Oh, you're not
the play. You're the theater. So
constantly expanding context means then
you're less and less vulnerable to what
people say and do because they're more
like in a movie. You see
this actor says this and this actor says
this and there's no point in taking it
personally because it's all just
happening in a movie and have nothing to
do with you because that which you are
is the context, the awareness
and not the content. You're not the
content.
So the less you identify yourself as
this thing here saying this thing here,
you're more the witness of what's
happening. You're the witness. So you're
the witness of what's happening in the
Middle East. You don't have to make it
right or wrong. You don't have to
feel bad about it. You don't have to try
and change it.
Ramana Maharshi who is well known to
probably many of you here
said there's no point to try to change
the world because the world you see is
just a perceptual illusion. There's
nothing that needs changing.
If the world is one big huge karmic
unity, then what is it you're going to
do that's going to change all that?
as General Powell just discovered.
I I could have saved him the bus fair to
begin with. Well, I'm sure he knew that,
too. But anyway, he went through the
motions because otherwise we don't look
like we're for peace. You know, all the
BS that goes on. So, to look like we're
for peace, he's got to go through the
actions and all. They don't want peace
anymore. The man on the moon, you know,
why would they want peace? I mean, their
whole life is war. So
um the Palestinians as a people want
peace resist the Palestinians the
Israeli as a people want peace resist
the politicians involved want peace
resist okay politicians don't want peace
so send the politician to talk to
politicians who don't want peace to go
for peace and um
you know they don't like wedies you know
selling to some wedies
they've already made up their mind. They
don't want any wedies.
All right. So, is that right or wrong?
Neither one. Is it something we should
desire or not desire? Neither one.
Armano Harshi says the world you see as
a projection of the ego, which is what
we're seeing this morning. So, how to
then change what it is you're
projecting. So, we won't see the Middle
East as good or evil. We'll see that
it's not too evolved, right? 70 is not
too far along.
It's it's over here someplace. It's not
too far along in the evolution of
consciousness.
Uh it's sort of u not too far from where
the
where the u
we showed this last week, but I just
wanted last time for those of you who
haven't seen it.
All
right, that's the next one.
So, you see
where where is this thing? Population
percentage.
Wow.
Oh, the world specified. I see. Where is
70? Oh, golly.
Way over here. Wow. So, it's a pretty
dark place to be, right? A dark place to
be. That's all.
To transcend good, the opposites of good
and evil, right and wrong, is already a
major spiritual advancement
because it means to let go positionality
and judgmentalism.
A positionality is after all a judgment.
The course of miracles says let go of
all judgments and then perception is
replaced by vision. You see
the magnificence and the beauty of life
without projecting anything onto it. So
that which is
then is beyond cate categorization and
beyond descriptive terms and it just
stands forth in the brilliance of
the divinity of its creator.
All that exists is innately a
manifestation of God. Uh
the nonform within form is the presence
of God within all of creation. Nothing
can exist otherwise.
and the letting go of positionality.
Then in one instance suddenly
at least in in this experience
there were a number of experiences um
incredibly beautiful
uh the snowbank and with my father and
many other similar ones but the one that
happened in ' 65 was very sudden and
unexpected
in which
all becomes totally silent and the word
the wording and the talking that people
do which to this day I have difficulty
understanding and I have to say what
many times
because
it's the silence that predominates
and the noise is
the noise the words the verbiage is in
the background
and you have to focus on it and bring
the verbiage
uh
in across the silence in ordinary
life sound predominates.
People don't notice silence because
they're hearing the birds and the
talking and the movie going on. And
um their focus is on the sound.
But you understand you cannot hear sound
except against the background of
silence. It's because of silence that
you can hear sound.
Without silence you can't hear any
sound.
For the same reason that without the
emptiness of space, you could not
discern an object.
Without the nonform of consciousness,
you would not be able to comprehend
perceive form. It's because of the
formlessness of consciousness, you can
perceive form.
It's because of the silence that you can
hear sound. And in that state one is the
silence and not the sound. And um people
are into sound all the time. And uh
anyway in trying to readjust to the
world, one has to readjust to focusing
on sound and verbiage and meaning and
all that. But it's tiring
and you have to say what all the time.
which makes you sort of stupid but
uh if people explain it then I guess
your intention to comprehend is what
makes it comprehensible you know
otherwise it's not really comprehensible
it's because the presence prevails as
the primary reality of which you were
there any more questions before we go on
I think I answered them all
>> um You said the Middle East was 65. I'm
curious to know whether if you looked at
the different components of that, say
Israel, the Palestinians, maybe some
that would be different.
>> Uh, no, because my interest is in the
context um, and not the content. My
interest is in the context of the
phenomena. So, the phenomena, see,
because I I'm not interested in
identities.
the phenomena is coming out of out of an
energy field at about 70.
Uh that's the field that prevails there
and those people are dominated by that
level of consciousness. So 70 is
dominating the field there
just like in other uh situations uh
other levels of consciousness let's say
in everyday America the the prevailing
level is 431
that's the level you're expected to live
up to you're expected to be able to read
and write and know how to make out your
income tax
uh because So the expectation of our
world is 431. Intelligence, education,
uh vocabulary,
responsibility,
reasonable degree of mathematics. You're
supposed to know how to work a VCR.
You're not supposed to have your light
thing blinking on your VCR.
70, those people are expected to be that
way. And you know how people live up to
what is expected of them.
So at 70
their society is expecting this. They're
politicians are presenting that as the
ideal
just as Stalin presented uh the ideals
of Lenin as an ideal for their society
and everybody then tries to live up to
that uh ideal.
due to to sort of mob psychology, you
know, I think they expect themselves and
each other to behave in that manner.
The world of the spleen is tit for tat u
this for that um
and getting even. So every night's
headline is they killed 12 on this side
and then the next day they killed 12 to
get even and they killed 12 to get even.
And so,
uh, the expectation then
is sort of
that the schoolyard boys in a fight.
You're not going to let them get away
with that, are you? So, you've got to
punch him back otherwise you look like a
coward. So you're more or less almost
forced into a fight that you don't
believe in because
prevailing social pressure is that you
need to continue to fight.
Fighting is part of the energy fuel 70.
Yes.
>> Could you repeat what you said in the
beginning about I think you said there
were three different elements you needed
in order to make the physiology testing
work about consciousness level in the
person.
Well, all we said was that um the
conscious level of the participants or
the person who's doing it by themsel has
to be over 200 has to be integrous
and the intention of the question has to
be integrous.
Sometimes I refuse certain questions
because I get what the intention is
behind the question
and um
and therefore it's not really
appropriate to do it
when you're identifying more with
context than with content. Then you see
you you be you become you become the
context. You don't become the context.
You identify, you realize that you are
the context out of which it is all
arising.
It is because of your consciousness, the
presence of your consciousness that
there's that the mind is thinking
thoughts without your consciousness
there. So you are that which activates
the mind to even think.
So your identifications become
progressively more one with of context
and the self with a capital S is that
out of which
and at one with all that is. So as you
let go
with content, you become more and more
context.
Yeah, that sort of takes us up the hill
here.
Anyway, I just thought that's sort of
interesting.
See, when you when you look on this when
you look on this, then your expectations
of the world change. You say, "Where is
200 here?"
this much of the world
population is uh not up to the level of
integrity yet. So, you can't expect them
to be uh integrous because they're not
there yet. It would be like asking a
Tyrannosaurus Rex to please be
considerate of the feelings
of that little goblin looking thing you
just ate. You know, it doesn't much care
about that.
So, these are really uh enlightenment
then is really uh I don't know how you
work this thing.
uh
divinity and all the levels of
enlightenment and sages and enlightened
beings and Buddhas and Christs and
Krishna and all all you're talking about
is what the person knows as what or who
they are.
Enlightenment is 600. So when we go up
that levels of consciousness, one goes
up through lovingness, the willingness
to surrender judgmentalism
to get to 540, which is unconditional
love. Unconditional means you got to let
go right and wrong.
Uh and begin to see that it's not
appropriate. It's irrelevant.
That's done in 12step groups all the
time. And I use an example. The guy runs
over three people on burns down a house
and uh
and uh goes to a meeting the next day
and they say, "George, we're sure glad
to see you here.
You sure belong here."
That's all they care is that he's at a
meeting where he needs to be. All right.
So, it means the willing the willingness
to forego judgmentalism.
The way you transcend judgmentalism is
the willingness to forgo it. How can you
forgo it? You can forgo it because you
see it's irrelevant. It's irrelevant.
It's irrelevant.
If a dog is biting your ankle, it's
irrelevant whether the dog is a bad dog
or not. He's biting your ankle. You
know, this is not the time to hang out
and decide whether he's a good or a bad
dog. You see,
whether what goes on in the Middle East
is good or bad is irrelevant. It's
relevant. It's irrelevant.
So
it's really that you transcend judg
judgmentalism because you see it's
irrelevant. It's a so what. So the way
you transcend
right and wrong and judgmentalism is you
see that it's just a so what. I mean so
what? You know what I mean?
The guy was wrong when he did so and so.
Well so what? So he was wrong. It's all
so big deal.
In other words, one gives up,
they're trying to juice it.
See, what people do with right and wrong
is they want to juice it. The people
like judgmentalism and right and
wrongness
and morality because you get to be on
the good side and you can juice it.
You hate to say that you're better than
they are, but you know it. See,
I hate to tell you you're wrong,
brother, but you know you're wrong. You
know, to be polite, you don't say it,
but you know it. He's a creep. You all
knew the creep.
All right. So, the lower levels of
consciousness all have their payoff.
the way you transcend them. You don't
have to transcend those levels of
judgment. All you have to do is
transcend to say no to the payoff.
And as you let go of the payoff, they
disappear.
When you don't take glee and putting
your thumb in somebody's eye anymore,
you stop putting your thumb in people's
eye. It's because you're getting off on
it. Take that. You
What's those What's those people on
television every night? every night on
television
throwing rocks at the Israelis and the
other side the Israeli kids are throwing
rocks at the Palestinians. I mean,
they're just loving it. You seen that,
man? They're having such a fall. Take
that. Take that.
It's the juice they get out of it that
that's that hooks them in it. So, people
the ego, what is the ego addicted to?
This is a great moment in history. The
ego is addicted to the juice it gets out
of its positionalities.
That's what keeps it in place. It gets
off on it.