what it takes to make people stop talking 100 decibels the calibrated
energy of that music is 700 so I just wanted to know what 700 sounds like it's
like being in shark Cathedral Notre Dame the same energy 700 hmm well let's see
what were we explained this morning Oh secret of the universe some things are
very simple once you understand the truth of them and the great mystery and
dissertation over the centuries falls apart so on the blackboard here on the
whiteboard we have a picture of God as indicated by these little dots the
little dots are just so you notice that the board is actually white and in the
middle we have the ego so as you see the ego is form
the
the ego is form the ego is form and spirit is the formless so spirit is the
field and the ego is the content of the field the content of the field
therefore the content of the field cannot be understood unless you define
what the time context is so no truth is definable unless you describe the
parameters of the context in which it's being described because that
which seems to be true in one context is a lie and another it's an it's not
possible to define truth without without stating the context without staying the
context and that is a great source of philosophic and intellectual error
scientific error is the failure to define the context in which a certain
thing is being said you mentioned this morning
projecting current social more ease backwards in time and then making them
wrong is one of the defects of faults of logic because what's true now is true
because of the field the social consciousness that is an awareness that
prevails today but that was not so in past times yeah all right so let's see
where were we with our projecting slides oh my goodness we're brushing up to
quantum mechanics oh and you see because we say that you know within the
Newtonian paradigm or causality reigns supreme this causes this everything is
definable and solvable by the differential calculus
but outside the realm of the definable knowable and predictable we begin to
discover another realm another region
The non-linear domain, yeah, the non-linear.
So this is linear, but around the edge, the linear starts to get a little fuzzy.
It gets a little fuzzy.
So quantum mechanics then takes us into the world of the fuzzy.
Yeah, the Newtonian paradigm, you see, here's the Newtonian paradigm,
which is the limitation of the mechanistic reductionist
who is stuck with a computational, limited, permanent, constricted, settled, sequential,
provable, highly predictable world.
However, although he believes in that, he doesn't live there.
He lives farther to the right in the quantum potential,
the quantum potential, you see,
because in actuality, subjectively, things are quite disorderly.
They're not at all predictable.
They're quite illogical, frankly.
Because they're creative, they're actually free.
They're not determined.
A little bit of imagination totally changes the whole thing
because it's progressive.
Things are not separate and discrete and therefore measurable
without defining context
because they're intermingled and interconnected.
They're diffuse.
The accident that happened with, what do you call that thing that was off in the air?
Space shuttle.
It's a consequence of the field.
It's not within the computer.
It's the carelessness, the indifference, the somewhatness,
the, oh yeah, of humankind.
That's not measurable.
Huh.
How many times have you taken off in your car
and you really should have checked the pressure in your left rear tire
and you didn't?
You know what I mean?
It's okay.
It drove me back and forth to work all week.
So you see, that's not measurable, though.
Caringness.
So it's diffuse.
It's vague.
It's non-local.
Things happen that are beyond comprehension.
Things don't happen separate from each other but simultaneously.
These things here are measurable.
These things here are observable.
You can measure a quantum.
But how would you measure, is it worth the bother or not
to check the pressure in the rear tire?
Is it worth the bother?
Ah, it's okay.
That's not immeasurable.
You understand?
On the other hand, your lip just hung in the balance.
Your lip hangs in the balance by, oh well.
Maybe we could.
Ah, I'd rather have it.
Thousands of lives just went down the soup there, folks.
Imagine the time of invasion of, I'm not very left-brained today,
the great invasion of Germany across the English Channel,
Britain and Normandy.
And who was the German general?
Rommel.
Rommel was off celebrating his wife's birthday
on the day of the great invasion,
which the Allies likely would not have won had Rommel been there.
But Rommel said, okay, Christina, or whatever his name is,
he didn't want to disappoint his wife, so he wasn't there.
Any more than the admirals were available in Pearl Harbor.
They were off at a party someplace, I think.
Yeah.
Where were the great admirals?
The great admirals to defend Pearl Harbor on December 7th, you know.
I think they were at a birthday party or someplace.
So those are the non-ponderables, the immeasurables.
And those are the things that define, decide human history, aren't they?
The human history is not decided by the Maginot Line.
The Maginot Line in World War II was indestructible.
Nothing could have gotten across the Maginot Line.
However, if I was the general on this side,
I would have said, I will put up a Maginot Line.
That forces them to come across through the Ardennes Forest.
So I would have been waiting for them.
And wouldn't have been surprised at all.
So history then is set by the imponderables.
Just fleeting mood, a slight forgetfulness, a little bit of tiredness.
You get something in your eye.
Infinite possibility.
And it's altered by observation.
And that is the whole quantum mechanics.
It's altered by observation.
Anybody interested in explanation of the quantum mechanics
and how it applies to consciousness?
Raise your hand.
Oh my goodness.
All right, we will show that after all.
Okay, it's expansive.
It has to do with context.
So the field then is context.
Now, this is the world of force.
The Newtonian paradigm is the world of force.
Force goes from here to there.
And consequently, it expends energy.
Consequently, it results in counter force.
Force always results in counter force.
Force always exhausts itself.
The great Roman Empire dominated for a thousand years.
Finally, it couldn't be fit anymore.
Money, gold, bodies, lives.
And it just petered out.
They just married the local women and the empire dissolved.
It just petered out.
The heck with it.
It killed so many people.
He just pooped from killing people.
And he just falls over and says,
The hell with it.
I think I'll get married and raise kids.
And that was the end of the Roman Empire.
Now, power is like gravity.
Power, which is like spirituality,
influences everything within its field
as a consequent of that which it is.
As a consequent of that which it is.
So spiritually devoted people
think that they're bringing about change in the world
by doing this and doing that.
It has nothing to do with doing this and doing that.
It has to do with what you have become.
What you have become then empowers the field.
The field then brings about
certain consequences automatically
as a consequence of the field.
So power does not consume energy.
You don't have to feed anything,
any energy to gravity.
Gravity just completely controls.
It influences everything within its domain
and it requires no power at all.
It does not consume power.
So divinity then encompasses all that exists.
And its power is infinite.
And like a great gravitational field,
everything within it then
is at the effect of the power of the field.
That's why divine justice is absolute,
impersonal and absolute
as a consequence of the power and the quality
and the nature of the field.
There's no point of fearing God
because the giant electromagnet
I saw out behind this building this morning,
every little iron filing
is completely told by the power
of the magnetic power then.
So we are all subject to divine justice
which is absolutely perfect
and not arbitrary or capricious
or vengeful.
It doesn't require all the things
that have been alluded to God.
It's the source of all power.
It's uncertain.
It's poised.
And it resides in the subjective.
So the quantum reality then is subjective.
All right, so let's skip that one
and instead we'll go to the left-hand side of the folder.
I think at the back we've got...
We weren't going to do quantum mechanics
but if they want quantum mechanics,
by God, they're going to get quantum mechanics.
I don't know anything about it
but you're going to hear what I know about it.
I wanted to show this one
because...
What's the name of that guy,
the morphogenetic...
Rupert Sheldrake.
I'm not very left-brained today.
Rupert Sheldrake's morphogenetic fields.
You see how the pattern within consciousness then
manifests in what appears to the world
to be a sequence.
It's the out-picturing of ABC.
The sequence...
This is actually just perception, see,
because you grasp first this,
grasp this, then you grasp this.
So you think it's happening that way.
No, you're perceiving it that way.
The way it is, is ABC, like a gestalt.
It then displays itself in the world suchly.
Okay.
Yeah.
Yeah, we weren't going to do this one
because it gets us off into left brain.
But we'll bless left brain.
God bless left brain.
And get right on in.
And go right in, yeah, you know.
So for those that like it, you see,
on the internet there's a fellow named Henry Stapp.
S-T-A-P-P.
Professor of Advanced Theoretical Physics at Berkeley.
And his program on the internet
is probably the best I know of
to make quantum mechanics
and how it would apply to spiritual reality
comprehensible to the ordinary mind.
We all have an ordinary mind as well as
an extraordinary mind.
Anyway, this came out in 1927.
You see the Schrodinger, famous Schrodinger equations.
There's two Schrodinger equations.
One's time dependent.
The other is time independent.
We don't have to go into its mathematics.
I purposely left off the mathematics.
But the quantum state of a system then is its potential.
The Heisenberg process is where choice and intention
and decision come in.
Because there can be no karmic responsibility,
no evolution if it weren't for choice and possibility.
So intentionality.
So karma is set by spiritual intention.
The power of intention is what sets one's spiritual karma.
It's not the act but the intention behind the act.
So intentionality.
So Heisenberg observation, of course,
was on the submicroscopic level
that you cannot do the same example twice
because having looked at it, you've already changed it
and it is no longer the same example.
So the Heisenberg process introduces choice
and intention and consciousness.
So consciousness enters in.
So the Dirac process is what happens after you observe it
or make a choice.
And it's called the collapse of the wave function.
Now the universe has changed.
It's changed because you've looked at it,
because you've decided something.
And the process by which this happens
was described by von Neumann as process two,
the physicality.
Process one, the mental.
And as you see here, the universe can only say,
what we said this morning,
the universe, according to quantum mechanics,
can only say yes or not yes.
It cannot say no.
So the kinesiologic response then
is explicable by quantum mechanics.
It's the thing is, and if it is, your arm goes strong.
If it is not, your arm goes weak.
But it cannot say yes or no.
It can only say yes or not yes.
So when I ask your arm, this is the truth.
And I do it by making a statement.
I don't ask a question.
We can say, this is an adequate description
of what I just got through explaining.
This is an adequate description of choice.
Spiritual decision and choice.
That's how we evolve spiritually.
So the collapse of the wave function
takes it from a potentiality to an actuality.
And in so doing, we fulfill our karmic evolution
and responsibility.
So we can go on to the sequence.
To this point of view, from this point of view,
of this, whatever is talking now,
it talks by itself, by the way, just like it moves by itself.
I can't explain it.
It sees this world, human world,
as a purgatorial realm.
Purgatorial in that human beings suffer.
Human beings have the opportunity to undo old bad karma.
They have the opportunity to create new karma.
Purgatorial in that it offers the opportunity
from the most base and hideous of human behaviors and choices
to the most lofty and exquisite.
Whether you're going to sacrifice others
to your personal ends,
or sacrifice your personal ends
to the welfare of others out of love,
is a huge choice.
And the karmic consequences are quite profound.
So, to evolve, then, we would have,
and to also be answerable for who we are,
you would have to have a universe
which is purgatorial in range of option.
If this was just heavenly,
and there was nothing but goodness,
and all you had was good options
about good people coming from good persons,
seeing things goodly,
you're stuck.
Right, aren't you?
You're stuck in heaven, huh?
Right.
We observed this morning that everybody is born
with a different calibrated level of consciousness.
So, therefore, life as we see it
within this domain is evolutionary.
Its expression has been evolutionary.
And the individual consciousness is evolutionary.
So, you need a realm of optimal opportunity.
Optimal opportunity.
We were talking today at lunch
about how people get over 200.
Viewed from that viewpoint,
then, war is really a necessity, isn't it, almost, right?
How are you going to undo the karma
of all the people that you've killed?
Well, you get killed yourself.
One way.
How do you get beyond 200?
Within the masculine domain,
you do it by walking into a hail of bullets
for the sake of the queen,
for the sake of the throne,
for the sake of God,
for the sake of your country,
for the sake of your comrades,
for the sake of your regiment.
For something greater than yourself,
you're willing to surrender your life.
That takes you above 200 forever.
That's in the masculine domain.
Not to win because you're going to get the ribbon,
but because you're doing it for the university.
You're using it for the country.
Women athletes do it for womanhood.
Men do it for whatever they may be doing it for.
Because they're run by testosterone.
The victims, there's real victimhood.
That testosterone loses on the planet,
and you got what you can see out there as history.
The way the traditional masculine way to cross over.
You say, why do wars keep recurring all that way?
In some ways, there's no way beyond that.
It's only when, for the good of the regiment,
you walk shoulder to shoulder
and walk right knowingly into a hail of bullets,
and you're willing to die for your country,
your flag, for your family, for your wife,
for womanhood.
That's what the man does.
Does it for God.
For a higher purpose.
You shoot above 200 forever.
The woman does the same thing in childbirth.
Instead of bullets, childbirth threatens her life.
Over the centuries, she died by the millions.
The average woman died sooner or later of childbirth.
She had three or four children and then died.
If she got as far as three or four.
And I looked through the old bible of my own family,
and there's the pattern.
She had little Ricky, she had little Jimmy,
and then she died when in childbirth.
And the man at that time was on his third wife.
First two had died in childbirth.
And this one's pregnant, God help her.
For the sake of bringing forth new life,
the woman passes over the likelihood of death
and faces death as a distinct possibility.
And she shoots above 200.
The paradigm then is a little bit different.
All right, so the calibrated levels of consciousness.
We went up as far as 600, I think, on that other scale.
Because 600, you enter a different dominion,
a different domain.
You begin to transcend.
You transcend identification with the ego.
And now you begin to identify as the field.
Actually, you don't do anything.
It happens.
Suddenly, one is blissed out.
And all thought stops.
The process usually stops at that point.
Usually stops at that point.
He walks and talks almost like a real human.
He's very good.
If we get over 600,
God help you if you do.
Anyway, 600 is enlightenment.
A very profound experience.
Happens 1 in 10 million human lifetimes.
Extremely profound.
50% of the people leave.
It seems like luck,
if it happens within your own experience,
that somebody may come along
and see to it that you get off the rock
and eat something, whatever.
Because by 700, again,
the experience of Ramana Maharshi,
for instance, is quite typical.
And if you've ever been in that state,
you know what it is.
He stopped eating.
He didn't talk for two years.
They found him in a bliss-out state.
He was covered with bugs and bugs and sores
and been nibbled on by mice and various things.
But he had spiritual friends who discovered him
and nurtured him and got him back to eating
and various things.
But he did not speak for two years.
So if you're into serious spiritual work
and meditation,
if you're into serious spiritual work,
somebody around should know about it.
Your friends, your family.
Not for the continuation of your physicality,
because that's irrelevant.
Whether you topple over or not
is really not of any particular importance.
But they might haul you to a psychiatrist
whose decision is to find out
whether you're catatonic
and need shock treatment or not.
Ramana Maharshi would have been taken to a psychiatrist,
wouldn't he, if he was doing that today?
Silent, not talking,
seemed out of this world, you know?
And when I was a consultant to Zen monasteries
and I've been consulting the Catholic diocese,
Epictetus diocese, Zen monasteries,
all kinds of people,
that was my job,
to differentiate between true spiritual states,
and pathologic psychiatric disorders.
Is this religious ecstasy?
Or is this manic depressive psychosis
and into religious delusions,
you know, grandiose delusions?
Once in a while I get a letter
from somebody that's in that state.
They just discovered they're God
and want to share the information.
Yeah, I tell them, if you were God,
you wouldn't be interested in sharing the information,
you know what I'm saying?
But the mere fact that you asked me
shows that it's not likely.
I think in chapter 10 of the last book,
we had an audience like this.
We went over the attributes of God,
as they really are.
And we had 100% unanimity.
We divided it up into ones and twos.
The whole crowd of us did it
at Creative Life Center.
And I think we listed about 18 of the qualities,
the actual qualities,
the qualities of God.
And that's using the term qualities lightly.
The reality of God.
And the answers were unanimous.
Unanimous.
And when you calibrate them,
the energy fields of God is infinite.
God manifests as divinity or creator is infinite.
Then we have other things that we have read about
in spiritual literature.
Within this domain,
within this domain,
the highest calibrated level of consciousness,
compatible with walking around on the planet,
is about a thousand.
And the reason for that appears to be
that the human nervous system
cannot really handle anything over a thousand.
It hasn't up until recent times,
but I think it's evolving
that it's going to be able to handle 1250.
But anything over 6 to 700 is already painful
and it feels like you're being slowly electrocuted.
The Buddha said
that he felt as though his bones were broken and cracked.
He said his bones were broken and cracked.
He tried the same thing, see?
He felt as though his bones were cracked and broken.
Yes, okay.
So, Christ, Buddha, Krishna, Brahman,
all one thousand.
Avatar, 985.
Self as beyond existence or non-existence,
we said at age three.
That was the confrontation
at about 850.
Reality as allness or nothingness.
Self as beyond existence or non-existence,
to transcend that duality.
To be a teacher of enlightenment, 800.
I as sage, 700.
Enlightenment, 600.
Because the other scale went up to 600
and then it stopped there,
you wonder what's beyond 600.
All right.
So that pretty much covers it.
Yes?
When you said over 600, 50% leave.
Yes, there, 50%.
You mean die?
The physicality, yes.
Yes, to leave the physicality.
Because there's no interest in it.
By choice?
No, it's not a realm of choice.
This is very hard to explain.
The presence becomes overwhelming.
And one has,
implicit and part and parcel
of the presence is permission.
There's a knowingness within the presence
that you have permission to leave.
You can be walking down the aisle
in the middle of a lecture
and then it becomes all of a sudden
very intense.
Almost like a magnetic attraction to leave.
You have complete permission.
There's a knowingness
that you have permission to leave.
You don't know whether
the physicality will continue or not.
It happened right during a lecture one time.
And other people know that.
The audience didn't know
whether it was going to continue
with the body or not either.
It just came out of its own.
And the attraction to leave the body
was quite intense.
And the permission was quite,
quite overt.
And there was no way,
it was, the witness watched to see
if the body was going to make it
to the end of the aisle and back or not.
And it did.
So, that's the way it went then.
It just comes out of its own.
You were talking about your own experience.
Well, this was, yes,
that was a personal experience.
When it first came out,
it was the same.
One can leave or not leave.
And my presumption was
that there is some karmic propensity
or some decision prior made
that's running it.
It's not a personal decision.
But if some purpose is served
by the continuation,
it may be that way.
It may go that way.
But there's no,
there's no inner self
saying yes or no to it.
You know, there was only the witnessing
of the body would continue
to walk down the aisle
and make it back again
or it wouldn't.
There was no way of knowing.
Was that similar to 1938
when you were in the snow bank?
No, that was different.
Well, yes, in the same way.
Those who've had near-death experiences,
I forget, there were some here, right?
Yes.
There was something
very characteristic about it.
And the difference between
out-of-body and near-death
is that without a body,
in out-of-body there's no change
of calibrated level of consciousness,
which is quite surprising.
Because here you think
you're a physical body.
You think your name is Dave.
You're laying in this bed.
Suddenly you're 12 feet away
from the body looking down here
and the you is up here.
The you is up here
and if thought moves
over this way,
the entity or whatever it is
moves over there.
You would think after
such an experience
that at least the realization
that I'm not a physical body
would bring about a shift
of level of consciousness.
But surprisingly it doesn't.
Out-of-body for some reason
does not bring
a shift of consciousness.
Near-death experience,
on the other hand,
is something else.
Near-death experience
is much more profound.
And that which was
that which you think you are
is replaced by a presence
of infinite love,
stillness, security,
that has always been.
One realizes
that that's who you are.
That that who I am,
that which I am,
existed before all universes
and will exist after all universes
have disappeared.
After all universes
have sprung forth
as a breath out of Indra,
and the dream
has sucked them back in,
that which I am will prevail.
The certainty then
that death is not a possibility.
Other people think
that the death is real.
Consequently,
because of love for them,
there may be a decision
to re-breathe the body.
There's no necessity
And my advice is don't.
However,
if your father thinks
that you've died
because he believes in death.
I see my father sitting there
and he believes in death.
And if you don't re-breathe the body,
he's going to think you died
and he's going to go through grief
and all such.
It's quite apparent in that state
that death is not a possibility.
So the other good news this morning
or this afternoon
is that death is not a possibility.
It's not possible to die.
That is not possible.
Why is that?
Because of the law of conservation of life.
There's the law of conservation of energy,
the law of conservation of matter,
and because that's the Newtonian paradigm,
they forgot the more important paradigm,
the law of the conservation of life.
You cannot extinguish life.
Life can go from one form into another,
but you cannot extinguish it.
So,
if a moth is flying by and you swat it,
the moth goes right on flying
and it's an etheric body.
It doesn't even notice the change.
It goes right on flying along
and it's an etheric body
and then it comes back after a while
through an egg and all that
and comes back
and has another physical body.
Swat that and it doesn't even notice it.
Let's see if that's true.
A moth doesn't even notice it
if you swat it out of its physicality.
It doesn't even notice it.
You think you killed it.
You didn't kill it.
What a joke.
How could you kill it?
That which is the essence of existence
is beyond the swat,
the energy of life.
You didn't kill its electrons.
You didn't kill anything about it,
but you did knock it out of form.
Now you feel guilty that you've killed something
and you go into lifetimes of penance,
all the things you've killed,
when you haven't killed anything.
If life was killable,
none of us would be here.
This is hardly everybody in this audience's first lifetime.
Nobody gets to an audience this advanced
in their first lifetime.
If life was killable,
there would be nobody here.
That's a fact.
We have permission to ask if there are people here
in their first karmic lifetime.
There are.
Nobody's here in their first karmic lifetime.
There are no newly born spirits amongst us.
Life is indestructible.
The law of the conservation of the energy of life,
far more important than the conservation of energy.
Life cannot be destroyed.
You can force it from one form into another form,
but you cannot kill life.
It's not possible to kill life.
Well, in the near-death experience,
that is a realization.
It's obvious that you are, before,
this physicality.
In fact, you are before this universe.
I was before this universe,
and I will still be here
after this universe had disappeared.
That is a statement of fact.
It came on as a realization
when I was 12 years old in a snowbank.
One's immortality is obvious
because the essence of the presence
of the source of your own existence
is what you are.
So, how could you be separated
from your own essence
of that which you are?
Not possible.
So, after a near-death experience,
there's a curious loss of fear of death,
which I didn't know about
until a few years ago.
But, experientially,
all fear of death disappeared.
So, in World War II,
when people were blowing up
and people were throwing up with fear, etc.,
there wasn't the slightest even concern.
You know, there'd be a mind
ready to go off right next to the ship
and the horns of this mind
would be bumping against them.
Everybody would swat with fear.
And I'd fear,
look, keep that guy away from me.
It was only concerned with the job
of keeping that thing from bumping us.
The fact that you could blow up
never even crossed my mind.
So, there was a peculiar loss of fear of death.
Death has lost its possibility as a reality.
And therefore, an oncoming bullet or something
doesn't bother you at all.
You just don't want the shooter
to feel guilty that he killed you
because, you know, it's not possible.
As I say,
you're enlightened
and somebody's going to assassinate you,
what do you do?
You go,
I hate loud noses, you know.
I hate loud noises.
He's doing what he thinks he's got to do,
you know, God bless him.
So,
if he does it for a holler or whatever.
All right, so,
that takes care of near death.
Near death experience.
Transformative.
And the calibrated level of consciousness
before and after a near death experience
is quite remarkable.
And of course,
many people have remarked about it.
Doctors have written about it.
People who survive heart attacks
will tell you their life is transformed.
All the materialistic goals they had before
now seem ridiculous.
The love of,
love then becomes the predominant motif.
Most people,
gone through double,
triple bypass
and near death of cardiac arrest,
usually are quite a bit different
when they survive.
Unless they're imbeciles.
Anybody here trans,
survived cardiac arrest
or major cardiac events?
No.
We have a pretty young audience.
Okay.
But any of those who have
know that life is profoundly different.
So, okay.
We're trying to transcend the mind then.
If the mind is the big block,
and then a group like this,
which calibrates at 435,
in a group like this,
the mind is the ultimate block.
You've got the spiritual motivation,
you've got the know-how,
you've got all the books,
the teachers, etc.
So, the thing that intervenes then
is thinkingness itself.
And the problem then
is how to transcend
the identification with the mind.
For a group like this,
which is pretty sophisticated,
we already know we're not the,
we know we're not the body.
That we're pretty certain about.
I mean, if you take off your arm,
you're still you.
If you take off this arm,
If you take off this leg,
you're still you.
You take off an ear,
you take off a thumb,
no matter what you take off,
you still say I.
So, you get,
I can't be the physical body,
or I'd only feel like half my eye,
half an eye.
You know?
If my thumb went to heaven,
I'd say,
well, I'm less of an eye
than I used to be.
You know what I mean?
He's waiting for me over there.
Give me back my thumb, God.
I don't know.
Take care of that karma.
Anyway, I'm sorry
I stuck my thumb in your eye,
Miss Kelly.
Okay, all right.
All right.
So, when you,
in contemplation and meditation then,
you'll notice that there are fields
and levels of awareness.
At first, you're aware of form.
That's content.
This is the ego,
structure and form.
This is what people complain about
when they go to try meditating.
I can't do that.
I can't get my mind to stop
creating pictures, images, memories
and all that whole tantasmagoria.
If you watch the rise and fall
of the content of consciousness,
pretty soon you become aware
that you're not the content
because the content is constantly flowing by
like a river.
And instead, what you are
is the witness, the watcher.
And so, identification is not
with the content of consciousness now,
but the witness,
the witness and the recognizing
or the observer.
You become that
which is witnessing the field.
So, instead of identifying
with the content of the field,
you become aware
that you are the field.
You are the witness,
the watcher,
the experiencer,
the observer.
Mr. Gadatta Maharaj
became enlightened
after only not too many years.
And the teaching of his guru
was to watch the mind.
And Mr. Gadatta,
who calibrated about 720 or so,
the same as Ramana Maharshi,
taught people to really watch the mind.
So, what he was saying was
focus on,
focus up here.
Don't focus on content of mind,
focus the watcher,
the watcher, the witness of mind.
Then you begin to realize
that watching and witnessing
is happening of its own.
You're not deciding to witness and watch
what goes on in your mind.
This is an impersonal phenomenon.
So, if you identify with the content of mind,
you think it's personal.
Then you realize,
how could it be personal?
Because you don't have any choice
whether to witness and watch
what's going on in the content of mind.
It's happening of its own.
You can't take credit for that.
Neither should you take this credit.
So, one quality,
now you begin to notice
the impersonal qualities of mind.
It automatically witnesses and watches
and automatically registers
because it is a phenomenon coming out
of a quality of consciousness itself.
The unmanifest,
the unmanifest,
the unmanifest becomes the manifest.
The unmanifest is the Godhead,
becomes manifest as divinity,
the allness of creation.
All that is created,
both visible and invisible,
comes out of the unmanifest,
becoming manifest,
radiates out as the light of consciousness,
which is the source of all life.
Consequently,
the reason you can't kill life
is because you can't kill God.
The thought that you could kill life
would mean that you could kill a part of God.
Not possible.
So, we can stop feeling guilty
about all the little ants we stepped on.
Yeah, there's a certain point
in spiritual evolution
where you feel guilty about every ant
that you might have stepped on.
It is some sort of a semi-Buddhist tradition
that religion,
they wear mosquito nettings
so they won't breathe any bacteria in their mosquitoes
and accidentally kill them.
They must be doing some karma there, right?
Let's go on next.
From carelessness about life,
now one becomes overly protective about it.
Okay?
What's the next one?
Is that the next one?
I don't believe it's the next one.
Let me see on the list.
Let me see the list on there.
It seems to me we're missing something
we wanted to explain.
We'll explain it.
We don't need a picture anyway.
Yeah?
Let me just see the list,
the typed list.
There you go.
There it is.
I just wanted to make sure
all the ones I brought.
Oh yes, we did, didn't we?
Okay, let's just go through
the application of calibrated levels of consciousness
to the world that we look at.
Hmm.
The calibrated levels of consciousness, then,
are a profound implication.
We mentioned this morning
the application of spiritual principles in business.
We gave Walmart as an example,
calibrating at around 350,
of integrity in business.
Integrity in business is not airy-fairy.
It shows up on the bottom line
as the biggest corporation
and most successful corporation in the world.
All right.
So this is application of business.
We've done a lot of research
calibrating the levels of consciousness
throughout the world of spirituality
over great periods of time,
from the Gitas,
where they calibrate ancient Hindu Vedas
in the 900s,
all the way down to current writers, etc.
One application that we ran across
because of the 9-11 and the recent events
was to calibrate the regions of the world.
So people are following
and demonstrating karmic patterns.
It's like great cycles of people
who come in and come in together.
We see North America.
What did we say our group was here today?
435, right?
Yeah, this group is 435.
You see, the higher you go,
the more high it is
because you're talking about
logarithmic progression.
So 400 is not twice 200.
But it's immensely more than 200
because it's the log of 400.
All right, so 421 is America today.
415, 410 is North America.
Right now, Mexico is 255.
Let's see if that's still so.
It seems to me it should be higher than that.
Mexico is over 255, 260.
No, it's still 255. Okay.
All right, then we go into the Caribbean islands.
We go into middle America.
We see that it's in the 300s.
So throughout...
So in the high 400s,
you go on down and you're in the 300s.
The 300s are still extremely high.
300s are a very high energy.
That's a lot of ambition,
a lot of integrity,
a lot of willingness.
And we see that this hemisphere, then,
is potentially a pretty peaceful place.
You've got 400s and you've got 300s.
And then suddenly in the middle of all this,
if you calibrate all these maps,
your Central America 305,
suddenly you see a 55.
Yeah, turns out to be Haiti.
Right, okay.
So, you see, consciousness research,
you don't take any position by it.
You say, if we use this research
and we begin examining nature, animals,
geography, populace, civilization,
you know, what kind of a picture will emerge?
So we find that here is a whole hemisphere,
extremely high calorific,
high calibration,
and right in the middle of it you have 55.
So you just put this in your noodle
to understand the events of history,
the events of political realities
and what the implication is.
What is the implication of 55
in the middle of 300s and 400s?
We know that sending,
it was tried to send money there
and it made things worse
because it increased nutrition,
it created population growth,
and the poverty got worse.
So the question is then,
what do you do with a country that calibrates at 55?
You see, it's a completely different question.
Okay, so let's go to the next one.
Calibration of 9-11?
I don't think so, no.
It takes a lot.
You see, the level of consciousness of mankind,
no single event changes it.
9-11 doesn't change it.
World War II doesn't change it.
It stayed at 190 after many centuries.
During those centuries,
you had the Black Plague,
you had the, what was it,
the Church of the Churches,
the Inquisition,
you had World War I,
you had the Napoleonic Wars,
you had mass starvation,
you had the great pneumonia,
encephalitis, epidemics after World War I.
And none of those things changed
the level of consciousness of mankind.
Now we see a more complicated picture.
What we did with one side of the hemisphere,
is this the right sequence?
Yeah?
Okay.
All right, so now if we do this
and calibrate all the levels
of all the countries in the world,
what do we find out?
Well, we see Australia, 410.
We see Malaysia, 405.
We see India, 355.
We see China, 305.
We see Japan and Korea.
Korea's about 425 or 430.
We see Mongolia, 175.
So what can we learn from this?
Well, the inference, of course, is quite profound.
Just merely looking it over,
you certainly get a different feeling
for life on this planet
and how it's distributed,
what to expect.
The implications for peace is profound
because the implications for government,
politics and economics is profound.
Because most countries seem to be completely insensitive
to what is the consciousness level
of the people they are talking to.
Are you expressing anything in a language
that is even comprehensible or meaningful?
You talk about democracy and freedom
to people who calibrate at 50,
they're worrying about whether or not
they're going to survive till tomorrow
if they don't have enough food.
Forget about voting for somebody.
They're going to vote for whoever gives them food,
that's how the drug dealer gains power
over the neighborhood
because he becomes the Don.
In Chicago, that was historic, wasn't it?
So the gangster becomes the hero
because they're all starving
and he passes out the jobs and the money.
So that's who you vote for.
You vote for somebody that's going to keep you
and your children alive.
So now you see the implications
for diplomacy, for understanding.
So if you look at each level of consciousness
and then you go back to the map of consciousness,
you begin to understand human history
in a completely different way
than you've ever understood it before.
Most of the problems in the world right now
are coming from North Africa.
What are those two countries that are always at it?
Israel and Palestine, where are they up there?
They're about 180, 180 to 190.
When people say, I want peace,
and you calibrate there at 180,
you know they're lying.
Because their whole shtick comes out of war, right?
I kill you, then you kill me, then I kill you,
then I throw a rocket at you,
then I put the fire hose on you, then I bomb you.
I mean, that's their whole life.
You get a gun, you're somebody,
you get on TV,
peace is political.
They don't mean peace at all.
Why?
Because if you want peace, you have peace.
If you actually want peace, you have it.
If you don't have it,
it's because you don't really want it.
You're just using it as a political slogan
to get votes and justify your political maneuvering.
So, the other thing that calibrating these things does
is unveil the liars in the world.
That's why these lectures are not necessarily popular
in that part of the world.
When the people think it's the walking god
and you calibrate his 180,
can we come down anymore?
Okay, I just wanted to get Africa
where I can put my fingers on it.
Here we have Africa.
You see, as low as 50, as low as 40.
40.
That's practically a walking death.
How they stay alive at 40 is a mystery.
70, 40.
Here you have ongoing civil wars for decades.
They don't just conquer each other,
they slaughter each other.
When this tribe takes this one over,
they kill them all and chop them in small pieces.
They don't just kill them.
They massacre them.
So here you see brutality, starvation.
You see AIDS ravaging the populace.
And you look up at Europe,
you see the 400s, the high 300s.
You look at Scandinavia.
Here's Spain, you see.
France, all these various countries.
And you begin to see the implications for mankind.
The implications for mankind.
What kind of attention has to be put where?
How to phrase that?
What is meaningful to people?
The holier-than-thou attitude of our government,
which antagonizes a good part of the world.
How should you address the president
of the largest country in the world
that has a culture 6,000 years old,
that was civilized for 6,000 years
before your country was even heard of?
How should one address such a person?
I would say with respect.
With respect, you might get a positive response.
With a superior attitude,
you get non-cooperation.
So the implications for international peace,
success, and diplomacy
of understanding the calibrated levels of consciousness
of various peoples,
the country, the government,
and the ruling regime
is quite profound.
It makes the difference between life and death.
There are not no such things
as we are talking about this morning.
Mankind was ignorant.
You see?
The bottom of the ocean is covered
with the skeletons of the dead sailors
of the centuries.
The bottom of the oceans are covered
with the wreckage of thousands
and thousands of ships
because they had no compass.
No compass.
The cost in lives was enormous.
The bottom of the sea
was covered with ships
and the bodies of brave people
who had no compass.
Now we have a compass.
So we can no longer claim ignorance.
No longer claim ignorance.
Here's an easier definition
which is quick to see.
And again, we see.
These all seem to be safe areas
where you can address people
from the viewpoint.
See, the world of the intellect
is for the 400s.
That's reason and logic.
To address people on a different
consciousness level with reason and logic,
you sound stupid.
You sound stupid.
Alright, so here you've got,
let me see the world again.
I just,
it's such an easy thing to hold in mind
but it changes your whole understanding
of the daily newspaper, of history,
of history as recounted by
the political history
and what has gone on
over the centuries.
And we just came back
from two weeks in Europe
where we talked at Oxford University
and we got to see,
it was like a rerun of history
from the 1400s, 1500s.
So it's like a confront
with human history
throughout the Middle Ages
up until the present time.
The architecture,
the lifestyle
and ambiance of the people
is frozen throughout all time
in its sculpture, in its art,
in its artistry.
Incredibly impressive.
So let's go on to the next one again
and then we'll look at the other side of the world.
And I don't know what happens
after the other side of the world.
Oh yeah, the application.
See what a profound importance
in consciousness research is
because you discover things
that nobody's ever known.
Nobody in the State Department
knows anything about what we're talking about today.
Nobody.
Not the most brilliant and experienced heads of government
know what we all know this instant.
We have already surpassed all governments
and diplomats
throughout all of human history.
We now know more at one glance
than they've ever been able to discover
throughout all of time.
That's the payoff of consciousness research.
So now,
we look at the great regions of the world.
Can you bring it down a little bit?
Here's South Africa.
Here's Madagascar.
Here's the very dark parts of Africa.
Here's the dark parts of Africa.
Here you see
North Africa,
the Near East, the Middle East
where all the trouble is constantly going on.
Where you're going to have trouble is
in countries that calibrate 180 to 190
because they're prideful,
they're into revenge,
they're into mutual hatred,
and they're into
lying, frankly.
Not telling the truth.
If they were telling the truth,
they would calibrate over 200.
So what's fun is to watch the evening news
and watch these world leaders come on
and calibrate.
He gives this big thing, you know?
You say, what's the level of truth
of that lecture that he just gave?
180.
We've had world-renowned figures and calibrated them
and the entire address
to the world
was one lie from the end.
You say, is there any truth in anything he said
in the last half hour?
He says, no.
To convincingly lie for half an hour
non-stop.
But that's a job requirement.
We say Australia should be doing
extremely well.
It is in any way.
You see the trouble spots of the world.
You can tailor your expectations then.
If you sign a contract,
it's only going to be valid
if the other person
holds the same values
as you do.
If they don't hold the same values,
they think you're stupid.
So we'll move on to the next one.
We want to see
the applications of consciousness research
in many areas of life.
This is how we do it.
As you can see,
it's not exactly ready for publication.
It's all done in pencil.
But it took a number of weekends to do all this
and great patience, I'll tell you.
Over on the upper right hand,
we can pull them down.
Somewhere we have this typed up.
This particular one, we didn't get around to typing it.
The trouble spots of the world.
We should really try to define
what is the problem with these people.
You see?
And you get their 185, their 165,
their 175, their 160,
180, 185,
190, 180,
all less than 200.
Unless you get the turkey,
70 turkeys is over 200, 245.
So you see,
we can tailor our expectation
of international relationships,
diplomacy,
our political ideology,
to the reality of who these people really are
and how they see life.
Okay, the next one.
How they see life.
The world in which I grew up
saw life in a certain way.
The world in which we live now
sees life in a different way.
So what's the implications
for human survival?
I just want to show you the practical results
of consciousness research.
It completely
strips illusion
and lays bare
the bonds of reality.
Because you will not find reality and truth
in the daily newspaper,
you'll find distortions.
Alright, so let's look at World War II.
To begin with,
peace is not something you cause
or create,
it's that which you become.
Peace is the automatic consequence
of truth.
Where truth prevails,
peace is automatic.
War is the automatic consequence
of falsehood.
So the way to peace then
is by insisting on
the prevalence of truth.
Integrity.
So the way to peace then
is through integrity,
the dedication and devotion
to God's truth and peace.
So can you bring it down just a little bit?
So peace is the natural state
where truth prevails.
War is the automatic state
when falsehood prevails.
Therefore, the basis of war
is ignorance.
Mankind has had no basis
to tell truth from falsehood,
so he's not faulted for ignorance.
Therefore, Jesus Christ
as well as the Buddha
said there's only one sin
and that is ignorance.
Man had no compass to go by,
so how answerable is he?
The basis of war, therefore,
is not evil and awfulness
but stupidity and ignorance.
Why is that so?
Because the human mind
cannot discern truth from falsehood.
The importance of the discovery
of a test to discern truth from falsehood
is that the human mind
is intrinsically designed
and incapable of telling truth from falsehood.
It's convincible.
You can argue with it.
You can persuade it.
But the mind in and of itself
is like the hardware of a computer.
So the ego,
all the belief systems
are the software.
You can see that the hardware
of a computer is innocent.
You can run any software through it.
The hardware remains unsullied.
So the ego is the software,
consciousness is the hardware,
and the human mind
cannot discern truth from falsehood.
So real spiritual progress
is always based on humility.
The first,
most profound humility
is the acceptance
that the human mind
in and of itself
is unable to tell truth from falsehood.
Unable to tell truth from falsehood.
The human mind can be
brainwashed into believing anything.
Joseph Gables
was an expert.
He could convince you
that black was white.
He just kept saying it over.
If a lie is repeated often enough,
the human mind will believe it.
So we as leaders
of spiritual truth
have to become aware
that our first humility
is, oh Lord,
in and of itself
and I cannot tell truth from falsehood.
Human mind cannot discern
truth from falsehood.
Consequence is
the inability to discern
a leader from a megalomaniac.
So the history of mankind
is in the last century
100 million human beings
have been slaughtered
by megalomaniacs.
How astonishing.
100 million people have died
because they can't tell
a megalomaniac from a leader.
It would be like 100 million people
dying of poison apples
because they can't discern
a poison apple from a regular apple.
Wouldn't you think a human being
would know that by now?
If you watched generation after generation
and hundreds of millions of people die,
people would begin to say
how can we tell a leader from a maniac?
Inability to discern a leader
from a megalomaniac.
The problem is,
the ego gets easily,
because of its ignorance,
polarized into ego positions,
distortion of truth and propaganda.
The cost to mankind
is death and destruction.
Let's just say,
if we have now something
that reveals the absolute truth,
what if we go back over history
and examine something,
I just picked this one
and I knew all the people.
All right, so we look
and we see,
how do all these people calibrate?
We can look at the Normandy,
we can look at all the details
of World War II
with which we're all familiar.
We can look at the military
at Pearl Harbor,
we can look at kamikaze pilots
at the lunch hour.
What about a kamikaze pilot?
I always see him
as a brave person
committed to serving
his emperor and his country
and the sun god,
and therefore a noble.
After World War II,
all the former enemies
forgave each other
and we all gave recognition
to the warrior,
the nobility of the warrior.
We may have been mistaken,
but we may have been mistaken,
but our motive was to serve
god, country, and family.
So a kamikaze pilot,
we see Adolf Hitler,
345.
Emperor Hirohito
was right on the edge.
Tojo was a little better.
Yamamoto, surprisingly,
was 205.
So these were people
who were patriotic,
dedicated to their country,
they believed in their cause.
Below 200,
we see Adolf Hitler,
45 at the time of his death.
I think Joseph Stalin,
was a wishy-washy guy.
And when Neville Chamberlain
went to Hitler and got him
to sign a peace treaty,
he went home a big hero.
Peace in our time.
And Hitler thought he was an idiot.
Hitler thought Neville Chamberlain
was really a dumbbell.
That is a fact.
Hitler thought, what an idiot.
Chamberlain walked out,
he went home a hero.
So he called up the troops,
no opposition now,
and so you can see
what went on with
the League of Nations,
did nothing really to stop it.
They could have stopped it very easily
in the beginning.
The attack on Pearl Harbor,
the London Blitz,
the Cambridge Five,
we see treason,
Lord Ha Ha,
traitors,
Tokyo Rose,
Dr. McGonagall.
You see,
we're consciousness scientists
this afternoon,
we're talking about
how can you objectively
re-examine spiritual truth.
A lot of the work I've done
has to do with
the verification of spiritual realities.
Yeah, well you see
there were the traitors
out of that,
the Cambridge Five,
you know,
who gave the nuclear secrets
to other countries,
however they rationalized it,
they did,
and they crashed.
Let's do with the Iraqi War
because it's very recent
in people's mind,
and it may not be
in accord with your belief system,
for which I apologize,
but the way to God, nobody said it was easy.
I'll explain
President Bush
so that you don't have to say,
what about President Bush?
President Bush,
I know his consciousness,
he took an oath,
in fact he told you,
I took an oath as President of the United States
to defend this country against all enemies,
and that is his prime commitment.
So when he puts his hand on a Bible,
he's a man who himself has evolved
because of spiritual convictions,
when he puts his hand on a Bible
that he will do that,
you know he will do that.
Now how he does that,
you may not agree with,
but his intention is at 460,
so these people are all coming from about 450 or 460.
The U.S. Congress,
everybody in the U.S. population,
you see the intention,
the intention was to,
was integrity.
Below 200,
we see the position of other
people at the time
of the
9-11,
we want to say,
we're rerunning what happened at 9-11,
you see Saddam Hussein,
you see Jihad,
Jihad is very dangerous,
you see Jihad at 50,
you better be scared of it,
Jihad is real,
and it's really,
they'll explode or bomb anything,
and the most dangerous person on the planet
is a religious zealot,
a religious zealot is the most dangerous thing going,
it's like an atomic bomb on the loose,
I mean,
North Korea,
I didn't do North Korea recently,
we did North Korea,
we were in Korea,
trying to resolve the conflict,
at that time we were successful in 1999 I think,
at the time I think,
let's just,
do you want to do them,
I don't know if we have permission?
Let's see.
We have permission to do the Koreas now
in front of this audience,
resist.
I thought I'd show it to you because you can see the practicality
of the application of consciousness research in
the everyday world and then the spiritual implications
of this work as it reveals itself.
One more. What did you sing?
It's coming out in a book that we're working on. Here we again
War and Peace. This is how we run quickly through a bunch of wars
so you can see the usefulness. The Korean War, you see
where everybody was there. North Korea at that time was 80.
The communist regime was at 90. The U.S. position was
300. South Korea was 300. All those things have shifted since
but at the time. At the time of the Korean War, this is how
things lined up. At the time of the Cold War
you find out some interesting things.
People accused the Vietnam War
veterans of faking it and all the Vietnam Syndrome, etc.
We ask, was PTSD an actual clinical fact?
We get, yes, it is an actual clinical fact. We know many
people blown out by the Vietnam War who never recovered.
We see what the positions of everyone
was at the time. Not too admirable on a
wide-scale viewpoint. During the Cold War, we see what the
positions were. That was quite a few years, wasn't it?
Neither side comes out particularly
brilliantly. Neither the CIA, U.S. Intelligence,
nor the Russian KGB.
None of them come out to be very sterling kind of institutions.
Khrushchev and Brezhnev, etc.
What went on in the Gulf War? We see President Bush, that was the elder,
at 400, U.S. Military at 310.
Again we ask, Gulf War Syndrome, is that a fact or is that something
they just made up? The answer we got was that it was an actual
fact. Saddam Hussein calibrated at 95.
Kuwait at the time was 195.
World War I, what went on? President Woodrow Wilson was 400.
And again we ask, was shell shock an actual clinical
fact? And the answer we get is yes. So the devastation
of war on individual soldier is real. The Gulf War Syndrome,
Vietnam War Syndrome, shell shock after
World War I are actual facts. It's a fact.
In World War I, President Wilson was 400 and Kaiser Wilhelm
was at 165. We thought for fun we'd go
back to the Battle of Waterloo. And the
Battle of Waterloo, the Duke of Wellington was 405
and Napoleon was 75.
So if you're going to put your money out there, it would be nice to know these, right?
Put your money on the Duke of Wellington.
So we invest then our energies and our efforts
in line with that which is integrous.
With that which is integrous. Definably and verifiably
integrous. Why? Because we say to
ourselves, my own mind in and of itself is unable
to discern truth from falsehood as clever as I think I am.
Everybody's mind thinks it's quite clever.
Anybody here who doesn't think his own mind is clever?
Whatever your mind is. It was so clever nobody
answered, right?
No, the mind is extremely clever. Why is this? Because the ego
cannot survive unless it can convince you
that it knows truth. If the ego knows
truth, you don't need God. You understand that? The ego's
position then is to displace God.
To displace God. And to displace
spiritual souls with
egocentric ones. One thing we've gotten out of consciousness
research then is a certain sense of humility.
A certain sense of humility. That as convincing as something may be
buttressed by centuries of argument, it can be
totally fallacious. What is the level of truth?
Truth is something by which mankind has lived for a thousand years
and you discover that it's only 160.
People sacrifice their lives
by the millions for that which is not even
true. By the millions people sacrifice
their lives for falsehood and illusion.
We're the first generation, we're the first generation
that's had a shot at truth. You realize that?
If you had the good luck to be a pal of Jesus Christ
2003 years ago, you got a shot at it.
You know how many people were within the province of his
teachings, within the purview of the Buddha or Jesus
or any of the great teachers. Of course, the Vedas have
been a source of extremely high truth
for close to 10,000 years, but they don't read the
Vedas in Chicago or Cincinnati
or London or any place else. You see, when
the truth did come about by virtue of the inner awareness
of some mystic who sometimes got burned at the stake for his
efforts, it still only
had a local kind of an effect. It only had a local kind of effect.
See what I'm saying? So, you
begin to become very compassionate about the human condition
itself. Born without fur or hooves
or claws or fangs, no way to survive.
How can you take this human being and put it out with
no clothes, nothing on, in the middle of woods, how is
he going to survive? So, you develop compassion
for the human condition, that it does whatever it thinks it has to
do to survive, because that's been the nature of life since it's
been on the planet as it evolved, was first
and foremost dedication to one's own survival.
And then, the extrapolation of that orientation
as it expresses itself in mind. So, the maps that we just looked at
then, are the expression of the animal
nature as it evolved over the course of time, expressing
itself in the intellect, then in politics.
So, all the maps were within the expression
of the primitive animal, how it expresses itself
politically. You see, the animal nature then
dominating whole continents. Whole continents
calibrate 70, 130, 140, 150,
160, less than John Dillinger.
So, you now develop a compassion, because you see
that which Jesus Christ and the Buddha both taught,
that there is only ignorance, that there is only ignorance.
And Krishna, of the great avatars of all history,
stand for compassion, stand for forgiveness, stand that the only
sin possible is coming out of ignorance. Therefore,
our generation somehow, now
at 207, we have come into a different dominion.
The world of consciousness at 207, we live in a different
world than our parents. We live in a different world
than we ourselves lived in until very recently. Our
expectations of our self have shifted. And spiritual
curiosity, spiritual education
has becoming more and more dominant in our society. The interest in
spiritual issues is now quite strong.
In the same time, we've seen the emergence of
basically purely spiritual, not religious, but purely spiritual
teachings reaching the core of society.
You see, the 12 steps of
what started out as AA, now it's the 12 step program which covers
just about every human condition. You see, the 12 steps have
leaked out and pervade all of society. I hear many people on TV
and they'll pull out a phrase and I know exactly that they've been in AA or they got it there.
It came right to me, it got out of the 12 steps and the 12 traditions.
And then that leads into A Course in Miracles.
So you see an evolution of, you see 12 step psychology
and thinking that's pervading business and society
in many non-visible ways. Then you see
going on to the Course in Miracles and you see forgiveness and
how to recontextualize things so that you see them differently.
The way to transcend the polarity of the opposites, the way to
transcend guilt and anger and hatred of others
is by recontextualization. That a thing looks
different when it's recontextualized is beginning to emerge in society.
See, people don't realize that we're having a profound effect.
On the news now you hear the word
perceived. Perceived. See, that perception
is one thing and reality is another. The police
responded to a perceived threat or the victim responded
to a perceived. So in court now we have
introduced the whole concept of perceived. It was
perceived that way. We don't say it was that way.
Just jumping into the whole idea of perceived
is such an enormous jump. Well that's just the basis of the Course
in Miracles, isn't it? That you ask the Holy Spirit
to help you forgive and the way the Holy Spirit does
it is changes how you see it. The purpose of these
maps this morning about rural governments and all was
to reveal unknown factors. That when you see it differently now
you feel differently about it. Just as those of us that
just came back from Europe got to look at
America's political positions from a broader view. How we are
viewed in Europe, let's say. And it gave us an easier
going view of it because we could see their thought was
look, it's their problem. Why try to get us in? Well, yeah, right.
So think of it, why not?
And you see, you know, that's sort of common sense. Why drag us into your mess?
We've got enough problems of our own with sort of the attitude, you know.
But there was no sharp anti-Americanism. Nobody was hostile to Americans.
Nothing like that. And an easy goingness.
So ignorance, if ignorance is the only sin then
the purpose of today's lecture then is to advance our consciousness
so that we're more aware. It changes our perception of the world.
We can transcend polarities that we would have gotten caught in before.
And we become more forgiving,
more easy going, more loving ourself. And that's
how world peace comes about because we as a group
are profoundly affecting the level of consciousness of the world.
You see on that graph of the distribution of consciousness
that at the very far right, the graph
becomes very slim. Very slim. On the other hand
it becomes extremely powerful. There we go.
We're back on. Thank you.
Yeah, you see over here, the number of people over here is very few
population wise. You know, here you're talking about
87% of the world. And people over here, this audience
here today, you're only a little bitty slice of the cucumber.
You understand? So you got one slice of the cucumber trying to influence
the whole rest of the cucumber. And it does so
by the fact that it's power. So as consciousness advances, it's power
increases logarithmically. So
for a group like this, for their consciousness to jump even five points
is already influencing the total consciousness of all of mankind.
And so we'll conclude with a break. And then what we're going to do
is we're going to answer questions. We're going to talk to people.
And what we discovered is when we meet
people and talk to them, we'll leave the audio on.
So the whole audience shares, you know? And you can come up and ask me individually
and I'll greet and hug you all. And try to answer every individual question.
But we'll all share it together. Okay? Will that be an alright thing to do?
So you want to take a ten minute break? Your minds must be exhausted
by now.