We are
all
he
Thinking that to mention the word God is
the same as practicing religion.
Religion is one thing. God is not
something else. God is a generic term
generic term for divinity. It is not a
religion.
All right. The importance of the 200s
then let's just go over there. I thought
I'd make a whole slide of it because it
is so important.
No, the 200s here. Yeah.
What do we call it? Virtues. Yeah.
Okay.
Transcending then the limitations of the
ego and the roadway to enlightenment is
simple is very simple.
The basic the basic characteristics of a
person has crossed over 200 let's say
could be stated simply
good will towards all. Goodwill good
will towards all.
Practice that in all
in all things. Kindness, respect for
life.
Respect for life, respect for the rights
of others, consideration.
No great requirement. That doesn't mean
leaving the world and sitting
cross-legged, shaving your head and
doing all those strange things.
It means you go through the world
as though you are part of a certain
field which is considerate of others
automatically considerate of others. And
when it's inconsiderate it corrects
itself.
The person who's gone over 200 when
they're inconsiderate it's not okay with
them. They go to bed that night. They
hear their mind trying to justify what
they said, but
part of their mind keeps nagging them,
keeps nagging them because it was not a
kind remark. It was, etc. So now this is
the new paradigm which we live up to. It
sounds very basic. Any one of these will
take you all the way to enlightened.
Take anything off this chart and
practice it incessantly,
constantly, run the clock with no
exceptions. Any one of these will take
you all the way. First one is
availability.
The availability of what? To be present.
To be present.
You walk into a restaurant and when she
never looks at you. She writes it down.
You can't fault her for it. She's not
present.
The next one comes in, smiles.
Instantly, there's a connection. They're
present. Present.
The old truck stop. You the witches
always called you sweetheart. And the
old truckers always call them honey. You
have the same thing, honey. Yep.
Sweetheart.
You see how the politically correct
person would be offended by that?
It was a style of connectedness. A style
of connectedness. It was a way of
lovingness actually lovingness
in and caringness an expression of
concern for your fellow human being
which you kind of have sweetheart same
as usual. Yeah any bud
sounds gruff sort of macho world of you
know the trucker but it you you get the
sense of it you get the sense of it
so they're available to each other
responsive to each other acknowledge
each other's importance in their life.
Yeah. And when you stop back at the same
truck stop, your favorite waitress isn't
there. You feel disappointed. Oh well,
you all sit in her section. You know,
there's a certain affectionateness then.
So the person is available. They're
present. They're present.
But I felt this morning when I felt
something go out in the unconscious. I
felt the being present pull back into
thinking this, you know.
Because thinking this is not present.
Being present. Thinkingness is thinking
this.
And I felt the energy pull out of being
present to thinkingness into it clicked
into the left brain. Being considerate
of others is merely being polite and
thoughtful. Being generous.
Being decent. Just being decent. You
think that's difficult?
MTV. That's decent. in the gangster rock
music talking about killing, murder,
raping, drugs, suicide,
all kinds of sexual deviations, etc.
One just doesn't have to make it bad.
One doesn't have to call it wicked. One
doesn't have to call it evil. One
doesn't have to get epopletic about it.
One doesn't have to get bombastic about
it, pontificate about it. You just don't
go there.
Somehow it's no longer appealing. No
longer appealing. The energy of the
casino just doesn't grab you anymore.
The glamour, the clicking, the sounds,
the magic, the ambiance.
You can see why it's attractive. It's
not like you make it wrong. And you can
see if you're really bored,
you put in $20 in the nickel machine and
when it's out, my god, it'll be two in
the morning when you finally get out of
there.
All right. So you can do it for lots of
reasons. Social curiosity what's and you
know casinos don't calibrate over 200.
All right. Just being decent then to be
decent to be responsible. This is so
difficult for so many people because the
kid in us always wants to deny
responsibility.
It's afraid of guilt and penance. And of
course that comes out of a culture in
which we look for the guilty party
right after the
disaster where the insulation fell off
the space machine whatever they call
that thing. They're right away looking
for who's responsible. Happily they
discovered it was the totality of the
field and not some poor
person that you could then persecute.
So the person then spiritually committed
tends to be reliable.
If you ask them to do something, they do
it. And if they can't, they tell you
they can't do it. You know, I can't be
there. They don't just leave you
standing on the street corner. They
don't tell you they mailed the letter
when it's still in the car. They just
say, "No, I forgot it. It's still in the
car." The willing to take
responsibility, uh, is integrity. So
integrity at 200 is so critical.
They're willing to be honest about the
thing. Well, people can't be honest
about the thing if they're going to
persecute themselves and vilify
themselves for having made a mistake.
So, consequently, we have to have an
easier conscience to begin conscience to
begin with. You can make a mistake and
you don't have to hit the bottom of the
barrel about that. It's just nothing.
So, integrous people are reliable. They
tend to be honest.
What about hard work? What does hard
work mean? All it means is that we put
forth the energy of our presence to the
best capacity that we have in everything
that we do.
Integrous people are integrous pretty
much round the clock. They may have
specific limitations, but if you ask
them to take out the garbage, they're
just as likely to do that as they are to
pay the day's bills as they are to stop
at the supermarket and get something
and refill the and refill that car with
oil. They're going to be dependable
that you can count on. If you can't
count on people, then they're an
aggravation. They're detrimental in your
life. They're detrimental in your life.
And people that are not reliable drive
you crazy.
Honesty, hard work then is just an
automatic consequence of the energy.
People 200 and up have higher energy.
They tend to be moral. Now, their morals
may differ from yours. Their moral
system may differ, but they're still
moral. So if on the other side of the
world they consider things moral or
immoral that we do not agree with, they
are nevertheless being moral in their
own eyes.
People that are above 200 tend to be
warm and they also tend to bring that
forth in others. So if you're a warm
friendly person, you say, "How was your
trip to Cincinnati?" they'll say, "Oh,
the people there were very nice."
The people were there were very nice.
People below 200 do not think the people
in Cincinnati are nice. They'll tell you
they're cold, self-centered, selfish,
and will treat you.
And for them, that's probably true.
The people there probably do hate them.
I never thought of that. Never thought
of that. Yeah. So, the warm person then
tends to bring forth warmth in in
others. What are you going to have for
breakfast? Sugar p plum. And he says,
"Same thing, sweetheart." So the trucker
and the waitress, you know, have a warm
and yet it remains moral and there's a
mutual kindness, a mutual kindness to be
kind to all living things. Now, one of
the things that's important to be kind
to is yourself.
And that's why you have to give your ego
a name. The bad side of you, the shadow
side of you,
what I think young side of this book
called the shadow side.
Give it a pet name that brings it closer
to reality.
Your own human nature deserves at least
as much respect as Coco
or Alex
or the cow with a running nose.
You don't kick the cow with a running
nose.
So at least be kind to your inner ego
instead of vilifying it.
You don't get over being a cow with
penance.
I can do the rosary century after
century and its nose still runs.
the running nose of guilt, self-penance,
and self-hatred. You understand how sin
and guilt and penance bring up
selfhatred?
Self-hatred brings up hatred and
intolerance of others.
This brings up intolerance and
persecution of others who think
differently than you do. That which is
cruel to itself is innately cruel to all
of life.
That which is cruel to itself, that
which wallows in penance,
watch out for it. First of all, don't
have a sense of humor, which is a
terrible, which is a sign of extreme
danger.
That which is gilly and you see gets
obsessive, compulsive, and it has no
sense of humor.
Those who have a sense of humor, watch
them.
warm, kind, helpful to others
automatically.
The Boy Scouts of America, I think, is a
great training in the Girl Scouts of
America. I guess you're not allowed to
call them Boys and Girls anymore. The
the young people of America, whatever
they call them, Boy Scouts of America.
Anyway, starts with moral principles,
you know, and the moral principles are
are designed to be honorable, to be
honorable, to be helpful, respectful,
all the basic virtues. All the basic
virtues. So, I can't see vilifying an
organization
that stands for the basic virtues. Yeah.
Kind, helpful, diligent, easygoing.
Easygoing is the hardest one I think for
people to get.
Easy going because when you deal with
loss or loss of potential gain the
person t in our society
uh
it's hard to be kind to yourself to be
warm kinds
and well-meaning towards yourself.
So easy goinging is a style. Is a style.
Remember in the 12step groups it says
easy does it. You know what I mean?
Somebody ran off with your car. Well,
look, the insurance company will pay for
it or I'll buy another. I'll borrow
money. It isn't the end of the world.
So, you don't commit suicide. Everything
that comes down the pike.
You don't commit emotional suicide by
getting disturbed over everything. Easy
does it. Live and let live, you know,
are easy. easygoing.
The easygoing person is therefore
thoughtful. They tend to be persistent.
They tend to be open. They're
approachable, approachable,
approachable.
They tend to be tolerant of others. They
tend to be calm, dependable,
genuine, meaning if you say you're going
to be that or do that to do that. What
does respectable mean? It doesn't means
prissy.
You know, when I first first time I went
to Europe, I was shocked that the men's
and women's rooms in France and Paris
were were one and the same and just they
had the same entrance and just the
stalls were different on this side than
this side. And I thought suddenly dawned
on me what I thought was morality wasn't
morality. It's just Puritanism.
It's puritinism.
There both sides washed their hands in
the same place. And so
anyway,
we're persistent. We tend to be open. We
tend to be tolerant of differences.
Tolerant of differences, calm,
dependable.
We can we tend to be genuine.
Respectable means then respecting
the divinity, the sacredness of the
existence of all of life.
When we're respectable, we respect the
black beetle fly lying on its back. We
respect the rights of the animal. We
respect the life the rights of all of
life to express itself to its most
favorable degree. And we tend to stand
for that.
We tend to be genuine, respectable.
Patient means not flying off the handle.
Now the more evolved we become, the
easier it is to become patient and to
delay delay things. So, as we get more
and more right brain,
we slow down. There's a delay. Let me
think about it a second. What color
shirt do you want? I don't know. I got
to think about it a second. So, we drive
people who are more driven somewhat
crazy.
Here, get the green one. Well, now I
have to think about it. Here's the one
with the long lapels. No, no, I got to
think about it. How many buttons? you
know you have to delay. So the think
about it is really a way to try and
delay. Why? Because as you get more and
more right brain you slow down with them
and the world is actually going too fast
for you all the time. It's very hard to
stay rightrain and also keep up with the
world world. Which one? What do you
want? Blue or green? Blue or green? Come
on. Give me your answer. You know blue
or green? What? You know
I'm still trying to catch up what
they're talking about. Oh, a shirt. Oh,
you mean buy your shirt. Oh,
you're trying to catch up with where
they're at. So, that's a stall. It's a
ploy. And uh give me a minute. Is uh
time out. So, the more right brain you
get, the slower you get. In many ways,
you need time out. So, you tend to be
more thoughtful, more deliberate, also
therefore more patient.
I realized I'd learned patience one time
when I
I had this old truck and it had a plow
and and to put the plow on these things
had to go up there and you had to get a
bolt exactly through and there was very
little clearance. So I took the truck
and I went up to the thing and I got out
bolt wouldn't go through. So I backed
the truck got back again and I moved it
forward and tried it again. It wouldn't
go.
I did that for an over an hour
and I finally got it
and I was like sort of ecstatic.
I said, "You know what? I could do that
all day and it wouldn't even bother me."
It was like the like a gift. I've got to
give me a gift. I don't have to have a
some fruits of my action. I don't have
to be successful.
You know what I'm saying? I can just
fumble it all day long.
And after I learned the lesson, all of a
sudden, bang, the boat went in.
So many of the things that we rail
about, we rail about are gifts from God
because only by going through that do
you realize that only by having that
energy go out in what was it? The solar
plexus of my devote this morning or
whatever it was, the theologian.
only by having it go out in an
inconvenient time. Who wants it to go
out when you're talking to a couple
hundred people suddenly you feel his
energy go out is not convenient.
Nor would it have been recognized if it
hadn't come up. So it took the energy of
a whole group like this to bring it up.
That's how deeply it was buried in the
unconscious.
So we're respectful. We tend to be
patient and the patience is a
consequence of the field.
If you try to make yourself patient, it
doesn't work. You know why? Because you
get impatient about making yourself
patient.
You get so angry that you can't make
yourself patient
that you're worse. It better be
impatient and forgive yourself and let
it wear out.
You tend to be stable. You tend to be
honorable. Cordiality. Cordiality is why
a spiritually evolved person can land in
New York City. You walk down the street
and talk to an old lady. You can strike
up a conversation with anybody in New
York City and instantly become a friend.
Once in a while you run into a paranoid
who goes,
but he's paranoid
till you say he's paranoid. Poor guy.
You tend to be friendly. Therefore, that
you you're described as mature, you get
that magazine called Modern Maturity.
You get to wear a strange thing in your
shoes. Moderate maturity has these
things. Dr. Scho's shoes. These are
genuine Dr. Scholes, by the way,
because they're uh because Dr.
official's shoes are helpful
and and they're kindly
easygoing. They're always the same,
dependable,
they're genuine,
and the company tends to be friendly.
They billion in an orderly manner and it
all seems normal. So normal. I like Dr.
Scholes.
So you see normal is all the way up at
300.
Orderly is a different way of loving.
Orderly now your caringness extends to
the world and to the environment around
you to the environment that you you tend
to encounter.
If you're orderly, you tend to
automatically sort of arrange things in
a more aesthetically balanced way while
you're on the phone. You're on the phone
and you're and you're picking crumbs off
there and
Ding up the tablecloth while you're
doing something else.
It's hard to stop yourself from
straightening out the world. I try hard
to stop myself, but I just automatically
have to straighten out the world
wherever I go. You see?
All right. So,
we straighten out the world. Uh, we said
we're friendly, idealistic, and we
finally reached a state called normal.
We say, "I just want a normal person for
guy's sake. I'd like to meet, you know,
you get tired of bizarre people that are
out in left field with one thing or
another. I just want to meet a a regular
guy." You know what I mean?
Just a regular person. That's all I
want. Would you like to be with you?
Somebody's just normal, please. Just
give me a regular.
Somebody who in better terminology is
called sane. What we call sane.
Sane people are people who agree with
us. Of course, everybody knows that.
However, we're willing to be fair and
give them a break and realize that they
may just have a different view of
reality. So, the same person is balanced
and you can say, I see how they see it
that way. I mean, I can see how Karl
Marx fell into it and he really fell
into it and the world paid a great price
for Karl Marx's error. If the world had
calibrated Karl Marx before they
instituted communism in a totalitarian
way, they would have saved themselves
tremendous disaster.
So
sanity then is people that think like
us. Fair is the way we treat people and
we hope they will reciprocate.
Ethical of course is who we are. We're
always ethical. And uh what does ethical
mean? It means you live up to your own
standards to the best of your ability.
It also means with the flexibility that
you won't succeed every time.
It means flexibility. You will not
succeed in being polite, friendly,
gregarious, etc. In every instance,
there are times when you won't. However,
by this time, your conscience has
softened so that you don't have to
vilify yourself about it. And you can
say I wasn't at my best.
I wasn't at my best. So self forgiveness
tends to be characteristic.
We're ethical. We become flexible.
We're balanced. Balance means to try to
stay neutral as much as possible. In a
heavily politicized world, it's it's a
constant task to try and stay neutral.
This side vilifies this side. this side
vilifies this side.
No matter who's president, half the
people in the world hate you. I mean, I
don't know how a person can be
president.
The instant you're elected, 40% of the
people hate you already.
I find it hard to sleep with 40% of the
people hating me already. And I haven't
even gotten there.
They hate you before you even get
elected, before you even take office,
don't they? And then if you switch
sides, now the other side hates them.
Right? First this side hates this side.
Then when they switch partners, then
this side hates this side. And after
you've lived long enough, you get, you
know, it's the same program, the same
program.
This side hates this side and this side
hates this side. And the details have
changed, but it's frankly the same
program. And what good comes out of
vilifying your opponent? I'll say to
political candidates, champion you
champion the one that you want elected
and you don't need to vilify the other
one. Why? You can love chocolate without
hating vanilla.
And you can love vanilla without hating
chocolate. Not necessarily to hate the
opposer. It's just better to prove that
you're better than they are. Better than
they are. That you have more to offer.
So then people elect you out of love and
consideration.
Yeah. So you're flexible, you're
ethical, you're balanced. So that's a
balanced view which is respectful.
It's also healthy. We pointed out this
morning
that the negative emotions, the negative
emotions, Canon's fight or flight
response is unhealthy. It causes you to
go weak kinesiologically. It blows out
the acupuncture system. It interferes
with the flow of energy through the
acupuncture meridians to the various
organs of the body. And as you keep
blowing out one meridian or another
repeatedly, eventually you end up with
organic physiologic changes in in
physical illness. So the person who is
then integrous tends to be more healthy
is re more respectful of his life or
their life and the life of other people
tends to be have a more balanced
acupuncture and health health system
altogether.
Faithful of course is obvious from above
the above sense of humor is more evolved
than I thought it was. I thought sense
of humor would come up before them
because there's animals with a sense of
humor.
But a sense of humor to me means the
piece of people are are you can relate
to them. People without a sense of humor
I think are difficult to relate to. Once
a person can laugh, you're much safer
with them. Why? Because you can try a
thing out in the abstract. Humor comes
from seeing the thing in the abstract.
So you can in humor you can put a thing
on in the abstract see it the
ridiculousness of it and discharge you
don't have to live it out if you don't
have a sense of humor you have to live
it out
there people tend to be loyal equitable
this all evolves into wisdom and at 405
we say the person is reliably rational
supportive of others they're benign
they're protective they're humane we can
trust them they're trustable They're
content. They're pleasing. Glad. Happy
to be with you. Sensible.
Salt of the earth is what we call them.
Diplomatic, polite, firm.
These are just the basic decencies.
Basic decencies. But any one of them,
you can see if you practice it around
the clock, seven days a week, you're in
and you're out, will automatically
transform you to the top of the deck.
Because if you're kind and loving
towards all that exists
and you see the beauty, then you begin
to see the beauty of all that exists,
you're already merging into a divine
state. So the divine state doesn't have
to come as a sudden impact. What it
means is as you go into spiritual work
then the field becomes predominant. The
field to which you're committed begins
to influence you not just the ego. So
below 200, the person is the victim of
their own ego. They're the victim of the
evolutionary animal within them.
From 200 and up, now a change takes
place physiologically,
psychologically, emotionally, in every
way. The neuro hummeral neuro hormones,
the brain neurotransmitters,
the brain physiology,
everything begins to shift into a
different spectrum. So you become more
now concordant with the field than with
the content of the field. You're not
just at the effect and especially in a
cause and effect kind of imaginary
relationship. You begin to reflect the
field which you have adopted which you
have committed to. The way to be all the
things on the board is to see yourself
as the field. You're the field of
consideration that walks through the
park. You're the fuel of consideration
that looks after the welfare of others.
You're the considerateness that gives
the guy a break. You're the person that
feels good that you let somebody out in
in front of you in traffic.
Letting somebody in in front of you in
traffic is a very spiritual act.
Not for other societies, but for our
society, it's a very spiritual act.
to hesitate in your own headlong rush uh
to let somebody else have a break, you
know, may not help him, but it helps you
instantly. And every time you do it, you
feel a little better. Once in a while,
you said, "But maybe I shouldn't have
that one." You know,
you let them in front of you and now
they do. Now you say,
"Now you got to honk the horn. you come
express it first you let him in then you
say let's get a move on.
So it's it's just a sense being
spiritual is really a sense of being one
with the field. The field with which
you're identified is innately gentle.
Innately, innate the field is
considerate. And if you just allow the
field to dominate who you are. So you
walk around in a contemplative state
identified with the field to being that
kind of a being. The kind of being that
you admire, be that being yourself.
Just be that being. And sometimes you do
things that your intellect will say are
idiotic. You know that you spent 20
minutes straightening out some stupid
thing. Except somehow you're now more
concordant with the field. So that which
is out, you'll feel a discord within
yourself, a little naggingness that you
should go back and turn that black
beetle over on its feet.
And when you get it bad enough, you'll
walk back a mile to turn that beetle. I
don't know. You just have to do it.
Uhhuh. I should have put him on his
feet.
It's a mile back. You know, people will
actually turn around and walk one mile
back because it nags them. That that
inconsideration for life. Now you feel
guilty about it. Now because you're
identified with the field, disregard for
the life of others is not concordant
with the field.
So the spiritual commitment tends to be
self-correcting.
It isn't that you have to exhaust
yourself and effort yourself with
mantras and meditation
and sitting cross-legged until you get
tendonitis.
Don't scratch.
Hit you with a You're not allowed
to scratch. And so,
all right, we'll stop there for lunch
and uh we'll all be very considerate at
lunch.
All the people that are here, all the
people that work here, community, the
bugs
will be considered the garbage,
the rug.
Excuse me. You'll have to go through the
main lobby if you guided where lunch is.
The wooden Let us know.
>> Thank you.
We'll resume
our
song.
>> Well, we're going to start today.
First of all, we want to thank the
staff, our staff. I wish all our staff
WOULD STAND UP.
I WANT TO SPECIALLY mention
I want to specially mention Brock.
Where's Brock? There's Brock.
Uh,
we thought we lost the music this
morning. Brock all ran all the way home
and got one.
All the way home and got one. And then
we It turned up there was one on the
premises.
Therefore, he's do double things.
Uh the other interesting thing is we
were at Unity, you know, and uh for a
week, couple days and uh met wonderful
people there. I'd never been to Unity
before. And one thing we found out is
that uh I'm going to be teaching
post-graduate courses in the school of
divinity
and hopefully one on mysticism. Oh, God
bless us. And uh
and um I want to just rem tell you that
uh Unity Church needs ministers. Need
about 50. Anybody who's had a hankering,
a longing
uh there's a need from Unity ministers.
And uh so I thought I'd pass that on.
Unity School of Divinity.
Uh
they need 50 like right away.
And I thought of becoming unity minister
at one time and then uh due to other
circumstances couldn't do it. Yes.
>> I just want to pass along that the
Catholic Church needs priest.
formal religion is not too attractive as
a career at the current moment.
And uh but it takes uh I think people
that are committed to the inner
spiritual p pathway whatever pathway
appeals to you is the right one. Uh I
just thought I'd mention unity because
we just came back from there and there
is a der of uh Catholic ministers as
well. Catholic priests rather h
all right so I didn't know there were so
many people who hadn't weren't familiar
with the work so this morning we
recapitulated
a good deal of it to bring those people
up so we're all at the same pace
um I also wanted to mention that uh
people that are seriously devoted to the
spiritual pathway we will we'll we'll
look at their physiology and things in a
few
I feel you know as a spiritual
instructor or teacher whatever my
function is here
to share um certain things you need to
know along the pathway
certain things will come up and if
they're not spoken about then you'll be
mystified or upset by them as you begin
spiritual work as you people are called
to it by a great variety of factors
we pointed out before you start to
become more rightrain.
You because 85% of the population is
leftrain and below 200 you are now to
some degree
um different discordant
not committed to exactly.
So the 85% comes with has certain
presumptions that you will of course do
such and such a thing. So you may find
yourself, you're going to find yourself
in fact at variance with a good deal of
what goes on in society at some variance
of society
because it exhilarates karma. Things may
happen in a in a rather tumultuous way.
You can go through very major changes in
a very short period of time. And um
everyone I think benefits by having a
spiritual mentor. I think everyone
priests in and ministers included,
everyone who's serious about any
dedicated life work, no matter what it
is, being the best veterinarian in the
world or whatever it is, you really need
sort of a mentor, somebody that you can
not necessarily a mitter, but a a
confidant, somebody with whom you can
exchange what's going on with yourself.
and uh a group of knowledgeable people
to that you can access.
Spiritual commitment can bring about
rather profound changes. For one thing,
it brings up the life energy. The life
energy starts shooting up through the
energy systems including the base
chakra. So there's a period of time when
you may go through very intense sexual
sexuality. Sex sex just seems to be very
powerfully driven and that very often is
in is concordant with being attractive
to other people. See the higher your
energy you get the more attractive you
get and people actually throw themsel at
your feet and there's a lot of books out
there the exposees of various gurus by
various people uh the guru fell for it.
So
don't forget you're more attractive to
people. Now, what they're attracted to
is your energy, but they personalize and
think that it's you that they're they've
suddenly fallen in love with and find
irresistible. It's not you. It's the
energy.
They don't be flattered by it.
People will beg you to go to bed with
you and throw themselves at your feet.
Okay?
Then there's the upset at the sexuality
itself because you see the life energies
that comes up goes through all the
chakras. Now you know eventually gets to
the heart but there's a period of time
when you may be more sexual than ever
before in your life and you think here I
am an old lady 67 years old and I'm
thinking about going to bed with five
guys tonight. You know what I'm saying?
There was a lady, she was on TV just
recently and she wrote a book, didn't
she?
>> Yeah. She looked up a thing in the paper
and wrote these guys and uh she had five
boyfriends and we went to bed with all
five of them in the first year. Ended up
with two of them nice guys and a couple
of them as friends. Anyway, it was fun.
She was very alive. So, you know, as I
looked at her, I wasn't seeing
sexuality. I was seeing aliveness. So
what you're getting is that the
aliveness electrifies everything about
you and your creativity becomes
electrified and many evolved people and
I've treated some of the most famous in
the world were brilliant artists world
famous artists and they were also very
creative in many fields.
Um
so that energy comes up then and you're
just more alive. You're more alive and
electric in every way.
as it proceeds there is um
as it gets to the heart etc. As it gets
to the heart then
you may experience what's classically
called the condundolini energy running
up your spine and that is exquisite.
This delicious, exquisite sensation is
running up your back may last several
years. And it seemed, at least in this
case, it would run into the brain. And
wherever it was in the brain was sort of
like a low-level orgasm, continuous. It
was extremely pleasurable
and
like the epitome of love. And it's a
it's an actual energy.
At times this energy will do things. Uh
I think I've related how it's you know
driving along the highway this energy
would just pour out through the heart
and down the highway on I 17 I17 twice
in heaven and the energy would pour down
the highway and around the bend and uh
when you got around the bend there was
an automobile accident. The wheels were
still turning on the car. this energy is
pouring into the people in the accident
in that particular incident. I said,
"Well, God, do you want me to stop
here?" And I got, "No, you're not needed
to stop here." So, another half a mile
down, the energy stopped.
Then about 10 minutes later going down I
17, the energy started all over again.
It went out and like went around the
corner
quarter half a mile down past the curve.
And as I got around the curve, by God,
there was a second automobile accident.
And this energy again went into the
people. One time in Chicago, there was
about a gang, two gangs were about to
attack each other. And this energy just
poured down the sidewalk and into the
members of the gang. And as it poured
into them, they let go their aggressive
knife. I'm going to stab you pose. And
they all fell back and started to laugh.
Oh well.
So this energy also had the capacity to
perform the miraculous. So sick people
would sit down next to me in the a or in
the aura in the aura
and uh crippled lady would sit down next
to me and then she'd get up and walk
away and you just witness this
phenomena. And the energy would fix
electronic equipment. I can remember a
guy coming over to my house. 100 amp
amplifier was not working. And I looked
at it and I thought, "Oh, that could be
working just fine." Instantly the
amplifier went on. This guy saw that and
he said, "How did you do that?"
I think I told that story before. And I
told him, I said, "Well, I was doing the
course of miracles." He says, "I want
that." I had one copy left. So, I gave
him the course of miracles and he left.
Apparently, his purpose was to come
witness the phenomena, get a copy of the
course of miracles, and go on his way,
which he did.
So then along with this energy there is
uh uh so-called cities si dd h i s a
cult sometimes included in the mystic.
It's got nothing to do with the
mysticism with mysticism
but anybody who has evolved this energy
um indulge you doesn't you the energy
has the capacity. So for a period of
maybe five years there's a clairvoyant
clare audient he had distant viewing
uh you know I could will myself to go
into a box read what's in the box come
out of the box say what's written there
um
uh psych uh they call it psychometry
where you pick up a thing and you know
you pick up a thing and I instantly know
who had this what it history is who
owned it. I can hear the conversation of
the people. Let's say you buy a piece of
used furniture, you put your hand on it,
you hear the husband and wife having the
argument, you hear them making love, all
kinds of it's like, you know, everything
any energy that's ever come into that,
you can read it. You read it back out.
So that's called psychometry.
Uh I forget the various phenomena. All
right. Happily, I had known of the
warning uh to not become glamorized by
these powers. Uh they're not yours. They
belong to the field, which was easy to
to see because it was the field doing
all these things. So if I went to
Lincoln Center to the opera, I would
just picture a picking a, you know,
parking space right next to Lincoln
Center. And I get to Lincoln Center, the
number one spot. the number one spot
with a guy would pull out the car to see
you ro I mean this was continuous
continuous the continuous miraculous and
of course that's what the course of
miracles predicts and at level 600 this
is a phenomena it occurs of its own
so the thing is not to uh identify with
it it's a phenomena of its own don't be
glamorized by it if you do you fall the
way of some eastern gurus who have
glamorized it and come back lifetime
after lifetime perfected certain aspects
of the occult. Okay. So the occult
itself is a seduction not to fall for
the seduction of of it. One uh is
grateful for it. You watch the crippled
person get up and walk away but it is
not of
no personal doingness is involved. No
person is involved in this. This energy
field is doing all this by itself.
Beyond that, as the energy goes even
higher, there's various aches and pains.
Various aches and pains.
I remember looking up mysticism in the
encyclopedia of Britannica and it would
say you probably spent six months out of
the year in bed.
Not too good.
that the aches and pains and the myas
asthmas and the various things and those
of course are due to resistances
resistances to the energy.
uh
so various aches and pains and then as
the energy gets even higher up that it's
let's say the 700s are very con very
comfortable the 700s are beatotific
maharaj
uh the 700s are very beatotific and um
and then beyond that starts peculiar
agonies again in which like in the 800s
or something around in there
uh the karma of the collective you you
start getting hit by the negative the
energies of the collective karma of uh
collective consciousness of mankind
let's see if that's a fact I just got it
right now 800 and over that okay all
right so it's not things in your
personal karma but it's things in the
collective karma like this morning what
came up right during the lecture we had
to go out check out what it was I
intuited what it was which chakra in
which archetype
in many lifetimes as a devoted Catholic
what I was saying had insulted that
archetype within me. So I had to clear
that through intense prayer and
surrender
etc. So you're actually doing it in to
some degree for everyone.
The aches and pains and the the strange
energy sensations. Unless you have
somebody consult about it, you won't
know what it is
and think you're losing it. So as I
said, I went through all kinds of agony,
some years of it, in fact, and it's
extreme agonies. And then we were in
Korea and Susan pulled out of the
sideboard. It said uh the Buddha said he
felt like his bones were racked with
pain. And I said, "Wow." He felt like
his bones were broken and racked with
pain. Oh, okay. So then it was okay. You
see, once you have it from spiritual
authority, once you have it from
spiritual truth, then the phenomena that
occur to you are okay. If they're not,
they could be frightening or you feel
that you must be doing something wrong.
Why? Because in the 600s, you were like
in bliss all the time. In the 700s,
you're in like serenity all the time.
And now you're pulling up,
now you're pulling up things from the
collective and getting hit by it that
you have to clear. And you think that
somehow you've fallen away from where
you were before. No, it's that you've
gone beyond it.
So, I just thought I'd tell you about
some of those things to to watch for
them. as the cities arise. Don't get
yourself a booth in the nearest new age
fair and setup shop because everybody is
psychic at that certain level. You know,
you're clairvoyant. I know what people
are thinking before they even speak. And
it's, you know, it doesn't mean that
you're uh the the wonder of the western
world.
So I what's the right attitude about
such things? Uh respect. respect the
phenomena. It's been well written about
uh and then there's some very funny and
heartwarm warming stories and u astral
projection near-death experiences all
these things are common
uh
to know to have somebody you can speak
to then gives you some kind of a
feedback and especially if you know
they're anchored in some kind of a basic
spiritual teaching which we try to stay
with the strict and neuro spiritual
truth
that somebody in the group can call
somebody in the group and say what do
you think about such and such and you
get feedback you know what I mean so
that you have access so the collective
experience of everybody here now is a
spiritual library
we are the spiritual library of the
knowingness of that comes only through
subjective experience
not through external authority I never
quote external authority for anything I
say or do you can quote somebody
somewhere in time in history
as a point of reference but that is not
the basis from which you're speaking
the speakingness comes from the
authenticity of the presence of self
within
we'll do some questions and all we'll
when we after the break today we'll do
uh questions we'll share all the
questions and answers with the audience
we'll sign books or do whatever people
would like us to do anybody got any
question right now I'll take it right
now about the phenomena that you might
experience erience on the spiritual
pathway, the physicality, the aches and
pains, the increased sexuality.
Trying to think what else could come up.
The increased energies. Now, the
increased energies
as the presence becomes more dominant,
you become the field instead of the
content of the field.
There's a critical point at which you
become the field altogether. And the
personal self disappears.
Which mystifies the world. Yes.
And it's difficult to find one's balance
back into the world. As I say, it took
many years. And to even be back in the
world, it's like the ox hurting
pictures, you know, the ox hurting
picture, the nearest one to the end,
you're taken out of the world. And uh
then that's extremely rare. even rare
still is to come out of the world and be
able to reenter. So the difficulty with
getting into intense spiritual energies
is balancing yourself as we'll see later
between left brain and right brain
between the presence which is silent
and is constantly pulling you to come
back in itself and the energy that it
requires to recommmit to rebalance to
function again within the world. Why
would one do that in the first place?
First of all, you don't have to. From
600 and up, you're you're welcome to
leave at any time. There's a standing
invitation
right this instant. You could leave. I
could leave right this instant. It would
be great.
You have permission to leave. The
permission then means the stayness is
only occurring as a result of one's own
spiritual will.
for some uh for some greater good than
one's own personal survival because
personal survival at that point is not
interesting. Whether the physicality
persists or not is irrelevant
because the physicality is frankly
clumsy and always in the way.
everything you want to do. If I want to
move from here to there, you can see I
have to stop and move the whole body
which is a really whereas in the true
state the thought of being there is the
same as being there. You understand? So
the body is a clumsiness which is
forever in the way and uh having adopted
it as a pet is the best technique to use
at that point and give it a name like
snuffy or something something cuddly and
warm and nice and uh that you can love
it. See besides other people see that as
you and if you don't have one of these
they would be greatly mystified.
There's a voice speaking to me out of
the bush. Okay. All right.
See, your spiritual intention is already
changing the world. Changing the world.
You'll say, "What can I do to change the
world?" Best thing to do to change the
world is leave it alone. Do it a favor.
do it a favor and don't improve it
because uh everything that goes this way
then comes back this way. You see, so
what can you do? You can incre increase
the density of the seawater so that all
the ships float higher in the ocean.
Therefore, your commitment to
spirituality reinforces the energy the
the field the energy field of the
collective and everyone benefits.
Everyone benefits every forgiveness that
you do, every kind thought, every kind
act because the universe counts every
hair on your head, every hair on one's
head is literally counted. Otherwise, we
wouldn't have the kinesiologic method.
Every kindness then, every kindness. So,
a person says, "Well, I don't think I'm
doing enough for the world." Well, first
of all, you're staying out of it. That's
doing a lot to begin with.
My contribution to the world is to
remain detached.
Thank you, oh Lord. All right, so let's
get on to more exciting things. We have
exciting things to talk about today. Uh
I knew you were just really dying to
know about the brain today. So
it's funny you know when I do a when I
do a transparency
almost almost you know nine out of 10
times within a week Time magazine will
have a big spread on the very
transparency that I was doing that's
funny you know I did one the
distribution of the energy fuels in the
planet you know North Africa and all
that that very week time magazine had
one and North Africa was marked as the
trouble spot of the world 40 plus
northern uh latitude
40 to 80 or something like that. So, and
this happened again. Uh we were doing
the brain. I don't know whether time is
a copycat or what. Anyway, no, we're all
course we're all because there's an
energy field bringing it into awareness.
So, this week it just happened to have
one on the brain. And uh I just want you
to know that what the next slide is not
made up. It's actually based on fact.
This had to do with uh the use of drugs
psychiatrically with children and you
know it was one of those iffy uh
semi-accurate kind of things. Anyway,
here we have the lyic system which is
the uh where the impulses coming in get
distributed to the whole nervous system.
I just want you to know that I didn't
make up these words.
Here we have something called the
amygdala. Where is the amygdala?
Which is the emotional center? Here we
have something called the thealamus
which is a relay center.
And here we have the prefrontal cortex.
And I just want you to know that I
didn't make these words up.
Now we're ready to go to the next slide.
It's funny how time came has come out
over and over again with practically a
variation of the very chart I'm working
on. Yeah.
Now,
this is what you call keeping it simple,
huh?
This is keeping it simple.
It's what we talked about this morning.
We found that calibration level less
than 200 has Oh, I need my pointer.
calibration level 200
below 200 has a different physiology
than above 200.
We found that below 200 you don't even
have an atheric brain yet.
200 and over energizes the production
and creation of an atheric brain. As we
said this morning below 200 in the
animal brain the sensory input
is very fast
to the relay station and then goes very
fast. So this is emotions fear and
hatred the cell's stress response
cannons fight or flight the emotional
center in the brain.
So the left brain below 200 animal
cortex animal brain then the input goes
unmodified fast as all get out to the
emotional center straight to the
amygdala.
At the same time the same stimuli goes
from the phalamus to the cortex
and then down to the amydala.
But this is fast and by the time the one
goes through your cerebral cortex and
you have a chance to think about it,
it's already happened in the emotions.
Therefore, it's necessary to forgive
85% of the people on the planet because
they react emotionally and then their
common sense comes around later.
That's how politicians get to be
politicians.
thinkingness happens much later.
By the time they've twisted it and
convinced you that their view of it is
true, you you're you're a goner.
So, they're counting on the fact that
they can beat your feelings about things
before your brain has a chance to
realize that it's BS.
That's spiritual talk. BS.
The other thing about devotional
non-duality
is that the devotion is to the truth and
not to piety.
Therefore,
a true teacher is sometimes outrageous,
more like more in the style of Zen than
in the style of a pious saint. People
think, well, advanced consciousness, you
can see somebody in rose with hands
folded and little cap praying as he goes
with his rosary beads. You know what I
mean?
Unlikely.
That's somebody play acting at piety.
See, because that which is pis pious
loves and respects life and is committed
to the truth and is very often abrupt
and uses ridicule and ridiculousness
and can be very funny. Sometimes
what comes to the mind, what comes out
of the mind is sometimes very funny. It
just cracks me up driving along and all
of a sudden I'll say that's hilarious.
Okay. So, here
you got a fast track.
You see the deer.
The mind says, "Get me the gun."
Then it thinks, "But I'm spiritual. I
should be loving the deer, but you've
already Or you curse somebody. You curse
somebody. You hate them. Now your slow
cortex gets around reminding you that
you're spiritual.
What does that do? That creates guilt.
Guilt.
So you have it really pushing people
into spiritual work then means you're
going to subject them to a lot of guilt
because they're never going to be able
to live up to the expectation. Why?
Because the expectation doesn't have a
chance until this has come up already.
Now this whole phenomena is then stored
in your hippocampus. I love that word,
hippocampus. Right south of uh Columbus,
isn't it?
That's the campus where the hippos all
go. The hippo campus.
And the hippo campus then
uh what is the hippocampus storing? It's
storing this phenomena here. So the
memory of it now reawakens the emotion.
I should have a arrow going from here to
here.
The memory now of it reawakens
that you hate that guy. You hate him.
You hate him because your memory of him
is this. That's what gets programmed
into your hippocampus is that you hate
him.
Hatred goes on generation after
generation,
century after century about the same
issue.
Stuck in people's hippocampus. stuck in
your hypoc campus. That's why the direct
pathway
of self-realization
bypasses all of that because you're not
referencing
that which happened centuries ago.
You're not stuck in history, ethnicism,
the geography and the politics of the
times which gets incorporated in
ecclesiastic
literature as scripture. There's nothing
scriptural about it.
Who walked down the sidewalk and did
what
2,000 years ago some other part of the
planet is irrelevant.
Relevant to what? Irrelevant to your
enlightenment.
It would just be excess baggage because
all that elicits emotion. Elicits
emotion.
And the hatred of one religion for
another which is ripping the world part
apart right now is based on this here
coming out of this here. Out of the
historic
out of the history of the various
religions out of the hippocampus
comes the hatred of one religion for
another.
Leftrain animal. They are the enemy.
Kill them.
Kill them for God.
I mean even anybody who's even up to 200
kill him for God they say huh kill him
for God. Yeah right.
All right. What what happens then above
200? Above 200 we see
now first of all for the first time an
athetheric brain
not just a physical brain the input is
very instant instantly to the etheric
brain. Why? Because the aetheric brain
is connected to the field.
The physical brain is connected to the
input, the senses. The atheric brain is
already connecting with the field. And
as you get more spiritually evolved, you
become the field rather than the content
of the field. So the athetheric brain is
now beginning to reflect the field.
Therefore, the input is fast to the
athetheric brain and to the amygdala and
the hippocampus stores it as a beautiful
deer that you loved instead of getting a
gun and killing it. Huh?
The downside of this is we warned before
is you love the tiger, the tiger loves
you.
And in the 500 you forget that it but
it's still a tiger.
And a tiger who's integrous will be
integrous to his tiger nature. And his
tiger nature is to eat you because he
loves you.
A tiger will eat you not because he
hates you, but because when you get his
nervous system over excited, he will eat
you because he loves you. Let's see.
The lion ate the lady with the lion out
of love. Is this uh we have permission
to ask God what I'm thinking about.
What's his name? Manor loved him so much
he ate him. What's the name of the
tiger? The white tiger. Monor.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Machor ate them. It's hard to eat
them out of love.
Excess love overactivates their nervous
system and they can't handle it. What
What do you say about children? They're
so adorable. I could just eat them up.
In the end, the animal gets overwhelmed
by this energy and doesn't know what to
do and it just has to eat up that which
it loves. See, ego would see it as
hatred. No, Monor didn't hate him at
all. Monor loved him.
Oh god,
I love you so much I could eat you up,
sweetheart.
All right. So the advantage then we have
to realize then the advantage of
spiritual commitment. It activates the
right brain. It causes a change in
physiology.
It allows for immediate knowingness.
That's what's speaking to you today.
Have permission to ask that? That's
what's speaking to them today
from the field. Got it? So that which is
called the atman is the divinity of the
field.
that which is called in Sanskrit the um
well we won't talk about it in Sanskrit
I'm not too left brain today anyway the
field is generally then the atheric
brain is very sensitive to the field
because it is really a variation of the
field
so the atheric brain is capable
of nonverbal
nonlinear knowingness.
The speakingness happening of its own
right this moment is coming from the
field through atheric brain.
That's a fact. Okay. I never did know it
work but
subjectively experientially it didn't
matter.
All right. So you develop an atheric
brain. The atheric brain is a
modification of the total energy field
of divinity which becomes modified more
progressively towards form but it is
quite a bit beyond form. So the field
knows
and we see from kinesiologic uh
kinesiologic testing that consciousness
knows everything. The omniscience of
God. Omniscience is the all knowingness
expressed as the infinite field of
consciousness beyond all time, beyond
all content, beyond all form.
Which only knows if a thing is and if a
thing is true. That's all it knows.
Because knowingness has non-existence.
There's no way consciousness can know
non-existence. Consciousness is unable
to recognize falsity because falsity has
no reality to consciousness.
Yeah. Therefore, the kinesiologic
response is only yes or a not yes.
Understanding comes through not through
election. Then as you get more rightrain
and more spiritual understanding comes
about as a self-realization. and it
reveals itself.
The idea that aic brain is connected to
the field and that's how the knowingness
speaks through is speaking right now.
The thought I mean the thought didn't
arise until I spoke it. I never thought
of it before.
It gives a sort of a physiologic
explanation. What is the name for the
teacher within the perushia? Oh yes, the
perushia.
So
the atheric brain's capacity to pick up
the knowingness of divinity omnipotence
is called classically the perushia of
the spiritual teacher. There is no
personal self speaking to you. There is
no personal self speaking to you at all.
That's rejection.
No such thing exists. the field
through the capacity of the etheric
brain can tell the cerebral cortex how
to speak it and verbalize it.
You get it the same time I get it.
I didn't hear it till I just heard it
when you got it. You know what I mean?
Which makes life an exciting adventure
because you live on the edge of the
unknown all the time.
And nobody knows what's going to come up
next.
What's the consequence for us all as
humans below 200? Then you have left
brain dominance in right brain in right
left-handed people of course is the
other the other side. But in common
parlance so-called leftbrain dominance
which is linear
which is linear.
It's like the difference between this is
like the digital computer and this is an
analog computer. The digital computer
left brain it's linear. It is
associated with the emotional base and
it release it releases hier's
stress reaction.
Selier described the three phases three
it was a physiologist
the first reaction and the emotion is
one of alarm
adrenaline shoots out we're set for
fight or flight which was described by
Walder Canyon Cannon another
physiologist
the fight or flight
the alarm reaction then once it's over
you can't stay terrified with the hair
standing up in the back of your head
forever. You go into a chronic a chronic
state of resistance.
This is where all the illnesses and the
aches and pains begin because part of
spiritual work in fact a considerable
part is overcoming resistance.
Overcoming resistance.
Overcoming resistance. The alarm
reaction is one of panic, one of hatred,
one of anger.
Then this then the stage of resistance
that's a rock right now Iraq right now
you see the resistance of the people the
resistance of the Americans the
resistance of the populace to change etc
resistance eventually leads to
exhaustion of
the glands above the the super adrenal
the adrenals leads to adrenal exhaustion
adrenal exhaustion
and eventually to apathy and death.
Well, adrenal exhaustion uncorrected.
Another aspect that it does is that it
it causes it stresses the thymus.
You remember with Dr. Diamond's thyic
thump, we went
to stimulate the thymus because stress
then causes suppression of the thymus
which is the center of balance of the
acupuncture system.
out of thymic balance. Then the
acupuncture system regulates the flow of
energy to the body's organs.
It the healthy thymus uh stimulates the
production of killer cells.
Killer cells are good because they are
killers of bad things like bacteria.
So here these are good killer cells and
therefore
stress then means you blow your
acupuncture meridian. disease
and you lose your immunity and the
inability to withstand various diseases,
cancer and all the rest
because of blowing the acupuncture
meridian disease process. Also, you get
a negative kinesiologic response. The
effect on the brain directly is the
neurotransmitters like serotonin and
norepinephrine
uh are stressed out. So Prozac its main
function is to increase serotonin in the
brain. So the stress centers in the
brain finally reach what cell called
exhaustion
and you lose the nor epinephrine and
serotonin neurotransmitters in the
brain. Prozac and drugs that restore it
are life-saving. I I in the old days
people just you know turn to drugs or
drink or suicide. Now they take a
Prozac. So it's better to be ridiculed
for taking Prozac and live to breathe
than to die of suicide or apathy. Huh?
So-called accidents where you don't care
enough to get out of the way of the
oncoming car. You say the hell with it.
So it's listed as an accident but it's
actually a suicide.
And we already mentioned the track to
the emotions is twice as fast as through
it's twice as fast
with spiritual evolution. Then we see
the beginning of right brain dominance.
You see the mind becomes more and more
the field. It tends to think more in
generalities
more as it all works out in the end. Why
worry about it? Why can't why fuss about
everything? It's going to be it's going
to work out. It all works out for the
best. Why? Because the infinite context
of the field is divinity.
So the right brain tends to be
nonlinear. It tends to get the gist of
things. You know what is the essence
that you're trying to say? Somebody will
give you a long-winded story about the
fifth paragraph. You say, you know,
what's the point?
They want to track you through their
left brain. You see, as you get right
brain, you're not interested in in
people's left brain anymore. And you
find yourself giving up reading books.
It's very rare that you read a book.
Why? Because the purpose is to get the
gist of it. And when you get the gist of
it by what? By one way or the other,
then you you move from there. By virtue
of the field there's a certain
familiarity and knowingness and the
ability to tell truth from falsehood.
The physiologic effect then is the
peacefulness then release releases
endorphins.
Endorphins are
what give you a positive feeling. It's
the reason drugs that get you high are
so popular because it artificially
recreates, mimics or releases endorphins
artificially.
The difficulty with it is after the drug
wears off then you crash down to less
than you were before which increases the
necessity to repeat repeat the drug. So
the addiction is not really to the drug.
The addiction is to the effect of the
drug which is to re induce euphoria by
the release of endorphins. So, you're
not addicted to the drug. Frankly,
you'll take anything that'll get you
high. A sophisticated addict knows. I
don't care what it is. If it gets you
high, I'll have some.
What's in the bottle? Who cares? Does it
get you there? Okay. Get you where? Get
you to positive emotions and mimics
mimics the effect of the endorphins.
True spiritual commitment then supports
the thymus gland, increases the body's
production of killer cells,
wherefore greater immunity, uh greater
resistance to cancer, uh faster healing,
spontaneous healings.
It balances the acupuncture system and
gives you a positive kinesiologic
response.
And we see the real critical factor
physiologically
is that the attract to the emotions is
much
faster through the atheric cortex faster
than the other side.
In summary then we can say spiritual
endeavor and commitment
changes literally changes the brain its
function its physiology.
It creates an atheric brain. The atheric
is much closer to the infinite
spiritual.
The aetheric brain and and it creates in
the preffrontal cortex prefrontal cortex
of the right brain an area specific for
spiritual knowledge and learning. Yeah,
let's verify that. That's a fact.
Resist. It's a literal fact.
physiologically
it creates now a place in the prefrontal
cortex for the storing and working
working together of spiritual awareness
and knowledge. So everything that you
read that's spiritually
correct,
everything that makes you go strong with
kinesiology
now contributes to the knowingness of
this atheric brain.
The right preffrontal cortex of the
atheric brain is as close as we need to
specify.
That's as close as we need to specify.
Is this? That's good enough.
Good enough. I don't want to get so left
brain I got to explain it all over
again.
This is as left brain as I could get
this week, folks.
And that left me with a headache. What
is it?
Should I have them coming down this way
and put these on the side or should I
have them coming this way? You know, big
decision like that.
Oh, yeah.
Let's Let's put it out. Let's put it
out. Yeah.
All right. So,
uh, we'll put the brain back up there
just so we know what we're talking about
because I tend to forget we're talking
about Oh, yes. We're talking about the
brain and physiologic differences.
Now is that phenomenal or what? Actual
physical physiologic and functional
change that spiritual commitment brings
about measurable identifiable.
The fastest way to know it is to test
kinesiology. You see it instantly makes
you go strong.
the change in the whole body's
physiology, its whole energy system
and the way in which it perceives and
processes data.
Therefore, you might say spiritual
commitment brings forth that was which
if it happens suddenly would be called
miraculous.
In the course of miracles, one asks the
Holy Spirit, you see, for a miracle.
What you're really asking is for for is
a recontextualization
to replace perception with vision
to replace left brain linearity with
right brain understanding which is more
holistic
holistic.
That seems like a rather amazing
discovery
when we realize that people below 200
can't help being the way they are. They
cannot help being the way they are
because that's the way their brain
actually processes information.
That helps us with forgiveness. It helps
us
with self forgiveness because you can
catch, you will catch a track, a sensory
track, especially if it's karmically
loaded, triggering a negative feeling, a
negative perception.
And then the next thing that comes up
with you is guilt. Now, why did I do
that? You hit your thumb with a hammer
and you and you and you swear. And then
you say, oh, why did I say that? You
know, you you've sworn off swearing and
there you are swearing after having
sworn off swearing.
The old paradigm would be guilt and
penance.
Guilt and penance.
On your new knees from here to New York
City,
which I think anchors it. Why does it
anchor it? Because it doesn't change
your brain physiology.
You're going to do the same thing the
next time you hit your thumb. Because it
hasn't changed your brain physiology.
We see, let's do the number one uh
thing, the levels of consciousness. You
can see that guilt
that guilt and remorse and penance and
all that
this doesn't have the capacity
to change your brain physiology
in a spiritual direction.
Wallowing in guilt and penance and self
flagagillation and self-hatred
anchors you at the bottom.
So now you're still at the mercy of your
left unmodified left brain.
No, the way to God is through joy. Yeah.
Devotional non-duality means a
commitment to the truth above all else.
You're more committed to truth than you
are to being a martyr. You're more
committed to truth than being right.
The way to God is through the joy of
one's existence. Joy and the awareness
of the source of one's own existence.
The way to God is through love, through
joy, through forgiveness,
through being benign, merciful,
considerate, polite.
Coin the waitress sweetie pie.
I have the usual sweetie pie. said,
"Thank you, honeybug." They don't even
know each other's name, but you know,
he's truck has stopped there for years.
So,
that lovingness towards life in all of
its expressions, the capacity to see the
truth within, what sounds like a casual
exchange is not really all that casual
because if he gets to the same truck
stop and she's off that week, he goes,
"Oh." He's disappointed. Why is he
disappointed? He doesn't even really
know her real name.
Why is he disappointed?
He doesn't see the familiar. Because the
familiar has come to represent love and
so he feels a little floren. And next
week when he stops by the same truck
stop, she's there again. Hi sweetheart.
Hi.
And everything is fine again. You see
the lovingness that prevails. So as we
become more loving ourself, we become
aware of the lovingness that is already
there in society which we didn't see
before. See we didn't see before.
You see how a person who's into leftrain
self-righteous political correctness and
all would see that as a belittlement
uh that you ought to feel offended
etc. You know he's being demeaning
towards her by calling her pussycat.
And I'm sure she's politically correct,
incorrect in calling them sugar puss.
Okay. Whatever they call each other for
20 years. Anyway, if you hang out in
truck stops, you'll get the sense of it.
That's why I used to like to drive at
night, you know, when I drove back east.
I drove west. I mean, you know, I left
everything in the east. and threw all my
tools in the back of the old truck and
headed west. And it was great fun living
the truck truck roots at night because
this is a total phenomena that you see
the camaraderie between the truck
drivers. If one's in trouble, they stop
their whole rig and a great financial
cost in itself help somebody out. Some
kind of a camaraderie and allegiance to
each other as humans.
uh which was characteristic of the
country you know in World War II it was
characteristic the whole world was the
whole country was that way every
hitchhiker got picked up everybody who
needed something somehow so there was a
a central commitment which kept the
fabric of society together you see and
that which is destructive to that fabric
to me is destructive to the quality of
human life. It's not going to destroy
human life, but it destroys the quality
of trust and mutuality
and the expression of love and concern
for your fellow human beings.
As we move then very committedly onto
the spiritual pathway, then we recommmit
to the very basics to be that which the
field is at all times to all forms of
life to
appreciate the exquisite beauty of every
leaf at this time of year to watch how
it sails down. It's incredibly
beautiful, you know, to see the beauty
of the snowfall, the beauty of the
animals, the beauty of our of human
life.
And what you see is the surge of the
energy of human life. So you say, well,
the factory is not where you see it.
Yes, the fact is is is exactly where you
see it.
You see the people who are holding back
below 200 and then you see the people
that are above 200. For the people above
200 that the workday is short. I say my
god is that the quitting whistle
already. And to the person who is
resisting it and not giving forth their
all. The day seems very very long.
They'll say my god isn't it even
lunchtime yet? They looked at their
watch 40 times.
The way to get beyond of a pain thing is
let go resisting it and 100%
participation.
If you're going to haul rocks, then by
God, haul rocks. And you haul rocks as
fast as you can haul rocks until you
fall over and the day is so quick. And
that's how you bring forth the
experience of joy at your own existence.
The source of joy is the awareness of
the quality and the nature
of divinity within you expressing itself
as life and one's own creation.
In reverencing it in others, you
reverence it in yourself. In re
reverencing both in yourself and others,
you reverence it for all of mankind.
When consciousness level went from 190
to 207,
it's much harder nowadays to be cruel to
people. It's harder. You don't In the
old days, cruelty was you all deserved
it. Now, you know, anything that is
non-intigorous is now called into
question
perhaps overboarding it because the
intellect is pretty dumb.
The intellect is trying to understand
codify it and polit and laws and
political positions and things but its
endeavor is in the right direction. It's
trying to correct sources of pain and
injustice and suffering in the world. In
so doing, it's clumsy and stumbles over
and overshoots the mark. But if you see
that behind all that is a kindly even if
bizarre
ventation attempts and a
misinterpretation. See
the willingness to forgive then
modifies our brain function so that
forgiveness becomes automatic. The
reason it's automatic is because we
experience the world differently than
other people do. Because we experience
the world differently, we don't see that
there's anything to forgive. Forgive
what? Everything is just being what it
is. Everything is being what it is.
So, we see the jackal eating the hen.
And instead of getting judgmental about
it, oh, bad jackal eating good hen.
Good jackal eaten.
The jackal folks over here, the hen
people over here.
Society is that way. Jackles and hens.
The field itself is the source of one's
inner instruction. The mystic is is
merely one who has learned to look
through the atheric brain and finesse
out of the field the answers to that
which it's it seeks
to merely hold a question. It's like
it's like a mudra. One holds the
question like this to divinity unspoken
and silently. Divinity knows what the
question is you're holding
and then it tries to find the answer.
Thank you. Answer.
The purpose of that is to bring it into
the
bring it into the linear world for
purposes of communication.
Once you're aware of a thing, it's
already complete and done. Unless you're
writing about it, lecturing about it, in
which case you want to demonstrate it.
Yeah. So that it is v ver verifiable by
others because people coming from this
field find the field that we are now
more familiar with as to be unreal,
unreal, not worthy of commitment.
When you look at whole countries uh that
deny the reality or existence of God, in
fact it's illegal to mention God. Whole
countries where being loving loving will
actually get you executed
actually get you executed.
Southeast Asia, the whole country is
there. To be loving in any way is
forbidden
and it'll get you executed for being
loving.
Loving then is of course the biggest
danger to the ego. So
that which is loving tends to bring up
that which is unloving. So you'll also
find people who despise you because
you're kind and loving. Huh?
So we brought up the various things can
happen along the pathway. sudden
breakoff of relationships because you
bring up its opposite and they're
unconscious
and therefore the relationship is no
longer compatible.
That's well known in Alcoholics
Anonymous that once the person gets
sober and he's no longer the bad guy
dependent on her. He becomes autonomous
and spiritually committed that's in the
relationship because being the enabler
was was her whole trip.
So becoming spiritually committed is not
necessarily going to delight everybody
around you.
So we can accept that that is part of
the price
for thee. Oh Lord, what I lay down all
because in the end when is faced the
last remaining thing
is the feeling of a personal self.
That which you identify with the essence
and source of life itself.
And in the end that is the only thing
still standing.
And then the knowingness arises. Lay
down even your life.
Lay down your life and surrender it to
God. And then out of the devotion, by
that time the devotion is still
powerful. That plus the knowingness
you've picked up from the teaching of
somebody who's been there.
You literally lay down your life for
God.
And then you die
one and only time.
You do die and you do experience death
and it's a moment of agony
and then all splendor shines through
shines forth forever more.
The death of the ego is the only death
you can experience.
Nobody can experience their own death.
Not possible.
The time of death is already preset at
the time you're born. The time you're
born is already a calibratable level of
consciousness. The exact moment of death
is already set at the time you're born.
Want to reconfirm
that is true.
Reconfirmed every lecture. The exact
moment is already predetermined. The
karmic said so. The how of it is not
set.
The how of it is not set. The exact
timing cannot be. You cannot leave an
instant before, nor can you remain an
instant beyond.
So that removes fear of death.
Anytime you think you're dying, that's
not it.
Oh god. Yeah. If you feel a bullet
ripping through you, you're not dying.
It's just agony.
No, there's only one death and you'll
know it. You recognize it's like a high
pass. It's like a high pass and there's
no one there except yourself.
And this sense of self
you see arises from the idea that the
self is the personal self is the source
of your existence.
People don't realize that it you survive
because of the field. The ego has you
convinced it's because it watches tra
traffic carefully and renews your life
insurance things.
Having let all dualities go,
having surrendered everything to God,
the willingness to let go having an
opinion, could you let go having
opinions to God?
Yeah.
Could you let go being right to God?
Yep. Would you be willing to do that?
Yes.
The love of God then brings you to a
point where you're willing to surrender
everything.
Then with fear you look at life itself.
The last remaining
pin in the bowling alley is standing
there
and you know that even that has to be
surrendered.
The knowingness to do it comes out of
the field
because the field of your higher self
and this higher self are one and the
same. So that will finesse it out of the
field.
Walk straight ahead. No matter what
is the teaching from Zen
that came up at the time. Walk straight
through. No matter what. Let's see.
That's trustable at 100.
That is trustable at 100.
And having lived through it, I stand
witness that it is trustable at 100.
Because at that moment
the memory of the teaching comes back
and then much to your surprise
the intensity of one's love for God
swells up with such enormous power.
Where did that come from? You didn't
consciously love God to that degree. No,
because you're not alone.
The divinity of it all comes to your
aid.
And now you surrender your life to God.
And sh the marilent the mind is stunned
silent.
The tail end of the ego right before the
radiant shines forth the tail end of the
e ego is still in witnessing.
And as it enters this new domain as the
new domain opens up the tail end of the
witnessing ego goes is struck dumb with
awe.
The the revelation is so profound the
ego is struck dumb. It would not presume
to even have a thought in the presence
of what is obviously divinity because
the divinity of all existence is what
stuns you at first revelation.
Not only its beauty, its oneness,
its exquisite gentleness, its infinite
power.
It stuns the mind into silence
and the mind never thinks again
which leaves you free to just be what
you are. You see what I mean?