So
So this
So this is
So this is the
So this is the start
So this is the start of
So this is the start of a
So this is the start of a new
So this is the start of a new year
So this is the start of a new year of
So this is the start of a new year of a
series
series this
So this is the start of a new year of a
series this long
series this long be
So this is the start of a new year of a
series this long be six
series this long be six lectures.
We'll
We'll cover
We'll cover um
We'll cover um new
We'll cover um new things
We'll cover um new things that
We'll cover um new things that have
We'll cover um new things that have uh
arisen
arisen and
We'll cover um new things that have uh
arisen and as
arisen and as a
We'll cover um new things that have uh
arisen and as a result
arisen and as a result of
We'll cover um new things that have uh
arisen and as a result of our
arisen and as a result of our research.
Anyway,
Anyway, we've
Anyway, we've discovered
Anyway, we've discovered uh
Anyway, we've discovered uh new
Anyway, we've discovered uh new things.
We
We share
Anyway, we've discovered uh new things.
We share them
We share them with
Anyway, we've discovered uh new things.
We share them with you.
Things
Things that
Things that are
Things that are utterly
Things that are utterly mind-boggling
Things that are utterly mind-boggling as
a
a result
Things that are utterly mind-boggling as
a result of
a result of spiritual
Things that are utterly mind-boggling as
a result of spiritual research.
To
To my
To my knowledge,
To my knowledge, we're
To my knowledge, we're the
To my knowledge, we're the only
To my knowledge, we're the only people
on
on the
To my knowledge, we're the only people
on the planet
on the planet doing
To my knowledge, we're the only people
on the planet doing spiritual
on the planet doing spiritual spiritual
research.
People
People do
religious
religious research.
religious research. They
religious research. They go
religious research. They go to
religious research. They go to the
religious research. They go to the holy
lands
lands and
religious research. They go to the holy
lands and dig
for
for artifacts
which
which is
for artifacts
which is historically
which is historically interesting.
The
The reason
The reason we've
The reason we've been
The reason we've been doing
The reason we've been doing spiritual
research
research is
The reason we've been doing spiritual
research is we
research is we have
The reason we've been doing spiritual
research is we have been
research is we have been using
The reason we've been doing spiritual
research is we have been using a
technique
which
which connects
technique
which connects consciousness
which connects consciousness with
technique
which connects consciousness with the
physical
physical domain
physical domain in
physical domain in such
physical domain in such a
physical domain in such a manner
physical domain in such a manner that
we've
we've been
physical domain in such a manner that
we've been able
we've been able to
physical domain in such a manner that
we've been able to discern
we've been able to discern the
difference
difference between
difference between truth
difference between truth and
difference between truth and falsehood.
And
And as
difference between truth and falsehood.
And as much
And as much as
difference between truth and falsehood.
And as much as that
And as much as that has
difference between truth and falsehood.
And as much as that has never
And as much as that has never occurred
on
on the
on the planet
on the planet before,
we're
we're still
on the planet before,
we're still um
we're still um reeling
on the planet before,
we're still um reeling from
we're still um reeling from the
implications.
And
And so
implications.
And so we
And so we share
implications.
And so we share the
And so we share the research
implications.
And so we share the research with
And so we share the research with you,
we
we share
we share the
we share the technique
we share the technique with
we share the technique with you.
Today
Today we'll
we share the technique with you.
Today we'll do
Today we'll do it
we share the technique with you.
Today we'll do it a
Today we'll do it a little
we share the technique with you.
Today we'll do it a little differently
than
than in
than in the
than in the past.
I
I want
than in the past.
I want to
I want to share
than in the past.
I want to share information
I want to share information that
than in the past.
I want to share information that um
I want to share information that um sort
of
of connects
of connects our
of connects our work
of connects our work in
of connects our work in the
of connects our work in the kinesi
kinesiologic
kinesiologic response
of connects our work in the kinesi
kinesiologic response with
kinesiologic response with modern
advanced
advanced theoretical
advanced theoretical physics,
advanced theoretical physics, quantum
mechanics,
quantum
quantum theory
so
so that
quantum theory
so that we
so that we can
completely
completely connect
completely connect the
completely connect the continuum
completely connect the continuum from
the
the rational
completely connect the continuum from
the rational conventional
the rational conventional Newtonian
paradigm
through
through its
paradigm
through its advancement
through its advancement and
paradigm
through its advancement and its
transcendence
transcendence into
transcendence into quantum
transcendence into quantum mechanics.
and
and those
transcendence into quantum mechanics.
and those aspects
and those aspects of
transcendence into quantum mechanics.
and those aspects of quantum
and those aspects of quantum mechanics
which
which explain
which explain the
which explain the kinesiologic
which explain the kinesiologic response.
This
This will
which explain the kinesiologic response.
This will make
This will make lots
which explain the kinesiologic response.
This will make lots of
This will make lots of people
which explain the kinesiologic response.
This will make lots of people in
This will make lots of people in the
world
world happy
because
because they
world happy
because they love
because they love the
world happy
because they love the world
because they love the world of
world happy
because they love the world of logic
because they love the world of logic and
science
and
and so
science
and so we'll
and so we'll make
science
and so we'll make that
and so we'll make that jump
science
and so we'll make that jump that
and so we'll make that jump that quantum
jump
jump with
jump with an
jump with an explanation
jump with an explanation that
jump with an explanation that I
jump with an explanation that I think
will
will be
jump with an explanation that I think
will be helpful.
We
We also
We also want
We also want to
We also want to go
We also want to go over
We also want to go over the
We also want to go over the kinesiologic
test
test itself
We also want to go over the kinesiologic
test itself because
test itself because we've
We also want to go over the kinesiologic
test itself because we've learned
test itself because we've learned a
We also want to go over the kinesiologic
test itself because we've learned a lot.
You
You know,
You know, we
You know, we first
You know, we first published
You know, we first published it
in
in 94
You know, we first published it
in 94 or
in 94 or 95,
You know, we first published it
in 94 or 95, its
in 94 or 95, its use
You know, we first published it
in 94 or 95, its use in
in 94 or 95, its use in um
You know, we first published it
in 94 or 95, its use in um researching
the
the nature
the nature of
the nature of consciousness
the nature of consciousness and
spiritual
spiritual reality.
Since
Since that
Since that time,
Since that time, we've
Since that time, we've learned
Since that time, we've learned a
Since that time, we've learned a great
deal.
deal. So
Since that time, we've learned a great
deal. So this
deal. So this morning,
Since that time, we've learned a great
deal. So this morning, we
deal. So this morning, we are
Since that time, we've learned a great
deal. So this morning, we are going
deal. So this morning, we are going to
share
share that
share that with
share that with you.
share that with you. Nothing
share that with you. Nothing is
share that with you. Nothing is causing
anything.
There
There is
There is no
There is no cause
There is no cause for
There is no cause for anything.
Everything
Everything is
There is no cause for anything.
Everything is unfolding
Everything is unfolding spontaneously
as
as it
as it is
as it is manifested
by
by creation
as it is manifested
by creation which
by creation which is
as it is manifested
by creation which is continuous
by creation which is continuous constant
unfoldingness
as
as witnessed
unfoldingness
as witnessed by
as witnessed by your
unfoldingness
as witnessed by your own
as witnessed by your own existence.
If
If that's
If that's not
If that's not apparent
If that's not apparent to
If that's not apparent to you,
you'll
you'll have
If that's not apparent to you,
you'll have to
you'll have to take
If that's not apparent to you,
you'll have to take my
you'll have to take my word
If that's not apparent to you,
you'll have to take my word for
you'll have to take my word for it.
Which
Which resolves
Which resolves the
Which resolves the whole
Which resolves the whole problem
Which resolves the whole problem of
Evolution
Evolution versus
Which resolves the whole problem of
Evolution versus creation.
The
The theory
The theory of
The theory of evolution.
Who's
Who's the
The theory of evolution.
Who's the author
Who's the author of
The theory of evolution.
Who's the author of that?
Who's the author of that? Darwin.
I'm
I'm not
I'm not too
I'm not too much
I'm not too much in
I'm not too much in to
I'm not too much in to mine
I'm not too much in to mine this
morning,
morning, but
I'm not too much in to mine this
morning, but we'll
morning, but we'll get
I'm not too much in to mine this
morning, but we'll get there.
morning, but we'll get there. Darwin's
theory
theory of
theory of evolution
calibrates.
We
We have
We have permission.
We have permission. over
We have permission. over 400,
We have permission. over 400, 405,
We have permission. over 400, 405, 410,
415,
415, 420,
We have permission. over 400, 405, 410,
415, 420, 425,
415, 420, 425, 4430,
We have permission. over 400, 405, 410,
415, 420, 425, 4430, 450,
415, 420, 425, 4430, 450, 460.
We have permission. over 400, 405, 410,
415, 420, 425, 4430, 450, 460. Tyron's
theory
theory of
theory of evolution
theory of evolution calibrates
theory of evolution calibrates over
theory of evolution calibrates over 460.
That's
sort
sort of
sort of pretty
sort of pretty smart.
sort of pretty smart. 450
sort of pretty smart. 450 is
sort of pretty smart. 450 is pretty
smart.
Uh
Uh it's
Uh it's quite
Uh it's quite smart.
Uh it's quite smart. 450
Uh it's quite smart. 450 is
Uh it's quite smart. 450 is enough
Uh it's quite smart. 450 is enough to
Uh it's quite smart. 450 is enough to be
president
president of
Uh it's quite smart. 450 is enough to be
president of the
president of the United
Uh it's quite smart. 450 is enough to be
president of the United States.
So
So that's
So that's very
So that's very smart.
Um
Um now
So that's very smart.
Um now let's
Um now let's ask
So that's very smart.
Um now let's ask what
Um now let's ask what is
So that's very smart.
Um now let's ask what is the
Um now let's ask what is the calibration
of
of our
of our explanation
of our explanation that
what
what you're
of our explanation that
what you're witnessing
what you're witnessing is
of our explanation that
what you're witnessing is trans
transitory
transitory phenomena
transitory phenomena transitory
perception
perception of
transitory phenomena transitory
perception of phenomena.
The
The evolution
The evolution is
The evolution is one
The evolution is one is
The evolution is one is merely
The evolution is one is merely the
procession
procession of
The evolution is one is merely the
procession of your
procession of your your
The evolution is one is merely the
procession of your your own
procession of your your own perception.
But
But the
But the unfoldingness
But the unfoldingness is
But the unfoldingness is that
But the unfoldingness is that the
But the unfoldingness is that the source
of
of all
But the unfoldingness is that the source
of all that
of all that exists
But the unfoldingness is that the source
of all that exists from
of all that exists from instant
But the unfoldingness is that the source
of all that exists from instant to
instant.
instant. So
instant. So that
instant. So that each
instant. So that each things
instant. So that each things comes
directly
directly out
instant. So that each things comes
directly out of
directly out of creation
instant. So that each things comes
directly out of creation and
directly out of creation and not
instant. So that each things comes
directly out of creation and not from
some
some preceding
some preceding cause.
We
We have
some preceding cause.
We have permission
We have permission to
some preceding cause.
We have permission to calibrate
We have permission to calibrate that.
That's
That's over
That's over 700.
That's over 700. 720
That's over 700. 720 740
That's over 700. 720 740 750
745 746.
Thank
Thank you.
Thank you. That
Thank you. That explanation
Thank you. That explanation is
Thank you. That explanation is a
Thank you. That explanation is a 746.
So
we're
we're talking
we're talking about
we're talking about different
dimensions
dimensions of
we're talking about different
dimensions of reality.
In
In understanding
In understanding spiritual
In understanding spiritual reality,
In understanding spiritual reality, one
has
has to
In understanding spiritual reality, one
has to understand
has to understand very
In understanding spiritual reality, one
has to understand very specifically
has to understand very specifically the
difference
difference between
content
content and
difference between
content and context.
Content
Content is
Content is the
Content is the ego,
Content is the ego, context
Content is the ego, context is
Content is the ego, context is the
spirit.
The
The infinite
The infinite context
The infinite context is
The infinite context is God.
The infinite context is God. out
The infinite context is God. out of
which
which everything
The infinite context is God. out of
which everything manifests
which everything manifests and
The infinite context is God. out of
which everything manifests and arises
and
and the
and the witness
and the witness of
and the witness of his
and the witness of his presence
and the witness of his presence is
and the witness of his presence is your
own
own existence
and the witness of his presence is your
own existence because
own existence because nothing
and the witness of his presence is your
own existence because nothing has
own existence because nothing has within
it
it the
it the power
it the power to
it the power to create
it the power to create its
it the power to create its own
existence.
So
So kinesiology
So kinesiology is
So kinesiology is a
So kinesiology is a very
So kinesiology is a very helpful
So kinesiology is a very helpful tool.
We
We can
So kinesiology is a very helpful tool.
We can calibrate
We can calibrate anything
So kinesiology is a very helpful tool.
We can calibrate anything and
We can calibrate anything and everything
anywhere
anywhere in
anywhere in time.
The
The only
anywhere in time.
The only limitations
The only limitations are
that
that you
that you be
that you be integrous.
That
That leaves
that you be integrous.
That leaves out
That leaves out 78%
that you be integrous.
That leaves out 78% of
That leaves out 78% of the
that you be integrous.
That leaves out 78% of the population.
So
So this
So this morning
So this morning because
So this morning because we
So this morning because we get
So this morning because we get so
So this morning because we get so many
inquiries
inquiries about
So this morning because we get so many
inquiries about kinesiology,
I
I thought
I thought I
I thought I would
I thought I would explain
I thought I would explain perhaps
the
the scientific
I thought I would explain perhaps
the scientific advanced
the scientific advanced theoretical
physics
physics which
physics which confirms
physics which confirms it
physics which confirms it which
physics which confirms it which is
physics which confirms it which is the
corollary
corollary which
uh
uh explains
uh explains it
uh explains it in
terminology
and
and we
and we want
and we want to
and we want to explain
and we want to explain reexlain
and we want to explain reexlain it
and we want to explain reexlain it again
as
as a
and we want to explain reexlain it again
as a technique
so
so that
so that we
so that we can
so that we can end
so that we can end forever.
so that we can end forever. questions
about
about it.
They
They come
They come by
They come by facts,
They come by facts, by
They come by facts, by mail,
They come by facts, by mail, by
They come by facts, by mail, by camel.
So
So Zeus
They come by facts, by mail, by camel.
So Zeus and
So Zeus and I
They come by facts, by mail, by camel.
So Zeus and I are
So Zeus and I are going
They come by facts, by mail, by camel.
So Zeus and I are going to
So Zeus and I are going to do
They come by facts, by mail, by camel.
So Zeus and I are going to do that.
We're
We're going
We're going to
We're going to recapitulate
how
how it
We're going to recapitulate
how it evolved,
how
how the
how the the
how the the fine
how the the fine points
how the the fine points of
how the the fine points of the
technique,
technique, which
how the the fine points of the
technique, which we
technique, which we have
how the the fine points of the
technique, which we have learned.
You
You see,
You see, when
You see, when you
You see, when you do
You see, when you do a
You see, when you do a thing
You see, when you do a thing yourself
thousands
thousands of
You see, when you do a thing yourself
thousands of times,
thousands of times, you
You see, when you do a thing yourself
thousands of times, you sort
thousands of times, you sort of
You see, when you do a thing yourself
thousands of times, you sort of lose
thousands of times, you sort of lose the
capacity
capacity to
capacity to teach
capacity to teach it,
capacity to teach it, you
capacity to teach it, you know,
capacity to teach it, you know, because
you
you do
capacity to teach it, you know, because
you do it
you do it automatically.
capacity to teach it, you know, because
you do it automatically. You
you do it automatically. You don't
realize
realize what
realize what you're
realize what you're doing
realize what you're doing automatically.
And
And so
realize what you're doing automatically.
And so we're
And so we're going
realize what you're doing automatically.
And so we're going to
And so we're going to explain
realize what you're doing automatically.
And so we're going to explain some
And so we're going to explain some of
the
the fine
the fine points.
All
All right.
the fine points.
All right. As
All right. As we
the fine points.
All right. As we said,
All right. As we said, the
the fine points.
All right. As we said, the kinesiologic
response
response when
response when I
response when I first
response when I first witnessed
response when I first witnessed it,
response when I first witnessed it, I
had
had already
response when I first witnessed it, I
had already been
had already been into
response when I first witnessed it, I
had already been into a
had already been into a rather
incredible
incredible state
incredible state some
incredible state some years
incredible state some years before.
incredible state some years before. So
when
when I
incredible state some years before. So
when I witnessed
when I witnessed it,
incredible state some years before. So
when I witnessed it, I
when I witnessed it, I I
incredible state some years before. So
when I witnessed it, I I grasped
when I witnessed it, I I grasped it
incredible state some years before. So
when I witnessed it, I I grasped it on
when I witnessed it, I I grasped it on a
totally
totally different
totally different plane
totally different plane than
totally different plane than it
totally different plane than it was
demonstrated.
demonstrated. It
totally different plane than it was
demonstrated. It was
demonstrated. It was demonstrated
by
by Dr.
by Dr. John
by Dr. John Diamond,
by Dr. John Diamond, who
by Dr. John Diamond, who was
by Dr. John Diamond, who was an
excellent
excellent teacher.
by Dr. John Diamond, who was an
excellent teacher. I
excellent teacher. I still
by Dr. John Diamond, who was an
excellent teacher. I still use
excellent teacher. I still use John
Diamond's
Diamond's technique.
It's
It's just
Diamond's technique.
It's just that
It's just that I
or
or this
or this consciousness
or this consciousness witnessed
or this consciousness witnessed it
or this consciousness witnessed it and
comprehended
comprehended it
or this consciousness witnessed it and
comprehended it on
comprehended it on a
or this consciousness witnessed it and
comprehended it on a different
comprehended it on a different plane
that
that it
that it was
that it was the
that it was the response
that it was the response of
that it was the response of an
that it was the response of an infinite
infinite
infinite field
that it was the response of an infinite
infinite field of
infinite field of consciousness.
that it was the response of an infinite
infinite field of consciousness. Isn't
that
that a
that a local
that a local response?
that a local response? So
that a local response? So the
that a local response? So the world
that a local response? So the world of
science,
science, the
that a local response? So the world of
science, the Newtonian
science, the Newtonian paradigm
that a local response? So the world of
science, the Newtonian paradigm is
science, the Newtonian paradigm is a
local
local causation
local causation kind
local causation kind of
local causation kind of a
local causation kind of a fixation
local causation kind of a fixation and
they
they really
local causation kind of a fixation and
they really get
they really get stuck
local causation kind of a fixation and
they really get stuck there.
they really get stuck there. I
local causation kind of a fixation and
they really get stuck there. I mean
they really get stuck there. I mean they
get
get stuck
get stuck like
get stuck like you
get stuck like you can't
get stuck like you can't unstick
get stuck like you can't unstick them.
Uh
Uh there's
get stuck like you can't unstick them.
Uh there's two
Uh there's two major
get stuck like you can't unstick them.
Uh there's two major uh
Uh there's two major uh conferences
get stuck like you can't unstick them.
Uh there's two major uh conferences on
science
science and
science and consciousness.
science and consciousness. Uh
science and consciousness. Uh Arizona
seems
seems to
science and consciousness. Uh Arizona
seems to be
seems to be the
science and consciousness. Uh Arizona
seems to be the center
seems to be the center of
science and consciousness. Uh Arizona
seems to be the center of it
seems to be the center of it all.
University
University of
University of Arizona
University of Arizona I
University of Arizona I believe
University of Arizona I believe has
University of Arizona I believe has one
in
in April.
Um
Um Albuquerque,
Um Albuquerque, New
Um Albuquerque, New Mexico
Um Albuquerque, New Mexico has
Um Albuquerque, New Mexico has a
Um Albuquerque, New Mexico has a major
one
one on
Um Albuquerque, New Mexico has a major
one on science
one on science and
Um Albuquerque, New Mexico has a major
one on science and consciousness.
They
They usually
They usually approach
They usually approach it
They usually approach it from
They usually approach it from the
They usually approach it from the level
of
of science
They usually approach it from the level
of science and
of science and they
They usually approach it from the level
of science and they get
of science and they get stuck
They usually approach it from the level
of science and they get stuck in
of science and they get stuck in the
brain.
brain. name.
brain. name. What
brain. name. What bothers
brain. name. What bothers them
brain. name. What bothers them is
brain. name. What bothers them is they
can't
can't get
brain. name. What bothers them is they
can't get how
can't get how thinkingness,
consciousness,
consciousness, subjectivity
consciousness, subjectivity connects
with
with brain
consciousness, subjectivity connects
with brain function.
It's
It's best
It's best not
It's best not to
It's best not to know
It's best not to know it
It's best not to know it actually.
It's
It's best
It's best not to know it actually.
It's best not
It's best not to
It's best not to know it actually.
It's best not to know
It's best not to know it,
It's best not to know it actually.
It's best not to know it, folks.
It's best not to know it, folks. And
It's best not to know it actually.
It's best not to know it, folks. And um
because
because th
because th those
because th those that
because th those that level
because th those that level of
consciousness
consciousness is
because th those that level of
consciousness is really
consciousness is really around
because th those that level of
consciousness is really around in
consciousness is really around in the
400s.
400s. I
400s. I want
400s. I want to
400s. I want to do
400s. I want to do this
400s. I want to do this new
400s. I want to do this new one
400s. I want to do this new one here.
I'm
I'm going
400s. I want to do this new one here.
I'm going to
I'm going to need
400s. I want to do this new one here.
I'm going to need this
I'm going to need this one
400s. I want to do this new one here.
I'm going to need this one here.
I'm going to need this one here. All
right.
right. So,
right. So, first
right. So, first I
right. So, first I want
right. So, first I want to
right. So, first I want to go
right. So, first I want to go over
right. So, first I want to go over the
uh
uh technique
right. So, first I want to go over the
uh technique itself.
Be
Be my
Be my guest.
All right.
All right. Uh
Be my guest.
All right. Uh the
All right. Uh the way
Be my guest.
All right. Uh the way I
All right. Uh the way I learned
Be my guest.
All right. Uh the way I learned it
All right. Uh the way I learned it from
John
John Diamond
John Diamond is
John Diamond is we
John Diamond is we we
John Diamond is we we face
John Diamond is we we face each
John Diamond is we we face each other.
I'm
I'm the
John Diamond is we we face each other.
I'm the doctor
I'm the doctor and
John Diamond is we we face each other.
I'm the doctor and you're
I'm the doctor and you're the
John Diamond is we we face each other.
I'm the doctor and you're the patient
and
and I
and I ask
and I ask you
to
to hold
and I ask you
to hold your
to hold your right
and I ask you
to hold your right arm
to hold your right arm out
and I ask you
to hold your right arm out at
to hold your right arm out at parallel
to
to the
to the ground.
to the ground. And
to the ground. And when
to the ground. And when I
to the ground. And when I say
to the ground. And when I say resist,
resist,
resist, resist.
to the ground. And when I say resist,
resist, resist. Okay.
resist, resist. Okay. Now
to the ground. And when I say resist,
resist, resist. Okay. Now I
resist, resist. Okay. Now I tend
to the ground. And when I say resist,
resist, resist. Okay. Now I tend to
resist, resist. Okay. Now I tend to you
push
push down
push down with
push down with one
push down with one finger.
push down with one finger. If
push down with one finger. If we
push down with one finger. If we had
push down with one finger. If we had to
estimate
estimate how
push down with one finger. If we had to
estimate how hard
estimate how hard I
push down with one finger. If we had to
estimate how hard I push
estimate how hard I push down
push down with one finger. If we had to
estimate how hard I push down I
estimate how hard I push down I would
say
say it's
say it's about
say it's about 7
say it's about 7 oz
6 oz.
You
You can
You can push
You can push push
You can push push down
You can push push down very
You can push push down very very
lightly.
Now
Now she
Now she tends
Now she tends to
Now she tends to resist
Now she tends to resist to
Now she tends to resist to the
Now she tends to resist to the degree
that
that I'm
Now she tends to resist to the degree
that I'm pressing
that I'm pressing down.
So
So I
So I ask
So I ask her
So I ask her to
So I ask her to hold
So I ask her to hold someone
So I ask her to hold someone in
So I ask her to hold someone in mind
that
that you
So I ask her to hold someone in mind
that you love.
that you love. Hold
So I ask her to hold someone in mind
that you love. Hold someone
that you love. Hold someone in
So I ask her to hold someone in mind
that you love. Hold someone in mind
that you love. Hold someone in mind that
you
you love.
Resist.
Resist. Okay.
Okay.
Okay. Uh
Okay. Uh I
Okay. Uh I ask
Okay. Uh I ask you
Okay. Uh I ask you to
Okay. Uh I ask you to hold
uh
uh bin
Okay. Uh I ask you to hold
uh bin Laden
uh bin Laden in
Okay. Uh I ask you to hold
uh bin Laden in mind.
uh bin Laden in mind. His
Okay. Uh I ask you to hold
uh bin Laden in mind. His picture
uh bin Laden in mind. His picture in
mind
mind resist.
All right.
All right. So
mind resist.
All right. So the
All right. So the first
mind resist.
All right. So the first thing
All right. So the first thing you
mind resist.
All right. So the first thing you want
to
to do
to do is
to do is make
to do is make sure
to do is make sure that
to do is make sure that they
to do is make sure that they go
to do is make sure that they go strong
with
with love
to do is make sure that they go strong
with love and
with love and go
to do is make sure that they go strong
with love and go weak
with love and go weak with
to do is make sure that they go strong
with love and go weak with the
with love and go weak with the absence
of
of love.
of love. Huh?
There
There are
of love. Huh?
There are entities
There are entities on
of love. Huh?
There are entities on the
There are entities on the planet
of love. Huh?
There are entities on the planet that
reacting
reacting in
reacting in the
reacting in the opposite
reacting in the opposite direction
and
and you
reacting in the opposite direction
and you don't
and you don't want
reacting in the opposite direction
and you don't want to
and you don't want to hang
reacting in the opposite direction
and you don't want to hang out
and you don't want to hang out with
them.
them. Well,
and
and now
them. Well,
and now the
and now the thing
them. Well,
and now the thing that
and now the thing that I
them. Well,
and now the thing that I did
and now the thing that I did not
emphasize
emphasize in
emphasize in the
emphasize in the book,
emphasize in the book, we've
emphasize in the book, we've only
emphasize in the book, we've only real
recent
recent really
emphasize in the book, we've only real
recent really realize
recent really realize the
emphasize in the book, we've only real
recent really realize the importance
recent really realize the importance of
is
is that
is that the
is that the uh
is that the uh the
is that the uh the response
is that the uh the response is
is that the uh the response is very
is that the uh the response is very very
rapid
as
as as
as as I
as as I ask
as as I ask a
as as I ask a question
as as I ask a question when
as as I ask a question when I
as as I ask a question when I say
um
um the
um the theory
um the theory of
um the theory of evolution
um the theory of evolution is
um the theory of evolution is over
um the theory of evolution is over 460
resist
resist 470
um the theory of evolution is over 460
resist 470 resist
the
the the
the the response
the the response is
the the response is extremely
the the response is extremely rapid.
the the response is extremely rapid. You
can't
can't have
the the response is extremely rapid. You
can't have her
can't have her hold
the the response is extremely rapid. You
can't have her hold her
can't have her hold her arm
the the response is extremely rapid. You
can't have her hold her arm out
can't have her hold her arm out and
the the response is extremely rapid. You
can't have her hold her arm out and say,
"Uh,
"Uh, Darwin
"Uh, Darwin is
"Uh, Darwin is over
"Uh, Darwin is over 450."
"Uh, Darwin is over 450." And
"Uh, Darwin is over 450." And then
"Uh, Darwin is over 450." And then blow
your
your nose,
"Uh, Darwin is over 450." And then blow
your nose, have
your nose, have a
"Uh, Darwin is over 450." And then blow
your nose, have a soda,
your nose, have a soda, and
"Uh, Darwin is over 450." And then blow
your nose, have a soda, and and
your nose, have a soda, and and press
"Uh, Darwin is over 450." And then blow
your nose, have a soda, and and press on
her
her arm.
her arm. You
her arm. You know,
her arm. You know, it's
her arm. You know, it's a
her arm. You know, it's a very
her arm. You know, it's a very quick
response.
response. The
her arm. You know, it's a very quick
response. The kinesiologic
response. The kinesiologic response,
her arm. You know, it's a very quick
response. The kinesiologic response, the
acupuncture
acupuncture system
acupuncture system recovers
acupuncture system recovers very
quickly.
quickly. You've
acupuncture system recovers very
quickly. You've only
quickly. You've only got
acupuncture system recovers very
quickly. You've only got really
quickly. You've only got really a
acupuncture system recovers very
quickly. You've only got really a few
seconds
seconds to
seconds to get
seconds to get an
seconds to get an accurate
seconds to get an accurate answer.
The
The second
seconds to get an accurate answer.
The second thing
The second thing that
seconds to get an accurate answer.
The second thing that happens
The second thing that happens is
seconds to get an accurate answer.
The second thing that happens is if
The second thing that happens is if you
wait
wait too
wait too long
the
the basic
wait too long
the basic animal
the basic animal the
wait too long
the basic animal the basic
the basic animal the basic animal
wait too long
the basic animal the basic animal I
won't
won't do
won't do a
won't do a test
won't do a test now
won't do a test now the
won't do a test now the basic
won't do a test now the basic animal
within
within us
once
once the
once the arm
once the arm goes
once the arm goes weak
your
your animal
once the arm goes weak
your animal comes
your animal comes up
once the arm goes weak
your animal comes up and
your animal comes up and tries
once the arm goes weak
your animal comes up and tries to
your animal comes up and tries to keep
you
you from
you from falling
you from falling out
you from falling out of
you from falling out of the
you from falling out of the tree
you from falling out of the tree it
you from falling out of the tree it regs
the
the branch
you from falling out of the tree it regs
the branch you
the branch you understand
you from falling out of the tree it regs
the branch you understand so
the branch you understand so if
you from falling out of the tree it regs
the branch you understand so if you
the branch you understand so if you wait
a
a sec
a sec if
a sec if you
a sec if you wait
a sec if you wait a
a sec if you wait a second
a sec if you wait a second first
a sec if you wait a second first of
a sec if you wait a second first of all
there's
there's a
a sec if you wait a second first of all
there's a a
there's a a weakness
a sec if you wait a second first of all
there's a a weakness that's
there's a a weakness that's very
instantaneous
If
If you
instantaneous
If you do
If you do kinesis
instantaneous
If you do kinesis kinesiology
If you do kinesis kinesiology a
instantaneous
If you do kinesis kinesiology a lot,
If you do kinesis kinesiology a lot, you
you
you sense
you sense it.
you sense it. In
you sense it. In other
you sense it. In other words,
you sense it. In other words, when
you sense it. In other words, when I
you sense it. In other words, when I ask
a
a question,
you sense it. In other words, when I ask
a question, I'm
a question, I'm already
you sense it. In other words, when I ask
a question, I'm already almost
a question, I'm already almost sens
you sense it. In other words, when I ask
a question, I'm already almost sens it
go
go down
go down my
go down my arm
go down my arm and
go down my arm and she
go down my arm and she senses
go down my arm and she senses it.
go down my arm and she senses it. And
go down my arm and she senses it. And we
both
both almost
go down my arm and she senses it. And we
both almost know
both almost know the
go down my arm and she senses it. And we
both almost know the answer
both almost know the answer before
go down my arm and she senses it. And we
both almost know the answer before the
arm
arm goes
arm goes down.
arm goes down. And
arm goes down. And by
arm goes down. And by that
arm goes down. And by that time,
arm goes down. And by that time, the
response
response is
arm goes down. And by that time, the
response is over.
response is over. By
arm goes down. And by that time, the
response is over. By that
response is over. By that time,
arm goes down. And by that time, the
response is over. By that time, the
acupuncture
acupuncture system
acupuncture system is
acupuncture system is coming
acupuncture system is coming back
acupuncture system is coming back again.
See?
See? Because
acupuncture system is coming back again.
See? Because every
See? Because every time
acupuncture system is coming back again.
See? Because every time you
See? Because every time you think
acupuncture system is coming back again.
See? Because every time you think a
negative
negative thought,
negative thought, you
negative thought, you you
negative thought, you you go
negative thought, you you go weak
negative thought, you you go weak like
that.
that. If
negative thought, you you go weak like
that. If you
that. If you didn't
negative thought, you you go weak like
that. If you didn't recover,
that. If you didn't recover, you'd
negative thought, you you go weak like
that. If you didn't recover, you'd still
be
be laying
be laying on
be laying on the
be laying on the ground.
be laying on the ground. So
be laying on the ground. So obviously
be laying on the ground. So obviously we
have
have the
be laying on the ground. So obviously we
have the capacity
have the capacity to
be laying on the ground. So obviously we
have the capacity to recharge
have the capacity to recharge after
we've
we've been
we've been discharged
and
and it's
we've been discharged
and it's a
and it's a very
we've been discharged
and it's a very fast
and it's a very fast response.
we've been discharged
and it's a very fast response. So
and it's a very fast response. So I
we've been discharged
and it's a very fast response. So I did
not
not emphasize
not emphasize that
not emphasize that in
not emphasize that in the
not emphasize that in the book.
not emphasize that in the book. In
not emphasize that in the book. In the
new
new book
not emphasize that in the book. In the
new book I
new book I did
not emphasize that in the book. In the
new book I did emphasize
new book I did emphasize that
not emphasize that in the book. In the
new book I did emphasize that it's
new book I did emphasize that it's a
very
very rapid
very rapid transitory
very rapid transitory response.
You
You don't
very rapid transitory response.
You don't want
You don't want anything
very rapid transitory response.
You don't want anything in
You don't want anything in the
background
background that's
background that's going
background that's going to
background that's going to give
background that's going to give you
false
false positives.
background that's going to give you
false positives. That
false positives. That kind
background that's going to give you
false positives. That kind of
false positives. That kind of music
background that's going to give you
false positives. That kind of music we
were
were playing
were playing which
were playing which calibrates
were playing which calibrates into
were playing which calibrates into 740s
or
or something
were playing which calibrates into 740s
or something like
or something like that
were playing which calibrates into 740s
or something like that and
or something like that and it
were playing which calibrates into 740s
or something like that and it takes
or something like that and it takes a
while
while to
while to recover
while to recover from
while to recover from it
while to recover from it will
while to recover from it will give
while to recover from it will give you
false
false positives
while to recover from it will give you
false positives because
false positives because it's
while to recover from it will give you
false positives because it's angelic.
That
That music
That music calibrates
That music calibrates over
That music calibrates over we
That music calibrates over we have
permission
permission over
That music calibrates over we have
permission over 700,
permission over 700, 720,
That music calibrates over we have
permission over 700, 720, 740,
permission over 700, 720, 740, 750.
That music calibrates over we have
permission over 700, 720, 740, 750. That
music
music calibrates
music calibrates around
music calibrates around 750
and
and an
music calibrates around 750
and an energy
and an energy of
music calibrates around 750
and an energy of 750.
and an energy of 750. You're
music calibrates around 750
and an energy of 750. You're not
to
to get
to get any
to get any nose.
It's
It's too
to get any nose.
It's too beautifific.
It's too beautifific. So,
to get any nose.
It's too beautifific. So, all right.
It's too beautifific. So, all right. So,
you
you don't
you don't want
you don't want angelic
you don't want angelic music.
you don't want angelic music. You
you don't want angelic music. You don't
want
want also
you don't want angelic music. You don't
want also want
want also want Eminem
you don't want angelic music. You don't
want also want Eminem in
want also want Eminem in the
you don't want angelic music. You don't
want also want Eminem in the background.
All right.
You
You try
All right.
You try not
You try not to
All right.
You try not to be
You try not to be loving.
All right.
You try not to be loving. You
You try not to be loving. You just
All right.
You try not to be loving. You just try
to
to be
to be you
to be you pretend
to be you pretend you're
to be you pretend you're doctor
to be you pretend you're doctor and
patient.
patient. It's
to be you pretend you're doctor and
patient. It's very
patient. It's very u
detached
detached and
detached and impersonal
and
and um
detached and impersonal
and um detached
and um detached and
detached and impersonal
and um detached and impersonal.
We've
We've learned
We've learned how
We've learned how to
We've learned how to detach
We've learned how to detach from
We've learned how to detach from the
field.
field. All right.
We've learned how to detach from the
field. All right. So
field. All right. So with
We've learned how to detach from the
field. All right. So with experience,
you
you get
you get it.
you get it. So
you get it. So So
you get it. So So the
you get it. So So the first
you get it. So So the first thing
you get it. So So the first thing is
that
that that
you get it. So So the first thing is
that that it's
that that it's a
you get it. So So the first thing is
that that it's a very
that that it's a very very
you get it. So So the first thing is
that that it's a very very quick.
that that it's a very very quick. You
notice
notice that
notice that I
notice that I make
notice that I make a
notice that I make a statement.
The
The statement
notice that I make a statement.
The statement does
The statement does not
notice that I make a statement.
The statement does not have
The statement does not have to
notice that I make a statement.
The statement does not have to be
verbalized.
What
What I'm
verbalized.
What I'm holding
What I'm holding in
verbalized.
What I'm holding in mind
What I'm holding in mind calibrates
verbalized.
What I'm holding in mind calibrates over
720,
720, 7:30.
What
What I
720, 7:30.
What I was
What I was holding
720, 7:30.
What I was holding in
What I was holding in mind
720, 7:30.
What I was holding in mind was
What I was holding in mind was the
720, 7:30.
What I was holding in mind was the music
which
which calibrates
which calibrates over
which calibrates over 7:30.
All right.
All right. So,
which calibrates over 7:30.
All right. So, she
All right. So, she doesn't
which calibrates over 7:30.
All right. So, she doesn't have
All right. So, she doesn't have to
which calibrates over 7:30.
All right. So, she doesn't have to know
what
what I'm
what I'm holding
what I'm holding in
what I'm holding in mind.
what I'm holding in mind. And
what I'm holding in mind. And we'll
explain
explain the
what I'm holding in mind. And we'll
explain the the
explain the the physics
what I'm holding in mind. And we'll
explain the the physics of
explain the the physics of this
what I'm holding in mind. And we'll
explain the the physics of this in
explain the the physics of this in a
minute
because
because the
minute
because the argument
because the argument comes
minute
because the argument comes up,
because the argument comes up, well,
what
what your
what your belief
what your belief system
what your belief system is
what your belief system is is
what your belief system is is affecting
the
the uh
what your belief system is is affecting
the uh response.
the uh response. It's
what your belief system is is affecting
the uh response. It's not.
And
And if
And if it
And if it is
And if it is then
And if it is then you
And if it is then you shouldn't
And if it is then you shouldn't be
And if it is then you shouldn't be doing
kinesiology
kinesiology because
And if it is then you shouldn't be doing
kinesiology because that
kinesiology because that the
And if it is then you shouldn't be doing
kinesiology because that the two
criteria
criteria are
criteria are that
criteria are that the
criteria are that the people
criteria are that the people doing
criteria are that the people doing it
themselves
themselves must
criteria are that the people doing it
themselves must calibrate
themselves must calibrate over
criteria are that the people doing it
themselves must calibrate over 200.
themselves must calibrate over 200. They
must
must be
must be integris
and
and the
must be integris
and the intention
and the intention of
must be integris
and the intention of the
and the intention of the question
must be integris
and the intention of the question must
be
be integris.
It
It would
be integris.
It would be
It would be hard
be integris.
It would be hard to
It would be hard to ask
be integris.
It would be hard to ask a
It would be hard to ask a question
be integris.
It would be hard to ask a question I
It would be hard to ask a question I am
handsome
handsome and
handsome and get
handsome and get a
handsome and get a objective
handsome and get a objective response.
anything
anything you
handsome and get a objective response.
anything you have
anything you have a
handsome and get a objective response.
anything you have a vested
anything you have a vested interest
handsome and get a objective response.
anything you have a vested interest in.
Lots
Lots of
Lots of people
Lots of people write
Lots of people write me
Lots of people write me about
Lots of people write me about their
favorite
favorite gurus
Lots of people write me about their
favorite gurus and
favorite gurus and send
Lots of people write me about their
favorite gurus and send me
favorite gurus and send me pictures
Lots of people write me about their
favorite gurus and send me pictures and
books
books and
books and things.
Ostensively,
Ostensively, they
books and things.
Ostensively, they want
Ostensively, they want to
books and things.
Ostensively, they want to know
Ostensively, they want to know what
books and things.
Ostensively, they want to know what he
calibrates.
calibrates. They
calibrates. They do
calibrates. They do not
calibrates. They do not want
calibrates. They do not want to
calibrates. They do not want to know
what
what he
calibrates. They do not want to know
what he calibrates.
what he calibrates. What
calibrates. They do not want to know
what he calibrates. What they
what he calibrates. What they want
calibrates. They do not want to know
what he calibrates. What they want you
to
to do
to do is
to do is confirm
to do is confirm or
to do is confirm or they
to do is confirm or they have
to do is confirm or they have a
to do is confirm or they have a vested
interest.
I
I used
I used to
I used to try
I used to try to
I used to try to answer
I used to try to answer them
I used to try to answer them and
I used to try to answer them and I
realized
realized you
I used to try to answer them and I
realized you can't
realized you can't because
I used to try to answer them and I
realized you can't because no
realized you can't because no matter
what
what you
what you answer,
what you answer, they
what you answer, they will
what you answer, they will refute
what you answer, they will refute it.
See?
Okay.
If
If he
Okay.
If he calibrates
If he calibrates 90,
Okay.
If he calibrates 90, they
If he calibrates 90, they think
Okay.
If he calibrates 90, they think he's
God.
God. So,
lots
lots of
God. So,
lots of people
lots of people on
God. So,
lots of people on the
lots of people on the planet
God. So,
lots of people on the planet worship
people
people who
people who are
people who are calibrated
people who are calibrated 90
people who are calibrated 90 and
people who are calibrated 90 and they
give
give their
people who are calibrated 90 and they
give their life
give their life for
people who are calibrated 90 and they
give their life for them.
give their life for them. And
people who are calibrated 90 and they
give their life for them. And 3,000
Americans
Americans found
Americans found that
Americans found that out.
Americans found that out. Huh.
So,
So, that
Americans found that out. Huh.
So, that which
So, that which is
Americans found that out. Huh.
So, that which is only
So, that which is only 90
Americans found that out. Huh.
So, that which is only 90 does
So, that which is only 90 does not
Americans found that out. Huh.
So, that which is only 90 does not lack
for
for worshippers.
All right.
All right. So,
for worshippers.
All right. So, we
All right. So, we said
for worshippers.
All right. So, we said people
All right. So, we said people have
for worshippers.
All right. So, we said people have to
All right. So, we said people have to be
integrous.
integrous. So
integrous. So you're
integrous. So you're you're
integrous. So you're you're we
integrous. So you're you're we ask
integrous. So you're you're we ask to
integrous. So you're you're we ask to to
do
do to to
integrous. So you're you're we ask to to
do to to affirm
do to to affirm that
integrous. So you're you're we ask to to
do to to affirm that we
do to to affirm that we have
integrous. So you're you're we ask to to
do to to affirm that we have permission
to
to ask
to ask this
to ask this question.
to ask this question. We
to ask this question. We have
to ask this question. We have permission
to
to say
to ask this question. We have permission
to say what
to say what we're
to ask this question. We have permission
to say what we're saying
to say what we're saying this
to ask this question. We have permission
to say what we're saying this morning
about
about this
about this test.
about this test. Oh
about this test. Oh Lord.
about this test. Oh Lord. Amen.
about this test. Oh Lord. Amen. Is
about this test. Oh Lord. Amen. Is it?
Okay.
So
So two
Okay.
So two people
So two people in
Okay.
So two people in an
So two people in an integrous
Okay.
So two people in an integrous intention
who
who are
who are aligned
who are aligned with
who are aligned with each
who are aligned with each other.
who are aligned with each other. So
who are aligned with each other. So are
we're
we're aligned
who are aligned with each other. So are
we're aligned in
we're aligned in our
who are aligned with each other. So are
we're aligned in our intention.
In
In the
In the research
In the research we
In the research we do,
In the research we do, what
In the research we do, what you
In the research we do, what you do
In the research we do, what you do is
you
you don't
In the research we do, what you do is
you don't have
you don't have a
In the research we do, what you do is
you don't have a vested
you you
you you disconnect
you you disconnect from
you you disconnect from a
you you disconnect from a vested
interest
interest in
you you disconnect from a vested
interest in the
interest in the answer.
you you disconnect from a vested
interest in the answer. It
interest in the answer. It doesn't
you you disconnect from a vested
interest in the answer. It doesn't make
any
any difference
any difference what
any difference what the
any difference what the answer
any difference what the answer is.
any difference what the answer is. I
don't
don't care
any difference what the answer is. I
don't care what
don't care what Darwin
any difference what the answer is. I
don't care what Darwin calibrates
don't care what Darwin calibrates that.
What
What the
What the hell
What the hell do
What the hell do I
What the hell do I care?
What the hell do I care? You
What the hell do I care? You know,
What the hell do I care? You know, I'm
What the hell do I care? You know, I'm I
don't
don't own
What the hell do I care? You know, I'm I
don't own any
don't own any stock
What the hell do I care? You know, I'm I
don't own any stock in
don't own any stock in his
What the hell do I care? You know, I'm I
don't own any stock in his company,
don't own any stock in his company, not
my
my brother-in-law.
my brother-in-law. What
my brother-in-law. What do
my brother-in-law. What do I
my brother-in-law. What do I care
my brother-in-law. What do I care if
my brother-in-law. What do I care if he
calibrates?
calibrates? People
my brother-in-law. What do I care if he
calibrates? People say,
calibrates? People say, "Well,
my brother-in-law. What do I care if he
calibrates? People say, "Well, you're
getting
getting what
getting what you
getting what you think."
getting what you think." I
getting what you think." I don't
getting what you think." I don't think
anything
anything about
getting what you think." I don't think
anything about Darren's
anything about Darren's calibrated
getting what you think." I don't think
anything about Darren's calibrated level
consciousness.
consciousness. In
consciousness. In fact,
consciousness. In fact, I
consciousness. In fact, I didn't
discover
discover it
consciousness. In fact, I didn't
discover it until
discover it until just
consciousness. In fact, I didn't
discover it until just a
discover it until just a week
consciousness. In fact, I didn't
discover it until just a week or
discover it until just a week or two
ago.
So
So the
ago.
So the dedication
the
the devotional
the devotional devotional
the devotional devotional path
the devotional devotional path the
devotional
devotional non-duality
what
what is
what is the
what is the devotion
what is the devotion to
what is the devotion to the
what is the devotion to the devotion
what is the devotion to the devotion is
to
to truth
what is the devotion to the devotion is
to truth the
to truth the absolute
what is the devotion to the devotion is
to truth the absolute truth
at
at all
at all cost
at all cost at
at all cost at any
at all cost at any cost.
The
The devotion
at all cost at any cost.
The devotion takes
The devotion takes you
at all cost at any cost.
The devotion takes you to
The devotion takes you to the
at all cost at any cost.
The devotion takes you to the point
where
where the
where the final
where the final moment
where the final moment arises
where the final moment arises which
where the final moment arises which we
handled
handled in
where the final moment arises which we
handled in the
handled in the last
where the final moment arises which we
handled in the last lecture
where
where the
where the devotion
where the devotion is
where the devotion is so
where the devotion is so extreme
where the devotion is so extreme that
one
is
is willing
is willing to
is willing to lay
is willing to lay down
is willing to lay down one's
is willing to lay down one's life
is willing to lay down one's life for
God
because
because that's
because that's what
because that's what you
because that's what you do.
because that's what you do. Life
because that's what you do. Life as
because that's what you do. Life as you
know
know it,
because that's what you do. Life as you
know it, experience
know it, experience and
because that's what you do. Life as you
know it, experience and understand
know it, experience and understand it
throughout
throughout all
throughout all the
throughout all the ages.
And
And that's
throughout all the ages.
And that's when
And that's when the
throughout all the ages.
And that's when the radiance
And that's when the radiance shines
forth.
So
So the
forth.
So the kinesiologic
So the kinesiologic technique
forth.
So the kinesiologic technique then
So the kinesiologic technique then we
stumbled
stumbled upon
stumbled upon I
stumbled upon I stumbled
stumbled upon I stumbled upon
stumbled upon I stumbled upon it
stumbled upon I stumbled upon it and
stumbled upon I stumbled upon it and we
discovered
discovered amazing
stumbled upon I stumbled upon it and we
discovered amazing things
discovered amazing things with
stumbled upon I stumbled upon it and we
discovered amazing things with it.
discovered amazing things with it. Let's
do
do this
do this slide.
do this slide. Huh.
The
The amazing
do this slide. Huh.
The amazing thing
The amazing thing about
do this slide. Huh.
The amazing thing about the
The amazing thing about the kinesiologic
response
response is
response is that
response is that it
response is that it bridges
response is that it bridges the
response is that it bridges the gap
between
between the
response is that it bridges the gap
between the Newtonian
linear
linear world
linear world of
linear world of logic,
linear world of logic, reason,
linear world of logic, reason, science,
and
and thingness,
the
the world
the world of
the world of form,
the
the world
the world of form,
the world of
the world of the
the world of form,
the world of the ego.
And
And it's
And it's a
And it's a transition
And it's a transition from
And it's a transition from context
And it's a transition from context to
content,
from
from the
from the content
from the content of
from the content of the
from the content of the field
from the content of the field to
from the content of the field to the
field
field itself.
That's
That's a
That's a jump
That's a jump which
That's a jump which the
That's a jump which the mind
That's a jump which the mind has
That's a jump which the mind has great
difficulty
difficulty in
That's a jump which the mind has great
difficulty in making.
difficulty in making. In
That's a jump which the mind has great
difficulty in making. In fact,
only
only 4%
only 4% of
only 4% of the
only 4% of the population
only 4% of the population is
only 4% of the population is capable
only 4% of the population is capable of
making
making that
only 4% of the population is capable of
making that jump.
making that jump. Ever
only 4% of the population is capable of
making that jump. Ever hits
making that jump. Ever hits calibrated
level
level 500
level 500 or
level 500 or over.
And
And this
level 500 or over.
And this morning
And this morning we'll
level 500 or over.
And this morning we'll find
And this morning we'll find out
level 500 or over.
And this morning we'll find out why
Einstein
Einstein calibrated
Einstein calibrated 499,
which
which you
Einstein calibrated 499,
which you can't
which you can't understand
Einstein calibrated 499,
which you can't understand without
quantum
quantum mechanics.
The
The world
quantum mechanics.
The world which
The world which science
quantum mechanics.
The world which science calls
The world which science calls real
quantum mechanics.
The world which science calls real then
is
is the
is the world
is the world of
is the world of logic
is the world of logic determinist
deterministic
deterministic predictability.
It's
It's based
It's based on
It's based on the
It's based on the premise
It's based on the premise of
It's based on the premise of causality.
The
The reason
It's based on the premise of causality.
The reason we
The reason we constantly
It's based on the premise of causality.
The reason we constantly work
The reason we constantly work on
It's based on the premise of causality.
The reason we constantly work on undoing
the
the illusion
the illusion of
the illusion of duality
the illusion of duality is
the illusion of duality is because
the illusion of duality is because as
long
long as
the illusion of duality is because as
long as you
long as you believe
the illusion of duality is because as
long as you believe in
long as you believe in duality,
you
you will
you will believe
you will believe that
you will believe that there
you will believe that there is
you will believe that there is a
you will believe that there is a this
causing
causing a
you will believe that there is a this
causing a that.
you
you will
you will reinforce
you will reinforce the
you will reinforce the belief
you will reinforce the belief that
you will reinforce the belief that the
ego
ego is
you will reinforce the belief that the
ego is a
ego is a reality.
So
So long
So long as
So long as there's
So long as there's causality,
So long as there's causality, there
So long as there's causality, there has
to
to be
So long as there's causality, there has
to be an
to be an is
So long as there's causality, there has
to be an is and
to be an is and an
So long as there's causality, there has
to be an is and an eye,
to be an is and an eye, an
So long as there's causality, there has
to be an is and an eye, an inner
to be an is and an eye, an inner eye,
So long as there's causality, there has
to be an is and an eye, an inner eye, a
self
self to
self to be
self to be the
self to be the cause
self to be the cause of
self to be the cause of that,
self to be the cause of that, the
movement
movement of
self to be the cause of that, the
movement of the
movement of the arm,
self to be the cause of that, the
movement of the arm, the
movement of the arm, the speech.
self to be the cause of that, the
movement of the arm, the speech. So
there's
there's a
there's a this
there's a this causing
there's a this causing a
there's a this causing a that.
there's a this causing a that. So
there's a this causing a that. So the
belief
belief in
there's a this causing a that. So the
belief in causality
belief in causality then
there's a this causing a that. So the
belief in causality then anchors
the
the belief
the belief in
the belief in the
the belief in the ego
the belief in the ego system
the belief in the ego system as
the belief in the ego system as a
reality.
All
All exist
All exist by
All exist by virtue
All exist by virtue of
All exist by virtue of divinity
All exist by virtue of divinity which
All exist by virtue of divinity which is
an
an infinite
All exist by virtue of divinity which is
an infinite field
which
which particularizes
and
is
is manifested
is manifested in
is manifested in the
is manifested in the world
is manifested in the world of
is manifested in the world of form
is manifested in the world of form which
is
is transitory.
is manifested in the world of form which
is transitory. All
is transitory. All that
is manifested in the world of form which
is transitory. All that you
is transitory. All that you witness
is manifested in the world of form which
is transitory. All that you witness is
transitory.
And
And so
transitory.
And so as
And so as consciousness
transitory.
And so as consciousness advances,
And so as consciousness advances, you
you
you advance
you advance out
you advance out of
you advance out of this
you advance out of this moment
and
and witness
you advance out of this moment
and witness everything
and witness everything as
you advance out of this moment
and witness everything as evolving
and witness everything as evolving over
great
great evolutionary
great evolutionary time.
The
The source
great evolutionary time.
The source of
The source of evolution,
great evolutionary time.
The source of evolution, however,
The source of evolution, however, is
great evolutionary time.
The source of evolution, however, is not
in
in mechanistic
in mechanistic determinism.
The
The source
in mechanistic determinism.
The source of
The source of evolution
in mechanistic determinism.
The source of evolution is
The source of evolution is within
consciousness
consciousness itself.
Anybody
Anybody who
consciousness itself.
Anybody who watches
Anybody who watches the
consciousness itself.
Anybody who watches the Animal
Anybody who watches the Animal Channel
night
night after
night after night
night after night or
night after night or the
night after night or the National
Geographic
becomes
becomes aware
that
that each
becomes aware
that each species
that each species is
becomes aware
that each species is a
that each species is a new
becomes aware
that each species is a new creation.
You
You don't
You don't go
You don't go from
You don't go from half
You don't go from half zebra
You don't go from half zebra to
You don't go from half zebra to half
camel.
camel. There
You don't go from half zebra to half
camel. There ain't
camel. There ain't no
You don't go from half zebra to half
camel. There ain't no such
camel. There ain't no such animal.
When
When you
When you witness
When you witness the
When you witness the aesthetics
of
of the
When you witness the aesthetics
of the world,
of the world, you
When you witness the aesthetics
of the world, you realize
of the world, you realize it's
When you witness the aesthetics
of the world, you realize it's coming
out
out of
out of a
out of a creative
out of a creative consciousness.
out of a creative consciousness. Okay.
Now,
Now, I
out of a creative consciousness. Okay.
Now, I want
Now, I want everybody
out of a creative consciousness. Okay.
Now, I want everybody to
Now, I want everybody to still
out of a creative consciousness. Okay.
Now, I want everybody to still be
Now, I want everybody to still be able
to
to face
their
their friends
to face
their friends and
their friends and say
to face
their friends and say they
their friends and say they believe
to face
their friends and say they believe in
science
science and
science and they
science and they also
science and they also believe
science and they also believe in
kinesiology
kinesiology and
science and they also believe in
kinesiology and spirituality.
kinesiology and spirituality. And
science and they also believe in
kinesiology and spirituality. And so,
you
you help
you help them
you help them bridge
you help them bridge the
you help them bridge the gap
you help them bridge the gap here.
The
The information
you help them bridge the gap here.
The information here
The information here is
you help them bridge the gap here.
The information here is available
The information here is available on
you help them bridge the gap here.
The information here is available on the
internet.
internet. Henry
internet. Henry Stap.
internet. Henry Stap. If
internet. Henry Stap. If you
internet. Henry Stap. If you look
internet. Henry Stap. If you look up
Henry
Henry Stap
internet. Henry Stap. If you look up
Henry Stap in
Henry Stap in the
internet. Henry Stap. If you look up
Henry Stap in the internet,
Henry Stap in the internet, the
consciousness
consciousness um
consciousness um conference
consciousness um conference uh
consciousness um conference uh Tucson
will
will be
consciousness um conference uh Tucson
will be on
will be on the
consciousness um conference uh Tucson
will be on the available
will be on the available on
consciousness um conference uh Tucson
will be on the available on the
internet.
These
These are
internet.
These are ponderous
These are ponderous toms
internet.
These are ponderous toms of
These are ponderous toms of wondrous
mathematics.
Ponderous
Ponderous tomes
mathematics.
Ponderous tomes of
Ponderous tomes of wondrous
mathematics.
Ponderous tomes of wondrous mathematics
trying
trying to
trying to connect
trying to connect it
trying to connect it with
trying to connect it with the
trying to connect it with the details
trying to connect it with the details of
neurohysiology.
And
my
my heart
And
my heart goes
my heart goes out
And
my heart goes out to
my heart goes out to them
And
my heart goes out to them because
my heart goes out to them because I
And
my heart goes out to them because I read
a
a lot
a lot of
a lot of these
a lot of these papers
a lot of these papers and
a lot of these papers and I
a lot of these papers and I can
a lot of these papers and I can see
a lot of these papers and I can see they
are
are trying
a lot of these papers and I can see they
are trying to
are trying to stretch
a lot of these papers and I can see they
are trying to stretch this.
are trying to stretch this. They're
trying
trying to
trying to stretch
trying to stretch the
trying to stretch the intellect
trying to stretch the intellect across
the
the bridge
trying to stretch the intellect across
the bridge and
the bridge and they
trying to stretch the intellect across
the bridge and they can't
the bridge and they can't make
trying to stretch the intellect across
the bridge and they can't make it.
But
But to
But to an
But to an exquisite
But to an exquisite degree
But to an exquisite degree they
But to an exquisite degree they pursue
the
the intellect
But to an exquisite degree they pursue
the intellect and
the intellect and so
But to an exquisite degree they pursue
the intellect and so is
the intellect and so is their
But to an exquisite degree they pursue
the intellect and so is their work
the intellect and so is their work is
very
very impressive
very impressive from
very impressive from an
very impressive from an intellectual
viewpoint.
viewpoint. Huh.
So
So we're
So we're going
So we're going to
So we're going to do
So we're going to do just
So we're going to do just a
So we're going to do just a brief
precise
precise for
So we're going to do just a brief
precise for the
precise for the for
So we're going to do just a brief
precise for the for only
precise for the for only spir
So we're going to do just a brief
precise for the for only spir for
spiritual
spiritual students.
spiritual students. This
spiritual students. This is
spiritual students. This is all
spiritual students. This is all you
spiritual students. This is all you got
to
to know.
The
The rest
The rest is
The rest is music.
The rest is music. Okay.
Beginning
Beginning around
The rest is music. Okay.
Beginning around 1900
Beginning around 1900 is
The rest is music. Okay.
Beginning around 1900 is the
Beginning around 1900 is the beginning
of
of quantum.
of quantum. Anybody
of quantum. Anybody here
of quantum. Anybody here know
of quantum. Anybody here know anything
about
about quantum
of quantum. Anybody here know anything
about quantum mechanics?
about quantum mechanics? Anybody
familiar
familiar with
familiar with it?
familiar with it? How
familiar with it? How many
familiar with it? How many people
familiar with it? How many people are
unfamiliar
unfamiliar with
familiar with it? How many people are
unfamiliar with it?
unfamiliar with it? All right.
familiar with it? How many people are
unfamiliar with it? All right. Okay.
right.
right. Classical
right. Classical physics,
right. Classical physics, you
right. Classical physics, you know,
right. Classical physics, you know, uh
arose
arose originally
right. Classical physics, you know, uh
arose originally from
arose originally from the
right. Classical physics, you know, uh
arose originally from the observation
arose originally from the observation of
Kepler,
Kepler, the
Kepler, the uh
Kepler, the uh rotation
Kepler, the uh rotation of
Kepler, the uh rotation of the
Kepler, the uh rotation of the planets
etc.
etc. Its
Kepler, the uh rotation of the planets
etc. Its mathematics
etc. Its mathematics were
Kepler, the uh rotation of the planets
etc. Its mathematics were evolved
etc. Its mathematics were evolved as
Kepler, the uh rotation of the planets
etc. Its mathematics were evolved as the
differential
differential calculus
differential calculus by
differential calculus by Sir
differential calculus by Sir Isaac
Newton.
Newton. Sir
differential calculus by Sir Isaac
Newton. Sir Isaac
Newton. Sir Isaac Newton.
Sir
Sir Isaac
Sir Isaac Newton,
Sir Isaac Newton, we
Sir Isaac Newton, we have
Sir Isaac Newton, we have permission.
Calibrates
Calibrates at
Sir Isaac Newton, we have permission.
Calibrates at 499.
Calibrates at 499. Sir
Sir Isaac Newton, we have permission.
Calibrates at 499. Sir Isaac
Calibrates at 499. Sir Isaac Newton
calibrates
calibrates 499.
So
So the
calibrates 499.
So the great
So the great mathematical
calibrates 499.
So the great mathematical scientific
geniuses
geniuses of
geniuses of all
geniuses of all time
geniuses of all time push
geniuses of all time push the
geniuses of all time push the intellect
to
to the
geniuses of all time push the intellect
to the max.
to the max. 499
is
is the
is the the
is the the ceiling.
is the the ceiling. This
is the the ceiling. This is
is the the ceiling. This is the
is the the ceiling. This is the ceiling
of
of this
is the the ceiling. This is the ceiling
of this world,
of this world, but
is the the ceiling. This is the ceiling
of this world, but the
of this world, but the floor
is the the ceiling. This is the ceiling
of this world, but the floor of
of this world, but the floor of the
next.
So
So what
next.
So what takes
So what takes you
next.
So what takes you to
So what takes you to the
next.
So what takes you to the top
So what takes you to the top in
next.
So what takes you to the top in this
dimension
dimension then
dimension then becomes
dimension then becomes the
dimension then becomes the limitation
dimension then becomes the limitation of
the
the next.
Making
Making that
Making that jump
Making that jump is
Making that jump is where
Making that jump is where what
Making that jump is where what makes
Making that jump is where what makes the
difference.
around
around the
around the turn
around the turn of
around the turn of the
around the turn of the century
around the turn of the century uh
around the turn of the century uh the
discovery
discovery uh
around the turn of the century uh the
discovery uh discoveries
discovery uh discoveries of
around the turn of the century uh the
discovery uh discoveries of plank
discovery uh discoveries of plank and
bore
bore Neil
bore Neil Boore
bore Neil Boore and
many
many famous
bore Neil Boore and
many famous physicists
Shredder
Shredder and
Shredder and Heisenberg
Shredder and Heisenberg and
Shredder and Heisenberg and Derek
um
it
it became
it became necessary
it became necessary when
it became necessary when you
it became necessary when you look
it became necessary when you look at
gross
gross phenomena
it became necessary when you look at
gross phenomena the
gross phenomena the microscopic
it became necessary when you look at
gross phenomena the microscopic world
the
the world
the world that
the world that you
the world that you can
the world that you can measure
the world that you can measure and
the world that you can measure and weigh
the
the rules
the world that you can measure and weigh
the rules begin
the rules begin to
the world that you can measure and weigh
the rules begin to change
the rules begin to change when
the world that you can measure and weigh
the rules begin to change when you
the rules begin to change when you start
examining
examining things
examining things microscopically,
subatomic
subatomic particles,
minute
minute energies
minute energies that
minute energies that can
minute energies that can no
minute energies that can no longer
minute energies that can no longer be
measured
measured in
minute energies that can no longer be
measured in conventional
measured in conventional ways.
minute energies that can no longer be
measured in conventional ways. Now
measured in conventional ways. Now you
enter
enter a
enter a different
enter a different dimension,
enter a different dimension, a
enter a different dimension, a different
domain
domain in
enter a different dimension, a different
domain in which
domain in which the
enter a different dimension, a different
domain in which the rules
domain in which the rules of
the
the gross
the gross domain,
the gross domain, the
the gross domain, the microscopic
the gross domain, the microscopic domain
of
of physicality,
the gross domain, the microscopic domain
of physicality, measurable
of physicality, measurable physicality,
suddenly
suddenly change.
Now
Now you're
suddenly change.
Now you're dealing
Now you're dealing not
suddenly change.
Now you're dealing not in
Now you're dealing not in what
suddenly change.
Now you're dealing not in what is
Now you're dealing not in what is is
suddenly change.
Now you're dealing not in what is is but
probabilities,
probabilities, likelihoods.
And
And what's
probabilities, likelihoods.
And what's happened
And what's happened is
probabilities, likelihoods.
And what's happened is you've
And what's happened is you've gone
probabilities, likelihoods.
And what's happened is you've gone from
the
the fixation
the fixation of
the fixation of content
to
to the
the fixation of content
to the infinite
to the infinite possibility
the fixation of content
to the infinite possibility of
to the infinite possibility of the
nonlinear
nonlinear domain
of
of context.
Context
Context is
Context is beyond
Context is beyond form.
So
So how
Context is beyond form.
So how do
So how do you
Context is beyond form.
So how do you make
So how do you make that
Context is beyond form.
So how do you make that jump?
So how do you make that jump? Well,
Context is beyond form.
So how do you make that jump? Well, in
1927,
1927, uh
1927, uh because
1927, uh because Neil's
1927, uh because Neil's Boore
1927, uh because Neil's Boore was
1927, uh because Neil's Boore was the
1927, uh because Neil's Boore was the uh
the
the host
1927, uh because Neil's Boore was the uh
the host in
the host in 1927
in
in uh
in uh in
in uh in Copenhagen,
the
the leading
in uh in Copenhagen,
the leading uh
the leading uh mathematician,
in uh in Copenhagen,
the leading uh mathematician, physic
researchers
researchers and
researchers and physicists
researchers and physicists got
researchers and physicists got together
and
and that
researchers and physicists got together
and that was
and that was the
researchers and physicists got together
and that was the famous
and that was the famous Copenhagen
conference
conference out
conference out of
conference out of which
conference out of which they
conference out of which they came
conference out of which they came to
certain
certain conclusions.
The
The most
The most amazing
The most amazing thing
The most amazing thing was
The most amazing thing was that
The most amazing thing was that they
The most amazing thing was that they had
to
to account
The most amazing thing was that they had
to account for
to account for was
The most amazing thing was that they had
to account for was Heisenberg's
observation.
observation. uh
observation. uh everybody's
observation. uh everybody's familiar
with
with Heisenberg's
observation. uh everybody's familiar
with Heisenberg's observation
with Heisenberg's observation that
observation. uh everybody's familiar
with Heisenberg's observation that once
you
you look
you look at
you look at a
you look at a phenomena
you look at a phenomena that
you look at a phenomena that phenomena
now
now is
you look at a phenomena that phenomena
now is different
now is different you
you look at a phenomena that phenomena
now is different you cannot
now is different you cannot measure
you look at a phenomena that phenomena
now is different you cannot measure the
same
same thing
same thing twice
same thing twice having
same thing twice having once
same thing twice having once measured
same thing twice having once measured it
having
having once
same thing twice having once measured it
having once observed
having once observed it
same thing twice having once measured it
having once observed it now
having once observed it now it
same thing twice having once measured it
having once observed it now it is
having once observed it now it is it
same thing twice having once measured it
having once observed it now it is it has
changed
on
on such
changed
on such a
on such a submicroscopic
changed
on such a submicroscopic level
on such a submicroscopic level that
changed
on such a submicroscopic level that in
the
the physical
the physical world
the physical world that's
the physical world that's canceled
the physical world that's canceled out
consciousness
consciousness we
the physical world that's canceled out
consciousness we are
consciousness we are not
the physical world that's canceled out
consciousness we are not dealing
consciousness we are not dealing with
pounds
pounds and
pounds and tons
We're
We're dealing
pounds and tons
We're dealing with
We're dealing with things
pounds and tons
We're dealing with things that
We're dealing with things that energies
that
that in
that in power
that in power versus
that in power versus force
that in power versus force I
that in power versus force I estimated
at
at 10
that in power versus force I estimated
at 10 the
at 10 the minus400
that in power versus force I estimated
at 10 the minus400 right
at 10 the minus400 right something
that in power versus force I estimated
at 10 the minus400 right something like
that
comparable
comparable to
that
comparable to 10
comparable to 10 the
that
comparable to 10 the minus400
comparable to 10 the minus400 watts
microwatts
microwatts like
microwatts like I
microwatts like I said
microwatts like I said just
microwatts like I said just so
microwatts like I said just so we
microwatts like I said just so we would
have
have something
microwatts like I said just so we would
have something to
have something to play
microwatts like I said just so we would
have something to play with
have something to play with in
microwatts like I said just so we would
have something to play with in our
have something to play with in our head
you
you know
you know how
you know how small
you know how small is
you know how small is small
you know how small is small well
you know how small is small well it's
you know how small is small well it's 0
all
all the
you know how small is small well it's 0
all the way
all the way down
you know how small is small well it's 0
all the way down the
all the way down the the
you know how small is small well it's 0
all the way down the the block
all the way down the the block that
you know how small is small well it's 0
all the way down the the block that many
O's
and
and then
O's
and then one
which
which is
which is insignificant,
which is insignificant, right?
Hardly
because
because over
because over great
because over great dimensions
because over great dimensions of
because over great dimensions of time
through
through sheer
because over great dimensions of time
through sheer iteration
what
what happens
what happens is
what happens is that
what happens is that the
what happens is that the predictable
waves
waves of
what happens is that the predictable
waves of the
waves of the ocean
predictable
predictable waves
predictable waves of
predictable waves of the
predictable waves of the oceanography
has
has to
predictable waves of the oceanography
has to explain
has to explain why
predictable waves of the oceanography
has to explain why is
has to explain why is it
predictable waves of the oceanography
has to explain why is it that
has to explain why is it that maybe
predictable waves of the oceanography
has to explain why is it that maybe 10
ships
ships a
ships a year
ships a year suddenly
ships a year suddenly are
ships a year suddenly are hit
ships a year suddenly are hit by
ships a year suddenly are hit by a
ships a year suddenly are hit by a wave
which
which cannot
ships a year suddenly are hit by a wave
which cannot exist.
It
It was
It was on
It was on a
It was on a documentary
It was on a documentary the
It was on a documentary the other
It was on a documentary the other night.
The
The giant
It was on a documentary the other night.
The giant so-called
The giant so-called giant
It was on a documentary the other night.
The giant so-called giant waves
The giant so-called giant waves are
It was on a documentary the other night.
The giant so-called giant waves are 100
ft
ft high.
ft high. And
ft high. And the
ft high. And the great
ft high. And the great ships
ft high. And the great ships are
ft high. And the great ships are made
ft high. And the great ships are made to
handle
handle ch
ft high. And the great ships are made to
handle ch waves
handle ch waves at
ft high. And the great ships are made to
handle ch waves at 40
handle ch waves at 40 ft
ft high. And the great ships are made to
handle ch waves at 40 ft of
handle ch waves at 40 ft of height.
ft high. And the great ships are made to
handle ch waves at 40 ft of height. But
about
about eight
about eight or
about eight or 10
about eight or 10 times
about eight or 10 times a
about eight or 10 times a year,
about eight or 10 times a year, ships
report
report they've
about eight or 10 times a year, ships
report they've been
report they've been hit
about eight or 10 times a year, ships
report they've been hit by
report they've been hit by a
about eight or 10 times a year, ships
report they've been hit by a wall
report they've been hit by a wall 100
about eight or 10 times a year, ships
report they've been hit by a wall 100 ft
high,
high, which
high, which science
high, which science says
high, which science says cannot
high, which science says cannot be
cannot
cannot exist.
high, which science says cannot be
cannot exist. If
cannot exist. If you
high, which science says cannot be
cannot exist. If you study
cannot exist. If you study wave
dynamics,
dynamics, a
dynamics, a wave
dynamics, a wave cannot
dynamics, a wave cannot be
dynamics, a wave cannot be 100
dynamics, a wave cannot be 100 ft
dynamics, a wave cannot be 100 ft high.
It's
It's not
dynamics, a wave cannot be 100 ft high.
It's not a
It's not a possibility.
dynamics, a wave cannot be 100 ft high.
It's not a possibility. So,
It's not a possibility. So, it
dynamics, a wave cannot be 100 ft high.
It's not a possibility. So, it was
alleged
alleged that
alleged that these
alleged that these sailors
alleged that these sailors have
alleged that these sailors have been
hitting
hitting the
alleged that these sailors have been
hitting the grog
hitting the grog a
alleged that these sailors have been
hitting the grog a little
hitting the grog a little too
alleged that these sailors have been
hitting the grog a little too hard.
except
except that
except that the
except that the ships
except that the ships went
except that the ships went down.
except that the ships went down. So
wasn't
wasn't just
except that the ships went down. So
wasn't just the
wasn't just the grog.
All right.
All right. So
All right. So the
All right. So the explanation
All right. So the explanation then
All right. So the explanation then uh
came
came about
All right. So the explanation then uh
came about through
uh
uh quantum
uh quantum mechanics
uh quantum mechanics and
uh quantum mechanics and uh
uh quantum mechanics and uh it
uh quantum mechanics and uh it is
uh quantum mechanics and uh it is not
understandable.
understandable. So
uh quantum mechanics and uh it is not
understandable. So even
understandable. So even 100
uh quantum mechanics and uh it is not
understandable. So even 100 foot
understandable. So even 100 foot waves
is
is not
is not understandable
is not understandable by
is not understandable by Newtonian
science.
science. It's
is not understandable by Newtonian
science. It's only
science. It's only understandable
is not understandable by Newtonian
science. It's only understandable by
quantum
quantum potentiality.
So
So when
quantum potentiality.
So when we
So when we talk
quantum potentiality.
So when we talk about
So when we talk about submicroscopic
when
when we
when we talk
when we talk about
when we talk about consciousness
when we talk about consciousness we're
talking
talking about
when we talk about consciousness we're
talking about energies
talking about energies of
when we talk about consciousness we're
talking about energies of such
talking about energies of such high
frequency
frequency that
frequency that they
frequency that they are
frequency that they are beyond
frequency that they are beyond the
physical
physical world.
frequency that they are beyond the
physical world. Okay.
So
So that
So that was
So that was the
So that was the famous
So that was the famous Copenhagen
conference.
conference. It
So that was the famous Copenhagen
conference. It caused
conference. It caused great
consternation
consternation because
it
it defied
consternation because
it defied the
it defied the law
consternation because
it defied the law of
it defied the law of causality
consternation because
it defied the law of causality for
it defied the law of causality for the
first
first time
first time in
first time in science.
first time in science. Heisenberg's
observation
observation then
first time in science. Heisenberg's
observation then caused
observation then caused a
first time in science. Heisenberg's
observation then caused a major
epistemologic
epistemologic ontologic
epistemologic ontologic philosophic
uh
uh metaphysical
epistemologic ontologic philosophic
uh metaphysical shift
uh metaphysical shift that
epistemologic ontologic philosophic
uh metaphysical shift that now
uh metaphysical shift that now what
bring
bring how
bring how to
bring how to account
bring how to account for
bring how to account for things
happening
happening was
bring how to account for things
happening was not
happening was not by
bring how to account for things
happening was not by causality.
All
All right.
The
The famous
All right.
The famous shred
The famous shred equations
All right.
The famous shred equations um
The famous shred equations um delineate
the
the state
the state of
the state of the
the state of the world
the state of the world the
the state of the world the quantum
the state of the world the quantum the
quantum
quantum state
the state of the world the quantum the
quantum state of
quantum state of reality
the state of the world the quantum the
quantum state of reality as
quantum state of reality as we
the state of the world the quantum the
quantum state of reality as we know
quantum state of reality as we know it.
There's
There's two
There's two shredding
There's two shredding equations
There's two shredding equations which
because
because I
There's two shredding equations which
because I love
because I love you
There's two shredding equations which
because I love you I
because I love you I did
There's two shredding equations which
because I love you I did not
because I love you I did not put
There's two shredding equations which
because I love you I did not put on
because I love you I did not put on the
board
board today.
board today. One's
board today. One's time
board today. One's time dependent,
board today. One's time dependent, the
other's
other's time
board today. One's time dependent, the
other's time independent.
other's time independent. And
board today. One's time dependent, the
other's time independent. And it
other's time independent. And it will
tell
tell you
tell you the
tell you the conditions
tell you the conditions of
tell you the conditions of a
tell you the conditions of a state
tell you the conditions of a state and
also
also what
tell you the conditions of a state and
also what it
also what it would
tell you the conditions of a state and
also what it would then
also what it would then be
tell you the conditions of a state and
also what it would then be in
also what it would then be in forward
tell you the conditions of a state and
also what it would then be in forward in
time.
The
The Heisenberg
time.
The Heisenberg phenomena
The Heisenberg phenomena however
time.
The Heisenberg phenomena however is
The Heisenberg phenomena however is that
once
once you
once you witness
once you witness it
once you witness it it
once you witness it it now
once you witness it it now changes
once you witness it it now changes and
when
when it
once you witness it it now changes and
when it changes
you
you end
you end up
you end up with
you end up with the
you end up with the direct
you end up with the direct process
you end up with the direct process the
direct
direct process.
you end up with the direct process the
direct process. So
direct process. So you
you end up with the direct process the
direct process. So you might
direct process. So you might say
you end up with the direct process the
direct process. So you might say the
shreddinger
shreddinger process
shreddinger process is
shreddinger process is how
shreddinger process is how you
shreddinger process is how you can
shreddinger process is how you can say
what
what it
shreddinger process is how you can say
what it is
what it is there
shreddinger process is how you can say
what it is there the
what it is there the direct
shreddinger process is how you can say
what it is there the direct process
mathematically
mathematically defines
mathematically defines what
mathematically defines what it
mathematically defines what it is
mathematically defines what it is now
but
but it's
mathematically defines what it is now
but it's the
but it's the high
mathematically defines what it is now
but it's the high the
but it's the high the the
mathematically defines what it is now
but it's the high the the Heisenberg
process
process that
process that collapses
process that collapses the
process that collapses the wave
function.
So
So reality
So reality can
So reality can be
So reality can be explained
So reality can be explained in
So reality can be explained in terms
So reality can be explained in terms of
events
events and
So reality can be explained in terms of
events and waves.
events and waves. And
So reality can be explained in terms of
events and waves. And what
events and waves. And what happens
So reality can be explained in terms of
events and waves. And what happens with
when
when with
when with consciousness
when with consciousness is
when with consciousness is that
consciousness
consciousness collapses
when with consciousness is that
consciousness collapses the
consciousness collapses the wave
function.
Now
that's
that's a
that's a little
that's a little difficult
that's a little difficult to
that's a little difficult to understand
but
but you
that's a little difficult to understand
but you don't
but you don't have
that's a little difficult to understand
but you don't have to.
Von
Von Nuyman
Von Nuyman made
Von Nuyman made it
Von Nuyman made it a
Von Nuyman made it a little
Von Nuyman made it a little simpler.
Von Nuyman made it a little simpler. He
more
more or
Von Nuyman made it a little simpler. He
more or less
more or less elaborated
Von Nuyman made it a little simpler. He
more or less elaborated the
more or less elaborated the Heisenberg
process.
process. See
process. See the
process. See the Heisenberg
process. See the Heisenberg process,
process. See the Heisenberg process, you
see,
see, by
process. See the Heisenberg process, you
see, by choice,
see, by choice, you've
process. See the Heisenberg process, you
see, by choice, you've already
see, by choice, you've already deted
responses,
responses, right?
responses, right? When
responses, right? When you
responses, right? When you choose
responses, right? When you choose to
responses, right? When you choose to buy
fruit,
fruit, you've
responses, right? When you choose to buy
fruit, you've already
fruit, you've already eliminated
everything
everything else
everything else in
everything else in the
everything else in the grocery
everything else in the grocery store.
So,
So, your
everything else in the grocery store.
So, your intention
So, your intention is
everything else in the grocery store.
So, your intention is already
So, your intention is already somewhat
specifying
specifying what
specifying what you're
specifying what you're going
specifying what you're going to
specifying what you're going to what
you're
you're going
specifying what you're going to what
you're going to
you're going to find
specifying what you're going to what
you're going to find by
you're going to find by limitation
specifying what you're going to what
you're going to find by limitation if
nothing
nothing else.
nothing else. Huh.
uh
uh so
nothing else. Huh.
uh so in
uh so in Henry
nothing else. Huh.
uh so in Henry Stap's
uh so in Henry Stap's exposition
nothing else. Huh.
uh so in Henry Stap's exposition of
uh so in Henry Stap's exposition of it
which
which is
which is currently
which is currently available
which is currently available on
which is currently available on the
internet
internet for
which is currently available on the
internet for those
internet for those are
which is currently available on the
internet for those are interested
internet for those are interested he's
which is currently available on the
internet for those are interested he's a
professor
professor of
professor of uh
professor of uh advanced
professor of uh advanced theoretical
physics
physics quantum
professor of uh advanced theoretical
physics quantum mechanics
physics quantum mechanics at
professor of uh advanced theoretical
physics quantum mechanics at Berkeley
and
and the
and the and
and the and the
and the and the United
and the and the United States
and the and the United States energy
commission
commission so
and the and the United States energy
commission so he
commission so he he's
and the and the United States energy
commission so he he's a
commission so he he's a very
knowledgeable
knowledgeable fellow
knowledgeable fellow and
knowledgeable fellow and he
knowledgeable fellow and he comes
knowledgeable fellow and he comes about
as
as close
knowledgeable fellow and he comes about
as close to
as close to it
knowledgeable fellow and he comes about
as close to it as
as close to it as I've
knowledgeable fellow and he comes about
as close to it as I've seen
as close to it as I've seen any
physicist
physicist come
physicist come to
physicist come to what
physicist come to what what
physicist come to what what it's
physicist come to what what it's really
all
all about
um
um so
um so vanoyman
um so vanoyman to
um so vanoyman to make
um so vanoyman to make this
um so vanoyman to make this easier
um so vanoyman to make this easier for
people
people divided
um so vanoyman to make this easier for
people divided into
people divided into process
um so vanoyman to make this easier for
people divided into process one
people divided into process one and
process
process two.
process two. Process
process two. Process two
is
the
the more
the more conventional
the more conventional sounding
the more conventional sounding physics
of
of shreddinger
and
and durk.
How
How do
and durk.
How do you
How do you explain
and durk.
How do you explain then
How do you explain then the
and durk.
How do you explain then the Heisenberg
phenomena?
phenomena? So
phenomena? So he
phenomena? So he divided
phenomena? So he divided the
phenomena? So he divided the process
phenomena? So he divided the process in
what's
what's called
phenomena? So he divided the process in
what's called process
what's called process one
phenomena? So he divided the process in
what's called process one which
what's called process one which is
phenomena? So he divided the process in
what's called process one which is the
mathematics
mathematics of
mathematics of it
mathematics of it turns
mathematics of it turns out
mathematics of it turns out kinesiology.
You
You remember
mathematics of it turns out kinesiology.
You remember in
You remember in the
mathematics of it turns out kinesiology.
You remember in the book
You remember in the book we
mathematics of it turns out kinesiology.
You remember in the book we said
You remember in the book we said power
versus
versus force
versus force revised
versus force revised edition
versus force revised edition at least
that
that the
versus force revised edition at least
that the answer
that the answer kines
versus force revised edition at least
that the answer kines logic
that the answer kines logic answer
versus force revised edition at least
that the answer kines logic answer is
not
not a
not a yes
not a yes or
not a yes or a
not a yes or a no.
not a yes or a no. It's
not a yes or a no. It's a
not a yes or a no. It's a yes
not a yes or a no. It's a yes or
not a yes or a no. It's a yes or a
not a yes or a no. It's a yes or a not
yes
the
the universe
the universe recognizes
the universe recognizes truth
and
and it
the universe recognizes truth
and it fails
and it fails to
the universe recognizes truth
and it fails to recognize
and it fails to recognize falsehood.
Consequently
Consequently if
Consequently if something
Consequently if something is
Consequently if something is true
Consequently if something is true your
arm
arm goes
Consequently if something is true your
arm goes strong.
arm goes strong. If
Consequently if something is true your
arm goes strong. If it's
arm goes strong. If it's false
Consequently if something is true your
arm goes strong. If it's false you
arm goes strong. If it's false you get
no
no response.
no response. So
no response. So that's
no response. So that's not
no response. So that's not a
no response. So that's not a no.
no response. So that's not a no. It's
no response. So that's not a no. It's a
it's
it's a
no response. So that's not a no. It's a
it's a not
it's a not yes.
Interestingly
Interestingly enough
Interestingly enough like
Interestingly enough like they
Interestingly enough like they were
uh
completely
completely correlated
completely correlated with
completely correlated with my
completely correlated with my own
understanding
understanding of
completely correlated with my own
understanding of it.
understanding of it. So
completely correlated with my own
understanding of it. So kinesiologic
response
response then
response then is
response then is either
response then is either a
response then is either a yes
response then is either a yes or
response then is either a yes or a
response then is either a yes or a not
yes.
yes. These
response then is either a yes or a not
yes. These are
yes. These are the
response then is either a yes or a not
yes. These are the only
yes. These are the only two
possibilities
possibilities and
possibilities and the
possibilities and the response
possibilities and the response is
possibilities and the response is set
possibilities and the response is set by
the
the state
possibilities and the response is set by
the state of
the state of the
possibilities and the response is set by
the state of the universe.
the state of the universe. So
Henry
Henry Stap
Henry Stap says
Henry Stap says the
Henry Stap says the universe
Henry Stap says the universe is
Henry Stap says the universe is a
repository
repository of
Henry Stap says the universe is a
repository of information,
repository of information, a
Henry Stap says the universe is a
repository of information, a quantum
state,
state, a
state, a wave
state, a wave function.
And
And I
state, a wave function.
And I didn't
And I didn't put
state, a wave function.
And I didn't put it
And I didn't put it in
state, a wave function.
And I didn't put it in here,
And I didn't put it in here, but
consciousness
consciousness is
consciousness is collapses
consciousness is collapses the
consciousness is collapses the wave
function,
function, which
consciousness is collapses the wave
function, which is
function, which is how
consciousness is collapses the wave
function, which is how you
function, which is how you experience
things.
things. It's
things. It's a
things. It's a potentiality.
things. It's a potentiality. By
intention,
intention, you've
things. It's a potentiality. By
intention, you've changed
intention, you've changed collapsed
things. It's a potentiality. By
intention, you've changed collapsed the
wave
wave function
wave function into
wave function into experience.
Consequently,
Consequently, a
wave function into experience.
Consequently, a group
Consequently, a group like
wave function into experience.
Consequently, a group like this
consistently
affects
affects the
consistently
affects the entire
affects the entire field
consistently
affects the entire field of
consciousness
of
of humanity.
A
A very
A very powerful
A very powerful group
like
like this
A very powerful group
like this has
like this has the
A very powerful group
like this has the power
like this has the power to
A very powerful group
like this has the power to affect
the
the consciousness
the consciousness level
the consciousness level of
the consciousness level of all
the consciousness level of all of
mankind.
We
We have
We have permission
We have permission to
We have permission to ask
We have permission to ask that
We have permission to ask that that
We have permission to ask that that is
We have permission to ask that that is a
fact.
If
If we
If we had
If we had time,
If we had time, we
If we had time, we could
If we had time, we could do
If we had time, we could do the
mathematics
mathematics of
If we had time, we could do the
mathematics of the
mathematics of the degree
If we had time, we could do the
mathematics of the degree to
mathematics of the degree to which
If we had time, we could do the
mathematics of the degree to which we
affected
affected except
affected except it's
affected except it's based
affected except it's based on
potentialities.
potentialities. Potentialities.
So
So in
So in quantum
So in quantum mechanics,
So in quantum mechanics, you're
So in quantum mechanics, you're dealing
with
with potentialities.
Now
Now out
Now out of
Now out of the
Now out of the Copenhagen
Now out of the Copenhagen conference
Now out of the Copenhagen conference in
which
which the
Now out of the Copenhagen conference in
which the advanced
which the advanced theoretical
physicists
Schrader
Schrader Boore
physicists
Schrader Boore and
Schrader Boore and Durac
physicists
Schrader Boore and Durac others
Schrader Boore and Durac others like
that
Eisen
Eisen Einstein
that
Eisen Einstein was
Eisen Einstein was bothered
that
Eisen Einstein was bothered by
Eisen Einstein was bothered by trying
that
Eisen Einstein was bothered by trying to
put
put consciousness
put consciousness in
put consciousness in with
put consciousness in with physics.
put consciousness in with physics. He
said
said I
put consciousness in with physics. He
said I prefer
said I prefer to
put consciousness in with physics. He
said I prefer to think
said I prefer to think that
put consciousness in with physics. He
said I prefer to think that there's
said I prefer to think that there's an
independent
independent physical
independent physical universe
independent physical universe out
independent physical universe out there
independent
independent of
independent physical universe out there
independent of man's
independent of man's consciousness.
But
But you
But you see
But you see what
But you see what quantum
But you see what quantum mechanics
But you see what quantum mechanics is.
It's
It's not
But you see what quantum mechanics is.
It's not about
It's not about the
But you see what quantum mechanics is.
It's not about the world.
It's not about the world. It's
But you see what quantum mechanics is.
It's not about the world. It's about
It's not about the world. It's about our
knowingness
knowingness of
knowingness of the
knowingness of the world.
knowingness of the world. Our
knowingness
knowingness of
knowingness of the world. Our
knowingness of the
knowingness of the world.
knowingness of the world. Our
knowingness of the world. You
knowingness of the world. You cannot
know
know the
know the world.
know the world. Nobody
know the world. Nobody here
know the world. Nobody here can
know the world. Nobody here can know
know the world. Nobody here can know the
world.
world. Not
know the world. Nobody here can know the
world. Not knowable.
You
You can
You can only
You can only know
You can only know your
You can only know your information
You can only know your information about
the
the world.
You can only know your information about
the world. Oh,
the world. Oh, the
You can only know your information about
the world. Oh, the information
the world. Oh, the information your
senses
senses give
senses give you,
senses give you, your
senses give you, your memory
senses give you, your memory gives
senses give you, your memory gives you,
your
your mother
senses give you, your memory gives you,
your mother gives
your mother gives you,
senses give you, your memory gives you,
your mother gives you, CBS
your mother gives you, CBS News
senses give you, your memory gives you,
your mother gives you, CBS News gives
you,
you, you
you, you can
you, you can only
you, you can only experience
you, you can only experience your
you, you can only experience your own
senses
senses of
you, you can only experience your own
senses of what
senses of what you
you, you can only experience your own
senses of what you think
senses of what you think is
you, you can only experience your own
senses of what you think is real.
transitory
transitory perceptions
transitory perceptions is
transitory perceptions is all
transitory perceptions is all you
transitory perceptions is all you can
say.
Einstein
Einstein couldn't
Einstein couldn't make
Einstein couldn't make the
Einstein couldn't make the jump.
Einstein couldn't make the jump. He
says,
says, "I
I
I cannot
I cannot accept
I cannot accept that
I cannot accept that there's
I cannot accept that there's not
I cannot accept that there's not an
independent
independent objective
I cannot accept that there's not an
independent objective universe
independent objective universe existent
on
on man's
on man's consciousness.
So
So 499
on man's consciousness.
So 499 is
So 499 is the
on man's consciousness.
So 499 is the limit
So 499 is the limit limit
on man's consciousness.
So 499 is the limit limit between
form
form and
form and non-formm
form and non-formm between
form and non-formm between duality
form and non-formm between duality and
non-duality.
Now
Now we
Now we know
Now we know why
Now we know why Einstein
Now we know why Einstein was
Now we know why Einstein was 499.
Einstein
Einstein at
Now we know why Einstein was 499.
Einstein at the
Einstein at the same
Now we know why Einstein was 499.
Einstein at the same time
Einstein at the same time was
Now we know why Einstein was 499.
Einstein at the same time was religious.
Religious
Religious is
Religious is different
Religious is different than
Religious is different than subjective
spiritual
spiritual experiential.
And
And so
And so most
And so most of
And so most of the
And so most of the students
And so most of the students of
And so most of the students of science
and
and consciousness
And so most of the students of science
and consciousness that
and consciousness that I
And so most of the students of science
and consciousness that I read
are
are quite
are quite brilliant
are quite brilliant and
are quite brilliant and their
mathematics
mathematics is
are quite brilliant and their
mathematics is very
mathematics is very impressive
are quite brilliant and their
mathematics is very impressive and
mathematics is very impressive and I
are quite brilliant and their
mathematics is very impressive and I go
wow
wow and
and
and it
wow and
and it can
and it can it
wow and
and it can it hits
and it can it hits right
wow and
and it can it hits right up
and it can it hits right up against
wow and
and it can it hits right up against 499
just
just can't
just can't seem
just can't seem to
just can't seem to make
just can't seem to make that
just can't seem to make that jump
the
the jump
just can't seem to make that jump
the jump to
the jump to the
just can't seem to make that jump
the jump to the subjective
the jump to the subjective experiential
as
as as
as as the
as as the radical
as as the radical reality
as as the radical reality out
as as the radical reality out of
as as the radical reality out of which
you
you can
as as the radical reality out of which
you can state
you can state that
as as the radical reality out of which
you can state that you're
you can state that you're objective.
How
How can
How can you
How can you state
How can you state that
How can you state that you're
How can you state that you're objective
and
and scientific?
How can you state that you're objective
and scientific? You
and scientific? You can
How can you state that you're objective
and scientific? You can only
and scientific? You can only do
How can you state that you're objective
and scientific? You can only do that
and scientific? You can only do that out
of
of a
of a subjective
of a subjective opinion
of a subjective opinion that
of a subjective opinion that that's
what's
what's so
of a subjective opinion that that's
what's so correct.
So
So the
So the basis
So the basis of
So the basis of all
So the basis of all reality
So the basis of all reality then
So the basis of all reality then is
subjectivity.
Which
Which is
Which is the
Which is the name
Which is the name of
Which is the name of the
Which is the name of the new
Which is the name of the new book?
I
What's
What's the
What's the name
What's the name of
What's the name of the
What's the name of the book?
What's the name of the book? Radical
subjectivity.
subjectivity. Isn't
What's the name of the book? Radical
subjectivity. Isn't that
subjectivity. Isn't that it?
>> Huh?
No,
No, the
>> Huh?
No, the book
No, the book itself
>> Huh?
No, the book itself it
No, the book itself it says
>> Huh?
No, the book itself it says I
No, the book itself it says I and
>> Huh?
No, the book itself it says I and then
it
it says
>> what's
>> what's the
it says
>> what's the name
>> what's the name of
it says
>> what's the name of it?
>> Subjectivity.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, reality
>> Subjectivity.
>> Oh, reality and
>> Oh, reality and subjectivity.
All right.
>> Reality
>> Reality and
All right.
>> Reality and subjectivity.
>> Reality and subjectivity. Yes,
All right.
>> Reality and subjectivity. Yes, that's
>> Reality and subjectivity. Yes, that's so
there
there is
there is nothing
there is nothing but
there is nothing but subjectivity,
folks.
folks. Nothing
there is nothing but subjectivity,
folks. Nothing else
folks. Nothing else out
there is nothing but subjectivity,
folks. Nothing else out there.
All right.
All right. So,
All right. So, I
All right. So, I just
All right. So, I just thought
All right. So, I just thought you'd
All right. So, I just thought you'd like
to
to be
All right. So, I just thought you'd like
to be able
to be able to
All right. So, I just thought you'd like
to be able to say
to be able to say to
All right. So, I just thought you'd like
to be able to say to your
to be able to say to your friends
All right. So, I just thought you'd like
to be able to say to your friends that
the
the kinesiologic
response
response comes
the kinesiologic
response comes out
response comes out of
the kinesiologic
response comes out of advanced
theoretical
theoretical physics.
theoretical physics. And
theoretical physics. And to
theoretical physics. And to understand
it,
it, you
theoretical physics. And to understand
it, you really
it, you really have
theoretical physics. And to understand
it, you really have to
it, you really have to understand
quantum
quantum mechanics.
quantum mechanics. If
quantum mechanics. If you
quantum mechanics. If you have
quantum mechanics. If you have any
arguments
arguments about
quantum mechanics. If you have any
arguments about it,
arguments about it, you
quantum mechanics. If you have any
arguments about it, you really
arguments about it, you really have
quantum mechanics. If you have any
arguments about it, you really have to
understand
understand quantum
understand quantum mechanics.
understand quantum mechanics. and
understand quantum mechanics. and tell
me
me how
understand quantum mechanics. and tell
me how it
me how it deviates
understand quantum mechanics. and tell
me how it deviates from
me how it deviates from the
understand quantum mechanics. and tell
me how it deviates from the shorter
Heisenberg
Heisenberg direct
Heisenberg direct process
Heisenberg direct process and
Heisenberg direct process and escapes
the
the fondman
Heisenberg direct process and escapes
the fondman process
the fondman process one
Heisenberg direct process and escapes
the fondman process one if
the fondman process one if you
Heisenberg direct process and escapes
the fondman process one if you can
explain
explain that
explain that then
explain that then I'll
explain that then I'll go
explain that then I'll go with
explain that then I'll go with you
explain that then I'll go with you yeah
it's
it's just
explain that then I'll go with you yeah
it's just a
it's just a pokey
explain that then I'll go with you yeah
it's just a pokey toky
it's just a pokey toky thing
explain that then I'll go with you yeah
it's just a pokey toky thing you
it's just a pokey toky thing you know
all
all right
all right anybody
all right anybody interested
all right anybody interested then
all right anybody interested then I
point
point out
all right anybody interested then I
point out you
point out you again
all right anybody interested then I
point out you again Henry
point out you again Henry staff
all right anybody interested then I
point out you again Henry staff I
point out you again Henry staff I like
his
his work
his work he's
his work he's also
his work he's also right
his work he's also right on
his work he's also right on the
his work he's also right on the verge
right
right on
his work he's also right on the verge
right on the
right on the verge
his work he's also right on the verge
right on the verge and
right on the verge and u
uh
uh all
uh all right
uh all right so
uh all right so the
uh all right so the problem
uh all right so the problem then
uh all right so the problem then in
all
all spiritual
uh all right so the problem then in
all spiritual work.
all spiritual work. The
uh all right so the problem then in
all spiritual work. The problem
all spiritual work. The problem in
jumping
jumping from
jumping from duality
jumping from duality nonduality
jumping from duality nonduality is
jumping from duality nonduality is a
paradigm
paradigm is
jumping from duality nonduality is a
paradigm is a
paradigm is a paradigm
jumping from duality nonduality is a
paradigm is a paradigm jump.
So
So the
So the quantum
So the quantum leap
So the quantum leap about
So the quantum leap about which
So the quantum leap about which people
like
like to
So the quantum leap about which people
like to write
like to write about
So the quantum leap about which people
like to write about but
like to write about but don't
So the quantum leap about which people
like to write about but don't experience
or
or they
or they wouldn't
or they wouldn't be
or they wouldn't be writing
or they wouldn't be writing about
or they wouldn't be writing about it
is
is a
or they wouldn't be writing about it
is a leap
is a leap from
or they wouldn't be writing about it
is a leap from the
is a leap from the sense
or they wouldn't be writing about it
is a leap from the sense of
is a leap from the sense of reality
or they wouldn't be writing about it
is a leap from the sense of reality from
the
the linear
the linear to
the linear to the
the linear to the nonlinear.
the linear to the nonlinear. All
the linear to the nonlinear. All right.
Has
Has anybody
the linear to the nonlinear. All right.
Has anybody got
Has anybody got any
the linear to the nonlinear. All right.
Has anybody got any questions?
I
I was
I was prepared
I was prepared to
I was prepared to do
I was prepared to do the
I was prepared to do the straighter
equations,
equations, but
I was prepared to do the straighter
equations, but then
equations, but then I
I was prepared to do the straighter
equations, but then I thought,
no,
no, I
no, I don't
no, I don't think
no, I don't think I'll
no, I don't think I'll do
no, I don't think I'll do them
no, I don't think I'll do them this
morning.
Anyway,
Anyway, it
Anyway, it is
Anyway, it is fun.
Anyway, it is fun. Um,
Anyway, it is fun. Um, if
Anyway, it is fun. Um, if you
Anyway, it is fun. Um, if you try
Anyway, it is fun. Um, if you try to
find
find a
Anyway, it is fun. Um, if you try to
find a primmer
find a primmer on
Anyway, it is fun. Um, if you try to
find a primmer on quantum
find a primmer on quantum mechanics,
there
there aren't
there aren't any.
So
So that's
there aren't any.
So that's uh
So that's uh the
there aren't any.
So that's uh the that's
So that's uh the that's the
there aren't any.
So that's uh the that's the reference
which
which Brock
which Brock uh
which Brock uh got
which Brock uh got got
which Brock uh got got for
which Brock uh got got for us
which Brock uh got got for us off
which Brock uh got got for us off the
which Brock uh got got for us off the uh
internet
internet is
which Brock uh got got for us off the uh
internet is Henry
internet is Henry Stab.
which Brock uh got got for us off the uh
internet is Henry Stab. He's
internet is Henry Stab. He's also
uh
uh writes
uh writes many
uh writes many books
uh writes many books uh
uh writes many books uh which
uh writes many books uh which I
uh writes many books uh which I haven't
read
read but
uh writes many books uh which I haven't
read but they
read but they must
uh writes many books uh which I haven't
read but they must be
read but they must be quite
uh writes many books uh which I haven't
read but they must be quite interesting.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So there
All right. So there we
All right. So there we have
All right. So there we have the
scientific
scientific correlation.
All right. So there we have the
scientific correlation. Then
scientific correlation. Then the
scientific
scientific correlation
that
that we're
scientific correlation
that we're dealing
that we're dealing in
scientific correlation
that we're dealing in likelihoods,
probabilities
probabilities and
probabilities and the
probabilities and the importance
probabilities and the importance of
probabilities and the importance of of
it
it to
probabilities and the importance of of
it to us
it to us is
probabilities and the importance of of
it to us is that
it to us is that and
probabilities and the importance of of
it to us is that and and
it to us is that and and to
probabilities and the importance of of
it to us is that and and to me
it to us is that and and to me in
probabilities and the importance of of
it to us is that and and to me in all
scientific
scientific research
scientific research is
scientific research is that
scientific research is that the
scientific research is that the field
scientific research is that the field is
often
often more
scientific research is that the field is
often more powerful
often more powerful than
scientific research is that the field is
often more powerful than the
often more powerful than the content.
The
The context
The context is
The context is often
The context is often more
The context is often more powerful
The context is often more powerful than
the
the content.
That's
That's why
That's why double
That's why double blind
That's why double blind uh
That's why double blind uh double
That's why double blind uh double blind
trials
trials and
That's why double blind uh double blind
trials and all
trials and all the
That's why double blind uh double blind
trials and all the scientific
trials and all the scientific research
that
that you
that you read
that you read is
that you read is all
that you read is all with
that you read is all with a
that you read is all with a grain
that you read is all with a grain of
salt
salt because
that you read is all with a grain of
salt because it
salt because it always
that you read is all with a grain of
salt because it always ignores
salt because it always ignores context
and
and instead
and instead it
and instead it deals
and instead it deals with
and instead it deals with uh
and instead it deals with uh numbers
and instead it deals with uh numbers and
groupings
groupings that
and instead it deals with uh numbers and
groupings that are
groupings that are really
and instead it deals with uh numbers and
groupings that are really probably
groupings that are really probably not
groupable.
The
The intention
groupable.
The intention flick
The intention flick that
groupable.
The intention flick that back
The intention flick that back on
groupable.
The intention flick that back on again.
What
What you
What you see
What you see what
What you see what you
What you see what you understand
What you see what you understand is
What you see what you understand is that
intention
intention already
What you see what you understand is that
intention already determines
intention already determines your
result.
Consequently,
any
any research
any research that
any research that anybody
any research that anybody proposes,
any research that anybody proposes, I
can
can tell
any research that anybody proposes, I
can tell them
can tell them what
any research that anybody proposes, I
can tell them what the
can tell them what the result
any research that anybody proposes, I
can tell them what the result is
can tell them what the result is going
to
to be
to be already.
to be already. Before
to be already. Before the
to be already. Before the research
to be already. Before the research is
done,
done, I
to be already. Before the research is
done, I already
done, I already know
to be already. Before the research is
done, I already know the
done, I already know the answer.
to be already. Before the research is
done, I already know the answer. Why?
Because
intention,
the
the intention
the intention is
the intention is so
the intention is so powerful
the intention is so powerful that
the intention is so powerful that it
already
already determines
the intention is so powerful that it
already determines what
already determines what you're
the intention is so powerful that it
already determines what you're going
already determines what you're going to
see.
see. Huh?
This
This is
see. Huh?
This is out
This is out of
see. Huh?
This is out of awareness
This is out of awareness because
see. Huh?
This is out of awareness because it's
This is out of awareness because it's in
the
the nonlinear
field.
A
A brief
A brief moment
A brief moment with
A brief moment with the
A brief moment with the scientist
A brief moment with the scientist and
A brief moment with the scientist and he
outlines
outlines what
A brief moment with the scientist and he
outlines what he's
outlines what he's going
A brief moment with the scientist and he
outlines what he's going to
outlines what he's going to research.
I'm
I'm going
I'm going to
I'm going to tell
I'm going to tell you
I'm going to tell you what
I'm going to tell you what he's
I'm going to tell you what he's going
I'm going to tell you what he's going to
find
find already.
For
For one
For one thing,
For one thing, I
For one thing, I know
For one thing, I know who's
For one thing, I know who's funding
For one thing, I know who's funding him.
If
If he
For one thing, I know who's funding him.
If he ain't
If he ain't going
For one thing, I know who's funding him.
If he ain't going to
If he ain't going to find
For one thing, I know who's funding him.
If he ain't going to find out,
If he ain't going to find out, he
For one thing, I know who's funding him.
If he ain't going to find out, he ain't
getting
getting funded.
What
What he's
getting funded.
What he's going
What he's going to
getting funded.
What he's going to tell
What he's going to tell you
getting funded.
What he's going to tell you out
What he's going to tell you out of
research
that
that taking
research
that taking vitamin
that taking vitamin A
and
and a
and a gram
and a gram a
and a gram a day
and a gram a day of
and a gram a day of vitamin
and a gram a day of vitamin C
and a gram a day of vitamin C cancels
out
out most
and a gram a day of vitamin C cancels
out most of
out most of the
and a gram a day of vitamin C cancels
out most of the negative
out most of the negative effects
and a gram a day of vitamin C cancels
out most of the negative effects of
smoking.
Nobody's
Nobody's going
smoking.
Nobody's going to
Nobody's going to get
smoking.
Nobody's going to get funded
Nobody's going to get funded for
smoking.
Nobody's going to get funded for that.
It's
It's not
It's not politically
It's not politically correct.
Nobody's
Nobody's going
It's not politically correct.
Nobody's going to
Nobody's going to tell
It's not politically correct.
Nobody's going to tell you
Nobody's going to tell you that
50%
50% of
50% of the
50% of the people
50% of the people have
50% of the people have heart
50% of the people have heart attacks
have
have normal
50% of the people have heart attacks
have normal cholesterol.
That
That does
That does not
That does not pull
That does not pull big
That does not pull big grants,
That does not pull big grants, folks.
So
So you
That does not pull big grants, folks.
So you see
So you see science
That does not pull big grants, folks.
So you see science has
So you see science has its
That does not pull big grants, folks.
So you see science has its vested
interests.
interests. The
interests. The institute
interests. The institute for
interests. The institute for something
or other
or other science
interests. The institute for something
or other science and
or other science and the
interests. The institute for something
or other science and the public
or other science and the public interest
or
or something
or something always
or something always has
or something always has a
or something always has a politicized
positionality.
positionality. So
or something always has a politicized
positionality. So as
positionality. So as you
or something always has a politicized
positionality. So as you get
positionality. So as you get more
spiritually
spiritually advanced
spiritually advanced your
spiritually advanced your own
discernment
discernment uh
spiritually advanced your own
discernment uh expands
discernment uh expands but
spiritually advanced your own
discernment uh expands but you
discernment uh expands but you begin
spiritually advanced your own
discernment uh expands but you begin to
realize
realize that
realize that all
realize that all these
realize that all these people
realize that all these people have
realize that all these people have an
axe
axe to
realize that all these people have an
axe to grind.
axe to grind. They
realize that all these people have an
axe to grind. They have
axe to grind. They have a
realize that all these people have an
axe to grind. They have a vested
interest.
Um
Um they
interest.
Um they have
Um they have an
interest.
Um they have an oxagore.
They
They have
They have a
They have a check
They have a check to
They have a check to expect.
You
You tell
They have a check to expect.
You tell me
You tell me who's
They have a check to expect.
You tell me who's doing
You tell me who's doing it
They have a check to expect.
You tell me who's doing it who
You tell me who's doing it who funded
it,
it, I'll
it, I'll tell
it, I'll tell you
it, I'll tell you the
it, I'll tell you the result
it, I'll tell you the result already.
Uh
Uh however,
it, I'll tell you the result already.
Uh however, we
Uh however, we can
it, I'll tell you the result already.
Uh however, we can do
Uh however, we can do it
it, I'll tell you the result already.
Uh however, we can do it more
Uh however, we can do it more accurately
by
by kinesiologic
by kinesiologic testing.
This
This is
by kinesiologic testing.
This is a
This is a profound
by kinesiologic testing.
This is a profound significance
This is a profound significance in
society
society where
let's
let's say
society where
let's say the
let's say the government
society where
let's say the government is
let's say the government is looking
society where
let's say the government is looking at
let's say the government is looking at a
certain
certain proposition
certain proposition whether
certain proposition whether to
certain proposition whether to put
certain proposition whether to put it
into
into law.
certain proposition whether to put it
into law. You
into law. You can
certain proposition whether to put it
into law. You can predict
into law. You can predict in
certain proposition whether to put it
into law. You can predict in advance
what
what the
what the consequence
what the consequence will
what the consequence will be
what the consequence will be to
what the consequence will be to society.
You
You can
what the consequence will be to society.
You can guarantee
You can guarantee what
what the consequence will be to society.
You can guarantee what the
You can guarantee what the consequence
will
will be
will be to
will be to society
will be to society by
will be to society by calibrating
will be to society by calibrating the
level
level of
will be to society by calibrating the
level of the
level of the principle
which
which is
which is about
which is about to
which is about to be
which is about to be instituted
which is about to be instituted in
which is about to be instituted in law.
it
it will
which is about to be instituted in law.
it will either
it will either be
which is about to be instituted in law.
it will either be destructive
it will either be destructive or
constructive.
So
So the
constructive.
So the kinesiologic
So the kinesiologic response
constructive.
So the kinesiologic response then
So the kinesiologic response then has
quite
quite profound
quite profound implications
quite profound implications for
quite profound implications for research
for
delineating
delineating the
delineating the real
delineating the real from
delineating the real from the
delineating the real from the unreal
delineating the real from the unreal in
the
the ordinary
delineating the real from the unreal in
the ordinary world.
the ordinary world. And
delineating the real from the unreal in
the ordinary world. And we
the ordinary world. And we we're
delineating the real from the unreal in
the ordinary world. And we we're not
going
going to
going to talk
going to talk about
going to talk about the
going to talk about the world
going to talk about the world today.
going to talk about the world today. The
world
world is
going to talk about the world today. The
world is lecture
world is lecture number
going to talk about the world today. The
world is lecture number three
world is lecture number three or
something.
today
today has
something.
today has to
today has to do
something.
today has to do with
today has to do with personal
something.
today has to do with personal life
today has to do with personal life and
but
but in
but in order
but in order to
but in order to utilize
but in order to utilize our
but in order to utilize our our
but in order to utilize our our tools
and
and techniques
but in order to utilize our our tools
and techniques which
and techniques which are
but in order to utilize our our tools
and techniques which are somewhat
and techniques which are somewhat based
on
on the
on the kinesiologic
on the kinesiologic response
on the kinesiologic response primarily
for
for research
on the kinesiologic response primarily
for research purposes.
for research purposes. So
I
I hope
I hope everybody
I hope everybody likes
I hope everybody likes this.
I hope everybody likes this. Let's
I hope everybody likes this. Let's see.
Let's
Let's see
I hope everybody likes this. Let's see.
Let's see if
Let's see if everybody
I hope everybody likes this. Let's see.
Let's see if everybody likes
Let's see if everybody likes this.
I hope everybody likes this. Let's see.
Let's see if everybody likes this. this
uh
uh we
uh we haven't
uh we haven't confirmed
uh we haven't confirmed that
uh we haven't confirmed that this
uh we haven't confirmed that this is
uh we haven't confirmed that this is a
correl
correl this
uh we haven't confirmed that this is a
correl this is
correl this is this
uh we haven't confirmed that this is a
correl this is this is
correl this is this is uh
uh we haven't confirmed that this is a
correl this is this is uh the
correl this is this is uh the truth
uh we haven't confirmed that this is a
correl this is this is uh the truth of
what
what the
what the kinesiological
what the kinesiological response
all
all right
what the kinesiological response
all right so
all right so this
what the kinesiological response
all right so this quantum
all right so this quantum explanation
then
then is
then is the
then is the explanation
then is the explanation of
then is the explanation of the
then is the explanation of the kines
kinesiologic
kinesiologic response
then is the explanation of the kines
kinesiologic response you
kinesiologic response you have
then is the explanation of the kines
kinesiologic response you have a
potentiality
potentiality the
potentiality the question
potentiality the question then
potentiality the question then is
confronting
confronting he
potentiality the question then is
confronting he likes
confronting he likes to
potentiality the question then is
confronting he likes to call
confronting he likes to call it
potentiality the question then is
confronting he likes to call it nature
nature
nature with
nature with it
nature with it and
nature with it and consciousness
nature with it and consciousness with
it.
If
If it's
If it's true,
If it's true, it
If it's true, it collapses
If it's true, it collapses the
If it's true, it collapses the wave
function.
And
And now
And now reality
And now reality has
And now reality has changed.
And now reality has changed. Every
And now reality has changed. Every time
we
we do
And now reality has changed. Every time
we do a
we do a kinesiologic
And now reality has changed. Every time
we do a kinesiologic test,
we do a kinesiologic test, we
And now reality has changed. Every time
we do a kinesiologic test, we have
changed
the
the universe.
We
We change
We change the
We change the universe
We change the universe a
We change the universe a lot
We change the universe a lot before
breakfast
breakfast even,
We change the universe a lot before
breakfast even, don't
breakfast even, don't we?
The
The mere
The mere asking
The mere asking of
The mere asking of the
The mere asking of the question
The mere asking of the question has
already
already changed
The mere asking of the question has
already changed things.
already changed things. You
The mere asking of the question has
already changed things. You understand?
Does
Does everybody
Does everybody get
Does everybody get what
Does everybody get what I'm
Does everybody get what I'm saying?
Anybody
Anybody got
Does everybody get what I'm saying?
Anybody got any
Anybody got any questions
Does everybody get what I'm saying?
Anybody got any questions about
Anybody got any questions about it?
Does everybody get what I'm saying?
Anybody got any questions about it? I
want
want to
want to make
want to make it
want to make it I
want to make it I want
want to make it I want everybody
want to make it I want everybody to
want to make it I want everybody to be
really
really clear
want to make it I want everybody to be
really clear on
really clear on it.
want to make it I want everybody to be
really clear on it. Okay,
we
we can
we can um
we can um check
we can um check out
we can um check out political
we can um check out political events.
Let's
Let's take
we can um check out political events.
Let's take uh
Let's take uh what
we can um check out political events.
Let's take uh what was
Let's take uh what was the
we can um check out political events.
Let's take uh what was the biggest
event?
event? Did
event? Did George
event? Did George Bush.
event? Did George Bush. Let's
event? Did George Bush. Let's do
event? Did George Bush. Let's do we
event? Did George Bush. Let's do we have
permission
permission to
event? Did George Bush. Let's do we have
permission to do
permission to do Bush's
event? Did George Bush. Let's do we have
permission to do Bush's address
permission to do Bush's address to
event? Did George Bush. Let's do we have
permission to do Bush's address to the
nation.
nation. He
nation. He says
>> Bush's
>> Bush's address
nation. He says
>> Bush's address to
>> Bush's address to the
nation. He says
>> Bush's address to the nation.
>> Bush's address to the nation. We
nation. He says
>> Bush's address to the nation. We have
permission
permission to
permission to do
permission to do that.
permission to do that. He's
permission to do that. He's over
permission to do that. He's over 450
permission to do that. He's over 450 460
465.
Bush's
Bush's address
Bush's address to
Bush's address to the
Bush's address to the nation
Bush's address to the nation was
Bush's address to the nation was about
which
which one?
Bush's address to the nation was about
which one? What
which one? What do
Bush's address to the nation was about
which one? What do they
which one? What do they call
Bush's address to the nation was about
which one? What do they call that?
which one? What do they call that? The
>> UN
>> State
>> State of
>> UN
>> State of the
>> State of the Union
>> UN
>> State of the Union State
>> State of the Union State of
>> UN
>> State of the Union State of the
>> State of the Union State of the Union
was
was over
was over 460,
was over 460, 465,
was over 460, 465, 468
about
about 468.
Presidents
Presidents tend
Presidents tend to
Presidents tend to calibrate
Presidents tend to calibrate around
Presidents tend to calibrate around 450.
So
So that's
Presidents tend to calibrate around 450.
So that's the
So that's the level
Presidents tend to calibrate around 450.
So that's the level of
So that's the level of reliability
Presidents tend to calibrate around 450.
So that's the level of reliability of
science
science and
science and truth
science and truth as
science and truth as we
science and truth as we understand
science and truth as we understand it
science and truth as we understand it in
our
our society.
science and truth as we understand it in
our society. In
our society. In fact,
science and truth as we understand it in
our society. In fact, that's
our society. In fact, that's quite
science and truth as we understand it in
our society. In fact, that's quite a
quite
quite high
quite high level
quite high level of
quite high level of it
of
of truth
quite high level of it
of truth and
of truth and reason
quite high level of it
of truth and reason and
of truth and reason and logic
quite high level of it
of truth and reason and logic and
decency
decency and
decency and the
decency and the solid
decency and the solid framework
decency and the solid framework of
decency and the solid framework of that
holds
holds the
decency and the solid framework of that
holds the fabric
holds the fabric of
decency and the solid framework of that
holds the fabric of society
holds the fabric of society together.
decency and the solid framework of that
holds the fabric of society together. So
that
that reflects
that reflects that
that reflects that level.
that reflects that level. Yeah.
>> What
>> What do
that reflects that level. Yeah.
>> What do you
>> What do you think?
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't know
>> I don't know that
>> I don't know that I
>> I don't know that I could
>> I don't know that I could do
>> I don't know that I could do that.
>> I don't know that I could do that. Um
the
the policy
>> I don't know that I could do that. Um
the policy because
the policy because they
>> I don't know that I could do that. Um
the policy because they don't
the policy because they don't really
have
have a
have a policy.
have a policy. They
have a policy. They have
>> speech.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, Powell.
>> Oh, Powell. Oh,
>> Oh, Powell. Oh, Powell.
>> General.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yes.
>> Oh, yes. Yes.
>> Oh, yes. Yes. Yes.
>> Oh, yes. Yes. Yes. Okay.
>> Was
>> Was truthful
>> Oh, yes. Yes. Yes. Okay.
>> Was truthful or
>> Was truthful or not?
>> Okay.
>> Okay. We
>> Okay. We have
>> Okay. We have permission
>> Okay. We have permission to
>> Okay. We have permission to do
>> Okay. We have permission to do Powell.
Paul's
Paul's speech
>> Okay. We have permission to do Powell.
Paul's speech is
Paul's speech is integrous
>> Okay. We have permission to do Powell.
Paul's speech is integrous over
Paul's speech is integrous over 450,
460,
460, 465.
460, 465. It's
460, 465. It's 465.
460, 465. It's 465. So
460, 465. It's 465. So they're
reflecting
reflecting that
460, 465. It's 465. So they're
reflecting that level
reflecting that level of
460, 465. It's 465. So they're
reflecting that level of truth
of
of verifiable
of verifiable likelihood,
of verifiable likelihood, an
of verifiable likelihood, an advanced
degree
degree of
of verifiable likelihood, an advanced
degree of certitude.
It's
It's the
It's the world
It's the world of
It's the world of logic,
It's the world of logic, science,
physics,
physics, chemistry.
It's the world of logic, science,
physics, chemistry. It's
physics, chemistry. It's the
It's the world of logic, science,
physics, chemistry. It's the world
physics, chemistry. It's the world of
pretty
pretty reliable
reliability.
reliability. Let's
pretty reliable
reliability. Let's do
reliability. Let's do what
pretty reliable
reliability. Let's do what medicine
reliability. Let's do what medicine is.
Clinical
Clinical medicine
Clinical medicine calibrate.
Clinical medicine calibrate. We
Clinical medicine calibrate. We have
permission.
permission. Calibrates
Clinical medicine calibrate. We have
permission. Calibrates over
permission. Calibrates over 400
Clinical medicine calibrate. We have
permission. Calibrates over 400 or
permission. Calibrates over 400 or 10
405 410.
405 410. Oh
405 410. Oh god,
405 410. Oh god, it's
405 410. Oh god, it's only
405 410. Oh god, it's only 410.
I'm
I'm keeping
405 410. Oh god, it's only 410.
I'm keeping these
I'm keeping these tonsils.
405 410. Oh god, it's only 410.
I'm keeping these tonsils. I
I'm keeping these tonsils. I love
405 410. Oh god, it's only 410.
I'm keeping these tonsils. I love you.
Give
Give me
Give me a
um
um psychiatry
Give me a
um psychiatry in
um psychiatry in its
Give me a
um psychiatry in its heyday.
I
I was
I was in
I was in its
I was in its heyday.
I was in its heyday. Psychiatry
I was in its heyday. Psychiatry in
I was in its heyday. Psychiatry in its
heyday
calibrated
calibrated over
calibrated over 420.
calibrated over 420. What?
calibrated over 420. What? Where
calibrated over 420. What? Where was
medicine?
medicine? What
calibrated over 420. What? Where was
medicine? What did
medicine? What did we
calibrated over 420. What? Where was
medicine? What did we say?
medicine? What did we say? 405.
>> 410.
>> 410. Okay.
>> We
>> We have
>> We have to
>> We have to have
>> We have to have permission.
>> We have to have permission. Do
>> We have to have permission. Do we
>> We have to have permission. Do we have
permission?
permission? We
>> We have to have permission. Do we have
permission? We have
permission? We have permission
>> We have to have permission. Do we have
permission? We have permission to
permission? We have permission to do
this.
Um,
Um, psychiatry
this.
Um, psychiatry in
Um, psychiatry in its
this.
Um, psychiatry in its heyday
Um, psychiatry in its heyday was
this.
Um, psychiatry in its heyday was over
420.
415.
420. Okay.
420. Okay. Psychiatry
420. Okay. Psychiatry nowadays
420. Okay. Psychiatry nowadays is
420. Okay. Psychiatry nowadays is over
415.
420.
420. That's
420. That's about
420. That's about 415.
H.
H. So,
we
we can
we can calibrate
we can calibrate just
we can calibrate just about
we can calibrate just about anything
we can calibrate just about anything and
everything.
everything. We
we can calibrate just about anything and
everything. We calibrated
everything. We calibrated the
we can calibrate just about anything and
everything. We calibrated the kitty's
purr
purr at
purr at 500,
purr at 500, the
purr at 500, the dog's
purr at 500, the dog's wagging
purr at 500, the dog's wagging tail
purr at 500, the dog's wagging tail at
500.
make
make everybody
make everybody feel
make everybody feel better
make everybody feel better and
make everybody feel better and um
that
that love
make everybody feel better and um
that love is
that love is amongst
make everybody feel better and um
that love is amongst those
that love is amongst those folk
disguised
disguised as
disguised as a
disguised as a pet.
disguised as a pet. So
disguised as a pet. So so
disguised as a pet. So so it
disguised as a pet. So so it won't
disguised as a pet. So so it won't be
politically
politically attacked,
disguised as a pet. So so it won't be
politically attacked, you
politically attacked, you know,
disguised as a pet. So so it won't be
politically attacked, you know, see
politically attacked, you know, see or
declared
declared illegal.
declared illegal. So
declared illegal. So it's
declared illegal. So it's not
declared illegal. So it's not illegal
declared illegal. So it's not illegal to
have
have your
declared illegal. So it's not illegal to
have your cat
have your cat purr
declared illegal. So it's not illegal to
have your cat purr your
have your cat purr your dog
declared illegal. So it's not illegal to
have your cat purr your dog way
have your cat purr your dog way to
declared illegal. So it's not illegal to
have your cat purr your dog way to sail.
Many
Many other
Many other things
Many other things that
Many other things that are
Many other things that are loving
Many other things that are loving are
illegal.
illegal. So
Many other things that are loving are
illegal. So anyway,
illegal. So anyway, we
Many other things that are loving are
illegal. So anyway, we get
illegal. So anyway, we get away
Many other things that are loving are
illegal. So anyway, we get away with
dogs
dogs and
dogs and cats.
All
All right.
dogs and cats.
All right. I
All right. I just
dogs and cats.
All right. I just thought
All right. I just thought you
dogs and cats.
All right. I just thought you might
All right. I just thought you might find
that
that that
that that was
that that was interesting.
that that was interesting. The
explanation
explanation of
that that was interesting. The
explanation of kinesiology.
explanation of kinesiology. Now
that that was interesting. The
explanation of kinesiology. Now other
tech
tech what
tech what other
tech what other aspects
tech what other aspects of
tech what other aspects of kinesiology
did
did we
tech what other aspects of kinesiology
did we forget
did we forget to
tech what other aspects of kinesiology
did we forget to explain?
did we forget to explain? You
tech what other aspects of kinesiology
did we forget to explain? You can
did we forget to explain? You can ask
tech what other aspects of kinesiology
did we forget to explain? You can ask oh
you
you cannot
you cannot ask
you cannot ask about
you cannot ask about the
you cannot ask about the future
you cannot ask about the future as
you cannot ask about the future as you
can
can see
you cannot ask about the future as you
can see from
can see from the
you cannot ask about the future as you
can see from the van
can see from the van process.
you cannot ask about the future as you
can see from the van process. What
happened
happened to
happened to my
happened to my van
happened to my van process?
The
The reason
happened to my van process?
The reason you
The reason you can't
happened to my van process?
The reason you can't ask
The reason you can't ask about
happened to my van process?
The reason you can't ask about the
future
future is
future is because
future is because the
future is because the wave
future is because the wave function
future is because the wave function does
not
not collapse
future is because the wave function does
not collapse until
not collapse until you
future is because the wave function does
not collapse until you ask
not collapse until you ask the
future is because the wave function does
not collapse until you ask the question.
So
the
the future
So
the future is
the future is not
So
the future is not knowable.
You
You can
You can make
You can make estimates
You can make estimates to
You can make estimates to the
You can make estimates to the future
You can make estimates to the future by
saying
if
if such
if such and
if such and such
if such and such a
if such and such a condition
if such and such a condition prevails.
All
All right.
if such and such a condition prevails.
All right. So
All right. So the
if such and such a condition prevails.
All right. So the kinesiologic
All right. So the kinesiologic test
if such and such a condition prevails.
All right. So the kinesiologic test then
is
is only
is only good
is only good for
is only good for that
is only good for that which
is only good for that which is
is only good for that which is has
reality
reality has
is only good for that which is has
reality has existence
reality has existence is
is only good for that which is has
reality has existence is verifiable.
about
about 10%
about 10% of
about 10% of the
about 10% of the population
for
for some
about 10% of the population
for some unknown
for some unknown reason
about 10% of the population
for some unknown reason is
for some unknown reason is not
about 10% of the population
for some unknown reason is not able
for some unknown reason is not able to
do
do it.
do it. We
do it. We haven't
do it. We haven't had
do it. We haven't had time
do it. We haven't had time to
do it. We haven't had time to research
it.
it. Um
do it. We haven't had time to research
it. Um why
it. Um why is
do it. We haven't had time to research
it. Um why is it
it. Um why is it sit
do it. We haven't had time to research
it. Um why is it sit up
it. Um why is it sit up closer?
do it. We haven't had time to research
it. Um why is it sit up closer? Let's
keep
keep walking
keep walking over.
keep walking over. Uh
keep walking over. Uh that
keep walking over. Uh that is
keep walking over. Uh that is let's
keep walking over. Uh that is let's see
we
we have
keep walking over. Uh that is let's see
we have permission
we have permission to
keep walking over. Uh that is let's see
we have permission to ask
we have permission to ask that
keep walking over. Uh that is let's see
we have permission to ask that now.
we have permission to ask that now. That
is
is still
is still correct.
is still correct. About
is still correct. About 10%
is still correct. About 10% of
is still correct. About 10% of the
general
general population
is still correct. About 10% of the
general population is
general population is unable
is still correct. About 10% of the
general population is unable to
general population is unable to do
is still correct. About 10% of the
general population is unable to do the
test.
test. It
test. It has
test. It has to
test. It has to do
test. It has to do with
test. It has to do with the
test. It has to do with the balance
test. It has to do with the balance of
theirqi
theirqi energy
test. It has to do with the balance of
theirqi energy resist.
theirqi energy resist. has
test. It has to do with the balance of
theirqi energy resist. has to
theirqi energy resist. has to do
test. It has to do with the balance of
theirqi energy resist. has to do with
the
the balance
the balance of
the balance of the
the balance of the condolini
the balance of the condolini energy
resist.
Um
this
this 10%
Um
this 10% also
this 10% also applies
Um
this 10% also applies to
um
um 10%
um 10% applies
um 10% applies to
um 10% applies to the
um 10% applies to the integrous
um 10% applies to the integrous also.
um 10% applies to the integrous also. So
it's
it's it
um 10% applies to the integrous also. So
it's it has
it's it has nothing
um 10% applies to the integrous also. So
it's it has nothing to
it's it has nothing to do
um 10% applies to the integrous also. So
it's it has nothing to do with
it's it has nothing to do with integrity
or
or non-
or non- integrity
or non- integrity had
or non- integrity had nothing
or non- integrity had nothing to
or non- integrity had nothing to do
or non- integrity had nothing to do with
integrity
integrity or
or non- integrity had nothing to do with
integrity or non
integrity or non integrity
or non- integrity had nothing to do with
integrity or non integrity but
integrity or non integrity but for
or non- integrity had nothing to do with
integrity or non integrity but for some
reason
reason 10%.
reason 10%. You
reason 10%. You know
reason 10%. You know we
reason 10%. You know we could
reason 10%. You know we could spend
reason 10%. You know we could spend the
morning
morning researching
reason 10%. You know we could spend the
morning researching that.
morning researching that. You
reason 10%. You know we could spend the
morning researching that. You know
morning researching that. You know what
I'm
I'm saying?
I'm saying? When
I'm saying? When I
I'm saying? When I first
I'm saying? When I first started
I'm saying? When I first started doing
kinesiologic
kinesiologic research,
I'm saying? When I first started doing
kinesiologic research, we'd
kinesiologic research, we'd meet
I'm saying? When I first started doing
kinesiologic research, we'd meet five
kinesiologic research, we'd meet five or
six
six of
six of us
six of us on
six of us on a
six of us on a Saturday
six of us on a Saturday morning
six of us on a Saturday morning and
break
break up
six of us on a Saturday morning and
break up into
break up into three
six of us on a Saturday morning and
break up into three teams
break up into three teams of
six of us on a Saturday morning and
break up into three teams of two
break up into three teams of two each
and
and research
and research things,
and research things, you
and research things, you know,
and research things, you know, whether
there's
there's beings
and research things, you know, whether
there's beings on
there's beings on other
and research things, you know, whether
there's beings on other planets
there's beings on other planets and
and research things, you know, whether
there's beings on other planets and all
kinds
kinds of
kinds of crap.
kinds of crap. And
kinds of crap. And then
kinds of crap. And then we
kinds of crap. And then we get
kinds of crap. And then we get together
and
and share,
kinds of crap. And then we get together
and share, you
and share, you know,
kinds of crap. And then we get together
and share, you know, get
and share, you know, get as
kinds of crap. And then we get together
and share, you know, get as wild
and share, you know, get as wild as
kinds of crap. And then we get together
and share, you know, get as wild as you
want.
want. Okay.
want. Okay. Uh
want. Okay. Uh so
want. Okay. Uh so for
want. Okay. Uh so for reasons
want. Okay. Uh so for reasons we're
want. Okay. Uh so for reasons we're not
sure,
sure, it
want. Okay. Uh so for reasons we're not
sure, it could
sure, it could be
want. Okay. Uh so for reasons we're not
sure, it could be karmic.
sure, it could be karmic. Let's
want. Okay. Uh so for reasons we're not
sure, it could be karmic. Let's ask
that.
that. Okay.
that. Okay. We
that. Okay. We have
that. Okay. We have permission
that. Okay. We have permission to
that. Okay. We have permission to ask
that.
that. That
that. Okay. We have permission to ask
that. That 10%
that. That 10% is
that. Okay. We have permission to ask
that. That 10% is some
that. That 10% is some karmic
disposition.
disposition. Resist.
disposition. Resist. It
disposition. Resist. It has
disposition. Resist. It has to
disposition. Resist. It has to do
disposition. Resist. It has to do with
their
their evolution.
disposition. Resist. It has to do with
their evolution. Resist.
their evolution. Resist. Oh,
disposition. Resist. It has to do with
their evolution. Resist. Oh, they
their evolution. Resist. Oh, they had
disposition. Resist. It has to do with
their evolution. Resist. Oh, they had a
different
different they
different they came
different they came through
different they came through a
different they came through a different
different
different evolutionary
different they came through a different
different evolutionary line.
different evolutionary line. Oh,
different they came through a different
different evolutionary line. Oh, no.
different evolutionary line. Oh, no. It
has
has to
has to do
has to do with
has to do with their
has to do with their evolution.
has to do with their evolution. Has
has to do with their evolution. Has to
do
do with
has to do with their evolution. Has to
do with karma.
do with karma. Resist
has to do with their evolution. Has to
do with karma. Resist something.
Evolutionary
Evolutionary karma.
Evolutionary karma. I
Evolutionary karma. I don't
Evolutionary karma. I don't know
Evolutionary karma. I don't know what
Evolutionary karma. I don't know what it
means.
Don't
Don't have
Don't have to
Don't have to know
Don't have to know everything.
Don't have to know everything. Thank
God.
God. And
Don't have to know everything. Thank
God. And uh
all
all right,
all right, 10%
all right, 10% of
all right, 10% of the
all right, 10% of the general
all right, 10% of the general population
then
then uh
all right, 10% of the general population
then uh it
then uh it has
all right, 10% of the general population
then uh it has to
then uh it has to do
all right, 10% of the general population
then uh it has to do with
then uh it has to do with the
all right, 10% of the general population
then uh it has to do with the balance
then uh it has to do with the balance of
the
the acupuncture
the acupuncture system,
the acupuncture system, so-called
the acupuncture system, so-called chi
energy,
energy, etc.
the
the immune
the immune system.
Um
the
the people
the people have
the people have to
the people have to be
the people have to be integrate.
the people have to be integrate. So
the people have to be integrate. So we
figure
figure statistically
the people have to be integrate. So we
figure statistically about
figure statistically about 20%
the people have to be integrate. So we
figure statistically about 20% of
figure statistically about 20% of the
population,
population, general
population, general population
population, general population and
population, general population and can
do
do kinesiologic
population, general population and can
do kinesiologic and
do kinesiologic and kinesiology
population, general population and can
do kinesiologic and kinesiology and
do kinesiologic and kinesiology and get
reasonably
reasonably accurate
reasonably accurate response.
reasonably accurate response. The
reasonably accurate response. The other
stranges
stranges is
reasonably accurate response. The other
stranges is sometimes
stranges is sometimes husbands
reasonably accurate response. The other
stranges is sometimes husbands and
stranges is sometimes husbands and wives
can't
can't do
can't do it
can't do it together.
can't do it together. Um
can't do it together. Um that's
can't do it together. Um that's we
can't do it together. Um that's we have
permission.
permission. That
can't do it together. Um that's we have
permission. That is
permission. That is a
can't do it together. Um that's we have
permission. That is a fact.
permission. That is a fact. He
can't do it together. Um that's we have
permission. That is a fact. He said,
"Yeah,
"Yeah, that's
"Yeah, that's a
"Yeah, that's a fact.
"Yeah, that's a fact. It
"Yeah, that's a fact. It isn't
"Yeah, that's a fact. It isn't just
"Yeah, that's a fact. It isn't just you.
It's
It's just
"Yeah, that's a fact. It isn't just you.
It's just the
It's just the peculiarity
"Yeah, that's a fact. It isn't just you.
It's just the peculiarity of
It's just the peculiarity of the
"Yeah, that's a fact. It isn't just you.
It's just the peculiarity of the energy
interchange
interchange between
interchange between man
interchange between man and
interchange between man and wife
interchange between man and wife that
interchange between man and wife that um
a
a certain
interchange between man and wife that um
a certain percentage
a certain percentage of
interchange between man and wife that um
a certain percentage of husbands
a certain percentage of husbands and
wives."
wives." We
wives." We could
wives." We could even
wives." We could even ask
wives." We could even ask that,
wives." We could even ask that, huh?
wives." We could even ask that, huh? We
never
never asked
wives." We could even ask that, huh? We
never asked that.
never asked that. More
wives." We could even ask that, huh? We
never asked that. More than
never asked that. More than 10%,
wives." We could even ask that, huh? We
never asked that. More than 10%, more
than
than 15%,
than 15%, more
than 15%, more than
than 15%, more than 20%,
than 15%, more than 20%, more
than 15%, more than 20%, more than
than 15%, more than 20%, more than 30%,
more
more than
than 15%, more than 20%, more than 30%,
more than 50%.
more than 50%. More
than 15%, more than 20%, more than 30%,
more than 50%. More than
more than 50%. More than 40%.
Well,
Well, why
Well, why close?
Well, why close? Um,
Well, why close? Um, yeah.
Well, why close? Um, yeah. So,
Well, why close? Um, yeah. So, that's
Well, why close? Um, yeah. So, that's a
pretty
pretty high
Well, why close? Um, yeah. So, that's a
pretty high percentage
pretty high percentage because
Well, why close? Um, yeah. So, that's a
pretty high percentage because we
pretty high percentage because we that's
the
the most
the most complaints
the most complaints we
the most complaints we get.
the most complaints we get. wise.
the most complaints we get. wise. We
the most complaints we get. wise. We try
it
it with
the most complaints we get. wise. We try
it with each
it with each other
the most complaints we get. wise. We try
it with each other and
it with each other and it
the most complaints we get. wise. We try
it with each other and it doesn't
it with each other and it doesn't work.
Each
Each one
Each one of
Each one of them
Each one of them can
Each one of them can get
Each one of them can get it
Each one of them can get it to
Each one of them can get it to work
Each one of them can get it to work with
a
a friend
Each one of them can get it to work with
a friend or
a friend or a
Each one of them can get it to work with
a friend or a buddy
a friend or a buddy or
Each one of them can get it to work with
a friend or a buddy or somebody
a friend or a buddy or somebody else,
but
but for
but for some
but for some reason
but for some reason they
but for some reason they can't
but for some reason they can't get
but for some reason they can't get it
but for some reason they can't get it to
work
work with
but for some reason they can't get it to
work with themselves.
As
As I
As I say,
As I say, each
As I say, each one
As I say, each one of
As I say, each one of these
As I say, each one of these things
As I say, each one of these things is
As I say, each one of these things is is
a
a separate
As I say, each one of these things is is
a separate research
project.
project. Why
project. Why that
project. Why that is
project. Why that is having
project. Why that is having to
project. Why that is having to do
probably
probably with
project. Why that is having to do
probably with the
probably with the auras,
project. Why that is having to do
probably with the auras, you
probably with the auras, you know,
project. Why that is having to do
probably with the auras, you know, maybe
maybe
maybe it
maybe it has
maybe it has to
maybe it has to do
maybe it has to do with
maybe it has to do with the
maybe it has to do with the auras.
maybe it has to do with the auras. Has
to
to do
maybe it has to do with the auras. Has
to do with
to do with their
maybe it has to do with the auras. Has
to do with their auras.
to do with their auras. Their
maybe it has to do with the auras. Has
to do with their auras. Their auras
to do with their auras. Their auras get
entangled.
entangled. Oh,
entangled. Oh, I
entangled. Oh, I got
entangled. Oh, I got it.
entangled. Oh, I got it. Okay.
entangled. Oh, I got it. Okay. Because
entanglement
entanglement is
entangled. Oh, I got it. Okay. Because
entanglement is part
entanglement is part of
entangled. Oh, I got it. Okay. Because
entanglement is part of the
entanglement is part of the nonlinear
quantum
quantum um
mechanics
mechanics mathematics
that
that in
that in uh
that in uh in
that in uh in the
that in uh in the world
that in uh in the world of
that in uh in the world of chaotic
non-predictability
non-predictability the
that in uh in the world of chaotic
non-predictability the the
non-predictability the the nonlinear
realm
uh
uh the
realm
uh the language
uh the language they
realm
uh the language they use
uh the language they use to
realm
uh the language they use to describe
uh the language they use to describe it
is
is that
is that realities
is that realities become
is that realities become entangled
is that realities become entangled you
know
know and
is that realities become entangled you
know and therefore
know and therefore there's
is that realities become entangled you
know and therefore there's some
perhaps
perhaps merging
perhaps merging of
perhaps merging of the
perhaps merging of the auras
perhaps merging of the auras you
perhaps merging of the auras you know
there
there is
perhaps merging of the auras you know
there is perhaps
there is perhaps a
perhaps merging of the auras you know
there is perhaps a merging
there is perhaps a merging of
perhaps merging of the auras you know
there is perhaps a merging of auras
between
between uh
between uh spouses
between uh spouses or
between uh spouses or is
between uh spouses or is this
between uh spouses or is this huh?
between uh spouses or is this huh? So
I
I we
between uh spouses or is this huh? So
I we don't
I we don't need
between uh spouses or is this huh? So
I we don't need to
I we don't need to know
between uh spouses or is this huh? So
I we don't need to know more
I we don't need to know more about
between uh spouses or is this huh? So
I we don't need to know more about it.
It's
It's just
It's just that
It's just that that
It's just that that it's
It's just that that it's a
It's just that that it's a fact.
It's just that that it's a fact. It's
not
not personal.
It's just that that it's a fact. It's
not personal. Uh
not personal. Uh and
It's just that that it's a fact. It's
not personal. Uh and they're
not personal. Uh and they're still
capable
capable of
capable of doing
capable of doing it.
capable of doing it. It's
capable of doing it. It's just
capable of doing it. It's just a
capable of doing it. It's just a lot
capable of doing it. It's just a lot of
times
times you
capable of doing it. It's just a lot of
times you got
times you got to
capable of doing it. It's just a lot of
times you got to find
times you got to find a
capable of doing it. It's just a lot of
times you got to find a different
partner.
uh
uh fortunate
partner.
uh fortunate for
uh fortunate for us
partner.
uh fortunate for us it
uh fortunate for us it works
partner.
uh fortunate for us it works and
uh fortunate for us it works and so
partner.
uh fortunate for us it works and so I
don't
don't you
don't you know
don't you know we
don't you know we don't
don't you know we don't have
don't you know we don't have to
don't you know we don't have to seek
don't you know we don't have to seek uh
others
others because
don't you know we don't have to seek uh
others because a
others because a lot
don't you know we don't have to seek uh
others because a lot of
others because a lot of times
don't you know we don't have to seek uh
others because a lot of times the
questions
questions arise
questions arise at
questions arise at midnight
questions arise at midnight or
questions arise at midnight or 4:22
questions arise at midnight or 4:22 in
the
the morning
questions arise at midnight or 4:22 in
the morning and
when
when it
when it when
when it when the
when it when the question
when it when the question arises
when it when the question arises you
just
just have
when it when the question arises you
just have to
just have to know
when it when the question arises you
just have to know the
just have to know the answer
when it when the question arises you
just have to know the answer that
instant
instant you
instant you know
just
just have
instant you know
just have to
just have to know
instant you know
just have to know the
just have to know the instant
instant you know
just have to know the instant the
okay
right
right so
okay
right so we
right so we have
okay
right so we have the
right so we have the scientific
okay
right so we have the scientific basis
then
then you
then you can
then you can look
then you can look up
then you can look up more
then you can look up more about
then you can look up more about it
then you can look up more about it and
it's
it's observed
then you can look up more about it and
it's observed is
it's observed is it's
then you can look up more about it and
it's observed is it's concordant
it's observed is it's concordant with
quantum
quantum mechanics
quantum mechanics but
quantum mechanics but not
quantum mechanics but not with
quantum mechanics but not with Newtonian
physics.
physics. Okay.
quantum mechanics but not with Newtonian
physics. Okay. And
physics. Okay. And the
quantum mechanics but not with Newtonian
physics. Okay. And the reason
physics. Okay. And the reason is
quantum mechanics but not with Newtonian
physics. Okay. And the reason is the
response
response is
response is coming
response is coming out
response is coming out of
response is coming out of a
potentiality.
The
The potentiality
The potentiality the
The potentiality the consequence
The potentiality the consequence of
The potentiality the consequence of the
potentiality
potentiality is
The potentiality the consequence of the
potentiality is already
potentiality is already predetermined
The potentiality the consequence of the
potentiality is already predetermined to
some
some degree
some degree influenced
some degree influenced by
some degree influenced by the
some degree influenced by the question.
The
The intention
some degree influenced by the question.
The intention of
The intention of the
some degree influenced by the question.
The intention of the question.
Therefore
the
the question
Therefore
the question itself
the question itself then
Therefore
the question itself then has
the question itself then has to
Therefore
the question itself then has to be
integrous.
integrous. In
integrous. In other
integrous. In other words,
integrous. In other words, if
integrous. In other words, if you
integrous. In other words, if you have
integrous. In other words, if you have a
stake
stake in
integrous. In other words, if you have a
stake in it,
stake in it, if
integrous. In other words, if you have a
stake in it, if you
stake in it, if you have
integrous. In other words, if you have a
stake in it, if you have a
stake in it, if you have a stake
integrous. In other words, if you have a
stake in it, if you have a stake in
stake in it, if you have a stake in it,
then
then you're
then you're already
then you're already influencing
then you're already influencing the
reliability
reliability of
then you're already influencing the
reliability of the
reliability of the response.
then you're already influencing the
reliability of the response. It
reliability of the response. It has
then you're already influencing the
reliability of the response. It has to
be
be a
be a detached.
Therefore,
Therefore, the
be a detached.
Therefore, the devotion
Therefore, the devotion to
be a detached.
Therefore, the devotion to truth
Therefore, the devotion to truth has
be a detached.
Therefore, the devotion to truth has to
surmount
surmount all
surmount all positionalities.
And
And as
surmount all positionalities.
And as you
And as you find
surmount all positionalities.
And as you find out,
And as you find out, those
surmount all positionalities.
And as you find out, those of
And as you find out, those of you
surmount all positionalities.
And as you find out, those of you who
are
are really
focused
focused on
are really
focused on enlightenment,
all
all positionalities
all positionalities have
all positionalities have to
all positionalities have to be
all positionalities have to be let
all positionalities have to be let go
along
along the
all positionalities have to be let go
along the way.
along the way. Even
all positionalities have to be let go
along the way. Even your
along the way. Even your most
all positionalities have to be let go
along the way. Even your most dear.
Oh
Oh no,
Oh no, not
Oh no, not my
Oh no, not my most
Oh no, not my most dear
Oh no, not my most dear one.
Oh no, not my most dear one. Yes,
Oh no, not my most dear one. Yes, your
most
most dear
Oh no, not my most dear one. Yes, your
most dear one
most dear one is
Oh no, not my most dear one. Yes, your
most dear one is your
most dear one is your main
Oh no, not my most dear one. Yes, your
most dear one is your main enemy,
most dear one is your main enemy, folks.
It's
It's your
It's your most
It's your most dear
It's your most dear positionality
that's
that's keeping
It's your most dear positionality
that's keeping you
that's keeping you glued
It's your most dear positionality
that's keeping you glued to
that's keeping you glued to your
It's your most dear positionality
that's keeping you glued to your seat.
And
And you
And you could
And you could be
And you could be flying
And you could be flying through
And you could be flying through the
universe
universe instead
And you could be flying through the
universe instead of
the
the problem
the problem of
the problem of God
the problem of God and
the problem of God and matter.
I
I say,
why
why in
why in God
why in God does
why in God does it
why in God does it matter?
Why
Why God
why in God does it matter?
Why God doesn't
Why God doesn't matter
why in God does it matter?
Why God doesn't matter what
Why God doesn't matter what the
difference
difference is
difference is between
difference is between God
difference is between God and
difference is between God and matter?
difference is between God and matter? I
mean,
all right.
all right. God
all right. God matter.
all right. God matter. So,
all right. God matter. So, trying
all right. God matter. So, trying to
cross
cross that
all right. God matter. So, trying to
cross that over,
cross that over, you
all right. God matter. So, trying to
cross that over, you can
cross that over, you can see
all right. God matter. So, trying to
cross that over, you can see that
cross that over, you can see that is
quite
quite a
quite a paradigm
quite a paradigm jump.
quite a paradigm jump. Oh,
quite a paradigm jump. Oh, quite
quite a paradigm jump. Oh, quite a
paradigm
paradigm jump.
quite a paradigm jump. Oh, quite a
paradigm jump. Um,
consequently,
consequently, it
consequently, it doesn't
consequently, it doesn't really
consequently, it doesn't really make
sense
sense until
consequently, it doesn't really make
sense until people
sense until people are
consequently, it doesn't really make
sense until people are pretty
sense until people are pretty much
consequently, it doesn't really make
sense until people are pretty much into
the
the 500s
the 500s in
the 500s in which
the 500s in which the
the 500s in which the focus
the 500s in which the focus is
the 500s in which the focus is not
the 500s in which the focus is not on
content.
The
The focus
The focus is
The focus is on
The focus is on context.
The
The spiritual
The focus is on context.
The spiritual domain
The spiritual domain then
The focus is on context.
The spiritual domain then is
The spiritual domain then is the
The focus is on context.
The spiritual domain then is the reality
that
that bypasses
that bypasses all
that bypasses all particularities,
includes
includes it
that bypasses all particularities,
includes it within.
And
And people
And people ask,
And people ask, how
And people ask, how can
And people ask, how can they
And people ask, how can they transcend
to
to that
And people ask, how can they transcend
to that awareness?
to that awareness? And
And people ask, how can they transcend
to that awareness? And of
to that awareness? And of course
And people ask, how can they transcend
to that awareness? And of course the
to that awareness? And of course the way
is
is very
is very simple.
One
One withdraws
is very simple.
One withdraws interest
One withdraws interest in
in
in the
in the particulars
in the particulars and
in the particulars and instead
in the particulars and instead comes
back
back to
in the particulars and instead comes
back to the
back to the experiencing
in the particulars and instead comes
back to the experiencing which
back to the experiencing which is
in the particulars and instead comes
back to the experiencing which is coming
out
out of
out of the
out of the silent
out of the silent area
out of the silent area of
out of the silent area of the
out of the silent area of the mind
out of the silent area of the mind as
the
the aware
out of the silent area of the mind as
the aware as
the aware as the
out of the silent area of the mind as
the aware as the general
the aware as the general awareness
out of the silent area of the mind as
the aware as the general awareness of
the
the totality.
The
The general
the totality.
The general awareness
The general awareness of
the totality.
The general awareness of the
The general awareness of the totality
doesn't
doesn't focus
doesn't focus on
doesn't focus on anybody's
doesn't focus on anybody's face.
doesn't focus on anybody's face. It
doesn't focus on anybody's face. It gets
the
the whole
doesn't focus on anybody's face. It gets
the whole crowd
the whole crowd here.
doesn't focus on anybody's face. It gets
the whole crowd here. It
the whole crowd here. It gets
doesn't focus on anybody's face. It gets
the whole crowd here. It gets the
ambiance
ambiance of
ambiance of the
ambiance of the room.
ambiance of the room. It
ambiance of the room. It gets
ambiance of the room. It gets the
dimension
dimension of
ambiance of the room. It gets the
dimension of the
dimension of the space.
ambiance of the room. It gets the
dimension of the space. It
dimension of the space. It gets
ambiance of the room. It gets the
dimension of the space. It gets the
intentionality
intentionality of
intentionality of our
intentionality of our being
intentionality of our being together.
And
And that
intentionality of our being together.
And that surpasses
And that surpasses all
intentionality of our being together.
And that surpasses all the
particularities
particularities about
particularities about what
particularities about what color
particularities about what color shoes
you're
you're wearing
particularities about what color shoes
you're wearing today
you're wearing today or
particularities about what color shoes
you're wearing today or something.
So
So that
So that awareness
So that awareness gradually
So that awareness gradually shifts
So that awareness gradually shifts from
the
the central
So that awareness gradually shifts from
the central focus
the central focus of
So that awareness gradually shifts from
the central focus of form,
the central focus of form, logic,
content,
content, reasonleness,
content, reasonleness, delineation,
difference.
And
And it
And it shifts
And it shifts to
And it shifts to the
And it shifts to the overall
And it shifts to the overall context.
And
And as
And it shifts to the overall context.
And as it
And as it does
And it shifts to the overall context.
And as it does so,
And as it does so, the
And it shifts to the overall context.
And as it does so, the context
And as it does so, the context gradually
becomes
becomes the
becomes the dominant
sense
sense out
becomes the dominant
sense out of
sense out of which
becomes the dominant
sense out of which one's
sense out of which one's sense
becomes the dominant
sense out of which one's sense of
reality
reality is
reality is arising
and
the
the sense
the sense of
the sense of self
the sense of self as
the sense of self as causal
the sense of self as causal disappears.
Everything
Everything is
the sense of self as causal disappears.
Everything is obviously
Everything is obviously spontaneously
arising
out
out of
arising
out of the
out of the reality
arising
out of the reality out
out of the reality out of
arising
out of the reality out of which
everything
everything exists.
and
and takes
everything exists.
and takes his
and takes his existence
everything exists.
and takes his existence and
and takes his existence and obviously
manifests
manifests its
manifests its potentiality
and
and what
manifests its potentiality
and what that
and what that is
manifests its potentiality
and what that is depends
and what that is depends on
manifests its potentiality
and what that is depends on how
and what that is depends on how you
collapse
collapse your
collapse your wave
collapse your wave function.
What
What you
collapse your wave function.
What you say
What you say yes
collapse your wave function.
What you say yes to
What you say yes to intention
collapse your wave function.
What you say yes to intention then
determines
determines the
determines the direction
determines the direction of
determines the direction of the
determines the direction of the spirit
and
and the
determines the direction of the spirit
and the calibrated
and the calibrated level
determines the direction of the spirit
and the calibrated level of
consciousness.
consciousness. It
consciousness. It obviously
consciousness. It obviously then
determines
determines where
consciousness. It obviously then
determines where where
determines where where that
consciousness
where
where that
consciousness
where that self
where that self goes
consciousness
where that self goes when
where that self goes when it
consciousness
where that self goes when it leaves
where that self goes when it leaves the
physicality
physicality of
physicality of the
physicality of the physical
physicality of the physical domain.
physicality of the physical domain. The
bodiness
with
with which
with which most
with which most people
with which most people uh
with which most people uh in
with which most people uh in the
with which most people uh in the world
identify
identify themsself.
And
And of
And of course
And of course this
And of course this body
And of course this body is
And of course this body is a
And of course this body is a transitory
phenomena.
phenomena. It
And of course this body is a transitory
phenomena. It arises
phenomena. It arises from
And of course this body is a transitory
phenomena. It arises from nature
phenomena. It arises from nature and
then
then it
then it returns
then it returns to
then it returns to nature.
a
a passing
then it returns to nature.
a passing phenomena.
a passing phenomena. So
then it returns to nature.
a passing phenomena. So all
a passing phenomena. So all things
then it returns to nature.
a passing phenomena. So all things are
witnessed
witnessed as
witnessed as passing
witnessed as passing transitory
phenomena.
The
The magnificence
The magnificence of
The magnificence of all
The magnificence of all things
The magnificence of all things begins
The magnificence of all things begins to
shine
shine forth.
Magnificence
Magnificence which
Magnificence which emanates
from
from the
Magnificence which emanates
from the reality
from the reality of
Magnificence which emanates
from the reality of existence
from the reality of existence itself.
Therefore,
Therefore, the
Therefore, the existence
Therefore, the existence of
Therefore, the existence of a
Therefore, the existence of a weed
Therefore, the existence of a weed is
not
not different
Therefore, the existence of a weed is
not different than
not different than the
Therefore, the existence of a weed is
not different than the existence
not different than the existence of
Therefore, the existence of a weed is
not different than the existence of a
diamond
or
or a
diamond
or a stone
or
or my
or my fingers.
It's
It's all
transitory
transitory phenomena.
And
And because
transitory phenomena.
And because it's
And because it's transitory,
transitory phenomena.
And because it's transitory, there's
And because it's transitory, there's no
point
point to
point to become
point to become attached
point to become attached to
point to become attached to anything
because
because those
point to become attached to anything
because those are
because those are only
point to become attached to anything
because those are only transitory
perceptions.
And
And boldness
perceptions.
And boldness will
And boldness will get
perceptions.
And boldness will get you
And boldness will get you sooner
perceptions.
And boldness will get you sooner or
later.
later. Wrinkles
later. Wrinkles will
later. Wrinkles will get
later. Wrinkles will get you.
Old
Old age
later. Wrinkles will get you.
Old age and
Old age and you
later. Wrinkles will get you.
Old age and you watch
Old age and you watch the
later. Wrinkles will get you.
Old age and you watch the body
Old age and you watch the body fall
over.
over. Boink.
A
A lot
over. Boink.
A lot of
A lot of people
over. Boink.
A lot of people remember
A lot of people remember leaving
over. Boink.
A lot of people remember leaving the
body
body in
body in previous
body in previous lifetimes.
body in previous lifetimes. And
body in previous lifetimes. And that's
pretty
pretty much
body in previous lifetimes. And that's
pretty much how
pretty much how it
body in previous lifetimes. And that's
pretty much how it is.
pretty much how it is. And
body in previous lifetimes. And that's
pretty much how it is. And then
pretty much how it is. And then you
body in previous lifetimes. And that's
pretty much how it is. And then you go,
"Wow."
One
One time
"Wow."
One time I
One time I think
"Wow."
One time I think I
One time I think I told
"Wow."
One time I think I told you
One time I think I told you when
"Wow."
One time I think I told you when I
One time I think I told you when I was
"Wow."
One time I think I told you when I was a
slave
slave on
slave on a
slave on a ship.
slave on a ship. Did
slave on a ship. Did I
slave on a ship. Did I tell
slave on a ship. Did I tell you
slave on a ship. Did I tell you about
that?
that? Yeah.
It's
It's done
It's done on
It's done on me.
It's done on me. I
It's done on me. I mean,
It's done on me. I mean, they
It's done on me. I mean, they don't
It's done on me. I mean, they don't have
me
me trapped.
It's done on me. I mean, they don't have
me trapped. They
me trapped. They can't
It's done on me. I mean, they don't have
me trapped. They can't keep
me trapped. They can't keep me
It's done on me. I mean, they don't have
me trapped. They can't keep me in
me trapped. They can't keep me in the
torture
torture chamber.
torture chamber. Hell
torture chamber. Hell with
torture chamber. Hell with them.
torture chamber. Hell with them. And
torture chamber. Hell with them. And I
just
just left
torture chamber. Hell with them. And I
just left the
just left the body
torture chamber. Hell with them. And I
just left the body and
just left the body and died
torture chamber. Hell with them. And I
just left the body and died free
just left the body and died free as
torture chamber. Hell with them. And I
just left the body and died free as a
bird.
bird. Nobody
bird. Nobody can
bird. Nobody can trap
bird. Nobody can trap you.
bird. Nobody can trap you. So,
all
all right.
bird. Nobody can trap you. So,
all right. Uh,
all right. Uh, it's
bird. Nobody can trap you. So,
all right. Uh, it's good
all right. Uh, it's good to
bird. Nobody can trap you. So,
all right. Uh, it's good to know
all right. Uh, it's good to know in
bird. Nobody can trap you. So,
all right. Uh, it's good to know in case
you
you get
you get trapped
you get trapped on
you get trapped on a
you get trapped on a slave
you get trapped on a slave ship
somewhere
somewhere and
you get trapped on a slave ship
somewhere and they're
somewhere and they're beating
you get trapped on a slave ship
somewhere and they're beating you
somewhere and they're beating you at
death
death and
death and it
death and it stinks,
death and it stinks, too.
death and it stinks, too. They
death and it stinks, too. They have
death and it stinks, too. They have no
latrines
latrines in
death and it stinks, too. They have no
latrines in those
latrines in those ships.
death and it stinks, too. They have no
latrines in those ships. God,
latrines in those ships. God, it
death and it stinks, too. They have no
latrines in those ships. God, it was
awful.
awful. I'll
awful. I'll tell
awful. I'll tell you,
always
always remember,
awful. I'll tell you,
always remember, you're
always remember, you're free
awful. I'll tell you,
always remember, you're free as
always remember, you're free as a
awful. I'll tell you,
always remember, you're free as a bird
and
and um
and um that
and um that the
and um that the body
and um that the body is
and um that the body is an
and um that the body is an an
and um that the body is an an option.
The
The body
and um that the body is an an option.
The body is
The body is an
and um that the body is an an option.
The body is an option
The body is an option which
and um that the body is an an option.
The body is an option which one
The body is an option which one chooses
because
because certain
because certain things
because certain things can
because certain things can only
because certain things can only be
learned
learned within
because certain things can only be
learned within the
learned within the domain
because certain things can only be
learned within the domain of
learned within the domain of uh
because certain things can only be
learned within the domain of uh linear
domain
domain of
domain of physicality
domain of physicality and
domain of physicality and form.
domain of physicality and form. Huh.
All
All right.
domain of physicality and form. Huh.
All right. Is
All right. Is there
domain of physicality and form. Huh.
All right. Is there any
All right. Is there any more
domain of physicality and form. Huh.
All right. Is there any more questions
on
on kinesiology?
on kinesiology? Don't
on kinesiology? Don't you
on kinesiology? Don't you dare
on kinesiology? Don't you dare write
on kinesiology? Don't you dare write me
if
if you
on kinesiology? Don't you dare write me
if you don't
if you don't ask
on kinesiology? Don't you dare write me
if you don't ask anything.
if you don't ask anything. Yes.
Yeah,
Yeah, somebody
Yeah, somebody left.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Well,
Yeah, somebody left.
>> Yes. Well, the
>> Yes. Well, the universe
Yeah, somebody left.
>> Yes. Well, the universe exists
>> Yes. Well, the universe exists as
see
see physics,
see physics, advanced
see physics, advanced theorical
see physics, advanced theorical physics,
you
you know
see physics, advanced theorical physics,
you know about
you know about waves
see physics, advanced theorical physics,
you know about waves and
you know about waves and particles.
Uh
Uh quantum
Uh quantum means
Uh quantum means um
Uh quantum means um small
Uh quantum means um small units.
Uh quantum means um small units. It
Uh quantum means um small units. It was
thought
thought that
Uh quantum means um small units. It was
thought that sunshine
thought that sunshine was
Uh quantum means um small units. It was
thought that sunshine was one
thought that sunshine was one continuous
radiation
radiation and
radiation and various
radiation and various things
radiation and various things were
various
various radiations.
radiation and various things were
various radiations. In
various radiations. In the
radiation and various things were
various radiations. In the blackbox
radiation
radiation experiment
radiation experiment plank
radiation experiment plank discovered
that
that is
radiation experiment plank discovered
that is not
that is not so
radiation experiment plank discovered
that is not so that
that is not so that things
radiation experiment plank discovered
that is not so that things uh
that is not so that things uh and
radiation experiment plank discovered
that is not so that things uh and the
discoveries
discoveries of
discoveries of early
discoveries of early physics
discoveries of early physics then
discoveries of early physics then it
discoveries of early physics then it was
discovered
discovered that
discoveries of early physics then it was
discovered that no
discovered that no energy
discoveries of early physics then it was
discovered that no energy comes
discovered that no energy comes in
discrete
discrete packets
discrete packets quanta.
discrete packets quanta. So
discrete packets quanta. So quant
discrete packets quanta. So quant means
um
um unit
discrete packets quanta. So quant means
um unit energy
um unit energy radiates
discrete packets quanta. So quant means
um unit energy radiates in
um unit energy radiates in units.
discrete packets quanta. So quant means
um unit energy radiates in units. Uhhuh.
And
And therefore
And therefore the
And therefore the physics
And therefore the physics of
And therefore the physics of microscopic
units
units is
And therefore the physics of microscopic
units is quite
units is quite different
And therefore the physics of microscopic
units is quite different than
units is quite different than the
physics
physics of
physics of advanced
physics of advanced um
physics of advanced um all
physics of advanced um all right
physics of advanced um all right so
physics of advanced um all right so you
can
can see
physics of advanced um all right so you
can see that
can see that what
physics of advanced um all right so you
can see that what we're
can see that what we're dealing
physics of advanced um all right so you
can see that what we're dealing with
can see that what we're dealing with is
not
not certainty.
not certainty. If
not certainty. If the
not certainty. If the world
not certainty. If the world is
not certainty. If the world is not
not certainty. If the world is not a
result
result of
not certainty. If the world is not a
result of causality
result of causality if
not certainty. If the world is not a
result of causality if the
result of causality if the world
not certainty. If the world is not a
result of causality if the world was
result of causality if the world was run
by
by co
by co deterministic
by co deterministic causality
by co deterministic causality there
would
would be
by co deterministic causality there
would be no
would be no spiritual
by co deterministic causality there
would be no spiritual reality.
would be no spiritual reality. There
would
would be
would be no
would be no accountability.
would be no accountability. There
would be no accountability. There would
be
be no
would be no accountability. There would
be no karma.
be no karma. There'd
would be no accountability. There would
be no karma. There'd be
be no karma. There'd be no
would be no accountability. There would
be no karma. There'd be no heaven
be no karma. There'd be no heaven or
hell.
Everything
Everything would
hell.
Everything would be
Everything would be like
hell.
Everything would be like machines.
Everything would be like machines. The
machine
machine doesn't
machine doesn't have
machine doesn't have any
machine doesn't have any karma.
machine doesn't have any karma. It
machine doesn't have any karma. It just
does
does what
machine doesn't have any karma. It just
does what it
does what it has
machine doesn't have any karma. It just
does what it has to
does what it has to do.
machine doesn't have any karma. It just
does what it has to do. So
the
the explanation
the explanation you
the explanation you see
the explanation you see all
the explanation you see all of
the explanation you see all of mankind
except
except modern
the explanation you see all of mankind
except modern America
except modern America perhaps
throughout
throughout all
throughout all of
throughout all of time
throughout all of time has
throughout all of time has been
throughout all of time has been aware
throughout all of time has been aware of
the
the nonlinear
throughout all of time has been aware of
the nonlinear dimension.
the nonlinear dimension. Many
throughout all of time has been aware of
the nonlinear dimension. Many cultures
in
in fact
in fact are
in fact are devoted
in fact are devoted almost
in fact are devoted almost completely
in fact are devoted almost completely to
the
the nonlinear
in fact are devoted almost completely to
the nonlinear dimension
the nonlinear dimension and
in fact are devoted almost completely to
the nonlinear dimension and uh
the nonlinear dimension and uh the
priesthood
priesthood and
priesthood and uh
priesthood and uh spiritual
priesthood and uh spiritual and
religious
religious rituals
priesthood and uh spiritual and
religious rituals uh
religious rituals uh was
priesthood and uh spiritual and
religious rituals uh was the
religious rituals uh was the predominant
motif
motif of
motif of their
motif of their society.
Um
all
all of
all of mankind
all of mankind has
all of mankind has been
all of mankind has been aware
all of mankind has been aware of
all of mankind has been aware of the
spiritual
spiritual side
all of mankind has been aware of the
spiritual side of
spiritual side of man
and
and um
and um to
and um to our
and um to our view
and um to our view of
and um to our view of it
and um to our view of it they
and um to our view of it they perhaps
neglected
neglected that
they
they should
they should have
they should have been
they should have been inventing
penicellin
penicellin instead
they should have been inventing
penicellin instead of
penicellin instead of sacrificing
virgins
virgins to
virgins to the
virgins to the volcano
virgins to the volcano god
virgins to the volcano god and
virgins to the volcano god and stuff
virgins to the volcano god and stuff but
that's
that's Monday
virgins to the volcano god and stuff but
that's Monday morning
that's Monday morning quarterbacking
right
right that's
right that's how
right that's how evolution
right that's how evolution came
right that's how evolution came about
and
and um
right that's how evolution came about
and um so
and um so we
right that's how evolution came about
and um so we became
and um so we became became
right that's how evolution came about
and um so we became became what
and um so we became became what we
right that's how evolution came about
and um so we became became what we have
become
become as
become as a
become as a result
become as a result of
become as a result of the
become as a result of the evolution
become as a result of the evolution of
consciousness
in
in which
in which choice
in which choice is
in which choice is possible.
in which choice is possible. So
in which choice is possible. So the
other
other interesting
in which choice is possible. So the
other interesting thing
other interesting thing about
in which choice is possible. So the
other interesting thing about quantum
mechanics
mechanics is
mechanics is explains
mechanics is explains how
mechanics is explains how how
mechanics is explains how how it
mechanics is explains how how it is
mechanics is explains how how it is that
prayer
prayer is
mechanics is explains how how it is that
prayer is efficacious.
Why
Why it
Why it is
Why it is that
Why it is that choice
Why it is that choice determines
spiritual
spiritual responsibility.
It's
It's the
It's the exercise
It's the exercise of
It's the exercise of one's
It's the exercise of one's spiritual
will.
will. And
It's the exercise of one's spiritual
will. And you
will. And you see
It's the exercise of one's spiritual
will. And you see that
will. And you see that the
It's the exercise of one's spiritual
will. And you see that the choices
will. And you see that the choices are
already
already predetermined
to
to either
already predetermined
to either yes
to either yes or
already predetermined
to either yes or not
to either yes or not yes.
Yes
Yes or
Yes or not
Yes or not yes.
So
So there
Yes or not yes.
So there is
So there is no
Yes or not yes.
So there is no duality
So there is no duality of
Yes or not yes.
So there is no duality of yes
So there is no duality of yes versus
Yes or not yes.
So there is no duality of yes versus not
yes.
yes. Just
yes. Just like
yes. Just like we've
yes. Just like we've spoken
yes. Just like we've spoken that
yes. Just like we've spoken that there
is
is no
yes. Just like we've spoken that there
is no duality
is no duality of
yes. Just like we've spoken that there
is no duality of good
is no duality of good versus
yes. Just like we've spoken that there
is no duality of good versus evil
is no duality of good versus evil or
yes. Just like we've spoken that there
is no duality of good versus evil or up
versus
versus down
versus down or
versus down or cold
versus down or cold versus
versus down or cold versus hot.
versus down or cold versus hot. To
transcend
transcend the
versus down or cold versus hot. To
transcend the positionalities
transcend the positionalities that
establish
establish the
establish the illusion
of
of the
establish the illusion
of the polarities
of the polarities of
establish the illusion
of the polarities of the
of the polarities of the opposites
establish the illusion
of the polarities of the opposites is
one
one of
one of the
one of the areas
one of the areas that
one of the areas that one
one of the areas that one has
one of the areas that one has to
transcend.
And
And I
And I think
And I think I've
And I think I've told
And I think I've told you
And I think I've told you the
And I think I've told you the one
And I think I've told you the one that
And I think I've told you the one that I
got
got hit
And I think I've told you the one that I
got hit with
got hit with first
And I think I've told you the one that I
got hit with first in
got hit with first in this
And I think I've told you the one that I
got hit with first in this lifetime
got hit with first in this lifetime was
existence
existence versus
existence versus non-existence.
And
And that
existence versus non-existence.
And that the
And that the answer
existence versus non-existence.
And that the answer to
And that the answer to that
existence versus non-existence.
And that the answer to that is
And that the answer to that is that
existence versus non-existence.
And that the answer to that is that the
truth
truth of
truth of God
truth of God that
truth of God that there
truth of God that there is
truth of God that there is no
truth of God that there is no opposite.
There
There is
truth of God that there is no opposite.
There is no
There is no opposite
truth of God that there is no opposite.
There is no opposite to
There is no opposite to reality.
truth of God that there is no opposite.
There is no opposite to reality. There
is
is no
is no opposite
is no opposite to
is no opposite to truth.
All
All right?
So
So one
So one is
So one is born
So one is born then
So one is born then with
So one is born then with the
So one is born then with the capacity
one
one capacity
um
um of
um of choice.
That
That choice
um of choice.
That choice then
That choice then has
um of choice.
That choice then has an
That choice then has an influence
karmically
karmically and
karmically and on
karmically and on the
karmically and on the whole
karmically and on the whole universe
karmically and on the whole universe in
that
that it
karmically and on the whole universe in
that it collapses
that it collapses the
karmically and on the whole universe in
that it collapses the wave
that it collapses the wave function.
karmically and on the whole universe in
that it collapses the wave function. Now
one
one reason
one reason the
one reason the brain
one reason the brain re
one reason the brain re oh oh
one reason the brain re oh oh god
one reason the brain re oh oh god this
is
is a
one reason the brain re oh oh god this
is a funny
is a funny morning.
one reason the brain re oh oh god this
is a funny morning. One
is a funny morning. One reason
one reason the brain re oh oh god this
is a funny morning. One reason the
is a funny morning. One reason the uh
brain
brain researchers
brain researchers can't
brain researchers can't get
brain researchers can't get the
brain researchers can't get the answers
they're
they're looking
brain researchers can't get the answers
they're looking for.
they're looking for. Let's
brain researchers can't get the answers
they're looking for. Let's see
they're looking for. Let's see if
brain researchers can't get the answers
they're looking for. Let's see if I
intuited
intuited that
intuited that right.
intuited that right. Okay.
intuited that right. Okay. Uh
intuited that right. Okay. Uh subjective
experience
experience experiencing
uh
uh such
uh such as
uh such as we
uh such as we experience
uh such as we experience when
uh such as we experience when we
uh such as we experience when we listen
to
to music
uh such as we experience when we listen
to music is
to music is experienced
uh such as we experience when we listen
to music is experienced in
to music is experienced in the
uh such as we experience when we listen
to music is experienced in the atheric
brain.
brain. We
brain. We said
well
well folks
brain. We said
well folks they're
well folks they're looking
brain. We said
well folks they're looking in
well folks they're looking in the
physical
physical brain
physical brain and
physical brain and the
physical brain and the experiential
physical brain and the experiential is
in
in the
physical brain and the experiential is
in the atheric
in the atheric brain.
You
You understand
You understand what
You understand what I'm
You understand what I'm saying?
When
When you
You understand what I'm saying?
When you go
When you go out
You understand what I'm saying?
When you go out of
When you go out of body,
You understand what I'm saying?
When you go out of body, anybody's
When you go out of body, anybody's going
out
out of
out of body
out of body here.
out of body here. How
out of body here. How many
out of body here. How many people
out of body here. How many people going
out
out of
out of body here. How many people going
out of body?
out of body? All right.
out of body here. How many people going
out of body? All right. You
out of body? All right. You know
out of body here. How many people going
out of body? All right. You know that
experiential
experiential awareness
experiential awareness went
experiential awareness went right
experiential awareness went right along
with
with you.
experiential awareness went right along
with you. Even
with you. Even though
experiential awareness went right along
with you. Even though the
with you. Even though the physical
experiential awareness went right along
with you. Even though the physical brain
was
was laying
was laying over
was laying over there
was laying over there or
was laying over there or under
anesthesia
anesthesia or
was laying over there or under
anesthesia or having
anesthesia or having brain
was laying over there or under
anesthesia or having brain surgery
anesthesia or having brain surgery or
shot
shot dead
shot dead with
shot dead with a
shot dead with a bullet
shot dead with a bullet wound
shot dead with a bullet wound or
whatever,
whatever, just,
shot dead with a bullet wound or
whatever, just, you
whatever, just, you know,
shot dead with a bullet wound or
whatever, just, you know, the
whatever, just, you know, the the
shot dead with a bullet wound or
whatever, just, you know, the the car
crashes
crashes over
crashes over the
crashes over the cliff
crashes over the cliff and
crashes over the cliff and there
crashes over the cliff and there you
crashes over the cliff and there you are
witnessing
witnessing the
crashes over the cliff and there you are
witnessing the whole
witnessing the whole thing.
crashes over the cliff and there you are
witnessing the whole thing. There's
witnessing the whole thing. There's a
car
car rolling
car rolling down
and
and uh
car rolling down
and uh you're
and uh you're not
car rolling down
and uh you're not affected
and uh you're not affected at
car rolling down
and uh you're not affected at all.
and uh you're not affected at all. Your
brain
brain is
brain is down
brain is down there
brain is down there and
brain is down there and you're
brain is down there and you're up
brain is down there and you're up here.
Consciousness
Consciousness then
brain is down there and you're up here.
Consciousness then is
Consciousness then is not
brain is down there and you're up here.
Consciousness then is not limited
Consciousness then is not limited to
physicality.
So
So the
physicality.
So the conferences
So the conferences on
physicality.
So the conferences on science
So the conferences on science and
consciousness
consciousness are
consciousness are up
consciousness are up against
consciousness are up against the
difficult
paradigm
paradigm jump
paradigm jump folks.
All right.
What
What they're
What they're looking
What they're looking for
What they're looking for is
What they're looking for is only
explicable
explicable by
What they're looking for is only
explicable by the
explicable by the awareness
What they're looking for is only
explicable by the awareness of
explicable by the awareness of the
function
function of
function of the
function of the atheric
function of the atheric brain.
function of the atheric brain. Is
function of the atheric brain. Is this
correct?
The
physical
physical brain
The
physical brain cerebration
is
is suitable
is suitable for
is suitable for handling
is suitable for handling form.
is suitable for handling form. Is
is suitable for handling form. Is this
okay?
okay? The
is suitable for handling form. Is this
okay? The physicality
okay? The physicality is
is suitable for handling form. Is this
okay? The physicality is suitable
okay? The physicality is suitable for
handling
handling form.
The
The physicality
handling form.
The physicality celebration
The physicality celebration is
handling form.
The physicality celebration is suitable
for
for uh
for uh comprehending
for uh comprehending the
for uh comprehending the significance
for uh comprehending the significance of
nonform.
the
the physical
the physical brain
the physical brain is
the physical brain is not
the physical brain is not capable.
the physical brain is not capable. So
cerebration.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So the
All right. So the way
All right. So the way one
All right. So the way one moves
All right. So the way one moves then
All right. So the way one moves then in
spiritual
spiritual work
All right. So the way one moves then in
spiritual work is
spiritual work is primarily
All right. So the way one moves then in
spiritual work is primarily from
spiritual work is primarily from the
left
left brain
uh
uh to
left brain
uh to the
uh to the right
left brain
uh to the right brain.
uh to the right brain. The
left brain
uh to the right brain. The classic
analogy
analogy was
analogy was left
analogy was left brain
analogy was left brain right
analogy was left brain right brain.
analogy was left brain right brain. I
remember
remember when
analogy was left brain right brain. I
remember when they
remember when they had
analogy was left brain right brain. I
remember when they had an
remember when they had an instrument
called
called the
called the mind
called the mind mirror.
called the mind mirror. It
called the mind mirror. It was
called the mind mirror. It was an
electrophiloggram
electrophiloggram with
called the mind mirror. It was an
electrophiloggram with electrodes
and
and it
and it had
and it had two
and it had two lightboards.
and it had two lightboards. One
and it had two lightboards. One light
board
board was
and it had two lightboards. One light
board was your
board was your left
and it had two lightboards. One light
board was your left brain,
board was your left brain, the
and it had two lightboards. One light
board was your left brain, the other
board was your left brain, the other was
your
your right
your right brain.
your right brain. They'd
your right brain. They'd say,
your right brain. They'd say, "Now
multiply
multiply 862
your right brain. They'd say, "Now
multiply 862 times
multiply 862 times 17."
your right brain. They'd say, "Now
multiply 862 times 17." You
multiply 862 times 17." You got
your right brain. They'd say, "Now
multiply 862 times 17." You got to
multiply 862 times 17." You got to go
like
like this.
like this. You
like this. You see
like this. You see all
like this. You see all the
like this. You see all the lights
like this. You see all the lights on
like this. You see all the lights on the
left
left side
like this. You see all the lights on the
left side of
left side of the
like this. You see all the lights on the
left side of the board
left side of the board light
like this. You see all the lights on the
left side of the board light up.
left side of the board light up. And
like this. You see all the lights on the
left side of the board light up. And the
right
right side
right side of
right side of the
right side of the board,
right side of the board, they
right side of the board, they would
practically
practically go
right side of the board, they would
practically go out.
practically go out. And
right side of the board, they would
practically go out. And and
practically go out. And and then
right side of the board, they would
practically go out. And and then you'd
say,
say, "All
say, "All right,
say, "All right, now
say, "All right, now I
say, "All right, now I want
say, "All right, now I want you
say, "All right, now I want you to
say, "All right, now I want you to think
of
Rap
Rap City
Rap City and
Rap City and Blue.
Rap City and Blue. I
Rap City and Blue. I want
Rap City and Blue. I want you
Rap City and Blue. I want you to
Rap City and Blue. I want you to think
of
the
the ballet.
the ballet. And
the ballet. And I
the ballet. And I want
the ballet. And I want you
the ballet. And I want you to
the ballet. And I want you to think
the ballet. And I want you to think of
the ballet. And I want you to think of a
lovely
lovely song
the ballet. And I want you to think of a
lovely song such
lovely song such as
the ballet. And I want you to think of a
lovely song such as the
lovely song such as the music
the ballet. And I want you to think of a
lovely song such as the music we
listened
listened to
listened to this
listened to this morning.
listened to this morning. Instantly
listened to this morning. Instantly you
see
see all
listened to this morning. Instantly you
see all the
see all the lights
listened to this morning. Instantly you
see all the lights go
see all the lights go up
listened to this morning. Instantly you
see all the lights go up on
see all the lights go up on the
listened to this morning. Instantly you
see all the lights go up on the right
side
side of
side of the
side of the vine
side of the vine mirror
side of the vine mirror machine
side of the vine mirror machine and
side of the vine mirror machine and the
lights
lights went
side of the vine mirror machine and the
lights went out
lights went out on
side of the vine mirror machine and the
lights went out on the
lights went out on the left
side of the vine mirror machine and the
lights went out on the left side.
lights went out on the left side. So
we're
we're all
we're all familiar
we're all familiar with
we're all familiar with that
we're all familiar with that that
we're all familiar with that that the
left
left hand
we're all familiar with that that the
left hand tends
left hand tends to
we're all familiar with that that the
left hand tends to be
left hand tends to be digital
we're all familiar with that that the
left hand tends to be digital how
left hand tends to be digital how things
are
are different
are different deal
are different deal in
are different deal in form.
are different deal in form. The
are different deal in form. The right
side
side tends
are different deal in form. The right
side tends to
side tends to be
are different deal in form. The right
side tends to be more
side tends to be more analog
are different deal in form. The right
side tends to be more analog computer
how
how things
how things are
how things are alike.
how things are alike. How
how things are alike. How so
how things are alike. How so the
how things are alike. How so the right
side
side of
how things are alike. How so the right
side of the
side of the brain
how things are alike. How so the right
side of the brain sees
side of the brain sees how
how things are alike. How so the right
side of the brain sees how we're
side of the brain sees how we're all
alike
alike here.
alike here. See,
alike here. See, the
alike here. See, the left
alike here. See, the left side
alike here. See, the left side of
alike here. See, the left side of the
brain
brain sees
alike here. See, the left side of the
brain sees that
brain sees that you
alike here. See, the left side of the
brain sees that you got
brain sees that you got an
alike here. See, the left side of the
brain sees that you got an orange
brain sees that you got an orange shirt
and
and you
and you got
and you got a
and you got a blue
and you got a blue shirt
and you got a blue shirt and
and you got a blue shirt and your
and you got a blue shirt and your name
is
is Joe
and you got a blue shirt and your name
is Joe and
is Joe and your
and you got a blue shirt and your name
is Joe and your name
is Joe and your name is
and you got a blue shirt and your name
is Joe and your name is Pete.
And
And if
And if you
And if you get
And if you get too
And if you get too far
And if you get too far right
And if you get too far right brain,
And if you get too far right brain, you
don't
don't remember
And if you get too far right brain, you
don't remember anybody's
don't remember anybody's name
And if you get too far right brain, you
don't remember anybody's name anymore.
You
You know
You know who
You know who they
You know who they are
You know who they are cuz
You know who they are cuz you're
connected
connected at
You know who they are cuz you're
connected at one
connected at one with
You know who they are cuz you're
connected at one with their
connected at one with their inner
You know who they are cuz you're
connected at one with their inner self.
You've
You've known
You've known them
You've known them for
You've known them for centuries.
You've known them for centuries. Number
of
of people
You've known them for centuries. Number
of people here
of people here I've
You've known them for centuries. Number
of people here I've known
of people here I've known for
You've known them for centuries. Number
of people here I've known for I
of people here I've known for I can't
tell
tell you
tell you I
tell you I won't
tell you I won't even
tell you I won't even tell
tell you I won't even tell you
tell you I won't even tell you how
tell you I won't even tell you how long.
Shake
Shake up
tell you I won't even tell you how long.
Shake up shake
Shake up shake up.
tell you I won't even tell you how long.
Shake up shake up. And
Shake up shake up. And um
we've
we've evolved
we've evolved together.
Obviously
Obviously we've
we've evolved together.
Obviously we've evolved
Obviously we've evolved together.
we've evolved together.
Obviously we've evolved together. We're
all
all here.
all here. So
all here. So we've
all here. So we've obviously
all here. So we've obviously evolved
together.
together. So
all here. So we've obviously evolved
together. So we
together. So we came
all here. So we've obviously evolved
together. So we came out
together. So we came out of
all here. So we've obviously evolved
together. So we came out of non
together. So we came out of non human
bodiness.
bodiness. Now
bodiness. Now we're
bodiness. Now we're all
bodiness. Now we're all here
bodiness. Now we're all here and
bodiness. Now we're all here and we're
all
all going
bodiness. Now we're all here and we're
all going to
all going to go
bodiness. Now we're all here and we're
all going to go over
all going to go over there
bodiness. Now we're all here and we're
all going to go over there on
all going to go over there on the
bodiness. Now we're all here and we're
all going to go over there on the other
side.
side. Right?
side. Right? So
side. Right? So we're
side. Right? So we're all
side. Right? So we're all going
side. Right? So we're all going to
side. Right? So we're all going to be
together
together no
side. Right? So we're all going to be
together no matter
together no matter what.
side. Right? So we're all going to be
together no matter what. Hang
together no matter what. Hang out
together
together for
together for probably
together for probably a
together for probably a long
together for probably a long time.
drawn
drawn together
together for probably a long time.
drawn together by
drawn together by what?
together for probably a long time.
drawn together by what? Drawn
drawn together by what? Drawn together
by
by uh
by uh intention,
drawn
drawn together
by uh intention,
drawn together by
drawn together by context,
drawn
drawn together
drawn together by
drawn together by karmic
drawn together by karmic propensity.
Um
you
you know,
you know, if
you know, if this
you know, if this was
you know, if this was a
you know, if this was a class
you know, if this was a class on
you know, if this was a class on how
you know, if this was a class on how to
drill
drill holes
you know, if this was a class on how to
drill holes in
drill holes in your
you know, if this was a class on how to
drill holes in your skull
drill holes in your skull and
you know, if this was a class on how to
drill holes in your skull and and
realize
realize God
realize God by
realize God by that,
realize God by that, we'd
realize God by that, we'd have
realize God by that, we'd have a
different
different crowd.
There
There are
There are people
There are people who
There are people who do
There are people who do that,
There are people who do that, by
There are people who do that, by the
way.
If
If we
If we were
If we were going
If we were going to
If we were going to find
If we were going to find God
If we were going to find God by
going
going out
If we were going to find God by
going out in
going out in the
If we were going to find God by
going out in the desert
going out in the desert waiting
If we were going to find God by
going out in the desert waiting for
UFOs,
UFOs, we'd
UFOs, we'd be
UFOs, we'd be out
UFOs, we'd be out there.
UFOs, we'd be out there. We
UFOs, we'd be out there. We wouldn't
UFOs, we'd be out there. We wouldn't be
here.
here. So,
UFOs, we'd be out there. We wouldn't be
here. So, you
here. So, you see
UFOs, we'd be out there. We wouldn't be
here. So, you see the
here. So, you see the similarity
UFOs, we'd be out there. We wouldn't be
here. So, you see the similarity of
intention
intention and
intention and there's
intention and there's a
intention and there's a some
intention and there's a some some
intention and there's a some some kind
of
of a
intention and there's a some some kind
of a contextualization
of a contextualization that
intention and there's a some some kind
of a contextualization that keeps
of a contextualization that keeps us
intention and there's a some some kind
of a contextualization that keeps us all
here
here together.
here together. We've
here together. We've all
here together. We've all explored
here together. We've all explored all
the
the astral
here together. We've all explored all
the astral domains
the astral domains and
here together. We've all explored all
the astral domains and the
the astral domains and the tarot
here together. We've all explored all
the astral domains and the tarot cards
and
and the
and the psychic
and the psychic readings
and the psychic readings and
and the psychic readings and doing
and the psychic readings and doing the
ruins
ruins and
we've
we've explored
we've explored all
we've explored all that.
we've explored all that. It's
we've explored all that. It's part
we've explored all that. It's part of,
you
you know,
we've explored all that. It's part of,
you know, uh,
you know, uh, when
we've explored all that. It's part of,
you know, uh, when you
you know, uh, when you go
we've explored all that. It's part of,
you know, uh, when you go to
you know, uh, when you go to college,
you
you know,
you know, when
you know, when you
you know, when you go
you know, when you go to
you know, when you go to college,
you know, when you go to college, you
learn
learn how
you know, when you go to college, you
learn how to
learn how to play
you know, when you go to college, you
learn how to play bridge,
learn how to play bridge, you
you know, when you go to college, you
learn how to play bridge, you know,
learn how to play bridge, you know, it's
one
one of
one of those
one of those things,
one of those things, how
one of those things, how to
one of those things, how to drink
one of those things, how to drink beer.
And
so,
so, we
so, we hung
so, we hung out
so, we hung out together
so, we hung out together and
so, we hung out together and we
so, we hung out together and we explored
all
all that
so, we hung out together and we explored
all that stuff
all that stuff and
so, we hung out together and we explored
all that stuff and then
all that stuff and then we
so, we hung out together and we explored
all that stuff and then we come
all that stuff and then we come out
so, we hung out together and we explored
all that stuff and then we come out of
we
we say,
we say, "Yeah,
we say, "Yeah, now
we say, "Yeah, now what?
we say, "Yeah, now what? Yeah,
we say, "Yeah, now what? Yeah, what
now?"
now?" Huh?
we say, "Yeah, now what? Yeah, what
now?" Huh? Those
now?" Huh? Those of
we say, "Yeah, now what? Yeah, what
now?" Huh? Those of us
now?" Huh? Those of us that
we say, "Yeah, now what? Yeah, what
now?" Huh? Those of us that have
now?" Huh? Those of us that have escaped
it,
it, by
it, by the
it, by the way,
it, by the way, and
it, by the way, and some
it, by the way, and some of
it, by the way, and some of them
it, by the way, and some of them are
still
still left
it, by the way, and some of them are
still left there
still left there caught
it, by the way, and some of them are
still left there caught in
still left there caught in the
it, by the way, and some of them are
still left there caught in the mire,
still left there caught in the mire, but
H
H is
H is there
H is there anything
H is there anything more
H is there anything more about
kinesiology?
kinesiology? I
H is there anything more about
kinesiology? I just
kinesiology? I just want
H is there anything more about
kinesiology? I just want to
kinesiology? I just want to make
H is there anything more about
kinesiology? I just want to make sure
that
that we
that we have
that we have knocked
that we have knocked this
that we have knocked this uh
that we have knocked this uh cold
that we have knocked this uh cold dead
and
and uh
that we have knocked this uh cold dead
and uh I
and uh I don't
that we have knocked this uh cold dead
and uh I don't want
and uh I don't want another
that we have knocked this uh cold dead
and uh I don't want another letter
and uh I don't want another letter email
facts
that
that you
facts
that you can't
that you can't get
facts
that you can't get the
that you can't get the same
facts
that you can't get the same numbers
that you can't get the same numbers as
facts
that you can't get the same numbers as I
get.
get. No,
get. No, you
get. No, you can't
get. No, you can't get
get. No, you can't get the
get. No, you can't get the same
get. No, you can't get the same numbers
as
as I
get. No, you can't get the same numbers
as I get
as I get because
get. No, you can't get the same numbers
as I get because you're
as I get because you're you
get. No, you can't get the same numbers
as I get because you're you and
as I get because you're you and I'm
get. No, you can't get the same numbers
as I get because you're you and I'm me.
My
My numbers
My numbers all
My numbers all belong
My numbers all belong to
My numbers all belong to me.
My numbers all belong to me. I
My numbers all belong to me. I own
My numbers all belong to me. I own all
the
the numbers
My numbers all belong to me. I own all
the numbers in
the numbers in the
My numbers all belong to me. I own all
the numbers in the universe.
the numbers in the universe. No,
it
it has
it has to
it has to do
it has to do with
it has to do with intentionality,
suitability,
suitability, the
it has to do with intentionality,
suitability, the technique
suitability, the technique itself.
And
And if
And if people
And if people don't
And if people don't get
And if people don't get the
And if people don't get the same
And if people don't get the same numbers
that
that we
And if people don't get the same numbers
that we do,
that we do, you
And if people don't get the same numbers
that we do, you can
that we do, you can make
And if people don't get the same numbers
that we do, you can make up
that we do, you can make up your
And if people don't get the same numbers
that we do, you can make up your own
scale,
scale, folks.
scale, folks. I
scale, folks. I mean,
scale, folks. I mean, I
scale, folks. I mean, I I
scale, folks. I mean, I I think
scale, folks. I mean, I I think I
mentioned
mentioned this
scale, folks. I mean, I I think I
mentioned this once
mentioned this once before,
scale, folks. I mean, I I think I
mentioned this once before, but
mentioned this once before, but I
scale, folks. I mean, I I think I
mentioned this once before, but I forgot
to
to remention
to remention it.
to remention it. You
to remention it. You can
to remention it. You can make
to remention it. You can make your
to remention it. You can make your own
scale.
scale. You
to remention it. You can make your own
scale. You say
scale. You say on
to remention it. You can make your own
scale. You say on the
scale. You say on the Williamson
to remention it. You can make your own
scale. You say on the Williamson scale
of
of one
of one to
of one to 100.
of one to 100. See,
of one to 100. See, where
of one to 100. See, where 100
of one to 100. See, where 100 is
of one to 100. See, where 100 is God
of one to 100. See, where 100 is God and
zero,
zero, we
of one to 100. See, where 100 is God and
zero, we don't
zero, we don't want
of one to 100. See, where 100 is God and
zero, we don't want to
zero, we don't want to mention
of one to 100. See, where 100 is God and
zero, we don't want to mention what
zero, we don't want to mention what it
is.
is. and
is. and uh
is. and uh you
is. and uh you know
is. and uh you know you
is. and uh you know you can
is. and uh you know you can make
is. and uh you know you can make a
is. and uh you know you can make a scale
in
in which
is. and uh you know you can make a scale
in which the
in which the number
is. and uh you know you can make a scale
in which the number 50
in which the number 50 is
is. and uh you know you can make a scale
in which the number 50 is true.
in which the number 50 is true. You
is. and uh you know you can make a scale
in which the number 50 is true. You see,
you
you say
you say on
you say on our
you say on our scale,
you say on our scale, the
you say on our scale, the Williamson
scale,
scale, let's
you say on our scale, the Williamson
scale, let's do
scale, let's do it.
you say on our scale, the Williamson
scale, let's do it. We'll
scale, let's do it. We'll just
you say on our scale, the Williamson
scale, let's do it. We'll just make
scale, let's do it. We'll just make a
scale
scale of
scale of one
scale of one to
scale of one to 100.
scale of one to 100. 50
scale of one to 100. 50 is
scale of one to 100. 50 is truth.
scale of one to 100. 50 is truth. Uh
well,
well, we
scale of one to 100. 50 is truth. Uh
well, we redo
well, we redo the
scale of one to 100. 50 is truth. Uh
well, we redo the same
well, we redo the same uh
scale of one to 100. 50 is truth. Uh
well, we redo the same uh presidential
addresses
addresses over
addresses over 50.
addresses over 50. Okay?
addresses over 50. Okay? See,
addresses over 50. Okay? See, so
addresses over 50. Okay? See, so we
addresses over 50. Okay? See, so we can
you
you can
addresses over 50. Okay? See, so we can
you can make
you can make your
addresses over 50. Okay? See, so we can
you can make your own
you can make your own scale.
addresses over 50. Okay? See, so we can
you can make your own scale. You
you can make your own scale. You can
make
make it
make it from
1 to
1 to 2
make it from
1 to 2 cm
1 to 2 cm and
make it from
1 to 2 cm and then
1 to 2 cm and then every
make it from
1 to 2 cm and then every millimeter
would
would mean,
would mean, you
would mean, you know
would mean, you know what
would mean, you know what I'm
would mean, you know what I'm saying?
You
You can
would mean, you know what I'm saying?
You can make
You can make it
would mean, you know what I'm saying?
You can make it a thousand
You can make it a thousand miles
would mean, you know what I'm saying?
You can make it a thousand miles long
and
and say,
and say, you
and say, you know,
and say, you know, anything
and say, you know, anything that's
and say, you know, anything that's over
500 miles
500 miles long
and say, you know, anything that's over
500 miles long is
500 miles long is true
and say, you know, anything that's over
500 miles long is true and
500 miles long is true and anything
that's
that's under
that's under 500
that's under 500 miles
that's under 500 miles is
that's under 500 miles is wrong.
that's under 500 miles is wrong. So,
you're
you're not
that's under 500 miles is wrong. So,
you're not stuck
you're not stuck with
that's under 500 miles is wrong. So,
you're not stuck with we
you're not stuck with we just
that's under 500 miles is wrong. So,
you're not stuck with we just picked
you're not stuck with we just picked one
to
to a,000
to a,000 because
to a,000 because it
to a,000 because it was
to a,000 because it was obvious
to a,000 because it was obvious and
because
because actually
to a,000 because it was obvious and
because actually these
because actually these numbers
to a,000 because it was obvious and
because actually these numbers become
extremely
extremely huge
extremely huge as
extremely huge as you
extremely huge as you go
extremely huge as you go up.
extremely huge as you go up. uh
extremely huge as you go up. uh you
extremely huge as you go up. uh you end
up
up in
extremely huge as you go up. uh you end
up in 20
up in 20 and
extremely huge as you go up. uh you end
up in 20 and 30
up in 20 and 30 zeros
extremely huge as you go up. uh you end
up in 20 and 30 zeros and
up in 20 and 30 zeros and um
and
and we
and we had
and we had to
and we had to use
and we had to use uh
and we had to use uh des
and we had to use uh des uh
and we had to use uh des uh we
and we had to use uh des uh we had
and we had to use uh des uh we had to
use
use the
and we had to use uh des uh we had to
use the logarithm
use the logarithm you
and we had to use uh des uh we had to
use the logarithm you know
use the logarithm you know we
and we had to use uh des uh we had to
use the logarithm you know we had
use the logarithm you know we had to
and we had to use uh des uh we had to
use the logarithm you know we had to use
logarithms
logarithms to
logarithms to make
logarithms to make it
logarithms to make it u
logarithms to make it u workable
logarithms to make it u workable so
logarithms to make it u workable so what
were
were the
logarithms to make it u workable so what
were the questions
were the questions in
logarithms to make it u workable so what
were the questions in the
were the questions in the back
logarithms to make it u workable so what
were the questions in the back because
we
we want
we want to
we want to knock
we want to knock it
we want to knock it dead
we want to knock it dead once
we want to knock it dead once and
forever
forever yeah
we want to knock it dead once and
forever yeah somebody
forever yeah somebody can
we want to knock it dead once and
forever yeah somebody can speak
forever yeah somebody can speak for
we want to knock it dead once and
forever yeah somebody can speak for her
so
so I
so I can
so I can hear
so I can hear what
so I can hear what she
so I can hear what she says
>> go
>> go ahead
so I can hear what she says
>> go ahead or
>> go ahead or you
so I can hear what she says
>> go ahead or you can
>> go ahead or you can come
so I can hear what she says
>> go ahead or you can come up
>> go ahead or you can come up if
so I can hear what she says
>> go ahead or you can come up if you
>> go ahead or you can come up if you want
>> to
>> to calibrate
>> to calibrate in
>> to calibrate in your
Yes.
>> The
>> The uh
>> The uh the
>> The uh the uh
All right.
All right. Okay.
>> The uh the uh
All right. Okay. The
All right. Okay. The kinesiologic
>> The uh the uh
All right. Okay. The kinesiologic test
is
is not
is not suitable
is not suitable for
is not suitable for fuss
is not suitable for fuss budgets.
The
The reason
is not suitable for fuss budgets.
The reason is
your
your experience
your experience of
your experience of reality
your experience of reality is
your experience of reality is is
constantly
constantly fluctuating.
your experience of reality is is
constantly fluctuating. you
constantly fluctuating. you understand
just
just in
just in the
just in the sheer
just in the sheer quantum
just in the sheer quantum mechanics
just in the sheer quantum mechanics of
it
it that
just in the sheer quantum mechanics of
it that my
it that my having
just in the sheer quantum mechanics of
it that my having asked
it that my having asked it
just in the sheer quantum mechanics of
it that my having asked it once
it that my having asked it once has
already
already changed
already changed the
already changed the universe.
already changed the universe. Um
already changed the universe. Um no
before
before I
already changed the universe. Um no
before I was
before I was listening
already changed the universe. Um no
before I was listening to
before I was listening to the
already changed the universe. Um no
before I was listening to the music
before I was listening to the music and
and
and what
and what I
and what I was
and what I was asking
and what I was asking her
and what I was asking her was
and what I was asking her was the
thought
thought of
and what I was asking her was the
thought of the
thought of the music.
and what I was asking her was the
thought of the music. So
thought of the music. So you
and what I was asking her was the
thought of the music. So you are
correct.
correct. Um
correct. Um I
correct. Um I was
correct. Um I was asking
correct. Um I was asking her
correct. Um I was asking her what
correct. Um I was asking her what the
thought
thought of
correct. Um I was asking her what the
thought of the
thought of the music
correct. Um I was asking her what the
thought of the music was
thought of the music was and
correct. Um I was asking her what the
thought of the music was and the
thought of the music was and the thought
of
of the
of the music
of the music as
of the music as I
of the music as I thought
of the music as I thought of
of the music as I thought of it
of the music as I thought of it was
of the music as I thought of it was 720.
The
The subjective
of the music as I thought of it was 720.
The subjective experience
The subjective experience of
of the music as I thought of it was 720.
The subjective experience of the
The subjective experience of the music
is
is more
is more like
is more like 740.
Um
Um so
is more like 740.
Um so that
Um so that is
is more like 740.
Um so that is another
Um so that is another reason
is more like 740.
Um so that is another reason for
variation
variation in
variation in kinesiologic
variation in kinesiologic response.
variation in kinesiologic response. Some
people
people process
variation in kinesiologic response. Some
people process primarily
people process primarily visual,
variation in kinesiologic response. Some
people process primarily visual, some
auditory,
some
some emotional.
auditory,
some emotional. So
some emotional. So if
auditory,
some emotional. So if I
some emotional. So if I say
uh
uh my
uh my aunt's
uh my aunt's energy
uh my aunt's energy is
uh my aunt's energy is at
uh my aunt's energy is at such
uh my aunt's energy is at such and
uh my aunt's energy is at such and such,
if
if we
uh my aunt's energy is at such and such,
if we both
if we both hold
uh my aunt's energy is at such and such,
if we both hold the
if we both hold the aunt
uh my aunt's energy is at such and such,
if we both hold the aunt in
if we both hold the aunt in mind,
uh my aunt's energy is at such and such,
if we both hold the aunt in mind, she's
holding
holding the
holding the feeling
holding the feeling of
holding the feeling of being
holding the feeling of being with
holding the feeling of being with her
aunt.
aunt. The
holding the feeling of being with her
aunt. The other
aunt. The other person
holding the feeling of being with her
aunt. The other person is
aunt. The other person is holding
holding the feeling of being with her
aunt. The other person is holding a
picture
picture of
picture of her
picture of her aunt
picture of her aunt from
picture of her aunt from childhood
whether
whether their
picture of her aunt from childhood
whether their aunt
whether their aunt and
picture of her aunt from childhood
whether their aunt and her
whether their aunt and her mother
picture of her aunt from childhood
whether their aunt and her mother were
photographed
photographed together.
photographed together. Another
photographed together. Another person
photographed together. Another person is
holding
holding in
photographed together. Another person is
holding in mind
holding in mind a
photographed together. Another person is
holding in mind a memory
holding in mind a memory of
photographed together. Another person is
holding in mind a memory of being
holding in mind a memory of being at
photographed together. Another person is
holding in mind a memory of being at her
aunt's
aunt's house
aunt's house and
aunt's house and the
aunt's house and the aunt
aunt's house and the aunt was
aunt's house and the aunt was making
cookies.
cookies. So
aunt's house and the aunt was making
cookies. So you're
cookies. So you're going
aunt's house and the aunt was making
cookies. So you're going to
cookies. So you're going to get
variation.
variation. Now
variation. Now every
variation. Now every time
variation. Now every time and
variation. Now every time and we
variation. Now every time and we said
every
every time
variation. Now every time and we said
every time you
every time you ask
variation. Now every time and we said
every time you ask the
every time you ask the question
variation. Now every time and we said
every time you ask the question you've
already
already changed
already changed the
already changed the response.
already changed the response. There's
already changed the response. There's a
little
little more
already changed the response. There's a
little more advanced
little more advanced u
already changed the response. There's a
little more advanced u understanding
little more advanced u understanding in
quantum
quantum mechanics
quantum mechanics having
quantum mechanics having which
quantum mechanics having which is
quantum mechanics having which is called
the
the xeno
quantum mechanics having which is called
the xeno effect.
the xeno effect. The
quantum mechanics having which is called
the xeno effect. The xeno
the xeno effect. The xeno effect
quantum mechanics having which is called
the xeno effect. The xeno effect is
the xeno effect. The xeno effect is that
if
if you
if you keep
if you keep asking
if you keep asking a
if you keep asking a yes
if you keep asking a yes question
repeatedly
repeatedly rapidly,
if you keep asking a yes question
repeatedly rapidly, you
repeatedly rapidly, you tend
if you keep asking a yes question
repeatedly rapidly, you tend to
repeatedly rapidly, you tend to fix
if you keep asking a yes question
repeatedly rapidly, you tend to fix the
answer
answer in
answer in yes.
The
The answer
answer in yes.
The answer the
The answer the capacity
answer in yes.
The answer the capacity to
The answer the capacity to respond
differently
differently than
differently than yes
differently than yes diminishes.
differently than yes diminishes. If
differently than yes diminishes. If I
repeatedly
repeatedly ask
differently than yes diminishes. If I
repeatedly ask the
repeatedly ask the same
differently than yes diminishes. If I
repeatedly ask the same question
repeatedly ask the same question which
is
is answer
is answer with
is answer with yes,
is answer with yes, the
is answer with yes, the xeno
is answer with yes, the xeno effect
is answer with yes, the xeno effect is
that
that you
is answer with yes, the xeno effect is
that you tend
that you tend to
is answer with yes, the xeno effect is
that you tend to freeze
that you tend to freeze that
is answer with yes, the xeno effect is
that you tend to freeze that response
that you tend to freeze that response in
the
the yes
the yes box.
the yes box. Okay.
the
the so
the yes box. Okay.
the so the
the so the experience
the yes box. Okay.
the so the experience of
the so the experience of it
the yes box. Okay.
the so the experience of it um
the so the experience of it um changes
because
because of
because of the
because of the audience
because of the audience and
because of the audience and the
because of the audience and the and
because of the audience and the and the
fact
fact we're
because of the audience and the and the
fact we're giving
fact we're giving a
because of the audience and the and the
fact we're giving a lecture
fact we're giving a lecture and
because of the audience and the and the
fact we're giving a lecture and we're
not
not doing
not doing it
not doing it at
not doing it at home.
not doing it at home. See
not doing it at home. See if
not doing it at home. See if I
not doing it at home. See if I ask
not doing it at home. See if I ask the
same
same question
not doing it at home. See if I ask the
same question for
same question for a
not doing it at home. See if I ask the
same question for a research
same question for a research purpose
then
then I
then I do
then I do it
then I do it I
then I do it I do
then I do it I do it
then I do it I do it differently
then I do it I do it differently today
we're
we're just
then I do it I do it differently today
we're just doing
we're just doing it
then I do it I do it differently today
we're just doing it for
we're just doing it for demonstration
then I do it I do it differently today
we're just doing it for demonstration of
the
the technique
the technique itself.
the technique itself. Okay.
>> Oh
>> Oh yes.
the technique itself. Okay.
>> Oh yes. Well,
>> Oh yes. Well, the
the technique itself. Okay.
>> Oh yes. Well, the fact
>> Oh yes. Well, the fact that
the technique itself. Okay.
>> Oh yes. Well, the fact that you
>> Oh yes. Well, the fact that you have
the technique itself. Okay.
>> Oh yes. Well, the fact that you have a
stake
stake in
stake in the
stake in the question
stake in the question means
stake in the question means a
stake in the question means a stake
stake in the question means a stake in
the
the yes
stake in the question means a stake in
the yes or
the yes or no.
stake in the question means a stake in
the yes or no. You
the yes or no. You don't
stake in the question means a stake in
the yes or no. You don't have
the yes or no. You don't have a
stake in the question means a stake in
the yes or no. You don't have a stake
the yes or no. You don't have a stake in
the
the question.
the question. What
the question. What you're
the question. What you're asking
the question. What you're asking is
the question. What you're asking is the
truth.
truth. You're
the question. What you're asking is the
truth. You're asking
truth. You're asking is,
the question. What you're asking is the
truth. You're asking is, you
truth. You're asking is, you know,
the question. What you're asking is the
truth. You're asking is, you know, this
is
is good
is good for
is good for me
is good for me or
is good for me or not.
is good for me or not. If
is good for me or not. If you're
is good for me or not. If you're trying
to
to prove
is good for me or not. If you're trying
to prove that
to prove that chocolate
is good for me or not. If you're trying
to prove that chocolate is
to prove that chocolate is harmless,
that's
that's different.
Then
Then you
that's different.
Then you would
Then you would have
that's different.
Then you would have a
Then you would have a vested
that's different.
Then you would have a vested interest.
Vested
Vested interest
Vested interest means
Vested interest means you
Vested interest means you have
Vested interest means you have a
positionality.
positionality. Now,
Vested interest means you have a
positionality. Now, you
positionality. Now, you can
Vested interest means you have a
positionality. Now, you can say
positionality. Now, you can say this
Vested interest means you have a
positionality. Now, you can say this is
compatible
compatible with
compatible with my
compatible with my body's
compatible with my body's health.
compatible with my body's health. Well,
this
this is
compatible with my body's health. Well,
this is not
this is not compatible
compatible with my body's health. Well,
this is not compatible with
this is not compatible with my
compatible with my body's health. Well,
this is not compatible with my body's
health.
health. And
health. And you
health. And you see,
health. And you see, you
health. And you see, you al
health. And you see, you al also
health. And you see, you al also ask
permission.
permission. And
health. And you see, you al also ask
permission. And sometimes
permission. And sometimes you'll
health. And you see, you al also ask
permission. And sometimes you'll get
permission. And sometimes you'll get a
no
no to
no to the
no to the permission.
no to the permission. And
no to the permission. And then
no to the permission. And then you
no to the permission. And then you find
it
it the
no to the permission. And then you find
it the no
it the no is
no to the permission. And then you find
it the no is because
it the no is because it's
no to the permission. And then you find
it the no is because it's not
it the no is because it's not worded
correctly.
Uh
Uh I'll
correctly.
Uh I'll speak
Uh I'll speak about
correctly.
Uh I'll speak about self
Uh I'll speak about self testing.
correctly.
Uh I'll speak about self testing. I'm
glad
glad you
glad you brought
glad you brought that
glad you brought that up.
glad you brought that up. Yes,
glad you brought that up. Yes, self
testing.
testing. Many
glad you brought that up. Yes, self
testing. Many people
testing. Many people ask
glad you brought that up. Yes, self
testing. Many people ask if
testing. Many people ask if they
glad you brought that up. Yes, self
testing. Many people ask if they don't
have
have a
have a partner.
have a partner. Um
you
you just
have a partner. Um
you just hold
you just hold these
have a partner. Um
you just hold these fingers
you just hold these fingers uh
have a partner. Um
you just hold these fingers uh like
you just hold these fingers uh like this
together.
together. You
together. You hold
together. You hold them
together. You hold them together.
together. You hold them together. Don't
forget,
forget, you're
together. You hold them together. Don't
forget, you're always
forget, you're always dealing
together. You hold them together. Don't
forget, you're always dealing with
relative
relative strength.
relative strength. Her
relative strength. Her relative
relative strength. Her relative strength
before
before and
relative strength. Her relative strength
before and after.
before and after. If
relative strength. Her relative strength
before and after. If she
before and after. If she was
relative strength. Her relative strength
before and after. If she was a
before and after. If she was a fullback
from
from a
from a football
from a football team,
from a football team, you
from a football team, you know
from a football team, you know that
you're
you're dealing
from a football team, you know that
you're dealing with
you're dealing with different
from a football team, you know that
you're dealing with different um
energies,
energies, any
energies, any different
energies, any different powers.
energies, any different powers. All
right.
right. So
energies, any different powers. All
right. So anyway,
right. So anyway, you
energies, any different powers. All
right. So anyway, you go
right. So anyway, you go like
energies, any different powers. All
right. So anyway, you go like this.
right. So anyway, you go like this. You
hold
hold what
hold what you
hold what you have
hold what you have in
hold what you have in mind
hold what you have in mind and
hold what you have in mind and say,
hold what you have in mind and say, "I
have
have permission
hold what you have in mind and say, "I
have permission to
have permission to ask
hold what you have in mind and say, "I
have permission to ask this
have permission to ask this question."
Um,
Um, the
Um, the feeling
Um, the feeling of
Um, the feeling of the
Um, the feeling of the music,
Um, the feeling of the music, the
feeling
feeling of
Um, the feeling of the music, the
feeling of the
feeling of the music
Um, the feeling of the music, the
feeling of the music we're
feeling of the music we're listening
Um, the feeling of the music, the
feeling of the music we're listening to
is
is over
is over 720.
is over 720. The
is over 720. The feeling
is over 720. The feeling of
is over 720. The feeling of it
is over 720. The feeling of it is
is over 720. The feeling of it is over
735.
This
This feeling
This feeling of
This feeling of it
This feeling of it is
This feeling of it is over
This feeling of it is over 740.
This feeling of it is over 740. The
feeling
feeling of
This feeling of it is over 740. The
feeling of it
feeling of it is
This feeling of it is over 740. The
feeling of it is over
feeling of it is over 745.
All
All right.
All right. You
All right. You see,
All right. You see, I'm
All right. You see, I'm being
All right. You see, I'm being a
All right. You see, I'm being a little
more
more specific
All right. You see, I'm being a little
more specific now
more specific now because
All right. You see, I'm being a little
more specific now because of
more specific now because of your
question.
question. Um,
you
you go
question. Um,
you go weak
you go weak then.
question. Um,
you go weak then. So
you go weak then. So the
question. Um,
you go weak then. So the technique
you go weak then. So the technique then
is
is like
is like anything
is like anything else
is like anything else like
is like anything else like riding
is like anything else like riding a
bicycle.
bicycle. It
is like anything else like riding a
bicycle. It takes
bicycle. It takes a
is like anything else like riding a
bicycle. It takes a little
bicycle. It takes a little practice.
You're
You're holding
You're holding this
You're holding this the
You're holding this the same.
You're holding this the same. You
You're holding this the same. You you
get
get to
You're holding this the same. You you
get to know
get to know how
You're holding this the same. You you
get to know how to
get to know how to hold
You're holding this the same. You you
get to know how to hold it
get to know how to hold it so
You're holding this the same. You you
get to know how to hold it so that
you're
you're you
you're you can
you're you can you're
you're you can you're pretty
you're you can you're pretty predictably
very
very close.
you're you can you're pretty predictably
very close. And
very close. And then
you're you can you're pretty predictably
very close. And then you
very close. And then you use
you're you can you're pretty predictably
very close. And then you use this
very close. And then you use this as
you're you can you're pretty predictably
very close. And then you use this as a
hook
hook and
hook and you
hook and you say
hook and you say what
hook and you say what I'm
hook and you say what I'm holding
hook and you say what I'm holding in
mind
mind uh
hook and you say what I'm holding in
mind uh the
mind uh the image
hook and you say what I'm holding in
mind uh the image I'm
mind uh the image I'm holding
hook and you say what I'm holding in
mind uh the image I'm holding in
mind uh the image I'm holding in mind
hook and you say what I'm holding in
mind uh the image I'm holding in mind is
integrous.
integrous. You
integrous. You say
integrous. You say the
integrous. You say the image
integrous. You say the image I'm
integrous. You say the image I'm holding
in
in mind
integrous. You say the image I'm holding
in mind is
in mind is below
integrous. You say the image I'm holding
in mind is below 200,
in mind is below 200, below
integrous. You say the image I'm holding
in mind is below 200, below 100,
in mind is below 200, below 100, below
95.
low
low 90.
95.
low 90. Okay.
So,
So, one
So, one can
So, one can do
So, one can do that.
So, one can do that. Um,
now
now it
So, one can do that. Um,
now it depends
now it depends on
So, one can do that. Um,
now it depends on spiritual
now it depends on spiritual honesty.
So, one can do that. Um,
now it depends on spiritual honesty. One
has
has to
has to really
has to really be
has to really be rigorous.
There's
There's nothing
has to really be rigorous.
There's nothing wrong
There's nothing wrong with
has to really be rigorous.
There's nothing wrong with having
There's nothing wrong with having a
positionality.
positionality. I
positionality. I didn't
positionality. I didn't want
positionality. I didn't want to
positionality. I didn't want to infer
that
that to
positionality. I didn't want to infer
that to your
that to your question
positionality. I didn't want to infer
that to your question either.
that to your question either. Nothing
wrong
wrong with
wrong with having
wrong with having it
wrong with having it so
wrong with having it so long
wrong with having it so long as
wrong with having it so long as you're
aware
aware of
wrong with having it so long as you're
aware of it.
aware of it. It's
wrong with having it so long as you're
aware of it. It's when
aware of it. It's when it's
wrong with having it so long as you're
aware of it. It's when it's an
unconscious
positionality
positionality that
unconscious
positionality that you
positionality that you you
unconscious
positionality that you you get
positionality that you you get more
erroneous
erroneous answers.
erroneous answers. If
erroneous answers. If you
erroneous answers. If you have
erroneous answers. If you have a
conscious
conscious positionality,
erroneous answers. If you have a
conscious positionality, you
conscious positionality, you can
erroneous answers. If you have a
conscious positionality, you can use
spiritual
spiritual techniques
spiritual techniques to
spiritual techniques to transcend
spiritual techniques to transcend it.
You
You can
spiritual techniques to transcend it.
You can surrender
You can surrender your
spiritual techniques to transcend it.
You can surrender your health
You can surrender your health to
spiritual techniques to transcend it.
You can surrender your health to God.
You can surrender your health to God. I
mean,
mean, it
mean, it doesn't
mean, it doesn't make
mean, it doesn't make any
mean, it doesn't make any difference
whether
whether you
mean, it doesn't make any difference
whether you live
whether you live or
mean, it doesn't make any difference
whether you live or die.
whether you live or die. You
mean, it doesn't make any difference
whether you live or die. You know,
whether you live or die. You know, some
people
people worry
people worry about
people worry about war.
people worry about war. People
people worry about war. People are
people worry about war. People are going
to
to get
people worry about war. People are going
to get killed.
to get killed. Of
people worry about war. People are going
to get killed. Of course,
to get killed. Of course, they
people worry about war. People are going
to get killed. Of course, they get
killed.
killed. I
killed. I mean,
killed. I mean, it
killed. I mean, it doesn't
killed. I mean, it doesn't make
killed. I mean, it doesn't make any
difference.
difference. They
killed. I mean, it doesn't make any
difference. They get
difference. They get killed
killed. I mean, it doesn't make any
difference. They get killed or
difference. They get killed or you
killed. I mean, it doesn't make any
difference. They get killed or you don't
kill
kill them.
kill them. But
kill them. But that's
kill them. But that's a
kill them. But that's a certain
kill them. But that's a certain level
kill them. But that's a certain level of
consciousness
consciousness which
kill them. But that's a certain level of
consciousness which not
consciousness which not may
kill them. But that's a certain level of
consciousness which not may not
consciousness which not may not be
kill them. But that's a certain level of
consciousness which not may not be one
that
that prevails
in
in which
that prevails
in which people
in which people have
that prevails
in which people have a
in which people have a big
that prevails
in which people have a big stake
in which people have a big stake in
that prevails
in which people have a big stake in one
one
one side
one side or
one side or the
one side or the other
one side or the other side.
one side or the other side. One
one side or the other side. One thing
happening
happening or
one side or the other side. One thing
happening or the
happening or the other
one side or the other side. One thing
happening or the other thing
happening or the other thing happening.
Um
Um so
Um so you
Um so you can
Um so you can first
Um so you can first detect
Um so you can first detect what
Um so you can first detect what the
positionality
positionality is
Um so you can first detect what the
positionality is and
positionality is and then
Um so you can first detect what the
positionality is and then try
positionality is and then try to
transcend
transcend it.
transcend it. All
transcend it. All positionalities
eventually
eventually um
transcend it. All positionalities
eventually um are
eventually um are tr
transcend it. All positionalities
eventually um are tr surrender
eventually um are tr surrender surrender
to
to God.
to God. Um
whether
whether it
to God. Um
whether it cures
whether it cures or
to God. Um
whether it cures or it
whether it cures or it doesn't
to God. Um
whether it cures or it doesn't cure.
That's
That's why
That's why I
That's why I tell
That's why I tell people
That's why I tell people if
That's why I tell people if you
That's why I tell people if you do
That's why I tell people if you do the
course
course of
That's why I tell people if you do the
course of miracles
course of miracles I
That's why I tell people if you do the
course of miracles I say
course of miracles I say I've
That's why I tell people if you do the
course of miracles I say I've got
course of miracles I say I've got this
rheumatoid
rheumatoid this
rheumatoid this and
rheumatoid this and I
rheumatoid this and I say
rheumatoid this and I say many
rheumatoid this and I say many people
done
done the
rheumatoid this and I say many people
done the course
done the course of
rheumatoid this and I say many people
done the course of miracles
done the course of miracles are
rheumatoid this and I say many people
done the course of miracles are cured
done the course of miracles are cured of
it.
it. And
it. And if
it. And if you're
it. And if you're not
it. And if you're not cured
it. And if you're not cured of
it. And if you're not cured of it
it. And if you're not cured of it it
doesn't
doesn't matter.
it. And if you're not cured of it it
doesn't matter. If
doesn't matter. If you
it. And if you're not cured of it it
doesn't matter. If you really
doesn't matter. If you really get
it. And if you're not cured of it it
doesn't matter. If you really get the
course
course of
course of miracles,
course of miracles, it
course of miracles, it really
course of miracles, it really doesn't
matter
matter whether
course of miracles, it really doesn't
matter whether the
matter whether the arthritis
course of miracles, it really doesn't
matter whether the arthritis remains
matter whether the arthritis remains or
not.
It's
It's irrelevant.
It's an
It's an so
It's an so what?
It's an so what? It's
It's an so what? It's a
It's an so what? It's a nothingness.
Uh
Uh so
It's an so what? It's a nothingness.
Uh so you
Uh so you can
It's an so what? It's a nothingness.
Uh so you can then
Uh so you can then transcend
It's an so what? It's a nothingness.
Uh so you can then transcend your
positionality.
positionality. Go
positionality. Go beyond
positionality. Go beyond it.
positionality. Go beyond it. You
positionality. Go beyond it. You can
also
also ask
positionality. Go beyond it. You can
also ask a
also ask a friend
positionality. Go beyond it. You can
also ask a friend to
also ask a friend to do
positionality. Go beyond it. You can
also ask a friend to do it.
Ask
Ask if
rudabas
rudabas are
Ask if
rudabas are bad
rudabas are bad for
Ask if
rudabas are bad for me.
rudabas are bad for me. You
Ask if
rudabas are bad for me. You know,
rudabas are bad for me. You know, you
can
can have
can have a
can have a friend
can have a friend do
can have a friend do it.
can have a friend do it. You
can have a friend do it. You can't
become
become non
can have a friend do it. You can't
become non positional
become non positional about
can have a friend do it. You can't
become non positional about it.
I
I get
I get lots
I get lots of
I get lots of letters
I get lots of letters requesting
I get lots of letters requesting things
that
that the
I get lots of letters requesting things
that the positionality
that the positionality is
I get lots of letters requesting things
that the positionality is so
that the positionality is so extreme
that
that you
that you can
that you can hardly
that you can hardly open
that you can hardly open the
that you can hardly open the envelope
that
that it
that you can hardly open the envelope
that it jumps
that it jumps at.
that you can hardly open the envelope
that it jumps at. You
that it jumps at. You know
that you can hardly open the envelope
that it jumps at. You know what
that it jumps at. You know what I
that you can hardly open the envelope
that it jumps at. You know what I mean?
He
He wants
He wants to
He wants to find
He wants to find his
He wants to find his dead
He wants to find his dead brother
He wants to find his dead brother so
that
that he
He wants to find his dead brother so
that he can
that he can collect.
He wants to find his dead brother so
that he can collect. You
that he can collect. You know
He wants to find his dead brother so
that he can collect. You know what
that he can collect. You know what I
mean?
mean? My
mean? My dead
mean? My dead brother
mean? My dead brother is
mean? My dead brother is on
mean? My dead brother is on the
mean? My dead brother is on the off
mean? My dead brother is on the off the
highway
highway near
mean? My dead brother is on the off the
highway near New
highway near New Mexico
mean? My dead brother is on the off the
highway near New Mexico 169.
highway near New Mexico 169. You
mean? My dead brother is on the off the
highway near New Mexico 169. You know,
all
all right.
all right. So
all right. So he's
all right. So he's got
all right. So he's got a
all right. So he's got a letter
all right. So he's got a letter lawyer
lawyer's
lawyer's letter
all right. So he's got a letter lawyer
lawyer's letter to
lawyer's letter to find
all right. So he's got a letter lawyer
lawyer's letter to find the
lawyer's letter to find the body.
all right. So he's got a letter lawyer
lawyer's letter to find the body. Okay.
All right.
All right. Any
All right. Any other
All right. Any other questions?
All right. Any other questions? Yes.
>> For
>> For better
All right. Any other questions? Yes.
>> For better understand
you
you elaborate
you elaborate a
you elaborate a bit
you elaborate a bit more
you elaborate a bit more on
you elaborate a bit more on why
you elaborate a bit more on why my
you elaborate a bit more on why my right
hand.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Well,
>> Yes. Well, the
>> Yes. Well, the intentionality
>> Yes. Well, the intentionality activates
the
the physical
activates
activates the
activates the physical
activates the physical system.
activates the physical system. And
activates the physical system. And of
course
course that
activates the physical system. And of
course that is
course that is a
activates the physical system. And of
course that is a great
course that is a great deal
activates the physical system. And of
course that is a great deal of
course that is a great deal of the
discussion
discussion in
discussion in kinesiology
discussion in kinesiology in
discussion in kinesiology in u
discussion in kinesiology in u in
quantum
quantum mechanics
discussion in kinesiology in u in
quantum mechanics in
quantum mechanics in science
discussion in kinesiology in u in
quantum mechanics in science and
consciousness
consciousness and
consciousness and people
consciousness and people have
consciousness and people have those
consciousness and people have those kind
of
of questions
consciousness and people have those kind
of questions they're
of questions they're really
consciousness and people have those kind
of questions they're really best
answered
answered at
answered at those
answered at those kind
answered at those kind of
answered at those kind of conferences
they
they go
answered at those kind of conferences
they go into
they go into that
answered at those kind of conferences
they go into that rather
they go into that rather extensively
answered at those kind of conferences
they go into that rather extensively not
only
only that
only that but
only that but the
only that but the mathematics
only that but the mathematics and
only that but the mathematics and the
theory
theory of
only that but the mathematics and the
theory of the
theory of the mathematics
um
um one
um one can
um one can pull
um one can pull off
um one can pull off the
um one can pull off the internet
um one can pull off the internet right
now
now a
um one can pull off the internet right
now a quite
now a quite an
um one can pull off the internet right
now a quite an extensive
now a quite an extensive discussion
um one can pull off the internet right
now a quite an extensive discussion of
that
that Brock
that Brock where
that Brock where do
that Brock where do you
that Brock where do you where
that Brock where do you where do
that Brock where do you where do we
that Brock where do you where do we find
that
that you
that Brock where do you where do we find
that you pulled
that you pulled off
that Brock where do you where do we find
that you pulled off that
that you pulled off that one
that Brock where do you where do we find
that you pulled off that one 81
that you pulled off that one 81 pages
that Brock where do you where do we find
that you pulled off that one 81 pages or
I
I forget
I forget where
I forget where he
I forget where he picked
I forget where he picked it
I forget where he picked it off,
I forget where he picked it off, but
anybody
anybody wants
I forget where he picked it off, but
anybody wants to
anybody wants to know
I forget where he picked it off, but
anybody wants to know if
anybody wants to know if you
I forget where he picked it off, but
anybody wants to know if you ask
anybody wants to know if you ask Brock.
Um,
Um, he
Um, he pulled
Um, he pulled it
Um, he pulled it off
Um, he pulled it off and
Um, he pulled it off and there's
there's
there's quite
Um, he pulled it off and there's
there's quite an
there's quite an intense
Um, he pulled it off and there's
there's quite an intense discussion
there's quite an intense discussion of
that.
that. Why
that. Why is
that. Why is it
that. Why is it that
that. Why is it that your
that. Why is it that your left
that. Why is it that your left arm
that. Why is it that your left arm moves
instead
instead of
that. Why is it that your left arm moves
instead of your
instead of your right
that. Why is it that your left arm moves
instead of your right arm
instead of your right arm and
that. Why is it that your left arm moves
instead of your right arm and um
instead of your right arm and um the
mathematical
mathematical predictabilities
mathematical predictabilities etc
mathematical predictabilities etc having
to
to do
mathematical predictabilities etc having
to do with
to do with choice
mathematical predictabilities etc having
to do with choice and
to do with choice and the
mathematical predictabilities etc having
to do with choice and the design
to do with choice and the design of
mathematical predictabilities etc having
to do with choice and the design of the
nervous
nervous system.
nervous system. And
nervous system. And of
nervous system. And of course
nervous system. And of course the
nervous system. And of course the answer
really
really is
nervous system. And of course the answer
really is neurologic
really is neurologic evolution
nervous system. And of course the answer
really is neurologic evolution over
really is neurologic evolution over the
courses
courses of
courses of time
courses of time and
courses of time and why
courses of time and why certain
courses of time and why certain synapses
have
have established
courses of time and why certain synapses
have established their
have established their dynamic
relationships
relationships etc
and
and by
relationships etc
and by bilateral
and by bilateral symmetry
relationships etc
and by bilateral symmetry and
propriception
propriception and
propriception and becomes
propriception and becomes extremely
complicated
um
um to
um to trace
um to trace its
um to trace its evolution
um to trace its evolution through
um to trace its evolution through the
evolution
evolution of
um to trace its evolution through the
evolution of the
evolution of the nervous
um to trace its evolution through the
evolution of the nervous system
evolution of the nervous system and
um to trace its evolution through the
evolution of the nervous system and its
complexity
complexity and
complexity and its
complexity and its neurochemistry
complexity and its neurochemistry and
its
its physics.
complexity and its neurochemistry and
its physics. Um
its physics. Um so
complexity and its neurochemistry and
its physics. Um so science
its physics. Um so science and
consciousness
consciousness conferences
consciousness conferences go
consciousness conferences go into
consciousness conferences go into that
quite
quite extensively.
It's
It's because
It's because you
It's because you have
It's because you have choice
It's because you have choice because
It's because you have choice because you
have
have choice
It's because you have choice because you
have choice and
have choice and then
It's because you have choice because you
have choice and then of
have choice and then of course
It's because you have choice because you
have choice and then of course certain
things
things become
things become automated
things become automated automated.
things become automated automated. So
when
when we
things become automated automated. So
when we said
when we said um
the
the response
the response is
the response is extremely
the response is extremely rapid
the response is extremely rapid and
the response is extremely rapid and if
you
you don't
the response is extremely rapid and if
you don't check
you don't check it
the response is extremely rapid and if
you don't check it right
you don't check it right then
the response is extremely rapid and if
you don't check it right then you'll
miss
miss it
miss it because
out
out of
miss it because
out of nature
out of nature we
miss it because
out of nature we our
out of nature we our propriceptive
responses
responses are
responses are anti-gravity.
So
So your
responses are anti-gravity.
So your anti-gravity
So your anti-gravity automat
responses are anti-gravity.
So your anti-gravity automat automated
responses
responses throughout
responses throughout 400
responses throughout 400 million
responses throughout 400 million years
of
of evolution
responses throughout 400 million years
of evolution will
of evolution will automatically
responses throughout 400 million years
of evolution will automatically give
of evolution will automatically give you
a
a false
a false positive.
And
And that's
a false positive.
And that's the
And that's the biggest
a false positive.
And that's the biggest trouble
And that's the biggest trouble we
a false positive.
And that's the biggest trouble we have
with
with men.
with men. Men
with men. Men tend
with men. Men tend to
with men. Men tend to be
with men. Men tend to be more
with men. Men tend to be more macho
with men. Men tend to be more macho and
you
you say
with men. Men tend to be more macho and
you say relax
you say relax and
uh
it's
it's hard
uh
it's hard to
it's hard to get
uh
it's hard to get them
it's hard to get them to
uh
it's hard to get them to let
it's hard to get them to let go
uh
it's hard to get them to let go be
it's hard to get them to let go be and
it's
it's because
it's because it's
it's because it's so
it's because it's so quick
it's because it's so quick and
it's because it's so quick and rapid.
It's
It's so
it's because it's so quick and rapid.
It's so quick
It's so quick and
it's because it's so quick and rapid.
It's so quick and rapid.
It's so quick and rapid. It's
instantaneous.
So
So it's
instantaneous.
So it's like
So it's like Gary
instantaneous.
So it's like Gary Kaspar's
So it's like Gary Kaspar's mind.
Yeah.
Yeah. He
Yeah. He the
Yeah. He the chess
Yeah. He the chess player
Yeah. He the chess player that
Yeah. He the chess player that beat
Yeah. He the chess player that beat uh
the
the computer
Yeah. He the chess player that beat uh
the computer the
the computer the second
Yeah. He the chess player that beat uh
the computer the second game.
the computer the second game. He
Yeah. He the chess player that beat uh
the computer the second game. He beat
him
him out of
him out of the
him out of the first
him out of the first game.
him out of the first game. I
him out of the first game. I think
him out of the first game. I think it
came
came to
him out of the first game. I think it
came to a
came to a draw
him out of the first game. I think it
came to a draw in
came to a draw in the
him out of the first game. I think it
came to a draw in the second
came to a draw in the second game.
If
If you
If you want
If you want to
If you want to appreciate
If you want to appreciate the
If you want to appreciate the function
of
of the
If you want to appreciate the function
of the London
of the London line
If you want to appreciate the function
of the London line here,
of the London line here, you
If you want to appreciate the function
of the London line here, you might
of the London line here, you might look
at
at the
at the fact
at the fact that
at the fact that the
at the fact that the computer
at the fact that the computer that
at the fact that the computer that Gary
Casper,
Casper, what's
at the fact that the computer that Gary
Casper, what's how
Casper, what's how does
at the fact that the computer that Gary
Casper, what's how does his
Casper, what's how does his name?
Casper's
Casper's off.
Casper's off. What's
Casper's off. What's his
Casper's off. What's his name?
Casper's off. What's his name? The
Casper's off. What's his name? The world
chess
chess champion.
Casper's off. What's his name? The world
chess champion. Yes.
chess champion. Yes. Well,
Casper's off. What's his name? The world
chess champion. Yes. Well, Big
chess champion. Yes. Well, Big Blue
Casper's off. What's his name? The world
chess champion. Yes. Well, Big Blue beat
him
him some
him some years
him some years ago,
him some years ago, but
him some years ago, but now
him some years ago, but now they've
him some years ago, but now they've got
a
a more
him some years ago, but now they've got
a more advanced
a more advanced computer
him some years ago, but now they've got
a more advanced computer and
a more advanced computer and Gary
him some years ago, but now they've got
a more advanced computer and Gary beat
the
the computer.
the computer. Um,
the
the more
the computer. Um,
the more advanced
the more advanced computer
the computer. Um,
the more advanced computer processes
the more advanced computer processes 10
million
million bits
million bits of
million bits of information
million bits of information per
million bits of information per second.
10 million
10 million per
million bits of information per second.
10 million per second.
Now
Now Gary
Now Gary got
Now Gary got the
Now Gary got the computers
Now Gary got the computers moves
Now Gary got the computers moves got
Now Gary got the computers moves got the
computer
computer baffled.
The
The baffle
The baffle didn't
The baffle didn't after
The baffle didn't after one
The baffle didn't after one move
The baffle didn't after one move the
computer
computer stopped
The baffle didn't after one move the
computer stopped for
computer stopped for 45
The baffle didn't after one move the
computer stopped for 45 minutes.
It
It stopped
It stopped for
It stopped for 45
It stopped for 45 minutes
at
at 10
It stopped for 45 minutes
at 10 million
at 10 million bits
It stopped for 45 minutes
at 10 million bits per
at 10 million bits per second.
45 minutes
45 minutes at
45 minutes at 10
45 minutes at 10 billion
45 minutes at 10 billion bits
45 minutes at 10 billion bits per
second.
After
After 45
After 45 minutes,
After 45 minutes, it
After 45 minutes, it made
After 45 minutes, it made a
After 45 minutes, it made a move
After 45 minutes, it made a move and
lost.
So
So the
So the question
So the question is,
So the question is, how
So the question is, how can
So the question is, how can this
So the question is, how can this man's
brain
brain process
at
at 10
at 10 million
at 10 million faster
at 10 million faster than
at 10 million faster than 10
at 10 million faster than 10 million
bits
bits of
at 10 million faster than 10 million
bits of per
bits of per second
at 10 million faster than 10 million
bits of per second and
bits of per second and beat
at 10 million faster than 10 million
bits of per second and beat this
computer?
Did
Did he
computer?
Did he do
Did he do it
computer?
Did he do it through
Did he do it through his
computer?
Did he do it through his celebration?
Uh,
Uh, we
Uh, we have
Uh, we have permission
Uh, we have permission to
Uh, we have permission to ask
Uh, we have permission to ask this.
Uh, we have permission to ask this. He
did
did it
Uh, we have permission to ask this. He
did it through
did it through celebration.
Uh, we have permission to ask this. He
did it through celebration. Is
did it through celebration. Is it
Uh, we have permission to ask this. He
did it through celebration. Is it He
did it through celebration. Is it He did
it
it through
it through holistic
it through holistic celebration.
it through holistic celebration. Oh,
it through holistic celebration. Oh, I
see.
see. He
it through holistic celebration. Oh, I
see. He did
see. He did it
it through holistic celebration. Oh, I
see. He did it out
see. He did it out of
it through holistic celebration. Oh, I
see. He did it out of knowingness.
see. He did it out of knowingness. He
did
did it
did it out
did it out of
did it out of nosis.
He
He did
did it out of nosis.
He did it
He did it out
did it out of nosis.
He did it out of
He did it out of the
did it out of nosis.
He did it out of the nosis
He did it out of the nosis of
knowingness
knowingness which
knowingness which calibrates
knowingness which calibrates around
knowingness which calibrates around 640.
Okay.
Okay. So,
knowingness which calibrates around 640.
Okay. So, the
Okay. So, the correlation
knowingness which calibrates around 640.
Okay. So, the correlation of
Okay. So, the correlation of all
knowingness which calibrates around 640.
Okay. So, the correlation of all that
information
information then
information then was
information then was done
information then was done in
information then was done in the
nonlinear
and
and then
and then channelled
and then channelled through
and then channelled through the
and then channelled through the linear.
So,
So, this
and then channelled through the linear.
So, this his
So, this his answerership
and then channelled through the linear.
So, this his answerership came
So, this his answerership came out
and then channelled through the linear.
So, this his answerership came out of
nosis.
nosis. He
nosis. He says
his
his answerership
nosis. He says
his answerership came
his answerership came out
nosis. He says
his answerership came out of
knowingness.
knowingness. While
knowingness. While the
knowingness. While the computer
knowingness. While the computer was
going
going through
knowingness. While the computer was
going through the
going through the linear
calculations,
he
he was
calculations,
he was enjoying
he was enjoying a
calculations,
he was enjoying a cigar
he was enjoying a cigar in
calculations,
he was enjoying a cigar in the
he was enjoying a cigar in the men's
room.
He
He came
room.
He came down
He came down and
room.
He came down and he
He came down and he looked
room.
He came down and he looked at
He came down and he looked at the
room.
He came down and he looked at the play
and
and he
and he said
that
that was
and he said
that was it.
That's
That's the
That's the way
That's the way we
That's the way we kill
That's the way we kill him
That's the way we kill him in
That's the way we kill him in karate.
And
And that's
That's the way we kill him in karate.
And that's where
And that's where I
That's the way we kill him in karate.
And that's where I killed
And that's where I killed that
That's the way we kill him in karate.
And that's where I killed that guy
And that's where I killed that guy in
the
That's
That's where
the
That's where we
That's where we killed
the
That's where we killed each
That's where we killed each other.
Just
Just the
Just the knowingness.
Just the knowingness. Wham!
Just the knowingness. Wham! Both
Just the knowingness. Wham! Both of
Just the knowingness. Wham! Both of us
at
at the
Just the knowingness. Wham! Both of us
at the same
at the same time,
Just the knowingness. Wham! Both of us
at the same time, skewered
at the same time, skewered like
Just the knowingness. Wham! Both of us
at the same time, skewered like two
chickens.
chickens. That's
chickens. That's how
chickens. That's how I
chickens. That's how I caught
chickens. That's how I caught the
chicken
chicken in
chickens. That's how I caught the
chicken in the
chicken in the hen
chickens. That's how I caught the
chicken in the hen house.
chicken in the hen house. There's
chickens. That's how I caught the
chicken in the hen house. There's a
chicken in the hen house. There's a sick
chicken.
chicken. They're
chicken. They're flying
chicken. They're flying all
chicken. They're flying all over
chicken. They're flying all over the
place.
place. I've
chicken. They're flying all over the
place. I've got
place. I've got a
chicken. They're flying all over the
place. I've got a net.
place. I've got a net. I'm
chicken. They're flying all over the
place. I've got a net. I'm trying
place. I've got a net. I'm trying to
catch
catch the
catch the chicken.
catch the chicken. This
catch the chicken. This is
catch the chicken. This is the
catch the chicken. This is the most
smart
smart wy
catch the chicken. This is the most
smart wy chicken
smart wy chicken that
catch the chicken. This is the most
smart wy chicken that ever
smart wy chicken that ever existed.
It's
It's got
It's got something
It's got something wrong
It's got something wrong with
It's got something wrong with his
feathers.
feathers. This
It's got something wrong with his
feathers. This needs
feathers. This needs lice
It's got something wrong with his
feathers. This needs lice powder
feathers. This needs lice powder on
It's got something wrong with his
feathers. This needs lice powder on it
or
or something.
or something. And
or something. And as
or something. And as I
or something. And as I go
or something. And as I go in
or something. And as I go in the
or something. And as I go in the chicken
coop,
coop, the
or something. And as I go in the chicken
coop, the dust
coop, the dust is
or something. And as I go in the chicken
coop, the dust is flying
coop, the dust is flying everywhere.
or something. And as I go in the chicken
coop, the dust is flying everywhere. Mad
chickens
chickens are
chickens are screeching.
chickens are screeching. It's
chickens are screeching. It's an
absolute
absolute mad
chickens are screeching. It's an
absolute mad house.
absolute mad house. There's
chickens are screeching. It's an
absolute mad house. There's absolutely
no
no way
no way you
no way you can
no way you can catch
no way you can catch this
no way you can catch this chicken.
If
If you
no way you can catch this chicken.
If you even
If you even look
no way you can catch this chicken.
If you even look like
If you even look like you're
no way you can catch this chicken.
If you even look like you're going
If you even look like you're going over
here,
here, he
here, he goes
here, he goes over
here, he goes over there.
Impossible.
I
I had
I had years
I had years of
I had years of karate.
I had years of karate. I
I had years of karate. I gave
I had years of karate. I gave it
I had years of karate. I gave it up.
Why?
because
because I
because I realized
because I realized it
because I realized it would
because I realized it would take
because I realized it would take forever
that
that way.
because I realized it would take forever
that way. I
that way. I got
because I realized it would take forever
that way. I got the
that way. I got the gist
because I realized it would take forever
that way. I got the gist of
that way. I got the gist of what
because I realized it would take forever
that way. I got the gist of what the
intended
intended realization
intended realization was
intended realization was and
intended realization was and I
intended realization was and I realized
by
by doing
intended realization was and I realized
by doing this
by doing this I
intended realization was and I realized
by doing this I want
by doing this I want to
intended realization was and I realized
by doing this I want to be
by doing this I want to be an
intended realization was and I realized
by doing this I want to be an old
by doing this I want to be an old man
intended realization was and I realized
by doing this I want to be an old man by
the
the time
the time I
the time I get
the time I get it.
the time I get it. So
the time I get it. So I
the time I get it. So I gave
the time I get it. So I gave up
the time I get it. So I gave up karate
even
even though
the time I get it. So I gave up karate
even though I
even though I had
the time I get it. So I gave up karate
even though I had a
even though I had a very
the time I get it. So I gave up karate
even though I had a very good
even though I had a very good teacher.
Year
Year many
Year many years
Year many years went
Year many years went by
Year many years went by and
Year many years went by and there
Year many years went by and there I'm
Year many years went by and there I'm in
the
the hen
Year many years went by and there I'm in
the hen house
the hen house and
Year many years went by and there I'm in
the hen house and uh
the hen house and uh this
Year many years went by and there I'm in
the hen house and uh this wy
the hen house and uh this wy chicken
Year many years went by and there I'm in
the hen house and uh this wy chicken is
beating
beating me
beating me at
beating me at the
beating me at the game.
He's
He's better
beating me at the game.
He's better than
He's better than the
beating me at the game.
He's better than the computer.
He's better than the computer. And
and
and I
and I all
and I all of
and I all of a
and I all of a sudden
and I all of a sudden with
and I all of a sudden with absolute
intensity
intensity of
and I all of a sudden with absolute
intensity of focus,
there
there was
there was nothing
there was nothing between
there was nothing between the
there was nothing between the action
there was nothing between the action and
the
the chicken
and
and I
and I had
and I had the
and I had the secret
and I had the secret of
and I had the secret of the
and I had the secret of the martial
arts.
There's
There's the
There's the nothing
There's the nothing between
There's the nothing between intention
and
and the
There's the nothing between intention
and the fruit
and the fruit of
There's the nothing between intention
and the fruit of that
and the fruit of that intention.
We
We recolaps
We recolaps the
We recolaps the wave
We recolaps the wave function.
We recolaps the wave function. That
chicken
chicken in
We recolaps the wave function. That
chicken in me,
chicken in me, boy.
That's
That's the
That's the zen
That's the zen of
That's the zen of the
That's the zen of the chicken
That's the zen of the chicken coupe.
All right.
All right. My
That's the zen of the chicken coupe.
All right. My brain
All right. My brain is
That's the zen of the chicken coupe.
All right. My brain is tired
All right. My brain is tired of
That's the zen of the chicken coupe.
All right. My brain is tired of all
All right. My brain is tired of all this
science
science this
science this morning.
science this morning. That's
science this morning. That's about
enough
enough linearity.
science this morning. That's about
enough linearity. Any
enough linearity. Any last
science this morning. That's about
enough linearity. Any last questions?
enough linearity. Any last questions? I
want
want everybody
want everybody to
want everybody to sleep
want everybody to sleep peacefully.
Please,
Please, sir.
want everybody to sleep peacefully.
Please, sir. Yes.
>> The
>> The uh
>> The uh answer
>> The uh answer is
>> The uh answer is preluded
>> The uh answer is preluded by
>> The uh answer is preluded by the
>> The uh answer is preluded by the design
of
of the
>> The uh answer is preluded by the design
of the question.
Some
Some things
Some things aren't
Some things aren't just
>> Oh,
>> Oh, you
Some things aren't just
>> Oh, you didn't
>> Oh, you didn't get
Some things aren't just
>> Oh, you didn't get to
>> Oh, you didn't get to lecture
Some things aren't just
>> Oh, you didn't get to lecture this
morning.
morning. Would
morning. Would you
morning. Would you put
morning. Would you put that
morning. Would you put that back
morning. Would you put that back on?
>> It's
>> It's either
morning. Would you put that back on?
>> It's either yes
>> It's either yes or
morning. Would you put that back on?
>> It's either yes or not
>> It's either yes or not yes,
morning. Would you put that back on?
>> It's either yes or not yes, sir.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Any
>> Okay. Any other
>> Okay. Any other questions?
>> Yes.
Oh
Oh yes.
Uh
Uh it's
Oh yes.
Uh it's it's
Uh it's it's advisable
Oh yes.
Uh it's it's advisable for
Uh it's it's advisable for safety
Oh yes.
Uh it's it's advisable for safety sake
as
as well
as well as
as well as accuracy.
I
I have
as well as accuracy.
I have permission
I have permission to
as well as accuracy.
I have permission to ask
I have permission to ask what
as well as accuracy.
I have permission to ask what I'm
holding
holding in
holding in mind.
holding in mind. Resist.
The
The permission
holding in mind. Resist.
The permission is
The permission is necessary
holding in mind. Resist.
The permission is necessary for
accuracy.
accuracy. The
accuracy. The permission
accuracy. The permission is
accuracy. The permission is accur
accuracy. The permission is accur is
necessary
necessary for
accuracy. The permission is accur is
necessary for safety.
It's
It's necessary
It's necessary because
It's necessary because of
It's necessary because of karmic
It's necessary because of karmic karmic
permission.
permission. Resist.
It's necessary because of karmic karmic
permission. Resist. It's
permission. Resist. It's necessary
because
because of
boundaries.
boundaries. Just
because of
boundaries. Just you
boundaries. Just you know
because of
boundaries. Just you know boundaries.
boundaries. Just you know boundaries. I
want
want to
want to make
want to make sure
want to make sure I'm
want to make sure I'm not
want to make sure I'm not invading
somebody
somebody else's
want to make sure I'm not invading
somebody else's privacy.
somebody else's privacy. I
want to make sure I'm not invading
somebody else's privacy. I ask
permission.
permission. Do
permission. Do I
permission. Do I have
permission. Do I have permission
permission. Do I have permission to
permission. Do I have permission to ask
uh
uh Darwin's
permission. Do I have permission to ask
uh Darwin's um
uh Darwin's um work?
permission. Do I have permission to ask
uh Darwin's um work? I'm
uh Darwin's um work? I'm not
permission. Do I have permission to ask
uh Darwin's um work? I'm not asking
about
about Darwin
about Darwin himself.
about Darwin himself. That's
about Darwin himself. That's his
problem.
Anyway,
Anyway, um,
Anyway, um, so
Anyway, um, so you
Anyway, um, so you you
Anyway, um, so you you may
Anyway, um, so you you may get
Anyway, um, so you you may get a
Anyway, um, so you you may get a no.
Anyway, um, so you you may get a no. You
see,
see, if
Anyway, um, so you you may get a no. You
see, if I
see, if I ask
Anyway, um, so you you may get a no. You
see, if I ask what
see, if I ask what is
Anyway, um, so you you may get a no. You
see, if I ask what is Darwin's
see, if I ask what is Darwin's level
Anyway, um, so you you may get a no. You
see, if I ask what is Darwin's level of
consciousness,
consciousness, I
consciousness, I might
consciousness, I might get
consciousness, I might get a
consciousness, I might get a no.
consciousness, I might get a no. So
consciousness, I might get a no. So I
may
may say,
consciousness, I might get a no. So I
may say, I'm
may say, I'm holding
consciousness, I might get a no. So I
may say, I'm holding in
may say, I'm holding in mind
consciousness, I might get a no. So I
may say, I'm holding in mind what
may say, I'm holding in mind what is
Darwin's
Darwin's level
Darwin's level of
Darwin's level of consciousness
Darwin's level of consciousness and
Darwin's level of consciousness and I
say,
say, do
Darwin's level of consciousness and I
say, do I
say, do I have
Darwin's level of consciousness and I
say, do I have permission
say, do I have permission to
Darwin's level of consciousness and I
say, do I have permission to ask
say, do I have permission to ask that?
Darwin's level of consciousness and I
say, do I have permission to ask that? I
get
get no.
get no. If
get no. If I
get no. If I say
get no. If I say I
get no. If I say I want
get no. If I say I want the
get no. If I say I want the energy
get no. If I say I want the energy of
Darwin's
Darwin's theory
get no. If I say I want the energy of
Darwin's theory of
Darwin's theory of evolution,
get no. If I say I want the energy of
Darwin's theory of evolution, I
Darwin's theory of evolution, I get
get no. If I say I want the energy of
Darwin's theory of evolution, I get a
yes.
yes. You
yes. You see
yes. You see what
yes. You see what I'm
yes. You see what I'm saying?
yes. You see what I'm saying? There's
yes. You see what I'm saying? There's a
boundary
boundary problem.
yes. You see what I'm saying? There's a
boundary problem. There's
boundary problem. There's permission
yes. You see what I'm saying? There's a
boundary problem. There's permission and
um
um many
um many other
um many other factors.
um many other factors. So,
um many other factors. So, I
um many other factors. So, I thought
um many other factors. So, I thought we
would
would uh
um many other factors. So, I thought we
would uh take
would uh take a
um many other factors. So, I thought we
would uh take a break
would uh take a break now.
um many other factors. So, I thought we
would uh take a break now. And
would uh take a break now. And uh
um many other factors. So, I thought we
would uh take a break now. And uh what'
you
you say?
>> Yes,
>> Yes, we
you say?
>> Yes, we said
>> Yes, we said that
you say?
>> Yes, we said that the
>> Yes, we said that the the
you say?
>> Yes, we said that the the two
>> Yes, we said that the the two people
involved
involved have
involved have to
involved have to be
involved have to be over
involved have to be over 200.
involved have to be over 200. If
involved have to be over 200. If you're
doing
doing it
involved have to be over 200. If you're
doing it by
doing it by yourself,
involved have to be over 200. If you're
doing it by yourself, you
doing it by yourself, you have
involved have to be over 200. If you're
doing it by yourself, you have to
doing it by yourself, you have to be
over
over 200.
over 200. Um
over 200. Um um
over 200. Um um that
over 200. Um um that just
over 200. Um um that just means
over 200. Um um that just means that
your
your dedication
over 200. Um um that just means that
your dedication to
your dedication to truth
over 200. Um um that just means that
your dedication to truth is
your dedication to truth is more
important
important than
important than your
important than your private
uh
uh investments.
important than your private
uh investments. It's
uh investments. It's more
important than your private
uh investments. It's more important
uh investments. It's more important to
you
you to
you to know
you to know the
you to know the truth.
you to know the truth. So
you to know the truth. So the
you to know the truth. So the pathway
you to know the truth. So the pathway to
God
God then
you to know the truth. So the pathway to
God then through
God then through non-duality
you to know the truth. So the pathway to
God then through non-duality is
God then through non-duality is a
pathway
pathway of
pathway of truth
pathway of truth in
pathway of truth in which
pathway of truth in which you're
pathway of truth in which you're willing
to
to let
pathway of truth in which you're willing
to let go
to let go and
pathway of truth in which you're willing
to let go and surrender
to let go and surrender positionalities.
And
And we
And we do
And we do that
And we do that out
And we do that out of
And we do that out of devotion.
And we do that out of devotion. It's
one's
one's it's
And we do that out of devotion. It's
one's it's not
one's it's not truth
And we do that out of devotion. It's
one's it's not truth is
one's it's not truth is one's
And we do that out of devotion. It's
one's it's not truth is one's devotion
to
to truth.
to truth. was
to truth. was devotion
to truth. was devotion to
to truth. was devotion to truth
to truth. was devotion to truth allows
you
you to
to truth. was devotion to truth allows
you to go
you to go through
to truth. was devotion to truth allows
you to go through surgery
you to go through surgery without
anesthesia
because
because it's
anesthesia
because it's a
because it's a laser-like
anesthesia
because it's a laser-like certainty.
>> Okay,
>> Okay, this
>> Okay, this is
>> Okay, this is the
>> Okay, this is the way
>> Okay, this is the way we
>> Okay, this is the way we evolved
>> Okay, this is the way we evolved this
technique.
technique. Uh,
>> Okay, this is the way we evolved this
technique. Uh, as
technique. Uh, as I
>> Okay, this is the way we evolved this
technique. Uh, as I say,
technique. Uh, as I say, I
>> Okay, this is the way we evolved this
technique. Uh, as I say, I learned
technique. Uh, as I say, I learned it
from
from George
from George Diamond.
from George Diamond. Other
from George Diamond. Other people
from George Diamond. Other people have
different
different techniques
which
which probably
which probably work
which probably work for
which probably work for them.
which probably work for them. So,
which probably work for them. So, it's
which probably work for them. So, it's a
matter
matter of
which probably work for them. So, it's a
matter of practice
matter of practice and
which probably work for them. So, it's a
matter of practice and familiarity.
matter of practice and familiarity. Some
people
people hold
people hold the
people hold the arm
people hold the arm in
people hold the arm in front.
people hold the arm in front. Some
people
people hold
people hold the arm in front. Some
people hold the
people hold the arm
people hold the arm in front. Some
people hold the arm to
people hold the arm to the
people hold the arm in front. Some
people hold the arm to the side.
Those
Those are
Those are all
Those are all differences
Those are all differences of
Those are all differences of technique.
Yes.
>> Minister
>> Minister and
>> Minister and his
>> Minister and his wife
>> Minister and his wife from
>> Minister and his wife from my
>> Minister and his wife from my state
>> Minister and his wife from my state went
home
home and
>> Minister and his wife from my state went
home and practiced
home and practiced said
>> Minister and his wife from my state went
home and practiced said they
home and practiced said they have
trouble
trouble getting
trouble getting consistent
trouble getting consistent results.
>> Ah
>> Ah yes.
trouble getting consistent results.
>> Ah yes. Um
>> yes
>> yes it
>> yes it could
>> yes it could be
>> yes it could be the
>> yes it could be the minister
>> yes it could be the minister and
>> yes it could be the minister and his
wife
wife are
>> yes it could be the minister and his
wife are not
wife are not a
>> yes it could be the minister and his
wife are not a good
wife are not a good pair.
>> yes it could be the minister and his
wife are not a good pair. It
wife are not a good pair. It could
>> yes it could be the minister and his
wife are not a good pair. It could be.
You
You see,
You see, as
You see, as you
You see, as you as
You see, as you as you
You see, as you as you get
You see, as you as you get more
You see, as you as you get more advanced
in
in in
You see, as you as you get more advanced
in in spiritual
in in spiritual awareness,
You see, as you as you get more advanced
in in spiritual awareness, you
in in spiritual awareness, you realize
that
that things
that things are
that things are very
that things are very radically
that things are very radically what
that things are very radically what they
are
are and
that things are very radically what they
are and not
are and not something
that things are very radically what they
are and not something else.
You
You can't
You can't be
You can't be loose
You can't be loose rattlerained
You can't be loose rattlerained when
You can't be loose rattlerained when you
do
do kinesiology.
You can't be loose rattlerained when you
do kinesiology. It's
do kinesiology. It's absolute
You can't be loose rattlerained when you
do kinesiology. It's absolute exact.
do kinesiology. It's absolute exact. You
have
have to
have to have
have to have a
have to have a laserike
uh
uh intention.
a
a laser-like
a laser-like intention
a laser-like intention without
considerations
uh
uh without
uh without any
uh without any investment
uh without any investment in
uh without any investment in the
uh without any investment in the answer.
You
You cannot
uh without any investment in the answer.
You cannot change
You cannot change the
uh without any investment in the answer.
You cannot change the wording.
You cannot change the wording. Now,
uh without any investment in the answer.
You cannot change the wording. Now, we
asked
asked one
asked one time,
asked one time, is
asked one time, is Carl
asked one time, is Carl Young
asked one time, is Carl Young over
asked one time, is Carl Young over five
uh
uh uh
asked one time, is Carl Young over five
uh uh 520?
uh uh 520? We
asked one time, is Carl Young over five
uh uh 520? We got
uh uh 520? We got no.
Well,
Well, I
Well, I know
Well, I know he's
Well, I know he's 520.
Well, I know he's 520. We've
Well, I know he's 520. We've done
Well, I know he's 520. We've done Carl
Young
Young for
Well, I know he's 520. We've done Carl
Young for years.
Young for years. He's
Well, I know he's 520. We've done Carl
Young for years. He's always
Young for years. He's always 520.
So,
So, we
So, we didn't
So, we didn't know
So, we didn't know why
So, we didn't know why we
So, we didn't know why we got
So, we didn't know why we got a
So, we didn't know why we got a no.
So, we didn't know why we got a no. It
was
was in
So, we didn't know why we got a no. It
was in front
was in front of
So, we didn't know why we got a no. It
was in front of an
was in front of an audience,
So, we didn't know why we got a no. It
was in front of an audience, too.
was in front of an audience, too. We
always
always looked
always looked at
always looked at each
always looked at each other
always looked at each other like,
"What?"
A
A couple
A couple other
A couple other people.
A couple other people. Uh,
A couple other people. Uh, then
A couple other people. Uh, then we
A couple other people. Uh, then we got
we
we had
A couple other people. Uh, then we got
we had to
we had to change
A couple other people. Uh, then we got
we had to change the
we had to change the wording.
A couple other people. Uh, then we got
we had to change the wording. Carl
we had to change the wording. Carl Young
was
was over
was over 520.
was over 520. He
was over 520. He isn't
was over 520. He isn't now
was over 520. He isn't now cuz
was over 520. He isn't now cuz he's
dead,
dead, right?
was over 520. He isn't now cuz he's
dead, right? So,
dead, right? So, in
was over 520. He isn't now cuz he's
dead, right? So, in other
dead, right? So, in other words,
was over 520. He isn't now cuz he's
dead, right? So, in other words, you
can't
can't be
can't be sloppy.
can't be sloppy. You
can't be sloppy. You have
can't be sloppy. You have to
can't be sloppy. You have to be
can't be sloppy. You have to be very
scientifically
scientifically trained
can't be sloppy. You have to be very
scientifically trained to
scientifically trained to be
can't be sloppy. You have to be very
scientifically trained to be very,
scientifically trained to be very, very
precise.
precise. You
precise. You can't
precise. You can't deal
precise. You can't deal in
precise. You can't deal in generalities.
Okay,
Okay, we
precise. You can't deal in generalities.
Okay, we will
Okay, we will take
precise. You can't deal in generalities.
Okay, we will take a
Okay, we will take a break
precise. You can't deal in generalities.
Okay, we will take a break and
Okay, we will take a break and um
precise. You can't deal in generalities.
Okay, we will take a break and um God
willing
willing we'll
willing we'll all
willing we'll all reconvene
willing we'll all reconvene shortly.