We are
on
here
Let us know when everybody's in.
>> Is everybody in?
>> Not yet. Okay. Well, we'll wait.
>> Okay.
>> Good morning, everybody.
>> It is the 1st of November, a powerful
day. Okay. Halloween is over.
And uh I hope everyone is well spooked.
And we're just uh waiting for just a
second to get everybody seated.
And uh on the way up this morning,
I noticed clouds in the sky and winter
setting in and an amazing energy. uh
coming probably from solar flares and
all kinds of stuff and it's a perfect
day. I see a lot of familiar faces and
I'm here to introduce Dr. Dr. David
Hawkins,
uh, worldrenowned spiritual teacher has
taught all over the world and, uh, we've
been all over the world with him
and, uh, to, uh, folks just like
yourself from here to Oxford.
And uh
I have no idea what he's doing behind
me,
but uh
just for the record, we have uh traveled
a lot and we have been from here to
Oxford to
Chicago to California.
All over the planet right now, people
are getting words about David Hawkins.
Okay. and power versus force and the eye
of the eye and the eye and it's becoming
a uh it's taken on its own energy
because everybody is so hungry and
thirsty for the pure truth. And so this
morning I would like you to uh welcome
with me my friend, my mentor and a
blessing to the world, Dr. David
Hawkins.
Hallelujah.
Everybody's here
and I forgot what we're talking about
today.
I thought it was going to be on here.
This is next year's.
The difficulty with having a blank mind
is that you don't know what you're going
to talk about next.
So it'll be a surprise to both of us.
Today we're talking about the
realization of the self
which as divinity
the radical subjectivity of the sense of
existence of iness
of beingness and of course that has been
the thrust of all the lectures
this would this will be with December's
election lecture the end of the second
year. Now, included in all these
lectures and wonders slides
is all the uh information you'll ever
need. Let's see.
That's a fact. All the information
you'll ever need throughout all time has
already been provided. Resist.
Well, I knew that already.
So, all we want to do is clarify
what we've already said and we have some
new slides today and some new
discoveries that were quite exciting
and um they're only a week old.
Uh,
this is a very arodite crowd. Very
ariodite.
They're over 435,
440,
445,
441, 442. Wow. It's the highest audience
we've spoken in front in front of
consciousness harder than any audience
we've spoken to. Okay.
Somebody must have been listening doing
homework.
Now this was an advanced crowd to begin
with.
Anybody who attends lectures on how to
become enlightened is already close
close to the goal.
Nobody else would be interested.
Well, you said if you'd asked if you
stopped 10,000 people on the streets of
Chicago and asked them their ambition in
life, you would find maybe uh you know
one in 150,000 or one in 200,000 they
said to reach enlightenment. So one
reason it's rare is very few people see
that as a possibility consciously.
However, as consciousness advances,
one starts to become aware that that is
the direction in which they are headed.
And now they get a map to make the way
quicker. So all we're providing is a map
to make the route quicker.
Everyone in a group like this is already
destined to be enlightened, karmically
destined to be enlightened, which is
that's a fact.
I never introduced Susan.
I'm afraid she might get a big head or
something.
Come over here, sweetheart.
Without Without the amazing discoveries,
without Susan, the amazing discoveries
which have to some degree uh already
influenced the world in a favorable way
would not have been made. And so I want
to thank you for
For instance, the two of us last week
discovered
that spiritual work, this will be the
final slides for today, but we'll say
about
that spiritual intention and spiritual
work literally literally changes the
brain's physiology.
It literally changes the brain. It
changes the way information is
processed.
And people that are spiritually oriented
literally experience things differently
than the other people.
The other people,
the the other people
who are more interested in killing you
than praying for you.
That's why we asked for double picture
ID when you came in.
All right. We found that uh actually the
brain physiology changes
and uh what I'm holding in mind
if uh I'm permitted to share with the
audience who's you know thank you
so we'll start with the conclusion of
today's lecture
because I forgot what the lecture was
about so
anyway we have slides and pictures you
can't present something without slides
and pictures
literally
a spiritual commit Commitment and
orientation
changes the brain's physiology and
functioning
and creates in the spiritually oriented
person
an actual place in the prefrontal cortex
on in the right brain of spiritual
information and simultaneously creates
an atheric brain.
People under 200
have an athetheric brain resist.
People over 200 have an atheric brain
resist.
Not only does it change how information
is processed through the brain, it
shifts you from left to right. You
experience things different and you
process things different.
People
who have be you know moved ahead a
little bit spiritually notice
that they see and experience things
differently than other people in the
world.
This creates quite a difficulty. In
fact,
people who who recover in the 12step
group find this very often. It leads to
matrimonial debates and divorces and
disruptions of families. Anybody who's
done intense spiritual work speeds up
their karma.
They think I'm going to be I'm going to
get into spiritual work and my life is
going to be be peaceful.
We're going to sit around and pray pray
for peace and flowers and birds and be
like St. St. Francis sit in a garden and
track birds.
What a joke.
More likely major disruption of one for
kind or another catapults you through
amazing experiences very rapidly.
Now all the
the worldly life of the spiritually
committed person can appear quite
chaotic.
They'll just up and leave everything,
walk away from everything. People decide
you must have gone mad.
So it speeds up one's karma.
That's a fact. Is it? That's a fact.
Speeds up your karma.
Changes your brain function, your brain
physiology. Creates an atheric brain
so that incoming data does not go
through a delayed pathway like in the
ordinary brain but goes through very
rapid pathway which bypasses the
emotional center
so that you see things differently and
experience things differently.
People who've done any of the spiritual
courses and people who do the course of
miracles will say, "I don't know. I just
see things differently."
So this allows this understanding then
allows for greater compassion for those
who do not see and experience things in
a spiritually oriented manner.
And we also see that
their responsibility is limited by the
fact that they do not have a
comprehension of spiritual truth.
It looks like
the animal evolution on up through
the c the cerebral hemispheres and the
animal kingdom, the early forms of
Neanderthal man, the homo rectus,
finally homo sapien.
But even in homo sapiion,
the majority of people do not have an
atheric brain.
H
that's a fact. Is it? Isn't that a
stunning fact? Sort of left left me been
dazed out all week thinking the
implications of it. You know,
I mean, we electrocute people because
they lack a moral sense.
They have no capacity for a moral sense.
But we with a moral sense think how bad
they'd be when So that's the
justification for electrocuting us
because they're so bad. You know,
I see the ambassador from Germany was
here in Arizona two weeks ago to try and
dissuade us from electrocuting somebody.
All right. So
then this brain sees things differently
than this brain does.
That's an important realization.
Spiritually oriented people experience
things differently, process things
differently, conceptualize it
differently, and come to a different
conclusion.
Also, there's major differences in the
physiologic response.
I'm giving the end of the lecture at the
beginning.
You made me do it.
So the left brain person then is more
coming from the animal instinctual.
An incoming impulse goes directly to his
emotional response to his amydala
and then a a sidetrack goes to his
frontal cortex and then to his
mal whoa his mal what is that thing
amygdala?
the emotional response center.
So I just thought I'd mention that in
the beginning and then in the end we'll
go back to it with a diagram.
So under 200 the people the input goes
directly to their emotional center twice
as fast
as it as it relays through the cerebral
cortex to the emotional center.
But the fast track from the input to the
emotional center is twice as fast in the
left brain person with a consciousness
less than 200. Twice as fast.
So first he says, "I'm going to kill
you." Then the slow track from his
frontal cortex comes back to him and
says, "Uh, but I didn't really mean
that." But it's already out. The frog's
out of the mouth.
In the spiritually committed person, I
guess there's a gift. Let's see if
that's a gift.
That's a divi a gift. Oh, wow. Is a gift
from divinity. One
has an atheric cortex where the
information instantly hits the
spiritualized
understanding center.
The left brain person puts out then and
because he emotionally responds first. I
hate you. I'm kill you.
Up comes adrenaline.
He's under fight or flight. Cannon's
fight or flight. He's under the sier
physiologic functions
then of adrenaline and the leftbrain
person's neurobrain neurotransmitters
are stressed out. He depletes his
serotonin and his norepinephrine and
gets depressed and goes into rages.
Because lepreane person less than 200 is
responding with stress all the time.
He suppresses the thymus gland which
decreases the number of killer cells.
Therefore loses immunity is more prone
to disease
and because the alarm reaction throws
out his acupuncture system which
deranges the energy flow to the various
organs of the body.
Therefore, the left brain person under
200 is more prone to disease, sickness,
depression, death,
and seeking relief from these
emergency emotions seeks addiction
because addiction gives relief.
Addiction to drugs or alcohol gives
relief. So there's greater propensity to
homicide, suicide, addiction,
rage attacks
and a shorter, more miserable life. Huh?
The person who is spiritually committed
now develops an atheric brain in which
the information is processed right
through your spiritual understanding
which releases endorphins instead of
adrenaline.
He balances his acupuncture system,
strengthens the thymus gland, increases
the number of circulating killer cells,
which increases immunity to disease.
that builds up the neurotransmitters in
the brain
and eventually end up
paralyzed anyway in bliss,
which which beats suicide. Anyway,
So there is, you see, because we set
goals for ourself. We read the spiritual
literature and we set goals for oursel
and we think, well, we're not there yet.
So we put oursel down, etc., etc.
Um,
not realizing that all along we are on a
different path. So never get discouraged
on the spiritual pathway because you are
on the pathway.
It's better to be discouraged on the
spiritual pathway
than in temporary euphoria on the other
pathway.
The temporary high that you get from
adrenaline. Yeah.
Yeah. Substitute for endorphins.
Well, I never didn't intend to speak
about this this morning until near the
end, but I thought it's so important.
I'll put it in in the beginning.
and then we'll get it back to it in the
end in pictures.
All right? Because this is a spiritually
oriented group of such a high
calibration, we can say things that we
can't say elsewhere
without being thought mad
or labeled a mystic.
uh
one technically is a mystic to realize
the presence of God as the self as the
innate sense of I the universalness of
it is the essence of the mystic
yeah
about which I have to do something some
kind of work for next month anyway Okay.
The way we've tried to describe really
we've avoided the whole subject of
religion.
We draw from the ranks of all religions
and incorporate the essential truth of
all religions
at the same same time avoid them. avoid
them
for specific reasons.
that
one's spiritual awareness
should really not depend on the say so
of authorities
or supposed authorities,
ecclesiastic authorities
of anybody anywhere in the past.
The source of the truth of spiritual
reality
has only one source and that's yourself.
The external can verify it, but it's a
substitute for the real.
Therefore, in the books I do and
lectures,
I don't try to give any authority to
what I say by quoting from elsewhere.
If elsewhere was successful, we wouldn't
all be here.
No, elsewhere has not been successful.
All right.
The difficulty is it gets stuck in
authoritarianism.
Authoritarianism
and one begins to quote out there.
Plus, all the religions have arisen in
ethnic situations,
geographic situations,
and they've become layered with
historical events and personages
and ecclesiastic languaging,
approval by higher authorities,
uh, subservience to ecclesiastic
authority,
All that is a great deterrence.
The spiritual reality described
throughout time has always been the
same.
In a week or two, I I ran across
the experience described here in these
lectures within
to all myself.
I finally read it somewhere. You
never read theods. I looked over the
planishads and there was somebody who
finally got it right.
Well, they got it right. Oh, wow.
Well, he got it right.
The undoing of the ego, then the
disassembling of the ego is what we've
really been talking about. How to
understand the levels of consciousness.
Each level of consciousness is unique in
to itself.
Each one has its own specific
characteristics.
We talk about very advanced levels of
consciousness, but today we're going to
do a whole slide on the levels in the
200s and 300s
because this is the critical line.
Once you're over the line, the rest is
certain. The real trick is getting over
the line. And we find that spiritual
attributes which calibrate maybe 250 or
something
if you persist in them will take you
rapidly up the scale of consciousness.
How many have not been here before?
Oh dear. Oh dear. Oh dear.
All right. We're going to rapidly
recapitulate the earlier lectures.
Nothing will be left out that you need
to know.
We all start the lectures at the same
understanding.
The difficulties of with an audience
like this which is in the 400s, many of
you in the high 400s.
The big barrier is the intellect.
Rare is the person who gets beyond
calibrated level 499. Huh? And so the
first thing we want to disassemble
is the worship of the intellect and
reason and logic
to a group like this. Reason and logic,
intelligence and education is the
leading light of their life. Huh?
it then becomes the very limitation to
transcending it.
So the first thing we need to do is to
disassemble
that major structure called the
intellect
which is a formidable strength.
The intellect out of which has come
science and the great wonders of this
world is formidable and quite powerful.
It's been capable of curing most of the
diseases I treated when I was
at a hospital for infectious diseases
etc. Almost all those diseases are gone.
So the 400s are extremely powerful. The
world of science invention,
the Newtonian paradigm of reality, the
differential calculus, the the computer,
the space age, all comes out of the
400s.
The 400s then become the limitation as
we see.
Einstein 499, Freud 499.
Sir Isaac Newton 499.
The 400s then become the barrier to the
500s.
>> Oh, we've got a pointer. Right there.
>> Right there.
>> Isn't that grand? Just like in the
movies.
All right. All right. So, for those who
haven't been here before, we have Cal.
Anybody who hasn't read Power versus
All right. So, I don't want to get too
rudimentary.
What we discovered is you can calibrate
the levels of consciousness. We created
a scale logarithmic one to a thousand.
We found everything that makes you go
weak. We
makes you go weak. We calibrated that.
It ended up at 200. Below 200 makes you
go weak. Over 200 makes you go strong.
It's based on the kinesiologic response
which is the reaction of consciousness
as life to truth or the absence thereof.
Therefore, it is not a yes or a no. It's
a yes or a not yes. The universe cannot
answer no. It either responds or does
not respond.
Once in a while somebody will write me a
letter. Couldn't we create an electronic
wonder computer machine that would do
kinesiology
thereby missing the whole point.
The whole point is it's the presence of
consciousness that is answering.
You could do that with a computer if it
you could turn it into a human being.
So the it's the response of life itself.
It's not a difficult concept. All of
protoplasm
is open to and responds positively to
that which is
true life and it tends to recoil from
that which is not life. The other
strange thing about consciousness is
that it's impersonal.
It's like a giant electromagnetic field
of in which you participate in which
your consciousness participates
at varying levels.
These are all levels of consciousness.
We see that from here up to once you get
over the level of integrity profound
changes happen. Therefore it's in that's
the most important step. People worry,
"How high is my calibrated level of
consciousness?" You don't have to worry
about that. As long as you're over 200,
you got nothing to worry about. You just
keep doing what you're doing and
eventually you get there. That's all.
Impatience. You have to let go
impatience. I want enlightenment. I want
it now.
Frankly, you don't want it now. You
think you do.
You think bad life was bad before. Wait.
All right.
Took me
30 years to talk about it or write about
it.
10 years to recover, I'd leave the world
and 10 years to recover so I could
function again.
You need friends that know that you're
serious about spiritual work. I tell
everybody, always have friends that you
know know you are serious about
spiritual work.
In case you do just go into a sudden 600
and you sit there sort of bliss bliss
out and the family wonders you've gone
crazy or you're catatonic and they call
in adopter.
All right. So the
people of a more advanced understanding
able to understand abstraction
understanding reason meaningfulness.
They see God as the infinite wisdom of
the universe. the omnition, the sense,
the omniscience of God.
But that reason then becomes the block.
The block
that was the block the height that
Einstein ran into
at the SV conference in Copenhagen
where all the great theoretical
physicists of the day mathematicians had
gathered
and the Heisenberg principle is what he
couldn't handle. The Heisenberg
principle introduced the realization
that consciousness itself already
profoundly alters the state and
condition of reality.
Uh
so
the 400s what the fortress behind the
400s is the belief in causality.
So we always start the lectures with
trying to explain how things come about.
The illusion of causality is the biggest
block to transcending the 400s.
The illusion of causality is profoundly
important to transcend.
Therefore, the beginning of every
lecture, we try to explain how things
actually come about
because you begin to intuitit it. You
begin to sense it.
Principle of causality calibrates around
450 or 460.
>> Sorry.
>> It calibrates over 450 over 460. 465.
All right. The principle of causality
calibrates around 460.
The theory of evolution, Darwin's theory
of evolution, calibrates around 450,
455.
Now,
you can't really explain the universe,
including divinity, from a consciousness
level at 455
won't work.
You have to transcend the Newtonian
paradigm of reality
which is based on the belief in
causality
that there's a this causing a that.
The pathway to enlightenment is
nondualistic.
The principle of causality is inherently
and profoundly dualistic. So one can see
to transcend the mind to become
enlightened to realize the truth of
presence of God within
it's necessary to transcend the
intellect.
Therefore it's necessary to transcend
the illusion of causality.
So long as you think there's a this
causing a that you're stuck in duality.
The most profound duality that you get
stuck in is that there must be an
independent separate personal eye that
is causing things out there.
A separate eye, separate from the one,
separate from the field, unique,
individual, autonomous,
a little god entity.
Nobody wants to admit that the core of
their ego wants to be God. But that's a
fact.
Can we reveal that truth?
Yes. Resist.
Yes. The core of egoentricity.
All right. Doesn't want to let go being
in charge
considers it the self
as the author.
So
it sees the ego sees the core of the ego
as
the source of its life. It sees it as
sovereign
and it will fight to the death to
maintain its sovereignty
including sacrificing your physical
existence. If you really threaten the
ego,
it will throw you over a cliff in an
instant
because it will survive. In this
physicality, it doesn't care anything
about.
This is just another opportunity for
itself to be what it is.
It will happily sacrifice itself to be
right. Everyday's headlines tell you
that people blow themselves up to be
right.
Or worse than that, they blow you up to
be right.
A busload of children will do. For
starters,
that should get a war going for 50 years
or so. And it has, hasn't it then? That
one started with a blowing up a bus load
of children.
So, it knows how to trigger hatred.
Knows all the tricks. The ego knows how
to survive.
It is frightened to death of peace.
Last thing wants is peace.
All right.
So let's see how this how causality
has to be replaced by a higher
understanding.
Everything already is what it is
because of its prior karma.
The marble sitting there because the kid
put it on the pool table or whatever.
You know all events have coalesed now
into
a present state or condition.
Everything karmically inherits
a potentiality
also a limitation.
A strawberry plant cannot become a rose.
It's already destined.
It has a potentiality.
The capacity to move from the unmanifest
to the manifest which is the source of
creation
is an aspect of divinity.
Everything then comes into existence
with a potentiality.
The potentiality then becomes an actual
actuality
if the field favors that. If it's
favored by the climate and by the
conditions and by the field,
there's no guarantee that the rose will
bloom at all. It has the potentiality.
Nothing can cause the rose to bloom.
Nothing.
If conditions are favorable then its
potentiality
is expressed in this domain as an
actuality.
You see the potentiality then becoming
actualized.
If conditions are correct, if conditions
are favorable,
it comes into existence as it the
fulfillment of its potentiality
by virtue
of the power of the overall field.
Everything exists within a field,
an infinite field which is like a giant
gravitational field.
Every decision we make, every thought,
every feeling first of all gets
registered forever in the field of
consciousness. That's why we can
retrieve it with kinesiology.
Every decision
if you look at your spirit karmic
core of your spirit as a little iron
filing then every decision thought
etc changes the charge on this little
filing more positive or more negative
the field which is the power and the
presence of God
is infinite infinitely powerful
powerful.
It doesn't do anything. Power stands
there
like a giant electromagnetic field like
like gravity. It just stands there. It
doesn't do anything.
Divinity is not arbitrary. It has no
parts. It doesn't move from here to
there.
Doesn't have a solar plexus. Doesn't
have emotions.
not subject to human limitations.
Therefore, the ancient anthropomorphic
projections of God do not calibrate
extremely high.
The field gravity doesn't get angry at
anybody.
He pushes over there.
God was angry at the Kleenex.
No, the response of the field is
absolute. The justice of God is
continuous,
always present.
Judgment day is always
judgment day is ongoing. Is this
alwaysness resist?
It's not then or then.
Neither in the past nor in the future.
The only thing possible to be going on
is already going on.
The charge on your little iron filing
has already put you in the field where
its charge automatically goes. It goes
as a consequence of its own potential.
You see the freedom of will, the
infinite and profound freedom. One does
not move anywhere in the universe except
by personal ascent. It's only by your
agreement
that you move from here to there.
The other night on TV they were doing a
rerun of that profound hero in
Where's the war?
What's where is the war? Where's the
war?
>> Huh?
>> Iraq. Don't be timid. Yes, Iraq. I'm not
too left for this morning. Anyway,
wasn't he a lawyer and detected an
injured uh American lady? young slim
young little blonde lady
that she was not only injured and
tortured but being tortured as well
abused
anyway heroic
we have permission to ask this we have
permission to ask this
his karma I mean let's see his
calibrated level of consciousness jumped
over 200 250 300 holy Christ 350
one instant 350 jump of calibration of
level of consciousness this. So how long
does it take to move ahead in
consciousness? One decision.
The average person advances five points
in a lifetime. One decision 350 points.
All right. So the decision to sacrifice
jeopardize his own life for the highest
good
out of love and service to love
etc. was a profound move.
Profound move. All right.
Things come about then as a result as a
consequence of the field.
We don't have a white board here today.
As a white as a con as a consequence of
the field
we detect. You know when we were in
Europe I think someplace
there was this space shuttle that uh
it's insulation fell off or something
and of course immediately they started
to look for the guilty party but after
thorough investigation they came the
closest to the truth that I've read in a
headline in years says it was a
consequence of the climate
the climate of NASA or whatever the
agency was the ambiance, the overall
climate of it. Huh? So when the climate
is correct, the potentiality to become a
rose blooms. You see,
things are not caused one.
Everything comes into existence as the
consequence of multi-millions of factors
all operating. And when they're
fortuitous, they cross a certain
threshold.
Going from potentiality to actuality
means crossing a certain threshold.
When enough grains of sand are put on
it, it goes.
Yeah.
When there's enough snow on the
in the mountains of Colorado,
the snow piles up, the temperatures
change, barometric pressure changes,
there's the layer of ice, then a lot of
snow, then soft snow, and then maybe a
little more ice. And the weight gets
bigger and bigger and bigger and bigger
based on what the incline is, what the
weather is, the barometric pressure, and
10 million other factors.
There's a certain threshold point at
which
boom, the avalanche starts. Yeah. A
slight vibration.
Slight vibration.
The coyote yips. And that's what does it
that's all it needed. low frequency, you
know,
the skier says, "Golly
all sudden."
Did the skier cause the avalanche? No.
Though every contributing factor then
you see for every factor to even exist
requires
the whole universe throughout all of
time
and all the complexity and
multi-billions and trillions
quadrillions there's numbers for big
words I forget what they are big numbers
I mean use in advanced physics
anyway the number of factors is
innumerable and And we found they're
actually infinite. The number of factors
required for any event to materialize to
actualize is actually infinite.
So things then coalesce out of the field
like a cloud appears in the sky. Its
design is not preset. Its potentiality
to become a cloud isn't even there. It's
not even a a little cloud becoming a big
cloud. It's a no cloud.
Out of no cloudness arises
when a million factors are favorable
out of it coalleses out of the field
comes into actuality within our domain.
Therefore there is no cause of anything.
There is only everything fulfilling its
karmic potential when the accumulated
conditions reach a certain threshold.
When the itch gets strong enough, you
scratch it. But not before it's strong
enough.
And how come the mosquito bite got
there? So to get an itchy mosquito bite,
you see, takes all of the entire
universe throughout all of time.
Is that clear?
Nothing is caused by I mean it's such a
simplistic and I always say the exa the
example of simplicity
is helotropism where the child says why
does the flower follow the sun and the
teacher says helotropism
and the child says oh he doesn't know
anything more than he knew before
and that's the principle of causality
Because nothing is causing anything and
therefore creation and evolution are one
and the same thing.
Evolution is the sequential witnessing
of creation
and creation is continuous because
creation is the continuous process
of the potential becoming the actual
continue. So creation is continuous and
ongoing.
You don't have to stand up every time
that's a fact. Is it creation is
continuous and ongoing because the
presence of God which is the powerful
field out of which potentiality becomes
actuality is constantly present.
The power of God then is the presence of
a field so powerful
that the unmanifest becomes manifest.
Out of the unmanifest
classically called out of the Godhead
arises
the unmanifest.
In Christianity called Godhead,
in Buddhism called the void, out of
seeming nothingness arises everything
by virtue of the power of divine
ordinance.
Nothing has the power within itself to
create its own existence.
Even the most radical
scientific redemptionist is stuck
to explain the existence of all the
things discussed including one's own
thoughts.
Now we want to catch up the people who
are not that familiar with it. So we
calibrated all the levels of
consciousness. We discovered that they
correlate with common human experience.
I can't use my finger anymore.
I have to use this.
The consciousness levels below 200
then
this is an evolutionary scale.
As you go up the scale, you see more
advanced evolution.
In the beginning, life had a very
difficult time to survive. In the
beginning, there was no animals here.
There was no advanced forms of life.
The most primitive form of life then to
survive. Let's say if you were going to
create life on Mars,
it would have to be programmed to
survive. So the energy of life as it
appears initially and throughout all the
lowest forms is solely concerned with
me, myself, my survival.
It is not concerned about you. It
doesn't even conceive of you unless
you're edible.
So the core of the ego then is survival
of what is thought to be the source of
one's life not realizing that it comes
out of divinity. It thinks it's
self-created. Huh?
So the source of life then becomes more
evolved. You see more and more evolved
animals.
You start out with bacteria that
calibrate at one.
We go up to insects. We'll do animals
later. But as you evolve through the
animal kingdom, then finally you see the
homminid. You see the early forms of pre
prehuman coagulan man who calibrates
around 75.
All the early forms of man, homo rectus
calibrates extremely low. It's not until
you see homo sapiens. Homo sapiens with
the
frontal cortex.
Homo sapien then didn't score very high
either.
If you look at the history of Europe and
the early history of civilization, you
see mankind was not too evolved anywhere
frankly.
And only in the late 1980s did the
consciousness level of mankind cross
over 200. It was at 190 all through the
middle ages, 1800s.
Suddenly, we're in a new paradigm.
And this new paradigm of reality, which
calibrates over 200, is spiritual
awareness. And we call it homospiritus.
Homospiritus because it now has a an
etheric brain. And it now processes
things differently than any of his
homminid predecessors.
Let's see. Homo spiritist is correct.
Homo spiritist then appears
and in future history books we could
date it to 19 late 1980s
when the consciousness level became
predominantly positive
and overruled the animal consciousness.
All the you look at the history of
Europe, it's nothing but
one tribe conquering another pack of
wolves attacking another pack of wolves
trying to take over its territory.
Frankly, they had no motivation or
justification at all. There's no
justification for any war in history
really. We just wanted your land other
than greed. Solar plexus greed.
So you see the animal history is nothing
but the animal acting itself out acting
out in human form.
Homo sapien then was a big advance over
his predecessor because he had a
cerebral cortex. The only difficulty was
the animal in him was still predominant.
And to the animal, the cerebral cortex
is only a more clever, successful way of
being an animal.
The fights on Monkey Island for
territory and mating privileges, etc.,
continued the same. But now
the animal ego became really dangerous
because now it had a cerebral cortex.
It could not only figure out how to tear
out your juggler vein, it could create
an atomic bomb to do it.
Wow. North Korea, various places were
scared of them because of
because of the power. because of the
irrationality behind the power.
Not the power, nuclear power,
but the finger on the trigger is not all
there.
Not all there upstairs. That's what we
worry about. Okay.
So, the difficulty then is now the
animal was given tools.
It's like you gave all the animals in
the woods guns.
That's what we did. That's what we did.
We gave all the animals guns. We went
into countries that the calibrated level
of consciousness is around 90. We gave
them all guns.
What do you think consciousness level 90
is going to do with a gun?
It's going to shoot you, idiot. What do
you think he's going to do with it?
What did they think they were going to
do with it?
Fight on our side. Yeah, right.
Your side.
Let's go on. So then
we see we don't have to make the ego
wrong. We have to see that the core of
the ego is the the remnant of the
animal.
Uh
that's right. So this is what's left of
the animal and this is transcending the
animal all the way to it. So this is to
me to to me the emergence of homo
spiritus
which became measurable in the late
1980s when the consciousness level of
mankind jumped from 190 spectacularly to
207. A huge jump. Not only is 17 points
a huge jump but it passed over a
critical line from destruction to
construction.
Yes, we should go to the next. Okay. So
we're we're just going back to
recapitulate the whole thing how we did
it. This is the distribution of levels
of consciousness in the mankind. In
mankind we see that 85% of the world's
population is still predominantly at the
effect of their animal nature.
If you're aware of that, you see it
instantly. I have to is walk down the
streets in a big city and you see
humanl looking animals.
Hang on to your billfold.
Yeah.
And this is uh Karen did this slide. She
did it originally in color, but I I
didn't want to go into color shock, so I
made her go back to gray. So this is a
different way of understanding it. The
power of the 15% is greater than the the
numbers of the 85%.
As we go up the calibrated scale of
consciousness, the power of
consciousness becomes so much more
powerful because those are logarithmic
numbers.
And
here's another way she did it.
Uh this 15%
counterbalances the 85%.
the rest of the world. Okay. So, the
evolution of consciousness then has not
moved since 19 the late 1980s. We all
hoped that they would. It would resist.
It hasn't moved since the late 1980s.
Resist. Mhm.
All right. So, it hasn't crossed a
certain threshold yet. Certain threshold
yet. Let's move on and see what is next.
Oh yes.
Because of causality, because of this
causing a that, the mind thinks
dualistic. The animal mind thinks
dualistically. It thinks of a me here
and a rabbit there. And it has to
measure the distance between the two. So
the animal brain then is equipped to
prey on others, etc. It has to divide
life into me versus that. And usually
it's me versus lunch
and you are lunch.
Political lunch when it gets more
sophisticated. Political lunch. And they
get out there and pontificate some of
these politicians if they knew how we
what I was calibrating. I think they
I said, "Is this has he told any truth
at all in the last 20 minutes?" And I
get no.
The ego loves to pontificate. It
pontificates.
and it loves to be right.
So one of the sacrifices one has to make
in spiritual work is the pleasure of
being right.
One ends up being neutral.
The intellect says, "But isn't that
being Nambi Pami?"
Yes, that's being powerfully Nandandy
Pami. Boy, you better watch out.
The pleasure of giving up the
righteousness of being right is that you
don't have the guilt of winning.
You have a big argument with your
spouse, your mother, somebody, and you
walk away, I want, but you also are
guilty. Now,
so when you really don't care who wins,
I feel that everybody, the other person
should always win, I tell them right off
the bat, I agree with you. What? You
win.
Oh, he says
it's fine with me if other people are
right and I'm wrong. It's great.
We want to get off the duality of the
ego. So, first we dissolve causality,
which is its real core.
Then we begin to see out of its idea of
causality. It splits everything
dualistically.
Actually, there is no duality in
reality. Duality is a projection of
perception in which we set an arbitrary
line and say everything on this side is
right and everything on this side is
wrong.
I could say this end of the stick is
long and this end of the stick is short
because this is my point from which I'm
I could go here and say well both ends
are equal. Then I could go here and say,
"No, the right end is longer than the
left end. All I've changed is
positionality. The reality hasn't
changed at all."
That's what the intellect does
constantly. And it's very fast at it,
too.
We can take it apart by showing that
there is actually only one variable, not
two variables, one variable. Here we
have the presence of heat or not heat.
Heat is either present or not present.
We call it hot and cold, but that's just
linguistic. There's no difference. Heat
is not the opposite of cold. Cold is the
absence of heat. We can do the same
thing with desiraability. Desiraability
or aesthetics.
We can do the same thing with goodness,
what we picture as heavenly, what we
picture as horrible, which is above or
below 200. Generally
the calibrated levels of consciousness
then are what you're really calibrating
is the evolution of consciousness. The
evolution of consciousness and while
it's still predominantly animal in
nature
it makes you go weak
when it becomes concerned with others
and values and
higher concepts then it makes you go
strong.
So light we see here there's no no
duality of light and darkness.
There's only a lot of light or not any
light. Lots and lots of light as light
goes away. So you don't have two
conditions. You don't have two
variables. You either have the presence
or the absence of light. Therefore
you have either the presence or the
absence of love.
And the presence of love
is at the high end of the scale. And as
you get to the bottom, there's the
absence of love. The komodo dragon does
not love you.
Does not love anybody.
And to him, an ankle is food.
Next,
the animal nature, as entertainers have
found out, which I've warned people many
times.
In the end, the lion will eat you.
Its intrinsic nature has not changed. In
the end, the tiger will eat you. The
lion will eat you. The komodo dragon
will bite you.
That's the naivee of the 500s. The naive
this
the na the blind side of the 500s
is its denial
that the wild animal still is within the
tame animal.
The people in the 500s get blindsided.
They're easy to take. And the sharks
know that.
The sharks know that people in the five
high 500s saintly people don't see any
evil out there.
think no there's no point to guard
against it
etc. You can trust everybody.
No, that's not the opening of the third
eye of the Buddhist body is discernment.
There are people
you can love them and not give them your
money
because they'll pad the bill.
Now a naive person. So the 500s people
tend to be naive.
They go into a a view of life in which
being other than the way they are see
life is not a possibility.
As you get more advanced you realize
that one takes into consideration the
other possibility.
One is merely aware of it, cautious
about it, but you no longer hate it or
fear it.
You don't hate it. If somebody pads the
bill, so they pad the bill.
Go away therein. Okay.
Uh we said that the mind the other
interesting thing we discovered this we
brought forth considerably in the
lectures is that the mind is primarily
silent.
As the ego dissolves and thinkingness
disappears,
the most stunning thing that happens is
not only the exquisite beauty and the
revelation of the divinity of all that
exists
and the presence of a love of of
infinite softness and yet infinite
power.
The mind goes silent
and one realizes that the mind is
actually silent at all times.
98% of the mind is silent at all times.
You don't have to pay attention to your
chemical processes, your physiology.
You don't have to be like a centipede
deciding which leg to put after which.
98% of it is done for you. You've only
got 2% left.
How does this 2% manage to survive? When
people to go to meditate they say my
mind keeps thinking thinking thinking I
can't make it stop.
This 2% then has certain certain modus
operandi.
98% of your mind is silent at all times.
Actually 98% of your mind easily as you
listen to me is already silent. You're
only listening to about 1% of your mind.
98% is silent. It's like a huge field.
big silent field and over here there's a
little bit of something going on.
You're focused on that little bit of
something that that's going on. And the
interesting thing is that that one or 2%
that's thinking and
mentalizing things uh you become
hypnotized by it.
98% of the mind is silent.
That's let's just verify that is silent.
only 2% is operating
and the 2% has hypnotized you. So you've
like watched television so long that
even after it's off you're still looking
at the screen.
And here's its tricks. It politicizes,
moralizes. This is everyday's newspaper.
Every night's news dramatizes,
catastrophizes.
You find yourself not being in accord
with
common humanity as it presents itself
via the news etc. If you begin to
transcend this because the media do the
same thing. They know this is how your
mind works.
Some type gets run over by a truck.
Types get run over by trucks every day
folks everywhere in the world. Is that
news? No.
If I could catastrophize it, dramatize
it, emotionalize it, and get the camera
right at the right image, I get the
mother blubbering and the poor little
dead baby there, I can get a sob out of
everybody, get indignant letters to the
trucking company.
Shouldn't have been loud. We can
politicize it. We can moralize it. We
can idealize how it should be. We can
hypothesize what the government should
have done.
We can criticize everybody in sight.
Every event, first two things happen.
Who's going to be the fall guy, right?
And who do we sue?
First phone call the families make is
through their lawyer.
We romanticize, we criticize,
emotionalize, dramatize, catastrophize.
We theorize about how it should and
could be. We rationalize it. We
fantasize. We infantalize everything.
It's like nobody, everybody in America
now is a infant, a neurotic infant.
Everybody is made uncomfortable by
something.
I'm made uncomfortable by people being
uncomfortable.
We just got a a book of all the all the
things you can't words you can't use in
the books anymore, you know, by somebody
named Ravage. Anyway, in the back
there's a whole list of all the words
you can't use anymore.
We're going to end up everything is
going to be generic.
We'll all just be people. You can't be a
male people or female people. Can't be
young. Can't be old. Can't be from any
particular country. Can't be any color.
Can't have any level of education. Can't
have any disability. Can't There's
nothing you can say about them.
Blank person met blank person and
they're dead blank.
can even mention husband or wife. It's a
marital person.
All right.
So that's intellectualization. See, and
it infantilizes people because in this
world you got to learn how to take it,
mentalize, idealize, glamorize, demonize
and predominantly victimize. Our whole
world is a world of
victim perpetrator and victim which is a
complete projection from mentalization
next slide.
I was reviewing uh Karl Marx when I was
in London in Oxford
and the glaring uh the glaring error in
in Marxism is so stunning. You say how
could large populations and whole
countries even fallen for it. Okay?
Because it instantly sees perpetrator
and victim.
Here you got a poor town. Company comes
in. They put spend their savings and
they build a store. They start an
enterprise. Now all the people in this
little town got something to do. They
all got jobs and now they can buy cars.
The population gets bigger. They build a
high school.
They got prosperity. Now this company
that came in and made this all possible
is the perpetrator.
These are all now victims according to
Markx
uh according to car marks. So that
dualizing things into perpetrator and
victim then
is misperceiving and projecting it onto
the world. Instead of seeing them as a
benefactor, they see it as the
perpetrator. And now you've got the
worker versus capitalism and all the
crap that goes with it. All right. So
we're talking about different universes.
We talked about the Newtonian paradigm
which is the world of the ego which
things are logical and progressive and
provable.
And then now science has discovered
quantum mechanics and we discovered that
things are quite disorderly
that they're not predictable that
they're sporadic
and therefore I use today the term
threshold. The threshold is a composite
of all things both predictable and
unpredictable.
All things knowable and unknowable
because the stochastic
is unknowable. Unknowable.
Unknowable.
And the sky diver whose parachute
doesn't open discovers that
everything knowable has been checked
out.
But he forgot about the unknowable.
The unknowable arises just as you leave
the plane. The unknown, undetectable,
one tiny flick in
one particular thought pattern in
consciousness.
And that's the difference between life
and death. the fact that
in the non-Newtonian subjective
matrix of reality
things are not predictable
is why
pushing one's luck with extreme sports
is
of course you don't really have to keep
this body you can have another one
we'll go on to the next one next one
these are just recapitul ulations and
uh
I had them all spread on the floor here
and you went and took them off the
floor. That's your problem.
Give me one more slide and we'll take a
break.
Uh
yeah, we calibrated the higher levels of
consciousness. You see enlightenment,
etc. Now, what was the purpose of this?
The purpose of this was because it's
there's never been
like proof of spiritual realities.
There's never been demonstration,
convincing demonstration,
verifiable proof, verifiable evidence of
the states of higher consciousness.
We take people's word for it.
The church says somebody's a saint, etc.
But there's never been any actual
objective verification of levels of
consciousness or spiritual states,
so-called spiritual realities. So the
purpose of this was to document and of
course we've done this with whole groups
in previous years.
We've doc documented the existence of
this reality
and we see that it's on that whole curve
of consciousness that it goes all the
way up to infinite all the way up to
infinite.
With kinesiology we've got that the in
the power of the field which is
continuously present is infinite
infinite. infinite.
We got that there are calibrated levels
of consciousness classically termed
enlightened from 600 and up. Although
rare, they are always the same
throughout history and we can calibrate
the level of consciousness of any of the
great saints or great spiritual teachers
of all time. Therefore, they are not
figments of people's imagination
or wishful thinking or are they unreal.
In fact, the person who says they're not
real is the one who's being unreal
because they're limited to mechanistic
reductionism, which doesn't even get up
to 450. I think mechanistic reductionism
is about 420.
Mechanistic reductionism is over 420,
425.
mechanistic reductionism. It isn't real
unless you can measure it way it
calibrates the 420. So it's sort of dumb
actually. I don't wish to be insulting
but it is pretty dumb.
All these great levels of consciousness
exist but beyond that person's
understanding. Next one then we're going
to take a break.
The verification of spiritual reality
then is one of the things we did. And
what we did this morning is we went
through form. We went through
recognition, awareness, observer,
witness. And we talked about the nature
of consciousness itself.
And this is the purpose of all the
lectures is to reach this realization.
Yeah. Okay. No, we we'll stop there.
liquid there.
So, what we did this morning was try to
recapitulate where we started so that
we're all in the same all in the same
field, right? We're all in the same.
Does everybody understand everything
said this morning? Anybody left?
We'll have questions and answers later
because I want everybody to understand
what we've talked about.
Everything comes into existence as a
result of the field. The totality of the
field. That's the essential point that
jumps you 450 lifetimes.
We'll resume after a short break.
>> Those that are not here don't deserve to
hear what we're going to say anyway.
Yeah, we don't want to be tardy to
heaven, do we?
I had to clear an energy that came up
during the lecture
out of the archetype of the religionist
in me
because self-realization means that the
absolute authority of the truth of the
divinity of God as the essence of your
existence comes from within.
that up brought up a fear of heresy in
the archetype of mind religionist
because
traditionally you're supposed to believe
what you're told to believe and anything
else is heresy. The pure heresy came up
so I had to go outside and clear the
prayer.
If it came up in me that means it's in
the unconscious of uh
probably everyone here. Yeah.
Yet we have permission to realize the
truth of our own existence.
We have the we have permission
collectively as a group. I have
permission to ask this question. Resist.
We have permission collectively as a
group to realize the truth of the source
of our own existence.
Resist.
We have permission.
I feel better.
It really came up as a bad energy and I
heard myself going flat. I thought, God,
there's somewhere energy in me here.
Yeah. Out of the unconscious.
Young's concepts of the archetypes is
quite interesting, you know. So, as you
get to certain levels, you pull up the
karma of all kinds of things, both
positive and negative. There you go.
All right. So, we calibrated the levels
of consciousness. We showed how they
evolve through evolution.
The profound impact it has on every
aspect of human life. How one changes
one's karmic potential by making
decisions every instant.
Then a couple lectures ago we showed the
distribution of the levels of
consciousness on the planet and that
brought up collective karma.
You see,
people of a similar pattern tend to come
on and off the planet collectively as
groups.
Let's say you have a whole group that
comes in and slaughter zillions of
peoples and they now they're living with
the with the karma of having slaughtered
millions and thousands and millions of
innocents. How are you going to undo
that, folks?
Are you going to undo the karma of
having slaughtered innocent people by
the millions?
In my lifetime, 100 million have been
slaughtered.
Just in this lifetime, one lifetime, 100
million. So, how do you undo that karma?
You go to a different domain where you
get a certain spiritual awareness.
Well, you come back
These are people that seem to have
pretty good karma, pretty good people.
And these people here have some pretty
bad karma. 55 in the middle of all these
300s and 400s. The western hemisphere
then tends to collect people who evolved
certain to a certain degree and they
tend to congregate together.
Understanding the consciousness of
various nations, their political
leaders, geographic areas is so crucial
to successful diplomacy
that frankly we've never had any very
successful diplomacy due to the lack of
this knowledge. You see, we think we're
talking to people like us.
Let's have the next thing. You are not
talking to people like us at all.
Resumption that other people are like
you is one of the great fallacies and
naivities.
You are not talking to people like you
at all. Get that? They are not at all
like you. They don't have the same
presumption of values.
Nothing like what you think at all.
Here
we see people congregating uh in
different levels of consciousness. You
see Australia 4410 355 305
India 355
then you you see Europe around 300 to
religion is not very big spirituality is
not very big in Europe in France only
15% of the population are religious
all right but they are into the 300s the
four00s which is certainly at least
humanism fairness rationality balance
then You get to North Africa and North
Africa you see we don't know anything if
we didn't read any newspapers we just
came here from another planet and
calibrated everything this is what we
would find now from what we know about
the levels of consciousness we could
write current history couldn't we
say if this country is 180 and this is
190 what's the likelihood of their
achieving peace
>> zero
because 180 and 190 would rather die for
the cause than give in. Huh? And so you
see it goes on there for centuries.
Having a peace parade is not going to
help it.
I don't go to peace parades. They're too
dangerous. The rocks, the police, the
dogs, all the maniacs, zealots, people
shouting, getting rid in the neck. Oh
yeah.
This is not going to be peace. And this
is going to be disaster.
What's the war that's been going on for
30 years there?
>> Rwanda.
Whatever. Anyway, civil war. They get
slaughtered by the thousands.
People say, "Is that fair?" Yeah, I
guess it is. Otherwise, it wouldn't be.
Huh?
So, there seems to be a collective
karma. Huh? Collective karma. Group
karma. There is such a thing as group
karma tends to interact with personal
karma. Sometimes overrules it resist.
Yeah. The group karma is more powerful
sometimes than your individual karma. So
we see a karmic phenomena. Then a whole
horde of people coming on do horrendous
things. Then we see 50 or 100 years
later a whole area of the country.
People already have a calibrated level
of consciousness at the time of their
birth. How did they get that?
How did they get it?
Here you see the consciousness level
predominance is 40 in certain parts of
central Africa. There
the average age of age of death is 12
and a half.
People are born with AIDS. It's a race
to see whether they're going to die of
AIDS or starvation or be slaughtered by
a neighboring tribe or just abandoned
and left on the side of the road by the
mother who is so weak from starvation
and disease that she herself. So they
live in the consciousness level of this
is apathy
insufficient energy to ensure your own
survival. Apathy.
Will money help it? No.
Because the animal brain when you give
it money makes bombs and kills you with
them. Doesn't know what to do with
money. Doesn't know understanding what
to do with money. If it knew what to do
with money, it wouldn't be calibrating
at 40. doesn't know what to do with
assets.
So,
we have to look at the reality of what
is before we can decide we're going to
improve it. If you don't know what the
problem is, how can you improve it?
All right. So, let's go to the next
slide.
And we said then calibrated levels can
are a way of investigating and
researching history, trying to discover
what was the mistake in the past. So we
don't do it in the future. Everybody's
been interested in pe peace has been a
big pop political slogan lately.
You see, when you take peace and turn it
into a political slogan, it just becomes
another weapon. And then what I told you
about the the cerebral cortex, the
animal in you that wants to be right and
go to war now uses peace
to attack you with
the peace wars is what we've been seeing
hearing on the television.
What people want peace. Well then what
is peace? In as much as people don't
know what peace is, how could they
achieve it?
Peace is the natural state when truth
prevails.
Therefore, any extreme political
position,
even ostensibly in peace, is nothing but
creating war, ideologic war, rather than
physical war. And ideologic war always
precedes physical war. Therefore, the
danger signs are in the distortions of
truth.
The basis of war state when falsehood
prevails, when the lie prevails. When
the lie prevails. If Marx was right,
communism would have brought great
benefit to all the world.
We see the collapse of one communist
country after another. So Marxism, if
you calibrate it, is well below 200.
It's based on a fallacy
of the duality of
perpetrator and victim, which is all in
your mind.
The basis of war then is ignorance. The
human mind cannot the human mind unaded
cannot discern truth from falsehood.
That was the value of the calibrated
levels of consciousness. For the first
time in all of human history, you could
tell the truth of the falsehood of
anything without a political historical
warp to it.
Consequences.
The human mind cannot discern truth from
falsehood. It can't tell a leader from a
megalomaniac.
To make it even more difficult, some
integrous leaders became megalomaniacs
after they had done great things for
society.
And they went from 450
or 460
down to 90. And at the time of the
battle of Waterlue, what had been a 460
consciousness was 90 and the Duke of
Wellington at 420,
Napoleon at 90 was no match. Huh?
Consequences. Inability discern leader
from a megalamomaniac. The basis is that
the ego is programmed into polarized ego
positions.
And we can see politicians every night
on television getting up,
presenting a programmed ego position,
and then trying to program you with it.
Program you with it.
Polarized ego positions.
The result is a distortion of truth and
propaganda.
People are shocked and bin Loud makes
you go weak and George Bush makes you go
strong. That's how badly they got
programmed.
That's a fact. I was speaking in
California. People are shocked. Why?
Because the political programming is so
severe. You think it's the opposite.
Bwah is our savior. Bush is the demon.
Right? Switching good and evil. You see
how profound is the ignorance? One
calibrates at 460, the other
calibrates at 90. Wow. To not know the
difference between 90 and 460 is to be
severely mentally distorted.
Distortion of truth results of
propaganda. The cost to mankind. Of
course, in my lifetime, 100 million
people's lives. Therefore, it's
important to be able to discern truth
from falsehood.
Devotional non-duality means one is
devoted to the truth and not to a
positionality.
One surrenders one's positionalities to
truth. Yeah.
A person unwilling to do that then is
not willing to really make the effort to
reach a really enlightened state of
consciousness. The willingness to
surrender everything to God as it arises
is a form of contemplation.
So the really spiritually committed
person
is really in a constant state of
contemplation of of varying degrees.
Sometimes mild, sometimes strong.
But the field the field you see
becomes now committed to spirituality
and therefore the person becomes a
different kind of person. Even though
you think you're worrying about the
grocery bill, you're doing it in a
different context than the person who
doesn't have an atheric brain.
You're not willing to kill over it. They
are.
They'll kill you for money. They do all
the time.
So, we walk through life as a
spiritually committed person.
It con and it's a contemplative
lifestyle.
You don't have to run off to a monastery
and sit cross-legged and shave your
head. You don't have to wear
birkenstocks.
You don't have to wear robes.
You don't have to do strange and
wondrous things, make wird sounds.
You can walk through life committed to
God and surrendering everything as it
arises.
So the surrendering process is
continuous.
constantly surrendering things to God.
You see them arise.
You realize now that it's arising out of
the animal. So instead of condemning it
and vilifying it and demonizing it, you
forgive the animal. You begin to
recognize your ego as the animal inside
of you and you make a pet out of it
instead of a demon.
You can call him Wall-E.
You can call her Trilla.
But that's sexist, isn't it? We can't do
that anymore.
We could call it Wolfy.
Woofy is your fuzzy animal. And of
course, Wolfy likes to chase rabbits and
eat them. That doesn't mean Wolf is not
lovable. It means he is. So you see your
own ego come up. Then we don't have to
go into guilt and penance. So the old
way, the thing that kicked me out this
morning was guilt and penance and
dependence on the church for salvation.
Giving away the authority of the essence
of divinity within yourself. Capacity
forgiveness. You give it to something
out there
which now runs you and has control of
you and your destiny. to break away from
that was the heretic
and I'd be burned long ago.
Yeah, they never get me that far.
Could think for oneself then
hypothetically it was dangerous and you
could see why the church authorities
considered it dangerous because you
could get off into any kind of bizarre
thought system.
New Aism.
Newagers get prone to getting off into
bizarre thought systems and we'll see
how that arises. Okay. Out of naive. So
we can go back now in history. We can go
to we'll stay away from recent history
because people still have feelings about
it. We'll go back to more remote
history. This is recent history in my
lifetime.
Well, these people are dead now. I don't
know.
And you see Winston Churchill at 510 was
the was the bulldog that held the empire
together and sustained Britain through
the London Blitz
etc. President Roosevelt happily was at
499. Later we see Truman who had to make
a very difficult decision. I don't envy
his decision about dropping the atomic
bomb. You see the integrity
tend tended to be here. We see General
Raml himself was 203
uh
and was integrous in what he did.
Emperor Hirohito Tojo Admiral Yamamoto
they were you know meritorious warriors.
They were doing what they thought was
right for the country. And we see below
200 we see all the people
that you don't want to know
and say Hitler started out around 450 or
so and then later crashed too
90 or whatever he was. Stalin I don't
think was ever up there.
Neville Chamberlain was just naive.
Neville Chamberlain's error was he
thought that other people think like we
do.
other people don't think like we do at
all
and we've done this before in front of a
group you know we'll do it again we have
permission to do what Hitler thought at
the time was after signing the peace
agreement peace in our time Neville
Chamberlain went home as a champion
Hitler thought he was an idiot and said
first thing Hitler thought was what an
idiot
it'd be like signing a contract with a
drug dealer
on credit.
So what our state department has done
and many in the western world is have
agreements with drug dealers disguised
as politicians. They're not going to
keep the agreement in the minute you
walk away. So they get on television,
they talk about peace, and that night
you see another busload of children is
blowing up at their command. Oh,
tech on Pearl Harbor 45. Joseph Gobles
60. Gobles was an expert at pro
programming people. We see all the
various elements that went on. The
London Blitz calibrated at 30.
And here's Lord Haha. He didn't come out
too good either.
Lord Haha.
Let's go on to the next one. All right.
So you see the profound importance to
the world. Not only is it important for
the evolution of your own consciousness,
but in when sharing it with the world,
you see to merely share the truth of all
of this already changes the world.
We haven't even published any of this.
And yet I can tell you it's already
changed the world. And to publish it
should have a profound impact.
To know the nature of the beast before
you take it on. Mankind has never had
any capacity to understand levels of
consciousness or truth from falsehood.
Well, we mentioned this morning uh I was
trying to do a diagram last night that
would explain God and the whole world,
the universe, the evolution of
consciousness, the human ego and
enlightenment.
But I forgot my crayons.
I did try it and if I succeed, I'll of
course share it with you. But at the end
I'll show you the how at least started.
All right. So this is the condition of
the world as it is.
You see it's the karmic evolution.
Feels they don't believe in karma. Well
you are aren't you? Yes.
Then you must have be come into
existence
and all that is confurious to you coming
into existence is collectively called
karma. Karma is really the totality of
all which has determined any specific t
state or point in time.
This little piece of dust floating
through here is the result of the karmic
influence of the totality of all
existence up to this moment. Okay. So
we'll flash that back in. So
the condition of the world then
condition of a state of consciousness
or a waring nation the condition of
anything then can be stated
theoretically in quantum mechanics as
the shreddinger process time dependent
and time independent two fancy formulas.
Then into this potentiality into this
potentiality you now introduce intention
human will
the Heisenberg process then
consciousness suddenly at the
submicroscopic level
enters the field. Now the consequence
will depend on local conditions.
the Heisenberg principle then I say yes
I'll do it instantly the person who just
said yes I'll do it is a com is
completely different than the person
before saying that why because the
Heisenberg process has already collapsed
the wave function the potential it's
already collapsed the wave function and
it has started a whole new process
the neat thing about the quantum
mechanics is that it gives the rational
person who is bound by science, logic
and reason
an avenue to transcend into the next
paradigm of reality. Although
Einstein refused the trans the
transition to the next paradigm,
spiritually evolved people have already
presumed that the reality of the 500s is
of a different dimension. It's a
different paradigm than the 400s. And
this is all explained quite correctly
on the internet. What do you call that
computer thing? Henry stat. Okay. You
can look up his website. That's the
word. Website. Okay. We'll move on.
Yeah. So, we've recapitulated
everything. Did we do animals with you?
Do we do animals?
>> Oh, we didn't do animals.
Well, because animals play a big part in
the evolution of consciousness. Don't
forget the ego is is the evolution of
the animal consciousness. So, we don't
demonize animals. We love them and we
see what they are.
And you don't put your ankle
in the cage of the Komodo dragon. Not
because you hate the Komodo dragon, not
because you're afraid of the Komodo
dragon,
but out of respect for how a Komodo
dragon sees the world and thinks. He
thinks of the world in terms of food.
All right. So, we thought, well, we
would ask about the animal kingdom then.
And we said, the best thing to do with
your ego is to be friendly with it and
see it as a a cute little animal.
In order for life to survive on this
planet, if you went to Mars now and
wanted to plant life, it would have to
be programmed 100% for survival.
So the core of the ego is interested in
its own survival and not yours.
You can see that be you can see as we
come up to the animal, if the animal's
concerned about your life, he probably
wouldn't survive.
The core of the essence of primitive
life can only be interested in itself.
It only has enough energy
to for its own survival.
It cannot be interested in you. The
bacteria does what it's got to do to
survive. The fact that it kills you in
the meantime is not the bacteria's
problem. Nor is it concerned.
If the bacteria began, if the staffus
was worried about you, it wouldn't
survive. you see would violate its own
programming. So from the beginning, life
is programmed at the basic animal level
for survival. Therefore, we can forgive
it and see that that's what it's
that's what it's programmed for.
People under 200 think they have to do
what they do in order to survive. See,
they still think like animals.
So, this is really fun. So one weekend
we did this and it starts out bacteria
are one, protozoa calibrated two,
crustaceians at three, insects at six,
arachnids seven.
Then we jump to amphibians 17, fish are
at 20, sharks are at 24,
vipers 35. Oh, here's my friend the
komodo dragon.
Komodo dragon calibrates higher than
serial child killers.
Do you know that a serial child killer
calibrates lower than a komodo dragon?
They calibrate about 30.
Reptiles are at 40. Therefore, being
friendly with your alligator is not
going to pay off.
Then we get from reptile into predatory
mammals.
The hyena, the lion, the tiger at 40.
Making friends with your tiger can only
go so far because his inner ego is 40.
And one day he's going to love you so
much he's going to eat you.
Because that's how an animal expresses
itself.
Snakes are at 45. Alligators here. No,
alligators are here. Reptiles are 40.
List an alligator. I'm sorry. Sorry.
Alligators.
Dinosaurs at 60.
Whales jump all the way up to 85.
Dolphins at 95. Migratory Birds 105.
There's a tremendous movie out called
Migratory Birds.
Anybody seen it?
>> It's stunning. Huh?
>> Wing Migration.
>> Huh?
>> Winged Migration.
>> Wing Migration. Yeah. Stunningly
beautiful.
Stunningly beautiful.
105. Birds of prey are at 105. See,
they're not they're not worse than they
eat seeds. And these one eat other
little living things, but they both
calibrate. So, they're both interested
in having lunch.
Little rodents are 105.
How is Hippopotamus on here? Uh oh,
we're missing hippopotamus.
Oh, there he is. Okay.
>> Okay, we got the rhinoceros who doesn't
seem too bright. He just charges
everything in sight.
Song birds jump up. Doves jump up. The
polar bear who also tends to eat
everything in sight. The grizzly bear
will attack and eat anything. The water
buffalo is extremely dangerous animal
will suddenly charge you for no no
reason. A black bear is trustable up to
a certain level, but not all the way
because he's 180. Jackals and foxes, you
begin to see intelligence really
beginning to show up. In the wolves, we
see very What's interesting is you see
group pack formation. You see the
dominant alpha male and female. You see
the territoriality.
You see group
identity, group
commitment. And we still see this in the
humans. So the characteristic of the
life of the wolf is very characteristic
of whole societies in today's world.
The hippopotamus of course kills more
humans than any other animal.
Interestingly enough, they look too dumb
to kill people, but I guess the people
they kill are dumber than they are.
Everybody knows not to swim with
alligators, but I guess they figure
hippopotamuses are too dumb. I don't
know how hippopotamus has killed so many
people. We'd have to find that out.
Havalina 195. They knock over our
garbage cans around this area.
You have to tie up your trasher because
the Havalina knock it over. They're
pretty smart. They know if they knock
over the trasher, garbage will come out.
And so they knock over every trasher and
sometimes when I go off to the girls
ranch in the morning, I'll see one
trasher after another down the street.
They happily knock them down. So at 195,
they're getting pretty smart. 195 is a
calibrated level uh
of the troublesome parts of the Middle
East, by the way.
Uhhuh.
All right, we get to Havalina. Then we
come to the a big transformation.
A big transformation is the appearance
on the great plains of Africa and the
North America of the grazing animals.
The zebra, the gazelle,
the deer, the elk, the buffalo, the deer
at 205, the buffalo is at 205.
Domestic pig is 205.
An elk somehow develops an even grander
stance in the world.
And you hear them whistling and talking
back and forth at night. And the elk are
talking to each other,
probably deciding which of the girls
belong to which of the guys because they
spend they spend a lot of time clashing
their horns together and doing
testosterone type things.
The world has been, you know, at the
devastation of lower levels of
consciousness plus test testosterone.
You put the two together and you got
human history.
Testosterone comes out of the animal
nature, does it not? And what does the
cerebral cortex of the people under 200
do with testosterone? They kill, kill,
and rape, right? Kill and rape. You have
Chung King in the 1930s. 30,000 people
slaughtered.
All the females raped and then killed.
Yeah.
Testosterone plus lack of
responsibility.
All right. Plus the animal nature. So we
come to the domestic animal, the elk,
and we get to the dairy cow at 210. I
don't like cows.
One time when I was trucking manure for
a living here,
I'd love to use that as I told you and I
truck manure for income and I used to
get the manure out at um Magguireville.
There was a 600 head dairy farm and you
could back up the truck for 10 bucks.
They dumped it in. You drove it to
Sedona, sold it for 40. Wonderful.
Great life.
Simple life. It didn't require thinking
going into left brain and I was just in
a state all the time so I could function
that way and survive.
I don't know why I started to tell you
that anyway.
Oh yeah. One day here here's this farm
these long fences going down white
fences you know and 600 head of cattle
dairy cattle and they all got their head
between the fence and it's the middle of
winter middle of winter January and all
their noses are running copiously just
all their noses are just running and
they don't have hankies they can't wipe
on their nose
there's hundreds of cattle sticking
their head out like this and all their
little noses are just running running
hysterical
So you see, we love them. Once they're
over 200, we love them. You know, these
folks over here are a little hard to
love, but 200 over, even if their noses
are running, you love them somehow.
And here's the sheep at 210. Range
cattle are the same as domestic cows,
interestingly enough. I thought they
would be calibrated lower. They aren't.
Then we jump to elephants at 235.
235 then is more trustable than a large
part of the human populace. You're safer
with
a friend of the elephant. You know, you
really are. And uh
so
they show group solidarity, group love.
The family sticks together. They mourn
the dead. They get together the
elephants and go through a mourning
process for the dead recognizing the
presence or the absence of life.
Elephants quite evolved. The farm horse
at 240. We always love the farm horse
and when I grew up they didn't have
electricity on the other side of the
highway and nobody had tractors that I
know of. They all they all had a gray
horse and everybody plowed behind the
plow. And so the farm horse was very
important to your own survival.
Cats as a genus as a species calibrated
at 240.
The family cat once once you have a cat
and it gets adopted by a family it jumps
to 245. It jumps five points just
because of the presence of humans. It
has that it has the capacity to respond
to the presence of humans by jumping
five points. So the family cat is 245
about the same as a raceh horse same as
dogs. The family a dog is 245 but if a
family adopts it its consciousness jumps
to 250.
So we see how dog don't forget the cats
we say this is you know the family of
cats. However the cat as we mentioned
before the cat's purr cal calibrates at
500.
The cat as a species, the dog as a
species, the dog's wagging tail
calibrates at 500. But dogs as dogs, the
family dog now jumps five points to 250.
Then we get to some interesting things.
We get up to the gorillas. We get to the
chimpanzees.
We're now getting into the high five
high 200s. And a chimpanzeee is almost
very much like a human. In fact,
genetically apparently it is except for
0.4% of its DNA or something like that.
And we know that you can talk to and
that Coco for instance uh Coco
calibrates at 405. Has quite an
extensive vocabulary.
Everybody knows who Koko is.
Yeah. All right. So, Koko has learned a
great deal of language. knows 600 uh
words or something and can actually
construct sentences, concepts, subject
and object gets the difference between
subject, object and verb. Really quite
quite advanced. 405 a songird song we
can add to the 500s is 500.
We go into rapture and the poet has done
so throughout time about the song of the
night and gale. the sound of a singing
bird at 500, the same as a cat's purr
and a dog's wagging tail. So somehow
mankind
uh gets back the goodness and love that
we give to the animal kingdom somehow
comes back to us because these these are
are close close to us and Alex the train
parrot I guess you're all familiar with
Alex calibrates with 401. Alex can think
400 is the beginning of intellect.
So, Alex can actually think and when he
when she says take two greens and one
orange and make three, he actually does
that. He does that. He actually can
think and Koko can actually figure it
out. Okay. So, that's the animal
kingdom. I thought
you see when we put the animal king
together, animal kingdom together with
the evolution of the ego, you see how we
remove demonization of the ego. That's
why guilt and penance
guilt and penance is not the way way to
God. Guilt and penance is down at the
bottom of the chart. God is at the top
of the chart
to seek God through endless sackloth and
ashes
through self- starvation, self
mutilation, self flagagillation,
through endless oh forgive me, sinner,
sinner, sinner, sinner, sinner. to
repeat that you're a sinner tens and
hundreds of thousands of times.
What could be the effect of repeating
over and over that you are a hopeless
sinner hundreds of thousands of times?
I'm a sinner. Give me a sinner. Sinner
profoundly impacted your belief system
that you are a guilty sinner. That
brings about self- condemnation and
guilt and guilt brings about hatred of
others.
Nobody hates the Catholic Church worse
than somebody who was brought up in
parochial school amongst my patients.
They're intractable atheists.
The hardest was brought up in parochial
grammar school. That inculcation of sin
and guilt and original sin and the
overplay of that has kept man
spiritually enthralled for centuries.
And it's heretical to say that one
should reject it and seek God within.
Yeah.
The necessity for the spiritual virtues.
I thought
these are taken as presumptions.
However,
people fail to see their value.
If we take just let's say what's the
difference between 190 and 205?
What's interesting 190 and 205? Well,
the cross over the threshold of the 200s
is probably the most important thing in
all of spiritual evolution. Why? Because
once you cross over 200, you're going to
be attracted to the rest.
Under 200, you're going to be repelled
or threatened by it. You're threatened
by spirituality.
You're going to pass laws condemning the
use of word God in all public places.
thinking that to mention the word God is
the same as practicing religion.
Religion is one thing. God is something
else. God is a generic term generic term
for divinity. It is not a religion.