We
We have
We have innate
We have innate within
We have innate within us
a
a tremendous
We have innate within us
a tremendous intense
powerful
devotion.
You
You don't
You don't have
You don't have to
You don't have to develop
You don't have to develop it.
You don't have to develop it. You
You don't have to develop it. You only
have
have to
You don't have to develop it. You only
have to rediscover
have to rediscover it.
There
There is
There is with
There is with within
There is with within us
There is with within us already
pre-existent
an
an energy
an energy of
an energy of such
an energy of such enormous
an energy of such enormous power
that
that one
an energy of such enormous power
that one sums
that one sums up
an energy of such enormous power
that one sums up that
that one sums up that power
to
to relinquish
to relinquish any
to relinquish any and
to relinquish any and every
to relinquish any and every attachment
that
that stands
to relinquish any and every attachment
that stands in
that stands in the
to relinquish any and every attachment
that stands in the way.
You
You won't
You won't find
You won't find the
You won't find the willingness
You won't find the willingness to
You won't find the willingness to do
that
that within
You won't find the willingness to do
that within the
that within the ego
You won't find the willingness to do
that within the ego structure.
The
The eagle
The eagle will
The eagle will instantly
The eagle will instantly give
The eagle will instantly give you
The eagle will instantly give you an
argument
argument why
The eagle will instantly give you an
argument why it
argument why it should
The eagle will instantly give you an
argument why it should not
argument why it should not persist
in
in the
in the direction
in the direction that
in the direction that it's
in the direction that it's positioned.
So
So one
in the direction that it's positioned.
So one has
So one has to
in the direction that it's positioned.
So one has to reach
So one has to reach deeper
in the direction that it's positioned.
So one has to reach deeper within
oneself.
At
At the
oneself.
At the very
At the very innate
oneself.
At the very innate core
At the very innate core of
oneself.
At the very innate core of one's
At the very innate core of one's being
is
is a
is a spiritual
is a spiritual power
of
of enormous
is a spiritual power
of enormous strength
which
which alone
which alone can
which alone can accomplish
which alone can accomplish the
impossible.
The
The ego
in
in and
The ego
in and of
in and of itself
The ego
in and of itself cannot
in and of itself cannot transcend
itself.
It
It requires
itself.
It requires the
It requires the presence
itself.
It requires the presence of
It requires the presence of God.
It
It is
It is by
It is by divine
It is by divine grace
It is by divine grace that
It is by divine grace that one
transcends
transcends the
It is by divine grace that one
transcends the ego.
It
It is
It is by
It is by divine
It is by divine grace
one
one moves
It is by divine grace
one moves from
one moves from mind
It is by divine grace
one moves from mind to
one moves from mind to no
It is by divine grace
one moves from mind to no mind.
It's
It's by
It's by divine
It's by divine grace
It's by divine grace one
It's by divine grace one moves
It's by divine grace one moves from
thinking
that
that content
that content and
that content and linearity
that content and linearity is
that content and linearity is the
ultimate
ultimate reality.
It's
It's by
It's by divine
It's by divine grace.
Now,
Now, no
It's by divine grace.
Now, no one
Now, no one would
It's by divine grace.
Now, no one would be
Now, no one would be here
It's by divine grace.
Now, no one would be here to
Now, no one would be here to pursue
It's by divine grace.
Now, no one would be here to pursue such
a
a goal
if
if such
a goal
if such grace
if such grace did
a goal
if such grace did not
if such grace did not already
a goal
if such grace did not already pre-exist.
Therefore,
Therefore, each
Therefore, each and
Therefore, each and every
Therefore, each and every one
Therefore, each and every one of
Therefore, each and every one of us
Therefore, each and every one of us here
this
this day
is
is here
is here by
is here by virtue
is here by virtue of
is here by virtue of divine
is here by virtue of divine grace.
Therefore,
I
I pray
I pray to
I pray to the
I pray to the divine
I pray to the divine grace
I pray to the divine grace in
I pray to the divine grace in thee
I pray to the divine grace in thee and
bless
bless it.
I pray to the divine grace in thee and
bless it. acknowledge
bless it. acknowledge it
because
because it
because it is
because it is the
because it is the divinity
because it is the divinity of
because it is the divinity of that
because it is the divinity of that grace
by
by which
because it is the divinity of that grace
by which we
by which we all
because it is the divinity of that grace
by which we all exist
by which we all exist at
because it is the divinity of that grace
by which we all exist at this
by which we all exist at this moment.
Huh?
So
So that
Huh?
So that which
So that which you're
Huh?
So that which you're looking
So that which you're looking for
Huh?
So that which you're looking for is
So that which you're looking for is not
beyond
beyond you.
beyond you. It's
beyond you. It's not
beyond you. It's not something
beyond you. It's not something you
beyond you. It's not something you have
to
to develop.
It's
It's not
It's not something
It's not something you
It's not something you have
It's not something you have to
It's not something you have to search
for.
One
One only
One only surreners
One only surreners to
One only surreners to that
One only surreners to that which
One only surreners to that which already
exists.
I
I want
I want the
I want the music
I want the music now.
The
The purpose
I want the music now.
The purpose of
The purpose of the
I want the music now.
The purpose of the music
The purpose of the music is
I want the music now.
The purpose of the music is that
The purpose of the music is that it
takes
takes us
takes us out
takes us out of
takes us out of content
takes us out of content and
takes us out of content and it
takes us out of content and it tends
takes us out of content and it tends to
put
put us
takes us out of content and it tends to
put us in
put us in context.
takes us out of content and it tends to
put us in context. It
put us in context. It tends
takes us out of content and it tends to
put us in context. It tends to
put us in context. It tends to take
takes us out of content and it tends to
put us in context. It tends to take us
out
out of
out of the
out of the linear,
put
put us
out of the linear,
put us in
put us in the
out of the linear,
put us in the nonlinear.
his
his own.
He
He be
The
The name
is
here.
song.
He
and
song.
is all
he
Keep
Keep We
he
Keep We are
the
song.
Here
Here we
Here we are.
song.
Give
Give me
Heaven
Oh,
here
here we
Oh,
here we are.
song.
So
he
song.
He
It
It swells
He
It swells up
It swells up from
He
It swells up from within
It swells up from within oneself.
The
The music
The music merely
The music merely creates
The music merely creates the
The music merely creates the field
The music merely creates the field which
allows
allows it
The music merely creates the field which
allows it to
allows it to come
The music merely creates the field which
allows it to come up.
allows it to come up. And
The music merely creates the field which
allows it to come up. And that
allows it to come up. And that power
is
is there
is there at
is there at all
is there at all times.
By
By being
is there at all times.
By being together
By being together today,
is there at all times.
By being together today, we
By being together today, we affirm
is there at all times.
By being together today, we affirm its
presence
presence within
presence within all
presence within all of
presence within all of us.
Well,
Well, I
presence within all of us.
Well, I didn't
Well, I didn't die
presence within all of us.
Well, I didn't die at
Well, I didn't die at all
presence within all of us.
Well, I didn't die at all after
Well, I didn't die at all after all.
Weakness,
Weakness, faintness,
and
and dying
Weakness, faintness,
and dying was
and dying was happening
Weakness, faintness,
and dying was happening on
and dying was happening on the
Weakness, faintness,
and dying was happening on the stage.
And
And then
And then I
And then I walked
And then I walked down
And then I walked down the
And then I walked down the field
And then I walked down the field and
And then I walked down the field and it
stopped.
Could
Could still
Could still be.
Could still be. So,
Could still be. So, what
Could still be. So, what would
Could still be. So, what would could
Could still be. So, what would could be
better?
What
What a
What a wonderful
What a wonderful place
What a wonderful place to
expire.
Came
Came close.
Let's
Let's see.
That's
That's what
That's what it
That's what it was.
That's what it was. Is
That's what it was. Is this
That's what it was. Is this That's
That's what it was. Is this That's what
it
it was.
Okay.
Okay. So,
Okay. So, maybe
Okay. So, maybe we
Okay. So, maybe we should
Okay. So, maybe we should take
Okay. So, maybe we should take a
Okay. So, maybe we should take a break
then.
I
I didn't
I didn't know
I didn't know if
I didn't know if I'd
I didn't know if I'd make
I didn't know if I'd make it
I didn't know if I'd make it to
I didn't know if I'd make it to the
I didn't know if I'd make it to the back
of
of the
I didn't know if I'd make it to the back
of the room
of the room or
I didn't know if I'd make it to the back
of the room or not.
And
And then
And then we'll
And then we'll have
And then we'll have questions
And then we'll have questions and
answers.
answers. Thank
And then we'll have questions and
answers. Thank you.
>> Please
>> Please speak
>> Please speak about
>> Please speak about drugs
>> Please speak about drugs and
>> Please speak about drugs and levels
>> Please speak about drugs and levels of
consciousness.
>> Drugs.
>> Like
>> Like penicellin.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Like
>> Like penicellin.
>> Yeah. Like penicellin.
You
You see
You see the
the
the power
You see the
the power of
the power of addiction
You see the
the power of addiction is
the power of addiction is this.
We
We need
We need the
We need the calibrated
We need the calibrated levels
We need the calibrated levels of
consciousness
consciousness thing
We need the calibrated levels of
consciousness thing up
consciousness thing up there.
We need the calibrated levels of
consciousness thing up there. Huh?
consciousness thing up there. Huh? What
the
the what
the what the
the what the drug
the what the drug does
the what the drug does is
the what the drug does is anesthetize
your
your perception
of
of the
of the lower
of the lower levels
of the lower levels of
of the lower levels of consciousness.
Yeah.
Yeah. Levels
of the lower levels of consciousness.
Yeah. Levels of
Yeah. Levels of consciousness.
>> Okay.
All
All right.
>> Okay.
All right. So,
All right. So, a
>> Okay.
All right. So, a drug
All right. So, a drug cal
>> Okay.
All right. So, a drug cal drugs
calibrate
calibrate around
calibrate around 70
calibrate around 70 or
calibrate around 70 or 80.
calibrate around 70 or 80. Alcohol,
drugs.
drugs. What
calibrate around 70 or 80. Alcohol,
drugs. What they
drugs. What they do
calibrate around 70 or 80. Alcohol,
drugs. What they do is
drugs. What they do is they
anesthetize
all
all this
anesthetize
all this down
all this down here
and
and suddenly
and suddenly you
and suddenly you go
and suddenly you go into
and suddenly you go into a
and suddenly you go into a state
and suddenly you go into a state of
and suddenly you go into a state of a
sense
sense of
and suddenly you go into a state of a
sense of well-being,
sense of well-being, joy,
and suddenly you go into a state of a
sense of well-being, joy, love,
sense of well-being, joy, love, love
everyone,
everyone, contentment,
serenity.
The
The drug
The drug doesn't
The drug doesn't cause
The drug doesn't cause this.
The drug doesn't cause this. What
The drug doesn't cause this. What it
does
does is
The drug doesn't cause this. What it
does is it
does is it blocks
The drug doesn't cause this. What it
does is it blocks these
does is it blocks these out.
Now
Now you
Now you get
Now you get to
Now you get to experience
Now you get to experience what
Now you get to experience what is
Now you get to experience what is there
all
all the
Now you get to experience what is there
all the time.
You
You think,
You think, isn't
You think, isn't that
You think, isn't that drug
You think, isn't that drug wonderful?
Look
Look what
You think, isn't that drug wonderful?
Look what it's
Look what it's done
You think, isn't that drug wonderful?
Look what it's done for
Look what it's done for me.
So
So the
So the error
So the error is
So the error is to
So the error is to ascribe
So the error is to ascribe the
So the error is to ascribe the power
So the error is to ascribe the power to
the
the drug
So the error is to ascribe the power to
the drug and
the drug and think
So the error is to ascribe the power to
the drug and think a
the drug and think a co
So the error is to ascribe the power to
the drug and think a co in
the drug and think a co in terms
So the error is to ascribe the power to
the drug and think a co in terms of
causality
causality that
causality that drug
causality that drug is
causality that drug is causing
causality that drug is causing this.
causality that drug is causing this. No,
this
this drug
causality that drug is causing this. No,
this drug does
this drug does not
causality that drug is causing this. No,
this drug does not have
this drug does not have the
causality that drug is causing this. No,
this drug does not have the power
this drug does not have the power to
cause
cause that.
Drugs
Drugs calibrate
cause that.
Drugs calibrate 80
Drugs calibrate 80 to
cause that.
Drugs calibrate 80 to 90s.
Drugs calibrate 80 to 90s. I
cause that.
Drugs calibrate 80 to 90s. I say,
Drugs calibrate 80 to 90s. I say, but
what
what the
what the drug
what the drug does
what the drug does is
what the drug does is blot
what the drug does is blot all
what the drug does is blot all this
what the drug does is blot all this out.
And
And now
what the drug does is blot all this out.
And now you
And now you feel
what the drug does is blot all this out.
And now you feel like
And now you feel like I
what the drug does is blot all this out.
And now you feel like I just
And now you feel like I just felt
what the drug does is blot all this out.
And now you feel like I just felt a
short
short while
short while ago.
Sort
Sort of
short while ago.
Sort of exquisite,
Sort of exquisite, ecstatic,
short while ago.
Sort of exquisite, ecstatic, joyful
serenity.
consequently
consequently not
serenity.
consequently not to
consequently not to do
serenity.
consequently not to do that
consequently not to do that again.
serenity.
consequently not to do that again. You'd
be
be an
be an idiot,
be an idiot, wouldn't
be an idiot, wouldn't you?
You'd
You'd really
be an idiot, wouldn't you?
You'd really have
You'd really have to
be an idiot, wouldn't you?
You'd really have to be
You'd really have to be stupid
be an idiot, wouldn't you?
You'd really have to be stupid if
something
that
that cost
something
that cost you
that cost you $4
something
that cost you $4 put
that cost you $4 put you
something
that cost you $4 put you in
that cost you $4 put you in that
condition.
Well,
the
the field
the field is
the field is so
the field is so powerful.
the field is so powerful. One
the field is so powerful. One exposure
is
is all
the field is so powerful. One exposure
is all you
is all you need.
the field is so powerful. One exposure
is all you need. You
is all you need. You will
the field is so powerful. One exposure
is all you need. You will never
is all you need. You will never be
the field is so powerful. One exposure
is all you need. You will never be the
same
same again.
same again. Anybody
who's
who's experienced
same again. Anybody
who's experienced up
who's experienced up here
same again. Anybody
who's experienced up here will
who's experienced up here will never
same again. Anybody
who's experienced up here will never be
satisfied
satisfied with
satisfied with anything
satisfied with anything less.
As
As the
satisfied with anything less.
As the Buddha
As the Buddha said,
satisfied with anything less.
As the Buddha said, once
As the Buddha said, once you
satisfied with anything less.
As the Buddha said, once you have
As the Buddha said, once you have heard
of
of enlightenment,
you
you will
of enlightenment,
you will never
you will never be
of enlightenment,
you will never be satisfied
you will never be satisfied with
anything
anything less.
The
The person
anything less.
The person then
The person then becomes
anything less.
The person then becomes so
The person then becomes so powerfully
reprogrammed,
reprogrammed, re
The
The person
reprogrammed, re
The person is
The person is never
reprogrammed, re
The person is never the
The person is never the same
reprogrammed, re
The person is never the same again.
Once
Once you've
Once you've been
Once you've been in
Once you've been in Shangla,
Once you've been in Shangla, the
Once you've been in Shangla, the memory
of
of Shangala
Once you've been in Shangla, the memory
of Shangala is
of Shangala is seared
Once you've been in Shangla, the memory
of Shangala is seared into
of Shangala is seared into your
Once you've been in Shangla, the memory
of Shangala is seared into your memory.
By
By comparison,
By comparison, everything
By comparison, everything else
By comparison, everything else in
By comparison, everything else in this
world
world is
By comparison, everything else in this
world is pale.
The
The experience
The experience of
The experience of the
The experience of the presence
The experience of the presence of
The experience of the presence of God
is
is so
The experience of the presence of God
is so overwhelming
that
that it
that it is
that it is transformative.
that it is transformative. And
that it is transformative. And people
who
who have
that it is transformative. And people
who have had
who have had near-death
that it is transformative. And people
who have had near-death experiences
to
to once
to once go
to once go into
to once go into that
to once go into that knowingness,
all
all else
to once go into that knowingness,
all else in
all else in the
to once go into that knowingness,
all else in the world
all else in the world fades
to once go into that knowingness,
all else in the world fades away.
all else in the world fades away. Huh?
That
That memory
That memory is
That memory is seared
That memory is seared in
That memory is seared in your
That memory is seared in your memory.
That's
That's what's
That memory is seared in your memory.
That's what's possible.
Now
Now to
Now to return
Now to return to
Now to return to Shangerla
Now to return to Shangerla by
Now to return to Shangerla by any
Now to return to Shangerla by any means
even
even if
Now to return to Shangerla by any means
even if it
even if it cost
Now to return to Shangerla by any means
even if it cost you
even if it cost you your
Now to return to Shangerla by any means
even if it cost you your life.
So
So the
So the doctor
So the doctor says
So the doctor says you
So the doctor says you keep
So the doctor says you keep doing
So the doctor says you keep doing that
and
and you'll
So the doctor says you keep doing that
and you'll die.
After
After being
After being told
After being told that,
After being told that, you
After being told that, you leave
After being told that, you leave the
doctor's
doctor's office
and
and you
and you go
and you go to
and you go to the
and you go to the bar
and you go to the bar and
and you go to the bar and order
and you go to the bar and order a
and you go to the bar and order a double
martini.
You
You say
You say to
You say to the
You say to the bartender,
You say to the bartender, "Guess
You say to the bartender, "Guess what
the
the doc
You say to the bartender, "Guess what
the doc told
the doc told me?"
You say to the bartender, "Guess what
the doc told me?" He says,
the doc told me?" He says, "I
You say to the bartender, "Guess what
the doc told me?" He says, "I keep
drinking.
drinking. I'm
drinking. I'm dead
drinking. I'm dead as
drinking. I'm dead as a
drinking. I'm dead as a duck."
You
You don't
drinking. I'm dead as a duck."
You don't say.
You don't say. The
drinking. I'm dead as a duck."
You don't say. The bartender
You don't say. The bartender is
consequently
consequently anything
consequently anything to
consequently anything to overcome
consequently anything to overcome that
addiction
addiction has
consequently anything to overcome that
addiction has to
addiction has to be
consequently anything to overcome that
addiction has to be of
addiction has to be of equal
consequently anything to overcome that
addiction has to be of equal power.
You
You see,
You see, because
You see, because now
You see, because now we're
You see, because now we're talking
You see, because now we're talking about
power.
power. We're
You see, because now we're talking about
power. We're talking
power. We're talking about
You see, because now we're talking about
power. We're talking about logarithmic
power.
This
This is
power.
This is not
This is not a
power.
This is not a little
This is not a little higher
power.
This is not a little higher than
This is not a little higher than this.
This
This is
This is a
This is a whole
This is a whole different
This is a whole different dimension
This is a whole different dimension of
experiencing
experiencing life.
This
This is
This is so
This is so powerful
This is so powerful that
This is so powerful that it's
unforgettable
unforgettable and
This is so powerful that it's
unforgettable and sears
unforgettable and sears itself
This is so powerful that it's
unforgettable and sears itself in
unforgettable and sears itself in one's
memory.
So
So the
memory.
So the desire
So the desire to
memory.
So the desire to reexperience
So the desire to reexperience that
memory.
So the desire to reexperience that high
is
is actually
is actually the
is actually the desire
to
to return
is actually the desire
to return to
to return to God.
The
The person
The person doesn't
The person doesn't know
The person doesn't know that
the
the exquisite
The person doesn't know that
the exquisite bliss
the exquisite bliss of
The person doesn't know that
the exquisite bliss of the
the exquisite bliss of the presence
The person doesn't know that
the exquisite bliss of the presence of
God
God is
God is overwhelming.
wipes
wipes out
God is overwhelming.
wipes out everything.
wipes out everything. Life,
God is overwhelming.
wipes out everything. Life, children,
wives,
wives, physical
wives, physical life,
wives, physical life, physical
wives, physical life, physical death
itself.
Any
Any program
Any program to
Any program to overcome
Any program to overcome it
Any program to overcome it then
Any program to overcome it then has
Any program to overcome it then has to
be
be promised
Any program to overcome it then has to
be promised an
be promised an equal
Any program to overcome it then has to
be promised an equal dimension.
So
So the
So the recovery
So the recovery programs
So the recovery programs from
So the recovery programs from drugs
So the recovery programs from drugs have
to
to calibrate
So the recovery programs from drugs have
to calibrate over
to calibrate over 540.
And
And as
And as a
And as a matter
And as a matter of
And as a matter of fact,
And as a matter of fact, they
And as a matter of fact, they do
calibrate
calibrate at
And as a matter of fact, they do
calibrate at 540.
It
It takes
It takes the
It takes the power
It takes the power of
It takes the power of unconditional
It takes the power of unconditional love
which
which is
It takes the power of unconditional love
which is a
which is a quality
It takes the power of unconditional love
which is a quality of
which is a quality of the
It takes the power of unconditional love
which is a quality of the presence
which is a quality of the presence of
God
God to
God to overcome
God to overcome that
God to overcome that powerful
God to overcome that powerful addiction.
Therefore,
the
the addict
the addict is
the addict is a
the addict is a victim
the addict is a victim of
the addict is a victim of an
the addict is a victim of an illusion
that
that it
the addict is a victim of an illusion
that it comes
that it comes from
the addict is a victim of an illusion
that it comes from out
that it comes from out there.
the addict is a victim of an illusion
that it comes from out there. What
that it comes from out there. What he
doesn't
doesn't know
doesn't know is
doesn't know is that
doesn't know is that what
doesn't know is that what he
doesn't know is that what he experiences
is
is the
doesn't know is that what he experiences
is the liberation
is the liberation of
doesn't know is that what he experiences
is the liberation of the
is the liberation of the experience
doesn't know is that what he experiences
is the liberation of the experience of
his
his own
his own inner
his own inner self.
So
>> what
>> what is
>> what is self
>> what is self sabotage?
>> what is self sabotage? What
>> what is self sabotage? What what
>> what is self sabotage? What what causes
self?
>> Well,
>> Well, it
>> Well, it we
>> Well, it we depend
>> Well, it we depend what
>> Well, it we depend what one
>> Well, it we depend what one means.
Conscious
Conscious or
>> Well, it we depend what one means.
Conscious or unconscious.
The
The appeal
The appeal of
The appeal of destroying
The appeal of destroying oneself
The appeal of destroying oneself is
The appeal of destroying oneself is like
an
an addiction.
You
You get
You get hooked
You get hooked on
You get hooked on degradation,
You get hooked on degradation, poverty,
sacrifice,
sacrifice, suffering,
You get hooked on degradation, poverty,
sacrifice, suffering, filth,
being
being the
being the victim.
And
And the
being the victim.
And the juice
And the juice you
being the victim.
And the juice you get
And the juice you get out
being the victim.
And the juice you get out of
And the juice you get out of all
being the victim.
And the juice you get out of all that
And the juice you get out of all that is
tremendous.
The
The juice
tremendous.
The juice of
The juice of being
tremendous.
The juice of being the
The juice of being the victim
tremendous.
The juice of being the victim can't
The juice of being the victim can't be
beat
beat in
beat in this
beat in this world.
I
I mean,
beat in this world.
I mean, other
I mean, other than
beat in this world.
I mean, other than being
I mean, other than being enlightened,
the
the juice
the juice of
the juice of being
the juice of being victim
the juice of being victim is
the juice of being victim is hard
the juice of being victim is hard to
beat.
You
You have
You have the
You have the trial
You have the trial lawyers
You have the trial lawyers on
You have the trial lawyers on your
You have the trial lawyers on your side.
You
You can
You have the trial lawyers on your side.
You can beat
You can beat up
You have the trial lawyers on your side.
You can beat up McDonald's.
Everybody
Everybody is
Everybody is thronging
Everybody is thronging to
Everybody is thronging to be
Everybody is thronging to be the
Everybody is thronging to be the victim.
There's
There's great
Everybody is thronging to be the victim.
There's great competition
There's great competition for
victimhood,
victimhood, you
victimhood, you know.
So
So the
victimhood, you know.
So the trial
So the trial lawyers
victimhood, you know.
So the trial lawyers association
So the trial lawyers association and
victimhood, you know.
So the trial lawyers association and the
judic
judic judiciary
judic judiciary backs
judic judiciary backs up
judic judiciary backs up that
judic judiciary backs up that whole
judic judiciary backs up that whole idea
of
of no
judic judiciary backs up that whole idea
of no responsibility.
of no responsibility. The
judic judiciary backs up that whole idea
of no responsibility. The cause
of no responsibility. The cause is
judic judiciary backs up that whole idea
of no responsibility. The cause is out
there.
there. The
there. The cause
there. The cause is
there. The cause is always
there. The cause is always deep
there. The cause is always deep pockets.
Somehow
Somehow the
there. The cause is always deep pockets.
Somehow the cause
Somehow the cause always
there. The cause is always deep pockets.
Somehow the cause always has
Somehow the cause always has deep
pockets.
You
You never
pockets.
You never hear
You never hear of
pockets.
You never hear of a
You never hear of a poor
pockets.
You never hear of a poor woman
You never hear of a poor woman being
sued
sued because
sued because somebody
sued because somebody fell
sued because somebody fell on
sued because somebody fell on the
sued because somebody fell on the snow
in
in her
sued because somebody fell on the snow
in her on
in her on her
sued because somebody fell on the snow
in her on her in
in her on her in front
sued because somebody fell on the snow
in her on her in front of
in her on her in front of her
sued because somebody fell on the snow
in her on her in front of her sidewalk.
Gimbals,
Gimbals, yes.
Gimbals, yes. Poor
Gimbals, yes. Poor lady
Gimbals, yes. Poor lady on
Gimbals, yes. Poor lady on the
Gimbals, yes. Poor lady on the corner,
no.
no. It
Gimbals, yes. Poor lady on the corner,
no. It only
no. It only happens
Gimbals, yes. Poor lady on the corner,
no. It only happens if
no. It only happens if you
Gimbals, yes. Poor lady on the corner,
no. It only happens if you have
no. It only happens if you have deep
pockets.
pockets. Oh,
pockets. Oh, yes.
pockets. Oh, yes. The
pockets. Oh, yes. The remuneration.
There's
There's a
pockets. Oh, yes. The remuneration.
There's a peculiar
There's a peculiar thing
pockets. Oh, yes. The remuneration.
There's a peculiar thing about
There's a peculiar thing about the
unconscious.
You
You know,
unconscious.
You know, I
You know, I was
unconscious.
You know, I was in
You know, I was in practice
unconscious.
You know, I was in practice over
You know, I was in practice over 50
years,
years, 52
years, 52 years,
years, 52 years, 55
years, 52 years, 55 years,
years, 52 years, 55 years, whatever.
And
And I've
years, 52 years, 55 years, whatever.
And I've treated
And I've treated many
years, 52 years, 55 years, whatever.
And I've treated many people
And I've treated many people on
disability.
I
I remember
disability.
I remember one
I remember one guy
disability.
I remember one guy was
I remember one guy was run
disability.
I remember one guy was run over
I remember one guy was run over by
disability.
I remember one guy was run over by a
backhole.
I
I mean,
backhole.
I mean, this
I mean, this guy
backhole.
I mean, this guy was
I mean, this guy was crushed.
backhole.
I mean, this guy was crushed. You
I mean, this guy was crushed. You know
what
what I'm
what I'm saying?
I
I mean,
what I'm saying?
I mean, to
I mean, to be
what I'm saying?
I mean, to be run
I mean, to be run over
what I'm saying?
I mean, to be run over by
I mean, to be run over by a
what I'm saying?
I mean, to be run over by a backhole
did
did bust
did bust him
did bust him up.
And
And so
did bust him up.
And so he
And so he was
did bust him up.
And so he was on
And so he was on workman's
did bust him up.
And so he was on workman's comp.
And so he was on workman's comp. Well,
he
he had
he had a
he had a a
he had a a workman's
he had a a workman's comp
he had a a workman's comp is
he had a a workman's comp is very
niggerly
and
and you
and you have
and you have to
and you have to really
and you have to really threaten
and you have to really threaten them,
beat
beat them
and you have to really threaten them,
beat them up,
beat them up, and
and you have to really threaten them,
beat them up, and get
beat them up, and get a
and you have to really threaten them,
beat them up, and get a lawyer.
beat them up, and get a lawyer. You
know,
know, if
know, if I
know, if I was
know, if I was running
know, if I was running workman's
know, if I was running workman's comp,
I'd
I'd say,
know, if I was running workman's comp,
I'd say, "How
I'd say, "How about
know, if I was running workman's comp,
I'd say, "How about 20
I'd say, "How about 20 grand?
know, if I was running workman's comp,
I'd say, "How about 20 grand? Will
I'd say, "How about 20 grand? Will I
make
make you
make you happy?"
make you happy?" Yeah.
make you happy?" Yeah. No.
make you happy?" Yeah. No. They
make you happy?" Yeah. No. They they
won't
won't give
make you happy?" Yeah. No. They they
won't give them
won't give them the
make you happy?" Yeah. No. They they
won't give them the 20
won't give them the 20 grand.
make you happy?" Yeah. No. They they
won't give them the 20 grand. So
won't give them the 20 grand. So 15
years
years later
years later at
years later at the
years later at the cost
years later at the cost of
years later at the cost of $250,000
years later at the cost of $250,000 in
legal
legal fees
years later at the cost of $250,000 in
legal fees on
legal fees on the
years later at the cost of $250,000 in
legal fees on the part
legal fees on the part of
years later at the cost of $250,000 in
legal fees on the part of Workman's
comp,
comp, they
comp, they now
comp, they now come
comp, they now come across.
comp, they now come across. Well,
anyway,
anyway, this
comp, they now come across. Well,
anyway, this guy
anyway, this guy is
comp, they now come across. Well,
anyway, this guy is fighting
anyway, this guy is fighting Workman's
comp
and
and he's
comp
and he's disabled.
and he's disabled. This
comp
and he's disabled. This was
and he's disabled. This was a
comp
and he's disabled. This was a very
honest
honest man.
He
He had
honest man.
He had pain.
He had pain. He
honest man.
He had pain. He had
He had pain. He had uh
honest man.
He had pain. He had uh disability.
He had pain. He had uh disability. He
was
was unemployable.
And
And finally
was unemployable.
And finally workman's
And finally workman's comp
was unemployable.
And finally workman's comp case
And finally workman's comp case got
solved.
He
He got
solved.
He got 50,000
He got 50,000 or
solved.
He got 50,000 or whatever
He got 50,000 or whatever it
solved.
He got 50,000 or whatever it was.
He got 50,000 or whatever it was. Do
solved.
He got 50,000 or whatever it was. Do you
know
know within
know within a
know within a week
know within a week he
know within a week he had
know within a week he had a
know within a week he had a job?
Within
Within a
know within a week he had a job?
Within a week
Within a week he
know within a week he had a job?
Within a week he was
Within a week he was a
know within a week he had a job?
Within a week he was a a
Within a week he was a a guard
know within a week he had a job?
Within a week he was a a guard in
Within a week he was a a guard in a
bank.
Now
Now this
bank.
Now this was
Now this was not
bank.
Now this was not conscious.
Now this was not conscious. It's
different
different than
different than malingering.
different than malingering. Malingering
is
is a
different than malingering. Malingering
is a conscious
is a conscious choice.
different than malingering. Malingering
is a conscious choice. No,
is a conscious choice. No, this
different than malingering. Malingering
is a conscious choice. No, this is
is a conscious choice. No, this is in
the
the unconscious.
Once
Once you're
the unconscious.
Once you're on
Once you're on disability,
the unconscious.
Once you're on disability, forget
Once you're on disability, forget it
because
because it
because it sets
because it sets up
because it sets up an
because it sets up an unconscious
mechanism
which
which keeps
which keeps you
which keeps you disabled.
which keeps you disabled. You
which keeps you disabled. You don't
choose
choose to
which keeps you disabled. You don't
choose to have
choose to have arthritis,
which keeps you disabled. You don't
choose to have arthritis, fibromyalgia,
asthma,
asthma, coughs,
asthma, coughs, diarrhea,
asthma, coughs, diarrhea, headaches,
asthma, coughs, diarrhea, headaches, and
going
going blind
asthma, coughs, diarrhea, headaches, and
going blind with
going blind with buzzing
asthma, coughs, diarrhea, headaches, and
going blind with buzzing in
going blind with buzzing in your
asthma, coughs, diarrhea, headaches, and
going blind with buzzing in your ears.
But
But when
But when the
But when the disability
But when the disability settles
But when the disability settles up,
somehow
somehow they
But when the disability settles up,
somehow they disappear.
It's
It's just
It's just not
It's just not within
It's just not within conscious
It's just not within conscious control.
It's
It's not,
It's just not within conscious control.
It's not, you
It's not, you know,
It's just not within conscious control.
It's not, you know, so
It's not, you know, so there
It's just not within conscious control.
It's not, you know, so there are
It's not, you know, so there are things
operating
operating in
operating in the
operating in the psyche
operating in the psyche over
operating in the psyche over which
operating in the psyche over which we
don't
don't have
operating in the psyche over which we
don't have conscious
don't have conscious control.
operating in the psyche over which we
don't have conscious control. That's
don't have conscious control. That's why
everybody
everybody deserves
everybody deserves our
everybody deserves our compassion
because
because as
everybody deserves our compassion
because as hard
because as hard as
everybody deserves our compassion
because as hard as you
because as hard as you try
everybody deserves our compassion
because as hard as you try to
because as hard as you try to be
conscious
conscious of
conscious of it
conscious of it and
conscious of it and I'm
conscious of it and I'm sure
conscious of it and I'm sure this
gentleman
gentleman who
conscious of it and I'm sure this
gentleman who I
gentleman who I treated
conscious of it and I'm sure this
gentleman who I treated was
gentleman who I treated was a
conscious of it and I'm sure this
gentleman who I treated was a very
honorable
honorable man.
honorable man. He
honorable man. He was
honorable man. He was a
honorable man. He was a blue
honorable man. He was a blue collar
honorable man. He was a blue collar blue
collar
collar guy.
honorable man. He was a blue collar blue
collar guy. I
collar guy. I mean
honorable man. He was a blue collar blue
collar guy. I mean a
collar guy. I mean a straight
honorable man. He was a blue collar blue
collar guy. I mean a straight blue
collar
collar guy
collar guy you
collar guy you know
collar guy you know and
collar guy you know and deception
collar guy you know and deception would
just
just an
collar guy you know and deception would
just an advent
just an advent to
collar guy you know and deception would
just an advent to him.
just an advent to him. He
collar guy you know and deception would
just an advent to him. He would
just an advent to him. He would never
have
have thought
have thought of
have thought of of
have thought of of using
have thought of of using deception
have thought of of using deception at
all.
all. And
have thought of of using deception at
all. And yet
all. And yet that
have thought of of using deception at
all. And yet that mechanism
all. And yet that mechanism was
have thought of of using deception at
all. And yet that mechanism was so
powerful
powerful because
powerful because I
powerful because I can
powerful because I can remember
powerful because I can remember you
powerful because I can remember you know
within
within a
powerful because I can remember you know
within a week
within a week or
powerful because I can remember you know
within a week or two
within a week or two he
powerful because I can remember you know
within a week or two he was
within a week or two he was working
powerful because I can remember you know
within a week or two he was working as
he
he said
he said I
he said I don't
he said I don't know
he said I don't know I
he said I don't know I just
he said I don't know I just feel
stronger
stronger or
he said I don't know I just feel
stronger or something
stronger or something but
he said I don't know I just feel
stronger or something but his
stronger or something but his commitment
to
to life
to life returned
to life returned and
to life returned and uh
and
and he
to life returned and uh
and he worked
and he worked as
to life returned and uh
and he worked as a
and he worked as a uh
to life returned and uh
and he worked as a uh guard
and he worked as a uh guard in
to life returned and uh
and he worked as a uh guard in a
and he worked as a uh guard in a uh
to life returned and uh
and he worked as a uh guard in a uh in
and he worked as a uh guard in a uh in a
bank.
bank. Yes.
bank. Yes. Yeah.
>> And
>> And he
bank. Yes. Yeah.
>> And he to
>> And he to this
bank. Yes. Yeah.
>> And he to this day
>> And he to this day he's
bank. Yes. Yeah.
>> And he to this day he's okay
>> And he to this day he's okay again.
>> But
>> But you
>> But you know
>> But you know it's
>> But you know it's like
>> But you know it's like when
>> But you know it's like when it
>> But you know it's like when it gets
>> But you know it's like when it gets hold
of
of you
>> But you know it's like when it gets hold
of you you
of you you can't
>> But you know it's like when it gets hold
of you you can't let
of you you can't let you
>> But you know it's like when it gets hold
of you you can't let you can't
of you you can't let you can't get
>> But you know it's like when it gets hold
of you you can't let you can't get away
from
from it.
from it. So
from it. So yes,
>> what
>> what is
from it. So yes,
>> what is the
>> what is the source
from it. So yes,
>> what is the source of
>> what is the source of early
from it. So yes,
>> what is the source of early morning
sadness
sadness and
sadness and depression
sadness and depression and
sadness and depression and how
sadness and depression and how do
sadness and depression and how do you
overcome
overcome or
sadness and depression and how do you
overcome or coexist
overcome or coexist with
sadness and depression and how do you
overcome or coexist with it?
>> Early
>> Early morning,
>> I
>> I suppose
>> Early morning,
>> I suppose cuz
>> I suppose cuz you
>> Early morning,
>> I suppose cuz you got
>> I suppose cuz you got to
>> Early morning,
>> I suppose cuz you got to get
>> I suppose cuz you got to get up,
>> Early morning,
>> I suppose cuz you got to get up, I
guess.
Well,
Well, there's
guess.
Well, there's A
Well, there's A people
guess.
Well, there's A people and
Well, there's A people and B
guess.
Well, there's A people and B people.
Well, there's A people and B people. And
a
a lot
a lot of
a lot of people
a lot of people that
a lot of people that are
a lot of people that are B
a lot of people that are B people
a lot of people that are B people strain
to
to be
a lot of people that are B people strain
to be A
to be A people.
Their
Their normal
Their normal sleep
Their normal sleep cycle
Their normal sleep cycle is
Their normal sleep cycle is actually
their
their night
Their normal sleep cycle is actually
their night night
their night night owls.
Their normal sleep cycle is actually
their night night owls. I
their night night owls. I I've
Their normal sleep cycle is actually
their night night owls. I I've seen
their night night owls. I I've seen a
number
number of
number of patients
number of patients who
number of patients who struggle
number of patients who struggle to
number of patients who struggle to be
awake
awake all
number of patients who struggle to be
awake all day
awake all day and
number of patients who struggle to be
awake all day and they're
awake all day and they're taking
number of patients who struggle to be
awake all day and they're taking all
kinds
kinds of
kinds of stuff
kinds of stuff to
kinds of stuff to try
kinds of stuff to try and
kinds of stuff to try and stay
kinds of stuff to try and stay awake
kinds of stuff to try and stay awake and
berating
berating themselves
kinds of stuff to try and stay awake and
berating themselves and
berating themselves and their
kinds of stuff to try and stay awake and
berating themselves and their mothers
are,
are, you
are, you know,
are, you know, mad
are, you know, mad at
are, you know, mad at them
are, you know, mad at them because
are, you know, mad at them because they
won't
won't get
are, you know, mad at them because they
won't get up
won't get up for
are, you know, mad at them because they
won't get up for school,
won't get up for school, etc.
And
And they
And they are
And they are frankly
And they are frankly be
And they are frankly be people.
And they are frankly be people. They
don't
don't wake
And they are frankly be people. They
don't wake up
don't wake up until
And they are frankly be people. They
don't wake up until afternoon.
don't wake up until afternoon. And
And they are frankly be people. They
don't wake up until afternoon. And at
3:00
3:00 in
3:00 in the
3:00 in the morning
3:00 in the morning when
3:00 in the morning when you've
3:00 in the morning when you've been
asleep
asleep for
3:00 in the morning when you've been
asleep for 6
asleep for 6 hours,
3:00 in the morning when you've been
asleep for 6 hours, they
asleep for 6 hours, they are
3:00 in the morning when you've been
asleep for 6 hours, they are just
asleep for 6 hours, they are just going
to
to bed.
to bed. So,
to bed. So, I
to bed. So, I always
to bed. So, I always advise
to bed. So, I always advise people
instead
instead of
to bed. So, I always advise people
instead of trying
instead of trying to
to bed. So, I always advise people
instead of trying to drug
instead of trying to drug yourself
to bed. So, I always advise people
instead of trying to drug yourself to
sleep
sleep at
sleep at night
sleep at night and
sleep at night and drug
sleep at night and drug yourself
sleep at night and drug yourself awake
during
during the
sleep at night and drug yourself awake
during the daytime,
uh,
uh, settle
uh, settle for
uh, settle for being
uh, settle for being a
uh, settle for being a B
uh, settle for being a B person
uh, settle for being a B person and
uh, settle for being a B person and get
a
a night
uh, settle for being a B person and get
a night job.
Well,
Well, the
Well, the night
Well, the night people
Well, the night people is
Well, the night people is a
Well, the night people is a whole
different
different culture.
Well, the night people is a whole
different culture. Anybody
different culture. Anybody who's
Well, the night people is a whole
different culture. Anybody who's been
different culture. Anybody who's been on
the
the road
the road at
the road at night,
the road at night, you
the road at night, you know,
the road at night, you know, uh,
the road at night, you know, uh, knows.
And
And the
the road at night, you know, uh, knows.
And the driver,
And the driver, the
the road at night, you know, uh, knows.
And the driver, the people
And the driver, the people that
the road at night, you know, uh, knows.
And the driver, the people that are
And the driver, the people that are on
the
the road
the road at
the road at night
the road at night are
the road at night are a
the road at night are a whole
the road at night are a whole different
bunch
bunch of
the road at night are a whole different
bunch of people
bunch of people than
the road at night are a whole different
bunch of people than the
bunch of people than the day
the road at night are a whole different
bunch of people than the day people.
bunch of people than the day people. And
I
I used
I used to
I used to love
I used to love the
I used to love the night
I used to love the night swing
I used to love the night swing because
uh
uh you're
I used to love the night swing because
uh you're just
uh you're just with
I used to love the night swing because
uh you're just with a
uh you're just with a different
I used to love the night swing because
uh you're just with a different culture.
It's
It's a
It's a more
It's a more informal,
It's a more informal, accepting
It's a more informal, accepting culture.
It's
It's more
It's a more informal, accepting culture.
It's more easygoing.
It's more easygoing. There's
It's a more informal, accepting culture.
It's more easygoing. There's more
camaraderie.
camaraderie. You
camaraderie. You stop
camaraderie. You stop in
camaraderie. You stop in at
camaraderie. You stop in at a
camaraderie. You stop in at a diner
camaraderie. You stop in at a diner and
wave
wave your
camaraderie. You stop in at a diner and
wave your bell.
wave your bell. And
camaraderie. You stop in at a diner and
wave your bell. And yeah,
wave your bell. And yeah, you
camaraderie. You stop in at a diner and
wave your bell. And yeah, you try
wave your bell. And yeah, you try that
in
in the
in the daytime,
in the daytime, they'll
in the daytime, they'll have
in the daytime, they'll have you
arrested.
arrested. You
in the daytime, they'll have you
arrested. You know,
day
day people
day people are
day people are much
day people are much more
day people are much more uptight.
day people are much more uptight. So
day people are much more uptight. So if
you're
you're a
day people are much more uptight. So if
you're a B
you're a B person
day people are much more uptight. So if
you're a B person instead
you're a B person instead of
day people are much more uptight. So if
you're a B person instead of struggling
to
to be
to be an
to be an A
to be an A person
to be an A person get
to be an A person get a
to be an A person get a B
to be an A person get a B person
to be an A person get a B person job
cuz
cuz that
to be an A person get a B person job
cuz that is
cuz that is there
to be an A person get a B person job
cuz that is there are
cuz that is there are dal
to be an A person get a B person job
cuz that is there are dal patterns
cuz that is there are dal patterns that
are
are really
are really endemic
are really endemic and
are really endemic and to
are really endemic and to try
are really endemic and to try and
are really endemic and to try and fight
it
it is
are really endemic and to try and fight
it is uh
it is uh I
are really endemic and to try and fight
it is uh I I
it is uh I I think
are really endemic and to try and fight
it is uh I I think it's
it is uh I I think it's miserable.
>> Mhm.
>> Is
>> Is there
>> Mhm.
>> Is there any
>> Is there any value
>> Mhm.
>> Is there any value in
>> Is there any value in using
>> Mhm.
>> Is there any value in using various
technologies
technologies to
technologies to attain
technologies to attain different
technologies to attain different brain
states
states i.e.
technologies to attain different brain
states i.e. alpha
states i.e. alpha theta
technologies to attain different brain
states i.e. alpha theta waves?
states i.e. alpha theta waves? Well,
technologies to attain different brain
states i.e. alpha theta waves? Well, I
sort
sort of
sort of took
sort of took that
sort of took that up
sort of took that up a
sort of took that up a little
sort of took that up a little bit
sort of took that up a little bit in
sort of took that up a little bit in the
boot
boot and
sort of took that up a little bit in the
boot and new
boot and new book.
sort of took that up a little bit in the
boot and new book. The
the
the normal
the normal uh
the normal uh brain
the normal uh brain frequency,
the normal uh brain frequency, EG,
the normal uh brain frequency, EG, is
the normal uh brain frequency, EG, is 8
to
to 14
the normal uh brain frequency, EG, is 8
to 14 cycles
to 14 cycles per
the normal uh brain frequency, EG, is 8
to 14 cycles per second.
to 14 cycles per second. That's
the normal uh brain frequency, EG, is 8
to 14 cycles per second. That's beta
rhythm.
rhythm. With
rhythm. With training,
rhythm. With training, one
rhythm. With training, one can
rhythm. With training, one can get
rhythm. With training, one can get into
the
the alpha
rhythm. With training, one can get into
the alpha state,
the alpha state, which
rhythm. With training, one can get into
the alpha state, which is
the alpha state, which is um
rhythm. With training, one can get into
the alpha state, which is um 8
the alpha state, which is um 8 to
rhythm. With training, one can get into
the alpha state, which is um 8 to 14,
maybe
maybe 6
maybe 6 to
maybe 6 to 8
maybe 6 to 8 somewhere
maybe 6 to 8 somewhere in
maybe 6 to 8 somewhere in there.
With
With alpha
maybe 6 to 8 somewhere in there.
With alpha training,
With alpha training, one
maybe 6 to 8 somewhere in there.
With alpha training, one can
With alpha training, one can get
maybe 6 to 8 somewhere in there.
With alpha training, one can get into
what
what seems
what seems to
what seems to me
what seems to me is
what seems to me is more
what seems to me is more like
what seems to me is more like an
what seems to me is more like an altered
state.
Now,
Now, an
Now, an altered
Now, an altered state
Now, an altered state does
Now, an altered state does give
Now, an altered state does give you
Now, an altered state does give you like
a
a glimpse
Now, an altered state does give you like
a glimpse of
a glimpse of what's
Now, an altered state does give you like
a glimpse of what's coming
a glimpse of what's coming ahead.
Now, an altered state does give you like
a glimpse of what's coming ahead. So,
a glimpse of what's coming ahead. So, I
think
think there's
think there's a
think there's a certain
think there's a certain value
think there's a certain value to
think there's a certain value to it.
think there's a certain value to it. And
many
many meditative
think there's a certain value to it. And
many meditative techniques
many meditative techniques take
think there's a certain value to it. And
many meditative techniques take you
many meditative techniques take you to
an
an alpha
an alpha state
that
that tends
an alpha state
that tends to
that tends to be
an alpha state
that tends to be temporary.
that tends to be temporary. However,
once
once the
once the mind
once the mind disappears,
where'd
where'd it
once the mind disappears,
where'd it go?
where'd it go? I
once the mind disappears,
where'd it go? I know
where'd it go? I know where
once the mind disappears,
where'd it go? I know where when
where'd it go? I know where when the
mind
mind goes
mind goes this
mind goes this way.
One
One is
mind goes this way.
One is run
One is run by
mind goes this way.
One is run by context
One is run by context rather
mind goes this way.
One is run by context rather than
content.
At
At that
content.
At that point,
At that point, the
content.
At that point, the mystic
uh
uh the
uh the theta
uh the theta waves
uh the theta waves of
uh the theta waves of the
uh the theta waves of the mystic
uh the theta waves of the mystic are
sometimes
sometimes as
uh the theta waves of the mystic are
sometimes as low
sometimes as low as
uh the theta waves of the mystic are
sometimes as low as two,
sometimes as low as two, three,
uh the theta waves of the mystic are
sometimes as low as two, three, four,
five.
five. Probably
five. Probably around
five. Probably around two
five. Probably around two to
five. Probably around two to four.
five. Probably around two to four. No.
Yeah.
Yeah. Around
five. Probably around two to four. No.
Yeah. Around four
Yeah. Around four to
five. Probably around two to four. No.
Yeah. Around four to five.
The
The brain
The brain waves
The brain waves slow
The brain waves slow down
The brain waves slow down in
The brain waves slow down in amplitude,
in
in volume,
The brain waves slow down in amplitude,
in volume, and
in volume, and in
The brain waves slow down in amplitude,
in volume, and in frequency.
And
And that's
And that's why
And that's why there
And that's why there is
And that's why there is a
And that's why there is a slowing
of
of comprehension
because
because to
because to be
because to be within
because to be within the
because to be within the world
because to be within the world really
requires
requires 18
because to be within the world really
requires 18 14
requires 18 14 8
because to be within the world really
requires 18 14 8 to
requires 18 14 8 to 14
because to be within the world really
requires 18 14 8 to 14 cycles
requires 18 14 8 to 14 cycles per
second.
The
The alpha
second.
The alpha state
The alpha state is
second.
The alpha state is usually
The alpha state is usually um
second.
The alpha state is usually um an
artificially
artificially induced
artificially induced al
artificially induced al alternative
state
state of
artificially induced al alternative
state of consciousness
state of consciousness which
artificially induced al alternative
state of consciousness which one
state of consciousness which one can
learn
learn to
learn to maintain.
the
the theta
learn to maintain.
the theta state.
In
In the
In the theta
In the theta state,
what's
what's going
In the theta state,
what's going on
what's going on in
In the theta state,
what's going on in the
what's going on in the world
In the theta state,
what's going on in the world comes
across
across as
across as a
across as a translation.
The
The events
as
as the
as the world
as the world see
as the world see them
as the world see them as
as the world see them as events
are
are translated
by
by the
by the presence
by the presence of
by the presence of the
by the presence of the Holy
by the presence of the Holy Spirit.
How
How to
by the presence of the Holy Spirit.
How to describe
How to describe it?
The
The condition
The condition is
The condition is one
The condition is one of
The condition is one of silence.
The
The world
The condition is one of silence.
The world is
The world is talking
by
by intention.
by intention. By
by intention. By intention.
by intention. By intention. The
by intention. By intention. The Holy
Spirit
Spirit translates
by intention. By intention. The Holy
Spirit translates the
Spirit translates the meaning
by intention. By intention. The Holy
Spirit translates the meaning of
Spirit translates the meaning of what
by intention. By intention. The Holy
Spirit translates the meaning of what is
being
being said
being said to
being said to you,
which
which is
being said to you,
which is like
which is like being
being said to you,
which is like being heart
which is like being heart of
being said to you,
which is like being heart of hearing,
hearing,
hearing, absent
hearing, absent minded.
There
There is
hearing, absent minded.
There is an
There is an explanation
hearing, absent minded.
There is an explanation of
There is an explanation of it
hearing, absent minded.
There is an explanation of it in
There is an explanation of it in quantum
mechanics.
So
So that
mechanics.
So that what
So that what the
mechanics.
So that what the world
So that what the world experiences
mechanics.
So that what the world experiences as
So that what the world experiences as a
happening
is
is translated.
happening
is translated. It's
is translated. It's as
happening
is translated. It's as though
digital
digital music
digital music is
digital music is transformed
digital music is transformed back
digital music is transformed back into
analog
analog or
digital music is transformed back into
analog or whatever.
There's
There's a
There's a translation.
There's a translation. So,
There's a translation. So, you
There's a translation. So, you speak
There's a translation. So, you speak to
me.
I
I have
I have no
I have no idea
I have no idea what
I have no idea what you're
I have no idea what you're talking
I have no idea what you're talking about
or
or saying.
I
I actually
I actually frankly
I actually frankly don't
I actually frankly don't have
I actually frankly don't have any.
The
The intention
I actually frankly don't have any.
The intention to
The intention to comprehend
I actually frankly don't have any.
The intention to comprehend what
The intention to comprehend what you're
saying
saying activates
saying activates the
saying activates the qual
saying activates the qual a
saying activates the qual a quality.
It's
It's an
saying activates the qual a quality.
It's an impersonal
It's an impersonal quality
saying activates the qual a quality.
It's an impersonal quality in
consciousness.
which
which translates
consciousness.
which translates the
which translates the knowingness.
consciousness.
which translates the knowingness. Huh?
It
It could
It could be
It could be that
It could be that the
It could be that the experiential
whatever
whatever it
It could be that the experiential
whatever it is
whatever it is that's
It could be that the experiential
whatever it is that's left
whatever it is that's left walking
around
around the
around the planet
around the planet is
around the planet is comprehending
around the planet is comprehending and
understanding
understanding by
around the planet is comprehending and
understanding by aic
understanding by aic brain
and
and not
and not celebrating.
Then
Then by
and not celebrating.
Then by divine
Then by divine intervention
it
it crosses
it crosses over
it crosses over somehow
it crosses over somehow into
celebrated
celebrated meaningfulness.
Huh?
>> I
>> I don't
Huh?
>> I don't know
>> I don't know what
Huh?
>> I don't know what she
>> I don't know what she said.
Huh?
>> I don't know what she said. She
>> I don't know what she said. She said
Pepsi.
Pepsi. Yes.
Pepsi. Yes. So,
Pepsi. Yes. So, let's
Pepsi. Yes. So, let's see
Pepsi. Yes. So, let's see what
Pepsi. Yes. So, let's see what these
brain
brain waves
Pepsi. Yes. So, let's see what these
brain waves are
brain waves are going
Pepsi. Yes. So, let's see what these
brain waves are going doing
brain waves are going doing right
Pepsi. Yes. So, let's see what these
brain waves are going doing right now.
Let's
Let's just
Let's just ask
Let's just ask for
Let's just ask for the
Let's just ask for the cio.
Let's just ask for the cio. He
Let's just ask for the cio. He brought
up
up brain
Let's just ask for the cio. He brought
up brain waves.
up brain waves. These
Let's just ask for the cio. He brought
up brain waves. These brain
up brain waves. These brain waves
Let's just ask for the cio. He brought
up brain waves. These brain waves are
less
less than
less than eight
less than eight per
less than eight per second,
less than eight per second, less
less than eight per second, less than
seven
seven per
less than eight per second, less than
seven per second,
seven per second, less
less than eight per second, less than
seven per second, less than
seven per second, less than six
less than eight per second, less than
seven per second, less than six per
second,
second, less
second, less five
second, less five per
second, less five per second,
second, less five per second, less
second, less five per second, less four
per
per second,
second, less five per second, less four
per second, less
per second, less three
second, less five per second, less four
per second, less three per
per second, less three per second,
second, less five per second, less four
per second, less three per second, less
two.
two. These
two. These brain
two. These brain waves
two. These brain waves are
two. These brain waves are running
two. These brain waves are running two
to
to three
two. These brain waves are running two
to three per
to three per second
which
which is
which is why
which is why it's
which is why it's difficult
to
to diff
which is why it's difficult
to diff to
to diff to navigate
which is why it's difficult
to diff to navigate because
to diff to navigate because of
which is why it's difficult
to diff to navigate because of the
altered
altered propriception
altered propriception because
altered propriception because the
altered propriception because the inner
sensy
sensy the
the
the intellect
the intellect the
the intellect the the
the intellect the the ego
the intellect the the ego is
the intellect the the ego is like
the intellect the the ego is like an
incredible
incredible computer
the intellect the the ego is like an
incredible computer and
incredible computer and within
the intellect the the ego is like an
incredible computer and within the
computer
computer there
computer there is
computer there is a
computer there is a central
computer there is a central control
computer there is a central control unit
which
which integrates
computer there is a central control unit
which integrates everything
and
and that's
and that's the
and that's the sense
and that's the sense of
and that's the sense of self
and that's the sense of self mem
When
When that
and that's the sense of self mem
When that disappears,
When that disappears, there's
and that's the sense of self mem
When that disappears, there's no
When that disappears, there's no center
from
from which
propriception
propriception or
from which
propriception or anything
propriception or anything else
originates.
Everything
Everything is
originates.
Everything is originating
Everything is originating from
everywhere
everywhere simultaneously
and
and that's
everywhere simultaneously
and that's why
and that's why it's
everywhere simultaneously
and that's why it's hard
and that's why it's hard to
everywhere simultaneously
and that's why it's hard to explain.
So
So this
So this is
So this is running
So this is running two
So this is running two to
So this is running two to four
So this is running two to four per
second
second at
So this is running two to four per
second at the
second at the moment.
So this is running two to four per
second at the moment. Okay.
I
I mean
I mean that
I mean that was
I mean that was the
I mean that was the explanation
I mean that was the explanation of
I mean that was the explanation of the
question.
question. Nothing.
Since
Since the
Since the consciousness
Since the consciousness of
Since the consciousness of mankind
Since the consciousness of mankind went
from
from 190
Since the consciousness of mankind went
from 190 to
from 190 to 207,
Since the consciousness of mankind went
from 190 to 207, will
from 190 to 207, will spiritual
Since the consciousness of mankind went
from 190 to 207, will spiritual growth
happen
happen faster
happen faster for
happen faster for those
happen faster for those who
happen faster for those who have
happen faster for those who have chosen
the
the spiritual
happen faster for those who have chosen
the spiritual path?
>> Yes,
>> Yes, I
>> Yes, I think
>> Yes, I think um
>> Yes, I think um the
>> Yes, I think um the answer
>> Yes, I think um the answer to
>> Yes, I think um the answer to that
>> Yes, I think um the answer to that is
rather
rather obvious.
You
You see,
You see, because
that
that which
You see, because
that which is
that which is antitheical
You see, because
that which is antitheical to
that which is antitheical to truth
You see, because
that which is antitheical to truth has
already
already lost
already lost the
already lost the game.
already lost the game. It
already lost the game. It lost
already lost the game. It lost it
already lost the game. It lost it lost
in
in the
already lost the game. It lost it lost
in the 19
in the 19 late
already lost the game. It lost it lost
in the 19 late 1980s
when
when the
when the consciousness
when the consciousness level
when the consciousness level of
when the consciousness level of mankind
went
went over
when the consciousness level of mankind
went over 200
went over 200 to
when the consciousness level of mankind
went over 200 to 207.
It
It lost.
So
So it's
It lost.
So it's doing
So it's doing a
It lost.
So it's doing a rear
So it's doing a rear guard
It lost.
So it's doing a rear guard action
So it's doing a rear guard action now
It lost.
So it's doing a rear guard action now to
try
try to
try to maintain
try to maintain its
try to maintain its dominion
try to maintain its dominion over
try to maintain its dominion over this
planet
planet as
try to maintain its dominion over this
planet as long
planet as long as
try to maintain its dominion over this
planet as long as it
planet as long as it can.
But
But it's
But it's lost
But it's lost the
But it's lost the game.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, it's
But it's lost the game.
>> Oh, it's lost
>> Oh, it's lost the
But it's lost the game.
>> Oh, it's lost the game.
>> Oh, it's lost the game. There's
But it's lost the game.
>> Oh, it's lost the game. There's no
question
question about
question about that.
It's
It's lost
question about that.
It's lost the
It's lost the game.
question about that.
It's lost the game. And
It's lost the game. And when
question about that.
It's lost the game. And when the
connection
connection was
connection was made
when
when the
connection was made
when the connection
when the connection was
connection was made
when the connection was made
when the connection was made about
connection was made
when the connection was made about the
correlation
correlation between
correlation between quantum
uh
uh I
correlation between quantum
uh I have
uh I have permission
correlation between quantum
uh I have permission to
uh I have permission to share
correlation between quantum
uh I have permission to share this
resistance.
resistance. Okay.
resistance. Okay. When
resistance. Okay. When the
resistance. Okay. When the connection
was
was completed
resistance. Okay. When the connection
was completed between
you
you see
you see uh
you see uh science
you see uh science is
you see uh science is like
you see uh science is like a
you see uh science is like a where
you see uh science is like a where what
happened
happened to
you see uh science is like a where what
happened to our
happened to our scale
you see uh science is like a where what
happened to our scale consciousness
sweetheart.
All
All right.
sweetheart.
All right. So
All right. So science,
sweetheart.
All right. So science, you
All right. So science, you see,
sweetheart.
All right. So science, you see, is
pushing
pushing up.
pushing up. Where's
pushing up. Where's the
pushing up. Where's the 400s?
Science
Science is
pushing up. Where's the 400s?
Science is pushing
Science is pushing up
pushing up. Where's the 400s?
Science is pushing up here
Science is pushing up here through
pushing up. Where's the 400s?
Science is pushing up here through the
400s.
And
And the
400s.
And the mystic
And the mystic is
400s.
And the mystic is pushing
And the mystic is pushing down
400s.
And the mystic is pushing down from
And the mystic is pushing down from up
here.
here. And
here. And they're
here. And they're going
here. And they're going to
here. And they're going to meet
here. And they're going to meet here
here. And they're going to meet here at
about
about 499,
here. And they're going to meet here at
about 499, right
about 499, right at
here. And they're going to meet here at
about 499, right at the
about 499, right at the right
here. And they're going to meet here at
about 499, right at the right at
about 499, right at the right at 500.
You
You see?
Um,
Um, so
You see?
Um, so the
Um, so the advanced
You see?
Um, so the advanced theoretical
physicist
physicist is
physicist is so
physicist is so close
physicist is so close to
physicist is so close to it.
And
And for
physicist is so close to it.
And for the
And for the mystic
physicist is so close to it.
And for the mystic to
And for the mystic to reenter
physicist is so close to it.
And for the mystic to reenter the
And for the mystic to reenter the world
and
and function
and function again
and function again and
and function again and even
and function again and even take
seriously
seriously the
and function again and even take
seriously the world
seriously the world of
and function again and even take
seriously the world of science
seriously the world of science and
and function again and even take
seriously the world of science and all
that
that is
that is again
that is again practically
that is again practically an
impossibility
for
for the
for the two
for the two to
for the two to go
for the two to go over
for the two to go over like
for the two to go over like that
closes
closes the
for the two to go over like that
closes the gap
closes the gap closes
for the two to go over like that
closes the gap closes the
closes the gap closes the gap
for the two to go over like that
closes the gap closes the gap between
the
the linear
the linear and
the linear and the
the linear and the nonlinear
the linear and the nonlinear between
reason
reason and
the linear and the nonlinear between
reason and experience.
reason and experience. You
the linear and the nonlinear between
reason and experience. You see,
reason and experience. You see, because
the
the quantum
mechanics
mechanics um
um
makes
makes spirituality
okay,
okay, huh?
Because
Because if
okay, huh?
Because if you
Because if you can
okay, huh?
Because if you can explain
Because if you can explain with
okay, huh?
Because if you can explain with quantum
mechanics,
mechanics, now
mechanics, now it's
mechanics, now it's okay.
mechanics, now it's okay. Not
mechanics, now it's okay. Not okay
otherwise.
otherwise. Right
mechanics, now it's okay. Not okay
otherwise. Right now
otherwise. Right now it's
mechanics, now it's okay. Not okay
otherwise. Right now it's okay.
Well,
Well, with
Well, with the
Well, with the closure
Well, with the closure of
Well, with the closure of the
realization,
realization, it
Well, with the closure of the
realization, it took
realization, it took some
Well, with the closure of the
realization, it took some study
realization, it took some study of
quantum
quantum mechanics
quantum mechanics because
quantum mechanics because to
quantum mechanics because to get
quantum mechanics because to get back
into
into the
quantum mechanics because to get back
into the linear,
into the linear, I'll
quantum mechanics because to get back
into the linear, I'll tell
into the linear, I'll tell you,
quantum mechanics because to get back
into the linear, I'll tell you, is
into the linear, I'll tell you, is not
my
my cup
my cup of
my cup of tea.
for
for God
my cup of tea.
for God and
for God and country
my cup of tea.
for God and country for
for God and country for you
my cup of tea.
for God and country for you people.
for God and country for you people. I
did
did it
actually
to
to conclude
to conclude the
to conclude the mission
to conclude the mission was
to conclude the mission was to
to conclude the mission was to close
to conclude the mission was to close the
gap
gap between
to conclude the mission was to close the
gap between the
gap between the linear
to conclude the mission was to close the
gap between the linear and
gap between the linear and the
to conclude the mission was to close the
gap between the linear and the nonlinear
between
between the
between the spiritual
uh
uh and
between the spiritual
uh and the
uh and the ego.
between the spiritual
uh and the ego. And
there
there was
there was an
there was an intense
there was an intense meditation
there was an intense meditation on
there was an intense meditation on the
mathematics
mathematics of
there was an intense meditation on the
mathematics of quantum
mathematics of quantum mechanics
there was an intense meditation on the
mathematics of quantum mechanics etc.
And
And suddenly
it
it all
And suddenly
it all came
it all came together
And suddenly
it all came together like
it all came together like that.
And suddenly
it all came together like that. And
it all came together like that. And I
knew
knew that
knew that that
knew that that which
knew that that which is
knew that that which is the
knew that that which is the reign
knew that that which is the reign of
that
that which
knew that that which is the reign of
that which is
that which is facious
knew that that which is the reign of
that which is facious has
that which is facious has ended.
That
That was
That was the
That was the end.
And
And at
That was the end.
And at that
And at that point
That was the end.
And at that point we
And at that point we got
That was the end.
And at that point we got hit
And at that point we got hit by
That was the end.
And at that point we got hit by the
Abraic,
Abraic, Luciferic
Abraic, Luciferic and
Abraic, Luciferic and Satanic
simultaneously
simultaneously resist.
The
The troops
The troops came
The troops came out
The troops came out and
God
God almighty
The troops came out and
God almighty what
God almighty what a
The troops came out and
God almighty what a day.
The
The nervous
The nervous system
The nervous system was
The nervous system was like
The nervous system was like on
The nervous system was like on fire
The nervous system was like on fire like
being
being electrocuted
The nervous system was like on fire like
being electrocuted slowly.
though
though the
though the combined
though the combined forces
though the combined forces that
though the combined forces that were
incredibly
incredibly threatened
though the combined forces that were
incredibly threatened by
incredibly threatened by the
though the combined forces that were
incredibly threatened by the completion
of
of that
of that within
of that within the
of that within the field
of that within the field of
consciousness.
Uh
Uh it's
Uh it's it
Uh it's it was
Uh it's it was their
Uh it's it was their death
Uh it's it was their death nail.
Uh it's it was their death nail. Let's
say
say let's
Uh it's it was their death nail. Let's
say let's see
say let's see if
Uh it's it was their death nail. Let's
say let's see if that
say let's see if that was
Uh it's it was their death nail. Let's
say let's see if that was their
say let's see if that was their death
now.
now. We
now. We have
now. We have permission
now. We have permission to
now. We have permission to ask
now. We have permission to ask that.
That
That was
now. We have permission to ask that.
That was their
That was their death.
now. We have permission to ask that.
That was their death. No.
That was their death. No. Resist.
Goodbye.
That
That was
Goodbye.
That was the
That was the death.
Goodbye.
That was the death. No.
That was the death. No. You
Goodbye.
That was the death. No. You see,
That was the death. No. You see, because
once
once you've
once you've whised
once you've whised the
once you've whised the sheep
once you've whised the sheep skin
once you've whised the sheep skin off
and
and exposed
once you've whised the sheep skin off
and exposed it
and exposed it for
once you've whised the sheep skin off
and exposed it for what
and exposed it for what it
once you've whised the sheep skin off
and exposed it for what it is,
and exposed it for what it is, now
once you've whised the sheep skin off
and exposed it for what it is, now you
can
can defend
can defend yourself,
can defend yourself, hey,
against
against the
can defend yourself, hey,
against the satanic
against the satanic energies.
can defend yourself, hey,
against the satanic energies. That's
easy.
easy. People
easy. People want
easy. People want to
easy. People want to chop
easy. People want to chop up
easy. People want to chop up little
girls
girls and
easy. People want to chop up little
girls and and
girls and and rape
easy. People want to chop up little
girls and and rape young
girls and and rape young boys
easy. People want to chop up little
girls and and rape young boys and,
girls and and rape young boys and, you
know,
know, burn
know, burn people
know, burn people in
know, burn people in their
know, burn people in their houses
know, burn people in their houses and
torture
torture victims.
know, burn people in their houses and
torture victims. I
torture victims. I mean,
know, burn people in their houses and
torture victims. I mean, you
torture victims. I mean, you don't
know, burn people in their houses and
torture victims. I mean, you don't have
to
to go
to go to
to go to high
to go to high school
to go to high school to
to go to high school to get
to go to high school to get that
to go to high school to get that is
evil,
evil, right?
No,
No, that's
No, that's not
No, that's not where
No, that's not where the
No, that's not where the danger
No, that's not where the danger is.
Although
Although there's
No, that's not where the danger is.
Although there's a
Although there's a great
No, that's not where the danger is.
Although there's a great deal
Although there's a great deal of
seduction
seduction in
seduction in that,
seduction in that, you
seduction in that, you know,
seduction in that, you know, the
seduction in that, you know, the rock
groups
groups that
seduction in that, you know, the rock
groups that cater
groups that cater to
seduction in that, you know, the rock
groups that cater to that
groups that cater to that and
seduction in that, you know, the rock
groups that cater to that and the
groups that cater to that and the drugs
and
and the
and the mayhem
and the mayhem and
and the mayhem and the
uh
uh child
and the mayhem and the
uh child abuse
uh child abuse and
and the mayhem and the
uh child abuse and wife
uh child abuse and wife abuse
and the mayhem and the
uh child abuse and wife abuse and
uh child abuse and wife abuse and all
that.
that. So
that. So that
that. So that which
that. So that which is
that. So that which is uh
that. So that which is uh horrific
except
except for
that. So that which is uh horrific
except for very
except for very demented
that. So that which is uh horrific
except for very demented people
except for very demented people uh
that. So that which is uh horrific
except for very demented people uh like
followers
followers of
followers of bin
followers of bin Laden
followers of bin Laden or
followers of bin Laden or something
followers of bin Laden or something uh
those
those people
followers of bin Laden or something uh
those people are
those people are very
followers of bin Laden or something uh
those people are very very
those people are very very demented.
followers of bin Laden or something uh
those people are very very demented. But
no,
no, the
no, the real
no, the real power,
no, the real power, the
no, the real power, the real
no, the real power, the real danger
no, the real power, the real danger is
that
that which
no, the real power, the real danger is
that which sounds
that which sounds sweet
no, the real power, the real danger is
that which sounds sweet and
that which sounds sweet and lovable
no, the real power, the real danger is
that which sounds sweet and lovable and
logical.
logical. There
logical. There is
logical. There is where
logical. There is where you
logical. There is where you get
logical. There is where you get wiped
out.
Especially
Especially Americans,
Especially Americans, you
Especially Americans, you know,
Especially Americans, you know, because
we're
we're in
Especially Americans, you know, because
we're in the
we're in the mid
Especially Americans, you know, because
we're in the mid 400s.
we're in the mid 400s. So,
Especially Americans, you know, because
we're in the mid 400s. So, it's
we're in the mid 400s. So, it's the
distortions
distortions of
distortions of logic
distortions of logic that
distortions of logic that are
the
the distortions
distortions of logic that are
the distortions in
the distortions in which
distortions of logic that are
the distortions in which you
the distortions in which you can't
distortions of logic that are
the distortions in which you can't tell
the
the perpetrator
the perpetrator from
the perpetrator from the
the perpetrator from the victim
the perpetrator from the victim anymore.
See,
See, somebody
the perpetrator from the victim anymore.
See, somebody bombs
See, somebody bombs the
the perpetrator from the victim anymore.
See, somebody bombs the Jesus
See, somebody bombs the Jesus out
the perpetrator from the victim anymore.
See, somebody bombs the Jesus out of
See, somebody bombs the Jesus out of us.
Oh,
Oh, he's
Oh, he's a
Oh, he's a basically
Oh, he's a basically a
Oh, he's a basically a psychopath.
He
He tortures
Oh, he's a basically a psychopath.
He tortures little
He tortures little animals,
Oh, he's a basically a psychopath.
He tortures little animals, etc.
And
now
now we
And
now we are
now we are Satan.
And
And the
And the movie
And the movie stars
And the movie stars go
And the movie stars go to
And the movie stars go to embrace
And the movie stars go to embrace him.
You
You see
And the movie stars go to embrace him.
You see the
You see the reversal,
And the movie stars go to embrace him.
You see the reversal, the
You see the reversal, the inability
And the movie stars go to embrace him.
You see the reversal, the inability to
tell
tell evil
tell evil from
tell evil from goodness,
tell evil from goodness, the
tell evil from goodness, the inability
to
to tell
tell evil from goodness, the inability
to tell victim
to tell victim from
tell evil from goodness, the inability
to tell victim from perpetrator.
And
And now
And now we
And now we are
And now we are the
And now we are the great
And now we are the great Satan.
If
If you
And now we are the great Satan.
If you don't
If you don't know
And now we are the great Satan.
If you don't know Satan
If you don't know Satan from
And now we are the great Satan.
If you don't know Satan from Satan,
you're
you're in
you're in a
you're in a difficult
you're in a difficult position,
you're in a difficult position, right?
To
To not
you're in a difficult position, right?
To not be
To not be able
you're in a difficult position, right?
To not be able to
To not be able to tell
holiness
holiness from
holiness from evil
holiness from evil is
holiness from evil is grave.
holiness from evil is grave. That
holiness from evil is grave. That is
holiness from evil is grave. That is so
grave.
grave. You
holiness from evil is grave. That is so
grave. You understand
grave. You understand the
holiness from evil is grave. That is so
grave. You understand the graveness
grave. You understand the graveness of
the
the inability
the inability to
the inability to tell
the inability to tell goodness
the inability to tell goodness from
the inability to tell goodness from evil
if
if you
the inability to tell goodness from evil
if you don't
if you don't know
the inability to tell goodness from evil
if you don't know Jesus
if you don't know Jesus from
the inability to tell goodness from evil
if you don't know Jesus from Satan.
And
And that
And that has
And that has already
And that has already happened.
And that has already happened. You
And that has already happened. You see,
so
that
that is
that is the
that is the the
that is the the way
that is the the way it
that is the the way it sneaks
that is the the way it sneaks in.
that is the the way it sneaks in. That's
the
the way
that is the the way it sneaks in. That's
the way the
the way the Trojan
that is the the way it sneaks in. That's
the way the Trojan horse
the way the Trojan horse sneaks
that is the the way it sneaks in. That's
the way the Trojan horse sneaks Trojan
horse
horse is
horse is brought
horse is brought in.
And
And then
horse is brought in.
And then the
And then the door
horse is brought in.
And then the door opens
And then the door opens and
horse is brought in.
And then the door opens and the
And then the door opens and the satanic
springs
springs forth
springs forth and
springs forth and cuts
springs forth and cuts your
springs forth and cuts your throat.
And
And you
springs forth and cuts your throat.
And you think
And you think the
springs forth and cuts your throat.
And you think the problem
And you think the problem is
springs forth and cuts your throat.
And you think the problem is the
And you think the problem is the satanic
force
force that
force that cuts
force that cuts your
force that cuts your throat.
force that cuts your throat. No,
force that cuts your throat. No, that's
just
just a
force that cuts your throat. No, that's
just a natural
just a natural consequence.
force that cuts your throat. No, that's
just a natural consequence. You
just a natural consequence. You invited
it
it in
it in the
it in the door
it in the door when
it in the door when it
it in the door when it was
it in the door when it was in
it in the door when it was in disguise.
So
So the
it in the door when it was in disguise.
So the reason
So the reason we
it in the door when it was in disguise.
So the reason we got
So the reason we got attacked
it in the door when it was in disguise.
So the reason we got attacked by
So the reason we got attacked by all
it in the door when it was in disguise.
So the reason we got attacked by all the
forces
forces that
forces that are
forces that are opposed
forces that are opposed to
forces that are opposed to truth
forces that are opposed to truth is
because
because we
forces that are opposed to truth is
because we closed
because we closed the
forces that are opposed to truth is
because we closed the gap
because we closed the gap by
forces that are opposed to truth is
because we closed the gap by which
falsity
falsity can
falsity can sneak
falsity can sneak through
falsity can sneak through the
falsity can sneak through the cracks
falsity can sneak through the cracks and
be
be disguised.
And
And we
And we were
And we were hit
And we were hit hard
And we were hit hard that
And we were hit hard that day.
So
>> you
>> you didn't
>> you didn't ask
>> you didn't ask for
>> you didn't ask for a
>> you didn't ask for a speech,
>> you didn't ask for a speech, did
>> you didn't ask for a speech, did you?
Is
Is it
>> you didn't ask for a speech, did you?
Is it possible
Is it possible to
>> you didn't ask for a speech, did you?
Is it possible to achieve
Is it possible to achieve enlightenment
while
while in
while in an
while in an intimate
while in an intimate relationship?
Doesn't
Doesn't family
while in an intimate relationship?
Doesn't family and
Doesn't family and intimacy
while in an intimate relationship?
Doesn't family and intimacy make
spiritual
spiritual pursuits
spiritual pursuits more
spiritual pursuits more challenging?
That's
That's a
spiritual pursuits more challenging?
That's a presumption
That's a presumption and
spiritual pursuits more challenging?
That's a presumption and of
That's a presumption and of course
spiritual pursuits more challenging?
That's a presumption and of course it's
part
part of
part of many
part of many uh
part of many uh traditional
part of many uh traditional religious
disciplines.
That's
That's impossible
That's impossible to
That's impossible to be
That's impossible to be enlightened
That's impossible to be enlightened and
also
also be
That's impossible to be enlightened and
also be in
also be in love
That's impossible to be enlightened and
also be in love or
also be in love or be
That's impossible to be enlightened and
also be in love or be enlightened
also be in love or be enlightened and
have
have a
have a wife
have a wife etc.
I
I think
have a wife etc.
I think we
I think we discussed
have a wife etc.
I think we discussed that
I think we discussed that somewhat
previously.
A
A renunciate,
previously.
A renunciate, a
A renunciate, a true
previously.
A renunciate, a true renunciate
is
is one
is one who
is one who renounces
is one who renounces falsehood,
renounces
renounces that
is one who renounces falsehood,
renounces that which
renounces that which is
is one who renounces falsehood,
renounces that which is devoid
renounces that which is devoid of
is one who renounces falsehood,
renounces that which is devoid of love.
To
To be
To be able
To be able to
To be able to do
To be able to do that
To be able to do that is
To be able to do that is therefore
committed
to
to learning
to learning discernment,
to learning discernment, to
to learning discernment, to be
to learning discernment, to be able
to learning discernment, to be able to
tell
tell good
to learning discernment, to be able to
tell good from
tell good from evil
to learning discernment, to be able to
tell good from evil and
tell good from evil and right
to learning discernment, to be able to
tell good from evil and right from
wrong,
wrong, etc.
wrong, etc. Very
wrong, etc. Very simple
wrong, etc. Very simple things.
What
What they
wrong, etc. Very simple things.
What they mean
What they mean is
wrong, etc. Very simple things.
What they mean is an
What they mean is an attachment
that
that the
that the ordinary
that the ordinary person
becomes
becomes attached
that the ordinary person
becomes attached in
becomes attached in relationship
that the ordinary person
becomes attached in relationship and
gets
gets diverted
gets diverted from
gets diverted from their
gets diverted from their path
begins
begins to
gets diverted from their path
begins to sacrifice
begins to sacrifice spiritual
gets diverted from their path
begins to sacrifice spiritual principle
for
for personal
for personal gain
for personal gain for
for personal gain for personal
for personal gain for personal pleasure
etc.
The
The it's
The it's the
The it's the attachment.
The it's the attachment. So
The it's the attachment. So Ramach
Krishna
Krishna you
The it's the attachment. So Ramach
Krishna you know
Krishna you know forbid
The it's the attachment. So Ramach
Krishna you know forbid money
Krishna you know forbid money or
The it's the attachment. So Ramach
Krishna you know forbid money or sex
Krishna you know forbid money or sex and
he
he only
he only took
he only took young
he only took young devotees
he only took young devotees and
He
He felt
he only took young devotees and
He felt even
He felt even the
he only took young devotees and
He felt even the money
He felt even the money of
he only took young devotees and
He felt even the money of the
He felt even the money of the energy
he only took young devotees and
He felt even the money of the energy of
money
money or
money or sex
money or sex was
money or sex was too
money or sex was too much.
money or sex was too much. I
money or sex was too much. I disagreed
with
with him.
money or sex was too much. I disagreed
with him. I
with him. I said
money or sex was too much. I disagreed
with him. I said it's
with him. I said it's the
money or sex was too much. I disagreed
with him. I said it's the attachment
with him. I said it's the attachment to
them.
them. However,
them. However, when
them. However, when you're
them. However, when you're young,
them. However, when you're young, it
them. However, when you're young, it may
be
be too
them. However, when you're young, it may
be too powerful
be too powerful for
them. However, when you're young, it may
be too powerful for you
be too powerful for you to
them. However, when you're young, it may
be too powerful for you to be
be too powerful for you to be uh
them. However, when you're young, it may
be too powerful for you to be uh you
know,
know, so
know, so aeticism
know, so aeticism is
know, so aeticism is the
know, so aeticism is the only
know, so aeticism is the only way
know, so aeticism is the only way out.
So,
So, how
know, so aeticism is the only way out.
So, how would
family
family or
having
having a
family or
having a wife
having a wife or
family or
having a wife or a
having a wife or a husband
family or
having a wife or a husband deter
having a wife or a husband deter one?
perhaps
perhaps by
perhaps by distraction.
Now
Now the
perhaps by distraction.
Now the various
Now the various religious
perhaps by distraction.
Now the various religious religious
organizations
organizations have
organizations have their
organizations have their own
organizations have their own techniques,
practices,
practices, classes
organizations have their own techniques,
practices, classes etc.
practices, classes etc. ranks
organizations have their own techniques,
practices, classes etc. ranks all
practices, classes etc. ranks all the
rest.
The
The thing
rest.
The thing that
The thing that actually
rest.
The thing that actually works
The thing that actually works is
rest.
The thing that actually works is that
because
because of
because of one's
because of one's commitment,
because of one's commitment, there
because of one's commitment, there is
because of one's commitment, there is a
willingness
willingness to
because of one's commitment, there is a
willingness to surrender
willingness to surrender everything
because of one's commitment, there is a
willingness to surrender everything as
it
it arises
it arises to
it arises to God
it arises to God as
it arises to God as it
it arises to God as it arises.
it arises to God as it arises. Huh?
So
So that
it arises to God as it arises. Huh?
So that a
So that a contemplative
it arises to God as it arises. Huh?
So that a contemplative surrendering
that
that mudra
that mudra that
that mudra that mudra
you
you see
that mudra that mudra
you see that's
you see that's the
that mudra that mudra
you see that's the mudra
you see that's the mudra in
that mudra that mudra
you see that's the mudra in which
you see that's the mudra in which I
surrender
surrender all
surrender all to
surrender all to thee
surrender all to thee oh
surrender all to thee oh lord
surrender all to thee oh lord before
surrender all to thee oh lord before I
experienced
experienced something
surrender all to thee oh lord before I
experienced something physically
never
never before
the
the physical
never before
the physical energy
the physical energy that
never before
the physical energy that energizes
the physical energy that energizes the
body
body was
body was leaving
body was leaving I
body was leaving I thought
body was leaving I thought dying
body was leaving I thought dying I
body was leaving I thought dying I guess
physically
physically you
body was leaving I thought dying I guess
physically you know
physically you know physical
body was leaving I thought dying I guess
physically you know physical dying
so
I
I walked
so
I walked down
I walked down in
so
I walked down in the
I walked down in the path
so
I walked down in the path and
I walked down in the path and came
so
I walked down in the path and came back
again.
again. Either
again. Either the
again. Either the body
again. Either the body survives
again. Either the body survives or
again. Either the body survives or it
doesn't.
doesn't. You
again. Either the body survives or it
doesn't. You know what
doesn't. You know what I'm
again. Either the body survives or it
doesn't. You know what I'm saying?
So,
So, one
So, one continuously
So, one continuously surreners
So, one continuously surreners whether
the
the physicality
So, one continuously surreners whether
the physicality survives,
the physicality survives, whether
So, one continuously surreners whether
the physicality survives, whether it
doesn't
doesn't survive.
doesn't survive. Sort
doesn't survive. Sort of
doesn't survive. Sort of curious.
I
I thought
doesn't survive. Sort of curious.
I thought sort
I thought sort of
doesn't survive. Sort of curious.
I thought sort of curious.
I thought sort of curious. I
doesn't survive. Sort of curious.
I thought sort of curious. I can
I thought sort of curious. I can he'll
drop
drop over
drop over on
drop over on the
drop over on the rug
drop over on the rug and
drop over on the rug and I'll
drop over on the rug and I'll be
drop over on the rug and I'll be looking
at
at him
drop over on the rug and I'll be looking
at him in
at him in the
drop over on the rug and I'll be looking
at him in the rug
at him in the rug and
drop over on the rug and I'll be looking
at him in the rug and what
at him in the rug and what will
drop over on the rug and I'll be looking
at him in the rug and what will the
people
people in
people in the
people in the room
people in the room do
people in the room do and
people in the room do and all
people in the room do and all God
almighty
see
see the
see the bells
see the bells and
see the bells and red
see the bells and red lights.
see the bells and red lights. You
see the bells and red lights. You see
the
the ambulance
see the bells and red lights. You see
the ambulance and
the ambulance and think,
see the bells and red lights. You see
the ambulance and think, "Oh,
the ambulance and think, "Oh, good
see the bells and red lights. You see
the ambulance and think, "Oh, good God.
Well,
Well, you
Well, you can't
Well, you can't die
Well, you can't die under
Well, you can't die under those
circumstances,
circumstances, could
Well, you can't die under those
circumstances, could you?
>> No.
>> Anyway,
>> no.
>> no. So,
>> no. So, it's
>> no. So, it's a
>> no. So, it's a matter
>> no. So, it's a matter of
>> no. So, it's a matter of no
>> no. So, it's a matter of no matter
>> no. So, it's a matter of no matter what
to
to walk
>> no. So, it's a matter of no matter what
to walk straight
to walk straight ahead.
>> no. So, it's a matter of no matter what
to walk straight ahead. And
to walk straight ahead. And so,
>> no. So, it's a matter of no matter what
to walk straight ahead. And so, that
willingness
willingness to
willingness to surrender
willingness to surrender all
positionalities
positionalities and
willingness to surrender all
positionalities and anything
positionalities and anything that
willingness to surrender all
positionalities and anything that is
positionalities and anything that is not
love.
Um
Um to
love.
Um to let
Um to let go,
love.
Um to let go, to
Um to let go, to see
love.
Um to let go, to see that
Um to let go, to see that everything
love.
Um to let go, to see that everything is
a
a transitory
a transitory perception.
The
The willingness
a transitory perception.
The willingness to
The willingness to surrender
a transitory perception.
The willingness to surrender attachment
to
to it.
to it. So
to it. So then
to it. So then attachments
uh
uh could
to it. So then attachments
uh could become
uh could become uh
to it. So then attachments
uh could become uh part
uh could become uh part of
to it. So then attachments
uh could become uh part of the
uh could become uh part of the problem
could
could become
could become part
could become part of
could become part of the
could become part of the problem.
So
So one
could become part of the problem.
So one would
So one would have
could become part of the problem.
So one would have to
So one would have to surrender
could become part of the problem.
So one would have to surrender one's
attachment
attachment to
attachment to that
person
person on
attachment to that
person on a
person on a personal
attachment to that
person on a personal level.
person on a personal level. No.
attachment to that
person on a personal level. No. So
person on a personal level. No. So for
many
many people
many people you
many people you know
many people you know there
many people you know there are
many people you know there are periods
of
of of
many people you know there are periods
of of leaving
of of leaving the
many people you know there are periods
of of leaving the world
of of leaving the world and
many people you know there are periods
of of leaving the world and many
of of leaving the world and many people
may
may leave
may leave for
may leave for years
may leave for years join
may leave for years join an
may leave for years join an ashim
join
join a
may leave for years join an ashim
join a sa
join a sa join
may leave for years join an ashim
join a sa join a
join a sa join a spiritual
may leave for years join an ashim
join a sa join a spiritual group
um
until
until it
um
until it served
until it served its
um
until it served its purpose
until it served its purpose and
um
until it served its purpose and after
that
that it
that it may
that it may it
that it may it may
that it may it may be
that it may it may be necessary
that it may it may be necessary to
that it may it may be necessary to learn
things
things that
that it may it may be necessary to learn
things that only
things that only can
that it may it may be necessary to learn
things that only can be
things that only can be learned
that it may it may be necessary to learn
things that only can be learned in
relationship
because
because certain
relationship
because certain things
because certain things and
relationship
because certain things and attachments
can
can only
can only be
can only be surrendered
can only be surrendered in
can only be surrendered in relationship.
You
You can't
can only be surrendered in relationship.
You can't really
You can't really do
can only be surrendered in relationship.
You can't really do it
You can't really do it when
can only be surrendered in relationship.
You can't really do it when you're
You can't really do it when you're out
in
in the
in the woods
in the woods by
in the woods by yourself.
in the woods by yourself. Having
in the woods by yourself. Having done
in the woods by yourself. Having done it
both
both ways.
They
They both
They both have
They both have their
They both have their upside
They both have their upside and
They both have their upside and their
downside.
The
The joy
The joy of
The joy of being
The joy of being totally
The joy of being totally all
The joy of being totally all alone,
having
having no
The joy of being totally all alone,
having no attachments,
having no attachments, no
The joy of being totally all alone,
having no attachments, no possessions,
walking
walking away
walking away from
walking away from it
walking away from it all,
walking away from it all, and
walking away from it all, and delivering
manure
manure for
walking away from it all, and delivering
manure for a
manure for a living
walking away from it all, and delivering
manure for a living is
manure for a living is joyful.
The
The fun
The fun of
The fun of having
The fun of having six
The fun of having six cars
The fun of having six cars and
The fun of having six cars and a
The fun of having six cars and a huge
estate
estate and
The fun of having six cars and a huge
estate and servants
estate and servants is
The fun of having six cars and a huge
estate and servants is joyful.
estate and servants is joyful. It's
The fun of having six cars and a huge
estate and servants is joyful. It's all
the
the same.
So
So to
the same.
So to discover
So to discover that
the same.
So to discover that is
So to discover that is all
the same.
So to discover that is all the
So to discover that is all the same.
the same.
So to discover that is all the same. So
people
people who
people who are
people who are on
people who are on a
people who are on a spiritual
people who are on a spiritual pathway
often
often their
people who are on a spiritual pathway
often their lives
often their lives are
people who are on a spiritual pathway
often their lives are quite
often their lives are quite chaotic.
They
They think
They think oh
They think oh I'm
They think oh I'm going
They think oh I'm going to
They think oh I'm going to become
They think oh I'm going to become a
spiritual
spiritual and
They think oh I'm going to become a
spiritual and they
spiritual and they they
They think oh I'm going to become a
spiritual and they they picture
spiritual and they they picture oh
They think oh I'm going to become a
spiritual and they they picture oh our
life
life is
life is going
life is going to
life is going to be
life is going to be wonderful.
life is going to be wonderful. We'll
pray
pray for
life is going to be wonderful. We'll
pray for peace
pray for peace and
life is going to be wonderful. We'll
pray for peace and sing
pray for peace and sing hymns
life is going to be wonderful. We'll
pray for peace and sing hymns and
pray for peace and sing hymns and life
is
is going
is going to
is going to be
is going to be joyful
is going to be joyful because
is going to be joyful because I've
committed
committed to
is going to be joyful because I've
committed to God
committed to God and
is going to be joyful because I've
committed to God and love.
committed to God and love. Huh.
is going to be joyful because I've
committed to God and love. Huh. Wow.
Yeah,
Yeah, that's
Yeah, that's a
Yeah, that's a good
Yeah, that's a good way
Yeah, that's a good way to
Yeah, that's a good way to bring
Yeah, that's a good way to bring up
everything
everything that
Yeah, that's a good way to bring up
everything that is
everything that is non-love
Yeah, that's a good way to bring up
everything that is non-love from
everything that is non-love from all
your
your past
your past lifetimes.
All
All the
your past lifetimes.
All the women
All the women you
left
left and
left and cheated
left and cheated on
left and cheated on come
left and cheated on come back
left and cheated on come back in
left and cheated on come back in their
energy
energy bodies
left and cheated on come back in their
energy bodies and
energy bodies and uh
left and cheated on come back in their
energy bodies and uh you
energy bodies and uh you know
left and cheated on come back in their
energy bodies and uh you know you
energy bodies and uh you know you now
you
you get
you get the
you get the karmic
you get the karmic attack
you get the karmic attack for
you get the karmic attack for all
you get the karmic attack for all the
crap
all
all the
all the guys
all the guys you
all the guys you kill
all the guys you kill show
all the guys you kill show up
all the guys you kill show up in
all the guys you kill show up in your
lifetime
lifetime again.
all the guys you kill show up in your
lifetime again. I
lifetime again. I don't
all the guys you kill show up in your
lifetime again. I don't know.
lifetime again. I don't know. Even
all the guys you kill show up in your
lifetime again. I don't know. Even you
showed
showed up
showed up and
showed up and brought
showed up and brought up
brought
brought up
showed up and brought up
brought up guilt
brought up guilt from
showed up and brought up
brought up guilt from leaving
brought up guilt from leaving the
showed up and brought up
brought up guilt from leaving the song
on.
Yeah,
Yeah, we
on.
Yeah, we just
Yeah, we just did,
on.
Yeah, we just did, you
Yeah, we just did, you know,
on.
Yeah, we just did, you know, some
Yeah, we just did, you know, some past
life
life research.
life research. It
life research. It was
life research. It was around
life research. It was around 650
life research. It was around 650 years
ago
ago and
life research. It was around 650 years
ago and I
ago and I left
life research. It was around 650 years
ago and I left the
ago and I left the the
life research. It was around 650 years
ago and I left the the Buddha
brotherhood
brotherhood in
brotherhood in the
brotherhood in the ashram
and
and suffered
brotherhood in the ashram
and suffered for
and suffered for guilt
brotherhood in the ashram
and suffered for guilt for
and suffered for guilt for it
brotherhood in the ashram
and suffered for guilt for it for
and suffered for guilt for it for till
now
now and
now and he
now and he brought
now and he brought it
now and he brought it up
now and he brought it up again.
now and he brought it up again. Okay.
>> So,
>> So, I
now and he brought it up again. Okay.
>> So, I had
>> So, I had to
now and he brought it up again. Okay.
>> So, I had to forgive
>> So, I had to forgive myself
now and he brought it up again. Okay.
>> So, I had to forgive myself and
>> So, I had to forgive myself and Yeah.
>> And
>> And uh
>> And uh I
>> And uh I forgive
>> And uh I forgive you,
>> And uh I forgive you, too.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, thank
>> And uh I forgive you, too.
>> Oh, thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Give
>> Give some
>> Yeah.
>> Give some examples
>> Give some examples of
>> Yeah.
>> Give some examples of when
>> Give some examples of when and
>> Yeah.
>> Give some examples of when and how
>> Give some examples of when and how to
use
use humility.
>> Now,
>> Now, I'm
use humility.
>> Now, I'm the
>> Now, I'm the world's
use humility.
>> Now, I'm the world's authority
>> Now, I'm the world's authority on
humility.
I'm
I'm proud
humility.
I'm proud of
I'm proud of my
humility.
I'm proud of my humility.
And
And I'll
And I'll kill
And I'll kill anybody
And I'll kill anybody that
And I'll kill anybody that says
And I'll kill anybody that says he's
And I'll kill anybody that says he's got
more
more humility
And I'll kill anybody that says he's got
more humility than
more humility than me.
Other
Other than
Other than that,
Other than that, I
Other than that, I don't
Other than that, I don't Anything
Other than that, I don't Anything else
you
you want
Other than that, I don't Anything else
you want to
you want to know
Other than that, I don't Anything else
you want to know about
you want to know about it?
You
You know,
You know, the
You know, the answer
You know, the answer to
You know, the answer to to
You know, the answer to to that
You know, the answer to to that is
You know, the answer to to that is is
devotion.
devotion. You
You know, the answer to to that is is
devotion. You see,
devotion. You see, because
You know, the answer to to that is is
devotion. You see, because true
humility,
uh,
uh, what
humility,
uh, what you
uh, what you usually
humility,
uh, what you usually see
uh, what you usually see is
humility,
uh, what you usually see is pseudo
humility.
If
If a
humility.
If a person
If a person didn't
humility.
If a person didn't have
If a person didn't have spiritual
vanity,
vanity, they
vanity, they wouldn't
vanity, they wouldn't have
vanity, they wouldn't have to
vanity, they wouldn't have to assume
the
the posture
vanity, they wouldn't have to assume
the posture of
the posture of pseudo
vanity, they wouldn't have to assume
the posture of pseudo humility.
That
That which
That which is
That which is truly
That which is truly of
That which is truly of God
That which is truly of God has
That which is truly of God has no
problem
problem recognizing
That which is truly of God has no
problem recognizing the
problem recognizing the magnificence
That which is truly of God has no
problem recognizing the magnificence of
the
the gift.
To
To pretend
the gift.
To pretend that
To pretend that is
the gift.
To pretend that is nothing
To pretend that is nothing is
the gift.
To pretend that is nothing is pseudo
humility.
The
The Buddha
humility.
The Buddha procla
The Buddha procla proclaimed
humility.
The Buddha procla proclaimed the
magnificence
magnificence of
magnificence of his
magnificence of his teaching.
The
The presence
magnificence of his teaching.
The presence of
The presence of God
magnificence of his teaching.
The presence of God within
The presence of God within is
acknowledged
acknowledged by
acknowledged by anyone
acknowledged by anyone who
acknowledged by anyone who has
experienced
experienced it.
acknowledged by anyone who has
experienced it. It's
experienced it. It's a
acknowledged by anyone who has
experienced it. It's a great
experienced it. It's a great gift.
What
What was
What was the
What was the question?
Because
Because it's
What was the question?
Because it's a
Because it's a gift
What was the question?
Because it's a gift um
Because it's a gift um one
What was the question?
Because it's a gift um one escapes
Because it's a gift um one escapes any
um
um temptation
um temptation to
um temptation to pridefulness.
What
What was
um temptation to pridefulness.
What was the
What was the question
um temptation to pridefulness.
What was the question about
What was the question about humility
though?
>> Give
>> Give some
though?
>> Give some examples
>> Give some examples of
though?
>> Give some examples of when
>> Give some examples of when and
though?
>> Give some examples of when and how
>> Give some examples of when and how to
use
use humility.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, it
use humility.
>> Oh, it isn't
>> Oh, it isn't a
use humility.
>> Oh, it isn't a thing
>> Oh, it isn't a thing you
use humility.
>> Oh, it isn't a thing you No,
>> Oh, it isn't a thing you No, there's
use humility.
>> Oh, it isn't a thing you No, there's not
that.
that. It's
that. It's a
that. It's a mudra.
that. It's a mudra. It's
that. It's a mudra. It's a
that. It's a mudra. It's a it's
that. It's a mudra. It's a it's a
that. It's a mudra. It's a it's a style
of
of being
that. It's a mudra. It's a it's a style
of being in
of being in the
that. It's a mudra. It's a it's a style
of being in the world.
I
I give
I give thanks
I give thanks to
I give thanks to thee,
I give thanks to thee, oh
I give thanks to thee, oh Lord,
I give thanks to thee, oh Lord, for
I give thanks to thee, oh Lord, for my
existence.
Beyond
Beyond that,
Beyond that, oh
Beyond that, oh Lord,
Beyond that, oh Lord, do
Beyond that, oh Lord, do I
Beyond that, oh Lord, do I give
Beyond that, oh Lord, do I give thanks
for
for my
Beyond that, oh Lord, do I give thanks
for my awareness
for my awareness of
Beyond that, oh Lord, do I give thanks
for my awareness of my
for my awareness of my existence.
I
I give
I give thanks
I give thanks to
I give thanks to thee,
I give thanks to thee, oh
I give thanks to thee, oh Lord,
I give thanks to thee, oh Lord, for
I give thanks to thee, oh Lord, for thy
presence.
It's
It's a
It's a gratitude
It's a gratitude for
It's a gratitude for one's
It's a gratitude for one's existence.
More
More than
It's a gratitude for one's existence.
More than that,
More than that, it's
It's a gratitude for one's existence.
More than that, it's the
More than that, it's the gratitude
It's a gratitude for one's existence.
More than that, it's the gratitude for
the
the awareness
the awareness of
the awareness of one's
the awareness of one's existence.
the awareness of one's existence. It's
gratitude
gratitude for
the awareness of one's existence. It's
gratitude for the
gratitude for the love
the awareness of one's existence. It's
gratitude for the love of
gratitude for the love of one's
existence.
existence. See,
existence. See, the
existence. See, the grace
existence. See, the grace of
existence. See, the grace of God,
existence. See, the grace of God, the
grace
grace of
existence. See, the grace of God, the
grace of the
grace of the an
existence. See, the grace of God, the
grace of the an animal,
grace of the an animal, it
existence. See, the grace of God, the
grace of the an animal, it reflects
grace of the an animal, it reflects the
grace
grace of
grace of God.
grace of God. Anybody
grace of God. Anybody who
grace of God. Anybody who doesn't
grace of God. Anybody who doesn't see
God
God in
in
in an
in an animal
um
um can't
in an animal
um can't recognize
um can't recognize God
in an animal
um can't recognize God because
um can't recognize God because the
in an animal
um can't recognize God because the grace
of
of the
of the animal
is
is its
of the animal
is its joy
is its joy in
of the animal
is its joy in its
is its joy in its own
of the animal
is its joy in its own existence.
The
The animal
The animal takes
constant
constant joy
The animal takes
constant joy in
constant joy in its
The animal takes
constant joy in its own
constant joy in its own existence.
As
As you
As you look
As you look into
As you look into the
As you look into the eyes
As you look into the eyes of
As you look into the eyes of the
As you look into the eyes of the deer,
it
it is
As you look into the eyes of the deer,
it is conscious
it is conscious of
As you look into the eyes of the deer,
it is conscious of its
it is conscious of its own
As you look into the eyes of the deer,
it is conscious of its own existence.
And
And that's
And that's why
And that's why you
And that's why you can't
And that's why you can't shoot
And that's why you can't shoot it
because
because when
And that's why you can't shoot it
because when you
because when you see
And that's why you can't shoot it
because when you see that
because when you see that you
And that's why you can't shoot it
because when you see that you have
because when you see that you have buck
fever
fever and
fever and you
fever and you cannot
fever and you cannot pull
fever and you cannot pull the
fever and you cannot pull the trigger.
You
You just
fever and you cannot pull the trigger.
You just saw
You just saw the
fever and you cannot pull the trigger.
You just saw the truth.
It
It loves
It loves its
It loves its existence
It loves its existence just
It loves its existence just as
It loves its existence just as you
It loves its existence just as you love
your
your existence.
It loves its existence just as you love
your existence. So
your existence. So you're
It loves its existence just as you love
your existence. So you're not
your existence. So you're not robbing
It loves its existence just as you love
your existence. So you're not robbing it
of
of life.
of life. You're
of life. You're love
of life. You're love robbing
of life. You're love robbing it
of life. You're love robbing it robbing
it
it of
of life. You're love robbing it robbing
it of the
it of the opportunity
of life. You're love robbing it robbing
it of the opportunity for
it of the opportunity for the
of life. You're love robbing it robbing
it of the opportunity for the love
it of the opportunity for the love of
its
its own
its own existence.
I
I remember
its own existence.
I remember a
I remember a patient
its own existence.
I remember a patient of
I remember a patient of mine
its own existence.
I remember a patient of mine who
couldn't
couldn't get
couldn't get silver.
He
He was
couldn't get silver.
He was going
He was going to
couldn't get silver.
He was going to he
He was going to he was
couldn't get silver.
He was going to he was trying
everything.
everything. Then
everything. Then he
everything. Then he went
everything. Then he went hunting,
everything. Then he went hunting, went
deer
deer hunting
everything. Then he went hunting, went
deer hunting with
deer hunting with his
everything. Then he went hunting, went
deer hunting with his old
deer hunting with his old pals.
everything. Then he went hunting, went
deer hunting with his old pals. Of
course,
course, they
course, they were
course, they were all
course, they were all drinking
course, they were all drinking and
whoring
whoring and
course, they were all drinking and
whoring and doing
whoring and doing all
course, they were all drinking and
whoring and doing all the
whoring and doing all the things
course, they were all drinking and
whoring and doing all the things that
people
people do
people do on
people do on hunting
people do on hunting trips.
people do on hunting trips. And
people do on hunting trips. And he's
people do on hunting trips. And he's out
in
in the
people do on hunting trips. And he's out
in the woods
in the woods and
people do on hunting trips. And he's out
in the woods and as
in the woods and as he
people do on hunting trips. And he's out
in the woods and as he looked
in the woods and as he looked down
people do on hunting trips. And he's out
in the woods and as he looked down the
sights,
sights, he
sights, he had
sights, he had a
sights, he had a deer.
sights, he had a deer. And
sights, he had a deer. And as
sights, he had a deer. And as he
sights, he had a deer. And as he looked
down
down the
sights, he had a deer. And as he looked
down the sights
down the sights of
sights, he had a deer. And as he looked
down the sights of the
down the sights of the deer,
the
the magnificence
the magnificence of
the magnificence of what
the magnificence of what I'm
the magnificence of what I'm just
the magnificence of what I'm just saying
came
came to
the magnificence of what I'm just saying
came to him
came to him and
the magnificence of what I'm just saying
came to him and he
came to him and he became
the magnificence of what I'm just saying
came to him and he became sober
came to him and he became sober in
the magnificence of what I'm just saying
came to him and he became sober in that
instant.
instant. In in
instant. In in that
instant. In in that instant
transformation,
he
he saw
he saw the
he saw the love
he saw the love of
he saw the love of one's
he saw the love of one's own
he saw the love of one's own existence
in
in the
he saw the love of one's own existence
in the eyes
in the eyes of
he saw the love of one's own existence
in the eyes of the
in the eyes of the deer.
he saw the love of one's own existence
in the eyes of the deer. At
in the eyes of the deer. At which
he saw the love of one's own existence
in the eyes of the deer. At which point,
of
of course,
of course, he
of course, he could
of course, he could not
of course, he could not pull
of course, he could not pull the
of course, he could not pull the trigger
because
because he
of course, he could not pull the trigger
because he was
because he was killing
of course, he could not pull the trigger
because he was killing God.
because he was killing God. And
of course, he could not pull the trigger
because he was killing God. And you
might
might say
the
the divinity
might say
the divinity of
the divinity of existence
might say
the divinity of existence shining
the divinity of existence shining forth
through
through the
through the love
through the love of
through the love of the
through the love of the deer.
>> Can
>> Can you
through the love of the deer.
>> Can you use
>> Can you use kinesiology
through the love of the deer.
>> Can you use kinesiology to
>> Can you use kinesiology to test
through the love of the deer.
>> Can you use kinesiology to test the
nature
nature of
nature of past
nature of past life
nature of past life agreements
nature of past life agreements and
relationships
relationships with
nature of past life agreements and
relationships with people
relationships with people we
nature of past life agreements and
relationships with people we know?
>> Probably.
I
I don't
>> Probably.
I don't know
I don't know why
>> Probably.
I don't know why you'd
I don't know why you'd want
>> Probably.
I don't know why you'd want to
I don't know why you'd want to know
that,
that, but
that, but uh
that, but uh yes.
that, but uh yes. No,
that, but uh yes. No, we
that, but uh yes. No, we did
that, but uh yes. No, we did it
that, but uh yes. No, we did it this
morning.
morning. Um,
we
we did
we did it
we did it this
we did it this morning.
we did it this morning. Um,
we did it this morning. Um, there
we did it this morning. Um, there it's
not
not usually
we did it this morning. Um, there it's
not usually not
not usually not necessary.
we did it this morning. Um, there it's
not usually not necessary. It
not usually not necessary. It may
clarify
clarify that
clarify that the
clarify that the value
clarify that the value of
clarify that the value of past
clarify that the value of past life
regressions.
First
First of
First of all,
First of all, they're
First of all, they're quite
First of all, they're quite interesting.
You
You can
First of all, they're quite interesting.
You can learn
You can learn a
First of all, they're quite interesting.
You can learn a lot.
You can learn a lot. Many
First of all, they're quite interesting.
You can learn a lot. Many things
You can learn a lot. Many things that
would
would cause
would cause pain
would cause pain and
would cause pain and suffering
would cause pain and suffering this
lifetime
are
are handled
are handled very
are handled very easily
are handled very easily once
are handled very easily once you
remember
remember the
are handled very easily once you
remember the incident.
remember the incident. I
are handled very easily once you
remember the incident. I mean,
remember the incident. I mean, if
are handled very easily once you
remember the incident. I mean, if that
happened
happened that
happened that way
happened that way and
happened that way and when
happened that way and when you
reexperience
reexperience it,
happened that way and when you
reexperience it, you
reexperience it, you know
happened that way and when you
reexperience it, you know it
reexperience it, you know it happened
that
that way
that way because
that way because you
that way because you just
that way because you just reexperienced
it.
it. Now
that way because you just reexperienced
it. Now you
it. Now you can
that way because you just reexperienced
it. Now you can understand
it. Now you can understand why
that way because you just reexperienced
it. Now you can understand why things
are
are the
are the way
are the way they
are the way they are
are the way they are in
are the way they are in the
are the way they are in the present.
are the way they are in the present. So
you
you can
are the way they are in the present. So
you can let
you can let go
are the way they are in the present. So
you can let go of
you can let go of a
are the way they are in the present. So
you can let go of a lot
you can let go of a lot of
are the way they are in the present. So
you can let go of a lot of guilt
you can let go of a lot of guilt and
self-lame
self-lame and
self-lame and self-hatred
self-lame and self-hatred and
self-lame and self-hatred and things
when
when you
self-lame and self-hatred and things
when you see
when you see considering
self-lame and self-hatred and things
when you see considering what
when you see considering what happened
then
then this
then this pattern
then this pattern would
then this pattern would certainly
then this pattern would certainly make
sense
sense in
then this pattern would certainly make
sense in this
sense in this lifetime
then this pattern would certainly make
sense in this lifetime and
sense in this lifetime and it's
therefore
therefore a
therefore a lot
therefore a lot easier
therefore a lot easier to
therefore a lot easier to heal.
therefore a lot easier to heal. Huh?
The
The other
therefore a lot easier to heal. Huh?
The other interesting
The other interesting thing
therefore a lot easier to heal. Huh?
The other interesting thing about
The other interesting thing about past
life
life regressions
life regressions is
it's
it's always
life regressions is
it's always the
it's always the same
life regressions is
it's always the same s
it's always the same s self
life regressions is
it's always the same s self that
it's always the same s self that that
life regressions is
it's always the same s self that that is
in
in each
in each experience,
you
you know.
in each experience,
you know. So
I've
I've recounted
I've recounted a
I've recounted a few
I've recounted a few lifetimes,
I've recounted a few lifetimes, but
I've recounted a few lifetimes, but I
I've recounted a few lifetimes, but I I
can
can remember
I've recounted a few lifetimes, but I I
can remember one
can remember one in
I've recounted a few lifetimes, but I I
can remember one in which
can remember one in which that
I've recounted a few lifetimes, but I I
can remember one in which that was
can remember one in which that was quite
stunning.
stunning. And
stunning. And I
stunning. And I went
stunning. And I went back
stunning. And I went back into
stunning. And I went back into that
period
period of
stunning. And I went back into that
period of time
period of time and
stunning. And I went back into that
period of time and walked
period of time and walked out
stunning. And I went back into that
period of time and walked out into
um
um I
um I looked
um I looked down
um I looked down at
um I looked down at the
um I looked down at the body
um I looked down at the body and
um I looked down at the body and uh
um I looked down at the body and uh it
was
was I
um I looked down at the body and uh it
was I was
was I was a
um I looked down at the body and uh it
was I was a real
was I was a real misamorph.
um I looked down at the body and uh it
was I was a real misamorph. I
was I was a real misamorph. I mean
um I looked down at the body and uh it
was I was a real misamorph. I mean I
was I was a real misamorph. I mean I had
tremendous
tremendous biceps
tremendous biceps man
tremendous biceps man and
tremendous biceps man and I
tremendous biceps man and I was
tremendous biceps man and I was a
blacksmith
blacksmith had
tremendous biceps man and I was a
blacksmith had a
blacksmith had a leather
tremendous biceps man and I was a
blacksmith had a leather apron
blacksmith had a leather apron on
tremendous biceps man and I was a
blacksmith had a leather apron on and
blacksmith had a leather apron on and I
mean
mean biceps
mean biceps like
mean biceps like like
mean biceps like like you
mean biceps like like you know
misamorphs
misamorphs have
mean biceps like like you know
misamorphs have I
misamorphs have I mean
mean biceps like like you know
misamorphs have I mean you
misamorphs have I mean you know
mean biceps like like you know
misamorphs have I mean you know like
linebackers
linebackers and
linebackers and stuff.
linebackers and stuff. I
linebackers and stuff. I said
linebackers and stuff. I said this
linebackers and stuff. I said this is
fantastic
fantastic man
linebackers and stuff. I said this is
fantastic man to
fantastic man to have
linebackers and stuff. I said this is
fantastic man to have a
fantastic man to have a body
linebackers and stuff. I said this is
fantastic man to have a body like
fantastic man to have a body like this
you
you know
you know man
you know man power.
you know man power. I
you know man power. I mean,
you know man power. I mean, you
you know man power. I mean, you don't
realize
realize the
you know man power. I mean, you don't
realize the power
realize the power of
you know man power. I mean, you don't
realize the power of a
realize the power of a fullback
you know man power. I mean, you don't
realize the power of a fullback or
whatever
whatever those
whatever those guys
whatever those guys are
whatever those guys are called
whatever those guys are called nowadays.
300 lb
300 lb of
whatever those guys are called nowadays.
300 lb of solid
300 lb of solid power.
whatever those guys are called nowadays.
300 lb of solid power. I
300 lb of solid power. I mean,
whatever those guys are called nowadays.
300 lb of solid power. I mean, geez,
staggering.
So,
no
no matter
no matter what
no matter what lifetime
no matter what lifetime you
no matter what lifetime you go
no matter what lifetime you go back
into,
into, it's
no matter what lifetime you go back
into, it's the
into, it's the same
no matter what lifetime you go back
into, it's the same you
into, it's the same you experiencing
that.
that. And
that. And when
that. And when you
that. And when you go
that. And when you go out
that. And when you go out of
that. And when you go out of body,
that. And when you go out of body, it's
the
the same
that. And when you go out of body, it's
the same you.
the same you. It's
that. And when you go out of body, it's
the same you. It's always
the same you. It's always the
that. And when you go out of body, it's
the same you. It's always the same
the same you. It's always the same self.
So
So it
So it can't
So it can't you
So it can't you can't
So it can't you can't be
So it can't you can't be possibly
different
different selves
So it can't you can't be possibly
different selves because
different selves because there's
So it can't you can't be possibly
different selves because there's only
one
one self
one self experiencing
one self experiencing yourself
one self experiencing yourself as
one self experiencing yourself as a
blacksmith
blacksmith one
one self experiencing yourself as a
blacksmith one self
blacksmith one self experiencing
yourself
yourself as
yourself as a
yourself as a warrior
yourself as a warrior one
same
same self-committing
yourself as a warrior one
same self-committing Harry
same self-committing Harry Kerry
yourself as a warrior one
same self-committing Harry Kerry that
was
was the
was the worst
was the worst of
was the worst of all
was the worst of all of
was the worst of all of them
went
went out
was the worst of all of them
went out of
went out of body
was the worst of all of them
went out of body and
went out of body and ecstasy
was the worst of all of them
went out of body and ecstasy on
went out of body and ecstasy on that
was the worst of all of them
went out of body and ecstasy on that one
ecstasy
ecstasy I
ecstasy I had
ecstasy I had surmounted
ecstasy I had surmounted all
ecstasy I had surmounted all fear
ecstasy I had surmounted all fear of
physicality
physicality so
ecstasy I had surmounted all fear of
physicality so you
physicality so you go
ecstasy I had surmounted all fear of
physicality so you go out
physicality so you go out in
ecstasy I had surmounted all fear of
physicality so you go out in a
physicality so you go out in a state
ecstasy I had surmounted all fear of
physicality so you go out in a state of
ecstasy
ecstasy But
ecstasy But the
ecstasy But the physicality
ecstasy But the physicality of
ecstasy But the physicality of it
ecstasy But the physicality of it was
horrific.
So
So it's
So it's very
So it's very interesting
So it's very interesting to
So it's very interesting to do
So it's very interesting to do past
So it's very interesting to do past life
regressions
regressions and
So it's very interesting to do past life
regressions and uh
regressions and uh it's
So it's very interesting to do past life
regressions and uh it's a
regressions and uh it's a very
So it's very interesting to do past life
regressions and uh it's a very easy
technique.
technique. Uh
technique. Uh you
technique. Uh you can
technique. Uh you can learn
technique. Uh you can learn it.
technique. Uh you can learn it. Uh
technique. Uh you can learn it. Uh the
hypnotist
hypnotist can
technique. Uh you can learn it. Uh the
hypnotist can teach
hypnotist can teach yourself
technique. Uh you can learn it. Uh the
hypnotist can teach yourself hypnosis.
Uh
Uh you
Uh you walk
Uh you walk down
Uh you walk down the
Uh you walk down the stairs
Uh you walk down the stairs and
Uh you walk down the stairs and and
Uh you walk down the stairs and and and
ask
ask the
Uh you walk down the stairs and and and
ask the question
ask the question and
Uh you walk down the stairs and and and
ask the question and permit
ask the question and permit it
Uh you walk down the stairs and and and
ask the question and permit it to
ask the question and permit it to be
Uh you walk down the stairs and and and
ask the question and permit it to be and
then
then suddenly
then suddenly much
then suddenly much to
then suddenly much to your
then suddenly much to your amazement
it's
it's not
then suddenly much to your amazement
it's not a
it's not a memory.
then suddenly much to your amazement
it's not a memory. A
it's not a memory. A memory
then suddenly much to your amazement
it's not a memory. A memory is
it's not a memory. A memory is a
different
different thing.
different thing. It's
different thing. It's a
different thing. It's a reexperiencing
it
it as
different thing. It's a reexperiencing
it as though
it as though it's
different thing. It's a reexperiencing
it as though it's it's
it as though it's it's as
different thing. It's a reexperiencing
it as though it's it's as though
it as though it's it's as though the
tape
tape is
tape is running
tape is running again.
tape is running again. Same
tape is running again. Same tape
tape is running again. Same tape that
was
was running
tape is running again. Same tape that
was running now
was running now then
tape is running again. Same tape that
was running now then was
was running now then was running
tape is running again. Same tape that
was running now then was running now.
You
You re
You re reexperience
You re reexperience the
You re reexperience the reality
You re reexperience the reality of
You re reexperience the reality of what
it
it was.
It's
It's not
It's not like
It's not like you're
It's not like you're out
It's not like you're out here
It's not like you're out here witnessing
like
like you
It's not like you're out here witnessing
like you would
like you would on
It's not like you're out here witnessing
like you would on TV.
like you would on TV. Oh,
It's not like you're out here witnessing
like you would on TV. Oh, there
like you would on TV. Oh, there was
It's not like you're out here witnessing
like you would on TV. Oh, there was the
life
life story.
life story. No,
life story. No, you
life story. No, you reexperience
life story. No, you reexperience the
life
life story.
life story. No, you reexperience the
life story. It's
life story. It's the
life story. No, you reexperience the
life story. It's the reality,
life story. It's the reality, subjective
experiential
experiential reality
experiential reality that
experiential reality that you
reexperience.
reexperience. As
experiential reality that you
reexperience. As such,
reexperience. As such, it's
experiential reality that you
reexperience. As such, it's quite
reexperience. As such, it's quite a
learning
learning experience.
learning experience. I
learning experience. I think
learning experience. I think it
learning experience. I think it can
learning experience. I think it can be
useful.
useful. Of
learning experience. I think it can be
useful. Of course,
useful. Of course, it's
learning experience. I think it can be
useful. Of course, it's used
useful. Of course, it's used in
learning experience. I think it can be
useful. Of course, it's used in many
healings.
healings. Many
healings. Many uh
healings. Many uh people
healings. Many uh people have
healings. Many uh people have been
healed
healed by
healings. Many uh people have been
healed by going
healed by going back
healings. Many uh people have been
healed by going back to
healed by going back to whatever
healings. Many uh people have been
healed by going back to whatever it
healed by going back to whatever it was
for
for and
for and then
for and then through
for and then through forgiveness
uh
uh overcoming
for and then through forgiveness
uh overcoming that
uh overcoming that animosity,
for and then through forgiveness
uh overcoming that animosity, that
uh overcoming that animosity, that guilt
or
or whatever.
Yeah,
Yeah, it's
or whatever.
Yeah, it's a
Yeah, it's a useful
or whatever.
Yeah, it's a useful tool.
won't
won't get
won't get you
won't get you the
won't get you the it
won't get you the it won't
won't get you the it won't get
won't get you the it won't get you
there,
there, but
won't get you the it won't get you
there, but it'll
there, but it'll make
won't get you the it won't get you
there, but it'll make the
there, but it'll make the pathway
won't get you the it won't get you
there, but it'll make the pathway more
comprehensible
and
and easier
comprehensible
and easier about
and easier about certain
comprehensible
and easier about certain specific
things.
things. You
things. You know,
why
why do
things. You know,
why do I
why do I feel
things. You know,
why do I feel like
why do I feel like killing
things. You know,
why do I feel like killing little
why do I feel like killing little dogs
all
all the
all the time
all the time or
all the time or something?
all the time or something? You
all the time or something? You know,
you
you reexerience
all the time or something? You know,
you reexerience yourself
you reexerience yourself as
all the time or something? You know,
you reexerience yourself as a
you reexerience yourself as a baby
all the time or something? You know,
you reexerience yourself as a baby and
there's
there's six
there's six of
there's six of them
there's six of them tearing
there's six of them tearing your
there's six of them tearing your throat
out.
out. You,
there's six of them tearing your throat
out. You, oh,
out. You, oh, you
there's six of them tearing your throat
out. You, oh, you now
out. You, oh, you now I
there's six of them tearing your throat
out. You, oh, you now I know
out. You, oh, you now I know I
there's six of them tearing your throat
out. You, oh, you now I know I don't
like
like dogs.
like dogs. You
like dogs. You know,
point
point is
like dogs. You know,
point is you
point is you reexperience
like dogs. You know,
point is you reexperience what
point is you reexperience what it
like dogs. You know,
point is you reexperience what it is
point is you reexperience what it is to
have
have your
have your neck
have your neck torn
have your neck torn out
have your neck torn out by
have your neck torn out by the
have your neck torn out by the doors
dog.
dog. So
have your neck torn out by the doors
dog. So when
dog. So when you
have your neck torn out by the doors
dog. So when you do
dog. So when you do past
have your neck torn out by the doors
dog. So when you do past life,
dog. So when you do past life, don't
forget
forget you're
forget you're going
forget you're going to
forget you're going to reexperience
forget you're going to reexperience the
reality
reality of
forget you're going to reexperience the
reality of what
reality of what you're
forget you're going to reexperience the
reality of what you're asking
reality of what you're asking about.
Reexperience
Reexperience the
Reexperience the reality
Reexperience the reality of
Reexperience the reality of it.
Reexperience the reality of it. Okay.
Can
Can we
Reexperience the reality of it. Okay.
Can we test
Can we test to
Reexperience the reality of it. Okay.
Can we test to discover
Can we test to discover what
Reexperience the reality of it. Okay.
Can we test to discover what lessons
Can we test to discover what lessons or
destinies
destinies we
destinies we have
destinies we have agreed
destinies we have agreed to
destinies we have agreed to work
destinies we have agreed to work out
with
with someone
destinies we have agreed to work out
with someone we
with someone we know
destinies we have agreed to work out
with someone we know in
with someone we know in this
destinies we have agreed to work out
with someone we know in this life?
>> I
>> I never
>> I never asked
>> I never asked that.
I've
I've never
>> I never asked that.
I've never asked
I've never asked it.
>> I never asked that.
I've never asked it. Um
I've never asked it. Um I
>> I never asked that.
I've never asked it. Um I suppose
I've never asked it. Um I suppose it
would
would be
would be a
would be a hypothetical
would be a hypothetical possibility.
You'd
You'd have
would be a hypothetical possibility.
You'd have to
You'd have to ask
would be a hypothetical possibility.
You'd have to ask whether
You'd have to ask whether it's
permitted.
permitted. It
permitted. It may
permitted. It may or
permitted. It may or may
permitted. It may or may not
permitted. It may or may not be
permitted
permitted to
permitted. It may or may not be
permitted to ask
permitted to ask the
permitted. It may or may not be
permitted to ask the question,
>> what's
>> what's the
>> what's the best
>> what's the best way
>> what's the best way of
>> what's the best way of applying
>> what's the best way of applying your
teachings
teachings to
>> what's the best way of applying your
teachings to CEOs
teachings to CEOs in
>> what's the best way of applying your
teachings to CEOs in the
teachings to CEOs in the business
>> what's the best way of applying your
teachings to CEOs in the business world?
>> There's
>> There's good
>> There's good CEOs
>> There's good CEOs and
>> There's good CEOs and there's
>> There's good CEOs and there's bad
>> There's good CEOs and there's bad ones.
Good
Good CEOs
>> There's good CEOs and there's bad ones.
Good CEOs are
Good CEOs are the
>> There's good CEOs and there's bad ones.
Good CEOs are the ones
Good CEOs are the ones that
>> There's good CEOs and there's bad ones.
Good CEOs are the ones that make
Good CEOs are the ones that make you
money
money and
money and bad
money and bad ones
money and bad ones are
money and bad ones are the
money and bad ones are the ones
money and bad ones are the ones that
leave
leave you.
>> I
>> I think
>> I think uh
>> I think uh the
to
to support
>> I think uh the
to support to
to support to to to
>> I think uh the
to support to to to support
to support to to to support the
>> I think uh the
to support to to to support the person
above
above you
above you is
above you is the
above you is the best
above you is the best way
above you is the best way to
above you is the best way to promote
yourself.
yourself. You
above you is the best way to promote
yourself. You you
yourself. You you know
above you is the best way to promote
yourself. You you know that
yourself. You you know that to
above you is the best way to promote
yourself. You you know that to make
yourself. You you know that to make your
boss
boss a
boss a success
boss a success is
boss a success is the
boss a success is the fastest
boss a success is the fastest route
boss a success is the fastest route to
success.
One
One has
One has to
One has to be
One has to be um
One has to be um convinced
One has to be um convinced that
One has to be um convinced that the
person
person to
One has to be um convinced that the
person to whom
person to whom you
One has to be um convinced that the
person to whom you are
person to whom you are going
One has to be um convinced that the
person to whom you are going to
person to whom you are going to with
whom
whom you're
whom you're going
whom you're going to
whom you're going to be
whom you're going to be aligned
whom you're going to be aligned is
integrous.
A
A CEO
A CEO I
A CEO I feel,
A CEO I feel, you
A CEO I feel, you know,
A CEO I feel, you know, I
A CEO I feel, you know, I have
A CEO I feel, you know, I have great
A CEO I feel, you know, I have great uh
compassion
compassion for.
If
If you're
If you're ever
If you're ever the
If you're ever the boss
If you're ever the boss of
If you're ever the boss of any
If you're ever the boss of any business,
you
you know
If you're ever the boss of any business,
you know what
you know what that
If you're ever the boss of any business,
you know what that is.
you know what that is. The
If you're ever the boss of any business,
you know what that is. The the
you know what that is. The the book
stops
stops here.
stops here. All
stops here. All the
stops here. All the pressurees
stops here. All the pressurees on
stops here. All the pressurees on you.
All
All the
stops here. All the pressurees on you.
All the guilts
All the guilts are
stops here. All the pressurees on you.
All the guilts are on
All the guilts are on you.
Uh
and
and the
Uh
and the enemies
and the enemies abound.
If
If you're
If you're successful,
If you're successful, everybody
If you're successful, everybody hates
you.
you. And
If you're successful, everybody hates
you. And if
you. And if you're
If you're successful, everybody hates
you. And if you're a
you. And if you're a failure,
If you're successful, everybody hates
you. And if you're a failure, everybody
hates
hates you.
hates you. So
hates you. So the
hates you. So the CEO
hates you. So the CEO is
hates you. So the CEO is not
hates you. So the CEO is not an
hates you. So the CEO is not an enviable
position.
position. You
hates you. So the CEO is not an enviable
position. You understand?
>> Why
>> Why are
>> Why are kinesiology
>> Why are kinesiology findings
>> Why are kinesiology findings not
accepted
accepted by
>> Why are kinesiology findings not
accepted by mainstream
accepted by mainstream science?
>> Uh
>> Uh just
>> Uh just about
>> Uh just about everything
>> Uh just about everything is
>> Uh just about everything is not
>> Uh just about everything is not accepted
by
by mainstream
>> Uh just about everything is not accepted
by mainstream science.
Now
Now measuring
Now measuring science
Now measuring science is
Now measuring science is a
Now measuring science is a limitation.
You
You see
Now measuring science is a limitation.
You see the
You see the 400s
Now measuring science is a limitation.
You see the 400s for
You see the 400s for people
Now measuring science is a limitation.
You see the 400s for people down
You see the 400s for people down here
the
the 400s
the 400s are
the 400s are very
the 400s are very impressive
the 400s are very impressive very
impressive.
impressive. You
the 400s are very impressive very
impressive. You went
impressive. You went to
the 400s are very impressive very
impressive. You went to college
impressive. You went to college you
the 400s are very impressive very
impressive. You went to college you can
think
think you
think you can
think you can do
think you can do reason
think you can do reason you
think you can do reason you can
think you can do reason you can do
think you can do reason you can do math.
So
So the
think you can do reason you can do math.
So the endy
So the endy of
think you can do reason you can do math.
So the endy of I
So the endy of I mean
think you can do reason you can do math.
So the endy of I mean the
So the endy of I mean the agilation
think you can do reason you can do math.
So the endy of I mean the agilation of
the
the unlearned
the unlearned for
the unlearned for the
the unlearned for the learned.
the unlearned for the learned. So
the unlearned for the learned. So to
have
have a
the unlearned for the learned. So to
have a PhD
have a PhD to
the unlearned for the learned. So to
have a PhD to be
have a PhD to be a
the unlearned for the learned. So to
have a PhD to be a professor
have a PhD to be a professor or
something
something impresses
something impresses a
something impresses a great
something impresses a great many
something impresses a great many people.
The
The minute
something impresses a great many people.
The minute I
The minute I find
something impresses a great many people.
The minute I find somebody's
The minute I find somebody's a
professor,
I
I have
professor,
I have a
I have a different
professor,
I have a different mindset.
Oh
Oh yeah.
Um,
are
are some
are some channel
are some channel sources
are some channel sources truthful?
are some channel sources truthful? And
if
if so,
are some channel sources truthful? And
if so, which
if so, which one?
are some channel sources truthful? And
if so, which one? And
if so, which one? And what
are some channel sources truthful? And
if so, which one? And what about
if so, which one? And what about the
ascended
ascended masters?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yeah.
ascended masters?
>> Oh, yeah. Okay.
>> Oh, yeah. Okay. So,
ascended masters?
>> Oh, yeah. Okay. So, we
>> Oh, yeah. Okay. So, we said
ascended masters?
>> Oh, yeah. Okay. So, we said with
kinesiology,
kinesiology, if
kinesiology, if you're
kinesiology, if you're going
kinesiology, if you're going to
kinesiology, if you're going to resort
to
to masters
kinesiology, if you're going to resort
to masters or
to masters or teachers
kinesiology, if you're going to resort
to masters or teachers or
to masters or teachers or wannabes
kinesiology, if you're going to resort
to masters or teachers or wannabes on
the
the other
the other side,
the other side, you
the other side, you should
the other side, you should calibrate
their
their energy
the other side, you should calibrate
their energy level.
their energy level. Uh,
the other side, you should calibrate
their energy level. Uh, never
their energy level. Uh, never trust
the other side, you should calibrate
their energy level. Uh, never trust any
I'll
I'll tell
I'll tell you
I'll tell you the
I'll tell you the best
I'll tell you the best uh
I'll tell you the best uh lesson
I'll tell you the best uh lesson is
never
never trust
I'll tell you the best uh lesson is
never trust any
never trust any thing
I'll tell you the best uh lesson is
never trust any thing you
never trust any thing you can't
I'll tell you the best uh lesson is
never trust any thing you can't see
never trust any thing you can't see in
I'll tell you the best uh lesson is
never trust any thing you can't see in a
physical
physical body.
physical body. Uh
physical body. Uh and
physical body. Uh and if
physical body. Uh and if you
physical body. Uh and if you do
calibrate
calibrate it,
if
if you
if you do
if you do calibrate
if you do calibrate it,
if you do calibrate it, um
all
all the
if you do calibrate it, um
all the truth
all the truth that
if you do calibrate it, um
all the truth that is
all the truth that is necessary
if you do calibrate it, um
all the truth that is necessary to
all the truth that is necessary to know
has
has already
has already been
has already been spoken.
All
All the
has already been spoken.
All the truth
All the truth that
has already been spoken.
All the truth that is
All the truth that is necessary
has already been spoken.
All the truth that is necessary to
All the truth that is necessary to know
is
is already
is already been
is already been spoken
is already been spoken and
is already been spoken and is
is already been spoken and is already
known.
known. Let's
is already been spoken and is already
known. Let's see
known. Let's see if
is already been spoken and is already
known. Let's see if that's
known. Let's see if that's so.
The
The reason
The reason is
The reason is that
The reason is that that
The reason is that that which
The reason is that that which is
integrous
which
which stems
which stems from
which stems from the
which stems from the presence
which stems from the presence within
which stems from the presence within and
is
is spoken
which stems from the presence within and
is spoken through
is spoken through nosis
which stems from the presence within and
is spoken through nosis really
is spoken through nosis really gn
which stems from the presence within and
is spoken through nosis really gn o
is spoken through nosis really gn o s
which stems from the presence within and
is spoken through nosis really gn o s i
s
s the
s the knowingness
s the knowingness of
s the knowingness of the
s the knowingness of the perushia
s the knowingness of the perushia within
the
the presence
s the knowingness of the perushia within
the presence of
the presence of god
s the knowingness of the perushia within
the presence of god within
the presence of god within as
knowingness
because
because it
knowingness
because it is
because it is aligned
knowingness
because it is aligned with
because it is aligned with truth
speaks
speaks it.
It
It has
speaks it.
It has no
It has no secrets.
That
That which
That which is
That which is integrous
That which is integrous has
That which is integrous has no
That which is integrous has no secrets.
Let
Let that
That which is integrous has no secrets.
Let that be
Let that be a
That which is integrous has no secrets.
Let that be a sign.
That's
That's a
That's a fact.
That's a fact. Is
That's a fact. Is it
that
that which
That's a fact. Is it
that which is
that which is integrous
opens
opens itself
opens itself completely
opens itself completely and
opens itself completely and totally
completely
completely and
opens itself completely and totally
completely and totally
completely and totally and
opens itself completely and totally
completely and totally and shares
completely
completely that
completely that which
completely that which it
completely that which it is.
completely that which it is. Why?
because
because it
completely that which it is. Why?
because it has
because it has no
completely that which it is. Why?
because it has no choice
because it has no choice other
completely that which it is. Why?
because it has no choice other than
because it has no choice other than to
be
be what
be what it
be what it is.
It
It can
be what it is.
It can only
It can only be
be what it is.
It can only be that
It can only be that which
be what it is.
It can only be that which it
It can only be that which it is.
be what it is.
It can only be that which it is. There
are
are no
are no secrets
are no secrets to
are no secrets to withhold
are no secrets to withhold because
are no secrets to withhold because there
are
are no
are no secrets to withhold because there
are no secrets.
Truth
Truth has
Truth has no
Truth has no secrets.
So
So that
Truth has no secrets.
So that which
So that which becomes
Truth has no secrets.
So that which becomes classified
So that which becomes classified and
hidden
hidden away
hidden away as
hidden away as a
hidden away as a secret
hidden away as a secret is
hidden away as a secret is a
hidden away as a secret is a means
hidden away as a secret is a means of
control,
control, mystification,
hidden away as a secret is a means of
control, mystification, and
glamorization.
And
And for
glamorization.
And for a
And for a price
glamorization.
And for a price I
And for a price I will
glamorization.
And for a price I will let
And for a price I will let you
glamorization.
And for a price I will let you join
And for a price I will let you join the
secret
secret society.
For
For another
secret society.
For another 5,000
For another 5,000 I
secret society.
For another 5,000 I will
For another 5,000 I will make
secret society.
For another 5,000 I will make you
For another 5,000 I will make you an
ascended
ascended master
ascended master in
ascended master in the
ascended master in the level
ascended master in the level of
ascended master in the level of esoteric
choose
choose from
ascended master in the level of esoteric
choose from ancient
choose from ancient masters.
Wow.
That's
That's an
Wow.
That's an absolute
That's an absolute sign
Wow.
That's an absolute sign of
That's an absolute sign of truth
is
is that
is that it
is that it has
is that it has nothing
is that it has nothing to
is that it has nothing to withhold.
Perhaps
at
at times
at times in
at times in certain
um
um environments
there
there may
there may be
there may be a
there may be a timing
there may be a timing of
there may be a timing of what
there may be a timing of what to
there may be a timing of what to reveal
out
out of
there may be a timing of what to reveal
out of compassion
out of compassion for
there may be a timing of what to reveal
out of compassion for the
out of compassion for the audience.
There's
There's no
There's no point
There's no point of
There's no point of throwing
There's no point of throwing a
There's no point of throwing a lot
There's no point of throwing a lot of
people
people into
There's no point of throwing a lot of
people into a
people into a state
There's no point of throwing a lot of
people into a state of
people into a state of shock.
There's no point of throwing a lot of
people into a state of shock. Huh?
Uh
it
it would
Uh
it would be
it would be a
Uh
it would be a non-compassionate
thing
thing to
thing to do
thing to do to
thing to do to confront
thing to do to confront people
thing to do to confront people with
thing to do to confront people with the
fact
that
that the
that the guru
that the guru that
that the guru that you've
that the guru that you've left
everything
everything for
that the guru that you've left
everything for and
everything for and worship
that the guru that you've left
everything for and worship as
everything for and worship as God
calibrates
calibrates frankly
calibrates frankly at
calibrates frankly at 102.
That's
That's why
calibrates frankly at 102.
That's why I
That's why I never
calibrates frankly at 102.
That's why I never answer
That's why I never answer it
calibrates frankly at 102.
That's why I never answer it when
That's why I never answer it when asked
in
in public.
I
I tell
in public.
I tell them,
I tell them, "Look
in public.
I tell them, "Look them
I tell them, "Look them up
in public.
I tell them, "Look them up on
I tell them, "Look them up on the
internet
internet and
internet and you'll
internet and you'll see
internet and you'll see result."
>> Yeah.
>> Is
>> Is there
>> Is there an
>> Is there an easier
>> Is there an easier way
>> Is there an easier way to
>> Is there an easier way to change
destructive
destructive behaviors
>> Is there an easier way to change
destructive behaviors other
destructive behaviors other than
consciously
consciously choosing
consciously choosing different
consciously choosing different thoughts?
>> Prayer,
faith,
joining
joining a
faith,
joining a group
joining a group of
faith,
joining a group of like-minded
individuals
individuals who
individuals who have
individuals who have overcome
individuals who have overcome it
individuals who have overcome it and
then
then by
individuals who have overcome it and
then by osmosis
then by osmosis picking
individuals who have overcome it and
then by osmosis picking up
then by osmosis picking up the
individuals who have overcome it and
then by osmosis picking up the energy
then by osmosis picking up the energy of
that.
that. You
that. You know,
that. You know, all
that. You know, all the
that. You know, all the 12step
that. You know, all the 12step groups
say
say that
that. You know, all the 12step groups
say that they
say that they say
that. You know, all the 12step groups
say that they say if
say that they say if you
that. You know, all the 12step groups
say that they say if you can't
say that they say if you can't give
that. You know, all the 12step groups
say that they say if you can't give it
up,
up, just
up, just keep
up, just keep going
up, just keep going to
up, just keep going to meetings
up, just keep going to meetings and
you'll
you'll get
up, just keep going to meetings and
you'll get it
you'll get it by
up, just keep going to meetings and
you'll get it by osmosis.
Well,
Well, the
Well, the group
Well, the group field
Well, the group field gets
Well, the group field gets you.
Well, the group field gets you. That's
why
why the
Well, the group field gets you. That's
why the group
why the group fielded
Well, the group field gets you. That's
why the group fielded 540.
why the group fielded 540. So
we
we know
we know that
we know that um
the
the um
we know that um
the um process
the um process of
we know that um
the um process of entrainment
the
the consciousness
the consciousness is
the consciousness is is
the consciousness is is a
the consciousness is is a frequency
level
and
and consciousness
and consciousness is
and consciousness is affected
and consciousness is affected by
and consciousness is affected by the
pendulum
pendulum effect
and consciousness is affected by the
pendulum effect of
pendulum effect of other
and consciousness is affected by the
pendulum effect of other people's
pendulum effect of other people's the
vibrational
vibrational frequency
vibrational frequency of
vibrational frequency of other
vibrational frequency of other people's
consciousness
consciousness levels.
The
The whole
The whole point
The whole point of
The whole point of a
The whole point of a great
The whole point of a great of
The whole point of a great of a
The whole point of a great of a good
teacher
teacher is
The whole point of a great of a good
teacher is that
teacher is that the
The whole point of a great of a good
teacher is that the frequency
teacher is that the frequency is
The whole point of a great of a good
teacher is that the frequency is picked
up
up in
up in the
up in the oral.
up in the oral. It's
up in the oral. It's an
up in the oral. It's an impersonal
transmission.
So
So a
So a person
So a person who's
So a person who's still
So a person who's still having
So a person who's still having trouble
giving
giving up
So a person who's still having trouble
giving up addiction
giving up addiction goes
So a person who's still having trouble
giving up addiction goes to
giving up addiction goes to let's
So a person who's still having trouble
giving up addiction goes to let's say
giving up addiction goes to let's say NA
or
or AA
or AA or
or AA or Elanon
any
any of
or AA or Elanon
any of the
any of the 12step
or AA or Elanon
any of the 12step groups
any of the 12step groups because
or AA or Elanon
any of the 12step groups because they
calibrate
calibrate at
calibrate at 540.
So
So the
calibrate at 540.
So the energy
So the energy field
calibrate at 540.
So the energy field of
So the energy field of 540
will
will then
will then your
will then your aura
will then your aura will
will then your aura will pick
will then your aura will pick up
will then your aura will pick up 540
and
and so
will then your aura will pick up 540
and so long
and so long as
will then your aura will pick up 540
and so long as your
and so long as your aura
will then your aura will pick up 540
and so long as your aura is
and so long as your aura is picking
will then your aura will pick up 540
and so long as your aura is picking up
that
that 540
that 540 sobriety
that 540 sobriety is
that 540 sobriety is is
that 540 sobriety is is spontaneous
that 540 sobriety is is spontaneous or
easy
if
if your
if your own
if your own level
if your own level of
if your own level of consciousness
doesn't
doesn't evolve
if your own level of consciousness
doesn't evolve to
doesn't evolve to the
if your own level of consciousness
doesn't evolve to the level
doesn't evolve to the level of
if your own level of consciousness
doesn't evolve to the level of 540.
doesn't evolve to the level of 540. What
happens
happens if
happens if you
happens if you walk
happens if you walk away
happens if you walk away from
happens if you walk away from the
happens if you walk away from the field
is
is you
happens if you walk away from the field
is you relapse
is you relapse into
happens if you walk away from the field
is you relapse into the
is you relapse into the previous
happens if you walk away from the field
is you relapse into the previous state
of
of consciousness
of consciousness and
of consciousness and the
of consciousness and the addiction
returns.
returns. So
of consciousness and the addiction
returns. So one
returns. So one is
of consciousness and the addiction
returns. So one is protected
returns. So one is protected from
of consciousness and the addiction
returns. So one is protected from and
don't
don't forget
don't forget addictions
don't forget addictions are
don't forget addictions are very
don't forget addictions are very very
powerful.
powerful. I
don't forget addictions are very very
powerful. I mean
powerful. I mean people
don't forget addictions are very very
powerful. I mean people are
powerful. I mean people are willing
don't forget addictions are very very
powerful. I mean people are willing to
die
die for
die for them.
die for them. That's
die for them. That's strong
die for them. That's strong huh?
It's
It's strong
die for them. That's strong huh?
It's strong enough
It's strong enough to
die for them. That's strong huh?
It's strong enough to kill
It's strong enough to kill you
die for them. That's strong huh?
It's strong enough to kill you and
It's strong enough to kill you and take
you
you out.
you out. And
a
a person
you out. And
a person who's
a person who's not
you out. And
a person who's not scared
a person who's not scared of
you out. And
a person who's not scared of it
a person who's not scared of it is
you out. And
a person who's not scared of it is not
facing
facing the
facing the truth
facing the truth of
facing the truth of it.
facing the truth of it. It
facing the truth of it. It is
facing the truth of it. It is its
intention
intention is
facing the truth of it. It is its
intention is to
intention is to take
facing the truth of it. It is its
intention is to take you
intention is to take you out
facing the truth of it. It is its
intention is to take you out frankly
intention is to take you out frankly to
prevail
prevail to
prevail to dominate
prevail to dominate and
prevail to dominate and take
prevail to dominate and take you
prevail to dominate and take you out
because
because then
prevail to dominate and take you out
because then it
because then it owns
prevail to dominate and take you out
because then it owns you.
because then it owns you. You
prevail to dominate and take you out
because then it owns you. You understand
the
the nature
the nature of
the nature of forces,
the nature of forces, what
the nature of forces, what we
traditionally
traditionally call
the nature of forces, what we
traditionally call dark
traditionally call dark forces.
the nature of forces, what we
traditionally call dark forces. Their
purpose
purpose is
purpose is to
purpose is to take
purpose is to take you
purpose is to take you out
purpose is to take you out and
purpose is to take you out and own
purpose is to take you out and own you.
You
You become
purpose is to take you out and own you.
You become one
You become one of
purpose is to take you out and own you.
You become one of their
You become one of their zombies
purpose is to take you out and own you.
You become one of their zombies and
You become one of their zombies and you
do
do as
do as you
do as you are
do as you are told.
You
You are
do as you are told.
You are now
You are now dominated
do as you are told.
You are now dominated by
You are now dominated by the
do as you are told.
You are now dominated by the field
You are now dominated by the field to
which
which you
which you surrendered.
which you surrendered. Okay?
which you surrendered. Okay? So,
which you surrendered. Okay? So, one
which you surrendered. Okay? So, one is
only
only safe
which you surrendered. Okay? So, one is
only safe so
only safe so long
which you surrendered. Okay? So, one is
only safe so long as
only safe so long as one
which you surrendered. Okay? So, one is
only safe so long as one is
only safe so long as one is in
which you surrendered. Okay? So, one is
only safe so long as one is in the
protection
protection of
protection of the
protection of the field.
If
If one's
protection of the field.
If one's own
If one's own level
protection of the field.
If one's own level consciousness
If one's own level consciousness evolves
beyond
beyond 540,
beyond 540, then
beyond 540, then one
beyond 540, then one has
beyond 540, then one has become
beyond 540, then one has become the
program
program itself
beyond 540, then one has become the
program itself and
program itself and no
beyond 540, then one has become the
program itself and no longer
program itself and no longer is
dependent
dependent on
dependent on an
dependent on an external
dependent on an external group
dependent on an external group energy.
That's
That's the
dependent on an external group energy.
That's the purpose
That's the purpose of
dependent on an external group energy.
That's the purpose of all
That's the purpose of all spiritual
groups
groups by
groups by the
groups by the way
groups by the way is
groups by the way is a
groups by the way is a devoted
groups by the way is a devoted group,
groups by the way is a devoted group, a
devoted
devoted ashram,
no
no matter
no matter what
no matter what they
no matter what they do,
no matter what they do, no
no matter what they do, no matter
no matter what they do, no matter what
kind
kind of
no matter what they do, no matter what
kind of haircuts,
kind of haircuts, colors
no matter what they do, no matter what
kind of haircuts, colors they
kind of haircuts, colors they wear,
no matter what they do, no matter what
kind of haircuts, colors they wear, etc.
It's
It's the
It's the devotional.
It's the devotional. It's
It's the devotional. It's the
It's the devotional. It's the devotion
that
that is
It's the devotional. It's the devotion
that is their
that is their power.
It's the devotional. It's the devotion
that is their power. You
that is their power. You know,
It's the devotional. It's the devotion
that is their power. You know, the
devotion
devotion is
devotion is their
devotion is their power.
Does
Does God
devotion is their power.
Does God have
Does God have an
devotion is their power.
Does God have an ego?
Does God have an ego? And
devotion is their power.
Does God have an ego? And if
Does God have an ego? And if not,
devotion is their power.
Does God have an ego? And if not, why
Does God have an ego? And if not, why do
we?
>> Who?
>> God.
Let's
Let's see.
>> God.
Let's see. That's
Let's see. That's funny.
>> Will
>> Will knee
>> Will knee replacement
>> Will knee replacement surgery
>> Will knee replacement surgery impede
spiritual
spiritual development?
>> No,
>> No, it'll
>> No, it'll assist
>> No, it'll assist it.
you'll
you'll be
>> No, it'll assist it.
you'll be able
you'll be able to
>> No, it'll assist it.
you'll be able to walk
you'll be able to walk the
>> No, it'll assist it.
you'll be able to walk the pathway
better.
However,
However, I
better.
However, I give
However, I give up
better.
However, I give up Christianity
However, I give up Christianity because
kneeling
kneeling in
kneeling in church
kneeling in church ain't
kneeling in church ain't going
kneeling in church ain't going to
kneeling in church ain't going to work
today.
>> What
>> What are
>> What are some
>> What are some recommended
>> What are some recommended study
>> What are some recommended study programs
for
for spiritual
>> What are some recommended study programs
for spiritual enlightenment?
I
I think
I think those
I think those that
I think those that prevail
I think those that prevail um
I think those that prevail um as
I think those that prevail um as the
ground
ground level
I think those that prevail um as the
ground level the
ground level the ground
I think those that prevail um as the
ground level the ground level
ground level the ground level I
I think those that prevail um as the
ground level the ground level I think
non-denominational
non-denominational churches
non-denominational churches uh
non-denominational churches uh like
unity
unity church
non-denominational churches uh like
unity church or
uh
uh science
uh science of
uh science of mind
uh science of mind etc
uh science of mind etc that
uh science of mind etc that are
uh science of mind etc that are based
uh science of mind etc that are based on
solid
solid spiritual
uh science of mind etc that are based on
solid spiritual foundations
solid spiritual foundations I
uh science of mind etc that are based on
solid spiritual foundations I think
solid spiritual foundations I think the
12step
12step groups
12step groups the
12step groups the um
course
course of
12step groups the um
course of miracles
course of miracles I
12step groups the um
course of miracles I think
course of miracles I think um
anything
anything that
anything that anything
anything that anything that
anything that anything that calibrates
um
um you
anything that anything that calibrates
um you know
um you know over
anything that anything that calibrates
um you know over 200
You'd
You'd have
You'd have to.
You'd have to. So,
You'd have to. So, anything
You'd have to. So, anything calibrates
over
over 200
You'd have to. So, anything calibrates
over 200 and
over 200 and is
You'd have to. So, anything calibrates
over 200 and is dedicated
over 200 and is dedicated to
You'd have to. So, anything calibrates
over 200 and is dedicated to spiritual
truth
truth will
truth will eventually
truth will eventually take
truth will eventually take you
truth will eventually take you there.
You
You know,
truth will eventually take you there.
You know, for
You know, for cultural,
truth will eventually take you there.
You know, for cultural, ethnic,
You know, for cultural, ethnic, and
karmic
karmic reasons,
karmic reasons, we're
karmic reasons, we're attracted
karmic reasons, we're attracted to
karmic reasons, we're attracted to one
group
group or
karmic reasons, we're attracted to one
group or another.
group or another. Don't
karmic reasons, we're attracted to one
group or another. Don't forget
group or another. Don't forget many
karmic reasons, we're attracted to one
group or another. Don't forget many of
us
us have
us have been
us have been aligned
us have been aligned in
us have been aligned in many
us have been aligned in many groups
us have been aligned in many groups for
many
many generations,
us have been aligned in many groups for
many generations, many
many generations, many lifetimes.
us have been aligned in many groups for
many generations, many lifetimes. You
know,
know, whole
know, whole whole
know, whole whole e
know, whole whole e whole
know, whole whole e whole ethnic
know, whole whole e whole ethnic groups
come
come in
know, whole whole e whole ethnic groups
come in and
come in and leave
know, whole whole e whole ethnic groups
come in and leave at
come in and leave at the
know, whole whole e whole ethnic groups
come in and leave at the same
come in and leave at the same time.
know, whole whole e whole ethnic groups
come in and leave at the same time. You
see
see people
see people coming
see people coming in
see people coming in as
see people coming in as a
see people coming in as a group
see people coming in as a group and
see people coming in as a group and then
four
four or
see people coming in as a group and then
four or five
four or five million
see people coming in as a group and then
four or five million of
four or five million of them
see people coming in as a group and then
four or five million of them are
four or five million of them are killed
or
or slaughtered
or slaughtered and
or slaughtered and they
or slaughtered and they all
or slaughtered and they all leave
or slaughtered and they all leave the
planet
planet at
or slaughtered and they all leave the
planet at the
planet at the same
or slaughtered and they all leave the
planet at the same time.
planet at the same time. It's
or slaughtered and they all leave the
planet at the same time. It's like
planet at the same time. It's like the
dance
dance of
dance of swarms
dance of swarms of
dance of swarms of birds.
dance of swarms of birds. You
dance of swarms of birds. You see
dance of swarms of birds. You see the
karmic.
karmic. So
dance of swarms of birds. You see the
karmic. So there's
karmic. So there's a
dance of swarms of birds. You see the
karmic. So there's a a
karmic. So there's a a group
dance of swarms of birds. You see the
karmic. So there's a a group karma
karmic. So there's a a group karma to
which
which everyone
which everyone in
which everyone in the
which everyone in the group
which everyone in the group is
which everyone in the group is ascribing
to
to a
which everyone in the group is ascribing
to a certain
to a certain positionality
and
and we
and we see
and we see things
and we see things happen
and we see things happen to
and we see things happen to them
and we see things happen to them that
seem
seem to
and we see things happen to them that
seem to us
seem to us unfair
and we see things happen to them that
seem to us unfair etc.
seem to us unfair etc. because
and we see things happen to them that
seem to us unfair etc. because we
seem to us unfair etc. because we don't
know
know what
know what their
know what their group
know what their group karma
know what their group karma is.
know what their group karma is. Once
know what their group karma is. Once you
know
know what
know what their group karma is. Once you
know what their
know what their group
know what their group karma is. Once you
know what their group karma
know what their group karma is,
know what their group karma is. Once you
know what their group karma is, you
know what their group karma is, you see
it's
it's the
it's the automatic
it's the automatic consequence,
it's the automatic consequence, the
unfoldment
unfoldment of
it's the automatic consequence, the
unfoldment of that
unfoldment of that which
it's the automatic consequence, the
unfoldment of that which was
unfoldment of that which was done
before.
It's
It's a
before.
It's a nonlinear
wavelike
wavelike phenomena.
How
How does
wavelike phenomena.
How does seeking
How does seeking to
wavelike phenomena.
How does seeking to express
How does seeking to express one's
creativity
creativity relate
creativity relate to
creativity relate to enlightenment?
creativity relate to enlightenment? Is
there
there a
creativity relate to enlightenment? Is
there a relationship
there a relationship between
creativity relate to enlightenment? Is
there a relationship between using
there a relationship between using one's
gifts
gifts and
gifts and enlightenment?
I
I don't
gifts and enlightenment?
I don't remember
I don't remember the
gifts and enlightenment?
I don't remember the question
before
before specifically.
before specifically. I
before specifically. I I
before specifically. I I would
before specifically. I I would say
before specifically. I I would say the
gratitude
gratitude for
before specifically. I I would say the
gratitude for one's
gratitude for one's gifts
before specifically. I I would say the
gratitude for one's gifts takes
gratitude for one's gifts takes one
closer
closer to
closer to God.
closer to God. In
closer to God. In other
closer to God. In other words,
closer to God. In other words, gratitude
instead
instead of
closer to God. In other words, gratitude
instead of pridefulness
instead of pridefulness or
closer to God. In other words, gratitude
instead of pridefulness or egotism
instead of pridefulness or egotism about
one's
one's gifts.
one's gifts. All
one's gifts. All of
one's gifts. All of us
one's gifts. All of us are
one's gifts. All of us are born
one's gifts. All of us are born with
certain
certain gifts
one's gifts. All of us are born with
certain gifts and
certain gifts and propensities
to
to be
to be thankful
to be thankful for
to be thankful for them
to be thankful for them and
to be thankful for them and gracious
about
about it.
to be thankful for them and gracious
about it. I
about it. I was
to be thankful for them and gracious
about it. I was talking
about it. I was talking outside.
to be thankful for them and gracious
about it. I was talking outside. I
about it. I was talking outside. I said
we
we just
we just happened
we just happened to
we just happened to see
we just happened to see a
we just happened to see a a
we just happened to see a a run
we just happened to see a a run on
we just happened to see a a run on BBC
of
of Paul
we just happened to see a a run on BBC
of Paul McCartney
of Paul McCartney and
we just happened to see a a run on BBC
of Paul McCartney and it
of Paul McCartney and it was
we just happened to see a a run on BBC
of Paul McCartney and it was a
of Paul McCartney and it was a very
beautiful
beautiful program.
beautiful program. It
beautiful program. It was
beautiful program. It was a
beautiful program. It was a very
Parkinson
Parkinson or
beautiful program. It was a very
Parkinson or somebody
Parkinson or somebody his
beautiful program. It was a very
Parkinson or somebody his name
Parkinson or somebody his name was
beautiful program. It was a very
Parkinson or somebody his name was the
interviewer
interviewer and
interviewer and Paul
interviewer and Paul was
interviewer and Paul was just
interviewer and Paul was just describing
some
some of
interviewer and Paul was just describing
some of his
some of his experiences
interviewer and Paul was just describing
some of his experiences in
some of his experiences in life
interviewer and Paul was just describing
some of his experiences in life and
some of his experiences in life and then
he
he then
he then he
he then he then
he then he then began
he then he then began to
he then he then began to play
uh
uh and
he then he then began to play
uh and then
uh and then he
he then he then began to play
uh and then he was
uh and then he was just
he then he then began to play
uh and then he was just very
uh and then he was just very very
natural
natural quite
natural quite charming
natural quite charming in
natural quite charming in a
natural quite charming in a way
natural quite charming in a way and
natural quite charming in a way and then
he
he uh
natural quite charming in a way and then
he uh played
he uh played something
natural quite charming in a way and then
he uh played something else
he uh played something else and
natural quite charming in a way and then
he uh played something else and uh
he uh played something else and uh then
they
they kept
they kept talking
they kept talking and
they kept talking and he
they kept talking and he explained
they kept talking and he explained what
his
his relationship
they kept talking and he explained what
his relationship was
his relationship was to
they kept talking and he explained what
his relationship was to John
his relationship was to John and
they kept talking and he explained what
his relationship was to John and why
they
they had
they had the
they had the strife
they had the strife and
they had the strife and how
they had the strife and how he
they had the strife and how he felt
about
about that
they had the strife and how he felt
about that and
about that and how
they had the strife and how he felt
about that and how grateful
about that and how grateful he
they had the strife and how he felt
about that and how grateful he was
about that and how grateful he was that
they
they had
they had made
they had made up
they had made up before
they had made up before John
they had made up before John died.
they had made up before John died. He
thinks
thinks uh
they had made up before John died. He
thinks uh he
thinks uh he said
they had made up before John died. He
thinks uh he said how
thinks uh he said how awful
they had made up before John died. He
thinks uh he said how awful it
thinks uh he said how awful it would
have
have been
have been if
have been if John
have been if John had
have been if John had died
have been if John had died before
have been if John had died before we
made
made up.
have been if John had died before we
made up. And
made up. And then
have been if John had died before we
made up. And then he
made up. And then he says
have been if John had died before we
made up. And then he says something
quite
quite significant
quite significant and
quite significant and of
quite significant and of use
quite significant and of use to
quite significant and of use to all
spiritual
spiritual seekers.
quite significant and of use to all
spiritual seekers. He
spiritual seekers. He says
quite significant and of use to all
spiritual seekers. He says um
what
what was
what was it?
what was it? Liverpool.
what was it? Liverpool. Yeah.
what was it? Liverpool. Yeah. He
what was it? Liverpool. Yeah. He says
what was it? Liverpool. Yeah. He says um
luckily
luckily for
what was it? Liverpool. Yeah. He says um
luckily for me
luckily for me I'm
what was it? Liverpool. Yeah. He says um
luckily for me I'm from
luckily for me I'm from Liverpool
what was it? Liverpool. Yeah. He says um
luckily for me I'm from Liverpool and
when
when you're
when you're from
when you're from Liverpool
when you're from Liverpool and
when you're from Liverpool and you
when you're from Liverpool and you start
getting
getting ahead
when you're from Liverpool and you start
getting ahead about
getting ahead about something
when you're from Liverpool and you start
getting ahead about something they
getting ahead about something they say,
hey
hey buddy,
hey buddy, you're
hey buddy, you're starting
hey buddy, you're starting to
hey buddy, you're starting to get
hey buddy, you're starting to get ahead
about
about that.
hey buddy, you're starting to get ahead
about that. So
about that. So he
hey buddy, you're starting to get ahead
about that. So he saw
about that. So he saw how
hey buddy, you're starting to get ahead
about that. So he saw how he
about that. So he saw how he had
hey buddy, you're starting to get ahead
about that. So he saw how he had escaped
the
the death
the death that
the death that ensues
the death that ensues from
the death that ensues from egotism
the death that ensues from egotism that
comes
comes to
the death that ensues from egotism that
comes to so
comes to so many
the death that ensues from egotism that
comes to so many rock
comes to so many rock stars
the death that ensues from egotism that
comes to so many rock stars and
celebrities
celebrities you
celebrities you know
celebrities you know that
celebrities you know that takes
celebrities you know that takes them
celebrities you know that takes them out
of
of here
celebrities you know that takes them out
of here or
of here or takes
celebrities you know that takes them out
of here or takes them
of here or takes them off
celebrities you know that takes them out
of here or takes them off into
of here or takes them off into insanity.
You
You can
You can see
You can see he
You can see he was
You can see he was very
You can see he was very grateful
You can see he was very grateful that
You can see he was very grateful that he
had
had not
You can see he was very grateful that he
had not been
had not been taken
You can see he was very grateful that he
had not been taken away
had not been taken away by
You can see he was very grateful that he
had not been taken away by the
had not been taken away by the egotism
and
and the
and the swelled
and the swelled head
and the swelled head and
and the swelled head and the
and the swelled head and the vanity
and the swelled head and the vanity and
the
the expansion
and the swelled head and the vanity and
the expansion of
the expansion of egoentricity
and the swelled head and the vanity and
the expansion of egoentricity that
the expansion of egoentricity that you
see
see in
see in people
see in people who
see in people who are
see in people who are celebrities
see in people who are celebrities in
see in people who are celebrities in the
eyes
eyes of
see in people who are celebrities in the
eyes of the
eyes of the media.
see in people who are celebrities in the
eyes of the media. So
eyes of the media. So that
see in people who are celebrities in the
eyes of the media. So that was
eyes of the media. So that was a
see in people who are celebrities in the
eyes of the media. So that was a gift
eyes of the media. So that was a gift to
him.
him. I
him. I could
him. I could see
him. I could see he
him. I could see he held
him. I could see he held it
him. I could see he held it as
him. I could see he held it as a
him. I could see he held it as a gift
that
that his
him. I could see he held it as a gift
that his musical
that his musical talent
him. I could see he held it as a gift
that his musical talent was
that his musical talent was a
him. I could see he held it as a gift
that his musical talent was a gift
that his musical talent was a gift and
therefore
therefore when
therefore when he
therefore when he played
therefore when he played for
therefore when he played for you
therefore when he played for you he
therefore when he played for you he was
playing
playing obviously
therefore when he played for you he was
playing obviously he
playing obviously he knew
therefore when he played for you he was
playing obviously he knew that
playing obviously he knew that lots
therefore when he played for you he was
playing obviously he knew that lots of
people
people are
people are out
people are out there
people are out there watching
people are out there watching him
people are out there watching him he
people are out there watching him he was
also
also playing
people are out there watching him he was
also playing it
also playing it for
people are out there watching him he was
also playing it for the
also playing it for the interviewing
people are out there watching him he was
also playing it for the interviewing but
he
he was
he was doing
he was doing it
he was doing it like
he was doing it like from
he was doing it like from the
he was doing it like from the space
he was doing it like from the space of
he was doing it like from the space of a
gift
gift you
he was doing it like from the space of a
gift you know
gift you know it's
he was doing it like from the space of a
gift you know it's like
gift you know it's like I
he was doing it like from the space of a
gift you know it's like I share
gift you know it's like I share this
with
with you
with you and
with you and that's
with you and that's who
with you and that's who I
with you and that's who I am
with you and that's who I am and
with you and that's who I am and uh
with you and that's who I am and uh the
humility
humility of
with you and that's who I am and uh the
humility of it
humility of it was
with you and that's who I am and uh the
humility of it was quite
humility of it was quite uh
with you and that's who I am and uh the
humility of it was quite uh beautiful
humility of it was quite uh beautiful so
one's
one's gifts
one's gifts then
one's gifts then to
one's gifts then to be
one's gifts then to be grateful
one's gifts then to be grateful for
one's gifts then to be grateful for them
and
and to
one's gifts then to be grateful for them
and to use
and to use them
one's gifts then to be grateful for them
and to use them for
and to use them for the
one's gifts then to be grateful for them
and to use them for the good
and to use them for the good of
one's gifts then to be grateful for them
and to use them for the good of others
So
So he
So he uses
So he uses his
So he uses his gift
So he uses his gift for
So he uses his gift for the
So he uses his gift for the joy
So he uses his gift for the joy of
So he uses his gift for the joy of the
world
world to
So he uses his gift for the joy of the
world to bring
world to bring beauty
So he uses his gift for the joy of the
world to bring beauty to
world to bring beauty to it
So he uses his gift for the joy of the
world to bring beauty to it because
um
um beauty
um beauty is
um beauty is one
um beauty is one of
um beauty is one of the
um beauty is one of the fastest
um beauty is one of the fastest avenues
to
to God.
Beauty
Beauty is
Beauty is one
Beauty is one of
Beauty is one of the
Beauty is one of the shortcuts
Beauty is one of the shortcuts to
Beauty is one of the shortcuts to God.
That
That which
worships
worships and
worships and values
worships and values beauty
worships and values beauty is
worships and values beauty is close
worships and values beauty is close to
God.
God. Just
worships and values beauty is close to
God. Just as
God. Just as you
worships and values beauty is close to
God. Just as you can
God. Just as you can see
worships and values beauty is close to
God. Just as you can see the
God. Just as you can see the music
worships and values beauty is close to
God. Just as you can see the music that
we
we played
we played at
we played at 7:40.
You're
You're halfway
we played at 7:40.
You're halfway there,
You're halfway there, folks.
From
From 7:40,
From 7:40, you
From 7:40, you don't
From 7:40, you don't have
From 7:40, you don't have to
From 7:40, you don't have to do
From 7:40, you don't have to do much,
you
you know,
From 7:40, you don't have to do much,
you know, except
you know, except lay
From 7:40, you don't have to do much,
you know, except lay back
you know, except lay back and
From 7:40, you don't have to do much,
you know, except lay back and let
you know, except lay back and let it
From 7:40, you don't have to do much,
you know, except lay back and let it do
it
it to
it to you.
it to you. Let
it to you. Let it
it to you. Let it be
it to you. Let it be what
it to you. Let it be what it
it to you. Let it be what it is,
it to you. Let it be what it is, you
know.
So,
>> are
>> are we
So,
>> are we here
>> are we here on
So,
>> are we here on earth
>> are we here on earth to
So,
>> are we here on earth to learn
>> are we here on earth to learn lessons?
Is
Is this
Is this school?
>> Well,
>> Well, let's
Is this school?
>> Well, let's see.
>> Well, let's see. We
Is this school?
>> Well, let's see. We said
>> Well, let's see. We said that
Is this school?
>> Well, let's see. We said that if
>> Well, let's see. We said that if you
look
look at
look at the
look at the nature,
look at the nature, the
look at the nature, the quality
look at the nature, the quality of
look at the nature, the quality of human
life,
life, you
look at the nature, the quality of human
life, you see
life, you see that
look at the nature, the quality of human
life, you see that it's
life, you see that it's purgatorial.
look at the nature, the quality of human
life, you see that it's purgatorial. You
so
so see
so see that
so see that it
so see that it goes
so see that it goes from
so see that it goes from the
so see that it goes from the serial
killer
killer who
so see that it goes from the serial
killer who kills
killer who kills 13
so see that it goes from the serial
killer who kills 13 children
to
to the
to the Buddha
to the Buddha and
to the Buddha and all
to the Buddha and all all
to the Buddha and all all possibilities
in
in between.
The
value
value of
The
value of this
value of this life
The
value of this life then
value of this life then is
The
value of this life then is the
value of this life then is the undoing
of
of karmic
of karmic debt
of karmic debt you
of karmic debt you might
of karmic debt you might say
of karmic debt you might say and
of karmic debt you might say and the
earning
earning of
of karmic debt you might say and the
earning of karmic
earning of karmic merit.
the
the incredible
the incredible number
the incredible number of
the incredible number of choices
so
so that
the incredible number of choices
so that at
so that at all
the incredible number of choices
so that at all times
so that at all times one
the incredible number of choices
so that at all times one has
so that at all times one has a
the incredible number of choices
so that at all times one has a multitude
of
of choices.
Each
Each choice
of choices.
Each choice then
Each choice then you
of choices.
Each choice then you might
Each choice then you might say
of choices.
Each choice then you might say increases
or
or decreases
or decreases the
or decreases the charge
or decreases the charge on
or decreases the charge on the
core
core puzzle
or decreases the charge on the
core puzzle of
core puzzle of the
or decreases the charge on the
core puzzle of the karmic
core puzzle of the karmic self
or decreases the charge on the
core puzzle of the karmic self which
determines
what
what happens
determines
what happens to
what happens to the
determines
what happens to the spirit
what happens to the spirit as
determines
what happens to the spirit as it
what happens to the spirit as it leaves
the
the body.
the body. You're
the body. You're obviously
the body. You're obviously attracted
the body. You're obviously attracted to
like
like goes
the body. You're obviously attracted to
like goes to
like goes to like
the body. You're obviously attracted to
like goes to like to
like goes to like to that
the body. You're obviously attracted to
like goes to like to that which
like goes to like to that which you
identify
identify with
identify with and
identify with and value
identify with and value is
identify with and value is that
identify with and value is that which
you're
you're attracted
identify with and value is that which
you're attracted to.
As
As I
As I said,
As I said, if
As I said, if you
As I said, if you clean
As I said, if you clean if
As I said, if you clean if you
As I said, if you clean if you clean
As I said, if you clean if you clean up
the
the old
As I said, if you clean if you clean up
the old hangout
the old hangout and
As I said, if you clean if you clean up
the old hangout and put
the old hangout and put up
As I said, if you clean if you clean up
the old hangout and put up new
the old hangout and put up new drapes
and
and new
and new carpets,
and new carpets, the
and new carpets, the old
and new carpets, the old gang
and new carpets, the old gang will
and new carpets, the old gang will not
come
come back.
You
You say,
You say, "Won't
You say, "Won't they
You say, "Won't they be
You say, "Won't they be happy
You say, "Won't they be happy after
You say, "Won't they be happy after we
fix
fix this
You say, "Won't they be happy after we
fix this all
fix this all up?
You say, "Won't they be happy after we
fix this all up? They
fix this all up? They won't
You say, "Won't they be happy after we
fix this all up? They won't eat
fix this all up? They won't eat in
You say, "Won't they be happy after we
fix this all up? They won't eat in your
restaurant
restaurant anymore.
They
They go
restaurant anymore.
They go back.
They go back. They
restaurant anymore.
They go back. They will
They go back. They will find
restaurant anymore.
They go back. They will find another
place
near
near the
place
near the gas
near the gas works.
It
It was
It was a
It was a place
It was a place near
It was a place near the
It was a place near the gas
It was a place near the gas works
It was a place near the gas works when
It was a place near the gas works when I
was
was a
It was a place near the gas works when I
was a cab
was a cab driver
It was a place near the gas works when I
was a cab driver and
was a cab driver and it
It was a place near the gas works when I
was a cab driver and it had
was a cab driver and it had a
It was a place near the gas works when I
was a cab driver and it had a certain
cache
cache because
cache because it
cache because it was
cache because it was next
cache because it was next to
cache because it was next to the
cache because it was next to the gas
works.
works. You
cache because it was next to the gas
works. You know what
works. You know what I
cache because it was next to the gas
works. You know what I mean?
works. You know what I mean? It
cache because it was next to the gas
works. You know what I mean? It was
cool.
cool. And
cool. And the
cool. And the really
cool. And the really hip
cool. And the really hip crowd
cool. And the really hip crowd used
cool. And the really hip crowd used to
go
go to
cool. And the really hip crowd used to
go to Dirty
go to Dirty Helens.
cool. And the really hip crowd used to
go to Dirty Helens. She
go to Dirty Helens. She was
cool. And the really hip crowd used to
go to Dirty Helens. She was very
go to Dirty Helens. She was very vulgar
and
and ex-prostitute.
She
She only
and ex-prostitute.
She only sold
She only sold whiskey.
and ex-prostitute.
She only sold whiskey. And
She only sold whiskey. And if
and ex-prostitute.
She only sold whiskey. And if you
She only sold whiskey. And if you wanted
a
a mixed
a mixed drink,
a mixed drink, she
a mixed drink, she told
a mixed drink, she told you
a mixed drink, she told you fruits
a mixed drink, she told you fruits could
drink
drink down
a mixed drink, she told you fruits could
drink down the
drink down the street.
because
because she
because she was
because she was a
because she was a convicted
because she was a convicted madam,
because she was a convicted madam, she
couldn't
couldn't get
because she was a convicted madam, she
couldn't get a
couldn't get a a
because she was a convicted madam, she
couldn't get a a license.
couldn't get a a license. This
because she was a convicted madam, she
couldn't get a a license. This is
couldn't get a a license. This is in
Milwaukee,
Milwaukee, Wisconsin.
Because
Because she
Milwaukee, Wisconsin.
Because she was
Because she was a
Milwaukee, Wisconsin.
Because she was a convicted
Because she was a convicted madam
Milwaukee, Wisconsin.
Because she was a convicted madam with
past
felonies
felonies or
past
felonies or whatever
felonies or whatever on
past
felonies or whatever on her
felonies or whatever on her record,
past
felonies or whatever on her record, she
couldn't
couldn't get
couldn't get a
couldn't get a liquor
couldn't get a liquor license.
couldn't get a liquor license. But
couldn't get a liquor license. But the
law
law in
couldn't get a liquor license. But the
law in the
law in the state
couldn't get a liquor license. But the
law in the state of
law in the state of Wisconsin
couldn't get a liquor license. But the
law in the state of Wisconsin was
law in the state of Wisconsin was you
could
could have
could have like
could have like three
could have like three bottles
could have like three bottles of
whiskey.
whiskey. You
could have like three bottles of
whiskey. You had
whiskey. You had to
could have like three bottles of
whiskey. You had to have
whiskey. You had to have a
could have like three bottles of
whiskey. You had to have a license
beyond
beyond two
beyond two or
beyond two or three
beyond two or three bottles.
beyond two or three bottles. So,
beyond two or three bottles. So, she
would
would only
beyond two or three bottles. So, she
would only keep
would only keep two,
beyond two or three bottles. So, she
would only keep two, three
would only keep two, three bottles
beyond two or three bottles. So, she
would only keep two, three bottles of
whiskey
whiskey in
whiskey in the
whiskey in the tavern.
whiskey in the tavern. She
whiskey in the tavern. She only
whiskey in the tavern. She only bug
whiskey in the tavern. She only bug a
shot,
shot, big
whiskey in the tavern. She only bug a
shot, big fat
shot, big fat shot.
whiskey in the tavern. She only bug a
shot, big fat shot. And
shot, big fat shot. And then
whiskey in the tavern. She only bug a
shot, big fat shot. And then she
shot, big fat shot. And then she would
call
call for
call for a
call for a cab.
call for a cab. So
call for a cab. So as
call for a cab. So as her
call for a cab. So as her whiskey
call for a cab. So as her whiskey got
down,
down, she
call for a cab. So as her whiskey got
down, she called
down, she called there.
call for a cab. So as her whiskey got
down, she called there. So
down, she called there. So I
call for a cab. So as her whiskey got
down, she called there. So I was
down, she called there. So I was driving
a
a cab.
a cab. She
a cab. She say,
a cab. She say, "Dirty
a cab. She say, "Dirty Helens,
a cab. She say, "Dirty Helens, you
a cab. She say, "Dirty Helens, you over
there."
there." She
a cab. She say, "Dirty Helens, you over
there." She give
there." She give you
a cab. She say, "Dirty Helens, you over
there." She give you the
there." She give you the money,
a cab. She say, "Dirty Helens, you over
there." She give you the money, you
there." She give you the money, you go
over,
over, you
over, you get
over, you get a
over, you get a bottle
over, you get a bottle of
over, you get a bottle of whiskey
over, you get a bottle of whiskey and
bring
bring it
over, you get a bottle of whiskey and
bring it back.
bring it back. So
over, you get a bottle of whiskey and
bring it back. So that's
bring it back. So that's the
over, you get a bottle of whiskey and
bring it back. So that's the way
bring it back. So that's the way she
over, you get a bottle of whiskey and
bring it back. So that's the way she ran
the
the tavern,
the tavern, you
the tavern, you know,
chic,
chic, you
the tavern, you know,
chic, you know,
chic, you know, cool
the tavern, you know,
chic, you know, cool hip
chic, you know, cool hip crowd.
Thick
Thick rugs
Thick rugs like
Thick rugs like this.
>> What?
>> What? Oh,
Thick rugs like this.
>> What? Oh, I
>> What? Oh, I told
Thick rugs like this.
>> What? Oh, I told that
>> What? Oh, I told that one.
Thick rugs like this.
>> What? Oh, I told that one. Oh,
>> What? Oh, I told that one. Oh, I'm
sorry.
>> No,
>> No, I
sorry.
>> No, I I
>> No, I I can't
sorry.
>> No, I I can't believe
>> No, I I can't believe you
sorry.
>> No, I I can't believe you told
>> No, I I can't believe you told it.
sorry.
>> No, I I can't believe you told it. Well,
it's
it's a
it's a fact.
I
I was
it's a fact.
I was a
I was a cab
it's a fact.
I was a cab driver
I was a cab driver and
it's a fact.
I was a cab driver and uh
I was a cab driver and uh and
it's a fact.
I was a cab driver and uh and she
I was a cab driver and uh and she had
she
she of
she of course
she of course Dirty
she of course Dirty Helen
she of course Dirty Helen had
she of course Dirty Helen had had
she of course Dirty Helen had had a
quite
quite a
she of course Dirty Helen had had a
quite a vocabulary.
So,
So, you
So, you see
So, you see the
So, you see the attraction
So, you see the attraction of
So, you see the attraction of the
So, you see the attraction of the hip
cool
cool degeneracy.
You
You know,
You know, whether
You know, whether it's
You know, whether it's evil
You know, whether it's evil or
You know, whether it's evil or not
You know, whether it's evil or not evil
depends
depends on
You know, whether it's evil or not evil
depends on context,
depends on context, right?
You know, whether it's evil or not evil
depends on context, right? It
depends on context, right? It was
You know, whether it's evil or not evil
depends on context, right? It was hip
and
and cool
and cool and
and cool and she
and cool and she was
and cool and she was an
and cool and she was an okay
and cool and she was an okay lady,
and cool and she was an okay lady, but
it
it was
and cool and she was an okay lady, but
it was illegal,
it was illegal, you
and cool and she was an okay lady, but
it was illegal, you know.
What
What are
What are some
What are some jobs
What are some jobs you
What are some jobs you would
What are some jobs you would see
unconditionally
unconditionally loving
What are some jobs you would see
unconditionally loving individuals
unconditionally loving individuals have?
And
And could
And could a
And could a film
And could a film could
And could a film could a
And could a film could a filmmaker
And could a film could a filmmaker be
enlightened?
>> Enlightened
>> Enlightened dirty
>> Enlightened dirty help.
You
You see,
>> Enlightened dirty help.
You see, all
You see, all of
>> Enlightened dirty help.
You see, all of us
You see, all of us serve
>> Enlightened dirty help.
You see, all of us serve in
You see, all of us serve in whatever
capacity
capacity we
capacity we are,
capacity we are, you
capacity we are, you know,
capacity we are, you know, and
capacity we are, you know, and we
radiate
radiate the
capacity we are, you know, and we
radiate the joy
radiate the joy of
capacity we are, you know, and we
radiate the joy of who
radiate the joy of who we
capacity we are, you know, and we
radiate the joy of who we are
radiate the joy of who we are into
everything
everything that
everything that we
everything that we do.
So,
So, you
everything that we do.
So, you can
So, you can get
everything that we do.
So, you can get on
So, you can get on an
everything that we do.
So, you can get on an elevator
So, you can get on an elevator and
everything that we do.
So, you can get on an elevator and the
elevator
elevator operator
elevator operator is
elevator operator is just
elevator operator is just turned
elevator operator is just turned on
elevator operator is just turned on and
turns
turns you
elevator operator is just turned on and
turns you on
turns you on and
elevator operator is just turned on and
turns you on and it's
turns you on and it's ecstatic.
And
And therefore,
And therefore, we
And therefore, we can
And therefore, we can bring
And therefore, we can bring joy
And therefore, we can bring joy to
And therefore, we can bring joy to the
world
world in
And therefore, we can bring joy to the
world in every
world in every opportunity,
And therefore, we can bring joy to the
world in every opportunity, you
world in every opportunity, you know.
Yeah.
We
We serve
Yeah.
We serve the
We serve the world
Yeah.
We serve the world by
We serve the world by the
Yeah.
We serve the world by the joy
We serve the world by the joy sharing
the
the joy
the joy of
the joy of the
the joy of the experience
the joy of the experience of
the joy of the experience of our
the joy of the experience of our own
existence.
existence. The
the joy of the experience of our own
existence. The source
existence. The source of
the joy of the experience of our own
existence. The source of joy
existence. The source of joy stems
the joy of the experience of our own
existence. The source of joy stems from
within
within and
within and we
within and we share
within and we share that
within and we share that with
within and we share that with everything
and
and everyone
within and we share that with everything
and everyone as
and everyone as we
within and we share that with everything
and everyone as we walk
and everyone as we walk through
within and we share that with everything
and everyone as we walk through the
world.
world. Huh?
world. Huh? Thus
world. Huh? Thus we
world. Huh? Thus we serve
world. Huh? Thus we serve God
world. Huh? Thus we serve God and
world. Huh? Thus we serve God and we
serve
serve oursel.
So
So you
So you can
So you can be
So you can be uh
So you can be uh joy
So you can be uh joy to
So you can be uh joy to the
So you can be uh joy to the world
So you can be uh joy to the world no
matter
matter what
So you can be uh joy to the world no
matter what you
matter what you do.
So you can be uh joy to the world no
matter what you do. Even
matter what you do. Even the
So you can be uh joy to the world no
matter what you do. Even the headsman,
you
you see,
you see, can
you see, can say
you see, can say to
you see, can say to you
you see, can say to you before
you see, can say to you before he
you see, can say to you before he chops
your
your head
you see, can say to you before he chops
your head off.
It's
It's nothing
It's nothing personal
It's nothing personal about
It's nothing personal about this.
It's nothing personal about this. You
understand?
Now,
Now, if
Now, if you're
Now, if you're a
Now, if you're a real
Now, if you're a real English
Now, if you're a real English gentleman,
you
you say,
Now, if you're a real English gentleman,
you say, "Of
you say, "Of course
Now, if you're a real English gentleman,
you say, "Of course not.
you say, "Of course not. You're
Now, if you're a real English gentleman,
you say, "Of course not. You're doing
your
your duty.
your duty. And
your duty. And here's
your duty. And here's a
your duty. And here's a few
your duty. And here's a few Bob
your duty. And here's a few Bob to
your duty. And here's a few Bob to take
care."
Uh,
Uh, it
Uh, it was
Uh, it was known
Uh, it was known if
Uh, it was known if you
Uh, it was known if you didn't
Uh, it was known if you didn't have
Uh, it was known if you didn't have a
few
few Bob
Uh, it was known if you didn't have a
few Bob extra,
few Bob extra, you
Uh, it was known if you didn't have a
few Bob extra, you could
few Bob extra, you could take
Uh, it was known if you didn't have a
few Bob extra, you could take him
few Bob extra, you could take him a
Uh, it was known if you didn't have a
few Bob extra, you could take him a heck
or
or two.
So,
So, even
or two.
So, even the
So, even the headsman,
or two.
So, even the headsman, you
So, even the headsman, you see,
or two.
So, even the headsman, you see, can
So, even the headsman, you see, can be
or two.
So, even the headsman, you see, can be a
joyful
joyful headsman.
>> Are
>> Are the
joyful headsman.
>> Are the training
>> Are the training programs
joyful headsman.
>> Are the training programs at
>> Are the training programs at the
joyful headsman.
>> Are the training programs at the Monroe
Institute
Institute useful
Institute useful on
Institute useful on the
Institute useful on the journey
Institute useful on the journey of
enlightenment
enlightenment or
Institute useful on the journey of
enlightenment or just
enlightenment or just dabbling
Institute useful on the journey of
enlightenment or just dabbling in
spiritual
spiritual realms?
uh
uh I
spiritual realms?
uh I don't
uh I don't know
spiritual realms?
uh I don't know about
uh I don't know about the
spiritual realms?
uh I don't know about the Monroe
Institute
Institute many
Institute many years
Institute many years ago
Institute many years ago journeys
Institute many years ago journeys out
Institute many years ago journeys out of
the
the body
Institute many years ago journeys out of
the body body
the body body uh
Institute many years ago journeys out of
the body body uh by
the body body uh by Monroe
Institute many years ago journeys out of
the body body uh by Monroe was
the body body uh by Monroe was of
Institute many years ago journeys out of
the body body uh by Monroe was of course
an
an innovative
an innovative and
an innovative and challenging
an innovative and challenging thing
an innovative and challenging thing and
he
he set
an innovative and challenging thing and
he set up
he set up the
an innovative and challenging thing and
he set up the Monroe
he set up the Monroe incident
Monroe
Monroe Institute
um
um I
Monroe Institute
um I thought
um I thought his
Monroe Institute
um I thought his book
um I thought his book was
Monroe Institute
um I thought his book was quite
um I thought his book was quite charming
here's
here's this
here's this innocent
here's this innocent man
here's this innocent man who
here's this innocent man who had
here's this innocent man who had never
heard
heard of
here's this innocent man who had never
heard of out
heard of out of
here's this innocent man who had never
heard of out of body
heard of out of body nobody
here's this innocent man who had never
heard of out of body nobody heard
heard of out of body nobody heard about
it
it in
it in the
it in the years
it in the years when
it in the years when that
it in the years when that was
it in the years when that was published
I
I forget
it in the years when that was published
I forget when
I forget when that
it in the years when that was published
I forget when that was
I forget when that was published
but
but when
but when we
but when we all
but when we all grew
but when we all grew up
but when we all grew up early
but when we all grew up early in
but when we all grew up early in the
spiritual
spiritual world
but when we all grew up early in the
spiritual world nobody
spiritual world nobody ever
but when we all grew up early in the
spiritual world nobody ever heard
spiritual world nobody ever heard of
but when we all grew up early in the
spiritual world nobody ever heard of out
of
of body
of body so
of body so Here
of body so Here he
of body so Here he was
of body so Here he was an
of body so Here he was an engineer
of body so Here he was an engineer and
he's
he's going
of body so Here he was an engineer and
he's going out
he's going out of
of body so Here he was an engineer and
he's going out of body
he's going out of body and
of body so Here he was an engineer and
he's going out of body and having
he's going out of body and having all
these
these astral
these astral adventures
and
and then
these astral adventures
and then coming
and then coming back
these astral adventures
and then coming back into
and then coming back into his
these astral adventures
and then coming back into his body
and then coming back into his body and
feeling
feeling guilty
feeling guilty because
feeling guilty because a
feeling guilty because a lot
feeling guilty because a lot of
feeling guilty because a lot of them
feeling guilty because a lot of them are
amorous
amorous and
feeling guilty because a lot of them are
amorous and there's
amorous and there's his
feeling guilty because a lot of them are
amorous and there's his wife
amorous and there's his wife laying
feeling guilty because a lot of them are
amorous and there's his wife laying in
bed
bed next
bed next to
bed next to him.
Well,
Well, Bob
bed next to him.
Well, Bob then
Well, Bob then Monroe
bed next to him.
Well, Bob then Monroe then
Well, Bob then Monroe then discovered
ways
ways to
ways to create
ways to create altered
ways to create altered states
ways to create altered states of
consciousness
consciousness using
ways to create altered states of
consciousness using uh
consciousness using uh sound
ways to create altered states of
consciousness using uh sound with
consciousness using uh sound with a
slight
slight difference
slight difference in
slight difference in the
slight difference in the frequency
between
between the
slight difference in the frequency
between the two
between the two ears.
slight difference in the frequency
between the two ears. And
between the two ears. And by
slight difference in the frequency
between the two ears. And by by
increasing
increasing decreasing
increasing decreasing the
increasing decreasing the frequency
increasing decreasing the frequency you
can
can alter
increasing decreasing the frequency you
can alter the
can alter the state
increasing decreasing the frequency you
can alter the state of
can alter the state of consciousness
together
together with
together with a
together with a hypnotic
together with a hypnotic state.
together with a hypnotic state. So
together with a hypnotic state. So you
can
can go
together with a hypnotic state. So you
can go into
can go into 10,
together with a hypnotic state. So you
can go into 10, you
can go into 10, you can
together with a hypnotic state. So you
can go into 10, you can go
can go into 10, you can go into
together with a hypnotic state. So you
can go into 10, you can go into 12,
can go into 10, you can go into 12, you
can
can go
can go into
can go into 14
and
and um
about
about any
about any time.
One
One time
about any time.
One time I
One time I did
about any time.
One time I did that,
One time I did that, I
about any time.
One time I did that, I did
One time I did that, I did it
about any time.
One time I did that, I did it out
One time I did that, I did it out of
curiosity
curiosity and
curiosity and I
curiosity and I remember
curiosity and I remember and
curiosity and I remember and then
curiosity and I remember and then he
curiosity and I remember and then he had
a
a whistle.
curiosity and I remember and then he had
a whistle. So
a whistle. So you
curiosity and I remember and then he had
a whistle. So you would
a whistle. So you would be
curiosity and I remember and then he had
a whistle. So you would be having
a whistle. So you would be having these
astral
astral adventures
astral adventures out
astral adventures out in
astral adventures out in different
realms
realms and
astral adventures out in different
realms and universes
and
and you
and you this
and you this sound
and you this sound would
and you this sound would bring
and you this sound would bring you
and you this sound would bring you back.
So
So you're
and you this sound would bring you back.
So you're conditioned
So you're conditioned to
and you this sound would bring you back.
So you're conditioned to come
So you're conditioned to come back
and you this sound would bring you back.
So you're conditioned to come back into
the
the body
the body when
the body when you
the body when you hear
the body when you hear like
the body when you hear like that.
There's
There's a
the body when you hear like that.
There's a sound
There's a sound and
the body when you hear like that.
There's a sound and so
There's a sound and so here
the body when you hear like that.
There's a sound and so here comes
There's a sound and so here comes the
sound
sound and
sound and I
sound and I forget
sound and I forget what
sound and I forget what the
sound and I forget what the adventure
was.
was. I
sound and I forget what the adventure
was. I was
was. I was involved
sound and I forget what the adventure
was. I was involved in
was. I was involved in some
sound and I forget what the adventure
was. I was involved in some dimension
and
and came
and came back
and came back into
and came back into the
and came back into the body
and came back into the body upside
and came back into the body upside down.
came
came into
and came back into the body upside down.
came into the
came into the body
and came back into the body upside down.
came into the body upside
came into the body upside down.
and came back into the body upside down.
came into the body upside down. The
came into the body upside down. The body
was
was laying
was laying this
was laying this side
was laying this side up.
was laying this side up. I
was laying this side up. I went
was laying this side up. I went in
was laying this side up. I went in the
body
body that
was laying this side up. I went in the
body that side.
body that side. I'm
was laying this side up. I went in the
body that side. I'm looking
body that side. I'm looking down
was laying this side up. I went in the
body that side. I'm looking down the
back
back of
back of the
back of the skull
back of the skull at
back of the skull at the
back of the skull at the floor
back of the skull at the floor and
back of the skull at the floor and I
realized
realized I
back of the skull at the floor and I
realized I had
realized I had to
back of the skull at the floor and I
realized I had to back
realized I had to back out,
back of the skull at the floor and I
realized I had to back out, come
realized I had to back out, come around
and
and redock.
So,
So, help
and redock.
So, help me
So, help me God.
and redock.
So, help me God. I
So, help me God. I did.
and redock.
So, help me God. I did. I
So, help me God. I did. I came
and redock.
So, help me God. I did. I came in
So, help me God. I did. I came in the
body
body upside
body upside down.
body upside down. So,
body upside down. So, anyway,
body upside down. So, anyway, there's
various
various techniques.
body upside down. So, anyway, there's
various techniques. It's
various techniques. It's sometimes
body upside down. So, anyway, there's
various techniques. It's sometimes used
for
for past
for past life
for past life regressions.
for past life regressions. Uh-huh.
for past life regressions. Uh-huh. So
there's
there's certain
for past life regressions. Uh-huh. So
there's certain types
there's certain types of
for past life regressions. Uh-huh. So
there's certain types of astral
there's certain types of astral uh
travel
travel in
travel in which
travel in which one
travel in which one goes
travel in which one goes back
travel in which one goes back through
different
different time
travel in which one goes back through
different time dimensions
different time dimensions and
reexperiences
because
because all
reexperiences
because all of
because all of that
reexperiences
because all of that all
because all of that all that
reexperiences
because all of that all that ever
experienced
experienced exists
experienced exists continues
experienced exists continues to
experienced exists continues to exist
within
within a
experienced exists continues to exist
within a certain
within a certain dimension.
What
>> you
>> you want
What
>> you want to
>> you want to take
What
>> you want to take a
>> you want to take a break
What
>> you want to take a break or
>> you want to take a break or you
What
>> you want to take a break or you want
>> you want to take a break or you want to
quit?
>> We
>> We are
>> give
>> give me
>> give me a
>> give me a couple
>> give me a couple just
>> give me a couple just more
>> give me a couple just more and
>> give me a couple just more and then
we'll
we'll we'll
>> give me a couple just more and then
we'll we'll be
we'll we'll be quick.
>> give me a couple just more and then
we'll we'll be quick. I'll
we'll we'll be quick. I'll be
>> give me a couple just more and then
we'll we'll be quick. I'll be give
we'll we'll be quick. I'll be give you
>> give me a couple just more and then
we'll we'll be quick. I'll be give you a
quick
quick answer.
>> Jesus
>> Jesus taught
quick answer.
>> Jesus taught salvation
>> Jesus taught salvation and
quick answer.
>> Jesus taught salvation and Buddha
>> Jesus taught salvation and Buddha taught
enlightenment.
enlightenment. That's
enlightenment. That's the
enlightenment. That's the difference.
>> Oh
>> Oh dear.
enlightenment. That's the difference.
>> Oh dear. Oh
>> Oh dear. Oh dear.
I
I think
I think I
I think I just
I think I just explained
I think I just explained it
I think I just explained it in
I think I just explained it in one
I think I just explained it in one of
the
the books.
I think I just explained it in one of
the books. Um,
salvation
salvation is
salvation is a
salvation is a different
salvation is a different goal
from
from from
salvation is a different goal
from from what
from from what we
salvation is a different goal
from from what we could
from from what we could learn
salvation is a different goal
from from what we could learn through
our
our own
our own kinesiologic
our own kinesiologic research.
our own kinesiologic research. Jesus
Christ
Christ came
our own kinesiologic research. Jesus
Christ came actually
Christ came actually directly
our own kinesiologic research. Jesus
Christ came actually directly from
heaven
heaven with
heaven with no
heaven with no previous
heaven with no previous physical
incarnations
to
to bring
to bring the
to bring the information
to bring the information about
to bring the information about heaven
and
and how
to bring the information about heaven
and how to
and how to reach
to bring the information about heaven
and how to reach it.
and how to reach it. And
to bring the information about heaven
and how to reach it. And he
and how to reach it. And he told
to bring the information about heaven
and how to reach it. And he told and
and how to reach it. And he told and he
told
told us
told us simply
told us simply anything
told us simply anything that
told us simply anything that calibrates
below
below 200
told us simply anything that calibrates
below 200 you
below 200 you won't
told us simply anything that calibrates
below 200 you won't get
below 200 you won't get into
told us simply anything that calibrates
below 200 you won't get into heaven.
That's
That's what
That's what he
That's what he said.
Any
Any mix
That's what he said.
Any mix weak
Any mix weak with
That's what he said.
Any mix weak with kinesiology
Any mix weak with kinesiology will
That's what he said.
Any mix weak with kinesiology will not
get
get you
get you where
get you where you
get you where you want
get you where you want to
get you where you want to go.
uh
uh the
get you where you want to go.
uh the Buddha
uh the Buddha taught
get you where you want to go.
uh the Buddha taught enlightenment
uh the Buddha taught enlightenment which
is
is different.
is different. So
is different. So Jesus
is different. So Jesus Christ
is different. So Jesus Christ is
is different. So Jesus Christ is more
like
like Lotus
is different. So Jesus Christ is more
like Lotus Land
like Lotus Land Buddhism
is different. So Jesus Christ is more
like Lotus Land Buddhism in
like Lotus Land Buddhism in which
is different. So Jesus Christ is more
like Lotus Land Buddhism in which one
like Lotus Land Buddhism in which one of
one's
one's own
one's own spiritual
one's own spiritual energy
one's own spiritual energy doesn't
one's own spiritual energy doesn't have
enough
enough personal
one's own spiritual energy doesn't have
enough personal spiritual
enough personal spiritual energy.
Um
Um and
Um and therefore
Um and therefore the
Um and therefore the savior
Um and therefore the savior by
Um and therefore the savior by your
devotion
um
um his
um his karmic
um his karmic sacrifice
um his karmic sacrifice and
um his karmic sacrifice and infinite
power
is
is the
is the means
is the means by
is the means by which
so
so in
is the means by which
so in Egypt
so in Egypt the
is the means by which
so in Egypt the lord
so in Egypt the lord of
is the means by which
so in Egypt the lord of Osiris
so in Egypt the lord of Osiris the
is the means by which
so in Egypt the lord of Osiris the world
the
the lord
the lord of
the lord of the
the lord of the underworld
the lord of the underworld you
the lord of the underworld you see
the lord of the underworld you see your
heart
heart is
the lord of the underworld you see your
heart is weighed
heart is weighed on
the lord of the underworld you see your
heart is weighed on the
heart is weighed on the scales
the lord of the underworld you see your
heart is weighed on the scales of
justice
in
in heavenly
justice
in heavenly realms
in heavenly realms your
justice
in heavenly realms your witness
in heavenly realms your witness at
justice
in heavenly realms your witness at the
time
time is
is
is the
time is
is the Christ
is the Christ who
time is
is the Christ who speaks
is the Christ who speaks on
time is
is the Christ who speaks on your
is the Christ who speaks on your behalf
that
that you
that you don't
that you don't have
that you don't have you
that you don't have you don't
that you don't have you don't have
enough
enough karmic
that you don't have you don't have
enough karmic merit
enough karmic merit to
that you don't have you don't have
enough karmic merit to enter
the
the fields
the fields of
the fields of heaven
the fields of heaven that
the fields of heaven that would
calibrate
calibrate over
the fields of heaven that would
calibrate over 600
calibrate over 600 on
the fields of heaven that would
calibrate over 600 on your
calibrate over 600 on your own.
the fields of heaven that would
calibrate over 600 on your own. So
calibrate over 600 on your own. So he
like
like speaks
like speaks for
like speaks for you.
like speaks for you. His
like speaks for you. His karmic
like speaks for you. His karmic merit
like speaks for you. His karmic merit is
such
such that
like speaks for you. His karmic merit is
such that he
absolve
absolve some
absolve some of
absolve some of your
absolve some of your karmic
absolve some of your karmic negativity
gets
gets absolved
absolve some of your karmic negativity
gets absolved by
gets absolved by your
absolve some of your karmic negativity
gets absolved by your devotion
gets absolved by your devotion to
absolve some of your karmic negativity
gets absolved by your devotion to him.
The
The Buddha
The Buddha taught
The Buddha taught us
The Buddha taught us a
The Buddha taught us a stricter
The Buddha taught us a stricter more
straight
straight way
The Buddha taught us a stricter more
straight way which
straight way which does
The Buddha taught us a stricter more
straight way which does not
straight way which does not depend
The Buddha taught us a stricter more
straight way which does not depend on
salvation.
salvation. It
salvation. It depends
salvation. It depends on
the
what
what the
what the level
what the level of
what the level of the
what the level of the teacher.
It's
It's a
what the level of the teacher.
It's a straight
It's a straight way
what the level of the teacher.
It's a straight way of
It's a straight way of non-duality.
what the level of the teacher.
It's a straight way of non-duality. Zen
is
is probably
is probably the
is probably the best
is probably the best example
is probably the best example of
is probably the best example of Mahayana
Buddhism.
Uh
Uh it's
Uh it's the
Uh it's the straight
Uh it's the straight way
Uh it's the straight way to
Uh it's the straight way to the
dissolution
dissolution of
Uh it's the straight way to the
dissolution of all
dissolution of all karma
Uh it's the straight way to the
dissolution of all karma altogether
dissolution of all karma altogether to
transcend
transcend uh
transcend uh the
transcend uh the ego
transcend uh the ego altogether.
Of
Of all
transcend uh the ego altogether.
Of all the
Of all the world's
transcend uh the ego altogether.
Of all the world's religions,
Of all the world's religions, you
transcend uh the ego altogether.
Of all the world's religions, you know,
Buddhism
Buddhism has
Buddhism has decreased
Buddhism has decreased the
Buddhism has decreased the least.
Buddhism has decreased the least. If
Buddhism has decreased the least. If you
go,
go, Christianity
Buddhism has decreased the least. If you
go, Christianity in
go, Christianity in the
Buddhism has decreased the least. If you
go, Christianity in the first
go, Christianity in the first century
was
was in
was in the
was in the high
was in the high 900s.
was in the high 900s. In
was in the high 900s. In the
was in the high 900s. In the first
was in the high 900s. In the first three
or
or four
was in the high 900s. In the first three
or four centuries
or four centuries by
was in the high 900s. In the first three
or four centuries by after
or four centuries by after the
was in the high 900s. In the first three
or four centuries by after the council
of
of Nika,
Christianity
Christianity which
of Nika,
Christianity which had
Christianity which had been
of Nika,
Christianity which had been in
Christianity which had been in the
of Nika,
Christianity which had been in the 900s
dropped
dropped to
dropped to 485
or
or something.
I
I think
I think that
I think that was
I think that was the
I think that was the time
I think that was the time in
I think that was the time in which
I think that was the time in which they
introduced
uh
uh perhaps
uh perhaps the
uh perhaps the book
uh perhaps the book of
uh perhaps the book of revelations
uh perhaps the book of revelations in
the
the New
uh perhaps the book of revelations in
the New Testament.
the New Testament. Anyway,
uh perhaps the book of revelations in
the New Testament. Anyway, there
the New Testament. Anyway, there was
uh perhaps the book of revelations in
the New Testament. Anyway, there was a
terrific
terrific crash
Um
the
the fate
the fate of
the fate of Islam
the fate of Islam is
the fate of Islam is uh
the fate of Islam is uh also
uh
uh depending
the fate of Islam is uh also
uh depending on
uh depending on which
the fate of Islam is uh also
uh depending on which branch
uh depending on which branch of
the fate of Islam is uh also
uh depending on which branch of Islam
you're
you're talking
you're talking about.
Buddhism
Buddhism fell
you're talking about.
Buddhism fell the
Buddhism fell the least.
you're talking about.
Buddhism fell the least. Buddhism
Buddhism fell the least. Buddhism in
you're talking about.
Buddhism fell the least. Buddhism in its
uh
uh pure
uh pure expression
at
at the
uh pure expression
at the time
at the time of
uh pure expression
at the time of Buddha
at the time of Buddha was
uh pure expression
at the time of Buddha was 1000
at the time of Buddha was 1000 and
uh pure expression
at the time of Buddha was 1000 and is
still
still in
still in the
still in the high
still in the high 900s.
probably
probably probably
still in the high 900s.
probably probably the
probably probably the least
still in the high 900s.
probably probably the least impaired
probably probably the least impaired by
falsehood
falsehood along
falsehood along the
falsehood along the way.
falsehood along the way. You
falsehood along the way. You know,
um
the
the institutional
the institutional the
the institutional the institutions
the institutional the institutions which
grow
grow around
the institutional the institutions which
grow around the
grow around the original
the institutional the institutions which
grow around the original truth
grow around the original truth then
tends
tends to
tends to obscure
tends to obscure the
tends to obscure the truth.
tends to obscure the truth. The
tends to obscure the truth. The truth
tends to obscure the truth. The truth of
course
course has
tends to obscure the truth. The truth of
course has not
course has not changed
tends to obscure the truth. The truth of
course has not changed and
course has not changed and the
tends to obscure the truth. The truth of
course has not changed and the core
course has not changed and the core of
truth
truth the
truth the essence
truth the essence the
truth the essence the flame
truth the essence the flame of
truth the essence the flame of truth
still
still exists
truth the essence the flame of truth
still exists pure
still exists pure and
truth the essence the flame of truth
still exists pure and undiluted
still exists pure and undiluted within
the
the core
the core of
the core of every
the core of every great
the core of every great religion.
The
The uh
the core of every great religion.
The uh Quran
The uh Quran celebrates
the core of every great religion.
The uh Quran celebrates at
The uh Quran celebrates at 700
the core of every great religion.
The uh Quran celebrates at 700 no
The uh Quran celebrates at 700 no matter
what
what happened
what happened with
what happened with Muhammad
what happened with Muhammad over
what happened with Muhammad over the
time
time over
what happened with Muhammad over the
time over time
>> and
>> and this
>> and this one
>> and this one is
>> and this one is appropriate.
>> and this one is appropriate. I
>> and this one is appropriate. I just
wanted
wanted to
>> and this one is appropriate. I just
wanted to thank
wanted to thank you
>> and this one is appropriate. I just
wanted to thank you for
wanted to thank you for the
>> and this one is appropriate. I just
wanted to thank you for the blessing
wanted to thank you for the blessing of
your
your grace
your grace and
your grace and I
your grace and I think
your grace and I think we
your grace and I think we are
your grace and I think we are finished
with
with the
your grace and I think we are finished
with the questions.
I
I am
I am graced
I am graced by
I am graced by a
I am graced by a thy
I am graced by a thy presence,
I am graced by a thy presence, oh
I am graced by a thy presence, oh Lord.
I'm
I'm graced
I am graced by a thy presence, oh Lord.
I'm graced by
I'm graced by thy
I am graced by a thy presence, oh Lord.
I'm graced by thy presence,
I'm graced by thy presence, oh
I am graced by a thy presence, oh Lord.
I'm graced by thy presence, oh Lord.