So those phenomena are understandable and experienced by others.
You don't have to be afraid of them.
Okay.
Yes.
And the dog has a question too.
I know many of us work with angels or spirit guides or inner self, true self.
Is it possible to calibrate them with the muscle test?
Whether you can calibrate your spirit guides?
I presume you could.
Yes.
Yes, so the muscle test.
You'd have to ask first, do I have permission?
Then you could find out whether they're lower, middle, or upper astral.
That would be a very good thing to know.
Rob the bank, it's okay, you're free of all negative karma.
Okay, master jerk, thank you.
Messages from on high.
So that level of consciousness is possible above 1,000 because they're not human beings?
It's possible within a human body, yes.
Yes.
The human limit is 1,000.
It's not advisable, but it happens, yeah.
But for spiritual realm, they can be exceed 1,000.
For spiritual what?
Spiritual beings, they can exceed 1,000.
Spiritual beings?
Like angels, archangels.
Oh, yes.
I said like archangels, I calibrated them 50,000 and up.
Now, you forget we're talking about logarithmic.
So 50,000 is a power of such immensity, as I always say experientially,
if a passing archangel, in response to your...
to your prayer, has a passing thought about you, it can blow you out for 30 years.
Silent, unable to speak, and the mind forever silent.
30 years to speak of it.
There's nothing but a passing response of an archangel who heard,
if there's a god, I ask him to help me.
It's the slightest thought, instantly.
So in the spiritual realm, they still have the range of consciousness from zero to infinity?
Yes, we get that actually all of them go up to infinity.
Within this domain, they were calibrated.
1,000, but in the absolute spiritual reality, they go to infinity.
Infinity.
So it's possible to calibrate them with the muscle gas, it can be done?
You can ask what it is, yeah.
Okay.
Yes, we got, in fact, the next book has to do, the various names for god
and what they really indicate, and they all indicate infinity, yeah.
Is this for you or the dog?
That's for you.
Yes.
Hi, David and bro.
So, animals, they use them as assistants.
I keep on being guided and have visions of doing, using dogs as helping humans with addictions.
Oh, yeah?
So it would be, instead of for blind people, it would be for addictions.
What's your take on that?
I don't know just how you would work it into it.
You know, they're very valuable in nursing homes.
I noticed the nursing homes that had dogs were much more energized,
more, higher energy than those that were owned by commercial companies and dogs weren't allowed.
Those that were easily run by some spiritual order seemed to be more humanistic.
And dogs would run back and forth, laboratory retrievers.
It seemed to be a good part of the healing process for geriatric.
We know that holding a dog or a cat, having a pet will lower your blood pressure.
The best cure for hypertension is to have a dog like that.
And for anxiety, too, you know, anxiety, depression and lowering blood pressure.
So they have a healing effect.
Well, look, it calibrates to 504 or whatever it is.
And 504, you know, is almost like a healing energy.
He is a healing, she is a healing dog.
But, you know, most addictions come from codependency.
You know, people trying to find their self-worth outside themselves.
I'm just I know there's something.
In booze, yeah.
But as in, I know there's something that is with that.
So I thought maybe you might have a take on it, but I'll meditate on it.
I don't know what it's used to be in the tools of work.
Yeah. Also, second question.
For those of us, I'm rarely in my body, I always astral project out all the time.
For those that are being attacked by dark entities, I know there's bringing the light.
There's connecting the light.
There's bringing the light.
There's connecting strongly with spirit.
I mean, any other, because every time you find a way to stop coming in,
they find a different way to come back, to short circus, short circus, short circuitousness.
Those are all psychic phenomena that I'm really not an expert in.
What you feel is attack is coming from the collective unconscious.
Right.
It's not coming from an out there-ness.
It's coming from an in here-ness.
So that takes you out of the victim and attack-y and attacker.
That protest is coming from one's, from the collective unconscious, see?
So it's within you.
So the only thing that needs to be answered is that what is within you,
the question that's being raised within you.
And then the seeming psychic attack disappears, disappears.
However, there's traditional spiritual techniques of which most people are aware
to try to handle the phenomena.
But those are psychic phenomena, which I'm not an expert in.
I'm not an expert in that.
Okay, all right, thank you.
I think I tried white light a couple of times and didn't do anything, so I had the hell with it.
He still stole my car keys, you know what I'm saying?
White light and all.
No, he stole my white light.
Come back here.
Yeah, my question is, I assume that, well, it's proven that the spirit and the ego are not in,
they're kind of separate.
Separate from each other?
They're not separate from each other.
As you see up there, you have the world of form, but the world of form exists within a greater field,
almost like a gravitational field called spirit, you know?
They coexist, but in different dimensions.
So you might say one is a different dimension than the other,
a higher frequency vibration dimension.
So when we calibrate levels of consciousness, you're almost talking about dimensions.
The energy field of this doesn't really live here, nor is it even accessible there.
It's not accessible until you get to here.
So how can the ego, say, you're an evil person, a murderer, or whatever,
how can that affect your spirit even after the ego dies?
I don't get the question.
Well, as far as karma goes, and I guess what we do now affects our karma,
how can that be if the ego and the...
I guess it almost seems like you're saying that the ego can somehow affect your karma
when I thought it would be more of a spiritual thing.
All right, hold on.
I understand the question.
You're confusing the ego with the physicality.
Is that what you're saying?
Yeah.
No, ego and physicality are not one and the same thing.
Part of the ego is to think that you're the physical, just like it thinks you're the mind,
and it believes that, however, it's not a fact.
So that which affects the ego then would affect one's karmic propensities, yeah.
It would affect one's calibrated levels of consciousness,
and at the point of death when you go over, you would go over at whatever...
Your spirit goes over at whatever level that you've achieved in this lifetime,
but it has nothing to do with the body.
Okay.
Yeah.
It has nothing to do with the body.
Thank you.
You can give the body away.
Yeah.
We're trying this as a form of seeing what is really on people's minds,
and then instead of what's on my mind that I want to lecture about.
We're going to take a break at 3, yeah?
Oh, well, we'll take a break at 3, yeah.
Go ahead.
Hi.
Yeah?
This is the first time I've been here.
This morning, you used the word guru.
You mentioned the guru, that as you get closer...
The historic function of the so-called guru, yeah.
Yeah.
My question centers around that.
Is the guru external or internal, and what should my relationship be with the guru?
The guru is a terminology, a classic terminology.
It made you go strong with kinesiology until the 1960s.
Since that time, the very term guru makes you go weak, as does the term baba.
Around in the 60s, it was taken over,
and glamorized, and commercialized, and exploited, and therefore, in the current book, or the
last book I did, I would check every page of kinesiology, and I would get, not to use
the term guru, that it had taken on a distorted meaning in our society, sort of a glamorized
distortion of what the true meaning is.
The source of spiritual knowledge is the state of your own spiritual evolution, which tends
to pull to it that which is appropriate for its own growth and development, tends to attract
or be drawn to, or to pull to it that for which it is appropriate, yeah?
So the correct term is teacher.
Yeah.
Nope.
It's super narrow in its own organization, and it has a considerable downside, and some
people that calibrated at one time in a relatively decent level no longer do it, and it had to
do with guruism, the glamor, the seduction, power over people, having followers, fame
and fortune, and 98 rulers' voices, and all that kind of thing, so those gurus who did
not survive as well.
none of them were enlightened. None of them were in the 700s or anything. They were almost
all in the 500s and still sufficient ego left as to be fallible. Once one has gone over
600, 700, then the likelihood of that is unlikely. In fact, the only time in history it ever
happened was Muhammad, who calibrated at 700 at the time he dictated the Koran, got it
as a transmission from, he thought, the Archangel Gabriel. Then at age 35 or age 38, I forget,
age 35, I think, he suddenly shifted major and took up the sword and calibrated about
135 and became the killer of infidels. He killed first the Jews and then the non-Islamic
people. So they're the most serious one.
In history, it was that one because he took up the sword and that civilization tends to
try to survive and kill others with a sword. So that was a grave drop in calibrated consciousness
that's affected all of mankind and still to this day is at the seat of conflict on this
planet and will be the cause of many more thousands of deaths, many more thousands of
deaths. A grave spiritual error.
Subtitles by the Amara.org community
to succumb to the sword. You see when Jesus Christ said I didn't come to bring you peace,
I came with a sword, he's talking about the sword of truth. Not the sword of death and
dividing people to the good and the bad and killing the bad. So there was some defect
in my head, either that or that which is antithetical to God found a weakness and preyed upon it.
It's a very serious question to people who are interested in consciousness research and
spiritual.
and religious history what has happened and why has it happened so the answer to
grew then is you want a calibrated pathway and a calibrated teacher there
are integrals that are integrals people think higher is better higher is not
better what what's best is what's best for you also any one of the levels one
can transcend all of them it's better to be integrally in the 200s
then non integrally in the 400s or 500 you see to the fitfully do the course of
miracles you know is one thing it would be better to just you know make it make
a decision that you're going to forgive everything and everyone all the time no
matter what and stick with that so just sticking with one thing like this you
can shoot right up and suddenly find yourself in a divine state so integrity
that means commitment to the
teaching the teacher merely reflects back to you your own capacity can only
be back to you so it's like a mirror so you see that which you really are begin
to sense it the teacher then operates also on a vibrational level that the
karmic vibration and frequency of the teacher is transmitted by what do you
call that where one thing begins to vibrate another enmeshment entrainment
yes entrainment that the aura picks up the frequency of the vibration of that in
carries it karmically so whatever happened in my lifetime at age 3 when the
first rather dazzling phenomena happened to occur was undoubtedly picked up you
know in many a previous lifetime and I picked up the frequency of something
extremely advanced at least over 850 because that's what came up to be
resolved so you see the transmission of that frequency in the vibration also
they'll teacher is supposed to contextualize
Because the purpose of the teacher is to contextualize truth in such a way that it's comprehensible.
To explain it, to represent it, to send forth the inspirational energy that makes it comprehensible.
Otherwise it sounds like nonsense, you understand?
To just speak from the inner knowingness of what is known would be incomprehensible.
So how to make it comprehensible?
So the books I've done and the teaching I do, I try to buttress it with so much explanation
that it can't be misrepresented later.
So much argument has to do with what did so-and-so mean in the year 450 B.C. when he said so-and-so.
Well, who knows?
First of all, he was talking in a foreign language to a bunch of foreigners.
And it got translated, first came down verbally, then translated into Greek and then to Aramaic
and then into Sanskrit and then back into English.
So who knows what he said?
The only way you can tell right now is check your kinesiology.
Did he mean this when he said this or that?
And so that brings up an intuitive knowing and you realize the capacity to understand
that it's already existent within yourself.
And all you need is confirmation.
I came to run a sword, does that mean to kill people with or the sword of truth, you know?
So you have to ask through kinesiology, are we supposed to kill infidels?
We gotta know.
You're supposed to kill untruth, oh, how do you kill untruth?
You don't kill untruth, what you do is you repeat the truth.
So you, you cheer vanilla and it doesn't mean you have to hate chocolate, that's what I
would say.
You become committed to the truth, integrous, in commitment to the truth.
And that's how truth becomes established, not by trying to slay non-truth.
You can't establish truth by slaying non-truth.
Okay?
All right, should we take a break and then we can conclude?
Should we take a short break?
Yeah.
All right, let's do that and then we'll conclude.
And I'll sign any books anybody has, I can't answer every question people can conjure up.
So, do you have any questions?
Huh?
Only if you have some, this is for my friend back.
Only if you have any specific advice for my spiritual team.
You follow what you're attracted to because.
That's going to be the most valid and meaningful thing to you.
I have found myself unemployed as a teacher and I have gone back to get my graduates.
So what happens is that you begin to affect the world by virtue of that which you have
become, not what you talk about.
Because the world is full of people who talk about peace and the minute they leave the
room. have already gone.
They've already started a corruption by taking a positionality and as we pointed out, that
war is the consequence of the natural prevailing state of truth and peace is the natural prevailing
state of truth and war is nothing but the consequence of the absence of truth.
Okay?
So that which you have become is what is influencing the world, not what you talk about because
talk is cheap and goes on around the clock.
Okay?
And it's worthless.
Also we demonstrate with kinesiology that, where's my witness here?
What percentage of free speech is fallacious?
Free speech that everybody lauds and gets on the soapbox and parades and all this.
Let's see.
Free speech is over 80% fallacious.
82, 84, 86, 88, 89, 90, 91, 94, 95, 100.
94, 98, 99.
About 98% of free speech is completely fallacious, illogical, stupid, comes out of all the positionalities
up there.
They're all promotions to develop one side or another, seduce you into buying a product.
Everything is fallacious.
So you watch an advertisement that tells you how good something is, it's a lie right off
the bat.
He's not telling you how good it is.
He's an actor.
As they'll be in advertising.
Okay?
If you want to sell something, have legitimacy up there because legitimacy has an energy
to it.
And you can't hire an actor to get up there and say what somebody else's experience is
and expect that the audience is going to be convinced.
Because the other thing we discovered is that everybody unconsciously realizes when they're
being lied to.
It's a fact that everybody unconsciously knows when they're being lied to.
Resist.
Most people know they're being lied to over 98% of the time.
You realize everybody realizes they're being lied to all the time.
That's why the endless talking is so unconvincing because it doesn't mean anything.
It's just filling up space.
And you see, if you want, somebody's going to convince you that they're, I used to sell
vacuum cleaners, you see, door to door.
Well, our competition was Electrolux and I sold the Kirby.
Well, I was convinced that the Kirby vacuum cleaner was the best vacuum cleaner in the
world.
So when I went into a woman and I said, I stand behind this, that the Kirby is the best
vacuum cleaner in the world, she would say, oh, she was impressed.
You know what I'm saying?
I'm not reading her some sales pitch.
I was convinced the Kirby was the best vacuum cleaner and would clean your carpet better
than Electrolux.
Please do not mention the term Electrolux around the Kirby man.
So what I'm talking about is the power of integrity.
The power of integrity that speaks for itself.
You can't substitute by having an actor come on and pretend that he's giving a speech about
that which is integrity.
So a person who really believes in peace creates peace, and a person who talks about it almost
inevitably creates war.
Thank you very much.
I appreciate it.
In New York City, on Madison Avenue, that Jesus and Buddha were just astrals, and frankly,
he was higher than Jesus.
When you hear somebody say they're higher than Jesus, take off.
In the meantime, as long as you're higher than Jesus, would you mind curing this arm?
It doesn't work very good.
Let's see if you can do miracles on demand, okay?
Usually, the way it goes is for $3,000, they'll give you a weekend course on how to heal stuff.
Give you a mantra and some googly goop to do.
I just want to tell you thank you very much.
All right.
No one's ever existed higher than Jesus.
First of all, the human nervous system can't handle that.
Anything over 700 is already painful and difficult.
I've been reading a lot this year.
I see.
You've been reading the same author here, huh?
Yes.
Between you and The Course in Miracles.
Oh, yeah.
Yeah, well, I love The Course in Miracles.
And I knew Helen, you know, and Bill Thuford.
And love is letting go of fear.
What was that, Doctor?
If I could just let go of my ego.
Right.
And then we started the Second Attitudinal Healing Center in the United States in New York.
It's a clinic there.
And the whole staff from Tiburon, the Attitudinal Healing Center there,
Jerry Jampolsky, and the whole crew came to my house back east.
And we started the Second Attitudinal Healing Center because I had a big clinic there.
So people with hopeless diseases came in and we did Course in Miracles Attitudinal Healing there.
And the eventual understanding of the group was that it didn't matter whether, you know,
you got cured or you didn't get cured.
Because if you really did The Course in Miracles, it was irrelevant.
And the minute you became irrelevant, it disappeared.
Of course.
Thank you.
Please, are you familiar with the Urantia book?
If you would like, I have a copy I'll give to you.
Oh, yeah, I don't need it.
Okay.
I don't, first of all, I don't read anything.
All the people who want to give me books and especially have me calibrate them, I'll tell you an inside secret.
I don't read anything.
Okay.
If I don't know it already, then what would be the point of reading it?
It's just not physically possible.
It's not physically possible to read all the books that are said.
We have piles of them all over.
And it's usually a hopeful author who wants you to calibrate them.
It's just not physically possible to answer all the mail, answer all the phone calls, the emails, and the letters.
However, we read them all.
And in my own mind, I try to figure it out.
I figure a way in which this can be answered and bring it to the writer's awareness.
But there's no physical way one can do it.
It's just not possible.
You know, if you've got 100,000 readers, how are you going to strike up a personal correspondence with 100,000 people?
You understand?
And they practically never send you a stamped self-addressed envelope.
So if there was any hope at all that I was going to say, okay, at the bottom, forget it.
Because I do not have the time to look up your phone number, your address, write it, go get a stamp, and take it to the mailbox.
You understand?
You have to put yourself in the other person's place and say, what would facilitate their being able to respond?
You know, if you've got a self-addressed stamped envelope that says, the question is two sentences long.
It says, check yes or no, you might get an answer.
But that's about all.
If it's more than one or two sentences, you're just running on.
You know, sometimes I get a 14-page letter handwritten, God bless them, and I can see the work that went into it.
All about their mother-in-law and their grief and all about the children and the marriages they came in and out of.
And I can't find where the question is in there.
So you see, this reason you signed the letter, it says, son's okay to me.
He didn't send it back to them.
I had a question.
I can't seem to get past the guilt that I have over mistakes I made with my son, who's now 32.
And I keep blaming myself.
No, you probably deserved it.
That's what you get for being a rotten parent in a previous lifetime.
Nice.
See what it's like.
I've been working on this with spiritual principles.
I'm trying and trying.
That agony, I just can't get past it.
So what you have a memory of is a perception.
Don't forget that all memory is only of a perception.
You don't remember what actually happened because you don't even know what happened.
You only have a perception.
What you remember is your perception of the event.
That takes it out of reality because the reality puts it back in a karmic overall context.
In which it obviously made sense and was due to happen.
See?
And you just got pulled into it for a moment.
For me.
You're stuck with the guilt.
You don't want the guilt.
I want to get rid of the guilt.
Oh, okay.
You have to be willing to surrender the pain.
See, I told you about what holds the ego in place is the payoff it gets.
Okay, it's not guilt.
It's the payoff of the pain and suffering you get out of the guilt.
You have to be willing to surrender that.
Yeah, you need somebody sort of spiritually sophisticated to work with you on this.
But you can undo that guilt, see?
You can undo that guilt.
It's just a trap that the ego is trying to hold up your spiritual progress.
You know, and it's telling you that guilt is good for what?
What is the guilt good for?
Penance?
Undo the error?
What?
She deserves better.
You do deserve better.
I agree.
So, maybe.
You've got to be willing to surrender it to God.
In the end, you've got to be willing to surrender everything, including self-judgment.
This is only the opinion of your ego, and it's worth a nickel, if that much.
My guess is the guy deserved it, and it's just payback time.
And now you can say, I have served thee well, young man.
Now you know what it's like to be neglected and kicked around, you little rotten butt.
Remember the last time you did that to me?
Try some past life recall on it and see what you can do with that.
Okay?
You'll get a whole story.
You'll just experience the whole story.
When you see the whole story, you'll say, ha, ha.
I don't feel guilty about that.
Self-hypnosis is the way to go to learn past life recall.
Self-hypnosis is very easy to learn, and you're not giving your power away to the hypnotist.
He's just teaching you the technique.
And then you decide when you want to put yourself under and look for a certain answer.
And the answers are very simple.
They're not complicated.
And almost always what you intuit or suspect went on.
That is what went on.
You were right all along.
I must have been a son of a gun in some lifetime.
You hear that often.
And by golly, almost always they were a son of a gun in that lifetime.
I have a question.
When I'm here in this room, things are a lot clearer.
And then when I go home, things get fuzzy again.
And I get pulled into my ego.
I mean, my ego is stronger.
You get pulled back into the details of the world.
Right.
When you're here, you see there isn't any problem.
When you get home, the ego gets seduced.
It gets seduced back into the world.
What I need, what I want, is more light.
Well, that comes from spiritual endeavor.
You know, spiritual work is usually relatively long.
It has very abrupt periods where suddenly it can go up or down in a very dramatic fashion.
But generally, it's more an orientation of your life.
So if you just continue on a spiritual orientation, these things all will resolve themselves.
You say, God, I don't see why this goes on.
And then forget about it.
Surrender to God.
And as you're driving along, all of a sudden you get, ah, hmm.
And then you see it differently, and now it's resolved.
Being around spiritual groups tends to advance your field of consciousness.
Just because the collective aura is sufficient, then it uplifts you.
And all of a sudden you see it differently.
You know, even if you're not doing the Course in Miracles, if you're hanging out with people who do,
you suddenly get the kind of answer that they know.
And you get it osmotically.
They say, if you don't get it yourself, then hang out with the group and you'll get it by osmosis.
And that's correct.
Count on osmosis until you get there.
Thank you.
Everybody loves to be of help in some way.
Dr. Hawkins, I had this question before the break.
You started off the talk about the lady with the gallbladder surgery.
Well, I'm scheduled for gallbladder removal surgery next week for gallstones.
Yeah.
And my question just for me personally was, should I do that or try some alternative?
I've got friends that want me to drink like gallons of apple juice and cups of olive oil.
Yeah, you get that homeopathic remedy deal.
I can't really tell you about it because I've never tried drinking all that olive oil and stuff to get rid of gallstones.
I don't know.
I can't really give you an answer to that.
All right.
Yeah.
I don't know from clinical experience that it's worked.
However, you know, in the alternate health field, there's a lot of beliefs that frankly are more beliefs than reality.
We don't want to ask it.
I was wondering if maybe you could expand on something that you said about sometimes the messenger from God is that maybe try some sort of drug or the doctor might be right.
For me, I thought when the doctor kept trying things for this weird pain and finally came up with abdominal ultrasound and found this, that was probably what I ought to do.
They fracture it with ultrasound.
So it's really relatively easy to go through.
A friend of mine, a fellow professional at the girls' ranch just went through it.
And they use a high ultrasound and it fractures the thing and there's really nothing to it.
So it's probably safer than drinking all that olive oil, which I'm telling you.
Thank you very much.
Olive oil and red pepper and squirrel dung or something, you know.
I think it's probably lethal.
I don't know.
I think I'd rather get my ultrasound.
Thank you.
All right.
You see, the doctor has responsibility.
He's got responsibility for your recovery.
The people who hand out all this crazy free advice don't have the responsibility.
So when it doesn't work and you croak, they're not answerable.
So I'd rather have a doctor who's answerable.
I heard that you're in the process of writing a book.
I'm always in the process of writing a book.
I've got about four of them at the moment.
Do you know when that's going to be coming out?
Oh, I don't.
Maybe a year.
Okay.
Thank you.
How's the weather?
I already answered my questions.
I'm just playing.
Thank you.
Yeah.
I don't have a question.
I just want to hug.
A lot of times, spiritual questions, what happens is the field, when you put it out
to the field, the field answers it.
And it answers it through annoyingness, not through a question-answer response.
All right.
Thank you.
question, answer, response, but all of a sudden you just sort of know it.
You know, a person will say, what should I do with my life? Should I do this or that?
All of a sudden, just suddenly a knowingness sort of comes out of the field.
It's really a neat way to live. Some people live that way all the time.
And they're still alive.
Is it true that our journey
on the Earth is completed once we're over 600 levels?
Let's see.
600, no, you don't have to come back. Let's see.
600 or over, you don't have to come back. Resist. Thank you.
It's an option. So like our
spiritual struggle or our will is used only below
600? Beyond that we don't know? Well, the struggle is
unconditional love, see? Unconditional love
is approximately the level of celestial realm.
It's heavenly, see? So Jesus said once you get to
unconditional love, you don't have any problem.
And the reason 12-step program is so attractive
is because it takes you over 500 to actual 540.
What does unconditional love mean? It means a guy is in the program,
he's doing well, he has a slip, he goes over, he drives his truck
over four kids, robs a bank, and blows up the house.
He goes back to AA, what do they think they say? They say, George glad to see you back.
That's the literal fact.
Glad to see you back, George. All that, they don't have anything to do with that.
No opinion on outside matters.
Is there any sign that we know that we are safe at a certain level, that we won't
be falling again, back to ego? Well actually you're always safe by virtue of your
spiritual commitment, you're always safe.
like that.
What's safe has to do with
being committed to unconditional
love and endeavoring.
You see, Krishna said,
those who commit themselves to me,
even if they're following wild
and crazy pathways,
are still mine.
So the devotion itself,
the devotion itself, is the commitment.
So people worship divinity
in many seemingly strange
and bizarre ways.
But as Krishna said,
it doesn't make any difference, because if you're not
mine, by cranking the prayer bell,
you are worshiping me, then you are
worshiping me. It has nothing to do with what's
written on the doorbell.
It's this drink of Coca-Cola. You didn't notice that
until after you cranked it.
In other words,
it's one's devotion that empowers
the pathway.
It's devotion.
Can you talk about spiritual vision and spiritual mission?
Some leaders, they claim that
they receive a mission of doing
something.
Well, that's only a way of describing
what you intuit as
the most committed thing for you
to be doing.
If
one's experience is beneficial
to others, then you share it because it's beneficial
to others. Like Bill Wilson
shared his sobriety with the world.
Not because he needed any
ego boost out of it. He couldn't have cared less.
But it's like an obligation.
You found the way out, so you
share the way out with others.
That's what a true teacher does.
Just share what they know.
There's no gain.
Nothing to be paid. Nobody owes you anything.
Is it highly individual,
that kind of desire to share
what they know?
I think it's very common.
For the 400s, everybody wants
to share the intellect, what they learned.
Science is full of that.
500s, they want to share
the lovingness.
540 becomes more unconditional.
600, they want to
explain higher states of consciousness
and what they mean and signify.
What do they signify for all of us
as human beings?
He says, the world that you think
needs correction out there doesn't even exist.
To realize that, all you have to do
is surrender everything to God.
That's profound, wonderful
spiritual advice. All you need is
two sentences. You don't have to
read the rest of the book. If you get two sentences
correctly, you can throw the rest of the book away.
laughter
Yeah, surrender everything to God
and forget it.
Except that you've got to know
an awful lot before you get to simplicity.
That's the problem.
Before you get to simplicity,
you have to have already a PhD
in the whole thing, right?
If the future
has already happened, can we ask about that
with kinesiology?
No.
We're talking about it as a
potentiality at the microcosm.
Yeah, yeah.
Well, no, the potentiality is not outside the world of form.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Well, what's the problem then?
It's still within the world of form.
The quantum mechanics is not outside the world of form.
It's outside the Newtonian paradigm of probability.
Right.
But it is still subject to the mathematics
and quantum mechanics within probability theory.
So likelihood, you're talking about potentiality and likelihood.
As far as certainty, no.
The field of consciousness itself doesn't register anything until it's in the bosom.
anything until it already is. So that which has reality has the reality of existence.
So only that which is so has become has existence. Everything else is a potentiality. You can
calibrate the likelihood of a potentiality, but that's not a certainty.
Okay, thank you.
Your books are at home.
What should I do?
Just sign it anywhere.
Sign someplace someplace?
Yeah, anywhere.
Thank you.
Is it possible to, like, experience unconditional love for, say, three days at one point in
your life and be totally blissed out of it and then kind of lose it because you're really
not up there yet?
Yeah, well, you know, it comes in fits and starts. And before people have permanent,
serious shifts of consciousness, very often they have flashes. They have flashes of intuitive
awareness.
It may not persist, but they've gotten the glimpse of what's to come. And suddenly they
feel a light within themselves. Or you're walking through the woods and suddenly all
sound comes to a stop. It's like a magical stillness. Those are the moments that tell
you what's ahead.
Oh, okay.
And when they happen, then be forewarned and tell your friends that you take spirituality
seriously.
As long as...
And you have to give them advice. If I sit there blissed out, whether to feed you or
not, see?
Okay. Well, as long as it's out there.
If you're blissed out, do you want me to feed your nut?
Oh, yeah. Yeah.
You do, huh?
Yeah. I'll stick around a while longer.
All right. Good luck.
Okay. Thanks.
I don't believe in leaving it up to the relatives. That's why I wrote...
David, could you sign my book for me, please?
Yeah.
I have a question. It echoes more or less what this lady said. Inexplicable experiences
where you suddenly transcend from where you think you are to another point with no reason
for it. I was driving from Glasgow to Auburn, which is going for the ferry out to Hebrides.
And suddenly, I was playing classical music. And I was playing this Liebeström, just to
keep me... Normally, I have my nose to the steering wheel and my hand on the steering
wheel like this. My nose on the windscreen, my hand on the steering wheel, because I'm
always very tense when I'm driving. But I was thinking about a past experience linked to
this music. And all of a sudden, I became aware of it. Total awareness around me. It
was beautiful. It was really beautiful. And when I was looking at the mountains and the
trees, instead of seeing them or not seeing them like I was doing before, they were suddenly
all in my vision without me even looking at them. And my driving was so totally focused
but so easy. And that condition lasted for, oh, maybe a day or so. And I just wondered
what, you know, how would you explain it. You've just actually said there, I just wondered
if you could add anything to why it happens to you out of the blue like that.
It's a why, and I can't answer why questions.
Oh, okay.
It's a preliminary. So it's like you get a glimpse of where you're going.
You get a glimpse. And then that really strengthens our spiritual resolve. And once you've experienced
that, you're going to be satisfied with anything less.
In the midst of that, there was a message also. It was like, love is all. Love is transcendental.
And love is eternal. And that, to me, was a message that I had to take away from that
experience. And when I was sitting on the ferry, I seemed to be aware of people who
were actually in trouble around me. But being able to empathize with them, it gave me a
different feeling.
Oh, yeah.
Normally, I would have thought, oh, that person's a nuisance. Look at them jumping up and down.
Yeah, yeah. You entered into that, like a oneness, a twinness, you see.
Yeah. So is that something that just shows you the door sort of thing?
Yeah, the door opened, yeah.
Yeah, okay. That's good to know.
From that point on, you'll never be satisfied with anything less.
I'm very happy with that. Thank you.
That's the point of it.
Now you see what can feed you. It won't sell out for anything less.
Don't worry. I'll keep feeding you, Mom.
And what was in that blueberry pie you gave her?
I don't know, but I want to go back to Glasgow and see if I can have a slice.
And feed her the same pie.
Thank you.
I have a question about the now.
Yes.
I believe you said in the now, there are no problems.
In the present, yeah.
In the present. But what if in the present, I mean, not to use a very horrible, but what
if in the present, I'm being raped? So right now, I'm being raped, and right now, I'm being
raped.
What's the problem?
In resisting it, in seeing it a certain way, it's going to be hard to see, but it is only
resistance that creates any suffering. The minute you surrender it, it's no longer suffering.
It's like you're out of the scene and you're witnessing it. There's nobody there to suffer.
That's a projection of the ego. There's no one present to suffer. That's an imagination.
So you can transcend the situation.
People have been raped and have been in the midst of being murdered and literally did
go out of the experience and witnessed it and came out of it unscathed. But that would
be a relatively spiritually advanced person who would know to do that, to merely surrender
and let it happen and don't even resist it.
And when burglars and all kill people, it's always for resistance. Housebreakers are the
most dangerous of all people.
And they will tell you, I want you to do this. I want you to bring me that coffee pot. I
want to see if there's anything in there. If you say no, they'll kill you because they're
in like a megalomaniac state. Any no will get you killed. That was typical of Saddam's
sons and him also. If you even looked at him like you didn't like him, he had you killed.
All right. So the ego then of that person will not brook enough.
Consequently, to survive, you transcend it and say yes to everything that may happen.
Because if you say yes to everything that happens, suffering is not possible. I've gone
through surgery, a lot of anesthesia, and I'll tell you, the minute there was a moment
of resistance to the cutting and to the pain, it was agony beyond description, severe agony.
And one had to instantly let go of resisting it. And as you became one with what the world
would call pain, the pain disappeared and you let go.
You transcend the body and you're the witness of the phenomena. So it would be a quick psychic
reading. You probably got one ten-thousandth of a second to read it. If this guy's a person
who's going to say, well, brook no, no, then you better go with it and try to transcend
it because otherwise it will kill you. And then it takes care of that karmic debt if he
does. So it's okay either way, you know what I'm saying? It's okay, and I said, well,
I'm a survivor, it's okay, I paid that one off, you know?
And then I just wanted to know, what does the group calibrate at? I don't think I heard
what...
I think we calibrated at 435 and let's see how far we went today. We have permission
to do this right. The group as a whole increased in consciousness from the beginning to the
end of the lecture by 10 points, 11, 12, 13, 13 points, which is okay for an afternoon.
You do that.
You do that every day for a week.
Thank you very much.
Thank you for the question. I tell you, the mind can think up the darnedest question,
can't it? But that's a reality question, how do you handle a life-threatening crisis?
How do you handle a life-threatening crisis? As I said before, if you're about to be assassinated,
what you do is you go...
I don't know if I really have a question, but it seems like...
When you're on this path, it's like you open a bunch of doors and then you go through them
and then there's more doors and it's like you just keep going through them and then
you sort of have a threshold for a while, like that's as much as you can take.
Yeah.
And then is that the nervous system or is that just integrating this or...
I don't know that I can really answer that, but it is characteristic. It's characteristic.
Also in meditation.
In meditation, you'll go into a great state and then you come to a door and the door is usually one of fear.
Right.
Yeah, because at this point you're leaving the known for the unknown.
And you either walk through the door, if you walk through the door of fear, then the fear disappears
and you come into a new state of even greater joy or ecstasy.
Right, right.
Which again takes you to another door which again...
Is another unknown.
Yeah, another unknown.
Right.
And of course you remember the training in Zen, walk straight ahead no matter what.
No matter what.
Thank you.
That's perfect.
Yeah.
I just want to say thank you. Your work has had just a very profound effect on my life.
It's been awesome. So thank you.
Thank you.
Could you just sign for a picture?
Picture, yes.
$70.
I got some change.
I told you I was up in the Himalayas.
The girl has this llama.
I said, can we take your picture?
And she said, that'll be a dollar.
So every time since then I said, that'll be a dollar.
Yes.
My question's embarrassing and I'd rather have asked it in private.
But is it necessary to have a period of celibacy to get to a more ascended state?
Is it necessary?
Hmm.
It's not necessary.
We've never really talked about that with the group, what happens with the sexual drive.
See?
But it has vicissitudes and we've never just gotten around to the subject.
When you're going through a period of rising consciousness, don't forget the kundalini energy is surging up.
And it's the energy of life.
Now, as the energy of life hits the chakras one after another, there may be a time when it hits the sexual chakra and one is intensely sexual for a while, insatiably.
You have to breathe the energy out.
Breathe the energy up and keep on surrendering and working your way through it and then it'll disappear.
I've seen people professionally where the energy got caught in that chakra and I sent them to energy balancing people to move the energy out of that chakra.
It was like stuck in there and how to breathe it up, etc.
Then there's periods where one is so unidentified with the physical that the physicality doesn't respond in that way.
There's not that much identification with the body.
There is a period where, I would say in the mid-500s, where everyone is extraordinarily beautiful and everybody is attracted to you.
You're in love with everybody and people are not used to that kind of love.
So what they're experiencing is spiritual love and they misinterpret it as personal love.
That's probably how some gurus get into problems because spiritual seekers have written books about that.
Gurus, I went to bed with it or something like it's called.
Anyway, it has to do with neither one of them having understood what it's about.
So the energy of life itself can energize that state of joy which may almost become semi-manic for a period of time.
So people may go through a phase of hypersexuality.
They may also go through a period of detachment.
So as one detaches from all of that, it stops running.
It isn't whether it's there or not.
It's whether it runs you.
And then at certain levels, it only crosses your mind like thinking does if you wish it to do so.
If you wish it.
It doesn't run you against your will.
It's like physical appetite.
You can either eat or not eat.
You can either choose or not choose.
So you're not run by it.
Periods of celibacy, I've never read any books about it.
But my feeling about it would be that it's inevitable.
Anybody seriously committed may go through long periods, even permanent.
It's just not interesting anymore.
There is a state where you can feel completely fulfilled.
You see, a lot of sexuality is coming from I need the outlet.
I need the orgasm.
I need whatever.
At a certain state, you are so complete you don't need anything, including sex.
And people have to remind you to eat, in fact.
Because there is no need for anything.
There is a feeling of being complete and total every instant all the time.
So you don't feel hungry until you start to eat.
Once you start to eat, now you're hungry.
Then if the phone rings and you have to put it down, you answer the phone,
you don't miss not having the rest of the dinner.
Because you see, you go from complete to complete to complete.
And because you're complete, you don't need anything.
So it would be like a pleasurable...
A pleasurable suggestion.
Watching a movie or going horseback riding or going swimming.
It would be a wonderful thing.
You say, yes, it would be wonderful to do that.
But you see you're at choice.
The difference is you're at choice and you're not coming from need or drivenness.
There we go.
Just a quick statement and then a quick question.
I just want to make the observation, and then perhaps I can speak for the group,
that it's very rare in our lifetimes that we get the opportunity to be with someone
who is the very best at what they do.
This is one of those opportunities.
You're a master teacher.
We all do what we can do.
I have to say a few words.
This calls for a few words.
Well, that indeed calls for a few words, does it not?
And a quick question.
It's because they are master students.
And they force me to be what I am.
And would you be willing to share with us your level of calibration?
I don't know what it is.
You don't know?
Anyone calibrate you?
I'll tell you that it's sufficient.
Yes, I know.
Over 200.
I'll tell you how my wife described it.
How should she describe it?
She says, oh, let's see.
We have permission to ask this question.
Resist.
He's the real McCoy.
People ask her, what is his level?
She says, he's the real McCoy.
He's the real McCoy.
You can only be, you know, what you actually are.
You understand?
And you just be that which you are.
And it speaks for itself.
Amazing.
Passing it around.
Okay.
I will see you in Aspen.
Now, the truth is, it's my joy to be here.
My joy to love these people.
And when I know on the way here,
I start to get excited because I see everybody here.
And I want to love them all, hug them all.
And share, you know, that which I am with them.
It's my joy, actually.
Yes, ma'am.
Sort of a personal question.
If a woman is able to go out of body during a sexual attack,
however, many years later, cellular memory comes up.
Physical ramifications occur.
They're coming in.
Yeah.
How is that woman able to deal with it if the doctors can't find a cure
for the cellular memory, pelvic burning?
All right.
I'm going to say it's not cellular memory.
Cells don't remember anything.
Consciousness remembers it.
That which is traumatic, PTSD, post-traumatic stress syndrome,
from that experience or any other, it can only be healed by love.
The kind of love that's required to heal it is a very high level of unconditional.
I can love my attacker as he kills me.
There is a level of love.
I can love him even as he kills me.
That's unconditional.
So you strive for unconditional love.
You pray for the healing of the memory.
Don't forget the memory is also your perception of the experience.
It's possible to transcend it.
It's possible to forgive and see that whatever it was,
it was driven by some energy, possibly even an entity within it.
Is it karmic?
That's what you're saying?
You'd have to ask in some kind of research within yourself.
Any experience, no matter how grave or horrible, can be transcended.
One commits oneself to transcend that.
Say, God, I have to reach that level of consciousness that allows it to be healed.
And you pester God with it.
So the drivenness to transcend that experience then becomes the drive.
There is a level of consciousness where I can love and forgive someone
who is right in the very process of killing me, having experienced it.
It was mutual.
As we killed each other, the love became transcendent.
So it's possible.
Now, those are great heights of love, and it takes work to reach it.
But it's reachable.
Where you actually...
The forgiveness of the experience happens of its own,
not through some me forgiving you,
but the forgiveness arises from the spiritual energy within,
and it transforms the experience.
The transformed experience, you'll see there's nothing to forgive,
but in the perceptual experience there is,
to go and can, to advance one's level of consciousness.
To advance one's level of consciousness is all you can do.
But if it comes out physically, in physical form, after many, many years...
Like psychosomatic, what kind of things are you saying?
Pelvic burning.
Yeah, a fixation of pain and suffering, correct?
I don't know, it's just...
Psychic pain that's like fixated in the body, are you talking about that?
Yeah, there's no explanation for it.
Huh?
No physical explanation.
No, no, it's a psychic imprint.
It's a psychic imprint.
You need somebody to sort of guide you through the experience,
where it's an experience where as each thing comes up,
you completely surrender it and don't resist it,
including the memory.
The pain and suffering of the memory is because you're resisting it.
There's a way of going through even physical surgery without anesthesia,
and you'll find that there's a way of going through it
and completely, and completely, completely at great depth surrendering it.
And as you surrender it, you disappear it.
Okay, so I'll say something that's very advanced, but it still is the truth.
You cannot experience anything unless you resist it.
Without resistance, you would not be experiencing anything.
Everything is only a divine oneness.
To experience anything out of it, you have to start resisting,
and as you resist it, you now bring it into experience.
I know I'm giving you a very advanced kind of an answer,
but if you persist with prayer and devotion, the answer will come to you.
So a stalker who...
Yes?
I kind of wonder why it happened, because there was ten of us.
We all looked alike.
It was a high-profile case.
There's no why to it.
Was it my energy that attracted it?
No, you're asking me why.
What you want to know is the mechanism by how come it happened to you, correct?
Because you were vulnerable, because you were there,
because you had some karmic obligation?
Well, any one or all of those things, right?
Let's see if it's accidental.
What happened to her?
We have permission to ask, resist.
It was accidental, resist.
Accidental.
Accidental within what frame?
Within what context?
Within the framework of causality, it was accidental, resist.
Within the frame of causality.
Within the framework of spiritual reality, it was accidental, resist.
Within the realm of spiritual context, it was not accidental.
Oh, I see.
It manifested then, within the world of form, as a seeming accident.
It takes a great deal of spiritual work
to completely resolve this on all levels.
You understand there's various levels.
There's how you remember it.
Then there's how you perceived it.
Then there's how you interpreted it.
Then there's what part you resisted which got fixated
as a physiologic problem, you understand?
There's ways to undo it.
There's ways to undo it with hypnotic and past life recall.
But it is a stimulus to constant spiritual work then,
how to transcend that, how to contextualize it,
how to understand it.
What does it mean?
Does it mean anything?
So sometimes a problem like that is what drives us.
All the people that we reach are out of advanced states
in the 12-step groups.
We're all driven there by a very severe and disturbing question
they could not find an answer to.
So you can turn this into the drivenness that drives you
until you find the answers.
But the answers are there, and it's healable.
I can tell you that much.
Yes?
Any suggestions for kind of being one with the light,
having God's will be your will?
Say it again.
Any suggestions for surrendering everything to God?
Aligning your will with God's will.
Yes.
That is the 11th step in the 12-step program.
Start through prayer and meditation, see,
to understand what God's will is for me.
So that really comes about through prayer and meditation.
That's why it says start through prayer and meditation,
to find out whether is my will aligned with God's will.
Well, there's more advanced answers to that,
which says they are one and the same thing eventually, you see.
There is no will but God's will.
And the illusion that you have a will that could be different
than God's will is an illusion.
So God's purpose would be one way of phrasing it.
God's will is another.
Trying to guess what is God's purpose for me.
Frankly, God doesn't have any purpose for you.
That's a fact.
See, because purpose would be taking form.
George, I want you to become a shoemaker
and open a factory in Nova Scotia.
No, that would be form.
So it would be like the field,
the field automatically pulls forth
your potentiality to become
that which you have the potential,
the capacity to be.
So if I were God and you asked me,
I'd say I want you to be the most beautiful flower
that you have the capacity to become, you see.
Because in that way you witness the reality of divinity
because there's no other way in which a flower
can come into existence except by divinity.
Nothing has the capacity to come into existence
except by divinity.
Divinity, okay.
That's not an answer, but it'll have to do you.
Is your personal meditation practice
when you sit down, do you just kind of
just let go, relax?
Is there a particular...
Meditation practice.
Yes.
That's a dollar, that lecture.
You want to hear it?
Yes.
How about a hundred?
Anyway, the meditation practice has to do...
We've described two different kinds of meditation.
We've described central fixed meditation,
you know, meditation is a whole project in itself,
a whole subject in itself.
Generally, they go into...
I prefer contemplation to meditation
because in meditation you've got to take time out
and eventually your life gets too busy,
you haven't got time out, so you skip it.
Contemplation is a way of being in the world
which is sort of continuous
in which one relates to the field
in sort of a general way
and then the particulars seem to be happening
of their own.
Meditation can be in the same way
in which one's focus is on the field
and not on the content of the field.
There's another way called the fixed focus
in which in meditation you fixate
on the phenomena as they appear
and surrender them as they appear
and then you go through the progressive
fields of realization.
You get that you are not the content of the field,
you get that you are the witness of the field
and you progressively withdraw from identification
with the content of consciousness
to become its witness
and eventually there's the realization
that one is the field of awareness,
that awareness...
because all this is happening without your say-so.
As you become aware that witnessing
is happening of its own,
you realize it's not me.
All this time you think that
the mind is me.
Well if the mind was me
you could stop witnessing.
You can't stop witnessing.
So obviously it is a phenomena
which is arising out of consciousness.
So you stop identifying with the content
and you identify with the witness,
the observer,
eventually you identify with consciousness itself
and then in a rather profound sweep of realization
you realize that
that which you are is beyond even consciousness itself.
That one's reality is the unmanifest
becoming manifest as consciousness
out of which arises awareness,
out of which arises witnessing,
out of which then arises perception
and then the identification with perception
and then the thought of self as mind.
It's a progression, progressive awareness.
There are
schools which do nothing but practice meditation,
no spiritual or religious direction.
They do not call themselves anything
except the meditation center.
You do nothing but meditate
and the purpose of it all is to merely assist you
in the process of meditation period.
They don't tell you what to meditate on or for
or give you any goal or any direction.
That's a very pure form of meditation.
You just go and meditate
like going to the
steam bath.
You go and meditate.
Generally meditation is coming out of an intentionality.
It's really a subject we should go into some other day
because there are very simple ways of meditating
that will take you there very rapidly.
You sit quietly and close your eyes.
If you close your eyes and look straight ahead
you will see tiny little specks
phos genes they call them.
You will see tiny little specks.
Okay, so you focus
on the field in which specks are happening.
As you do that you will begin to feel
that your field of awareness begins to expand now
as though the specks are almost representing
a mini cosmos.
And you keep surrendering
and letting go of wanting to resist anything
and you merely witness
the phos genes.
You witness the tiny little specks.
If you close your eyes right now
it's not all pitch black.
No, no.
There's a million little tiny lights.
Don't you see them?
Yeah, way off in the distance.
Spark like sparkling stars way off in the distance.
So you just then
look like beyond them and past them.
So you're the witness of the field.
Already you're just the witness of the field.
It's quite clear you are not the field.
You're the witness of the field.
You do nothing but breathe quietly.
Be aware of your breathing
and witness the field.
You will go into a more advanced state of consciousness.
You don't have to do anything else but that.
Don't try and do anything with it.
Just witness the field.
Your eyes are closed so
now you let the focus
instead of being on the little spots
you let it go to the totality
beyond the spots.
And all of a sudden you'll feel yourself
in a different dimension.
It can happen very rapidly.
It can happen slowly.
It's very simple.
But it'll take you right out of the dimension
right into a different dimension.
Utter simplicity.
Watch the breathing.
Be with the breathing
and just watch straight ahead.
That's all you have to do.
Nothing else.
You'll automatically shift into a different level of consciousness.
It's automatic.
And then you realize
I'm not the thoughts.
I'm not the content of the field.
And as you practice this
the field gets bigger and bigger.
Finally it seems like
what you're focused on is the whole cosmos.
It's as though
instead of these little sparkly lights here
it's like it's all coming out there.
It's like 4th of July
and all this is going off.
And then it's like
the field of consciousness
is almost like the cosmos
when it goes beyond any limited definition.
of self.
It's a very simple technique.
People try to mystify
mystify these various spiritual techniques.
There's nothing mystical about it.
It's just your dedication to reach the truth.
So you're asking God
please reveal to me
the nature of consciousness.
And once you see the nature of consciousness
you're very close to what you want to know.
And that solves itself.
Thank you for such a wonderful question.
In I you talk about
how there are entities
in the lower astral
who have consciously turned away from God.
That's true.
We choose God.
So my question is
if God is eminent and transcendent
how is that even possible?
That's a wide question I can't answer.
I'll tell you what.
My understanding of it is
you're created with absolute freedom.
You've got freedom to say no.
Because the ego would like to think it's God.
We see the battle
in every young infant.
At age two they got the nose.
Alright.
Who's going to dominate?
Who's going to rule?
So you see the egocentricity of the infant
which the psychopath by the way
never gets over.
Can never understand no.
You see the challenge now
is between the two year olds
megalomania
and surrender to God.
And some would rather
maintain the egomania
than the megalomania.
One reason for oppositionalism
because in teenage misbehavior
oppositionalism is the main trend
is the confusion between authority
and authoritarianism.
It's a great mistake philosophically
to think that your only way to freedom
is to defy authority.
No.
One should defy authoritarianism
but not authority.
Why?
Because authority is spoken from truth
and therefore is to be respected.
So we respect authority
and I see a bumper sticker
that says question authority.
It's a great mislead.
It sends people off of the earth.
No. Question authoritarianism
because now you're talking about
a fascist dictator.
But true authority stems from
the reality of the experience.
If a person stands there
and he's broken 10 or 15 or 20 broncos
I'm not going to question his authority,
am I?
Because he's coming from the authority
of the real, genuine experience.
If somebody comes on in an authoritarian manner
and you find out he's read some good books on it
but he's never broken a bronco yet,
you see?
So there's quite a difference between
authority which is truthful and integrity
and authoritarianism which is
the exploitation of one's position.
It's very crucial to see the difference,
you see?
Because in one case we should stand up and say no
and in the other case we should
give it agreement or respect.
Okay. Thank you for such a great question.
Okay.
I wanted to expand a little bit on
you talked about resistance to
an earlier questioner.
Resistance as a path to learning.
I mean you were saying
she had a difficult experience in resisting
and that experience was
a way for her to learn.
Could you expand?
I think I've lost you.
All right. You're going from...
You can only...
The source of all experiencing is resistance.
You see?
And because resistance is dealing with perception.
What is it you're resisting?
You're resisting that which you perceive.
That which you perceive is a projection upon reality.
In the absolute reality,
if your thumb gets sawed off, it gets sawed off.
So?
If you resist it,
it's extremely painful.
If you completely surrender it,
there's almost a feeling of joy.
It's like you go out of body.
It's like you're picked up by the angelic.
And so?
Let me see.
I just lost my thumb.
So?
What?
Goodbye.
And the kid sits at the girl's bed and says,
Doc, what happened to your thumb?
I say,
It's waiting in heaven, waiting for me to come over.
It wants to make sure I come home.
I got your thumb, but I got you coming back to get it.
That makes them laugh, you know?
So?
You see?
To grieve it would be resisting it.
You understand?
The minute I resist it,
I would then grieve it
and feel sad about it.
Okay.
The minute you resist pain,
you feel suffering.
If you don't resist it,
it disappears it.
Yeah.
It can just be what it is.
The way to disappear something is,
and I teach people how to do it,
is to not resist it.
You see?
If you fall down and you feel terrible pain in your ankle,
the minute you say sprained ankle,
you already just gave yourself a problem.
You can't label it anything.
You can't even call it pain.
You can't even say it's in my ankle
because you're not experiencing.
If you keep letting go, resisting it,
I mean surrender at great depth
to just let it be what it is.
Don't call it anything.
Don't call it pain.
Don't try and resist it.
Don't try and call it sprained ankle.
As you completely surrender
to any kind of injury to yourself,
next time you hurt yourself, try this.
Don't call it anything.
Don't call it pain.
Don't call it bruised knee.
Whatever you're going to give it.
Completely and relentlessly surrender to it.
You'll find the pain is there,
but the suffering now disappears.
The next thing you'll notice
is that the sensation leaves the local area
and becomes diffuse in your whole aura.
What you felt was your ankle
now you'll feel it in your whole aura.
And you just lay there in the field
and keep surrendering to it.
Just keep surrendering to it.
And within a minute or two,
so you're surrendering to this phenomena
and it's in your whole aura.
It's not in your leg anymore.
And it's general.
It's all around you.
And you keep surrendering to it
and gradually it fades away
and you get up and you walk away.
No problem.
Now, if you resist it
and say, I've got a sprained ankle,
you'll end up in a splint
because you give yourself a sprained ankle.
So getting raped and not surrendering to it
as it was happening,
which would require a very advanced person
to do, by the way,
so I'm not faulting her.
It got fixated in the body.
See what I'm saying?
So if you resist the twisting of the ankle
and resist it,
then you will end up with a twisted ankle
and you'll have to have a bandage
and you'll be limping.
Understand?
As you surrender to it,
you disappear it.
You disappear it.
So anybody,
if you're in the midst of a catastrophe,
your car turning over or surgery,
the anesthesia is not working,
whatever,
the horrible thing you can imagine,
your head hitting the windshield,
whatever,
at that moment,
you completely and totally surrender to God
at great depth
with no resistance
unto the God to which I surrender
and you will disappear it.
And even if you leave the physical body
and in the terms of the world die,
you won't even notice it.
I should have not resisted the dust.
It probably would have fallen off.
I must have resisted the dust.
Sneaking up the psychic body.
Yeah.
Okay.
Good to see you again.
See, there's a real mesomorph.
Oh yeah.
My question is,
being in the spiritual realm,
what is your input on hypnotherapy?
I think hypnotherapy can be extremely good
and you want to make sure
that the hypnotherapist is integrous,
that's all,
and those are what they're talking about.
No, hypnotherapy can be very good.
Also, it's a very good way to go back.
Very good way to go back to past life recall.
Also, it's curative of a number of disorders
and I believe the most integrous way,
the most integrous way for hypnotherapy
is the hypnotist teaches you self-hypnosis.
That way you're not,
that's the way you're not dependent on them.
So I teach the patient self,
how to put yourself under
and then I give them certain realistic parameters
of what you can do with it
and I tell them,
go outside those parameters,
give me a call,
we'll see if it's,
if it's safe for you to go outside those parameters,
you know,
if he wants to start astral projection or something,
you better know getting okay.
But I mean,
I like to teach,
you know,
teach people self-hypnosis
so they're not dependent on you.
That was one more question.
Yeah.
That is just,
in doing hypnotherapy,
my whole purpose has been
to help people empower themselves.
Right, yeah.
So it's not to get them dependent
and understanding the field of psychiatry.
That whole basis
was to keep them coming back for talk therapy,
to talk about it.
In hypnotherapy,
you don't talk about it on the conscious level,
you go in on a deep level.
Yeah.
So that's why I wanted to ask you
because being a psychiatrist,
it's more the conscious level.
Well, no,
use all of them, see?
Because although you talk to the patient
on the conscious level,
it's all,
it's,
what's happening is more on the unconscious
and as you get more advanced,
the spiritual level, see?
And I was a Freudian,
I was a neo-Freudian psychoanalyst
and I,
my analysis was Freudian
and I'll tell you,
I wouldn't poo-poo with the unconscious.
Freudian,
the so-called Freudian conflicts
in the unconscious are very powerful.
They can paralyze you with anxiety attacks
or you're in a severe depression.
So there's nothing to fool around with.
People who poo-poo with the Freudian theory,
I tell them,
yeah, try laying on the couch
five days a week for a couple of years
and let's see what comes up.
I won't say anything,
you just lay there
and tell me what's coming up
and they'll recreate everything
that Freud wrote about
because it's in the unconscious.
Yeah,
so I'm glad you're using it
and teaching them
how to be independent of you.
Do you do past life regression with it too?
I have not,
but I'm looking into it.
Yeah,
it's a very interesting phenomena.
It's amazing to watch the transformation
on the table
when we're there.
It's as if I'm there with them.
It's something else just takes over
and it's like a different person comes out.
The emotion,
as you said,
they're there in the moment.
Yeah.
But then there's this like freeing
when they're done.
So,
I just wondered.
Well,
anybody who tries to help others grow
and recover from whatever ails them,
by means of spiritual growth,
we certainly,
yeah,
it's time.
It's,
what time do we have to be out of here today?
They didn't tell us what time to be out of here.
Well,
maybe we can chant our way out.
Anybody want to hear Nico chant?
Hey.
All right,
we'll give Nico the microphone.
I'm going to disconnect this.
I'll go about it.
Testing one, two.
There we go.
And for those who have asked questions,
I do have a recorded studio version of this
and we're working right now
to get it in commercial form.
So,
if you'll put your name on the email list
and when it gets,
it'll be about another week,
maybe before we have full production
and we will email you
and you can order
if you want one.
So,
thank you.
Thank you.
Lean back,
relax.
Oh.
Hugo,
ah
Oh
So
Chimono, Sakkomo, Gaya, Koisei, Buku, Soku, Gensa
Ibambo, Tenno, Jitsudai, Niigame, Tsui, Dōgen, Gakko
Isokoshi, Shinho, Itadaki, Koyaki, Dao, Akito, Chu
Gajo, Jizu, Tokyo, Fukuoka, Tsuyo, Toka, Toin, Seisho, Toho
Maishisa, Seinen, Ikazosu, Rō
Ikado, Shodō, Takunomo, Tōtō
Takuto, Tsubu, Shin, Nā
Nammyo, Hōringeiko, Nammyo, Hōringeiko
Nammyo, Hōringeiko
Listen to the silence we've created
Thank you, go live in that
Thank you