So success is then looking at what is successful
and trying to detect the sense of it.
It's the sense of it.
It's the out here-ness of it.
So the 24-year-old accountant is looking in here
trying to examine the books to see
how they turned that much profit on that much growth.
But that's the consequent and not the cause,
which brings us back to the spiritual principle
that the world that you see is not only a world of perception,
it's an out-picturing of what already has existence
within the field of consciousness.
We've used the Empire State Building over and over.
The Empire State Building, a guy sits back, lights a cigar,
and pictures the biggest, tallest building in the world.
Wham!
In that instant, the Empire State Building was done.
Then the consequent was the energy, enthusiasm,
and the vision of it captured the imagination of others
who then brought out billions of dollars from their banks
and then, of course, the infighting between the unions
and the banks and the percentage rates,
but that's all trivia.
The creation was the inspiration
within the head of the creator of the Empire State Building.
That's how every great thing comes out.
So here was the power of the Empire State Building,
and this is nothing but the concept,
and this is nothing but the consequence.
If you've got an inspiring vision,
then it's just a matter of meeting the right people
to find people who want to get involved in that
because they themselves are uplifted by the image.
All right, so the company has to increase,
it needs a much better image of who it is in the world.
It's walking around with a defensive inferiority complex,
lying instead of telling the truth,
using an image of the world,
and the image of the world,
people that, to my mind,
are just too young to have wisdom.
All right, there's a difference between intelligence and wisdom.
Intelligence is very good at thinking up very clever things,
but what to do with those clever things is up to wisdom,
and too many decisions, in my view,
are made up by people who have great intelligence,
great cleverness,
but lack wisdom of how to contextualize that
and how to time it and how to present it
and how to shade it,
so that it wins you friends and influences people.
Yeah?
Everybody knows there's advertisements
that make you love them,
and there's advertisements that make you hate them.
Now, why is it these companies that are spending billions of dollars
on all this don't know that?
Do they not know that, or what?
No, because they don't calibrate it.
You say, what's the calibrated level
of the audience I want to hit with this advertising?
The calibrated level.
You don't want people over 400.
You want people about 80.
Depraved.
You want the depraved market.
No, that's your market.
Depraved, right?
It's better to write the advertising about your product
in graffiti and then pay people a dollar for every graffiti
they smudge in the subway car,
because that's where your people are.
They're not in the Library of Congress.
All right, so you can define your target market.
What's the calibrated energy?
The field that they're going to go for my product.
Every product has a market that thinks it's great
and a market outside those parameters think it's stupid.
So what is the consciousness level I'm trying to reach?
Let's say you're trying to reach
the great American populace is in the 200s to the 300s.
I want to reach the 200s to the 300s.
So what good is an advertisement that's calibrated
by some smart-ass kid who's age 24
designed for the 400s?
You missed your market.
Here's your market here.
What will appeal to this market?
People over the age of 20, 30
are going to be annoyed as hell with a quacking duck,
I'll tell you that.
So who are they trying to appeal with,
with a quacking duck?
Is that their purchase?
Are those their purchases?
Is that their market, you know?
All right, so we can align our advertising
with our market.
You can also take a piece of advertising
and calibrate the effect of every piece of that,
that commercial.
You can take a commercial and take it apart
and get what is the energy of this aspect,
what's the energy of this side of the field.
You can then shift to the next scene.
What's the energy of this?
You find this whole image makes you go strong,
except this woman's smile makes you go weak.
She puts you right down.
She's all teeth.
There's a certain very famous female model
whose teeth, her smile,
makes everybody go weak with kinesiology.
You don't want her.
You just spent a quarter of a million dollars
to have this lady smile
and lose you a huge market out there.
So the first thing we want to know is something simple,
and you don't have to be a genius.
And I say to Suzy,
does this make you go strong or weak?
She looks at it and says,
how are you going to sell a product that makes you go weak?
In other words, every time your customer
looks at this commercial,
their acupuncture blows out and they go weak.
That's not a way to make friends
and influence people, right?
All right, let's go back to Venice.
All right, so you see the practicality of it,
the capacity to discern your market,
to discern whether your marketing
is aligned with your market.
There's other markets that you want 400 and over.
So a 250 calibrated advertisement
is going to turn them off
because your product looks stupid to them.
Stupid, yeah?
It's in the wrong ballpark.
Okay.
We want to avoid touchy-feely workshops
and self-improvement lectures.
Touchy-feely workshops
because they're called touchy-feely workshops.
You just lost.
Self-improvement means there's something wrong with you
and we're going to help you.
I don't want to be helped and improved.
I want to be appreciated for who I am.
Oh, that's a different ballgame.
So I'm saying that
Venice has to appreciate itself for what it is.
It's the backbone of survival of all of us.
It belongs collectively
to all of America.
It came out of my grandparents,
my parents, myself.
It'll come out of our children
as a continuation of that
which we've put out into this world.
In doing this, we ennoble ourself.
We gain an image of who we really are.
Now, this doesn't mean some kind of
manipulation of self-image.
See, that's totally different.
We don't want to design an improved self-image program.
Point one.
Paint all chairs green.
Paint number two.
You know what I mean?
We don't want a fallacious program.
No, what we're talking about is reality.
The source of the human spirit
is Almighty God and none other.
So what is the source of business and industry?
The same.
Without divinity, nothing would come into existence.
Certainly nothing human in the form of life
would come into existence.
So by virtue of the divinity of our own existence,
the source of our own existence,
we manifest out into the world,
at some level,
the benefit of that existence
to ourself and to others.
I gave you the story of the peanut vending machine
that when society calibrated it 190,
if you don't get the sucker's money,
somebody will, would fly.
It won't fly in today's world.
However, you'll find plenty of people
that will go for it,
but our society will not go for it.
So every company should picture
who am I vis-a-vis society.
Am I really valuing and appreciating
the reality of who I really am?
No railroad train can drive without the spikes.
Every single spike in that entire thousands of roads
is critical to life.
We move one spike, the railroad car goes over.
The rail begins to shake.
So everyone must value
that they are an integral and valuable part of the whole.
We certainly want to get up.
Here's Walmart up here.
So you don't have to become a saint.
We didn't say Walmart was a saint.
It's into willingness.
And as you walk in,
what does it say on the back of their jacket?
How can I help you?
So let's have the business story again.
All right.
So we reflect to the customer.
We want to reflect back to the customer
his value to us, to our work, to our business.
After all, we're supporting our wife and our children
due to their customerhood.
So I like to acknowledge to the customer,
you know, we really appreciate it.
And not as a slogan, but as a fact.
That customer walking in is your bread and butter
and your children's and your children after that.
They stand for survival.
So we regain respect through integrity
by we ennoble ourselves and our workers.
We re-acknowledge to the customer his value to us
and not as a slick slogan.
Too many things like this sound genuine,
but they're put out there as a slick slogan.
It has to come from a genuine realization
on the part of corporate executives.
Somebody has to envision back to the employee.
Back to the employees and to the public
who you really are.
And your devotion to certain principles.
Then you don't need to advertise it.
It shines forth starkly from you
in the way your company is vis-a-vis the world.
The value of the total economy then.
Each one of us is an integral part of the economy.
And abundance is the consequence of integrity.
Abundance is the consequence of integrity.
What about the cheaters and the liars
and all those who get a piece of it?
They don't create abundance.
They just get to haul away a little bit more of it.
They don't create it.
The billions that are out there
were not created by the CEO thieves
that recently ransacked the stock market.
It was created by the industry itself.
They just hauled off a rather piggy piece of it.
So there are piggies out there.
And it's okay to say there are piggies out there.
We don't run a monastery here.
So the economy then is the product
of the energy of mankind.
The vilifiers of free enterprise then
are coming from a Luciferic distortion of reality
which tends to vilify all excellence.
The Marxist Luciferic distortion of truth.
It vilifies and hates true power and true excellence.
The Pieta, due to itself,
a maniac who tried to destroy it.
The paintings of Rembrandt
attract the maniac who wants to cut it up and rip it.
That which is integrous and successful
summons to it its opposite
which hates integrity, truth, goodness, beauty.
Most great leaders of peace
in the history of the world have been assassinated.
That which is a threat to the dominance
of that which is nonintegrous
is hated by the nonintegrous.
The way to get hated
is to show how to tell truth from falsehood.
How to remove the sheep's clothing from the wolf.
And the energy that came up as that was
prepared for the audience was horrific.
Now, 78% of mankind is invested in the nonintegrous.
All right, so the Marxist fallacy, then,
is workers of the world unite.
You have nothing to lose but your chains.
Nobody's chaining you to the job, frankly.
The reason people work for the Ford Motor Company
is because they pay $5 an hour,
which in those days, when I grew up, was terrific.
As a head of employee satisfaction and happiness there,
I would have allowed them to smile several times a day.
Once in the morning, once at night.
Once in the afternoon.
Make it a little more human.
But when industry starts out,
it starts out like Mr. Scrooge.
But then, like Mr. Scrooge,
pretty soon the feedback of its own success
begins to push for a higher level of consciousness.
So success then tends to become self-reinforcing.
So we want to re-authenticate the true value
of industry and commerce to the world.
It's true value.
You wouldn't even be alive without them.
Now, you understand that?
So we do owe.
Corporate America represents
the collective effort of all of us.
We all knocked our brains out to get where we are.
I used to work 14 hours a day, 16 hours a week,
16 hours a day, under horrendous conditions.
So that energy...
I'm working in a warehouse 110 degrees,
and I've worked 14 hours already,
and it's already 2 in the morning.
And the whole crop hasn't been canned yet for that day.
And I said, God, I can't make it.
I can't make it.
I was 14 or something, 15.
I didn't have the strength.
I was a shrimpy ectomorph.
It's 110 in there, and there's no windows
in this freaking warehouse.
Can you believe they didn't have a window in it?
And I hit the point of exhaustion
where I could not go on.
And at that point, I gritted my teeth,
and I refused the barrier.
And I crashed through it by sheer energy of will.
And I think I've told you that,
and I've said this before.
Instantly, every carton of canned goods
became light as a feather.
Effortless.
And I lifted them like they were feathers,
and I could keep going all night.
And to this day, I know how to do that.
I can keep going after they've all dropped dead
from exhaustion and heart attacks.
Oh, God.
Okay, so out of such ferocious effort,
self-sacrifice, sweat,
and really an inner agony
comes out the crop
from this canning company.
So the cans of peas
on the shelves
came from my agony.
It came from the agony of all the farmers
who brought the peas in
on these big hay wagons behind horses,
and they were covered with sweat.
They were covered with sweat.
So from the exhaustion and the sweat
and the sacrifice,
the sheer willpower, the sheer grit,
we have produced an incredible product.
A product called America.
And instead of attacking it,
vilifying it,
which I think is non-integrous,
we should be thankful and grateful for it.
And that's the fallacy
of the Marxist positionality,
is because you're not a victim of anything.
The whole idea of perpetrator and victim
is a fallacy,
and it's a paranoid distortion of reality.
If I take a job at Ford,
they're not victimizing me at all.
I'm victimizing them.
I'm taking five dollars a day
and they're not paying me.
I went to the bathroom twice
and they didn't notice.
Alright, so
the spiritual warrior in us says,
you know, I'm sick of being
denigrated
and vilified and demonized.
If I was corporate America,
I would fight back, pissed off.
You know, you're vilifying truth,
you're telling lies.
And of course you can see what's going to happen
with a big fat juicy plum like Walmart.
It's going to attract all the bottom feeders
to see if it can create this
quietude conflict
and all kinds of wicked stories on the internet
about how everybody's exploited and abused
and oh God, help us all.
Alright, so before you take a thing over,
you demonize it.
Before you try to take over something,
You demonize the product, the leaders.
I remember I could see, you know,
like socialization of medicine coming
because every periodical had demon doctors.
Doctors over-inflated fees,
doctors doing
plastic surgery,
horrible doctors.
I looked around all my colleagues I've been with
all these years and I thought,
where are those bastards?
Let me at them, let me at them.
No, it was invented by the media.
Okay, let's see the bottom here.
Alright,
those of you interested in the
purposeful demonization
of that which is
in America,
there's a very excellent book
written by the University of Chicago.
Jackal and Hirota 2000
The Image Makers
which documents
the exact technique
that demonization
and denigration
and the causing of
negative images
is a huge industry.
The disgruntled
moral
righteous anger
which rises up over everything
from the color of the carpet
to its fabric to what clothes I have on
in the room.
There isn't anything you can't get into
an agitated, moralistic,
holier-than-thou
attack mode
which fragments the very
integrity of society.
We don't have time to go into it, but anyway
it is a whole industry of its own.
So when you run out of one poor victim
you quickly can find new victims
and you can advertise on
television
were you in Chicago in 1937 and got a sunburn
called your coat on poo-poo.
It's a self-feeding
industry, self-propagating.
We want to couch our language
when we're addressing business
and business people in non-religious
and non-spiritual terms.
We want to use common terms
that denote exactly what we're talking about.
God can creep into the marketplace
so long as you don't use the term God
and you don't use religious terminology.
You can talk about integrity.
You can talk about honesty.
You can talk about many things.
So you don't want to use
people have to have dignity.
You have to have confidence,
support, the importance of who they are
and we don't need
spiritual language to do that.
So
we'll take a break
and I'm trying to give you more
a feeling for the field.
The field is
I'm sick and tired of being
attacked and criticized.
I'm sick and tired of it.
I'm speaking as Mr. Business.
I'm sick and tired of being lied about,
denigrated, falsified,
corrupted by
fallacy.
I demand to be respected
for who I really am.
I'm the totality of the output
of all the sweat and labor
of the heart and the solar plexus
of all the generations that have gone before
including this one
and your parents
and the ones that come after you.
I demand to be respected
and demonized
and denigrated
is the same as vilifying
the value of human life
because this is the product of human life.
This is human life made manifest
as what I've got on.
So we have to ruin our own integrity
and we must insist on it
on the behalf of industry.
I don't have to be in industry
to redefine its value
to the populace as I see it
because industry can't see it itself
who it is.
Without you industry
I'd be dead a long time ago.
I'd be walking to work every day.
Without you industry
I'd be making my own shoes.
So a certain gratitude
so I would like to see gratitude
and thankfulness
which doesn't mean
that we have to consider
everything they do is perfect
because I just got through telling you
their advertising stinks.
I feel embarrassed for them.
I can't wait until this TV program is over
because he's just lying through his teeth
and he's doing such a bad job.
If you're going to get a liar, get a good one.
At least get a good liar.
You know what I'm saying?
Always agree with your opponent.
And somebody says
you're the worst so and so
you say I sure am.
Somebody says you're a liar
you say I'm the best liar there is.
You want to hire me? I'm worth a fortune.
I can say I'm not a liar
when you're obviously a liar.
You say I lie when I think it's going to be beneficial
to the company and good for our stock prices.
Well there's an honest man
I can trust him now.
He's told me he's going to pull a fast one
whenever you let him get away with it.
Well that's integrous isn't it?
He's saying I've got pleptomania
and I can't help it
but you'll have to set up these safeguards
because I'm just going to have to reach in that pot
and take some more.
I say well at least I know who this guy is.
He'll have a little liquor cabinet
when a certain day came over.
You know what I'm saying?
So I just want you to know
that I am on the side of corporate America
business America
free enterprise
I feel that it reflects the dignity of man
to the best we've been able to evolve
in the development
of mankind and humanity
to this point.
You see the product of it
is still capitalism.
In socialism
the capitalistic output
is named differently
but it's still the capital
put out by the people
and whose ever name it might be.
You can put it in the name of the people
and you don't specifically own any.
Collectively you own it all.
Collectively all of us own
all of corporate America's product.
We own all the sidewalks,
the roadways,
the railroad cars,
the airplanes,
all these industries.
We all own it all, don't we?
I don't have to have a piece of ownership
on this carpet to walk on it.
It's here, paid by somebody's money.
You know what I mean?
I'll lead a protest I don't like the design though.
Alright, I thank you
then we're going to have a short break
then we'll have questions
and I'll sign books
and I thank you all for the blessedness
of your presence.
Well we want to reorganize because
we have to be out here at a certain time
there's two weddings coming up.
Two weddings after us.
We wanted to answer some questions.
If we have time we'll ask
Nico to chant for us.
All in favor
of Nico chanting.
Alright, we'll cut the questions short.
There are a lot of questions
having to do with cause and effect.
I want to re-clarify that.
Because the mind is so used to explaining
things in terms of cause and effect
it has difficulty in understanding
how things manifest
as the consequence
of the totality of prevailing conditions.
You understand?
Nothing causes the rain to fall.
But when multiple
conditions are favorable
it comes about
as an expression of quality.
So karma
is not cause and effect.
It's by
every spiritual intention
by spiritual intention
by the exercise of the spiritual will
one adds
or detracts weight
from the quirk
of your spirit
which then rises higher
or lower
in the karmic sea
we call
the infinite context
of which is God.
As a consequence
what has changed
is a quality.
As we said
as you go up the level of consciousness
it's not quantitative
it isn't that 800
is many times better than 400
it has a different quality.
At the top of the
atomic table
you've got let's say platinum
you can't compare
things by atomic weights
because as it shifts
from lead to platinum
platinum has totally different qualities
than lead
a little bit of platinum
can catalyze tons and tons of ore
and a piece of lead can't do much
but a kick in the butt.
There are charismatic
truly charismatics
in every field
of sports, art
every field of endeavor including business
there are companies
whose leaders are so charming
and honest
and straightforward
you feel good in their company
and you feel honored to be able to work with them
I work with a group
Monday, Wednesday and Friday morning
that is like one loving family
we've all just created
that's who we are to each other
we cover each other's backs
somebody says I can't come in Friday
you say don't worry about it I'll cover you
in other words there's that willingness
to be the best you can
for everyone
and as a consequence
the Joint Commission on Accreditation
has given us a common
three times approval
with commendation
to pass the Joint Commission
a numerous examination
is one thing
to get it with commendation is another
and three times in a row we got it with commendation
so that's just the reflection of excellence
and the Joint Commission examiners
who came said we've never been to a place like this
where everybody seems to do everything
out of joy
out of fulfillment of who they are
out of recognition of the importance
of the work
because all work is important
the work I did in that warehouse all by myself
I know what the spiritual
price and the price of
will overcoming my resistance was
I gave it my best
and I broke through the barrier
and my reward for giving it the best
was I found how to function
effortlessly
and tirelessly
alright so karmic merit then is
not cause and effect
cause and effect is a mental construction
this is a very difficult
jump to make
to translate
to stop
this is the tautology
the intellect
deals in abstract symbols
and then thinks it has just
explained something
it has not explained anything
in reality it's only explained
how you picture it
how you explain it
so it's still it begins and ends
within the intellect
it has no connection with what's out there
don't feel bad if you can't make that jump
you know
Einstein couldn't make it
he got to the point
where the Heisenberg principle
he was up against the Heisenberg principle
that all you have to do is observe
the sub-microscopic level
and you've already changed the
consequence
well that's to me at a gross level
what the world considers
sub-microscopic and infinitely small
to me is gross
because thought operates at the
level of minus 400
the logarithm
minus 400
watts
so if the Heisenberg principle
means merely observe things at the
sub-microscopic level
already changes consequences
can you imagine what it does at
infinitely higher frequency and vibration
so every thought
every decision you make
already alters the whole field
and what happens to
the spirit is a consequence
of your positionality
your polarity
your molecular configuration
now within the soup
of the giant field
so nothing is causing anything
it's the automatic
consequence
this much charge
this much polarity
and this much position
is automatically going to move
things this
but it's not causing it to move that way
so we want to jump out of causality
because causality is what keeps
the ego anchored as a belief system
I don't know that one
so there's many questions
having to do with karma
and humanity's consciousness
we said that in the
infinite field of context here
if this is consciousness
which can be called by any name
you can call it Allah
you can call it the unmanifest
you can call this consciousness
would be the manifest
you can look at it as a vibrational
field of extremely high frequency
which is aware of everything
that happens
not from knowingness
but by the consequence
of that which it is
therefore we can calibrate the truth
of anything anywhere in time or place
the field registers every event
therefore every hair on your head
is counted literally
this ends up
as a vibrational frequency
which is translated
in and out picturing
this as karma
and the consequences of karma
consequently
it's a purgatorial realm
where it's purgatorial by definition
in that you start from zero
and you go up to a thousand
it's the whole circus
you can ride any one of the merry-go-round
you can eat cotton candy
you've got a whole selection here
of what you want to do with yourself
what you want to do with yourself
is already the result of your karmic inheritance
so if people say
well I'm worried about what is my karmic inheritance
your karmic inheritance is what you are
you're it baby
you don't have to worry about it
you're it already
now you can hate it
or love it
or say thank you lord
that I am in a place
where I have infinite number of choices
and where I have a chance
to redeem myself
for past errors
and earn merit
I don't believe in doing it for that
it sounds too much like
commercialized
spiritual commercialization
there's positive karmic merit in it
and avoid that
because it's got bad merit
humanity's
consciousness level is rising
how does that affect the purgatorial function of the world
well, quite well
if this world is
over time becomes a heavenly domain
if this becomes a celestial realm
it will have lost its purpose
for people
who are calibrating
here
if we become celestial
then we'll start inheriting
saints
at 570 they drop over
and they come to our celestial realm
where you can now become
a Buddha student
a student of Buddha
there you go
there's the karmic inheritance of mankind
and there you are sir
translated into Russian
the books are being translated
into all different languages
you don't have to worry about it
you just do the best you can
from moment to moment
and what you do
you see the source of joy is not out there
the source of joy
is the realization
of the presence of God within you
as the source of life itself
so you give
from moment to moment
there is a joy
at the awareness of your own existence
at no time is it possible
to have a problem
so there's no point in worrying
about war and peace and karma
because you can transcend it all
just prior to every thought
is an infinite field of stillness and silence
99% of your mind
is still and silent
only 1% of your mind
like a dumb little TV set
is over in the corner
and keeps you preoccupied
you keep watching this little story over there
because that's the only story that's going on
the rest of your life is silent
your mind is silent
right now everybody's mind here is silent
there's a little corner of it
making up some words and images
but 99.9% of your mind is silent
let's see if that's a fact
that is a fact
that's a fact
all you have to do is discover that
and identify with the silent part
instead of the noisy part
instantly you're home
how long does it take to become enlightened
about 1 100th of a second
one instant you're this
and you wonder how you ever could have believed
that you were the story
how can that be
it's a willingness then to surrender
the fascination
the payoff
the juice you get out of watching
the program
the program you're creating yourself
your own perceptions of the world
the payoff we get from being right
the payoff we get from making other people wrong
the payoff we get from feeling better than others
getting even with others
getting more of whatever there is out there
the gain
the relinquishment of the desire to control it all
the instant way to God
is to completely surrender
everything to God
it's usually only done
at the bottom of the pit of despair
probably statistically
when the torture gets bad enough
you say I give up
this identification with the mind
the self
is very powerfully strong
the willingness to give it up
then to let go all positionalities
what would give you the motivation
to do that
nothing will give you the motivation to do that
except spiritual ambition
so the only thing you could gain out of that
would be spiritual pride
out of spiritual inspiration then
comes
the willingness
to surrender totally
all that you think you are and hold dear
and to surrender it
to the unknown
which you then experience
as the infinite presence
so the power to do it
comes out of devotion
the devotion to truth
to say one is devoted to God
sounds terrific
but nobody knows what God is
they can hear how it's defined by theology
how it's been experienced by others
the desire to experience that then
opens up the channel
of inspiration
it's finally inspiration
it will take you to the point
where I cannot lift
one more box
I cannot lift one more box
and I refuse that impossibility
and you crash through
because that's a belief system
that's a limitation
that you're run by your ego
that you're the victim of your own ego
is a limitation in a belief system
with absolute intention
of all your spiritual will
refuse it
because it is a lie
you grit your teeth
and you surrender everything to God
every instant no matter what
and then you will come up against life itself
you'll have to surrender life itself
it wants everything
who I am gets surrendered
and at that moment
arises the fear of death
and then you realize you have to
actually give up life
not just what you think is life
but the core experience of life itself
this to thee oh Lord
do I surrender
and you do lay down your life for God
for thee oh Lord
do I die for thee
and then
suddenly the screen goes blank
and there you are
only after you actually die
only one death possible
death of the physical body
joke
as you go out you laugh
remember all the other times
ridiculous
ridiculous that you believed you were going to die
how could I be so stupid
you literally die
from the essence of who you think you are
and the source of your life itself
because this belief
in causality is very profound
one really believes
that it is the I
within me and by that you mean
the personal I which is the source
of my life
and if I let it go I will die
and that is true
one will you do die
so the willingness to surrender
what you believe is the essence and the core
and the source of life itself
is surrendered from
a devotion
that is so powerful
that it is greater
than your love of your own life
and to thee oh Lord
do I die
and then comes life eternal
and then you realize it always was eternal
how did you ever think it was
other than what it is
it is so starkly obvious
like noticing space for the first time
you are so used to space you don't notice it
alright that's enough for today
the good news
is you don't have to do it today
you've got
millions of years if you like
it's choice
and there the words of the teacher
come forth the vibrational frequency
of the truth stands there
and as you go through that gate
there is a knowingness
that comes from within
to walk straight ahead no matter what
into the face of death itself
and so the last barrier
is death
and it is death
not pretend death
not fake death
not the illusion of death
it is death
and that's the one that takes the great courage
hmm
the surrendering of the will to live
out of what one considers
one's source of life itself
and trust that God alone
is the source of life
the great threshold of faith
without hearing it
from the truth of it
no one would have the courage to do it
having heard the truth of it
you all have the courage
everything that is spoken here
I stand by
we calibrate and verify
all that is spoken here
I stand by the karmic consequence
should it be fallacious
or not the absolute truth
and out of that sincerity do I share it with you
now Niko has been begging
to be left alone
but we insist
come up here Niko
he's trying to disappear and hide
but we see him
and now we just sit near him
we don't have to be far from him
sit right down you have the chair
because this microphone will pick him up
for most people you have to put the microphone close
for Niko you have to get six feet away
now this is
the Lotus Sutra
chanted in Sanskrit
a great and rare opportunity
and we are highly fortunate
to have it with us and God bless you
chanted in Sanskrit
Oh
Thank you.
We got the Buddha here with us today.