We
We are
on
Here
Here we
Here we go.
Mhm.
Wow.
Wow. I
Wow. I I
Wow. I I have
Wow. I I have a
Wow. I I have a question
Wow. I I have a question but
Wow. I I have a question but I
Wow. I I have a question but I also
wanted
wanted to
Wow. I I have a question but I also
wanted to share
wanted to share something
Wow. I I have a question but I also
wanted to share something you
wanted to share something you said
Wow. I I have a question but I also
wanted to share something you said that
had
had a
had a profound
impact.
Um
Um and
Um and that
Um and that was
Um and that was basically
Um and that was basically the
Um and that was basically the fortune
cookie
cookie thing.
Um and that was basically the fortune
cookie thing. It
cookie thing. It was
Um and that was basically the fortune
cookie thing. It was uh
cookie thing. It was uh I
Um and that was basically the fortune
cookie thing. It was uh I just
cookie thing. It was uh I just do
Um and that was basically the fortune
cookie thing. It was uh I just do one
thing
and
and the
thing
and the thing
and the thing that
thing
and the thing that um
I
I chose
is
is not
I chose
is not to
is not to give
I chose
is not to give reality
is not to give reality or
I chose
is not to give reality or value
is not to give reality or value to
I chose
is not to give reality or value to any
thought
thought that
thought that is
thought that is in
thought that is in contradiction
thought that is in contradiction to
peace,
peace, love
thought that is in contradiction to
peace, love or
peace, love or joy.
Any
Any value
Any value or
Any value or reality,
Any value or reality, any
Any value or reality, any thought
Any value or reality, any thought is
Any value or reality, any thought is in
contradiction
contradiction to
Any value or reality, any thought is in
contradiction to peace,
contradiction to peace, love
Any value or reality, any thought is in
contradiction to peace, love and
contradiction to peace, love and joy.
It's
>> It
>> It obscures
It's
>> It obscures it.
>> It obscures it. It's
It's
>> It obscures it. It's not
>> It obscures it. It's not a
It's
>> It obscures it. It's not a contradiction
to
to it.
to it. It's
to it. It's not
to it. It's not the
to it. It's not the opposite
to it. It's not the opposite of
to it. It's not the opposite of it,
to it. It's not the opposite of it, but
it
it obscures
to it. It's not the opposite of it, but
it obscures it.
>> It
>> It obscures
>> It obscures it.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Obscures
>> It obscures it.
>> Yeah. Obscures it.
>> Being
>> Being beheaded
>> Being beheaded is
>> Being beheaded is a
>> Being beheaded is a bad
>> Being beheaded is a bad deal.
>> Being beheaded is a bad deal. But
>> Being beheaded is a bad deal. But just
as
as your
>> Being beheaded is a bad deal. But just
as your head
as your head goes
>> Being beheaded is a bad deal. But just
as your head goes off,
as your head goes off, you
>> Being beheaded is a bad deal. But just
as your head goes off, you say,
as your head goes off, you say, "God,
thank
thank you."
thank you." I
thank you." I mean,
thank you." I mean, cuz
thank you." I mean, cuz now
thank you." I mean, cuz now you're
thank you." I mean, cuz now you're in
thank you." I mean, cuz now you're in a
different
different presence.
thank you." I mean, cuz now you're in a
different presence. See?
different presence. See? You
thank you." I mean, cuz now you're in a
different presence. See? You know,
different presence. See? You know, it
looked
looked like
looked like a
looked like a bad
looked like a bad bad
looked like a bad bad deal
looked like a bad bad deal to
looked like a bad bad deal to get
beheaded,
beheaded, but
looked like a bad bad deal to get
beheaded, but frankly,
beheaded, but frankly, it
looked like a bad bad deal to get
beheaded, but frankly, it was
beheaded, but frankly, it was a
looked like a bad bad deal to get
beheaded, but frankly, it was a great
favor
God
God finally
favor
God finally gave
God finally gave you
favor
God finally gave you as
God finally gave you as he
favor
God finally gave you as he felt
God finally gave you as he felt sorry
for
for you
for you and
for you and you'd
for you and you'd earned
for you and you'd earned it.
>> So,
>> fastest
>> fastest way,
>> huh?
>> Fastest
>> Fastest way
>> Fastest way to
>> Fastest way to God
>> is
>> is to
>> Fastest way to God
>> is to hit
>> is to hit bottom
>> Fastest way to God
>> is to hit bottom with
>> is to hit bottom with a
>> Fastest way to God
>> is to hit bottom with a loud
>> is to hit bottom with a loud ringing
thud.
You
You see
thud.
You see the
You see the the the
thud.
You see the the the kindness
You see the the the kindness the
kindness
kindness expressed
kindness expressed in
kindness expressed in that
kindness expressed in that for
kindness expressed in that for empathy
you
you know
kindness expressed in that for empathy
you know be
you know be kind
kindness expressed in that for empathy
you know be kind towards
you know be kind towards all
kindness expressed in that for empathy
you know be kind towards all of
you know be kind towards all of life
kindness expressed in that for empathy
you know be kind towards all of life no
matter
matter what
I
I just
matter what
I just don't
I just don't want
matter what
I just don't want the
I just don't want the guy
matter what
I just don't want the guy who
I just don't want the guy who does
matter what
I just don't want the guy who does the
beheading
beheading to
beheading to feel
beheading to feel guilty
beheading to feel guilty about
beheading to feel guilty about it
beheading to feel guilty about it say
look
look don't
beheading to feel guilty about it say
look don't worry
look don't worry about
beheading to feel guilty about it say
look don't worry about it
look don't worry about it man
beheading to feel guilty about it say
look don't worry about it man it's
look don't worry about it man it's your
job
job you
job you know
job you know it's
job you know it's okay
I
I don't
job you know it's okay
I don't I'm
I don't I'm feeling
job you know it's okay
I don't I'm feeling guilty
I don't I'm feeling guilty you
job you know it's okay
I don't I'm feeling guilty you know
that's
that's your
that's your concern
that's your concern after
that's your concern after a
that's your concern after a Well,
>> so
>> so the
that's your concern after a Well,
>> so the net
>> so the net results
is
is just
is just um
is just um I
is just um I find
is just um I find I
is just um I find I can't
is just um I find I can't complain
is just um I find I can't complain about
a
a moment
is just um I find I can't complain about
a moment because
well
well I
well I just
well I just don't
well I just don't anymore
well I just don't anymore because
well I just don't anymore because I
decided
decided not
well I just don't anymore because I
decided not to.
Your
Your contemplative
Your contemplative lifestyle
Your contemplative lifestyle changes
Your contemplative lifestyle changes how
you
you see
Your contemplative lifestyle changes how
you see and
you see and experience
Your contemplative lifestyle changes how
you see and experience the
you see and experience the world.
And
And therefore,
And therefore, one
And therefore, one times
And therefore, one times a
And therefore, one times a contemplative
lifestyle
is
is being
is being aware
is being aware of
is being aware of the
is being aware of the of
is being aware of the of the
is being aware of the of the field
is being aware of the of the field in
which
which all
is being aware of the of the field in
which all is
which all is happening.
is being aware of the of the field in
which all is happening. And
which all is happening. And you
is being aware of the of the field in
which all is happening. And you begin
which all is happening. And you begin to
see
see everything
see everything is
see everything is happening
automatically
automatically of
see everything is happening
automatically of its
automatically of its own
see everything is happening
automatically of its own accord
automatically of its own accord as
see everything is happening
automatically of its own accord as an
expression
expression of
expression of of
expression of of its
expression of of its own
expression of of its own design
expression of of its own design as
expression of of its own design as an
expression
expression of
expression of of its own design as an
expression of its
expression of its own
expression of of its own design as an
expression of its own potentiality
becoming
becoming an
becoming an actuality.
And
And it's
becoming an actuality.
And it's so
And it's so everything
becoming an actuality.
And it's so everything is
And it's so everything is unfolding
becoming an actuality.
And it's so everything is unfolding of
its
its own.
We
We didn't
its own.
We didn't even
We didn't even tell
its own.
We didn't even tell the
We didn't even tell the truth
its own.
We didn't even tell the truth about
We didn't even tell the truth about life
this
this morning,
this morning, did
this morning, did we?
this morning, did we? Wow.
this morning, did we? Wow. It's
this morning, did we? Wow. It's 11:30
already.
>> That's
>> That's right.
>> That's right. We
>> That's right. We got
>> That's right. We got seven.
>> So,
so
so without
so without complaints
which
which are
so without complaints
which are just
which are just add-ons,
this
this life
this life is
magnificent.
magnificent. It's
this life is
magnificent. It's really
>> It
>> It just
>> It just keeps
>> It just keeps unfolding
>> It just keeps unfolding of
>> It just keeps unfolding of its
>> It just keeps unfolding of its own.
>> It just keeps unfolding of its own. See,
because
all
all you
all you can
all you can ever
all you can ever witness
all you can ever witness is
all you can ever witness is potentiality
becoming
becoming actuality.
And
And because
And because it's
And because it's happening
And because it's happening in
And because it's happening in form,
And because it's happening in form, you
think
think there's
And because it's happening in form, you
think there's separation.
But
But recognition
But recognition is
But recognition is from
But recognition is from within.
But recognition is from within. It's
But recognition is from within. It's not
out
out there.
But recognition is from within. It's not
out there. So
out there. So you
But recognition is from within. It's not
out there. So you see
out there. So you see the
potentiality
manifesting
manifesting itself
potentiality
manifesting itself as
manifesting itself as an
potentiality
manifesting itself as an actuality.
And
And because
And because it's
And because it's witnessed
And because it's witnessed sequentially,
one
one presumes
And because it's witnessed sequentially,
one presumes that
one presumes that that
And because it's witnessed sequentially,
one presumes that that is
one presumes that that is a
And because it's witnessed sequentially,
one presumes that that is a sequence
happening
happening in
happening in the
happening in the world.
happening in the world. The
happening in the world. The sequence
happening in the world. The sequence is
the
the only
happening in the world. The sequence is
the only sequence
the only sequence that's
happening in the world. The sequence is
the only sequence that's happening
the only sequence that's happening is
happening in the world. The sequence is
the only sequence that's happening is in
the
the witnessing.
If
If I
the witnessing.
If I go
If I go through
the witnessing.
If I go through the
If I go through the garden
the witnessing.
If I go through the garden and
If I go through the garden and I
the witnessing.
If I go through the garden and I pick
If I go through the garden and I pick up
a
a tomato
a tomato and
a tomato and then
a tomato and then a
a tomato and then a squash
a tomato and then a squash and
a tomato and then a squash and then
a tomato and then a squash and then a
cucumber,
cucumber, the
a tomato and then a squash and then a
cucumber, the tomato
cucumber, the tomato is
a tomato and then a squash and then a
cucumber, the tomato is not
cucumber, the tomato is not causing
a tomato and then a squash and then a
cucumber, the tomato is not causing me
to
to go
to go to
to go to the
to go to the squash.
to go to the squash. That's
to go to the squash. That's not
to go to the squash. That's not causing
me
me to
to go to the squash. That's not causing
me to go
me to go to
to go to the squash. That's not causing
me to go to the
me to go to the cucumber.
to go to the squash. That's not causing
me to go to the cucumber. You
me to go to the cucumber. You see,
to go to the squash. That's not causing
me to go to the cucumber. You see, but
in
in the
in the Newtonian
in the Newtonian paradigm,
in the Newtonian paradigm, they
in the Newtonian paradigm, they would
you
you could
in the Newtonian paradigm, they would
you could start
you could start setting
in the Newtonian paradigm, they would
you could start setting it
you could start setting it up,
in the Newtonian paradigm, they would
you could start setting it up, setting
it
it up
it up like
it up like this
it up like this is
it up like this is causing
it up like this is causing this,
it up like this is causing this, causing
this,
this, causing
it up like this is causing this, causing
this, causing this.
Nothing
Nothing is
Nothing is causing
Nothing is causing anything
Nothing is causing anything because
Nothing is causing anything because the
field
field really
Nothing is causing anything because the
field really lights
field really lights a
Nothing is causing anything because the
field really lights a butterfly
field really lights a butterfly on
Nothing is causing anything because the
field really lights a butterfly on this.
Nothing
Nothing is
Nothing is causing
Nothing is causing the
Nothing is causing the butterfly
Nothing is causing the butterfly to
light
light on
Nothing is causing the butterfly to
light on that.
light on that. Its
Nothing is causing the butterfly to
light on that. Its potentiality
light on that. Its potentiality to
Nothing is causing the butterfly to
light on that. Its potentiality to land
on
on a
on a flower
on a flower becomes
on a flower becomes an
on a flower becomes an actuality.
It
It just
on a flower becomes an actuality.
It just thinks
It just thinks flower
on a flower becomes an actuality.
It just thinks flower smells
It just thinks flower smells good
on a flower becomes an actuality.
It just thinks flower smells good and
It just thinks flower smells good and so
it
it goes
it goes there.
it goes there. See,
it goes there. See, but
it goes there. See, but there's
it goes there. See, but there's nothing
causing
causing it
it goes there. See, but there's nothing
causing it to
causing it to do
it goes there. See, but there's nothing
causing it to do that.
See,
See, life
See, life then
See, life then is
See, life then is an
See, life then is an unfoldingness
See, life then is an unfoldingness of
potentiality
becoming
becoming actuality.
And
And you
becoming actuality.
And you see
And you see that
becoming actuality.
And you see that all
And you see that all things
becoming actuality.
And you see that all things are
And you see that all things are just
happening
happening spontaneously
happening spontaneously of
happening spontaneously of their
happening spontaneously of their own.
Just
Just like
happening spontaneously of their own.
Just like this
Just like this lady's
happening spontaneously of their own.
Just like this lady's son
Just like this lady's son or
happening spontaneously of their own.
Just like this lady's son or whoever
Just like this lady's son or whoever it
is
is is
is is going
is is going to
is is going to bring
is is going to bring himself
is is going to bring himself right
is is going to bring himself right down
to
to frankly
is is going to bring himself right down
to frankly killing
to frankly killing himself
is is going to bring himself right down
to frankly killing himself and
to frankly killing himself and maybe
kill
kill himself
kill himself and
kill himself and then
kill himself and then he'll
kill himself and then he'll unfold
kill himself and then he'll unfold as
kill himself and then he'll unfold as a
potentiality.
potentiality. Oh.
So
So why
So why would
So why would one
So why would one interfere
So why would one interfere with
creation?
creation? You
So why would one interfere with
creation? You see
creation? You see so
So why would one interfere with
creation? You see so you
creation? You see so you see
So why would one interfere with
creation? You see so you see life
creation? You see so you see life is
So why would one interfere with
creation? You see so you see life is the
unfolding
unfolding of
unfolding of creation.
unfolding of creation. The
unfolding of creation. The witnessing
unfolding of creation. The witnessing of
the
the unfolding
unfolding of creation. The witnessing of
the unfolding of
the unfolding of creation.
unfolding of creation. The witnessing of
the unfolding of creation. Human
the unfolding of creation. Human life
unfolding of creation. The witnessing of
the unfolding of creation. Human life is
the
the witnessing
the witnessing of
the witnessing of the
the witnessing of the unfolding
the witnessing of the unfolding of
creation.
The
The witnessing
The witnessing to
The witnessing to the
The witnessing to the to
The witnessing to the to the
The witnessing to the to the singularity
of
of the
The witnessing to the to the singularity
of the observer
of the observer that
The witnessing to the to the singularity
of the observer that therefore
of the observer that therefore seems
sequential
to
to every
sequential
to every hornness
to every hornness of
sequential
to every hornness of reality.
to every hornness of reality. There
sequential
to every hornness of reality. There is
no
no sequence.
no sequence. So
no sequence. So there
no sequence. So there is
no sequence. So there is no
no sequence. So there is no sequential
due
due to
no sequence. So there is no sequential
due to the
due to the ominous
no sequence. So there is no sequential
due to the ominous presence
of
of consciousness.
of consciousness. It
of consciousness. It does
of consciousness. It does not
of consciousness. It does not see
sequence
sequence at
of consciousness. It does not see
sequence at all.
sequence at all. doesn't
of consciousness. It does not see
sequence at all. doesn't see
sequence at all. doesn't see sequence.
It
It only
It only sees
It only sees the
It only sees the unfoldingness
It only sees the unfoldingness of
everything.
everything. But
It only sees the unfoldingness of
everything. But it
everything. But it doesn't
program
program that
program that conceptually
program that conceptually as
program that conceptually as a
program that conceptually as a se
program that conceptually as a se as
program that conceptually as a se as a
sequence.
sequence. The
program that conceptually as a se as a
sequence. The butterfly
sequence. The butterfly doesn't
experience
experience sequence.
experience sequence. It
experience sequence. It only
experience sequence. It only experiences
flowers.
An
An easier
An easier way
An easier way to
An easier way to see
An easier way to see how
An easier way to see how to
An easier way to see how to how
An easier way to see how to how to
An easier way to see how to how to get
beyond
beyond a
An easier way to see how to how to get
beyond a sequential
beyond a sequential as
An easier way to see how to how to get
beyond a sequential as as
beyond a sequential as as a
An easier way to see how to how to get
beyond a sequential as as a Newtonian
reality
is
is the
reality
is the holographic
is the holographic paradigm.
reality
is the holographic paradigm. No
holographic
holographic conceptualization.
holographic conceptualization. Of
course,
course, hologram
holographic conceptualization. Of
course, hologram is
course, hologram is again
holographic conceptualization. Of
course, hologram is again a
conceptualization,
conceptualization, but
conceptualization, but it's
conceptualization, but it's one
conceptualization, but it's one little
closer
closer to
conceptualization, but it's one little
closer to reality
closer to reality that
conceptualization, but it's one little
closer to reality that what
closer to reality that what seems
conceptualization, but it's one little
closer to reality that what seems to
closer to reality that what seems to be
depends
depends on
depends on how
depends on how you're
depends on how you're looking
depends on how you're looking at
depends on how you're looking at it.
depends on how you're looking at it. And
as
as you
depends on how you're looking at it. And
as you look
as you look at
depends on how you're looking at it. And
as you look at it
as you look at it this
depends on how you're looking at it. And
as you look at it this way,
as you look at it this way, it
depends on how you're looking at it. And
as you look at it this way, it looks
this
this way.
this way. And
this way. And when
this way. And when you
this way. And when you look
this way. And when you look at
this way. And when you look at it
this way. And when you look at it this
way,
way, and
this way. And when you look at it this
way, and the
way, and the only
this way. And when you look at it this
way, and the only thing
way, and the only thing that
this way. And when you look at it this
way, and the only thing that has
way, and the only thing that has changed
is
is the
is the point
is the point of
is the point of observation.
From
From the
is the point of observation.
From the viewpoint
From the viewpoint of
is the point of observation.
From the viewpoint of real,
From the viewpoint of real, the
is the point of observation.
From the viewpoint of real, the absolute
reality,
reality, the
reality, the source
reality, the source out
reality, the source out of
reality, the source out of which
conscious
conscious arises,
reality, the source out of which
conscious arises, there
conscious arises, there is
reality, the source out of which
conscious arises, there is no
conscious arises, there is no sequence.
Therefore,
Therefore, there's
Therefore, there's no
Therefore, there's no illusion.
Therefore, there's no illusion. to
transcend,
transcend, you
Therefore, there's no illusion. to
transcend, you know,
transcend, you know, cuz
Therefore, there's no illusion. to
transcend, you know, cuz they
transcend, you know, cuz they one
doesn't
doesn't believe
doesn't believe that
doesn't believe that that's
doesn't believe that that's the
doesn't believe that that's the way
doesn't believe that that's the way it
is
is in
doesn't believe that that's the way it
is in the
is in the first
doesn't believe that that's the way it
is in the first place.
is in the first place. One
doesn't believe that that's the way it
is in the first place. One just
is in the first place. One just is
doesn't believe that that's the way it
is in the first place. One just is all
that
that is.
>> I
>> I still
that is.
>> I still have
>> I still have time
that is.
>> I still have time for
>> I still have time for a
that is.
>> I still have time for a question.
>> Is
>> Is that
>> Is that your
>> Is that your question?
>> No,
>> No, my
>> Is that your question?
>> No, my question
>> No, my question was
>> You
>> You can
>> You can throw
>> You can throw me.
>> I
>> I thought
>> You can throw me.
>> I thought that
>> I thought that was
>> You can throw me.
>> I thought that was your
>> I thought that was your question.
I'll
I'll ask
I'll ask you
I'll ask you if
I'll ask you if you
I'll ask you if you if
I'll ask you if you if you
I'll ask you if you if you don't
I'll ask you if you if you don't I'll
ask
ask you
I'll ask you if you if you don't I'll
ask you and
ask you and if
I'll ask you if you if you don't I'll
ask you and if you
ask you and if you don't
I'll ask you if you if you don't I'll
ask you and if you don't have
ask you and if you don't have time
I'll ask you if you if you don't I'll
ask you and if you don't have time you
can
can throw
can throw me
can throw me out.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. The
can throw me out.
>> Okay. The question
>> Okay. The question was
can throw me out.
>> Okay. The question was the
>> Okay. The question was the way
can throw me out.
>> Okay. The question was the way you
>> Okay. The question was the way you use
the
the words
the words um
the words um entity
the words um entity and
the words um entity and um
the words um entity and um soul.
the words um entity and um soul. I
the words um entity and um soul. I never
heard
heard them
the words um entity and um soul. I never
heard them really
heard them really explain
the words um entity and um soul. I never
heard them really explain what
heard them really explain what you
the words um entity and um soul. I never
heard them really explain what you mean
by
by them
by them entity
by them entity and
by them entity and what
by them entity and what you
by them entity and what you mean
by them entity and what you mean by
soul.
soul. I
by them entity and what you mean by
soul. I assume
soul. I assume that
by them entity and what you mean by
soul. I assume that entity
soul. I assume that entity is
by them entity and what you mean by
soul. I assume that entity is kind
soul. I assume that entity is kind of
like
like egoic
like egoic consciousness
like egoic consciousness or
like egoic consciousness or small
like egoic consciousness or small ass
self.
self. Is
like egoic consciousness or small ass
self. Is that
self. Is that what
like egoic consciousness or small ass
self. Is that what that
self. Is that what that uh
like egoic consciousness or small ass
self. Is that what that uh and
self. Is that what that uh and I
like egoic consciousness or small ass
self. Is that what that uh and I finally
found
found a
found a page
found a page in
found a page in I
found a page in I don't know
found a page in I don't know something
in
in the
found a page in I don't know something
in the book
in the book I
found a page in I don't know something
in the book I soul
in the book I soul is
uh
uh non-physical
egoic
egoic uh
uh non-physical
egoic uh ego
egoic uh ego non-phys
uh non-physical
egoic uh ego non-phys which
egoic uh ego non-phys which I
uh non-physical
egoic uh ego non-phys which I found
egoic uh ego non-phys which I found kind
of
of interesting
of interesting and
of interesting and then
of interesting and then it
of interesting and then it I
of interesting and then it I I
of interesting and then it I I would
assume
assume from
of interesting and then it I I would
assume from that
assume from that at
of interesting and then it I I would
assume from that at some
assume from that at some point
that
that that
that that soul
that that soul itself
that that soul itself gets
that that soul itself gets seen
that that soul itself gets seen through
in
in because
that that soul itself gets seen through
in because soul
in because soul steals
that that soul itself gets seen through
in because soul steals like
in because soul steals like a
that that soul itself gets seen through
in because soul steals like a separation
from
from the
from the whole
from the whole from
from the whole from from
from the whole from from self.
from the whole from from self. So
from the whole from from self. So I'm
sort
sort of
from the whole from from self. So I'm
sort of curious
sort of curious about
from the whole from from self. So I'm
sort of curious about self
sort of curious about self in
relationship
relationship to
relationship to all
relationship to all this
relationship to all this self.
>> It
>> It has
relationship to all this self.
>> It has to
>> It has to do
relationship to all this self.
>> It has to do with
>> It has to do with um
relationship to all this self.
>> It has to do with um the
>> It has to do with um the nature
relationship to all this self.
>> It has to do with um the nature of
consciousness
consciousness itself
consciousness itself as
consciousness itself as as
consciousness itself as as energy
as
as energy
consciousness itself as as energy
as energy rather
as energy rather than
consciousness itself as as energy
as energy rather than a
as energy rather than a physicality
that
that dissolves
that dissolves too
that dissolves too because
that dissolves too because physicality
at
at it
that dissolves too because physicality
at it at
at it at its
that dissolves too because physicality
at it at its most
at it at its most basic
that dissolves too because physicality
at it at its most basic level
at it at its most basic level again
dissolves
dissolves into
dissolves into energy.
dissolves into energy. So
dissolves into energy. So that
dissolves into energy. So that mass
dissolves into energy. So that mass and
energy
energy are
dissolves into energy. So that mass and
energy are one
energy are one and
dissolves into energy. So that mass and
energy are one and the
energy are one and the same
dissolves into energy. So that mass and
energy are one and the same thing.
All
All it
All it that
All it that exists
All it that exists within
All it that exists within discernable
domain
is
is reducible
is reducible to
is reducible to energy
is reducible to energy patterns.
is reducible to energy patterns. Huh?
The
The only
is reducible to energy patterns. Huh?
The only thing
The only thing that
is reducible to energy patterns. Huh?
The only thing that can
The only thing that can move
is reducible to energy patterns. Huh?
The only thing that can move supposedly
move
move through
move through time
move through time or
move through time or sequential
move through time or sequential is
move through time or sequential is is
patterns.
And
And so
And so that
And so that which
And so that which is
And so that which is beyond
And so that which is beyond patterns
And so that which is beyond patterns but
the
the source
And so that which is beyond patterns but
the source the
the source the matrix
And so that which is beyond patterns but
the source the matrix out
the source the matrix out of
And so that which is beyond patterns but
the source the matrix out of which
the source the matrix out of which in
which
which the
which the pattern
which the pattern can
which the pattern can take
which the pattern can take form
which the pattern can take form is
which the pattern can take form is the
ultimate
ultimate reality.
which the pattern can take form is the
ultimate reality. See,
ultimate reality. See, so
which the pattern can take form is the
ultimate reality. See, so you
ultimate reality. See, so you can't
confuse
confuse the
confuse the unmanifest
confuse the unmanifest and
confuse the unmanifest and the
confuse the unmanifest and the manifest.
So
So the
confuse the unmanifest and the manifest.
So the manifest
So the manifest is
confuse the unmanifest and the manifest.
So the manifest is within
So the manifest is within a
confuse the unmanifest and the manifest.
So the manifest is within a vibrational
energy
energy field
energy field of
energy field of a
energy field of a potentiality
which
man
man projects
man projects back
man projects back and
man projects back and says
man projects back and says is
man projects back and says is due
man projects back and says is due to
man projects back and says is due to the
valition
valition of
man projects back and says is due to the
valition of God.
valition of God. It
man projects back and says is due to the
valition of God. It was
valition of God. It was out
man projects back and says is due to the
valition of God. It was out of
valition of God. It was out of God's
choice
choice to
choice to create
the
the universe
and
and all
and all that
and all that lives
and all that lives within
and all that lives within it.
and all that lives within it. that
and all that lives within it. that sort
of
of personalizing
and all that lives within it. that sort
of personalizing and
of personalizing and an
and all that lives within it. that sort
of personalizing and an anthropomorphic
projection
projection onto
projection onto divinity
with
with unmanifest
projection onto divinity
with unmanifest intends
with unmanifest intends anything
projection onto divinity
with unmanifest intends anything at
with unmanifest intends anything at all
is
is not
is not really
is not really knowable.
>> Mhm.
>> Because
>> Because then
>> Because then it
>> Because then it would
>> Because then it would be
>> Because then it would be manifest
already.
already. It
>> Because then it would be manifest
already. It wouldn't
already. It wouldn't be
>> Because then it would be manifest
already. It wouldn't be unmanifest.
We'll
We'll worry
We'll worry about
We'll worry about that
We'll worry about that some
We'll worry about that some other
We'll worry about that some other time.
By
what
what process
what process does
what process does the
what process does the unmanifest
what process does the unmanifest become
manifest?
manifest? Then
because
because that's
because that's the
because that's the expression
because that's the expression of
because that's the expression of its
essence
because
because that
because that is
because that is its
because that is its reality.
That
That doesn't
because that is its reality.
That doesn't need
That doesn't need an
because that is its reality.
That doesn't need an explanation.
Yeah.
Yeah. Thank
Yeah. Thank you.
You're
You're going
Yeah. Thank you.
You're going to
You're going to be
Yeah. Thank you.
You're going to be an
You're going to be an easier
Yeah. Thank you.
You're going to be an easier one.
>> I
>> I hope
>> I hope so.
>> I hope so. I'll
>> I hope so. I'll try
>> I hope so. I'll try and
>> I hope so. I'll try and make
>> I hope so. I'll try and make you
>> I hope so. I'll try and make you were
the
the toughest,
>> I hope so. I'll try and make you were
the toughest, wasn't
the toughest, wasn't you?
>> First
>> First of
>> First of all,
>> First of all, I
>> First of all, I just
>> First of all, I just want
>> First of all, I just want to
>> First of all, I just want to say
>> First of all, I just want to say that
it's
it's it's
>> First of all, I just want to say that
it's it's a
it's it's a pleasure
>> First of all, I just want to say that
it's it's a pleasure to
it's it's a pleasure to uh
>> First of all, I just want to say that
it's it's a pleasure to uh to
it's it's a pleasure to uh to be
>> First of all, I just want to say that
it's it's a pleasure to uh to be here.
Uh
Uh my
Uh my girlfriend
Uh my girlfriend and
Uh my girlfriend and I
Uh my girlfriend and I started
Uh my girlfriend and I started reading
your
your material
Uh my girlfriend and I started reading
your material about
your material about a
Uh my girlfriend and I started reading
your material about a year
your material about a year ago
Uh my girlfriend and I started reading
your material about a year ago and
your material about a year ago and just
have
have been
have been drawn
have been drawn to
have been drawn to you
have been drawn to you and
have been drawn to you and it's
have been drawn to you and it's it's
wonderful.
wonderful. My
have been drawn to you and it's it's
wonderful. My question
wonderful. My question is
have been drawn to you and it's it's
wonderful. My question is a
wonderful. My question is a two-part
question.
question. We've
question. We've also
question. We've also started
question. We've also started um
question. We've also started um taking
classes
classes in
question. We've also started um taking
classes in a
classes in a course
question. We've also started um taking
classes in a course of
classes in a course of miracles
question. We've also started um taking
classes in a course of miracles and
classes in a course of miracles and the
two
two two-part
two two-part question
two two-part question is
two two-part question is first
two two-part question is first of
two two-part question is first of all
can
can you
two two-part question is first of all
can you help
can you help explain
two two-part question is first of all
can you help explain a
can you help explain a little
two two-part question is first of all
can you help explain a little bit
can you help explain a little bit the
concept
concept of
concept of this
concept of this is
concept of this is all
concept of this is all um
concept of this is all um an
concept of this is all um an illusion.
The
The whole
concept of this is all um an illusion.
The whole world
The whole world is
concept of this is all um an illusion.
The whole world is an
The whole world is an illusion
concept of this is all um an illusion.
The whole world is an illusion what
The whole world is an illusion what we
see.
see. And
see. And second
see. And second part
see. And second part is
see. And second part is if
see. And second part is if the
see. And second part is if the course
see. And second part is if the course I
think
think in
see. And second part is if the course I
think in one
think in one of
see. And second part is if the course I
think in one of your
think in one of your books
see. And second part is if the course I
think in one of your books it
think in one of your books it says
see. And second part is if the course I
think in one of your books it says it
calibrates
calibrates in
calibrates in the
calibrates in the 600s
calibrates in the 600s or
calibrates in the 600s or somewhere
calibrates in the 600s or somewhere in
there.
>> Mhm.
>> Mhm. What's
>> Mhm. What's what
>> Mhm. What's what is
>> Mhm. What's what is precluding
>> Mhm. What's what is precluding it
>> Mhm. What's what is precluding it from
calibrating
calibrating higher?
>> Mhm. What's what is precluding it from
calibrating higher? And
calibrating higher? And what
>> Mhm. What's what is precluding it from
calibrating higher? And what does
calibrating higher? And what does my
question
question of
question of that
question of that even
question of that even mean?
question of that even mean? What
question of that even mean? What does
question of that even mean? What does it
mean
mean to
question of that even mean? What does it
mean to calibrate
mean to calibrate even
question of that even mean? What does it
mean to calibrate even higher?
>> It
>> It means
>> It means you
>> It means you don't
>> It means you don't have
>> It means you don't have to
>> It means you don't have to worry
>> It means you don't have to worry about
it
it yet.
Um
now
now that
Um
now that question
now that question does
Um
now that question does arise
now that question does arise and
Um
now that question does arise and it
becomes
becomes out
becomes out al
becomes out al also
becomes out al also the
becomes out al also the ancient
becomes out al also the ancient Hindu
literature
literature and
becomes out al also the ancient Hindu
literature and all
literature and all uh
becomes out al also the ancient Hindu
literature and all uh that
literature and all uh that the
becomes out al also the ancient Hindu
literature and all uh that the world
literature and all uh that the world you
see
see it
see it doesn't
see it doesn't even
see it doesn't even exist
see it doesn't even exist you
see it doesn't even exist you see
see it doesn't even exist you see so
see it doesn't even exist you see so it
doesn't
doesn't mean
see it doesn't even exist you see so it
doesn't mean that
doesn't mean that the
see it doesn't even exist you see so it
doesn't mean that the hologram
doesn't mean that the hologram let's
see it doesn't even exist you see so it
doesn't mean that the hologram let's say
uh
uh doesn't
uh doesn't exist
uh doesn't exist it
uh doesn't exist it means
uh doesn't exist it means that
uh doesn't exist it means that your
perception
perception of
uh doesn't exist it means that your
perception of it
perception of it is
uh doesn't exist it means that your
perception of it is not
perception of it is not what
uh doesn't exist it means that your
perception of it is not what it
perception of it is not what it is
uh doesn't exist it means that your
perception of it is not what it is what
you
you think
you think it
you think it means
you think it means what
you think it means what you
you think it means what you believe
you think it means what you believe It
means
means what
you think it means what you believe It
means what you
means what you see
you think it means what you believe It
means what you see it,
means what you see it, what
you think it means what you believe It
means what you see it, what you
means what you see it, what you think
it,
it, your
it, your perception
it, your perception is
it, your perception is not
it, your perception is not the
it, your perception is not the way
it, your perception is not the way it
is.
is. First
it, your perception is not the way it
is. First of
is. First of all,
it, your perception is not the way it
is. First of all, perception
is. First of all, perception arbitrarily
selects
selects out
selects out of
selects out of time.
selects out of time. See,
selects out of time. See, all
selects out of time. See, all things
selects out of time. See, all things are
in
in the
selects out of time. See, all things are
in the process
in the process of
selects out of time. See, all things are
in the process of evolution.
in the process of evolution. So,
selects out of time. See, all things are
in the process of evolution. So, per
perception
perception does
perception does like
perception does like a
perception does like a cross-section
chop.
chop. It
perception does like a cross-section
chop. It puts
chop. It puts it
perception does like a cross-section
chop. It puts it up
chop. It puts it up on
perception does like a cross-section
chop. It puts it up on the
chop. It puts it up on the screen
perception does like a cross-section
chop. It puts it up on the screen and
says
says this
says this the
says this the way
says this the way it
says this the way it is.
So,
So, it
says this the way it is.
So, it takes
So, it takes it
says this the way it is.
So, it takes it out
So, it takes it out of
says this the way it is.
So, it takes it out of time.
So, it takes it out of time. It
says this the way it is.
So, it takes it out of time. It takes
So, it takes it out of time. It takes it
out
out of
out of context.
And
And uh
out of context.
And uh so
And uh so perception
out of context.
And uh so perception by
And uh so perception by virtue
out of context.
And uh so perception by virtue like
And uh so perception by virtue like a
camera
camera you
camera you know
camera you know takes
camera you know takes a
camera you know takes a snapshot
but
but it
camera you know takes a snapshot
but it takes
but it takes it
camera you know takes a snapshot
but it takes it out
but it takes it out of
camera you know takes a snapshot
but it takes it out of time.
but it takes it out of time. It
camera you know takes a snapshot
but it takes it out of time. It takes
but it takes it out of time. It takes it
out
out of
out of meaning
out of meaning takes
out of meaning takes it
out of meaning takes it out
out of meaning takes it out of
out of meaning takes it out of karmic
evolution.
So
So we
So we can't
So we can't really
So we can't really see.
So we can't really see. The
So we can't really see. The reason
So we can't really see. The reason we
can't
can't judge
So we can't really see. The reason we
can't judge anything
can't judge anything is
So we can't really see. The reason we
can't judge anything is because
can't judge anything is because we
So we can't really see. The reason we
can't judge anything is because we can't
even
even see
even see what
even see what it
even see what it is.
even see what it is. You
even see what it is. You know
even see what it is. You know all
even see what it is. You know all we
have
have is
even see what it is. You know all we
have is an
have is an appearance
and
and then
and then make
and then make a
and then make a snap
and then make a snap judgment
and then make a snap judgment on
and then make a snap judgment on an
appearance.
appearance. And
and then make a snap judgment on an
appearance. And the
appearance. And the appearance
and then make a snap judgment on an
appearance. And the appearance of
appearance. And the appearance of course
is
is not
is not what
is not what the
is not what the thing
is not what the thing is.
is not what the thing is. And
is not what the thing is. And then
is not what the thing is. And then when
we
we see
is not what the thing is. And then when
we see what
we see what the
is not what the thing is. And then when
we see what the thing
we see what the thing is,
is not what the thing is. And then when
we see what the thing is, it
we see what the thing is, it all
dissolves.
dissolves. So
dissolves. So when
dissolves. So when you
dissolves. So when you ask
dissolves. So when you ask the
dissolves. So when you ask the Holy
Spirit
Spirit to
dissolves. So when you ask the Holy
Spirit to for
Spirit to for a
dissolves. So when you ask the Holy
Spirit to for a miracle,
Spirit to for a miracle, what
dissolves. So when you ask the Holy
Spirit to for a miracle, what you're
asking
asking the
asking the Holy
asking the Holy Spirit
asking the Holy Spirit to
asking the Holy Spirit to do
asking the Holy Spirit to do is
asking the Holy Spirit to do is to
recontextualize
recontextualize this
asking the Holy Spirit to do is to
recontextualize this thing,
recontextualize this thing, to
asking the Holy Spirit to do is to
recontextualize this thing, to take
recontextualize this thing, to take it
out
out of
out of time,
out of time, place,
out of time, place, judgmental,
limitation
limitation of
out of time, place, judgmental,
limitation of perception
limitation of perception and
out of time, place, judgmental,
limitation of perception and reveal
limitation of perception and reveal it,
you
you know,
you know, as
you know, as as
you know, as as a
you know, as as a consequence
you know, as as a consequence of
you know, as as a consequence of the
field,
which
which takes
which takes you
which takes you out
which takes you out of
which takes you out of temporal
which takes you out of temporal time.
which takes you out of temporal time. So
it's
it's saying
which takes you out of temporal time. So
it's saying that
it's saying that temporal
which takes you out of temporal time. So
it's saying that temporal time
it's saying that temporal time and
which takes you out of temporal time. So
it's saying that temporal time and the
appearance,
appearance, the
appearance, the illusion
appearance, the illusion of
appearance, the illusion of sequence,
etc.,
etc., which
appearance, the illusion of sequence,
etc., which we
etc., which we just
appearance, the illusion of sequence,
etc., which we just talked
etc., which we just talked about
appearance, the illusion of sequence,
etc., which we just talked about a
etc., which we just talked about a few
minutes
minutes ago
minutes ago is
minutes ago is just
minutes ago is just an
minutes ago is just an illusion
minutes ago is just an illusion and
minutes ago is just an illusion and that
you
you know
minutes ago is just an illusion and that
you know such
you know such no
minutes ago is just an illusion and that
you know such no such
you know such no such sequence
minutes ago is just an illusion and that
you know such no such sequence is
you know such no such sequence is even
happening
and
and um
happening
and um the
and um the reason
happening
and um the reason you
and um the reason you can't
happening
and um the reason you can't judge
and um the reason you can't judge about
anything
anything make
anything make any
anything make any judgment
anything make any judgment good
anything make any judgment good or
anything make any judgment good or bad
by
by the
anything make any judgment good or bad
by the way
by the way people
anything make any judgment good or bad
by the way people think
by the way people think good
anything make any judgment good or bad
by the way people think good judgments
are
are okay
are okay now
are okay now they're
are okay now they're the
are okay now they're the same
are okay now they're the same downside
as
as bad
are okay now they're the same downside
as bad ones
as bad ones because
are okay now they're the same downside
as bad ones because they're
as bad ones because they're still
are okay now they're the same downside
as bad ones because they're still based
on
on illusion
on illusion of
on illusion of merit
on illusion of merit that
on illusion of merit that that
on illusion of merit that that you
on illusion of merit that that you have
the
the capacity
on illusion of merit that that you have
the capacity to
the capacity to arrive
on illusion of merit that that you have
the capacity to arrive at
the capacity to arrive at a
on illusion of merit that that you have
the capacity to arrive at a current
judgment
judgment unless
judgment unless you
judgment unless you see
judgment unless you see where
judgment unless you see where that
judgment unless you see where that is
judgment unless you see where that is at
evolutionary
evolutionary time.
Let's
Let's say
Let's say a
Let's say a person
Let's say a person goes
Let's say a person goes out
Let's say a person goes out of
Let's say a person goes out of a
Let's say a person goes out of a body
after
after the
Let's say a person goes out of a body
after the fourth
after the fourth lifetime
Let's say a person goes out of a body
after the fourth lifetime of
after the fourth lifetime of failure
Let's say a person goes out of a body
after the fourth lifetime of failure and
says
this
this time
says
this time I'm
this time I'm going
says
this time I'm going to
this time I'm going to make
says
this time I'm going to make it
this time I'm going to make it or
says
this time I'm going to make it or die
and
and chooses
and chooses the
and chooses the pathway
and chooses the pathway of
and chooses the pathway of addiction
as
as they
and chooses the pathway of addiction
as they go
as they go to
and chooses the pathway of addiction
as they go to hit
as they go to hit bottom.
and chooses the pathway of addiction
as they go to hit bottom. Uh
then
then what
then what you're
then what you're seeing
then what you're seeing is
then what you're seeing is a
then what you're seeing is a success.
said
finally
finally getting
finally getting near
finally getting near the
finally getting near the end
finally getting near the end lifetime
after
after lifetime
finally getting near the end lifetime
after lifetime of
after lifetime of agony,
finally getting near the end lifetime
after lifetime of agony, pain,
after lifetime of agony, pain, and
suffering.
suffering. Randy
suffering. Randy had
suffering. Randy had desperately
successful
successful lifetime
suffering. Randy had desperately
successful lifetime that
successful lifetime that you're
witnessing
for
for us
witnessing
for us to
for us to say,
witnessing
for us to say, "Oh,
for us to say, "Oh, he's
witnessing
for us to say, "Oh, he's a
for us to say, "Oh, he's a spiritual
failure
failure because
failure because he
failure because he hasn't
failure because he hasn't surrendered
yet."
yet." Wow.
failure because he hasn't surrendered
yet." Wow. You
yet." Wow. You can't
failure because he hasn't surrendered
yet." Wow. You can't surrender
yet." Wow. You can't surrender until
failure because he hasn't surrendered
yet." Wow. You can't surrender until you
surrender.
And
And we
surrender.
And we turn
And we turn up
surrender.
And we turn up the
And we turn up the energy,
the
the dole
the dole meter
the dole meter that
the dole meter that measures
the dole meter that measures pain.
The
The ego
the dole meter that measures pain.
The ego lets
The ego lets go.
So
So who
So who would
So who would throw
So who would throw themsself
So who would throw themsself into
So who would throw themsself into a
So who would throw themsself into a pain
meter,
meter, a
So who would throw themsself into a pain
meter, a pain
meter, a pain machine?
Only
Only a
Only a person
Only a person desperate
Only a person desperate to
Only a person desperate to reach
Only a person desperate to reach God.
Spiritual
Spiritual desperation
Only a person desperate to reach God.
Spiritual desperation drives
Spiritual desperation drives people
Only a person desperate to reach God.
Spiritual desperation drives people to
such
such extremes.
So
So we
such extremes.
So we can't
So we can't say
such extremes.
So we can't say good
So we can't say good or
such extremes.
So we can't say good or bad.
So we can't say good or bad. We're
such extremes.
So we can't say good or bad. We're glad
if
if he
if he makes
if he makes it,
but
but if
if he makes it,
but if he
but if he makes
if he makes it,
but if he makes it,
but if he makes it, we
if he makes it,
but if he makes it, we say
but if he makes it, we say glad
if he makes it,
but if he makes it, we say glad to
but if he makes it, we say glad to see
you.
you. But
you. But yeah,
you. But yeah, so
you. But yeah, so it's
you. But yeah, so it's outside
you. But yeah, so it's outside of
judgmentalism.
And
And we
And we know
And we know that,
And we know that, you
And we know that, you know,
And we know that, you know, perception
itself
itself then
And we know that, you know, perception
itself then is
itself then is limitation
And we know that, you know, perception
itself then is limitation and
itself then is limitation and beyond
perception
perception is
perception is revealed
perception is revealed a
perception is revealed a different
world.
Also,
Also, there's
Also, there's different
Also, there's different levels
Also, there's different levels of
reality
reality going
Also, there's different levels of
reality going on
reality going on at
Also, there's different levels of
reality going on at the
reality going on at the same
Also, there's different levels of
reality going on at the same time.
reality
reality and
reality and codes.
reality and codes. And
reality and codes. And as
reality and codes. And as one
reality and codes. And as one moves
through
through the
reality and codes. And as one moves
through the course
through the course of
reality and codes. And as one moves
through the course of miracles,
through the course of miracles, one
seems
seems to
seems to move
seems to move into
seems to move into a
seems to move into a different
seems to move into a different world
seems to move into a different world in
which
which everything
seems to move into a different world in
which everything seems
which everything seems to
seems to move into a different world in
which everything seems to happen
wonderfully.
wonderfully. I
wonderfully. I mean,
wonderfully. I mean, you
wonderfully. I mean, you drive
wonderfully. I mean, you drive up
wonderfully. I mean, you drive up there
and
and there's
wonderfully. I mean, you drive up there
and there's a
and there's a parking
wonderfully. I mean, you drive up there
and there's a parking space
and there's a parking space and
wonderfully. I mean, you drive up there
and there's a parking space and then
your
your lost
your lost button
your lost button shows
your lost button shows up
your lost button shows up and
your lost button shows up and it
your lost button shows up and it all
seems
seems automatic.
your lost button shows up and it all
seems automatic. Didn't
seems automatic. Didn't used
your lost button shows up and it all
seems automatic. Didn't used to
seems automatic. Didn't used to be
your lost button shows up and it all
seems automatic. Didn't used to be that
way.
You
You never
way.
You never find
You never find a
way.
You never find a parking
You never find a parking place.
Everybody
Everybody gave
Everybody gave you
Everybody gave you a
Everybody gave you a dented
Everybody gave you a dented fender.
Everybody gave you a dented fender. You
never
never found
Everybody gave you a dented fender. You
never found a
never found a button.
Life
Life was
Life was horrible.
Life was horrible. Really?
No,
No, the
Life was horrible. Really?
No, the miraculous
No, the miraculous just
Life was horrible. Really?
No, the miraculous just seems
No, the miraculous just seems to
Life was horrible. Really?
No, the miraculous just seems to unfold.
Wonderful
Wonderful things
Wonderful things happen.
Wonderful things happen. Wonderful
people
people appear
Wonderful things happen. Wonderful
people appear in
people appear in your
Wonderful things happen. Wonderful
people appear in your life.
Money
Money for
Money for whatever
Money for whatever you
Money for whatever you think
Money for whatever you think you
Money for whatever you think you need
appears
appears mysteriously
Money for whatever you think you need
appears mysteriously one
appears mysteriously one way
Money for whatever you think you need
appears mysteriously one way or
appears mysteriously one way or the
other.
other. And
other. And if
other. And if it
other. And if it doesn't,
other. And if it doesn't, you
other. And if it doesn't, you couldn't
care
care less.
So
So why
So why does
So why does it
So why does it only
So why does it only calibrate
So why does it only calibrate in
So why does it only calibrate in the
So why does it only calibrate in the I
shouldn't
shouldn't say
So why does it only calibrate in the I
shouldn't say only.
shouldn't say only. What's
So why does it only calibrate in the I
shouldn't say only. What's precluding
shouldn't say only. What's precluding it
from
from calibrating
from calibrating higher?
>> Nothing's
>> Nothing's precluding
from calibrating higher?
>> Nothing's precluding it
>> Nothing's precluding it from
from calibrating higher?
>> Nothing's precluding it from being
higher.
higher. It
higher. It only
higher. It only chooses
higher. It only chooses to
higher. It only chooses to be
higher. It only chooses to be what
higher. It only chooses to be what it
is.
>> It's
>> It's hard
>> It's hard enough
>> It's hard enough to
>> It's hard enough to grab
>> It's hard enough to grab at
>> It's hard enough to grab at 600.
>> It's hard enough to grab at 600. You
>> It's hard enough to grab at 600. You can
imagine
imagine what
>> It's hard enough to grab at 600. You can
imagine what it'd
imagine what it'd be
>> It's hard enough to grab at 600. You can
imagine what it'd be like
imagine what it'd be like at
>> It's hard enough to grab at 600. You can
imagine what it'd be like at 900.
I
I mean,
I mean, most
I mean, most people
I mean, most people have
I mean, most people have trouble
I mean, most people have trouble getting
a
a Chinese
I mean, most people have trouble getting
a Chinese fortune
a Chinese fortune cookie.
That's
That's only
That's only 350
to
to be
That's only 350
to be kind
to be kind to
That's only 350
to be kind to other
to be kind to other people.
That's only 350
to be kind to other people. I
to be kind to other people. I mean,
whoa.
Let's
Let's see.
whoa.
Let's see. Why
Let's see. Why do
whoa.
Let's see. Why do we
Let's see. Why do we say
whoa.
Let's see. Why do we say 85%
Let's see. Why do we say 85% of
whoa.
Let's see. Why do we say 85% of the
people
people on
people on the
people on the planet
people on the planet calibrate
people on the planet calibrate below
200?
85%
85% of
85% of the
85% of the people
85% of the people on
85% of the people on this
85% of the people on this planet
calibrate
calibrate below
85% of the people on this planet
calibrate below the
calibrate below the level
85% of the people on this planet
calibrate below the level of
calibrate below the level of wisdom
85% of the people on this planet
calibrate below the level of wisdom of
calibrate below the level of wisdom of a
Chinese
Chinese fortune
Chinese fortune cookie.
So
So 600
Chinese fortune cookie.
So 600 is
So 600 is pretty
Chinese fortune cookie.
So 600 is pretty staggeringly
So 600 is pretty staggeringly high
Chinese fortune cookie.
So 600 is pretty staggeringly high for
So 600 is pretty staggeringly high for a
population
population like
population like that.
population like that. It's
population like that. It's a
population like that. It's a wonder
population like that. It's a wonder that
anybody
anybody gets
population like that. It's a wonder that
anybody gets it,
especially
especially intelligent
especially intelligent people.
However,
this
this intelligence
this intelligence got
this intelligence got captivated
this intelligence got captivated by
this intelligence got captivated by the
lesson
lesson that
this intelligence got captivated by the
lesson that says
lesson that says my
this intelligence got captivated by the
lesson that says my thoughts
lesson that says my thoughts don't
this intelligence got captivated by the
lesson that says my thoughts don't mean
anything.
anything. I
anything. I said
anything. I said they
anything. I said they read
anything. I said they read that
anything. I said they read that I
anything. I said they read that I said
this
this is
anything. I said they read that I said
this is genius.
I've
I've been
I've been a
I've been a psychiatrist
I've been a psychiatrist for
I've been a psychiatrist for many
I've been a psychiatrist for many years.
You
You know,
I've been a psychiatrist for many years.
You know, my
You know, my thoughts
I've been a psychiatrist for many years.
You know, my thoughts tell
You know, my thoughts tell me.
I've been a psychiatrist for many years.
You know, my thoughts tell me. Whoa,
man.
man. That's
man. That's fantastic.
I
I knew
man. That's fantastic.
I knew it
I knew it was
man. That's fantastic.
I knew it was a
I knew it was a great
man. That's fantastic.
I knew it was a great book
I knew it was a great book the
man. That's fantastic.
I knew it was a great book the minute
I knew it was a great book the minute I
read
read that.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Mhm.
>> Very
>> Very much.
>> Yes.
>> Mhm.
>> Hope
>> Hope it's
>> Hope it's an
>> Hope it's an easy
>> Hope it's an easy one.
>> Hope it's an easy one. I
>> Hope it's an easy one. I think
>> Hope it's an easy one. I think some
>> Hope it's an easy one. I think some have
a
a question
>> Hope it's an easy one. I think some have
a question about
a question about your
>> Hope it's an easy one. I think some have
a question about your views
a question about your views on
psychotherapy
psychotherapy as
psychotherapy as a
psychotherapy as a method
psychotherapy as a method or
psychotherapy as a method or pathway,
but
but I'd
psychotherapy as a method or pathway,
but I'd first
but I'd first like
psychotherapy as a method or pathway,
but I'd first like to
but I'd first like to ask
psychotherapy as a method or pathway,
but I'd first like to ask another
question
question about
question about your
question about your calibration
question about your calibration method
and
and you
question about your calibration method
and you seem
and you seem to
question about your calibration method
and you seem to put
and you seem to put a
question about your calibration method
and you seem to put a lot
and you seem to put a lot of
question about your calibration method
and you seem to put a lot of faith
and you seem to put a lot of faith into
it
it and
it and I'm
it and I'm curious
it and I'm curious uh
it and I'm curious uh how
it and I'm curious uh how you
it and I'm curious uh how you know
it and I'm curious uh how you know that
it's
it's the
it and I'm curious uh how you know that
it's the truth
it's the truth and
it and I'm curious uh how you know that
it's the truth and um
it's the truth and um Oh,
it and I'm curious uh how you know that
it's the truth and um Oh, I
it's the truth and um Oh, I don't
it and I'm curious uh how you know that
it's the truth and um Oh, I don't and
reliable.
>> No,
>> No, I
reliable.
>> No, I just
>> No, I just I
reliable.
>> No, I just I just
>> No, I just I just know
reliable.
>> No, I just I just know what
>> No, I just I just know what shows
reliable.
>> No, I just I just know what shows up.
How
How do
How do I
How do I know
How do I know it's
How do I know it's the
How do I know it's the truth?
How do I know it's the truth? Couldn't
tell
tell you.
Well,
Well, it
Well, it seems
Well, it seems to
Well, it seems to correlate.
I
I don't
Well, it seems to correlate.
I don't know
I don't know where
Well, it seems to correlate.
I don't know where the
I don't know where the car's
Well, it seems to correlate.
I don't know where the car's going
I don't know where the car's going to
start
start until
start until I
start until I turn
start until I turn the
start until I turn the key
start until I turn the key and
start until I turn the key and it
start until I turn the key and it goes
and
and goes
start until I turn the key and it goes
and goes and
and goes and doesn't
start until I turn the key and it goes
and goes and doesn't I
and goes and doesn't I don't
start until I turn the key and it goes
and goes and doesn't I don't want
and goes and doesn't I don't want to
convince
convince anybody
convince anybody about
convince anybody about it.
It
It all
convince anybody about it.
It all seems
It all seems to
convince anybody about it.
It all seems to fall
It all seems to fall that
convince anybody about it.
It all seems to fall that way
It all seems to fall that way as
convince anybody about it.
It all seems to fall that way as a
pattern.
pattern. See
pattern. See now
pattern. See now some
pattern. See now some people
pattern. See now some people have
evolved
evolved to
pattern. See now some people have
evolved to the
evolved to the point
pattern. See now some people have
evolved to the point uh
evolved to the point uh just
pattern. See now some people have
evolved to the point uh just to
evolved to the point uh just to show
them
them the
them the pattern
them the pattern instantly
them the pattern instantly they
them the pattern instantly they get
them the pattern instantly they get it.
through
through the
them the pattern instantly they get it.
through the evolution
through the evolution of
them the pattern instantly they get it.
through the evolution of consciousness
throughout
throughout all
throughout all of
throughout all of time
throughout all of time and
throughout all of time and all
throughout all of time and all the
throughout all of time and all the the
dimensions
dimensions human
throughout all of time and all the the
dimensions human through
dimensions human through the
throughout all of time and all the the
dimensions human through the intellect
through
through the
through the animal
through the animal kingdom
through the animal kingdom through
life
life itself
once
once you
once you reach
once you reach a
once you reach a certain
once you reach a certain level
once you reach a certain level wisdom
you
you get
once you reach a certain level wisdom
you get aha
you get aha what
once you reach a certain level wisdom
you get aha what it
you get aha what it all
once you reach a certain level wisdom
you get aha what it all means
you get aha what it all means there's
once you reach a certain level wisdom
you get aha what it all means there's no
point
point to
point to make
point to make any
point to make any claim
point to make any claim or
point to make any claim or anything
about
about it
point to make any claim or anything
about it I
about it I don't
point to make any claim or anything
about it I don't claim
about it I don't claim it
point to make any claim or anything
about it I don't claim it as
about it I don't claim it as truth
point to make any claim or anything
about it I don't claim it as truth or
useful
useful or
useful or anything
>> okay
>> the
>> the question
>> the question about
>> the question about psychotherapy
>> the question about psychotherapy is
>> the question about psychotherapy is how
effective
effective do
>> the question about psychotherapy is how
effective do You
effective do You see
>> the question about psychotherapy is how
effective do You see psychoanalysts,
psychoanalysis
psychoanalysis or
psychoanalysis or other
psychoanalysis or other psychoanalytic
therapies,
therapies, body
psychoanalysis or other psychoanalytic
therapies, body work
therapies, body work that
psychoanalysis or other psychoanalytic
therapies, body work that use
therapies, body work that use breath
psychoanalysis or other psychoanalytic
therapies, body work that use breath and
things
things in
things in terms
things in terms of
things in terms of removing
things in terms of removing the
obstacles
obstacles that
things in terms of removing the
obstacles that you
obstacles that you talk
things in terms of removing the
obstacles that you talk about
obstacles that you talk about to
things in terms of removing the
obstacles that you talk about to uh
obstacles that you talk about to uh to
love
love or
love or to
love or to understanding
love or to understanding the
love or to understanding the self
love or to understanding the self uh
better
given
given a
given a case
given a case where
>> well
>> well man
given a case where
>> well man has
>> well man has has
given a case where
>> well man has has all
>> well man has has all kinds
given a case where
>> well man has has all kinds of
>> well man has has all kinds of inventions
and
and discoveries
and discoveries along
and discoveries along the
and discoveries along the way.
and discoveries along the way. So
and discoveries along the way. So these
are
are all
and discoveries along the way. So these
are all various
are all various tools.
and discoveries along the way. So these
are all various tools. All
are all various tools. All various
and discoveries along the way. So these
are all various tools. All various tools
um
some
some of
um
some of which
some of which I've
um
some of which I've experienced
some of which I've experienced some
um
some of which I've experienced some of
which
which I've
which I've only
which I've only heard
which I've only heard about
psychoanalysis
psychoanalysis you
which I've only heard about
psychoanalysis you know
psychoanalysis you know was
which I've only heard about
psychoanalysis you know was a
psychoanalysis you know was a is
which I've only heard about
psychoanalysis you know was a is a
psychoanalysis you know was a is a major
project
uh
uh it
project
uh it leads
uh it leads to
project
uh it leads to a
uh it leads to a sophistication
project
uh it leads to a sophistication and
uh it leads to a sophistication and a
maturity
maturity and
maturity and an
maturity and an understanding
maturity and an understanding of
maturity and an understanding of human
nature
nature and
maturity and an understanding of human
nature and your
nature and your own
maturity and an understanding of human
nature and your own as
nature and your own as well
maturity and an understanding of human
nature and your own as well as
nature and your own as well as other
people's
people's and
people's and the
people's and the unconscious
people's and the unconscious and
people's and the unconscious and the
party
party it
people's and the unconscious and the
party it plays.
So
So it's
So it's a
So it's a form
So it's a form of
So it's a form of education.
So it's a form of education. Form
So it's a form of education. Form of
education.
education. What
So it's a form of education. Form of
education. What other
education. What other people
So it's a form of education. Form of
education. What other people experience
this
this way,
this way, you
this way, you just
this way, you just see
this way, you just see it
this way, you just see it as
this way, you just see it as a
projection
projection from
this way, you just see it as a
projection from the
projection from the ego,
this way, you just see it as a
projection from the ego, you
projection from the ego, you know.
this way, you just see it as a
projection from the ego, you know. So
your
your understanding
your understanding of
your understanding of the
your understanding of the mental
mechanisms,
mechanisms, the
your understanding of the mental
mechanisms, the mind,
mechanisms, the mind, uh
your understanding of the mental
mechanisms, the mind, uh the
mechanisms, the mind, uh the unconscious
and
and how
and how it
and how it all
and how it all fits
and how it all fits together.
Sean
Sean analysis
and how it all fits together.
Sean analysis is
Sean analysis is is
and how it all fits together.
Sean analysis is is part
Sean analysis is is part of
and how it all fits together.
Sean analysis is is part of uh
Sean analysis is is part of uh maturing.
So
So spirituality
So spirituality comes
So spirituality comes out
So spirituality comes out of
So spirituality comes out of matur
maturation.
maturation. So
So spirituality comes out of matur
maturation. So maturation
then
then all
then all that
then all that supports
then all that supports maturation
education,
education, psychotherapy,
then all that supports maturation
education, psychotherapy, psychoanalysis
whatever
whatever is
whatever is supporting
whatever is supporting the
whatever is supporting the ultimate
spiritual
spiritual intention
whatever is supporting the ultimate
spiritual intention because
spiritual intention because when
whatever is supporting the ultimate
spiritual intention because when m
maturity
maturity reaches
maturity reaches a
maturity reaches a certain
maturity reaches a certain point
maturity reaches a certain point it
begins
begins to
maturity reaches a certain point it
begins to look
begins to look beyond
maturity reaches a certain point it
begins to look beyond the
begins to look beyond the intellect.
maturity reaches a certain point it
begins to look beyond the intellect. It
looks
looks for
looks for it
looks for it begins
looks for it begins to
looks for it begins to evolve
looks for it begins to evolve and
looks for it begins to evolve and look
to
to greater
looks for it begins to evolve and look
to greater domains
to greater domains but
looks for it begins to evolve and look
to greater domains but it
to greater domains but it doesn't
looks for it begins to evolve and look
to greater domains but it doesn't do
that
that until
that until it's
that until it's perfected
that until it's perfected itself
that until it's perfected itself to
that until it's perfected itself to a
certain
certain degree
that until it's perfected itself to a
certain degree fulfilled
certain degree fulfilled its
that until it's perfected itself to a
certain degree fulfilled its own
potential.
I
I think
potential.
I think the
I think the psychotherapies
potential.
I think the psychotherapies are
I think the psychotherapies are terrific
and
and uh
and uh when
and uh when I
and uh when I became
and uh when I became a
and uh when I became a psychiatrist
and uh when I became a psychiatrist in
those
those days
and uh when I became a psychiatrist in
those days psychoanalysis
those days psychoanalysis was
and uh when I became a psychiatrist in
those days psychoanalysis was very
those days psychoanalysis was very big
and
and frankly
and frankly you
and frankly you couldn't
and frankly you couldn't really
and frankly you couldn't really do
and frankly you couldn't really do uh
and frankly you couldn't really do uh I
mean
mean you
and frankly you couldn't really do uh I
mean you could
mean you could legally
and frankly you couldn't really do uh I
mean you could legally do
mean you could legally do it
and frankly you couldn't really do uh I
mean you could legally do it but
mean you could legally do it but nobody
would
would even
would even think
would even think of
would even think of doing
would even think of doing uh
psychotherapy
psychotherapy psycho
would even think of doing uh
psychotherapy psycho analysis
psychotherapy psycho analysis unless
they
they had
they had it
they had it done
they had it done themselves
they had it done themselves and
they had it done themselves and who
they had it done themselves and who you
were
were depended
they had it done themselves and who you
were depended on
were depended on who
they had it done themselves and who you
were depended on who your
were depended on who your analyst
they had it done themselves and who you
were depended on who your analyst was
were depended on who your analyst was in
New
New York
New York depended
New York depended pretty
New York depended pretty much
New York depended pretty much whether
you
you was
New York depended pretty much whether
you was on
you was on the
New York depended pretty much whether
you was on the east
you was on the east side
New York depended pretty much whether
you was on the east side or
you was on the east side or the
New York depended pretty much whether
you was on the east side or the west
side.
My
My analyst
side.
My analyst was
My analyst was on
side.
My analyst was on East
My analyst was on East 83rd
side.
My analyst was on East 83rd Street
My analyst was on East 83rd Street and
he
he was
he was a
he was a full
he was a full professor
he was a full professor at
he was a full professor at Columbia.
he was a full professor at Columbia. So
I
I had
he was a full professor at Columbia. So
I had status
by
by virtue
by virtue of
by virtue of who
by virtue of who my
by virtue of who my analyst
by virtue of who my analyst was.
by virtue of who my analyst was. He
by virtue of who my analyst was. He his
grandfather
grandfather analyst
by virtue of who my analyst was. He his
grandfather analyst wise
grandfather analyst wise was
by virtue of who my analyst was. He his
grandfather analyst wise was for
grandfather analyst wise was for it
by virtue of who my analyst was. He his
grandfather analyst wise was for it etc.
So
no
no it's
So
no it's a
no it's a very
So
no it's a very humbling
no it's a very humbling humbling
procedure
procedure of
procedure of psychoanalysis.
procedure of psychoanalysis. If
procedure of psychoanalysis. If a
procedure of psychoanalysis. If a person
is
is stuck
procedure of psychoanalysis. If a person
is stuck spiritually
uh
uh it's
uh it's one
uh it's one of
uh it's one of the
uh it's one of the options
uh it's one of the options you
uh it's one of the options you could
choose.
choose. Why
uh it's one of the options you could
choose. Why am
choose. Why am I
uh it's one of the options you could
choose. Why am I stuck?
choose. Why am I stuck? Why
uh it's one of the options you could
choose. Why am I stuck? Why am
choose. Why am I stuck? Why am I
uh it's one of the options you could
choose. Why am I stuck? Why am I stuck?
Why
Why can't
Why can't I
Why can't I seem
Why can't I seem to
Why can't I seem to move
Why can't I seem to move on
Why can't I seem to move on on
Why can't I seem to move on on from
where
where I'm
Why can't I seem to move on on from
where I'm at?
uh
uh let's
uh let's say
uh let's say you
uh let's say you can't
uh let's say you can't let
uh let's say you can't let you
uh let's say you can't let you find
you're
you're unable
uh let's say you can't let you find
you're unable to
you're unable to let
uh let's say you can't let you find
you're unable to let go
you're unable to let go wanting
uh let's say you can't let you find
you're unable to let go wanting to
control
control a
control a certain
control a certain situation
control a certain situation you
control a certain situation you know
control a certain situation you know and
if
if you
control a certain situation you know and
if you keep
if you keep trying
control a certain situation you know and
if you keep trying you're
if you keep trying you're still
control a certain situation you know and
if you keep trying you're still unable
to
to let
to let go
to let go you
to let go you know
to let go you know I
to let go you know I frankly
to let go you know I frankly go
to let go you know I frankly go and
to let go you know I frankly go and see
a
a therapist
to let go you know I frankly go and see
a therapist to
a therapist to say
to let go you know I frankly go and see
a therapist to say you
a therapist to say you know
to let go you know I frankly go and see
a therapist to say you know how
a therapist to say you know how come
to let go you know I frankly go and see
a therapist to say you know how come I
can't
can't let
can't let go
can't let go of
can't let go of this
can't let go of this what
can't let go of this what is
can't let go of this what is it
can't let go of this what is it in
can't let go of this what is it in me
you
you know
can't let go of this what is it in me
you know what
you know what is
can't let go of this what is it in me
you know what is that
you know what is that repressed
omnipotence
omnipotence or
omnipotence or whatever
omnipotence or whatever it
omnipotence or whatever it is
omnipotence or whatever it is what
omnipotence or whatever it is what is
the
the drive
omnipotence or whatever it is what is
the drive you
the drive you know
omnipotence or whatever it is what is
the drive you know I
the drive you know I would
omnipotence or whatever it is what is
the drive you know I would seek
psychotherapy
psychotherapy as
psychotherapy as part
psychotherapy as part of
psychotherapy as part of the
psychotherapy as part of the whole
maturation
maturation process
psychotherapy as part of the whole
maturation process and
maturation process and uh
psychotherapy as part of the whole
maturation process and uh also
maturation process and uh also highly
educative
educative you
educative you know
educative you know unless
educative you know unless you
educative you know unless you sat
educative you know unless you sat down
and
and uh
you
you I
you I get
you I get a
you I get a kick
you I get a kick out
you I get a kick out of
you I get a kick out of people
you I get a kick out of people who
you I get a kick out of people who who
poo
poo poo
you I get a kick out of people who who
poo poo the
poo poo the unconscious
you I get a kick out of people who who
poo poo the unconscious and
poo poo the unconscious and Freud.
you I get a kick out of people who who
poo poo the unconscious and Freud. I'll
tell
tell them,
tell them, "Well,
tell them, "Well, you
tell them, "Well, you want
tell them, "Well, you want to
tell them, "Well, you want to lay
tell them, "Well, you want to lay on
tell them, "Well, you want to lay on the
couch
couch for
tell them, "Well, you want to lay on the
couch for an
couch for an hour
tell them, "Well, you want to lay on the
couch for an hour or
couch for an hour or once
tell them, "Well, you want to lay on the
couch for an hour or once a
couch for an hour or once a day
tell them, "Well, you want to lay on the
couch for an hour or once a day uh
couch for an hour or once a day uh for
tell them, "Well, you want to lay on the
couch for an hour or once a day uh for a
week
week uh
week uh and
week uh and see
week uh and see what
week uh and see what comes
week uh and see what comes up.
What
What comes
week uh and see what comes up.
What comes up?"
What comes up?" Yeah.
week uh and see what comes up.
What comes up?" Yeah. The
What comes up?" Yeah. The first
week uh and see what comes up.
What comes up?" Yeah. The first day
suddenly
suddenly silence
suddenly silence and
suddenly silence and blocking.
suddenly silence and blocking. Well,
what
what are
suddenly silence and blocking. Well,
what are you
what are you thinking
suddenly silence and blocking. Well,
what are you thinking about?
what are you thinking about? Oh,
suddenly silence and blocking. Well,
what are you thinking about? Oh, I
what are you thinking about? Oh, I know
what
what he's
what he's thinking
what he's thinking about.
what he's thinking about. He's
what he's thinking about. He's he's
wondering
wondering what
what he's thinking about. He's he's
wondering what I
wondering what I think
what he's thinking about. He's he's
wondering what I think about
wondering what I think about him.
what he's thinking about. He's he's
wondering what I think about him. That's
what
what he's
what he's thinking
what he's thinking about.
what he's thinking about. Of
what he's thinking about. Of course.
Next
Next day
what he's thinking about. Of course.
Next day he
Next day he thinks
what he's thinking about. Of course.
Next day he thinks I'm
Next day he thinks I'm not
what he's thinking about. Of course.
Next day he thinks I'm not talking
Next day he thinks I'm not talking to
him
him because
him because I
him because I dislike
him because I dislike him.
Next
Next thing
him because I dislike him.
Next thing he
Next thing he thinks
him because I dislike him.
Next thing he thinks I
Next thing he thinks I hate
him because I dislike him.
Next thing he thinks I hate him.
Next
Next thing
Next thing he
Next thing he thinks
Next thing he thinks I'm
Next thing he thinks I'm after
Next thing he thinks I'm after his
money.
So
So projection
So projection went
So projection went after.
So projection went after. No,
So projection went after. No, I
So projection went after. No, I think
it's
it's very
So projection went after. No, I think
it's very educative,
it's very educative, very
So projection went after. No, I think
it's very educative, very uh
it's very educative, very uh helpful.
And
And it
And it makes
And it makes you
And it makes you just
And it makes you just a
And it makes you just a more
sophisticated
sophisticated aware
And it makes you just a more
sophisticated aware person
sophisticated aware person in
And it makes you just a more
sophisticated aware person in general
sophisticated aware person in general to
have
have had
have had some
have had some kind
have had some kind of
have had some kind of therapy
have had some kind of therapy so
have had some kind of therapy so that
you
you had
have had some kind of therapy so that
you had the
you had the practice
have had some kind of therapy so that
you had the practice of
you had the practice of looking
have had some kind of therapy so that
you had the practice of looking at
yourself
yourself from
yourself from outside
yourself from outside yourself.
yourself from outside yourself. You
yourself from outside yourself. You see?
So
So it
yourself from outside yourself. You see?
So it it
So it it has
yourself from outside yourself. You see?
So it it has a
So it it has a broadening
yourself from outside yourself. You see?
So it it has a broadening effect
So it it has a broadening effect just
like
like tra
like tra foreign
like tra foreign travel
like tra foreign travel has.
like tra foreign travel has. Foreign
travel
travel has
like tra foreign travel has. Foreign
travel has a
travel has a broadening
like tra foreign travel has. Foreign
travel has a broadening effect.
travel has a broadening effect. You
travel
travel to
travel to Europe
travel to Europe to
travel to Europe to come
travel to Europe to come back
travel to Europe to come back to
travel to Europe to come back to states
you
you don't
travel to Europe to come back to states
you don't see
you don't see see
travel to Europe to come back to states
you don't see see life
you don't see see life the
travel to Europe to come back to states
you don't see see life the same
you don't see see life the same exactly
the
the same
the same way
the same way as
the same way as somehow
the same way as somehow just
the same way as somehow just the
experience
experience amongst
the same way as somehow just the
experience amongst other
experience amongst other people
the same way as somehow just the
experience amongst other people who
experience amongst other people who see
it
it differently
it differently already
it differently already influences
it differently already influences your
own
own sophistication.
As
As far
As far as
As far as the
As far as the various
As far as the various energy
As far as the various energy techniques
I'm
I'm not
As far as the various energy techniques
I'm not familiar
I'm not familiar with
As far as the various energy techniques
I'm not familiar with lots
I'm not familiar with lots of
As far as the various energy techniques
I'm not familiar with lots of them.
I'm not familiar with lots of them. You
know
know the
know the reason
know the reason is
know the reason is you
know the reason is you don't
know the reason is you don't have
know the reason is you don't have enough
time
time and
know the reason is you don't have enough
time and I
time and I got
know the reason is you don't have enough
time and I got books
time and I got books on
know the reason is you don't have enough
time and I got books on various
time and I got books on various energy
programs
this
this high
programs
this high each
this high each one
programs
this high each one of
this high each one of them
programs
this high each one of them is
this high each one of them is a
programs
this high each one of them is a learning
discipline
discipline in
discipline in itself
discipline in itself you
discipline in itself you know
discipline in itself you know each
discipline in itself you know each one
has
has its
discipline in itself you know each one
has its own
has its own school
discipline in itself you know each one
has its own school you
has its own school you know
discipline in itself you know each one
has its own school you know polarity
therapy
therapy and
therapy and gag
therapy and gag therapy
therapy and gag therapy and
therapy and gag therapy and balancing
therapy
therapy and
therapy and gag therapy and balancing
therapy and inner
therapy and inner ear
therapy and gag therapy and balancing
therapy and inner ear therapy
therapy and inner ear therapy and
therapy and gag therapy and balancing
therapy and inner ear therapy and chakra
balancing
balancing and
balancing and energy
balancing and energy and
balancing and energy and music
balancing and energy and music and
balancing and energy and music and uh
color
color and
balancing and energy and music and uh
color and uh
color and uh aromas
balancing and energy and music and uh
color and uh aromas and
color and uh aromas and um
balancing and energy and music and uh
color and uh aromas and um you
color and uh aromas and um you know
keeps
keeps you
keeps you really
keeps you really busy.
keeps you really busy. Yeah,
keeps you really busy. Yeah, I
keeps you really busy. Yeah, I mean
keeps you really busy. Yeah, I mean you
spent
spent about
keeps you really busy. Yeah, I mean you
spent about 20
spent about 20 years
keeps you really busy. Yeah, I mean you
spent about 20 years checking
spent about 20 years checking all
keeps you really busy. Yeah, I mean you
spent about 20 years checking all these
things
things out
and
and um
I
I think
I think each
I think each one
I think each one there's
I think each one there's a
I think each one there's a certain
uh
uh knowingness
I think each one there's a certain
uh knowingness that
uh knowingness that comes
I think each one there's a certain
uh knowingness that comes out
uh knowingness that comes out of
I think each one there's a certain
uh knowingness that comes out of it.
Aside
Aside from
Aside from the
Aside from the description,
Aside from the description, there's
Aside from the description, there's a
certain
certain knowingness,
Aside from the description, there's a
certain knowingness, certain
certain knowingness, certain knowingness
that
that comes
that comes out
that comes out of
that comes out of each
that comes out of each exploration.
Just
Just as
that comes out of each exploration.
Just as every
Just as every country
that comes out of each exploration.
Just as every country you
Just as every country you travel
that comes out of each exploration.
Just as every country you travel in
Just as every country you travel in in
traveling
traveling around
traveling around the
traveling around the world
traveling around the world without
traveling around the world without being
able
able to
traveling around the world without being
able to describe
able to describe there's
traveling around the world without being
able to describe there's a
able to describe there's a certain
knowingness
knowingness that
knowingness that comes
knowingness that comes out
knowingness that comes out of
knowingness that comes out of it
knowingness that comes out of it there's
a
a certain
knowingness that comes out of it there's
a certain understanding
a certain understanding of
knowingness that comes out of it there's
a certain understanding of human
a certain understanding of human nature
that
that comes
that comes out
that comes out of
that comes out of having
that comes out of having been
that comes out of having been in
that comes out of having been in China
you
you know
that comes out of having been in China
you know to
you know to be
that comes out of having been in China
you know to be in
you know to be in China
that comes out of having been in China
you know to be in China to
you know to be in China to just
that comes out of having been in China
you know to be in China to just be
you know to be in China to just be in
the
the vibrational
the vibrational field
the vibrational field to
the vibrational field to witness
the vibrational field to witness and
experience
experience life
the vibrational field to witness and
experience life from
experience life from a
the vibrational field to witness and
experience life from a wholly
experience life from a wholly different
viewpoint
is
is different
viewpoint
is different than
is different than not
viewpoint
is different than not having
is different than not having been
viewpoint
is different than not having been to
there
in
in the
there
in the street
in the street of
there
in the street of Shanghai,
in the street of Shanghai, you
there
in the street of Shanghai, you know,
after
after World
after World War
after World War II,
after World War II, we
after World War II, we were
after World War II, we were the
after World War II, we were the first
ships
ships in
after World War II, we were the first
ships in the
ships in the mind
after World War II, we were the first
ships in the mind sweeps
ships in the mind sweeps because
after World War II, we were the first
ships in the mind sweeps because we
ships in the mind sweeps because we were
went
went in
went in to
went in to sweep
went in to sweep the
went in to sweep the sea
went in to sweep the sea before
went in to sweep the sea before the
ships
ships could
went in to sweep the sea before the
ships could come
ships could come in.
went in to sweep the sea before the
ships could come in. So
ships could come in. So there
went in to sweep the sea before the
ships could come in. So there you
ships could come in. So there you are
went in to sweep the sea before the
ships could come in. So there you are in
the
the streets
the streets of
the streets of Shanghai
the streets of Shanghai in
the streets of Shanghai in the
the streets of Shanghai in the Bund
the streets of Shanghai in the Bund or
something
something it
the streets of Shanghai in the Bund or
something it was
something it was called
the streets of Shanghai in the Bund or
something it was called and
something it was called and a
the streets of Shanghai in the Bund or
something it was called and a throng
something it was called and a throng of
people
people like
people like you've
people like you've never
people like you've never seen.
people like you've never seen. There's
people
people everywhere.
people like you've never seen. There's
people everywhere. They
people everywhere. They live
people like you've never seen. There's
people everywhere. They live on
people everywhere. They live on the
sidewalk.
sidewalk. Here's
sidewalk. Here's a
sidewalk. Here's a guy
sidewalk. Here's a guy getting
sidewalk. Here's a guy getting his
here's
here's a
sidewalk. Here's a guy getting his
here's a guy
here's a guy going
sidewalk. Here's a guy getting his
here's a guy going like
here's a guy going like this
sidewalk. Here's a guy getting his
here's a guy going like this and
here's a guy going like this and and
sidewalk. Here's a guy getting his
here's a guy going like this and and the
guy's
guy's going
guy's going like
guy's going like this.
guy's going like this. The
guy's going like this. The dentist
guy's going like this. The dentist he's
drilling
drilling this
guy's going like this. The dentist he's
drilling this guy's
drilling this guy's tooth
guy's going like this. The dentist he's
drilling this guy's tooth and
drilling this guy's tooth and all
guy's going like this. The dentist he's
drilling this guy's tooth and all the
people
people around
people around him
people around him are
people around him are going,
people around him are going, "Oh."
people around him are going, "Oh." every
time
time it
people around him are going, "Oh." every
time it screams,
time it screams, you
people around him are going, "Oh." every
time it screams, you know,
time it screams, you know, and
people around him are going, "Oh." every
time it screams, you know, and over
there
there lady's
there lady's having
there lady's having a
there lady's having a baby.
there lady's having a baby. Over
there lady's having a baby. Over here,
somebody's
somebody's getting
there lady's having a baby. Over here,
somebody's getting a
somebody's getting a haircut.
there lady's having a baby. Over here,
somebody's getting a haircut. I
somebody's getting a haircut. I mean,
all
all of
all of life
all of life is
all of life is being
all of life is being lived
all of life is being lived in
all of life is being lived in a
all of life is being lived in a communal
oneness,
oneness, you
all of life is being lived in a communal
oneness, you know,
oneness, you know, was
all of life is being lived in a communal
oneness, you know, was fantastic.
oneness, you know, was fantastic. What
an
an experience.
an experience. And
an experience. And the
an experience. And the smell
an experience. And the smell of
an experience. And the smell of all
an experience. And the smell of all the
cooking
cooking coming
an experience. And the smell of all the
cooking coming from
cooking coming from all
an experience. And the smell of all the
cooking coming from all the
cooking coming from all the things.
an experience. And the smell of all the
cooking coming from all the things. And
the
the feeling
the feeling of
the feeling of humanity
the feeling of humanity you
the feeling of humanity you get,
the feeling of humanity you get, you
the feeling of humanity you get, you can
only
only get
the feeling of humanity you get, you can
only get in
only get in the
the feeling of humanity you get, you can
only get in the far
only get in the far east.
the feeling of humanity you get, you can
only get in the far east. You
only get in the far east. You can't
really
really get
really get it,
really get it, you
really get it, you know,
really get it, you know, in
really get it, you know, in suburbia.
So,
So, there's
really get it, you know, in suburbia.
So, there's a
So, there's a certain
really get it, you know, in suburbia.
So, there's a certain knowingness
So, there's a certain knowingness that
comes
comes out
comes out of
comes out of experience.
comes out of experience. So
comes out of experience. So that's,
comes out of experience. So that's, you
know,
know, we
comes out of experience. So that's, you
know, we we
know, we we bemoan
comes out of experience. So that's, you
know, we we bemoan the
know, we we bemoan the fact
comes out of experience. So that's, you
know, we we bemoan the fact we're
know, we we bemoan the fact we're not
enlightened
enlightened yet,
enlightened yet, but
enlightened yet, but the
enlightened yet, but the totality
enlightened yet, but the totality of
that
that experiencing
enlightened yet, but the totality of
that experiencing of
that experiencing of the
enlightened yet, but the totality of
that experiencing of the totality
that experiencing of the totality of
enlightened yet, but the totality of
that experiencing of the totality of all
that's
that's noble
that's noble about
that's noble about one's
that's noble about one's own
that's noble about one's own expression
as
as humanity
that's noble about one's own expression
as humanity because
as humanity because that's
that's noble about one's own expression
as humanity because that's your
as humanity because that's your own
humanity
humanity expressed
humanity expressed out
humanity expressed out there
humanity expressed out there as
humanity expressed out there as its
potentiality.
potentiality. I'm
humanity expressed out there as its
potentiality. I'm the
potentiality. I'm the guy
humanity expressed out there as its
potentiality. I'm the guy sitting
potentiality. I'm the guy sitting there
getting
getting my
getting my tooth
getting my tooth drilled.
getting my tooth drilled. I
getting my tooth drilled. I know
getting my tooth drilled. I know just
what
what it
getting my tooth drilled. I know just
what it feels
what it feels like,
getting my tooth drilled. I know just
what it feels like, you
what it feels like, you know,
getting my tooth drilled. I know just
what it feels like, you know, and
what it feels like, you know, and I
getting my tooth drilled. I know just
what it feels like, you know, and I can
see
see all
see all the
see all the people
see all the people wincing
see all the people wincing and
see all the people wincing and holding
me.
me. Oh,
see all the people wincing and holding
me. Oh, every
me. Oh, every time
see all the people wincing and holding
me. Oh, every time you
me. Oh, every time you would
see all the people wincing and holding
me. Oh, every time you would scream,
they
they would
they would all
they would all scream
they would all scream their
they would all scream their pieces
they would all scream their pieces with
all
all like.
they would all scream their pieces with
all like. So,
all like. So, we
they would all scream their pieces with
all like. So, we share
all like. So, we share we
they would all scream their pieces with
all like. So, we share we share
all like. So, we share we share our
humanity
humanity with
humanity with each
humanity with each other
humanity with each other and
humanity with each other and we
humanity with each other and we broaden
ourself
ourself as
humanity with each other and we broaden
ourself as a
ourself as a consequence.
So,
So, I
So, I think
So, I think therapy
So, I think therapy like
So, I think therapy like you
So, I think therapy like you mentioned
these
these are
So, I think therapy like you mentioned
these are all
these are all broadening
So, I think therapy like you mentioned
these are all broadening experiences.
It's
It's not
It's not the
It's not the same
It's not the same if
It's not the same if you
It's not the same if you haven't
It's not the same if you haven't been
there.
there. You've
It's not the same if you haven't been
there. You've been
there. You've been to
It's not the same if you haven't been
there. You've been to Alhamra.
there. You've been to Alhamra. It's
different
different than
different than not
different than not been
different than not been to
different than not been to Alhhamra.
Thank
Thank you.
Mhm.
>> We
>> We will
Mhm.
>> We will finish
>> We will finish up
Mhm.
>> We will finish up quickly.
>> We will finish up quickly. Yes.
Mhm.
>> We will finish up quickly. Yes. And
>> We will finish up quickly. Yes. And then
we'll
we'll break
we'll break for
we'll break for lunch,
we'll break for lunch, you
we'll break for lunch, you know,
we'll break for lunch, you know, because
they
they expect
we'll break for lunch, you know, because
they expect us
they expect us at
we'll break for lunch, you know, because
they expect us at what
they expect us at what time
we'll break for lunch, you know, because
they expect us at what time for
they expect us at what time for lunch?
12.
>> I
>> I don't know.
12.
>> I don't know. Go
>> I don't know. Go ahead.
>> Hi.
>> Yes.
>> Hi,
>> Hi, Susan.
>> Hi, Susan. How
>> Hi, Susan. How are
>> Hi, Susan. How are you?
>> How
>> How is
>> Hi, Susan. How are you?
>> How is it
>> How is it that
>> Hi, Susan. How are you?
>> How is it that a
>> How is it that a being
>> Hi, Susan. How are you?
>> How is it that a being like
>> How is it that a being like Muhammad
>> Hi, Susan. How are you?
>> How is it that a being like Muhammad who
seemingly
seemingly transcended
seemingly transcended the
seemingly transcended the ego
seemingly transcended the ego and
reached
reached a
seemingly transcended the ego and
reached a consciousness
reached a consciousness of
seemingly transcended the ego and
reached a consciousness of 740
reached a consciousness of 740 then
seemingly transcended the ego and
reached a consciousness of 740 then has
this
this great
this great fall
this great fall Yeah.
this great fall Yeah. to
this great fall Yeah. to 70?
this great fall Yeah. to 70? Oh,
>> I
>> I get
this great fall Yeah. to 70? Oh,
>> I get that
>> I get that question
this great fall Yeah. to 70? Oh,
>> I get that question often.
It
It seems
It seems to
It seems to me
It seems to me dominion
It seems to me dominion over
It seems to me dominion over man
It seems to me dominion over man is
It seems to me dominion over man is a
struggle
struggle between
It seems to me dominion over man is a
struggle between various
struggle between various kinds
It seems to me dominion over man is a
struggle between various kinds of
forces.
forces. And
forces. And as
forces. And as one
forces. And as one crab
forces. And as one crab starts
forces. And as one crab starts to
forces. And as one crab starts to get
out
out of
forces. And as one crab starts to get
out of the
out of the bucket,
forces. And as one crab starts to get
out of the bucket, the
out of the bucket, the other
forces. And as one crab starts to get
out of the bucket, the other crabs
out of the bucket, the other crabs begin
to
to try
to try and
to try and pull
to try and pull him
to try and pull him back.
Also,
Also, Muhammad
to try and pull him back.
Also, Muhammad reached
Also, Muhammad reached calibrated
to try and pull him back.
Also, Muhammad reached calibrated level.
I
I think
I think 700
I think 700 or
I think 700 or so
I think 700 or so on
I think 700 or so on there,
I think 700 or so on there, which
I think 700 or so on there, which is
I think 700 or so on there, which is not
a
a thousand.
I think 700 or so on there, which is not
a thousand. 700
a thousand. 700 is
I think 700 or so on there, which is not
a thousand. 700 is very
a thousand. 700 is very impressive
I think 700 or so on there, which is not
a thousand. 700 is very impressive but
it
it is
it is not
it is not a
it is not a thousand
it is not a thousand because
it is not a thousand because the
spiritual
spiritual ego
it is not a thousand because the
spiritual ego at
spiritual ego at an
it is not a thousand because the
spiritual ego at an advanced
spiritual ego at an advanced level
it is not a thousand because the
spiritual ego at an advanced level still
has
has perfections
and
and in
has perfections
and in fact
and in fact on
has perfections
and in fact on the
and in fact on the way
has perfections
and in fact on the way from
and in fact on the way from 700
has perfections
and in fact on the way from 700 on
and in fact on the way from 700 on up
these
these can
these can be
these can be experienced
these can be experienced as
extraordinarily
extraordinarily painful
these can be experienced as
extraordinarily painful and
agonizing
>> because
>> because within
agonizing
>> because within the
>> because within the spiritual
agonizing
>> because within the spiritual ego
>> because within the spiritual ego see
agonizing
>> because within the spiritual ego see the
ego
ego itself
ego itself is
ego itself is made
ego itself is made up
ego itself is made up of
ego itself is made up of these
ego itself is made up of these various
archetypes
archetypes the
ego itself is made up of these various
archetypes the collective
archetypes the collective archetypes
ego itself is made up of these various
archetypes the collective archetypes of
all
all of
all of uh
all of uh humanity
all of uh humanity as
all of uh humanity as it's
all of uh humanity as it's evolved
all of uh humanity as it's evolved over
all
all the
all of uh humanity as it's evolved over
all the course
all the course of
all of uh humanity as it's evolved over
all the course of time.
all the course of time. And
all of uh humanity as it's evolved over
all the course of time. And each
archetype
archetype has
archetype has within
archetype has within it
archetype has within it a
archetype has within it a chakra
archetype has within it a chakra system.
Each
Each one
archetype has within it a chakra system.
Each one of
Each one of these
archetype has within it a chakra system.
Each one of these unless
Each one of these unless it's
archetype has within it a chakra system.
Each one of these unless it's wound
within
within yourself
within yourself transcended
within yourself transcended through
prayer,
prayer, forgiveness,
within yourself transcended through
prayer, forgiveness, understanding,
prayer, forgiveness, understanding, and
compassion
compassion can
compassion can wait
compassion can wait to
compassion can wait to catch
compassion can wait to catch you.
compassion can wait to catch you. All
right?
right? One
compassion can wait to catch you. All
right? One of
right? One of them
compassion can wait to catch you. All
right? One of them that
right? One of them that catches
compassion can wait to catch you. All
right? One of them that catches you
right? One of them that catches you is
the
the spiritual
the spiritual knight.
The
The spiritual
the spiritual knight.
The spiritual knight.
The spiritual knight. See,
the spiritual knight.
The spiritual knight. See, you
The spiritual knight. See, you see
the spiritual knight.
The spiritual knight. See, you see Islam
inflamed
inflamed by
inflamed by the
inflamed by the spiritual
inflamed by the spiritual knight.
inflamed by the spiritual knight. Well,
that's
that's the
inflamed by the spiritual knight. Well,
that's the black
that's the black knight.
inflamed by the spiritual knight. Well,
that's the black knight. There's
that's the black knight. There's the
white
white knight.
white knight. also
white knight. also like
white knight. also like that.
white knight. also like that. Anyway,
white knight. also like that. Anyway, so
the
the solar
white knight. also like that. Anyway, so
the solar plexus
the solar plexus of
white knight. also like that. Anyway, so
the solar plexus of the
the solar plexus of the spiritual
warrior
warrior now
warrior now is
warrior now is going
warrior now is going to
warrior now is going to kill
warrior now is going to kill everybody
in
in the
warrior now is going to kill everybody
in the name
in the name of
warrior now is going to kill everybody
in the name of God.
in the name of God. Well,
too
too bad.
too bad. So,
too bad. So, he
too bad. So, he got
too bad. So, he got tempted
too bad. So, he got tempted somehow
too bad. So, he got tempted somehow by
the
the drama,
too bad. So, he got tempted somehow by
the drama, the
the drama, the power,
too bad. So, he got tempted somehow by
the drama, the power, the
the drama, the power, the glamour,
too bad. So, he got tempted somehow by
the drama, the power, the glamour, the
not
not knowingness
not knowingness out
not knowingness out of
not knowingness out of it
not knowingness out of it because
there's
there's only
not knowingness out of it because
there's only one
there's only one defect
not knowingness out of it because
there's only one defect possible
there's only one defect possible in
not knowingness out of it because
there's only one defect possible in all
of
of humanity,
of humanity, including
of humanity, including the
of humanity, including the great
spiritual
spiritual figures
of humanity, including the great
spiritual figures of
spiritual figures of history
of humanity, including the great
spiritual figures of history in
contemporary
contemporary time.
There
There is
contemporary time.
There is illusions.
There is illusions. You
contemporary time.
There is illusions. You see
There is illusions. You see illusions.
Now
Now the
Now the Buddha
Now the Buddha said
Now the Buddha said that
Now the Buddha said that he
Now the Buddha said that he was
Now the Buddha said that he was wrecked
by
by pain
Now the Buddha said that he was wrecked
by pain because
by pain because as
Now the Buddha said that he was wrecked
by pain because as his
by pain because as his consciousness
reached
reached the enlighta
the
the demons
reached the enlighta
the demons the
the demons the demons
because
because that
because that which
because that which is
because that which is not
because that which is not integrous
seeks
seeks power.
because that which is not integrous
seeks power. You
seeks power. You see
because that which is not integrous
seeks power. You see and
seeks power. You see and sees
because that which is not integrous
seeks power. You see and sees the
evolution
evolution of
evolution of spiritual
evolution of spiritual truth
evolution of spiritual truth as
evolution of spiritual truth as a
evolution of spiritual truth as a threat
to
to its
evolution of spiritual truth as a threat
to its demise.
to its demise. If
evolution of spiritual truth as a threat
to its demise. If you
to its demise. If you want
evolution of spiritual truth as a threat
to its demise. If you want to
to its demise. If you want to trigger
psychic
psychic attack,
psychic attack, all
psychic attack, all you
psychic attack, all you have
psychic attack, all you have to
psychic attack, all you have to do
psychic attack, all you have to do is
discover
discover a
psychic attack, all you have to do is
discover a new
discover a new way
psychic attack, all you have to do is
discover a new way to
discover a new way to remove
psychic attack, all you have to do is
discover a new way to remove the
discover a new way to remove the sheep
from
from the
from the the
from the the sheepkin
from the the sheepkin from
from the the sheepkin from the
from the the sheepkin from the covering
of
of the
from the the sheepkin from the covering
of the wolf
and
and you
and you pull
and you pull them
and you pull them out
and you pull them out of
and you pull them out of the
and you pull them out of the woodwork.
I
I remember
and you pull them out of the woodwork.
I remember talking
I remember talking I
and you pull them out of the woodwork.
I remember talking I was
I remember talking I was doing
and you pull them out of the woodwork.
I remember talking I was doing a
I remember talking I was doing a radio
program
program somewhere
program somewhere and
program somewhere and we
program somewhere and we were
program somewhere and we were talking
about
about calibrating
program somewhere and we were talking
about calibrating levels
about calibrating levels of
program somewhere and we were talking
about calibrating levels of business
about calibrating levels of business and
you
you know
you know that
you know that some
you know that some were
you know that some were actually
non-integrous
non-integrous not
you know that some were actually
non-integrous not prior
non-integrous not prior to
you know that some were actually
non-integrous not prior to prior
non-integrous not prior to prior in
you know that some were actually
non-integrous not prior to prior in Ron
Paul
Paul no
Paul no and
Paul no and uh
Paul no and uh all
Paul no and uh all of a
Paul no and uh all of a sudden
Paul no and uh all of a sudden I'm
talking
talking to
Paul no and uh all of a sudden I'm
talking to this
talking to this he's
Paul no and uh all of a sudden I'm
talking to this he's a
talking to this he's a woman
Paul no and uh all of a sudden I'm
talking to this he's a woman interviewer
all
all of a
all of a sudden
all of a sudden the
all of a sudden the male
all of a sudden the male voice
all of a sudden the male voice cuts
all of a sudden the male voice cuts in
on
on the
all of a sudden the male voice cuts in
on the radio
on the radio and
all of a sudden the male voice cuts in
on the radio and says
on the radio and says you
all of a sudden the male voice cuts in
on the radio and says you don't
on the radio and says you don't intend
to
to publish
to publish that
to publish that do
to publish that do you
to publish that do you and
to publish that do you and I
to publish that do you and I said
to publish that do you and I said well
we
we might
to publish that do you and I said well
we might he
we might he says
to publish that do you and I said well
we might he says well
we might he says well prepare
to publish that do you and I said well
we might he says well prepare to
we might he says well prepare to get
sued
sued then
sued then he
sued then he went
sued then he went off
sued then he went off the
I'm
I'm think
sued then he went off the
I'm think what
I'm think what kind
sued then he went off the
I'm think what kind of
I'm think what kind of a
sued then he went off the
I'm think what kind of a company
I'm think what kind of a company is
sued then he went off the
I'm think what kind of a company is this
guy
guy running
you
you know
guy running
you know that
you know that he's
guy running
you know that he's frightened
you know that he's frightened of
guy running
you know that he's frightened of the
revelation
revelation of
revelation of truth
revelation of truth you
revelation of truth you know
right
right so
revelation of truth you know
right so lot
right so lot lots
revelation of truth you know
right so lot lots of
right so lot lots of people
revelation of truth you know
right so lot lots of people are
right so lot lots of people are not
happy
happy if
happy if you
happy if you uh
happy if you uh are
happy if you uh are going
happy if you uh are going to
happy if you uh are going to shine
happy if you uh are going to shine the
light
light on
happy if you uh are going to shine the
light on their
light on their dentist
happy if you uh are going to shine the
light on their dentist of
light on their dentist of of
happy if you uh are going to shine the
light on their dentist of of wickedness
you
you see
>> any
>> any more
you see
>> any more than
>> any more than you're
you see
>> any more than you're going
>> any more than you're going to
you see
>> any more than you're going to be
>> any more than you're going to be popular
amongst
amongst a
amongst a drug
amongst a drug gang
amongst a drug gang you
amongst a drug gang you know
amongst a drug gang you know that
amongst a drug gang you know that you
become
become a
amongst a drug gang you know that you
become a former
become a former for
amongst a drug gang you know that you
become a former for the
become a former for the police
amongst a drug gang you know that you
become a former for the police they're
not
not going
not going to
not going to like
not going to like it.
not going to like it. Well,
so
so it
not going to like it. Well,
so it seems
so it seems like
not going to like it. Well,
so it seems like unless
so it seems like unless unless
not going to like it. Well,
so it seems like unless unless you've
got
got a
got a teacher
got a teacher been
got a teacher been the
got a teacher been the whole
got a teacher been the whole way
got a teacher been the whole way and
knows
knows all
got a teacher been the whole way and
knows all the
knows all the traps
got a teacher been the whole way and
knows all the traps and
knows all the traps and can
got a teacher been the whole way and
knows all the traps and can educate
knows all the traps and can educate you
about
about the
about the traps,
about the traps, what
about the traps, what to
about the traps, what to watch
about the traps, what to watch out
about the traps, what to watch out for.
You
You see
about the traps, what to watch out for.
You see it
You see it happen
about the traps, what to watch out for.
You see it happen in
You see it happen in our
about the traps, what to watch out for.
You see it happen in our current
society.
society. They're
society. They're on
society. They're on the
society. They're on the internet.
society. They're on the internet. The
the
the glamour
society. They're on the internet. The
the glamour of
the glamour of having
society. They're on the internet. The
the glamour of having many
the glamour of having many followers,
the
the glamour
the glamour of
the glamour of um
the glamour of um being
the glamour of um being from
the glamour of um being from a
the glamour of um being from a foreign
culture,
culture, you
the glamour of um being from a foreign
culture, you know,
culture, you know, the
the glamour of um being from a foreign
culture, you know, the swami
culture, you know, the swami and
the glamour of um being from a foreign
culture, you know, the swami and all,
you
you know,
you know, the
you know, the sandals
you know, the sandals and
you know, the sandals and all
you know, the sandals and all that
you know, the sandals and all that that
music
music and
you know, the sandals and all that that
music and the
music and the swirling.
you know, the sandals and all that that
music and the swirling. There's
music and the swirling. There's a
there's
there's a
there's a glamour
there's a glamour there's
there's a glamour there's a
there's a glamour there's a seduction
there's a glamour there's a seduction to
the
the glamour.
>> So
>> So there's
>> So there's a
>> So there's a glamour
and
and a
>> So there's a glamour
and a seduction
to
doing
doing what
to
doing what you
doing what you do
to
doing what you do in
doing what you do in the
to
doing what you do in the name
doing what you do in the name of
to
doing what you do in the name of God
doing what you do in the name of God and
that
that is
that is the
that is the ultimate
that is the ultimate trap.
So
So that's
that is the ultimate trap.
So that's why
So that's why I
that is the ultimate trap.
So that's why I feel
So that's why I feel sorry
that is the ultimate trap.
So that's why I feel sorry for
So that's why I feel sorry for jihad.
that is the ultimate trap.
So that's why I feel sorry for jihad. I
also
also notice
also notice the
also notice the hopelessness
also notice the hopelessness of
also notice the hopelessness of that
also notice the hopelessness of that pit
because
because once
also notice the hopelessness of that pit
because once you
because once you get
also notice the hopelessness of that pit
because once you get taken
because once you get taken over,
also notice the hopelessness of that pit
because once you get taken over, once
your
your crown
your crown chakra
your crown chakra gets
your crown chakra gets taken
your crown chakra gets taken over,
your crown chakra gets taken over, then
you
you and
your crown chakra gets taken over, then
you and you
you and you think
your crown chakra gets taken over, then
you and you think what
you and you think what you're
your crown chakra gets taken over, then
you and you think what you're doing,
you're
you're doing
you're doing for
you're doing for God,
you're doing for God, there's
you're doing for God, there's no
stopping
stopping you.
>> That's
>> That's the
>> That's the most
>> That's the most dangerous
>> That's the most dangerous person
>> That's the most dangerous person on
>> That's the most dangerous person on the
planet
planet is
>> That's the most dangerous person on the
planet is a
planet is a person
>> That's the most dangerous person on the
planet is a person who
planet is a person who thinks
>> That's the most dangerous person on the
planet is a person who thinks they're
doing
doing what
doing what they're
doing what they're doing
doing what they're doing in
doing what they're doing in the
doing what they're doing in the name
doing what they're doing in the name of
God
>> because
>> because there's
>> because there's no
>> because there's no human
>> because there's no human source
>> because there's no human source of
stopping
stopping such
>> because there's no human source of
stopping such a
stopping such a delusion.
>> because there's no human source of
stopping such a delusion. Why?
stopping such a delusion. Why? because
it
it trig
it trig it
it trig it triggers
it trig it triggers the
it trig it triggers the very
it trig it triggers the very core
egoentricity
of
of the
of the ego.
of the ego. And
of the ego. And what
of the ego. And what is
of the ego. And what is the
of the ego. And what is the ego's
difficulty?
That
That it's
That it's not
That it's not God.
That's
That's the
That it's not God.
That's the ego's
That's the ego's difficulty.
That it's not God.
That's the ego's difficulty. That's
That's the ego's difficulty. That's why
it
it hates
it hates you
it hates you and
it hates you and wants
it hates you and wants to
it hates you and wants to kill
it hates you and wants to kill you.
It
It knows
it hates you and wants to kill you.
It knows it's
It knows it's God.
it hates you and wants to kill you.
It knows it's God. And
It knows it's God. And the
it hates you and wants to kill you.
It knows it's God. And the fact
It knows it's God. And the fact that
it hates you and wants to kill you.
It knows it's God. And the fact that you
don't
don't recognize
don't recognize it's
don't recognize it's God,
don't recognize it's God, it
don't recognize it's God, it will
don't recognize it's God, it will put
you
you to
don't recognize it's God, it will put
you to death.
you to death. Put
don't recognize it's God, it will put
you to death. Put you
you to death. Put you to
don't recognize it's God, it will put
you to death. Put you to death.
So
So you
So you see
So you see the
So you see the core
So you see the core of
So you see the core of the
So you see the core of the ego
So you see the core of the ego and
So you see the core of the ego and its
whole
whole structure
So you see the core of the ego and its
whole structure is
whole structure is to
So you see the core of the ego and its
whole structure is to maintain
whole structure is to maintain the
illusion
illusion that
illusion that it
illusion that it is
illusion that it is the
illusion that it is the source
illusion that it is the source of
illusion that it is the source of your
life
life and
illusion that it is the source of your
life and existence
life and existence that
illusion that it is the source of your
life and existence that it
life and existence that it is
illusion that it is the source of your
life and existence that it is God.
life and existence that it is God. You
see
see the
see the megalomania
see the megalomania of
see the megalomania of the
see the megalomania of the dictator
Melovich
Melovich or
see the megalomania of the dictator
Melovich or Hitler
Melovich or Hitler or
see the megalomania of the dictator
Melovich or Hitler or Stalin
Melovich or Hitler or Stalin or
see the megalomania of the dictator
Melovich or Hitler or Stalin or did
Melovich or Hitler or Stalin or did Lden
or
or any
or any of
or any of these
or any of these people
or any of these people they're
or any of these people they're all
carried
carried away
or any of these people they're all
carried away by
carried away by the
or any of these people they're all
carried away by the same
megalomania.
So
So I'm
megalomania.
So I'm sure
So I'm sure Muhammad
megalomania.
So I'm sure Muhammad you
So I'm sure Muhammad you know
megalomania.
So I'm sure Muhammad you know was
So I'm sure Muhammad you know was not
megalomania.
So I'm sure Muhammad you know was not a
sophisticated
sophisticated devote
sophisticated devote of
sophisticated devote of some
sophisticated devote of some spiritual
master
and
and he
and he had
and he had a
and he had a great
and he had a great spiritual
and he had a great spiritual opportunity
and
and he
and he had a great spiritual opportunity
and he and
and he and he
and he had a great spiritual opportunity
and he and he did
and he and he did that
and he had a great spiritual opportunity
and he and he did that and
and he and he did that and then
and he had a great spiritual opportunity
and he and he did that and then the
forces
forces that
forces that he
forces that he was
forces that he was a
forces that he was a threat
forces that he was a threat to
they
they know
forces that he was a threat to
they know the
they know the primitive
forces that he was a threat to
they know the primitive you
they know the primitive you see
forces that he was a threat to
they know the primitive you see because
the
the source
the source is
the source is within
the source is within the
the source is within the primitive.
the source is within the primitive. So
it
it came
the source is within the primitive. So
it came up
it came up through
the source is within the primitive. So
it came up through the
it came up through the primitive
the source is within the primitive. So
it came up through the primitive in
it came up through the primitive in his
spiritual
spiritual night
spiritual night and
spiritual night and grabbed
spiritual night and grabbed him
spiritual night and grabbed him by
spiritual night and grabbed him by the
solar
solar plexus
and
and he
and he killed
and he killed for
and he killed for God.
and he killed for God. Well,
and he killed for God. Well, I
and he killed for God. Well, I once
killed
killed for
and he killed for God. Well, I once
killed for God.
killed for God. I
and he killed for God. Well, I once
killed for God. I remember
killed for God. I remember very
and he killed for God. Well, I once
killed for God. I remember very well.
killed for God. I remember very well. In
fact,
fact, the
fact, the guy
fact, the guy and
fact, the guy and I
fact, the guy and I killed
fact, the guy and I killed each
fact, the guy and I killed each other.
He
He was
fact, the guy and I killed each other.
He was Islamic
He was Islamic and
fact, the guy and I killed each other.
He was Islamic and I
He was Islamic and I was
fact, the guy and I killed each other.
He was Islamic and I was Christian.
He was Islamic and I was Christian. I'll
kill
kill him
kill him for
kill him for God
kill him for God and
kill him for God and he
kill him for God and he killed
kill him for God and he killed me
kill him for God and he killed me for
God.
God. By
kill him for God and he killed me for
God. By God,
God. By God, we
kill him for God and he killed me for
God. By God, we were
God. By God, we were serious
kill him for God and he killed me for
God. By God, we were serious about
God. By God, we were serious about it.
You
You know,
You know, I
You know, I know
You know, I know how
You know, I know how serious
You know, I know how serious they
You know, I know how serious they are
because
because I
You know, I know how serious they are
because I was
because I was that
You know, I know how serious they are
because I was that serious.
I
I would
I would do
I would do anything
I would do anything for
I would do anything for what
I would do anything for what I
I would do anything for what I believed
in.
in. And
I would do anything for what I believed
in. And he
in. And he would
I would do anything for what I believed
in. And he would do
in. And he would do anything
I would do anything for what I believed
in. And he would do anything for
in. And he would do anything for what
I would do anything for what I believed
in. And he would do anything for what he
believed
believed in.
believed in. And
believed in. And that's
believed in. And that's what
believed in. And that's what we
believed in. And that's what we took.
That's
That's what
believed in. And that's what we took.
That's what we
That's what we pull
believed in. And that's what we took.
That's what we pull forth
That's what we pull forth to
believed in. And that's what we took.
That's what we pull forth to transcend
that
that because
that because it's
that because it's only
that because it's only when
that because it's only when you
transcend
transcend that
that because it's only when you
transcend that you're
transcend that you're free.
>> Up
>> Up until
>> Up until that
>> Up until that point,
>> Up until that point, you're
>> Up until that point, you're dangerous.
>> So
>> So the
>> Up until that point, you're dangerous.
>> So the Gi
>> So the Gi people
>> Up until that point, you're dangerous.
>> So the Gi people are
>> So the Gi people are very
>> Up until that point, you're dangerous.
>> So the Gi people are very dangerous
because
because they
because they are
because they are caught
because they are caught by
because they are caught by that.
>> So
>> So Muhammad
because they are caught by that.
>> So Muhammad got
>> So Muhammad got pulled
because they are caught by that.
>> So Muhammad got pulled in
>> So Muhammad got pulled in because
because they are caught by that.
>> So Muhammad got pulled in because he
>> So Muhammad got pulled in because he did
not
not have
not have a
not have a teacher
not have a teacher to
not have a teacher to warn
not have a teacher to warn him
not have a teacher to warn him warn
not have a teacher to warn him warn him
of
of this
not have a teacher to warn him warn him
of this trap.
of this trap. And
not have a teacher to warn him warn him
of this trap. And so
of this trap. And so I'm
not have a teacher to warn him warn him
of this trap. And so I'm sure
of this trap. And so I'm sure he
not have a teacher to warn him warn him
of this trap. And so I'm sure he did
what
what he
what he thought
what he thought because
what he thought because the
what he thought because the first
what he thought because the first people
he
he killed,
what he thought because the first people
he killed, you
he killed, you know,
what he thought because the first people
he killed, you know, he
he killed, you know, he became
enlightened
enlightened at
enlightened at 35
enlightened at 35 where
enlightened at 35 where he
enlightened at 35 where he channeled
enlightened at 35 where he channeled the
the
the holy
enlightened at 35 where he channeled the
the holy book
the holy book of
enlightened at 35 where he channeled the
the holy book of Islam
the holy book of Islam and
enlightened at 35 where he channeled the
the holy book of Islam and then
the holy book of Islam and then within
enlightened at 35 where he channeled the
the holy book of Islam and then within 3
years
years he
years he succumbed
years he succumbed to
years he succumbed to that
years he succumbed to that and
years he succumbed to that and began
killing
killing people.
years he succumbed to that and began
killing people. In
killing people. In fact,
years he succumbed to that and began
killing people. In fact, the
killing people. In fact, the first
people
people he
people he killed
people he killed were
people he killed were Jews
people he killed were Jews and
people he killed were Jews and they've
been
been at
people he killed were Jews and they've
been at it
been at it ever
people he killed were Jews and they've
been at it ever since.
There's
There's the
There's the history
There's the history of
There's the history of the
There's the history of the Middle
There's the history of the Middle East,
no
no different
There's the history of the Middle East,
no different than
no different than it
There's the history of the Middle East,
no different than it was
>> in
>> in 750
>> in 750 or
>> in 750 or whatever
>> in 750 or whatever year
>> in 750 or whatever year it
>> in 750 or whatever year it was
that
that opposition.
>> in 750 or whatever year it was
that opposition. See,
that opposition. See, so
>> in 750 or whatever year it was
that opposition. See, so what
that opposition. See, so what we're
seeing
seeing there
seeing there then
seeing there then is
seeing there then is the
seeing there then is the evolution
seeing there then is the evolution of
spiritual
spiritual consciousness
seeing there then is the evolution of
spiritual consciousness on
spiritual consciousness on its
seeing there then is the evolution of
spiritual consciousness on its way
spiritual consciousness on its way to
truth.
truth. And
truth. And it
truth. And it has
truth. And it has to
truth. And it has to pass
truth. And it has to pass certain
truth. And it has to pass certain tests.
These
These are
truth. And it has to pass certain tests.
These are challenges
These are challenges of
truth. And it has to pass certain tests.
These are challenges of truth.
These are challenges of truth. To
truth. And it has to pass certain tests.
These are challenges of truth. To be
These are challenges of truth. To be a
master,
master, you
master, you have
master, you have to
master, you have to face
master, you have to face this,
master, you have to face this, owned
master, you have to face this, owned it
in
in yourself,
master, you have to face this, owned it
in yourself, transcended
in yourself, transcended it,
of
of being
of being seduced,
of being seduced, seduced
of being seduced, seduced by
of being seduced, seduced by power
of being seduced, seduced by power and
the
the glamour
of being seduced, seduced by power and
the glamour of
the glamour of it.
of being seduced, seduced by power and
the glamour of it. See
the glamour of it. See the
of being seduced, seduced by power and
the glamour of it. See the look
the glamour of it. See the look at
of being seduced, seduced by power and
the glamour of it. See the look at the
powerful
powerful glamour
of
of being
powerful glamour
of being a
of being a warrior,
powerful glamour
of being a warrior, a
of being a warrior, a chosen
powerful glamour
of being a warrior, a chosen warrior
of being a warrior, a chosen warrior for
God.
God. I
God. I mean,
God. I mean, you
God. I mean, you can't
God. I mean, you can't beat
God. I mean, you can't beat that.
>> You
>> You show
God. I mean, you can't beat that.
>> You show me
>> You show me a
God. I mean, you can't beat that.
>> You show me a reward
>> You show me a reward that
God. I mean, you can't beat that.
>> You show me a reward that can
>> You show me a reward that can beat
God. I mean, you can't beat that.
>> You show me a reward that can beat being
chosen
chosen to
chosen to be
chosen to be a
chosen to be a warrior
chosen to be a warrior for
chosen to be a warrior for God.
chosen to be a warrior for God. You
can't
can't beat
chosen to be a warrior for God. You
can't beat it.
You
You take
You take a
You take a poor
You take a poor kid
You take a poor kid there,
You take a poor kid there, a
You take a poor kid there, a stone
You take a poor kid there, a stone age
people,
people, a
You take a poor kid there, a stone age
people, a teenager
people, a teenager who
You take a poor kid there, a stone age
people, a teenager who is
people, a teenager who is nobody,
You take a poor kid there, a stone age
people, a teenager who is nobody, lives
in
in rags,
in rags, and
in rags, and he's
in rags, and he's lucky
in rags, and he's lucky to
in rags, and he's lucky to get
in rags, and he's lucky to get somebody.
And
And you
in rags, and he's lucky to get somebody.
And you give
And you give him
in rags, and he's lucky to get somebody.
And you give him a
And you give him a gun
in rags, and he's lucky to get somebody.
And you give him a gun from
And you give him a gun from nobody,
in rags, and he's lucky to get somebody.
And you give him a gun from nobody, he's
somebody,
somebody, right?
somebody, right? Why
somebody, right? Why would
somebody, right? Why would an
somebody, right? Why would an Afghani
teenager
teenager want
somebody, right? Why would an Afghani
teenager want to
teenager want to give
somebody, right? Why would an Afghani
teenager want to give up
teenager want to give up his
somebody, right? Why would an Afghani
teenager want to give up his gun?
teenager want to give up his gun? Cuz
you
you got
you got some
you got some silly
you got some silly ass
you got some silly ass dream
you got some silly ass dream poetic
goody
goody goodiness
you got some silly ass dream poetic
goody goodiness about
goody goodiness about democracy
you got some silly ass dream poetic
goody goodiness about democracy or
goody goodiness about democracy or some
horseshit.
horseshit. Give
horseshit. Give me
horseshit. Give me a
horseshit. Give me a break.
horseshit. Give me a break. You
horseshit. Give me a break. You know
what
what I
horseshit. Give me a break. You know
what I mean?
what I mean? Get
horseshit. Give me a break. You know
what I mean? Get real,
what I mean? Get real, man.
horseshit. Give me a break. You know
what I mean? Get real, man. I'm
what I mean? Get real, man. I'm a
horseshit. Give me a break. You know
what I mean? Get real, man. I'm a man
and
and you
and you got
and you got to
and you got to pay
and you got to pay me
and you got to pay me money
and you got to pay me money to
and you got to pay me money to work
and you got to pay me money to work for
you.
you. Without
and you got to pay me money to work for
you. Without my
you. Without my gun,
and you got to pay me money to work for
you. Without my gun, I'm
you. Without my gun, I'm nobody.
and you got to pay me money to work for
you. Without my gun, I'm nobody. You
want
want me
want me to
want me to vote
want me to vote for
want me to vote for democracy?
want me to vote for democracy? Oh
want me to vote for democracy? Oh my
god.
god. Get
want me to vote for democracy? Oh my
god. Get off
god. Get off it,
want me to vote for democracy? Oh my
god. Get off it, will
god. Get off it, will you?
>> That's
>> That's why
>> That's why all
>> That's why all these
>> That's why all these peace
>> That's why all these peace nicks
>> That's why all these peace nicks give
>> That's why all these peace nicks give me
a
a pain
>> That's why all these peace nicks give me
a pain in
a pain in the
>> That's why all these peace nicks give me
a pain in the neck.
>> Why?
>> Why? because
>> Why? because they
>> Why? because they destroy
>> Why? because they destroy peace.
>> Peace
>> Peace is
>> Why? because they destroy peace.
>> Peace is the
>> Peace is the automatic
>> Why? because they destroy peace.
>> Peace is the automatic consequence
>> Peace is the automatic consequence of
the
the prevalence
the prevalence of
the prevalence of truth
the prevalence of truth and
the prevalence of truth and illusion
the prevalence of truth and illusion is
the
the propagation
the prevalence of truth and illusion is
the propagation of
the propagation of falsehood
the prevalence of truth and illusion is
the propagation of falsehood and
the propagation of falsehood and it's
falsehood
falsehood that
falsehood that is
falsehood that is the
falsehood that is the propagation
falsehood that is the propagation of
war.
war. So
falsehood that is the propagation of
war. So if
war. So if you
falsehood that is the propagation of
war. So if you want
war. So if you want to
falsehood that is the propagation of
war. So if you want to be
war. So if you want to be a
falsehood that is the propagation of
war. So if you want to be a pisnick
war. So if you want to be a pisnick then
get
get hard
get hard asked
get hard asked about
get hard asked about truth.
>> Well
>> Well said
get hard asked about truth.
>> Well said well
>> Well said well said
>> confrontational
>> confrontational about
how
how is
>> confrontational about
how is he
how is he posing
>> confrontational about
how is he posing this?
how is he posing this? No.
>> confrontational about
how is he posing this? No. Unless
how is he posing this? No. Unless these
guys
guys get
guys get respect
guys get respect for
guys get respect for their
guys get respect for their conviction,
they
they are
guys get respect for their conviction,
they are convinced.
they are convinced. They
guys get respect for their conviction,
they are convinced. They are
they are convinced. They are convinced.
And
And if
And if you
And if you respect
And if you respect them
And if you respect them for
And if you respect them for their
conviction,
conviction, then
And if you respect them for their
conviction, then you
conviction, then you undo
And if you respect them for their
conviction, then you undo the
conviction, then you undo the hook
And if you respect them for their
conviction, then you undo the hook of
their
their having
their having to
their having to hang
their having to hang on
their having to hang on to
their having to hang on to it
their having to hang on to it out
their having to hang on to it out of
resistance.
resistance. If
their having to hang on to it out of
resistance. If you
resistance. If you want
their having to hang on to it out of
resistance. If you want this
resistance. If you want this kid
their having to hang on to it out of
resistance. If you want this kid to
resistance. If you want this kid to hang
on
on to
on to his
on to his gun,
on to his gun, try
on to his gun, try pulling
on to his gun, try pulling it
on to his gun, try pulling it out
on to his gun, try pulling it out of
on to his gun, try pulling it out of his
hand.
hand. The
on to his gun, try pulling it out of his
hand. The harder
hand. The harder you
on to his gun, try pulling it out of his
hand. The harder you try
hand. The harder you try and
on to his gun, try pulling it out of his
hand. The harder you try and pull
hand. The harder you try and pull it,
see,
>> the
>> the more
see,
>> the more he
>> the more he will
see,
>> the more he will grab
>> the more he will grab onto
see,
>> the more he will grab onto that.
>> the more he will grab onto that. So
trying
trying to
trying to pull
trying to pull war
trying to pull war out
trying to pull war out of
trying to pull war out of the
trying to pull war out of the hands
trying to pull war out of the hands of
the
the warlike
trying to pull war out of the hands of
the warlike intensifies
the warlike intensifies the
trying to pull war out of the hands of
the warlike intensifies the war.
No,
No, we
No, we melt
No, we melt it
No, we melt it and
No, we melt it and dissolve
No, we melt it and dissolve it
No, we melt it and dissolve it by
No, we melt it and dissolve it by our
humanness,
humanness, by
No, we melt it and dissolve it by our
humanness, by our
humanness, by our compassion.
No, we melt it and dissolve it by our
humanness, by our compassion. We
humanness, by our compassion. We say,
No, we melt it and dissolve it by our
humanness, by our compassion. We say, "I
know
know how
know how you
know how you must
know how you must feel.
know how you must feel. I
know how you must feel. I used
know how you must feel. I used to
know how you must feel. I used to feel
the
the same
know how you must feel. I used to feel
the same way
the same way myself."
know how you must feel. I used to feel
the same way myself." Everybody
the same way myself." Everybody becomes
a
a convert
a convert to
a convert to something.
a convert to something. You
a convert to something. You become
a convert to something. You become a
a convert to something. You become a boy
scout.
scout. You
a convert to something. You become a boy
scout. You got
scout. You got to
a convert to something. You become a boy
scout. You got to sign
scout. You got to sign up
a convert to something. You become a boy
scout. You got to sign up all
scout. You got to sign up all your
friends.
friends. You
friends. You join
friends. You join a
friends. You join a you
friends. You join a you got
friends. You join a you got to
friends. You join a you got to sober
friends. You join a you got to sober up
the
the world
friends. You join a you got to sober up
the world through
the world through the
friends. You join a you got to sober up
the world through the course
the world through the course of
miracles.
miracles. You
miracles. You got
miracles. You got to
miracles. You got to get
miracles. You got to get everybody
forgiving.
You
You got
You got to
You got to pull
You got to pull everybody
You got to pull everybody on
You got to pull everybody on your
You got to pull everybody on your trip
with
with you.
All right?
All right? We
All right? We do
All right? We do that
All right? We do that out
All right? We do that out of
All right? We do that out of our
All right? We do that out of our love
for
for each
All right? We do that out of our love
for each other.
for each other. And
All right? We do that out of our love
for each other. And therefore,
for each other. And therefore, we
All right? We do that out of our love
for each other. And therefore, we can
forgive
forgive oursel,
forgive oursel, our
forgive oursel, our clumsiness
forgive oursel, our clumsiness and
awkwardness.
awkwardness. So,
forgive oursel, our clumsiness and
awkwardness. So, we
awkwardness. So, we forgive
forgive oursel, our clumsiness and
awkwardness. So, we forgive the
awkwardness. So, we forgive the jihad
people.
people. I'm
people. I'm sure
people. I'm sure they're
people. I'm sure they're doing
people. I'm sure they're doing what
people. I'm sure they're doing what they
are
are convinced
people. I'm sure they're doing what they
are convinced they
are convinced they are
people. I'm sure they're doing what they
are convinced they are supposed
are convinced they are supposed to
people. I'm sure they're doing what they
are convinced they are supposed to do.
And
And and
And and out
And and out of
And and out of our
And and out of our love
And and out of our love and
And and out of our love and compassion,
see,
see, out
And and out of our love and compassion,
see, out of
see, out of our
And and out of our love and compassion,
see, out of our compassion
see, out of our compassion for
And and out of our love and compassion,
see, out of our compassion for knowing
where
where they're
where they're at,
where they're at, if
where they're at, if you
where they're at, if you haven't
where they're at, if you haven't been
willing
willing to
where they're at, if you haven't been
willing to kill
willing to kill for
where they're at, if you haven't been
willing to kill for God,
willing to kill for God, you
where they're at, if you haven't been
willing to kill for God, you aren't
willing to kill for God, you aren't that
far
far along
far along the
far along the path.
far along the path. When
far along the path. When did
far along the path. When did you
far along the path. When did you get
willing
willing to
far along the path. When did you get
willing to kill
willing to kill for
far along the path. When did you get
willing to kill for God?
willing to kill for God? And
far along the path. When did you get
willing to kill for God? And then
willing to kill for God? And then you
see,
see, oh,
see, oh, I
see, oh, I see
see, oh, I see I'm
see, oh, I see I'm caught
see, oh, I see I'm caught in
see, oh, I see I'm caught in that.
see, oh, I see I'm caught in that. And
then
then you
see, oh, I see I'm caught in that. And
then you forgive
then you forgive it.
see, oh, I see I'm caught in that. And
then you forgive it. By
then you forgive it. By forgiving
see, oh, I see I'm caught in that. And
then you forgive it. By forgiving them,
we
we undo
we undo them.
we undo them. You
we undo them. You understand
we undo them. You understand that?
we undo them. You understand that? You
want
want to
we undo them. You understand that? You
want to do
want to do what
we undo them. You understand that? You
want to do what you
want to do what you can
we undo them. You understand that? You
want to do what you can do
want to do what you can do for
we undo them. You understand that? You
want to do what you can do for world
peace.
peace. See
peace. See how
peace. See how these
peace. See how these people
peace. See how these people are
peace. See how these people are hooked
on
on that?
peace. See how these people are hooked
on that? They're
on that? They're hooked
peace. See how these people are hooked
on that? They're hooked and
on that? They're hooked and we
peace. See how these people are hooked
on that? They're hooked and we feel
sorry
sorry for
sorry for themselves.
Teenage
Teenage boy
sorry for themselves.
Teenage boy in
Teenage boy in Afghanistan,
sorry for themselves.
Teenage boy in Afghanistan, how
Teenage boy in Afghanistan, how can
sorry for themselves.
Teenage boy in Afghanistan, how can he
do
do anything
do anything but
do anything but what
do anything but what he
do anything but what he does,
do anything but what he does, you
do anything but what he does, you know?
So
So we
do anything but what he does, you know?
So we have
So we have compassion
do anything but what he does, you know?
So we have compassion for
So we have compassion for them
do anything but what he does, you know?
So we have compassion for them and
So we have compassion for them and out
of
of our
of our compassion
of our compassion then
of our compassion then our
of our compassion then our compassion
radiates
radiates into
of our compassion then our compassion
radiates into the
radiates into the field
of our compassion then our compassion
radiates into the field and
radiates into the field and the
of our compassion then our compassion
radiates into the field and the field
offers
offers them
offers them a
offers them a way
offers them a way of
offers them a way of release
offers them a way of release because
sooner
sooner or
offers them a way of release because
sooner or later
sooner or later they
offers them a way of release because
sooner or later they will
sooner or later they will see
offers them a way of release because
sooner or later they will see the
sooner or later they will see the same
thing.
All
All right.
thing.
All right. Thank
All right. Thank you
thing.
All right. Thank you so
All right. Thank you so much.
thing.
All right. Thank you so much. We'll
All right. Thank you so much. We'll meet
again.
Uh,
Uh, what
again.
Uh, what time
Uh, what time do
again.
Uh, what time do we
Uh, what time do we meet
again.
Uh, what time do we meet again?
>> 1
>> 1 hour
>> 1 hour and
>> 1 hour and 4
>> 1 hour and 4 minutes
>> and
>> and 32
>> 1 hour and 4 minutes
>> and 32 seconds.
>> What
>> What was
>> What was Krishna's
>> What was Krishna's purpose?
>> You
>> You mentioned
>> What was Krishna's purpose?
>> You mentioned Christ
>> You mentioned Christ salvation.
>> What was Krishna's purpose?
>> You mentioned Christ salvation. Christ
salvation.
>> Yeah.
>> Buddha
>> Buddha enlightenment.
>> Yeah.
What
What was
What was Krishna's?
I
I love
What was Krishna's?
I love people
great
great in
great in New York.
Great
Great restaurant
great in New York.
Great restaurant in
Great restaurant in New York
great in New York.
Great restaurant in New York doesn't
have
have any
have any music.
have any music. You
have any music. You just
have any music. You just hear
have any music. You just hear the
have any music. You just hear the soft
chattering
chattering of
have any music. You just hear the soft
chattering of hundreds
chattering of hundreds of
have any music. You just hear the soft
chattering of hundreds of people
chattering of hundreds of people all
talking.
talking. Really
talking. Really sounds
talking. Really sounds nice.
Lucha
Lucha Lucha
talking. Really sounds nice.
Lucha Lucha famous
Lucha Lucha famous German
talking. Really sounds nice.
Lucha Lucha famous German restaurant
huge
huge place
huge place huge
huge place huge place
huge place huge place here
huge place huge place here you
huge place huge place here you hear
huge place huge place here you hear like
500 people
500 people all
huge place huge place here you hear like
500 people all talking
500 people all talking at
huge place huge place here you hear like
500 people all talking at one
500 people all talking at one it's
huge place huge place here you hear like
500 people all talking at one it's sort
of
of mystical
of mystical and
of mystical and wonderful
but
but we
of mystical and wonderful
but we wanted
but we wanted to
of mystical and wonderful
but we wanted to continue
but we wanted to continue we
of mystical and wonderful
but we wanted to continue we were
but we wanted to continue we were saying
we
we were
we were talking
we were talking at
we were talking at lunch
we were talking at lunch how
we were talking at lunch how do
we were talking at lunch how do you
we were talking at lunch how do you save
your
your children
we were talking at lunch how do you save
your children the
your children the pain
we were talking at lunch how do you save
your children the pain of
your children the pain of their
we were talking at lunch how do you save
your children the pain of their mistakes
and
and of
and of course
you
you can't
and of course
you can't but
What
What we're
What we're really
What we're really interested
What we're really interested in
What we're really interested in is
saving
saving ourselves
What we're really interested in is
saving ourselves the
saving ourselves the pain
What we're really interested in is
saving ourselves the pain of
saving ourselves the pain of witnessing
our
our children's
our children's mistakes
our children's mistakes and
our children's mistakes and then
our children's mistakes and then the
unwillingness
unwillingness to
our children's mistakes and then the
unwillingness to allow
unwillingness to allow them
our children's mistakes and then the
unwillingness to allow them to
unwillingness to allow them to pursue
their
their karmic
their karmic course
their karmic course because
the
the gray
their karmic course because
the gray hairs
the gray hairs of
their karmic course because
the gray hairs of wisdom
the gray hairs of wisdom are
their karmic course because
the gray hairs of wisdom are earned.
the gray hairs of wisdom are earned. See
it's
it's one
it's one spiritual
it's one spiritual naivity
it's one spiritual naivity is
it's one spiritual naivity is one
it's one spiritual naivity is one thing,
spiritual
spiritual wisdom
it's one spiritual naivity is one thing,
spiritual wisdom is
spiritual wisdom is another.
it's one spiritual naivity is one thing,
spiritual wisdom is another. And
spiritual wisdom is another. And in
between
between there's
between there's many
between there's many karmic
between there's many karmic lessons.
The
The question
between there's many karmic lessons.
The question of
The question of Muhammad,
between there's many karmic lessons.
The question of Muhammad, you
The question of Muhammad, you know,
between there's many karmic lessons.
The question of Muhammad, you know, it's
a
a just
a just a
a just a painful
a just a painful spiritual
a just a painful spiritual lesson.
a just a painful spiritual lesson. So
yeah,
yeah, we
a just a painful spiritual lesson. So
yeah, we support
yeah, we support each
a just a painful spiritual lesson. So
yeah, we support each other
yeah, we support each other uh
a just a painful spiritual lesson. So
yeah, we support each other uh with
yeah, we support each other uh with uh
compassion
compassion for
compassion for the
compassion for the mistakes
compassion for the mistakes they've
made.
made. I
compassion for the mistakes they've
made. I feel
made. I feel great
compassion for the mistakes they've
made. I feel great compassion
made. I feel great compassion that
compassion for the mistakes they've
made. I feel great compassion that any
kind
kind of
kind of spiritual
kind of spiritual tragedy
kind of spiritual tragedy happens
kind of spiritual tragedy happens in
kind of spiritual tragedy happens in the
world.
world. But
kind of spiritual tragedy happens in the
world. But you
world. But you see
kind of spiritual tragedy happens in the
world. But you see that
world. But you see that appears
kind of spiritual tragedy happens in the
world. But you see that appears to
world. But you see that appears to be
kind of spiritual tragedy happens in the
world. But you see that appears to be a
spiritual
spiritual tragedy
spiritual tragedy and
spiritual tragedy and every
spiritual tragedy and every one
spiritual tragedy and every one of
spiritual tragedy and every one of them
is
is I
spiritual tragedy and every one of them
is I suppose
is I suppose a
spiritual tragedy and every one of them
is I suppose a hidden
is I suppose a hidden spiritual
spiritual tragedy and every one of them
is I suppose a hidden spiritual victory.
Huh?
Huh? because
Huh? because I
Huh? because I know
Huh? because I know what
Huh? because I know what appears
Huh? because I know what appears to
Huh? because I know what appears to be
tragedy,
tragedy, the
Huh? because I know what appears to be
tragedy, the gray
tragedy, the gray hairs
Huh? because I know what appears to be
tragedy, the gray hairs of
tragedy, the gray hairs of wisdom.
Uh,
Uh, and
Uh, and I've
Uh, and I've told
Uh, and I've told you
Uh, and I've told you the
Uh, and I've told you the story
Uh, and I've told you the story about
that
that warrior
Uh, and I've told you the story about
that warrior and
that warrior and myself.
Uh, and I've told you the story about
that warrior and myself. And
that warrior and myself. And uh,
Uh, and I've told you the story about
that warrior and myself. And uh, I'll
tell
tell you,
tell you, we
tell you, we went
tell you, we went the
tell you, we went the whole
tell you, we went the whole way
tell you, we went the whole way with
each
each other.
tell you, we went the whole way with
each other. I
each other. I mean,
tell you, we went the whole way with
each other. I mean, for
each other. I mean, for karma
tell you, we went the whole way with
each other. I mean, for karma to
each other. I mean, for karma to be
tell you, we went the whole way with
each other. I mean, for karma to be to
transcend
transcend a
transcend a lesson,
transcend a lesson, you
transcend a lesson, you have
transcend a lesson, you have to
transcend a lesson, you have to be
transcend a lesson, you have to be the
whole
whole way
transcend a lesson, you have to be the
whole way with
whole way with it.
transcend a lesson, you have to be the
whole way with it. So,
whole way with it. So, people's
convictions
convictions have
convictions have to
convictions have to be
convictions have to be what
convictions have to be what they
convictions have to be what they are.
And
And uh
convictions have to be what they are.
And uh they're
And uh they're very
convictions have to be what they are.
And uh they're very tenacious
And uh they're very tenacious about
convictions have to be what they are.
And uh they're very tenacious about uh
victory
victory over
victory over certain
victory over certain barriers.
victory over certain barriers. You
victory over certain barriers. You see
the
the if
victory over certain barriers. You see
the if these
the if these barriers
victory over certain barriers. You see
the if these barriers were
the if these barriers were easy
victory over certain barriers. You see
the if these barriers were easy to
transcend,
transcend, everybody
transcend, everybody would
transcend, everybody would be
enlightened.
enlightened. Yes,
transcend, everybody would be
enlightened. Yes, they're
enlightened. Yes, they're extremely
difficult
difficult to
difficult to transcend.
difficult to transcend. That's
difficult to transcend. That's the
difficult to transcend. That's the whole
point.
point. It
difficult to transcend. That's the whole
point. It uh
point. It uh it's
difficult to transcend. That's the whole
point. It uh it's only
point. It uh it's only when
difficult to transcend. That's the whole
point. It uh it's only when you
point. It uh it's only when you go
difficult to transcend. That's the whole
point. It uh it's only when you go the
extreme.
extreme. I
extreme. I mean,
extreme. I mean, I
extreme. I mean, I remember
extreme. I mean, I remember this
extreme. I mean, I remember this warrior
and
and myself
extreme. I mean, I remember this warrior
and myself who
and myself who are
extreme. I mean, I remember this warrior
and myself who are the
and myself who are the greatest.
extreme. I mean, I remember this warrior
and myself who are the greatest. We
and myself who are the greatest. We we
love
love each
love each other
love each other uh
love each other uh greatly,
love each other uh greatly, you
love each other uh greatly, you know,
and
and always
love each other uh greatly, you know,
and always did.
and always did. But
love each other uh greatly, you know,
and always did. But only
and always did. But only for
love each other uh greatly, you know,
and always did. But only for his
and always did. But only for his sake,
only
only for
only for my
only for my sake
only for my sake did
only for my sake did we
only for my sake did we both
only for my sake did we both go
only for my sake did we both go the
extreme.
extreme. And
only for my sake did we both go the
extreme. And I'm
extreme. And I'm sure
only for my sake did we both go the
extreme. And I'm sure that's
extreme. And I'm sure that's what
only for my sake did we both go the
extreme. And I'm sure that's what the
warriors
warriors of
warriors of today
warriors of today do.
warriors of today do. You
warriors of today do. You know,
you've
you've got
warriors of today do. You know,
you've got to
you've got to go
warriors of today do. You know,
you've got to go the
you've got to go the whole
warriors of today do. You know,
you've got to go the whole way
you've got to go the whole way in
warriors of today do. You know,
you've got to go the whole way in order
to
to transcend
to transcend it.
to transcend it. Half
to transcend it. Half measures
to transcend it. Half measures of
to transcend it. Half measures of illus.
Half
Half measures
to transcend it. Half measures of illus.
Half measures have
Half measures have us
to transcend it. Half measures of illus.
Half measures have us nothing.
Half measures have us nothing. It's
to transcend it. Half measures of illus.
Half measures have us nothing. It's only
when
when we
when we completely
when we completely surrendered
when we completely surrendered that
divinity
divinity revealed
when we completely surrendered that
divinity revealed itself
divinity revealed itself as
when we completely surrendered that
divinity revealed itself as hidden
within
within what
within what we
within what we thought
within what we thought was
within what we thought was tragedy
within what we thought was tragedy at
the
the time.
within what we thought was tragedy at
the time. So
the time. So tragedy
within what we thought was tragedy at
the time. So tragedy then
the time. So tragedy then what
within what we thought was tragedy at
the time. So tragedy then what we
the time. So tragedy then what we see
within what we thought was tragedy at
the time. So tragedy then what we see as
tragedy
tragedy is
tragedy is the
tragedy is the open
tragedy is the open door.
So
So when
tragedy is the open door.
So when we
So when we deprive
tragedy is the open door.
So when we deprive another
So when we deprive another person
tragedy is the open door.
So when we deprive another person of
So when we deprive another person of the
victory
victory of
victory of defeat,
we
we have
victory of defeat,
we have not
we have not done
victory of defeat,
we have not done them
we have not done them a
victory of defeat,
we have not done them a favor.
we have not done them a favor. See,
victory of defeat,
we have not done them a favor. See, to
prop
prop them
prop them up
prop them up and
prop them up and keep
prop them up and keep them
prop them up and keep them going
prop them up and keep them going past
the
the quitting
prop them up and keep them going past
the quitting point
the quitting point is
prop them up and keep them going past
the quitting point is a
the quitting point is a way
prop them up and keep them going past
the quitting point is a way is
the quitting point is a way is sort
prop them up and keep them going past
the quitting point is a way is sort of
sadistic.
sadistic. You
sadistic. You understand?
It's
It's sort
sadistic. You understand?
It's sort of
It's sort of sadistic
sadistic. You understand?
It's sort of sadistic to
It's sort of sadistic to keep
sadistic. You understand?
It's sort of sadistic to keep him
It's sort of sadistic to keep him keep
somebody
somebody going
somebody going when
somebody going when they
somebody going when they should
somebody going when they should be
allowed
allowed to
somebody going when they should be
allowed to topple
allowed to topple over.
Boing.
Here,
Here, have
Boing.
Here, have another
Here, have another vitamin
Boing.
Here, have another vitamin tablet.
Here, have another vitamin tablet. And
this
this guy's
this guy's drinking
this guy's drinking himself
this guy's drinking himself to
this guy's drinking himself to death
this guy's drinking himself to death and
you're
you're giving
this guy's drinking himself to death and
you're giving him
you're giving him vitamin
this guy's drinking himself to death and
you're giving him vitamin tablets.
you're giving him vitamin tablets. I
mean,
mean, do
mean, do you
mean, do you hate
mean, do you hate this
mean, do you hate this guy
mean, do you hate this guy or
mean, do you hate this guy or what?
mean, do you hate this guy or what? You
trying
trying to
mean, do you hate this guy or what? You
trying to destroy
trying to destroy him?
I
I tell
I tell him,
I tell him, "Quit
I tell him, "Quit eating,
I tell him, "Quit eating, man.
I tell him, "Quit eating, man. It
I tell him, "Quit eating, man. It just
interferes
interferes with
I tell him, "Quit eating, man. It just
interferes with the
interferes with the booze."
I tell him, "Quit eating, man. It just
interferes with the booze." You
what
what I'm
what I'm saying?
Vitamin
Vitamin tablets
what I'm saying?
Vitamin tablets will
Vitamin tablets will kill
what I'm saying?
Vitamin tablets will kill you.
And
And I
And I wouldn't
And I wouldn't give
And I wouldn't give up
And I wouldn't give up unless
And I wouldn't give up unless I
And I wouldn't give up unless I had
And I wouldn't give up unless I had to.
Take
Take that.
And I wouldn't give up unless I had to.
Take that. There
Take that. There you
And I wouldn't give up unless I had to.
Take that. There you go.
Take that. There you go. I'm
And I wouldn't give up unless I had to.
Take that. There you go. I'm going
Take that. There you go. I'm going to
push
push him
push him over
push him over the
push him over the edge.
push him over the edge. You
push him over the edge. You know what
I'm
I'm saying?
push him over the edge. You know what
I'm saying? So,
I'm saying? So, out
push him over the edge. You know what
I'm saying? So, out of
I'm saying? So, out of kindness,
push him over the edge. You know what
I'm saying? So, out of kindness, I
I'm saying? So, out of kindness, I push
him
him over
him over the
him over the edge.
And
And so
him over the edge.
And so that's
And so that's how
him over the edge.
And so that's how we
And so that's how we assist
him over the edge.
And so that's how we assist somebody
And so that's how we assist somebody on
the
the way
the way down
the way down is
the way down is we
the way down is we help
the way down is we help them
the way down is we help them get
the way down is we help them get there.
Divine
Divine neglect.
Loving
Loving neglect.
Loving neglect. Loving
Loving neglect. Loving neglect.
Loving neglect. Loving neglect. The
environment
environment case
Loving neglect. Loving neglect. The
environment case of
environment case of whiskey
Loving neglect. Loving neglect. The
environment case of whiskey and
environment case of whiskey and venom.
Very
Very well.
Very well. And
Very well. And I'll
Very well. And I'll see
Very well. And I'll see you
Very well. And I'll see you after
Christmas
Christmas if
Very well. And I'll see you after
Christmas if you're
Christmas if you're still
Very well. And I'll see you after
Christmas if you're still breathing.
So
So anyway,
So anyway, love
So anyway, love takes
So anyway, love takes many
So anyway, love takes many forms.
So anyway, love takes many forms. Love
takes
takes many
So anyway, love takes many forms. Love
takes many forms
takes many forms and
So anyway, love takes many forms. Love
takes many forms and one
takes many forms and one form
So anyway, love takes many forms. Love
takes many forms and one form it
takes many forms and one form it takes
is
is allowing
is allowing people
is allowing people to
is allowing people to be
is allowing people to be who
is allowing people to be who they
is allowing people to be who they are
and
and fulfill
is allowing people to be who they are
and fulfill their
and fulfill their mission.
is allowing people to be who they are
and fulfill their mission. You
and fulfill their mission. You see,
understand
understand that
understand that cuz
understand that cuz that
understand that cuz that way
understand that cuz that way the
understand that cuz that way the world
is
is easier
understand that cuz that way the world
is easier to
is easier to live
understand that cuz that way the world
is easier to live in.
is easier to live in. When
understand that cuz that way the world
is easier to live in. When you
is easier to live in. When you see
understand that cuz that way the world
is easier to live in. When you see that
everything
everything is
everything is fulfilling
everything is fulfilling its
everything is fulfilling its destiny
and
and certain
everything is fulfilling its destiny
and certain things
and certain things can
everything is fulfilling its destiny
and certain things can only
and certain things can only be
everything is fulfilling its destiny
and certain things can only be learned
through
through certain
through certain ways,
through certain ways, you
through certain ways, you know,
without
going,
going, you
going, you know,
going, you know, through
going, you know, through anesthesia.
Sure.
Sure. Without
going, you know, through anesthesia.
Sure. Without anesthesia,
Sure. Without anesthesia, you
going, you know, through anesthesia.
Sure. Without anesthesia, you wouldn't
think
think it's
think it's you
think it's you wouldn't
think it's you wouldn't know
think it's you wouldn't know it's
possible.
Would
Would you
Would you like
Would you like to
Would you like to come
Would you like to come up?
Would you like to come up? Yes.
>> My
>> My question
Would you like to come up? Yes.
>> My question is
>> My question is about
Would you like to come up? Yes.
>> My question is about um
>> My question is about um your
Would you like to come up? Yes.
>> My question is about um your lecture
>> My question is about um your lecture in
May
May 2002.
You
You ended
May 2002.
You ended the
You ended the class
May 2002.
You ended the class early
You ended the class early and
May 2002.
You ended the class early and took
You ended the class early and took them
over
over to
over to see
over to see the
over to see the relics
over to see the relics that
over to see the relics that were
over to see the relics that were on
display.
display. And
over to see the relics that were on
display. And then
display. And then I
over to see the relics that were on
display. And then I was
display. And then I was wondering
over to see the relics that were on
display. And then I was wondering what
is
is the
is the effect
is the effect of
is the effect of the
is the effect of the relics
is the effect of the relics such
is the effect of the relics such as
is the effect of the relics such as that
on
on a
is the effect of the relics such as that
on a person's
on a person's energy
is the effect of the relics such as that
on a person's energy or
on a person's energy or karma
is the effect of the relics such as that
on a person's energy or karma or
whatever.
>> I
>> I don't
whatever.
>> I don't know
the
the um
the um bones
the um bones of
the um bones of St.
the um bones of St. Peter
the um bones of St. Peter underneath
the um bones of St. Peter underneath the
the
the bones
the um bones of St. Peter underneath the
the bones of
the bones of St.
the um bones of St. Peter underneath the
the bones of St. Peter
the bones of St. Peter in
the um bones of St. Peter underneath the
the bones of St. Peter in Basilica
in
in Rome
in Rome underneath
in Rome underneath the
in Rome underneath the er
in Rome underneath the er calibrate.
Let's
Let's see.
in Rome underneath the er calibrate.
Let's see. We
Let's see. We have
in Rome underneath the er calibrate.
Let's see. We have permission
Let's see. We have permission to
calibrate
calibrate them.
They
They are
calibrate them.
They are so
They are so this
calibrate them.
They are so this they
They are so this they calibrate
calibrate them.
They are so this they calibrate over
They are so this they calibrate over 900
the
the bones
the bones of
the bones of St.
the bones of St. Peter
the bones of St. Peter in
the bones of St. Peter in the
the bones of St. Peter in the basilica
of
of the
of the alderum
of the alderum basilica
of the alderum basilica in
of the alderum basilica in the
of the alderum basilica in the Vatican
Rome
Rome calibrated
of the alderum basilica in the Vatican
Rome calibrated over
Rome calibrated over 900
therefore
therefore the
spiritual
spiritual tradition
therefore the
spiritual tradition of
spiritual tradition of relics
therefore the
spiritual tradition of relics apparently
has
has some
has some merit
because
because when
has some merit
because when we
because when we calibrated
has some merit
because when we calibrated the
because when we calibrated the relics
that
that have
that have made
that have made the
that have made the rounds
that have made the rounds of
that have made the rounds of the
that have made the rounds of the world
by
by that
that have made the rounds of the world
by that that
by that that Tibetan
that have made the rounds of the world
by that that Tibetan community
by that that Tibetan community we
calibrated
calibrated they
calibrated they were
calibrated they were over
calibrated they were over 900
So
So it's
calibrated they were over 900
So it's not
So it's not just
calibrated they were over 900
So it's not just uh
So it's not just uh the
calibrated they were over 900
So it's not just uh the Buddha
So it's not just uh the Buddha the
Buddha
Buddha Tibetan
Buddha Tibetan Buddhist
Buddha Tibetan Buddhist relics
Buddha Tibetan Buddhist relics but
Christian
Christian as
Buddha Tibetan Buddhist relics but
Christian as well
Christian as well and
Buddha Tibetan Buddhist relics but
Christian as well and we
Christian as well and we haven't
Buddha Tibetan Buddhist relics but
Christian as well and we haven't had
Christian as well and we haven't had a
chance
chance to
chance to it
chance to it doesn't
chance to it doesn't just
chance to it doesn't just hasn't
chance to it doesn't just hasn't come
chance to it doesn't just hasn't come up
uh
uh about
chance to it doesn't just hasn't come up
uh about anything
uh about anything else
what
what effect
what effect it
what effect it has
what effect it has on
what effect it has on the
what effect it has on the surroundings
what effect it has on the surroundings I
have
have no
what effect it has on the surroundings I
have no idea
have no idea I
what effect it has on the surroundings I
have no idea I haven't
have no idea I haven't asked
what effect it has on the surroundings I
have no idea I haven't asked about
have no idea I haven't asked about at
all
>> what
>> what effect
all
>> what effect it
>> what effect it has
all
>> what effect it has on
>> what effect it has on what
>> like
>> like on
>> like on the
>> like on the person
>> like on the person who
>> like on the person who goes
>> like on the person who goes to
>> like on the person who goes to see
>> like on the person who goes to see them
>> my
>> my understanding
>> like on the person who goes to see them
>> my understanding would
>> my understanding would be
>> like on the person who goes to see them
>> my understanding would be your
intentionality
intentionality you
intentionality you know
intentionality you know you're
intentionality you know you're it's
intentionality you know you're it's your
intent
intent that
intentionality you know you're it's your
intent that gives
intent that gives them
intentionality you know you're it's your
intent that gives them the
intent that gives them the power.
intentionality you know you're it's your
intent that gives them the power. It's
your
your intentionality
in
in which
your intentionality
in which you
in which you u
which
which you
which you don't
which you don't call
which you don't call it
which you don't call it the
which you don't call it the sickness
which you don't call it the sickness of
them
them that
which you don't call it the sickness of
them that accounts
them that accounts for
which you don't call it the sickness of
them that accounts for it
them that accounts for it was
which you don't call it the sickness of
them that accounts for it was just
them that accounts for it was just yeah
I
I don't
I don't think
I don't think it's
I don't think it's the
I don't think it's the bones
I don't think it's the bones themsel
it's
it's not
I don't think it's the bones themsel
it's not the
it's not the radiance
I don't think it's the bones themsel
it's not the radiance it's
it's not the radiance it's not
I don't think it's the bones themsel
it's not the radiance it's not the
radiance
radiance of
radiance of the
radiance of the bones
radiance of the bones themselves
radiance of the bones themselves no
radiance of the bones themselves no the
radiance
radiance of
radiance of the bones themselves no the
radiance of the
radiance of the bone
radiance of the bones themselves no the
radiance of the bone itself
radiance of the bone itself so
radiance of the bones themselves no the
radiance of the bone itself so it
doesn't
doesn't have
doesn't have some
doesn't have some kind
doesn't have some kind of
doesn't have some kind of a
doesn't have some kind of a magical
effect
effect it's
doesn't have some kind of a magical
effect it's that
effect it's that you
doesn't have some kind of a magical
effect it's that you recognize
effect it's that you recognize and
acknowledge
acknowledge divinity
as
as it
acknowledge divinity
as it existed
so
so so
so so you
so so you it's
so so you it's your
so so you it's your intentional
so so you it's your intentional ity
so so you it's your intentional ity then
that
that gives
so so you it's your intentional ity then
that gives it
that gives it um
the
the quality
the quality of
the quality of acting
the quality of acting like
the quality of acting like a
the quality of acting like a lever
the quality of acting like a lever let's
say.
say. So
the quality of acting like a lever let's
say. So it's
say. So it's like
the quality of acting like a lever let's
say. So it's like a
say. So it's like a lever
the quality of acting like a lever let's
say. So it's like a lever but
say. So it's like a lever but you've
decided
decided to
decided to use
decided to use the
decided to use the lever.
decided to use the lever. Other
decided to use the lever. Other people
would
would just
decided to use the lever. Other people
would just poo
would just poo poo
decided to use the lever. Other people
would just poo poo with
would just poo poo with the
decided to use the lever. Other people
would just poo poo with the whole
would just poo poo with the whole idea.
See
>> so
>> so it's
See
>> so it's only
>> so it's only by
See
>> so it's only by your
>> so it's only by your own
See
>> so it's only by your own valition
>> so it's only by your own valition then
that
that you
that you acknowledge.
>> So
>> So it
that you acknowledge.
>> So it differs
>> So it differs from
that you acknowledge.
>> So it differs from coming
>> So it differs from coming like
that you acknowledge.
>> So it differs from coming like to
>> So it differs from coming like to see
you
you the
you the way
you the way you're
The
The aura
you the way you're
The aura of
The aura of a
you the way you're
The aura of a teacher
The aura of a teacher affects
you the way you're
The aura of a teacher affects a
The aura of a teacher affects a student.
>> The
>> The intentionality
>> The intentionality of
>> The intentionality of Oh,
>> The intentionality of Oh, I
>> The intentionality of Oh, I see
>> The intentionality of Oh, I see you're
you're
you're asking
>> The intentionality of Oh, I see you're
you're asking a
you're asking a different
>> The intentionality of Oh, I see you're
you're asking a different question.
Okay.
Okay. Okay.
Okay. Okay. All right.
Okay. Okay. All right. The
Okay. Okay. All right. The question
Okay. Okay. All right. The question uh
now
now I
Okay. Okay. All right. The question uh
now I understand
now I understand where
Okay. Okay. All right. The question uh
now I understand where the
now I understand where the question
Okay. Okay. All right. The question uh
now I understand where the question is.
The
The question
The question the
The question the answer
The question the answer to
The question the answer to that
The question the answer to that is
The question the answer to that is uh
yes,
yes, it
The question the answer to that is uh
yes, it does
yes, it does have
The question the answer to that is uh
yes, it does have an
yes, it does have an influence
The question the answer to that is uh
yes, it does have an influence on
yes, it does have an influence on the
vibrational
vibrational frequency
vibrational frequency of
vibrational frequency of the
vibrational frequency of the aura
resist.
resist. Yes,
vibrational frequency of the aura
resist. Yes, I
resist. Yes, I see
vibrational frequency of the aura
resist. Yes, I see what
resist. Yes, I see what you're
vibrational frequency of the aura
resist. Yes, I see what you're asking.
resist. Yes, I see what you're asking. I
didn't
didn't understand
didn't understand what
didn't understand what you're
didn't understand what you're asking.
That's
That's in
didn't understand what you're asking.
That's in some
That's in some kind
didn't understand what you're asking.
That's in some kind of
That's in some kind of mechanical
didn't understand what you're asking.
That's in some kind of mechanical way.
Now
Now the
Now the um
Now the um we're
Now the um we're going to
Now the um we're going to say
Now the um we're going to say the
vibration
vibration of
Now the um we're going to say the
vibration of the
vibration of the teacher
Now the um we're going to say the
vibration of the teacher the
vibration of the teacher the classic
transmission
transmission see
transmission see which
transmission see which is
transmission see which is described
transmission see which is described by
the
the Buddha
transmission see which is described by
the Buddha which
the Buddha which is
transmission see which is described by
the Buddha which is des
the Buddha which is des it's
transmission see which is described by
the Buddha which is des it's actually
the Buddha which is des it's actually no
mind
mind you
mind you see
mind you see the
mind you see the transmission
mind you see the transmission of
mind you see the transmission of no
mind you see the transmission of no mind
is
is a
mind you see the transmission of no mind
is a paradox
is a paradox and
mind you see the transmission of no mind
is a paradox and and
is a paradox and and and
mind you see the transmission of no mind
is a paradox and and and you
is a paradox and and and you know
mind you see the transmission of no mind
is a paradox and and and you know it
sounds
sounds idiotic
sounds idiotic um
sounds idiotic um the
sounds idiotic um the transmission
sounds idiotic um the transmission of
sounds idiotic um the transmission of no
mind
mind is
sounds idiotic um the transmission of no
mind is a
mind is a frequency
sounds idiotic um the transmission of no
mind is a frequency of
mind is a frequency of the
sounds idiotic um the transmission of no
mind is a frequency of the vibration
within
within the
within the frequency
within the frequency and
within the frequency and the
within the frequency and the vibration
which
which is
within the frequency and the vibration
which is an
which is an extremely
within the frequency and the vibration
which is an extremely high
which is an extremely high frequency
within the frequency and the vibration
which is an extremely high frequency is
a
a knowing
a knowing ingness
a knowing ingness the
a knowing ingness the knowingness
a knowing ingness the knowingness the
information
information is
a knowing ingness the knowingness the
information is encoded
information is encoded in
a knowing ingness the knowingness the
information is encoded in the
information is encoded in the frequency
resist
resist the
resist the information
resist the information is
resist the information is encoded
resist the information is encoded within
the
the frequency
resist the information is encoded within
the frequency resistance
the frequency resistance yes
resist the information is encoded within
the frequency resistance yes see
the frequency resistance yes see that
frequency
frequency uh
frequency uh has
frequency uh has that
frequency uh has that awareness
associated
associated with
frequency uh has that awareness
associated with it
associated with it that's
frequency uh has that awareness
associated with it that's why
associated with it that's why it
calibrates
calibrates where
calibrates where it
calibrates where it does
calibrates where it does so
calibrates where it does so like
calibrates where it does so like at
death's
death's door
calibrates where it does so like at
death's door I
death's door I mean
calibrates where it does so like at
death's door I mean what
death's door I mean what you
calibrates where it does so like at
death's door I mean what you think
death's door I mean what you think is
death
death store
death store what
death store what the
death store what the mind
death store what the mind thinks
death store what the mind thinks is
death
death store
nothing
nothing is
nothing is remembered
nothing is remembered all
nothing is remembered all you
nothing is remembered all you know
nothing is remembered all you know is
that
that you
nothing is remembered all you know is
that you exist
that you exist and
nothing is remembered all you know is
that you exist and you
that you exist and you see
nothing is remembered all you know is
that you exist and you see that
that you exist and you see that your
existence
existence is
existence is going
existence is going to
existence is going to be
existence is going to be surrendered
existence is going to be surrendered to
God.
And
And as
And as you
And as you start
And as you start to
And as you start to do
And as you start to do it,
And as you start to do it, the
And as you start to do it, the anguish
of
of death
And as you start to do it, the anguish
of death overtakes
of death overtakes you.
And as you start to do it, the anguish
of death overtakes you. It's
of death overtakes you. It's you
And as you start to do it, the anguish
of death overtakes you. It's you you
actually
actually are
actually are dying
actually are dying and
actually are dying and you've
actually are dying and you've never
actually are dying and you've never died
before.
before. You
actually are dying and you've never died
before. You realize
before. You realize you've
actually are dying and you've never died
before. You realize you've never
before. You realize you've never died
before
before and
before and this
before and this is
before and this is it.
before and this is it. And
before and this is it. And then
before and this is it. And then the
before and this is it. And then the fear
and
and the
before and this is it. And then the fear
and the doubt
and the doubt comes
before and this is it. And then the fear
and the doubt comes up.
Then
Then to
Then to have
Then to have reached
Then to have reached that
Then to have reached that height
Then to have reached that height already
brings
brings forth
Then to have reached that height already
brings forth the
brings forth the knowingness
Then to have reached that height already
brings forth the knowingness of
brings forth the knowingness of the
energies
energies that
energies that have
energies that have been
energies that have been there
energies that have been there and
energies that have been there and comes
forth
forth then
energies that have been there and comes
forth then the
forth then the certainty.
energies that have been there and comes
forth then the certainty. There
forth then the certainty. There has
energies that have been there and comes
forth then the certainty. There has to
be
be certainty.
be certainty. The
be certainty. The certainty
be certainty. The certainty of
be certainty. The certainty of the
knowingness
knowingness of
be certainty. The certainty of the
knowingness of a
knowingness of a consciousness
be certainty. The certainty of the
knowingness of a consciousness from
which
which you
which you have
which you have heard
which you have heard has
which you have heard has walked
which you have heard has walked through
that
that door.
which you have heard has walked through
that door. Then
that door. Then the
which you have heard has walked through
that door. Then the certainty
that door. Then the certainty of
which you have heard has walked through
that door. Then the certainty of that
that door. Then the certainty of that is
sufficient
sufficient to
sufficient to overcome
sufficient to overcome the
sufficient to overcome the fear.
But
But it
sufficient to overcome the fear.
But it has
But it has to
sufficient to overcome the fear.
But it has to be
But it has to be of
sufficient to overcome the fear.
But it has to be of that
But it has to be of that level
sufficient to overcome the fear.
But it has to be of that level of
certainty
certainty because
certainty because it
certainty because it is
certainty because it is death
certainty because it is death and
nobody's
nobody's going
certainty because it is death and
nobody's going to
nobody's going to surrender
certainty because it is death and
nobody's going to surrender death
without
without absolute
without absolute certainty.
without absolute certainty. Takes
without absolute certainty. Takes more
than
than hope.
without absolute certainty. Takes more
than hope. Good
than hope. Good wishes.
It
It takes
It takes certainty.
It takes certainty. The
It takes certainty. The vibrational
frequency
frequency of
It takes certainty. The vibrational
frequency of the
frequency of the knowingness
It takes certainty. The vibrational
frequency of the knowingness is
frequency of the knowingness is not
It takes certainty. The vibrational
frequency of the knowingness is not it
doesn't
doesn't come
doesn't come through
doesn't come through memory.
doesn't come through memory. There
doesn't come through memory. There is
doesn't come through memory. There is no
memory
memory track
doesn't come through memory. There is no
memory track because
memory track because at
doesn't come through memory. There is no
memory track because at that
memory track because at that point
doesn't come through memory. There is no
memory track because at that point there
is
is no
is no memory
is no memory track.
is no memory track. There's
is no memory track. There's only
is no memory track. There's only the
stunning
confrontation
confrontation of
confrontation of the
confrontation of the reality
confrontation of the reality of
confrontation of the reality of of
confrontation of the reality of of the
confrontation.
There's
There's no
There's no preceding
There's no preceding it.
There's no preceding it. There's
There's no preceding it. There's no
there's
there's no
There's no preceding it. There's no
there's no connected
there's no connected not
There's no preceding it. There's no
there's no connected not connected
there's no connected not connected to
anything
anything else.
anything else. So
anything else. So there's
anything else. So there's no
anything else. So there's no memory
track.
track. You
anything else. So there's no memory
track. You can
track. You can go
anything else. So there's no memory
track. You can go back
track. You can go back to
anything else. So there's no memory
track. You can go back to search
track. You can go back to search for
what
what do
what do I
what do I do
what do I do at
what do I do at this
what do I do at this point?
It's
It's burnt
what do I do at this point?
It's burnt behind
It's burnt behind you.
what do I do at this point?
It's burnt behind you. There's
It's burnt behind you. There's no
what do I do at this point?
It's burnt behind you. There's no memory
track.
track. The
track. The knowingness
track. The knowingness comes
track. The knowingness comes out
track. The knowingness comes out of
track. The knowingness comes out of the
reality
reality of
track. The knowingness comes out of the
reality of the
reality of the presence.
It
It cannot
It cannot be
It cannot be prepared
It cannot be prepared for.
It cannot be prepared for. But
It cannot be prepared for. But the
frequency
frequency of
It cannot be prepared for. But the
frequency of the
frequency of the vibration
It cannot be prepared for. But the
frequency of the vibration is
frequency of the vibration is there.
It cannot be prepared for. But the
frequency of the vibration is there. So
at
at that
at that level,
at that level, your
at that level, your aura
at that level, your aura knows
at that level, your aura knows the
answer
answer and
at that level, your aura knows the
answer and you
answer and you walk
at that level, your aura knows the
answer and you walk through
answer and you walk through the
at that level, your aura knows the
answer and you walk through the door.
And
And Ed,
And Ed, you're
And Ed, you're knowing
And Ed, you're knowing this
And Ed, you're knowing this too.
Sorry.
Sorry. Bring
And Ed, you're knowing this too.
Sorry. Bring it
Sorry. Bring it back.
You
You add
You add your
You add your own
You add your own energy
You add your own energy which
You add your own energy which at
You add your own energy which at that
time
time at
You add your own energy which at that
time at that
time at that point
You add your own energy which at that
time at that point it's
time at that point it's in
You add your own energy which at that
time at that point it's in the
time at that point it's in the eye
You add your own energy which at that
time at that point it's in the eye and
reinforces
reinforces the
reinforces the knowingness.
reinforces the knowingness. So
it's
it's like
reinforces the knowingness. So
it's like going
it's like going through
reinforces the knowingness. So
it's like going through the
it's like going through the 4minute
reinforces the knowingness. So
it's like going through the 4minute mile
once
once it's
once it's been
once it's been done.
once it's been done. It's
once it's been done. It's easier
once it's been done. It's easier for
once it's been done. It's easier for the
next
next and
once it's been done. It's easier for the
next and it's
next and it's easier
once it's been done. It's easier for the
next and it's easier for
next and it's easier for the
once it's been done. It's easier for the
next and it's easier for the next
next and it's easier for the next and
it's
it's easier
it's easier for
it's easier for the
it's easier for the next.
it's easier for the next. So
it's easier for the next. So the
it's easier for the next. So the power
of
of the
it's easier for the next. So the power
of the knowingness
of the knowingness stands
it's easier for the next. So the power
of the knowingness stands there.
of the knowingness stands there. It
stands
stands still
stands still forever.
It's
It's there
stands still forever.
It's there for
It's there for all
stands still forever.
It's there for all eternity.
Consequently,
recoverable
recoverable by
Consequently,
recoverable by every
recoverable by every consciousness
Consequently,
recoverable by every consciousness that
reaches
reaches that
reaches that point
reaches that point fall
reaches that point fall into
reaches that point fall into the
automatic
automatic knowingness
reaches that point fall into the
automatic knowingness of
automatic knowingness of that
reaches that point fall into the
automatic knowingness of that certainty
without
without which
without which one
without which one could
without which one could not
without which one could not face
without which one could not face the
possibility
possibility of
being
being extinguished
being extinguished because
being extinguished because one
being extinguished because one is
convinced
convinced at
being extinguished because one is
convinced at that
convinced at that point
being extinguished because one is
convinced at that point that
convinced at that point that one
being extinguished because one is
convinced at that point that one is
about
about to
about to be
about to be extinguished.
And
you
you are
that
that what
you are
that what you
that what you thought
you are
that what you thought you
that what you thought you were
you are
that what you thought you were in.
So
So do
So do the
So do the energies
So do the energies that
So do the energies that you
So do the energies that you pick
So do the energies that you pick up
So do the energies that you pick up in
So do the energies that you pick up in a
situation
situation such
So do the energies that you pick up in a
situation such as
situation such as you
So do the energies that you pick up in a
situation such as you mentioned
situation such as you mentioned are
So do the energies that you pick up in a
situation such as you mentioned are they
of
of assist?
of assist? Yes.
of assist? Yes. I
of assist? Yes. I think
of assist? Yes. I think because
of assist? Yes. I think because karma
you
you went
of assist? Yes. I think because karma
you went there
you went there and
of assist? Yes. I think because karma
you went there and acknowledged
you went there and acknowledged it.
of assist? Yes. I think because karma
you went there and acknowledged it. Yes.
You
You answered
You answered yes.
You answered yes. Yes
You answered yes. Yes I
You answered yes. Yes I did.
You answered yes. Yes I did. Mhm.
>> I
>> I like
You answered yes. Yes I did. Mhm.
>> I like it.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. It
>> Yes. It was
>> Yes. It was very
>> Yes. It was very uh
>> Yes. It was very uh identifiable
>> Yes. It was very uh identifiable and
>> Yes. It was very uh identifiable and uh
>> we
>> we were
>> Yes. It was very uh identifiable and uh
>> we were all
>> we were all surprised.
>> Yes. It was very uh identifiable and uh
>> we were all surprised. We
>> we were all surprised. We had
>> Yes. It was very uh identifiable and uh
>> we were all surprised. We had no
>> we were all surprised. We had no idea.
See,
See, but
See, but the
See, but the reason
See, but the reason we
See, but the reason we went
See, but the reason we went over
See, but the reason we went over is
because
because we
See, but the reason we went over is
because we calibrated
because we calibrated it
See, but the reason we went over is
because we calibrated it before
because we calibrated it before we
See, but the reason we went over is
because we calibrated it before we went.
So
So I
So I went
>> we
>> we weren't
So I went
>> we weren't going
>> we weren't going on
So I went
>> we weren't going on a
>> we weren't going on a blind
So I went
>> we weren't going on a blind chase.
>> we weren't going on a blind chase. We
got
got Yes.
got Yes. Yeah.
got Yes. Yeah. And
got Yes. Yeah. And we
got Yes. Yeah. And we got
got Yes. Yeah. And we got what
got Yes. Yeah. And we got what it
got Yes. Yeah. And we got what it was
got Yes. Yeah. And we got what it was in
the
the 900s.
got Yes. Yeah. And we got what it was in
the 900s. I
the 900s. I said
>> in
>> in the
>> in the 900
>> in the 900 hunds.
>> in the 900 hunds. Get
>> in the 900 hunds. Get my
>> in the 900 hunds. Get my hat.
>> in the 900 hunds. Get my hat. We're
leaving.
So
So there.
So there. Yes.
So there. Yes. So
So there. Yes. So your
So there. Yes. So your question
So there. Yes. So your question was
So there. Yes. So your question was does
that
that accumulate
So there. Yes. So your question was does
that accumulate karmic
that accumulate karmic merit
So there. Yes. So your question was does
that accumulate karmic merit and
that accumulate karmic merit and my
answer
answer is
answer is yes
answer is yes it
answer is yes it does
answer is yes it does accumulate
answer is yes it does accumulate merit.
So
So everything
answer is yes it does accumulate merit.
So everything done
So everything done in
answer is yes it does accumulate merit.
So everything done in the
So everything done in the name
answer is yes it does accumulate merit.
So everything done in the name of
you
you see
you see everything
you see everything done
you see everything done in
you see everything done in the
you see everything done in the name
you see everything done in the name of
truth
truth everything
you see everything done in the name of
truth everything done
truth everything done in
you see everything done in the name of
truth everything done in the
truth everything done in the name
you see everything done in the name of
truth everything done in the name of
truth everything done in the name of uh
um
um glorification
um glorification of
um glorification of realization
um glorification of realization of
divinity
divinity as
um glorification of realization of
divinity as truth
divinity as truth anything
um glorification of realization of
divinity as truth anything done
divinity as truth anything done in
um glorification of realization of
divinity as truth anything done in its
name
then
then adds
name
then adds to
then adds to one's
name
then adds to one's karmic
then adds to one's karmic merit
name
then adds to one's karmic merit you
then adds to one's karmic merit you see
things
things done
things done out
things done out of
things done out of faith
things done out of faith trust
things done out of faith trust service
to
to others
things done out of faith trust service
to others expecting
to others expecting no
things done out of faith trust service
to others expecting no recompense
to others expecting no recompense no
recognition
I'm
I'm glad
recognition
I'm glad you
I'm glad you went.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you. You
>> Thank you. You too.
>> Thank you. You too. Thank
>> Thank you. You too. Thank you
>> Thank you. You too. Thank you very
>> Thank you. You too. Thank you very much.
>> We're
>> We're fellow
>> Thank you. You too. Thank you very much.
>> We're fellow vibrators
>> We're fellow vibrators on
>> Thank you. You too. Thank you very much.
>> We're fellow vibrators on that
>> We're fellow vibrators on that little
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yes
>> Oh, yes indeed.
>> Greetings.
>> Greetings. Um,
>> yeah.
>> I'd
>> I'd like
>> yeah.
>> I'd like to
>> I'd like to delve
>> yeah.
>> I'd like to delve a
>> I'd like to delve a little
>> yeah.
>> I'd like to delve a little into
>> I'd like to delve a little into the
>> yeah.
>> I'd like to delve a little into the I
>> I'd like to delve a little into the I am
presence
presence and
presence and awareness.
presence and awareness. That's
presence and awareness. That's a
presence and awareness. That's a phrase.
>> Where'd
>> Where'd you
presence and awareness. That's a phrase.
>> Where'd you get
>> Where'd you get that
presence and awareness. That's a phrase.
>> Where'd you get that phrase?
>> The
>> The verbiage
>> The verbiage from
>> The verbiage from Nisagarat.
>> Huh?
>> From
>> From the
>> From the I
>> From the I am
>> From the I am that
>> From the I am that book.
>> From the I am that book. Nisagar
>> From the I am that book. Nisagar Gadata.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, there
>> From the I am that book. Nisagar Gadata.
>> Oh, there you
>> Oh, there you go.
>> From the I am that book. Nisagar Gadata.
>> Oh, there you go. From
>> Oh, there you go. From there.
>> From the I am that book. Nisagar Gadata.
>> Oh, there you go. From there. Yeah.
>> And
>> And I
>> And I was
>> And I was just
>> And I was just for
>> And I was just for as
>> And I was just for as a
>> And I was just for as a mantra
>> And I was just for as a mantra for
myself,
myself, I've
>> And I was just for as a mantra for
myself, I've been
myself, I've been using
>> And I was just for as a mantra for
myself, I've been using a
myself, I've been using a number
>> And I was just for as a mantra for
myself, I've been using a number of
different
different ones,
different ones, but
different ones, but it
different ones, but it seems
different ones, but it seems to
different ones, but it seems to me
different ones, but it seems to me when
I'm
I'm meditating,
different ones, but it seems to me when
I'm meditating, the
I'm meditating, the best
different ones, but it seems to me when
I'm meditating, the best one
I'm meditating, the best one would
different ones, but it seems to me when
I'm meditating, the best one would be
I'm meditating, the best one would be I
am
am since
am since it
am since it seems
am since it seems to
am since it seems to be
am since it seems to be the
am since it seems to be the root
am since it seems to be the root of
am since it seems to be the root of all
thought
thought and
am since it seems to be the root of all
thought and that
thought and that it
am since it seems to be the root of all
thought and that it sort
thought and that it sort of
am since it seems to be the root of all
thought and that it sort of takes
thought and that it sort of takes me
am since it seems to be the root of all
thought and that it sort of takes me to
the
the root.
the root. So,
the root. So, it
the root. So, it helped
the root. So, it helped me
the root. So, it helped me sort
the root. So, it helped me sort of
the root. So, it helped me sort of get
to
to that
the root. So, it helped me sort of get
to that point.
to that point. And
the root. So, it helped me sort of get
to that point. And I
to that point. And I was
the root. So, it helped me sort of get
to that point. And I was wondering
to that point. And I was wondering what
I
I am
I am would
I am would calibrate
I am would calibrate as
I am would calibrate as a
I am would calibrate as a mantra.
>> Um,
you
you want
you want my
you want my view?
Please.
Amnest
Amnest amnness
Amnest amnness is
Amnest amnness is already
Amnest amnness is already a
Amnest amnness is already a step
Amnest amnness is already a step away
from
from the
Amnest amnness is already a step away
from the ultimate
from the ultimate realization
Amnest amnness is already a step away
from the ultimate realization because
it's
it's a
it's a intransitive
it's a intransitive verb.
There
There is
it's a intransitive verb.
There is a
There is a this
it's a intransitive verb.
There is a this that
There is a this that is
it's a intransitive verb.
There is a this that is expressing
There is a this that is expressing of
that.
Uh
Uh an
that.
Uh an I
Uh an I that
that.
Uh an I that is
Uh an I that is representing
that.
Uh an I that is representing the
Uh an I that is representing the quality
of
of beingness
as
as isness
of beingness
as isness in
as isness in the
of beingness
as isness in the intransitive
as isness in the intransitive verb
amnness.
It's
It's a
amnness.
It's a step
It's a step away
amnness.
It's a step away from
It's a step away from the
amnness.
It's a step away from the ultimate
reality.
It's
It's not
reality.
It's not it
It's not it doesn't
reality.
It's not it doesn't calibrate
It's not it doesn't calibrate this
reality.
It's not it doesn't calibrate this high.
It's
It's unnecessary
It's unnecessary to
It's unnecessary to say
It's unnecessary to say am.
It's unnecessary to say am. What
It's unnecessary to say am. What do
It's unnecessary to say am. What do you
want
want to
It's unnecessary to say am. What do you
want to say
want to say M
It's unnecessary to say am. What do you
want to say M for
want to say M for without
It's unnecessary to say am. What do you
want to say M for without Mness?
want to say M for without Mness? There's
no
no statement
no statement such
no statement such as
no statement such as I
no statement such as I could
no statement such as I could even
no statement such as I could even be
made.
made. So
no statement such as I could even be
made. So therefore,
made. So therefore, it's
no statement such as I could even be
made. So therefore, it's redundant.
It's
It's an
It's an excess
It's an excess verbage
It's an excess verbage and
It's an excess verbage and an
It's an excess verbage and an excess
concept.
And
And an
And an intritive
And an intritive verb
And an intritive verb is
And an intritive verb is not
And an intritive verb is not an
improvement
improvement on.
So
So I
So I would
So I would not,
So I would not, you
So I would not, you know,
So I would not, you know, if
So I would not, you know, if you're
asking
asking me
So I would not, you know, if you're
asking me as
asking me as a
So I would not, you know, if you're
asking me as a teacher,
asking me as a teacher, I
So I would not, you know, if you're
asking me as a teacher, I would
asking me as a teacher, I would say
you
you don't
you don't need
you don't need to
you don't need to chant
you don't need to chant words.
you don't need to chant words. You
you don't need to chant words. You don't
need
need to
you don't need to chant words. You don't
need to repeat
need to repeat um
you don't need to chant words. You don't
need to repeat um the
need to repeat um the words
you don't need to chant words. You don't
need to repeat um the words themselves.
Experience
Experience the
Experience the reality,
Experience the reality, the
Experience the reality, the source
Experience the reality, the source out
of
of which
Experience the reality, the source out
of which those
of which those words
Experience the reality, the source out
of which those words arise.
Save
Save yourself
Save yourself 22
Save yourself 22 lifetimes.
Save yourself 22 lifetimes. Yeah.
the
the source
Save yourself 22 lifetimes. Yeah.
the source out
the source out of
Save yourself 22 lifetimes. Yeah.
the source out of which
the source out of which s
Save yourself 22 lifetimes. Yeah.
the source out of which s such
the source out of which s such a
statement
statement could
statement could arise
you
you recognize
statement could arise
you recognize and
you recognize and identified
statement could arise
you recognize and identified that
you recognize and identified that as
statement could arise
you recognize and identified that as the
source
source of
source of your
source of your own
source of your own existence.
So
So to
source of your own existence.
So to realize
So to realize it
source of your own existence.
So to realize it as
So to realize it as the
source of your own existence.
So to realize it as the source
So to realize it as the source of
source of your own existence.
So to realize it as the source of your
existence,
it's
it's not
existence,
it's not necessary.
it's not necessary. In
existence,
it's not necessary. In fact,
it's not necessary. In fact, it's
existence,
it's not necessary. In fact, it's d
it's not necessary. In fact, it's d even
diloterious
diloterious to
diloterious to say
diloterious to say that
diloterious to say that it
diloterious to say that it is
diloterious to say that it is the
diloterious to say that it is the source
of
of my
diloterious to say that it is the source
of my existence
of my existence because
diloterious to say that it is the source
of my existence because that's
of my existence because that's a
wordingness
wordingness that's
wordingness that's going
wordingness that's going on
wordingness that's going on in
wordingness that's going on in the
wordingness that's going on in the mind
already
already and
wordingness that's going on in the mind
already and structure
already and structure and
wordingness that's going on in the mind
already and structure and some
already and structure and some syntax.
You
You understand?
>> Yes,
>> Yes, I
You understand?
>> Yes, I do.
>> I
>> I was
>> I was thinking
>> I was thinking um
>> I was thinking um excuse
>> I was thinking um excuse me,
>> I was thinking um excuse me, but
>> I was thinking um excuse me, but I
>> I was thinking um excuse me, but I was
thinking
thinking that
>> I was thinking um excuse me, but I was
thinking that it's
thinking that it's an
>> I was thinking um excuse me, but I was
thinking that it's an intermediate
stuff.
stuff. I
stuff. I recognize
stuff. I recognize that
stuff. I recognize that to
stuff. I recognize that to let's
stuff. I recognize that to let's say
meditate
meditate on
>> um
>> um without
>> um without any
>> um without any verbiage
>> um without any verbiage or
>> um without any verbiage or just
>> um without any verbiage or just the
source
source of
>> um without any verbiage or just the
source of that
>> thoughts
>> thoughts still
>> thoughts still sort
>> thoughts still sort of
>> thoughts still sort of creep
>> thoughts still sort of creep in
>> thoughts still sort of creep in and
>> thoughts still sort of creep in and it
seemed
seemed to
>> thoughts still sort of creep in and it
seemed to me
seemed to me that
>> thoughts still sort of creep in and it
seemed to me that as
seemed to me that as an
>> thoughts still sort of creep in and it
seemed to me that as an intermediate
step
step in
step in as
step in as as
step in as as one
step in as as one progresses
step in as as one progresses it
step in as as one progresses it seems
step in as as one progresses it seems to
get
get to
step in as as one progresses it seems to
get to the
get to the root
step in as as one progresses it seems to
get to the root of
get to the root of all
step in as as one progresses it seems to
get to the root of all the
get to the root of all the other
extraneous
extraneous thoughts
extraneous thoughts and
extraneous thoughts and it
extraneous thoughts and it and
extraneous thoughts and it and so
extraneous thoughts and it and so as
>> no
>> no pragmatic
extraneous thoughts and it and so as
>> no pragmatic use
>> no pragmatic use youthfulness
extraneous thoughts and it and so as
>> no pragmatic use youthfulness along
>> no pragmatic use youthfulness along the
way
way I
way I never
way I never agreed
way I never agreed with
way I never agreed with that
way I never agreed with that title
way I never agreed with that title for
the
the book
way I never agreed with that title for
the book and
the book and I
way I never agreed with that title for
the book and I never
the book and I never would
way I never agreed with that title for
the book and I never would have
the book and I never would have picked
it
it up
it up that
it up that title
it up that title myself
because
there's
there's an
there's an implied
there's an implied duality.
there's an implied duality. There's
there's an implied duality. There's an
eye
eye that
there's an implied duality. There's an
eye that is
eye that is a
there's an implied duality. There's an
eye that is a that
eye that is a that you
there's an implied duality. There's an
eye that is a that you know.
eye that is a that you know. So,
there's an implied duality. There's an
eye that is a that you know. So, and
eye that is a that you know. So, and I'm
from
from a
from a non-dualistic
from a non-dualistic viewpoint,
there's
there's no
from a non-dualistic viewpoint,
there's no division
there's no division and
there
there is
there is no
there is no subject
there is no subject that
there is no subject that could
there is no subject that could be
exhibiting
exhibiting it.
there is no subject that could be
exhibiting it. The
exhibiting it. The qualities
there is no subject that could be
exhibiting it. The qualities of
exhibiting it. The qualities of an
intransitive
intransitive verb
intransitive verb beingness,
intransitive verb beingness, existence,
uh
uh wasness,
intransitive verb beingness, existence,
uh wasness, will
uh wasness, will will
intransitive verb beingness, existence,
uh wasness, will will beingness
uh wasness, will will beingness or
intransitive verb beingness, existence,
uh wasness, will will beingness or any
other
other quality.
other quality. See,
>> that's
>> that's like
other quality. See,
>> that's like uh
>> that's like uh qualifying
other quality. See,
>> that's like uh qualifying it.
>> that's like uh qualifying it. And
other quality. See,
>> that's like uh qualifying it. And uh
>> that's like uh qualifying it. And uh so
it's
it's an
it's an unnecessary
it's an unnecessary um
it's an unnecessary um implication
beneath
beneath the
it's an unnecessary um implication
beneath the thought
beneath the thought eye
is
is that
is that out
is that out of
is that out of which
is that out of which the
is that out of which the thought
is that out of which the thought eye
arises.
arises. That's
is that out of which the thought eye
arises. That's where
arises. That's where to
is that out of which the thought eye
arises. That's where to look
and
and it's
and it's silent.
and it's silent. So
and it's silent. So it
and it's silent. So it doesn't
and it's silent. So it doesn't say
anything.
anything. So
and it's silent. So it doesn't say
anything. So to
anything. So to verbalize
and it's silent. So it doesn't say
anything. So to verbalize the
anything. So to verbalize the thought
and it's silent. So it doesn't say
anything. So to verbalize the thought is
already
already to
already to preclude
already to preclude it
already to preclude it because
already to preclude it because it
already to preclude it because it arises
out
out of
already to preclude it because it arises
out of nothing.
The
The source
The source of
The source of all
The source of all that
The source of all that exists
The source of all that exists is
The source of all that exists is out
The source of all that exists is out of
it.
it. The
The source of all that exists is out of
it. The nothingness,
it. The nothingness, you
The source of all that exists is out of
it. The nothingness, you know,
each
each thought
each thought arises
each thought arises out
each thought arises out of
each thought arises out of nothing.
each thought arises out of nothing. Each
thought
becomes
becomes u
becomes u actualization
becomes u actualization of
becomes u actualization of its
becomes u actualization of its own
potential.
The
The awareness
The awareness of
The awareness of your
The awareness of your own
The awareness of your own existence
arises
arises out
The awareness of your own existence
arises out of
arises out of the
The awareness of your own existence
arises out of the unmanifest
arises out of the unmanifest becoming
manifest
manifest as
manifest as the
manifest as the awareness
manifest as the awareness of
manifest as the awareness of your
manifest as the awareness of your own
existence.
existence. It
manifest as the awareness of your own
existence. It comes
existence. It comes out
manifest as the awareness of your own
existence. It comes out of
existence. It comes out of the
manifest as the awareness of your own
existence. It comes out of the field
existence. It comes out of the field of
consciousness
consciousness itself
consciousness itself which
consciousness itself which is
consciousness itself which is all
non-verbal.
So
So why
So why take
So why take that's
So why take that's a
So why take that's a longer
So why take that's a longer route
So why take that's a longer route best
to
to just
So why take that's a longer route best
to just bypass.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. No,
>> Yeah. No, but
>> Yeah. No, but it's
>> Yeah. No, but it's takes
>> Yeah. No, but it's takes more
discipline.
>> No,
>> No, it's
>> No, it's very
>> No, it's very good
>> No, it's very good along
>> No, it's very good along the
>> No, it's very good along the way.
>> No, it's very good along the way. See,
but
but then
>> No, it's very good along the way. See,
but then there
but then there comes
>> No, it's very good along the way. See,
but then there comes the
but then there comes the point
>> No, it's very good along the way. See,
but then there comes the point where
but then there comes the point where you
have
have to
have to let
have to let go.
I
I amness.
have to let go.
I amness. You
I amness. You see,
have to let go.
I amness. You see, and
I amness. You see, and I
have to let go.
I amness. You see, and I never
I amness. You see, and I never agreed
with
with that
with that title
with that title anyway.
with that title anyway. I
with that title anyway. I thought
with that title anyway. I thought it
with that title anyway. I thought it was
an
an incorrect
with that title anyway. I thought it was
an incorrect title.
an incorrect title. There
with that title anyway. I thought it was
an incorrect title. There is
an incorrect title. There is no
with that title anyway. I thought it was
an incorrect title. There is no I
an incorrect title. There is no I that
is
is a
is a that
is a that you
is a that you know
is a that you know no
is a that you know no way.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. So
is a that you know no way.
>> Yes. So in
>> Yes. So in just
is a that you know no way.
>> Yes. So in just if
>> Yes. So in just if I
is a that you know no way.
>> Yes. So in just if I understand
>> Yes. So in just if I understand it
correctly
the
the as
correctly
the as an
the as an intermediate
correctly
the as an intermediate step
the as an intermediate step it
correctly
the as an intermediate step it may
the as an intermediate step it may be
okay
okay but
okay but ideally
okay but ideally one
okay but ideally one would
okay but ideally one would bypass
okay but ideally one would bypass it
completely
completely and
okay but ideally one would bypass it
completely and go
completely and go straight
okay but ideally one would bypass it
completely and go straight to
completely and go straight to that
source
source and
source and that's
source and that's where
source and that's where the
source and that's where the discip
source and that's where the discip you
know
know in
source and that's where the discip you
know in that's
know in that's where
source and that's where the discip you
know in that's where the
know in that's where the discipline
comes
comes in
comes in because
comes in because it's
comes in because it's I
comes in because it's I am
comes in because it's I am is
comes in because it's I am is a
comes in because it's I am is a little
easier
easier than
comes in because it's I am is a little
easier than going
easier than going straight
comes in because it's I am is a little
easier than going straight to
easier than going straight to it
comes in because it's I am is a little
easier than going straight to it because
being
being just
being just in
being just in source
being just in source without
being just in source without any
being just in source without any verb
>> you
>> you meditate
being just in source without any verb
>> you meditate on
>> you meditate on where
being just in source without any verb
>> you meditate on where such
>> you meditate on where such a
being just in source without any verb
>> you meditate on where such a thought
could
could arise.
>> Yeah
>> the
>> the thought
>> the thought I
>> the thought I is
>> the thought I is a
>> the thought I is a Nominalization.
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Well,
>> Okay. Well, I
>> Okay. Well, I got
>> Okay. Well, I got I
>> Okay. Well, I got I get
>> Okay. Well, I got I get it
>> Okay. Well, I got I get it better
>> Okay. Well, I got I get it better now.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's
>> Okay. Well, I got I get it better now.
>> Yeah. It's a
>> Yeah. It's a nominalization.
>> Okay. Well, I got I get it better now.
>> Yeah. It's a nominalization. Therefore,
it's
it's a
it's a interference.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. Yeah.
it's a interference.
>> Yes. Yeah. Okay.
>> Cuz
>> Cuz it's
>> Cuz it's a
>> Cuz it's a distraction.
>> It's
>> It's putting
>> Cuz it's a distraction.
>> It's putting into
>> It's putting into form
>> Cuz it's a distraction.
>> It's putting into form that
>> It's putting into form that which
>> Cuz it's a distraction.
>> It's putting into form that which is
formless.
formless. The
formless. The word
formless. The word I
formless. The word I and
formless. The word I and the
formless. The word I and the word
amnness
or
or thatness
or thatness are
or thatness are already
or thatness are already taking
or thatness are already taking the
nonlinear
nonlinear and
or thatness are already taking the
nonlinear and giving
nonlinear and giving it
or thatness are already taking the
nonlinear and giving it some
nonlinear and giving it some kind
or thatness are already taking the
nonlinear and giving it some kind of
form.
>> Mhm.
>> The
>> The formless
>> The formless and
>> The formless and giving
>> The formless and giving it
>> The formless and giving it form.
>> The formless and giving it form. The
unmanifest
unmanifest is
>> The formless and giving it form. The
unmanifest is formless.
>> Right?
>> Right? So,
>> and
>> and when
>> Right? So,
>> and when it
>> and when it does
>> Right? So,
>> and when it does manifest,
>> and when it does manifest, it
>> Right? So,
>> and when it does manifest, it manifests
as
as all
as all the
as all the totality
as all the totality of
as all the totality of all
as all the totality of all of
as all the totality of all of existence.
First
First discernable
as all the totality of all of existence.
First discernable at
First discernable at the
as all the totality of all of existence.
First discernable at the base
First discernable at the base of
consciousness
consciousness as
consciousness as the
consciousness as the source
consciousness as the source of
consciousness as the source of existence
itself.
itself. But
consciousness as the source of existence
itself. But even
itself. But even that
consciousness as the source of existence
itself. But even that you
itself. But even that you see
consciousness as the source of existence
itself. But even that you see as
itself. But even that you see as a
verbalization,
verbalization, you
verbalization, you know,
verbalization, you know, verbalization,
>> right?
>> right? Just
verbalization, you know, verbalization,
>> right? Just to
>> right? Just to finish
verbalization, you know, verbalization,
>> right? Just to finish up
>> right? Just to finish up then
verbalization, you know, verbalization,
>> right? Just to finish up then when
>> right? Just to finish up then when I'm
in
in a
in a traffic
in a traffic jam
in a traffic jam or
in a traffic jam or a
in a traffic jam or a bank
in a traffic jam or a bank lineup,
in a traffic jam or a bank lineup, I
usually
usually repeat.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah.
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. I
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. I see
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. I see the
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. I see the point
>> just
>> just because
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. I see the point
>> just because that's
>> just because that's it's
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. I see the point
>> just because that's it's practical
>> just because that's it's practical in
>> Oh, yeah. Yeah. I see the point
>> just because that's it's practical in a
bank
bank when
bank when there's
bank when there's noise
bank when there's noise around
>> pragmatically
>> pragmatically useful.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. And
>> Yes. And as
>> Yes. And as compared
>> Yes. And as compared now
is
is still
>> Yes. And as compared now
is still obviously
is still obviously form
>> Yes. And as compared now
is still obviously form you're
is still obviously form you're thinking
you're
you're asking
yourself
yourself along
you're asking
yourself along the
yourself along the way
you're asking
yourself along the way like
yourself along the way like you
you're asking
yourself along the way like you say
>> right
>> and
>> and so
>> right
>> and so the
>> and so the I
>> right
>> and so the I am
>> and so the I am is
>> right
>> and so the I am is equivalent
>> and so the I am is equivalent to
>> right
>> and so the I am is equivalent to that.
>> That's
>> That's yes
>> That's yes it's
>> That's yes it's just
>> That's yes it's just different
languaging
languaging for
>> That's yes it's just different
languaging for the
languaging for the same
>> okay
>> okay I
>> okay I got
>> okay I got it
>> okay I got it then.
>> That's
>> That's great.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
Good
Good to
>> Thank you.
Good to see
Good to see you.
>> I'd
>> I'd like
>> I'd like to
>> I'd like to start
>> I'd like to start by
>> I'd like to start by referring
>> I'd like to start by referring back
>> I'd like to start by referring back to
your
your page
>> I'd like to start by referring back to
your page 19
your page 19 or
>> I'd like to start by referring back to
your page 19 or slide
your page 19 or slide 19
>> I'd like to start by referring back to
your page 19 or slide 19 with
your page 19 or slide 19 with the
>> I'd like to start by referring back to
your page 19 or slide 19 with the uh
animals.
animals. My
animals. My question
animals. My question has
animals. My question has to
animals. My question has to do
animals. My question has to do with
animals
and
and uh
uh
uh in
and uh
uh in reading
uh in reading the
and uh
uh in reading the eye
uh in reading the eye I
and uh
uh in reading the eye I believe
uh in reading the eye I believe I
comprehended
comprehended it
comprehended it correctly
comprehended it correctly in
comprehended it correctly in that
comprehended it correctly in that a
comprehended it correctly in that a dog
doesn't
doesn't know
comprehended it correctly in that a dog
doesn't know the
doesn't know the difference
comprehended it correctly in that a dog
doesn't know the difference between
doesn't know the difference between its
sleeping
sleeping state
sleeping state and
sleeping state and its
sleeping state and its awake
sleeping state and its awake state
sleeping state and its awake state and
I
I then
sleeping state and its awake state and
I then think
I then think somehow
sleeping state and its awake state and
I then think somehow I
I then think somehow I came
sleeping state and its awake state and
I then think somehow I came along
I then think somehow I came along to
sleeping state and its awake state and
I then think somehow I came along to the
>> it
>> it doesn't
>> it doesn't identify
>> it doesn't identify one
>> it doesn't identify one is
>> it doesn't identify one is more
>> it doesn't identify one is more real
than
than another
>> right
>> they
>> they have
>> right
>> they have equal
>> they have equal levels
>> right
>> they have equal levels of
reality
>> so
>> so it
reality
>> so it doesn't
>> so it doesn't really
reality
>> so it doesn't really experience
>> so it doesn't really experience its
reality
>> so it doesn't really experience its own
death.
death. Is
death. Is that
death. Is that was
death. Is that was that
death. Is that was that part
death. Is that was that part of
death. Is that was that part of that
section?
>> What?
>> It
>> It doesn't
>> What?
>> It doesn't really
>> It doesn't really experience
>> What?
>> It doesn't really experience its
>> It doesn't really experience its own
death.
>> The
>> The dog,
>> right?
That
That was
>> right?
That was uh
>> Are
>> Are you
>> Are you going
>> Are you going to
>> Are you going to move
>> Are you going to move around?
The
The dog
>> Are you going to move around?
The dog does
The dog does not
>> Are you going to move around?
The dog does not experience
The dog does not experience its
>> Are you going to move around?
The dog does not experience its own
death.
The
The dog
death.
The dog experiences
The dog experiences its
death.
The dog experiences its own
The dog experiences its own physical
death.
It
It experiences
death.
It experiences its
It experiences its own
death.
It experiences its own spiritual
It experiences its own spiritual death.
The
The dog
The dog goes
The dog goes right
The dog goes right on,
but
but now
The dog goes right on,
but now it
but now it has
The dog goes right on,
but now it has a
but now it has a new
The dog goes right on,
but now it has a new chapter
but now it has a new chapter as
The dog goes right on,
but now it has a new chapter as a
different
different doggy
different doggy story.
>> Right.
>> Right. So,
different doggy story.
>> Right. So, does
>> Right. So, does it
different doggy story.
>> Right. So, does it have
>> Right. So, does it have a
different doggy story.
>> Right. So, does it have a does
>> Right. So, does it have a does the
spirit
>> I
>> I don't
spirit
>> I don't get
>> I don't get that
spirit
>> I don't get that it
>> I don't get that it prefers
spirit
>> I don't get that it prefers one
>> I don't get that it prefers one of
spirit
>> I don't get that it prefers one of the
one
one level
one level over
one level over the
one level over the other?
one level over the other? It
one level over the other? It doesn't
differentiate.
differentiate. In
one level over the other? It doesn't
differentiate. In other
differentiate. In other words,
one level over the other? It doesn't
differentiate. In other words, when
you're
you're in
you're in the
you're in the middle
you're in the middle of
you're in the middle of a
you're in the middle of a nightmare,
you
you know,
you're in the middle of a nightmare,
you know, it
you know, it seems
you're in the middle of a nightmare,
you know, it seems real
you know, it seems real at
you're in the middle of a nightmare,
you know, it seems real at the
you know, it seems real at the time
you're
you're experiencing
you're experiencing it.
And
And um
you're experiencing it.
And um so
And um so at
you're experiencing it.
And um so at that
And um so at that time
you're experiencing it.
And um so at that time it
And um so at that time it seems
you're experiencing it.
And um so at that time it seems as
And um so at that time it seems as real
as
as any
as any other
as any other state
as any other state of
as any other state of consciousness.
Yeah.
>> And
>> And does
>> And does that
>> And does that dog
>> And does that dog have
>> And does that dog have an
>> And does that dog have an eternal
existence?
existence? Does
>> And does that dog have an eternal
existence? Does it
existence? Does it spirit
>> And does that dog have an eternal
existence? Does it spirit have
existence? Does it spirit have an
eternal
eternal life?
eternal life? Or
eternal life? Or does
eternal life? Or does the
eternal life? Or does the horse
eternal life? Or does the horse have
eternal life? Or does the horse have an
eternal
>> dude?
>> dude? I
>> dude? I don't
>> dude? I don't know.
>> Right.
>> Right. So
>> dude? I don't know.
>> Right. So you
>> Right. So you never
>> Well,
>> Well, you'd
>> Well, you'd have
>> Well, you'd have to
>> Well, you'd have to be
>> Well, you'd have to be it
>> Well, you'd have to be it to
>> Right.
>> Right. Yeah.
>> Well, you'd have to be it to
>> Right. Yeah. That's
>> Right. Yeah. That's like
>> Well, you'd have to be it to
>> Right. Yeah. That's like not
>> Right. Yeah. That's like not knowing
>> Well, you'd have to be it to
>> Right. Yeah. That's like not knowing the
rock
rock unless
rock unless the
rock unless the question.
>> I
>> I think
rock unless the question.
>> I think it
>> I think it wants
rock unless the question.
>> I think it wants you
>> I think it wants you to
rock unless the question.
>> I think it wants you to answer
>> I think it wants you to answer it
rock unless the question.
>> I think it wants you to answer it from
>> I think it wants you to answer it from a
dog's
dog's point
dog's point of
dog's point of view.
dog's point of view. You
dog's point of view. You can't
dog's point of view. You can't because
you're
you're not
dog's point of view. You can't because
you're not a
you're not a dog.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, from
>> Oh, from a
>> Oh, from a dog's
>> Oh, from a dog's point
>> Oh, from a dog's point of
>> Oh, from a dog's point of view.
>> Oh, from a dog's point of view. Oh.
>> Oh, from a dog's point of view. Oh. Oh.
Well,
Well, actually,
>> Oh, from a dog's point of view. Oh. Oh.
Well, actually, I'm
Well, actually, I'm asking
>> Oh, from a dog's point of view. Oh. Oh.
Well, actually, I'm asking is
Well, actually, I'm asking is is
>> Oh, from a dog's point of view. Oh. Oh.
Well, actually, I'm asking is is is
Well, actually, I'm asking is is is the
is
is the
is the human
is the human the
is the human the only
>> you're
>> you're asking
is the human the only
>> you're asking some
>> you're asking some more
is the human the only
>> you're asking some more existential
question.
question. If
question. If you
question. If you phrase
question. If you phrase it
question. If you phrase it more
generally,
generally, I'll
question. If you phrase it more
generally, I'll get
generally, I'll get it.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. So,
>> Okay. So, is
>> Okay. So, is the
>> Okay. So, is the human
>> Okay. So, is the human the
>> Okay. So, is the human the only
>> Okay. So, is the human the only uh
existence
existence on
>> Okay. So, is the human the only uh
existence on earth
existence on earth that
>> Okay. So, is the human the only uh
existence on earth that has
existence on earth that has an
>> Okay. So, is the human the only uh
existence on earth that has an eternal
spirit?
>> It
>> It has
spirit?
>> It has an
>> It has an eternal
spirit?
>> It has an eternal spirit.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. The
>> Yeah. The collective
>> Yeah. The collective meaning
>> Yeah. The collective meaning multiple
lifetimes.
Oh,
Oh, karmically
Oh, karmically evolves,
>> right?
>> right? Karmically
Oh, karmically evolves,
>> right? Karmically evolves.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, okay.
>> Oh, okay. So,
>> Oh, okay. So, the
>> Oh, okay. So, the animal
>> Oh, okay. So, the animal kingdom,
>> Oh, okay. So, the animal kingdom, well,
we
we demonstrated
>> Oh, okay. So, the animal kingdom, well,
we demonstrated this
we demonstrated this morning.
>> Oh, okay. So, the animal kingdom, well,
we demonstrated this morning. It
we demonstrated this morning. It is
>> Oh, okay. So, the animal kingdom, well,
we demonstrated this morning. It is its
own
own evolution.
own evolution. You
own evolution. You know,
>> confusing.
>> Well,
>> Well, I
>> Well, I know
>> Well, I know that's
>> Well, I know that's what
>> Well, I know that's what he's
>> Well, I know that's what he's acting.
See,
See, because
>> Well, I know that's what he's acting.
See, because he's
See, because he's begging
>> Well, I know that's what he's acting.
See, because he's begging the
See, because he's begging the question
by
by saying
by saying it's
by saying it's an
by saying it's an individual
by saying it's an individual to
by saying it's an individual to begin
with.
with. See?
>> Well,
>> Well, you
>> Well, you said
>> Well, you said that
>> Well, you said that a
>> Well, you said that a fly
>> Well, you said that a fly once
>> Well, you said that a fly once you
>> Well, you said that a fly once you hit
>> once
>> once you
>> Well, you said that a fly once you hit
>> once you hit
>> once you hit a
>> Well, you said that a fly once you hit
>> once you hit a fly,
>> once you hit a fly, it
>> Well, you said that a fly once you hit
>> once you hit a fly, it doesn't
>> once you hit a fly, it doesn't notice
the
the difference.
the difference. That's
the difference. That's right.
>> Ethereal
>> Ethereal kind
the difference. That's right.
>> Ethereal kind of
>> Ethereal kind of goes
the difference. That's right.
>> Ethereal kind of goes in.
>> He
>> He goes
>> He goes right
>> He goes right on
>> He goes right on flying
>> He goes right on flying along
>> He goes right on flying along the
difference.
difference. I
>> He goes right on flying along the
difference. I just
difference. I just asking
>> He goes right on flying along the
difference. I just asking are
difference. I just asking are the
animals
animals experiencing
animals experiencing that?
>> Yes,
>> Yes, that's
animals experiencing that?
>> Yes, that's what
>> Yes, that's what I'm
animals experiencing that?
>> Yes, that's what I'm asking.
>> Yes, that's what I'm asking. Right.
>> Uh
>> Uh we
>> Uh we have
>> Uh we have permission
>> Uh we have permission to
>> Uh we have permission to ask
>> Uh we have permission to ask this.
Uh
Uh like
>> Uh we have permission to ask this.
Uh like um
Uh like um mammals
>> Uh we have permission to ask this.
Uh like um mammals uh
Uh like um mammals uh go
>> Uh we have permission to ask this.
Uh like um mammals uh go through
Uh like um mammals uh go through the
same
same transition.
A
A mammal
same transition.
A mammal does
A mammal does not
same transition.
A mammal does not realize
A mammal does not realize it's
same transition.
A mammal does not realize it's left
A mammal does not realize it's left one
physicality
physicality and
physicality and now
physicality and now is
physicality and now is in
physicality and now is in a
physicality and now is in a different
state.
state. Is
physicality and now is in a different
state. Is it?
It
It does
It does recognize
It does recognize a
It does recognize a shift.
Uh
Uh it
It does recognize a shift.
Uh it doesn't
Uh it doesn't know
It does recognize a shift.
Uh it doesn't know what
Uh it doesn't know what it
It does recognize a shift.
Uh it doesn't know what it means.
resist.
resist. It
resist. It doesn't
resist. It doesn't know
resist. It doesn't know what
resist. It doesn't know what it
resist. It doesn't know what it means.
It
It just
resist. It doesn't know what it means.
It just is
It just is different
>> and
>> and then
>> and then it
>> and then it finds
>> and then it finds itself
>> and then it finds itself back
>> and then it finds itself back in
>> and then it finds itself back in the
field
field in
>> and then it finds itself back in the
field in Iowa
field in Iowa again.
>> Right.
>> Right. That's
>> Right. That's okay.
>> Right. That's okay. Good.
>> Right. That's okay. Good. Because
>> Right. That's okay. Good. Because cuz
>> Right. That's okay. Good. Because cuz my
my
my curiosity
>> Right. That's okay. Good. Because cuz my
my curiosity in
my curiosity in there
>> Right. That's okay. Good. Because cuz my
my curiosity in there has
my curiosity in there has to
>> Right. That's okay. Good. Because cuz my
my curiosity in there has to do
my curiosity in there has to do with
>> Right. That's okay. Good. Because cuz my
my curiosity in there has to do with the
fact
fact that
fact that we
fact that we do
fact that we do therapy
fact that we do therapy work
fact that we do therapy work with
animals
animals and
fact that we do therapy work with
animals and so
animals and so many
fact that we do therapy work with
animals and so many humans
animals and so many humans project
fact that we do therapy work with
animals and so many humans project the
animal
animal has
animal has a
animal has a spirit
animal has a spirit or
>> Oh,
>> Oh, I
animal has a spirit or
>> Oh, I see
>> Oh, I see what
animal has a spirit or
>> Oh, I see what you're
>> Oh, I see what you're saying.
>> Other
>> Other things
>> Other things like
>> Other things like that.
>> Other things like that. So
>> Other things like that. So for
>> Other things like that. So for me
>> Other things like that. So for me as
>> Other things like that. So for me as a
witness
witness to
>> Other things like that. So for me as a
witness to this
witness to this therapy.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. All right.
>> Okay. All right. See
>> Okay. All right. See what
>> Okay. All right. See what what
>> Okay. All right. See what what I
>> Okay. All right. See what what I got
about
about it
>> Okay. All right. See what what I got
about it was
uh
there's
there's a
uh
there's a collective
there's a collective animal
uh
there's a collective animal spirit.
there's a collective animal spirit. Yes.
>> See
>> See the
>> See the primitive
>> See the primitive man
>> See the primitive man sense
>> See the primitive man sense that
>> See the primitive man sense that there's
a
a collective
>> See the primitive man sense that there's
a collective animal
a collective animal spirit.
>> See the primitive man sense that there's
a collective animal spirit. See
a collective animal spirit. See certain
parts
parts of
parts of India
you
you know
parts of India
you know the
you know the tiger
is
is a
is a demi
is a demi god
is a demi god and
is a demi god and he's
is a demi god and he's he's
is a demi god and he's he's the
is a demi god and he's he's the god
is a demi god and he's he's the god of
the
the jungle.
>> Right?
>> Right? So
>> Right? So the
>> Right? So the tiger
>> Right? So the tiger spirit
>> Right? So the tiger spirit then
>> Right? So the tiger spirit then so
>> Right? So the tiger spirit then so all
right
right so
>> Right? So the tiger spirit then so all
right so the
right so the karma
>> Right? So the tiger spirit then so all
right so the karma of
right so the karma of animals
>> Right? So the tiger spirit then so all
right so the karma of animals is
collective
collective within
collective within the
collective within the collective
collective within the collective animal
spirit
spirit see
collective within the collective animal
spirit see so
spirit see so there's
collective within the collective animal
spirit see so there's a
spirit see so there's a collective
animal
animal spirit
animal spirit so
animal spirit so when
people
people have
animal spirit so when
people have intuited
people have intuited this
animal spirit so when
people have intuited this you
people have intuited this you know
animal spirit so when
people have intuited this you know a
long
long time
long time ago
long time ago and
long time ago and address
long time ago and address the
long time ago and address the animal
spirit
spirit directly
long time ago and address the animal
spirit directly they
spirit directly they are
long time ago and address the animal
spirit directly they are uh
spirit directly they are uh dealing
long time ago and address the animal
spirit directly they are uh dealing with
a
a certain
a certain reality
a certain reality okay
a certain reality okay we
a certain reality okay we could
a certain reality okay we could say
a certain reality okay we could say It's
an
an appropriate
a certain reality okay we could say It's
an appropriate reality.
an appropriate reality. Yes,
a certain reality okay we could say It's
an appropriate reality. Yes, it's
an appropriate reality. Yes, it's an
actually
actually an
actually an appropriate
actually an appropriate reality.
actually an appropriate reality. So
beyond
beyond consciousness
actually an appropriate reality. So
beyond consciousness level
what
what I
what I don't
what I don't know
what I don't know I
what I don't know I guess
what I don't know I guess humanness
what I don't know I guess humanness we
begin
begin to
what I don't know I guess humanness we
begin to develop
begin to develop an
what I don't know I guess humanness we
begin to develop an individual
begin to develop an individual spirit.
Okay.
Okay. So
Okay. So the
Okay. So the an
Okay. So the an individual
Okay. So the an individual spirit
Okay. So the an individual spirit spirit
is
is solely
Okay. So the an individual spirit spirit
is solely acruable
is solely acruable to
Okay. So the an individual spirit spirit
is solely acruable to the
is solely acruable to the karma
Okay. So the an individual spirit spirit
is solely acruable to the karma of
is solely acruable to the karma of man
and
and below
and below man.
and below man. Okay.
and below man. Okay. So
and below man. Okay. So it
and below man. Okay. So it could
and below man. Okay. So it could be
collective.
collective. All
and below man. Okay. So it could be
collective. All right.
collective. All right. Could
and below man. Okay. So it could be
collective. All right. Could be
individual
individual over
individual over 200
individual over 200 resist
individual over 200 resist below
individual over 200 resist below 200
it's
it's collective
individual over 200 resist below 200
it's collective above
it's collective above 200
individual over 200 resist below 200
it's collective above 200 it's
individual
more
more than
individual
more than 200
more than 200 over
individual
more than 200 over 200
yeah
yeah the
yeah the karma
yeah the karma becomes
yeah the karma becomes individualized
the
the spirit
yeah the karma becomes individualized
the spirit becomes
the spirit becomes individualized
yeah the karma becomes individualized
the spirit becomes individualized resist
all right
all right so
all right so over
all right so over 200
all right so over 200 the
all right so over 200 the indivi
all right so over 200 the indivi the
spirit
spirit becomes
all right so over 200 the indivi the
spirit becomes individualized
spirit becomes individualized before
that
that it's
that it's collective
>> so
>> so I
that it's collective
>> so I I
>> so I I did
that it's collective
>> so I I did understand
>> so I I did understand what
that it's collective
>> so I I did understand what you
>> so I I did understand what you said
that it's collective
>> so I I did understand what you said and
thank
thank you
thank you for
thank you for that.
thank you for that. And
thank you for that. And the
thank you for that. And the reason
thank you for that. And the reason and
asking
asking and
thank you for that. And the reason and
asking and wanting
asking and wanting to
thank you for that. And the reason and
asking and wanting to know
asking and wanting to know that
thank you for that. And the reason and
asking and wanting to know that is
asking and wanting to know that is that
when
uh
uh we
when
uh we deal
uh we deal with
when
uh we deal with addicts
uh we deal with addicts and
when
uh we deal with addicts and and
uh we deal with addicts and and people
in
in deep
in deep depressions
in deep depressions and
in deep depressions and they
in deep depressions and they come
in deep depressions and they come into
in deep depressions and they come into a
round
round pen
in deep depressions and they come into a
round pen area
round pen area where
in deep depressions and they come into a
round pen area where there's
round pen area where there's a
in deep depressions and they come into a
round pen area where there's a loose
horse
horse and
horse and just
horse and just by
horse and just by being
horse and just by being in
horse and just by being in that
horse and just by being in that that
human
human experience
horse and just by being in that that
human experience of
human experience of that
horse and just by being in that that
human experience of that uh
human experience of that uh bottom
hitting
hitting experience,
hitting experience, they
hitting experience, they have
hitting experience, they have a
hitting experience, they have a spiked
energy
energy whether
hitting experience, they have a spiked
energy whether it's
energy whether it's a
hitting experience, they have a spiked
energy whether it's a spiked
energy whether it's a spiked grief,
hitting experience, they have a spiked
energy whether it's a spiked grief, a
spiked
spiked anger.
spiked anger. Uh
spiked anger. Uh and
spiked anger. Uh and so
spiked anger. Uh and so when
spiked anger. Uh and so when they
spiked anger. Uh and so when they come
in,
in, the
spiked anger. Uh and so when they come
in, the horse
in, the horse reacts
spiked anger. Uh and so when they come
in, the horse reacts very
in, the horse reacts very specifically
to
>> Yes,
>> Yes, I
to
>> Yes, I know
>> Yes, I know what
to
>> Yes, I know what you're
>> Yes, I know what you're talking
to
>> Yes, I know what you're talking about.
>> Right.
>> Right. And
>> Right. And so
>> just
>> just like
>> Right. And so
>> just like they
>> just like they can
>> Right. And so
>> just like they can recognize
>> just like they can recognize a
>> Right. And so
>> just like they can recognize a lie
>> just like they can recognize a lie from
the
the truth.
>> Exactly.
>> Exactly. Yes.
the truth.
>> Exactly. Yes. So
>> Exactly. Yes. So my
the truth.
>> Exactly. Yes. So my question
>> Exactly. Yes. So my question was
the truth.
>> Exactly. Yes. So my question was and
>> Exactly. Yes. So my question was and I
we
we also
we also have
we also have horses
we also have horses die
we also have horses die on
we also have horses die on the
we also have horses die on the ranch.
It's
It's part
we also have horses die on the ranch.
It's part of
It's part of a
we also have horses die on the ranch.
It's part of a ranch
It's part of a ranch experience
we also have horses die on the ranch.
It's part of a ranch experience when
It's part of a ranch experience when you
have
have 30
have 30 horses
have 30 horses that
have 30 horses that horses
have 30 horses that horses are
have 30 horses that horses are going
have 30 horses that horses are going to
die
die and
have 30 horses that horses are going to
die and I
die and I see
have 30 horses that horses are going to
die and I see the
die and I see the reactions
have 30 horses that horses are going to
die and I see the reactions in
die and I see the reactions in in
have 30 horses that horses are going to
die and I see the reactions in in our
our
our human
our human customers
our human customers uh
our human customers uh when
our human customers uh when they
our human customers uh when they come
and
and and
our human customers uh when they come
and and you
and and you know
our human customers uh when they come
and and you know they're
and and you know they're wondering
our human customers uh when they come
and and you know they're wondering where
Jasmine
Jasmine went,
Jasmine went, where
Jasmine went, where Fluffy
Jasmine went, where Fluffy went
Jasmine went, where Fluffy went and
Jasmine went, where Fluffy went and all
that.
>> The
>> The same
>> The same thing
>> The same thing at
>> The same thing at the
>> The same thing at the girls
>> The same thing at the girls ranch,
>> The same thing at the girls ranch, you
know.
>> Right.
>> Right. Right.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. We
>> Right. Right.
>> Yeah. We got
>> Yeah. We got 30
>> Right. Right.
>> Yeah. We got 30 horses
>> Yeah. We got 30 horses there.
>> Right. Right.
>> Yeah. We got 30 horses there. And
>> Yeah. We got 30 horses there. And so
>> Right. Right.
>> Yeah. We got 30 horses there. And so my
my
my take
my take that
my take that was
my take that was so
my take that was so healing
my take that was so healing and
liberating
liberating for
my take that was so healing and
liberating for me
liberating for me was
my take that was so healing and
liberating for me was realizing
liberating for me was realizing that
basically
basically the
basically the animal
basically the animal is
basically the animal is going
basically the animal is going to
basically the animal is going to that
ethereal
ethereal place
basically the animal is going to that
ethereal place that
ethereal place that it
basically the animal is going to that
ethereal place that it was
ethereal place that it was here
basically the animal is going to that
ethereal place that it was here as
ethereal place that it was here as a
tool
tool and
tool and instrument
tool and instrument and
tool and instrument and and
tool and instrument and and not
tool and instrument and and not to
project
project all
tool and instrument and and not to
project all of
project all of the
tool and instrument and and not to
project all of the spirit
project all of the spirit and
tool and instrument and and not to
project all of the spirit and thinking
that
that I
that I was
that I was a
that I was a horse
that I was a horse once
that I was a horse once or
that I was a horse once or I
that I was a horse once or I was
that I was a horse once or I was a
that I was a horse once or I was a dog
once
once and
that I was a horse once or I was a dog
once and now
once and now I'm
that I was a horse once or I was a dog
once and now I'm a
once and now I'm a human,
that I was a horse once or I was a dog
once and now I'm a human, but
once and now I'm a human, but that
that I was a horse once or I was a dog
once and now I'm a human, but that I'm
here
here specifically
here specifically for
here specifically for the
here specifically for the human
experience
experience and
here specifically for the human
experience and that
experience and that the
here specifically for the human
experience and that the animals
experience and that the animals are
here specifically for the human
experience and that the animals are in
experience and that the animals are in a
very
very specific
very specific animal
very specific animal experience
very specific animal experience and
very specific animal experience and that
they're
they're of
very specific animal experience and that
they're of service
they're of service to
very specific animal experience and that
they're of service to the
they're of service to the humans
very specific animal experience and that
they're of service to the humans in
they're of service to the humans in this
um
um uh
um uh projection
um uh projection screen
um uh projection screen experience
um uh projection screen experience and
that
that when
um uh projection screen experience and
that when I
that when I come
um uh projection screen experience and
that when I come in
that when I come in with
um uh projection screen experience and
that when I come in with a
that when I come in with a spiked
energy,
energy, I
energy, I project
energy, I project it
energy, I project it right
energy, I project it right on
energy, I project it right on the
energy, I project it right on the horse.
And
And if
energy, I project it right on the horse.
And if I'm
And if I'm angry,
energy, I project it right on the horse.
And if I'm angry, the
And if I'm angry, the horse
energy, I project it right on the horse.
And if I'm angry, the horse starts
kicking.
kicking. If
kicking. If I'm
kicking. If I'm in
kicking. If I'm in deep
kicking. If I'm in deep grief
kicking. If I'm in deep grief or
kicking. If I'm in deep grief or apathy,
the
the horse
kicking. If I'm in deep grief or apathy,
the horse won't
the horse won't even
kicking. If I'm in deep grief or apathy,
the horse won't even move
the horse won't even move when
kicking. If I'm in deep grief or apathy,
the horse won't even move when you
the horse won't even move when you crack
a
a wet
a wet behind
a wet behind it.
>> So
>> So that's
a wet behind it.
>> So that's excuse
>> So that's excuse me,
a wet behind it.
>> So that's excuse me, my
>> So that's excuse me, my uh
a wet behind it.
>> So that's excuse me, my uh curiosity
>> So that's excuse me, my uh curiosity is
their
their role
their role in
their role in our
their role in our melting
their role in our melting pot.
You
You know
their role in our melting pot.
You know it
You know it says
their role in our melting pot.
You know it says ina
You know it says ina in
their role in our melting pot.
You know it says ina in the
You know it says ina in the u
their role in our melting pot.
You know it says ina in the u says
You know it says ina in the u says in
what
what you
what you call
what you call it
what you call it ga
what you call it ga that
what you call it ga that each
what you call it ga that each level
what you call it ga that each level is
subservient
subservient to
what you call it ga that each level is
subservient to the
subservient to the one
what you call it ga that each level is
subservient to the one above
subservient to the one above it.
what you call it ga that each level is
subservient to the one above it. The
subservient to the one above it. The rig
vida
vida the
vida the rig
vida the rig vida
vida the rig vida the
vida the rig vida the rig
vida the rig vida the rig vida
vida the rig vida the rig vida states
that
that each
vida the rig vida the rig vida states
that each level
that each level of
vida the rig vida the rig vida states
that each level of consciousness
that each level of consciousness is
subservient
subservient and
subservient and is
subservient and is sacrifices
subservient and is sacrifices itself
subservient and is sacrifices itself to
the
the level
subservient and is sacrifices itself to
the level above
the level above it.
subservient and is sacrifices itself to
the level above it. So
the level above it. So the
subservient and is sacrifices itself to
the level above it. So the animal
sacrifices
sacrifices his
sacrifices his life
sacrifices his life to
sacrifices his life to serve
sacrifices his life to serve the
sacrifices his life to serve the higher
energy
energy and
sacrifices his life to serve the higher
energy and by
energy and by so
sacrifices his life to serve the higher
energy and by so doing
uh
uh karmically
uh karmically earns
uh karmically earns its
uh karmically earns its own
uh karmically earns its own progression.
Yeah.
Yeah. So
uh karmically earns its own progression.
Yeah. So I
Yeah. So I agree
uh karmically earns its own progression.
Yeah. So I agree with
Yeah. So I agree with you.
uh karmically earns its own progression.
Yeah. So I agree with you. The
Yeah. So I agree with you. The animal
uh karmically earns its own progression.
Yeah. So I agree with you. The animal is
there
there to
there to serve
there to serve us
>> and
>> and but
there to serve us
>> and but in
>> and but in serving
there to serve us
>> and but in serving us
>> and but in serving us it
there to serve us
>> and but in serving us it also
>> and but in serving us it also serves
itself
itself inadvertently.
itself inadvertently. And
itself inadvertently. And and
itself inadvertently. And and that's
itself inadvertently. And and that's the
the
the last
itself inadvertently. And and that's the
the last part
the last part of
itself inadvertently. And and that's the
the last part of the
the last part of the question
itself inadvertently. And and that's the
the last part of the question is
the last part of the question is uh
itself inadvertently. And and that's the
the last part of the question is uh I
know
know you
know you can't
know you can't be
know you can't be the
know you can't be the rock
know you can't be the rock so
know you can't be the rock so I
know you can't be the rock so I can't
ask
ask you
know you can't be the rock so I can't
ask you what
ask you what the
know you can't be the rock so I can't
ask you what the horse
ask you what the horse experiences
know you can't be the rock so I can't
ask you what the horse experiences but
ask you what the horse experiences but I
guess
guess that's
guess that's the
guess that's the answer
guess that's the answer of
guess that's the answer of uh
guess that's the answer of uh I
guess that's the answer of uh I guess
that
that is
guess that's the answer of uh I guess
that is a
that is a self-answering
guess that's the answer of uh I guess
that is a self-answering to
that is a self-answering to the
guess that's the answer of uh I guess
that is a self-answering to the question
and
and that
and that the
and that the horse
and that the horse is
and that the horse is involved
and that the horse is involved because
it
it is
and that the horse is involved because
it is evolving
it is evolving also.
>> So
>> So is
>> So is benefiting
>> So is benefiting uh
>> So is benefiting uh by
>> So is benefiting uh by being
>> So is benefiting uh by being trapped
>> So is benefiting uh by being trapped in
an
an area
>> So is benefiting uh by being trapped in
an area with
an area with something
>> So is benefiting uh by being trapped in
an area with something with
an area with something with spiked
energy
>> and
>> and being
energy
>> and being of
>> and being of service
energy
>> and being of service to
>> and being of service to that
energy
>> and being of service to that healing
process.
>> Mhm.
>> Got
>> Got it.
>> Got it. That
>> Got it. That was
>> Got it. That was a
>> Got it. That was a long
>> Got it. That was a long mystery.
>> Got it. That was a long mystery. See
because
because divinity
>> Got it. That was a long mystery. See
because divinity is
because divinity is present
>> Got it. That was a long mystery. See
because divinity is present in
because divinity is present in all
>> Got it. That was a long mystery. See
because divinity is present in all that
it
it exists
it exists and
it exists and only
it exists and only the
it exists and only the awareness
it exists and only the awareness of
it exists and only the awareness of it
differentiates
differentiates the
it exists and only the awareness of it
differentiates the animal
differentiates the animal from
it exists and only the awareness of it
differentiates the animal from the
differentiates the animal from the human
and
and the
and the enlightened
and the enlightened being
>> right
>> the
>> the awareness
>> the awareness but
>> the awareness but the
>> the awareness but the presence
>> the awareness but the presence of
divinity
divinity as
>> the awareness but the presence of
divinity as the
divinity as the source
>> the awareness but the presence of
divinity as the source of
divinity as the source of one's
existence
existence is
existence is the
existence is the same
>> right
>> you
>> you can't
>> you can't exist
>> you can't exist as
>> you can't exist as a
>> you can't exist as a horse
>> you can't exist as a horse or
>> you can't exist as a horse or a
>> you can't exist as a horse or a human
>> right
>> without
>> without divinity
>> without divinity as
>> without divinity as a
>> without divinity as a source
>> without divinity as a source of
existence
>> it's
>> it's all
>> it's all one
>> it's all one but
>> it's all one but it
>> it's all one but it is
>> it's all one but it is there
>> it's all one but it is there there
>> it's all one but it is there there is
differentiation
>> yep
>> got
>> got it
>> yep
>> got it thank
>> got it thank you
>> yes
>> yes we
>> yes we use
>> yes we use horses
>> yes we use horses you
>> yes we use horses you at
>> yes we use horses you at girls
>> yes we use horses you at girls rants
>> yes we use horses you at girls rants to
uh
uh at
>> yes we use horses you at girls rants to
uh at part
uh at part of
>> yes we use horses you at girls rants to
uh at part of the
uh at part of the therapy
>> yes we use horses you at girls rants to
uh at part of the therapy coin
uh at part of the therapy coin therapy
uh
uh to
uh to reestablish
uh to reestablish uh
uh to reestablish uh self-confidence
uh to reestablish uh self-confidence and
dignity
dignity and
uh to reestablish uh self-confidence and
dignity and learn
dignity and learn to
uh to reestablish uh self-confidence and
dignity and learn to care
dignity and learn to care for
uh to reestablish uh self-confidence and
dignity and learn to care for others
dignity and learn to care for others to
care
care for
care for the
care for the value
care for the value of
care for the value of life.
care for the value of life. Yeah,
we
we all
care for the value of life. Yeah,
we all serve
we all serve each
care for the value of life. Yeah,
we all serve each other.
Yeah,
Yeah, we
Yeah, we all
Yeah, we all serve
Yeah, we all serve each
Yeah, we all serve each other.
It
It reminds
Yeah, we all serve each other.
It reminds me
It reminds me of
Yeah, we all serve each other.
It reminds me of our
It reminds me of our staff
Yeah, we all serve each other.
It reminds me of our staff that
It reminds me of our staff that serves
us.
us. We
us. We have
us. We have a
us. We have a huge
us. We have a huge staff
us. We have a huge staff that
us. We have a huge staff that works
seven
seven days
us. We have a huge staff that works
seven days a
seven days a week,
us. We have a huge staff that works
seven days a week, practically
seven days a week, practically around
the
the clock
the clock to
the clock to make
the clock to make things
the clock to make things like
the clock to make things like this
happen.
happen. And
the clock to make things like this
happen. And I
happen. And I wish
the clock to make things like this
happen. And I wish everybody
happen. And I wish everybody say
the clock to make things like this
happen. And I wish everybody say hi
happen. And I wish everybody say hi all
the
the staff
the staff people
the staff people that
the staff people that work
the staff people that work hard
the staff people that work hard to
the staff people that work hard to make
this
this happen.
Yeah.
Yeah. The
Yeah. The devotion
Yeah. The devotion of
Yeah. The devotion of karma
Yeah. The devotion of karma yoga,
Yeah. The devotion of karma yoga, you
know,
know, you
Yeah. The devotion of karma yoga, you
know, you serve
know, you serve that
Yeah. The devotion of karma yoga, you
know, you serve that that
know, you serve that that which
Yeah. The devotion of karma yoga, you
know, you serve that that which serves
that
that which
that which serves
that which serves and
that which serves and in
that which serves and in so
that which serves and in so doing
that which serves and in so doing we
that which serves and in so doing we uh
you
you know
that which serves and in so doing we uh
you know contribute
you know contribute to
that which serves and in so doing we uh
you know contribute to the
you know contribute to the consciousness
level
level of
level of all
level of all of
level of all of mankind.
level of all of mankind. You
level of all of mankind. You know
level of all of mankind. You know people
think
think what
level of all of mankind. You know people
think what can
think what can I
level of all of mankind. You know people
think what can I do
think what can I do to
level of all of mankind. You know people
think what can I do to save
think what can I do to save mankind?
level of all of mankind. You know people
think what can I do to save mankind? You
know
stay
stay out
know
stay out of
stay out of it.
Be
Be the
Be the best
Be the best human
Be the best human being
Be the best human being you
Be the best human being you know
Be the best human being you know how
Be the best human being you know how to
be.
be. Love
Be the best human being you know how to
be. Love the
be. Love the animals
Be the best human being you know how to
be. Love the animals to
be. Love the animals to the
Be the best human being you know how to
be. Love the animals to the best
be. Love the animals to the best of
Be the best human being you know how to
be. Love the animals to the best of your
ability
ability to
ability to love
ability to love the
ability to love the animals.
ability to love the animals. And
ability to love the animals. And uh
ability to love the animals. And uh that
dog
dog we
ability to love the animals. And uh that
dog we met
dog we met during
ability to love the animals. And uh that
dog we met during the
dog we met during the break
ability to love the animals. And uh that
dog we met during the break it
calibrates
calibrates very
calibrates very high
calibrates very high you
calibrates very high you know.
calibrates very high you know. And
calibrates very high you know. And we
were
were saying
why
why is
why is it
why is it wagging
why is it wagging its
why is it wagging its tail?
why is it wagging its tail? because
why is it wagging its tail? because the
reality
reality of
why is it wagging its tail? because the
reality of its
reality of its subjectivity
why is it wagging its tail? because the
reality of its subjectivity uh
reality of its subjectivity uh as
intrinsic
intrinsic to
intrinsic to its
intrinsic to its own
intrinsic to its own experience
intrinsic to its own experience is
intrinsic to its own experience is being
acknowledged
acknowledged and
intrinsic to its own experience is being
acknowledged and recognized.
acknowledged and recognized. You
intrinsic to its own experience is being
acknowledged and recognized. You know
that
that the
that the dog
that the dog acknowledges
that the dog acknowledges your
lovingness
lovingness for
that the dog acknowledges your
lovingness for them
lovingness for them and
that the dog acknowledges your
lovingness for them and you
lovingness for them and you acknowledge
their
their lovingness
their lovingness and
their lovingness and thereby
their lovingness and thereby you
reempower
reempower you
their lovingness and thereby you
reempower you empower
reempower you empower each
their lovingness and thereby you
reempower you empower each other.
reempower you empower each other. So
their lovingness and thereby you
reempower you empower each other. So we
empower
empower the
empower the dog
empower the dog and
empower the dog and the
empower the dog and the dog
empower the dog and the dog empowers
empower the dog and the dog empowers us.
You
You see,
empower the dog and the dog empowers us.
You see, and
You see, and then
empower the dog and the dog empowers us.
You see, and then unconsciously
You see, and then unconsciously we
experience
experience the
experience the essence
experience the essence of
experience the essence of the
experience the essence of the divinity
of
of that
experience the essence of the divinity
of that lovingness
which
which allows
which allows the
which allows the dog
which allows the dog to
which allows the dog to experience
which allows the dog to experience the
joy
joy of
which allows the dog to experience the
joy of you're
joy of you're loving
which allows the dog to experience the
joy of you're loving him.
joy of you're loving him. you
which allows the dog to experience the
joy of you're loving him. you know
what's
what's up.
>> Um
>> Um I
what's up.
>> Um I I
>> Um I I chose
what's up.
>> Um I I chose to
>> Um I I chose to ask
what's up.
>> Um I I chose to ask you
>> Um I I chose to ask you if
what's up.
>> Um I I chose to ask you if you
>> Um I I chose to ask you if you could
maybe
maybe even
maybe even give
maybe even give me
maybe even give me a
maybe even give me a oneliner
maybe even give me a oneliner or
something
something very
maybe even give me a oneliner or
something very laser
something very laser when
maybe even give me a oneliner or
something very laser when the
something very laser when the emotional
body
body engages
body engages very
body engages very you
body engages very you know
body engages very you know immediately
and
and tenaciously
body engages very you know immediately
and tenaciously with
and tenaciously with something
body engages very you know immediately
and tenaciously with something that's
taking
taking me
taking me out
taking me out from
taking me out from my
taking me out from my alignment
taking me out from my alignment with
source
source and
taking me out from my alignment with
source and I
source and I and
taking me out from my alignment with
source and I and I
source and I and I know
taking me out from my alignment with
source and I and I know you
source and I and I know you have
taking me out from my alignment with
source and I and I know you have that
whole
whole process
whole process and
whole process and it
whole process and it is
whole process and it is effective
whole process and it is effective but
sometimes
sometimes it
whole process and it is effective but
sometimes it happens
sometimes it happens so
whole process and it is effective but
sometimes it happens so fast.
sometimes it happens so fast. I
whole process and it is effective but
sometimes it happens so fast. I was
wondering
wondering if
wondering if there
wondering if there was
wondering if there was something
wondering if there was something that
would
would be
wondering if there was something that
would be really
would be really effective
wondering if there was something that
would be really effective quickly.
would be really effective quickly. Y
wondering if there was something that
would be really effective quickly. Y all
be
be an
be an angel.
be an angel. Be
be an angel. Be an
be an angel. Be an angel
be an angel. Be an angel and
be an angel. Be an angel and you
be an angel. Be an angel and you won't
have
have a
be an angel. Be an angel and you won't
have a deal.
Live
Live in
Live in the
Live in the celestial
Live in the celestial realms
Live in the celestial realms and
Live in the celestial realms and uh
where
where you're
Live in the celestial realms and uh
where you're not
where you're not subject
Live in the celestial realms and uh
where you're not subject to
where you're not subject to the
assaults.
It's
It's the
assaults.
It's the discipline
It's the discipline you
assaults.
It's the discipline you see
It's the discipline you see and
assaults.
It's the discipline you see and uh
that's
that's why
that's why being
that's why being a
that's why being a human
that's why being a human being
that's why being a human being is
that's why being a human being is so
difficult
difficult because
that's why being a human being is so
difficult because you're
difficult because you're transcending
the
the residual
the residual of
the residual of the
the residual of the animal.
the residual of the animal. So
the residual of the animal. So in
the residual of the animal. So in the
the residual of the animal. So in the in
your
your left
the residual of the animal. So in the in
your left brain
your left brain the
the residual of the animal. So in the in
your left brain the sensory
your left brain the sensory stimulus
comes
comes in
comes in goes
comes in goes through
comes in goes through the
comes in goes through the relay
comes in goes through the relay station
uh
ends
ends up
ends up in
ends up in the
ends up in the amygdala
ends up in the amygdala as
ends up in the amygdala as an
ends up in the amygdala as an emotional
reaction.
Then
Then from
Then from the
Then from the frontal
Then from the frontal cortex
Then from the frontal cortex arrives
Then from the frontal cortex arrives the
spiritual
spiritual information
Then from the frontal cortex arrives the
spiritual information you've
spiritual information you've learned
Then from the frontal cortex arrives the
spiritual information you've learned but
the
the emotional
the emotional reaction
the emotional reaction has
the emotional reaction has happened
already.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So by
All right. So by repetitive
All right. So by repetitive spiritual
discipline
discipline and
All right. So by repetitive spiritual
discipline and training
discipline and training then
All right. So by repetitive spiritual
discipline and training then we
discipline and training then we begin
All right. So by repetitive spiritual
discipline and training then we begin to
shift
shift the
shift the way
shift the way in
shift the way in which
shift the way in which information
shift the way in which information is
processed
processed within
shift the way in which information is
processed within the
processed within the brain.
shift the way in which information is
processed within the brain. We
processed within the brain. We begin
shift the way in which information is
processed within the brain. We begin to
experience
experience it
experience it differently.
experience it differently. That's
experience it differently. That's called
uh
uh the
experience it differently. That's called
uh the miracle.
That's
That's whole
That's whole purpose
That's whole purpose of
That's whole purpose of the
That's whole purpose of the course
That's whole purpose of the course of
miracles
miracles is
That's whole purpose of the course of
miracles is by
miracles is by constant
That's whole purpose of the course of
miracles is by constant forgivingness
miracles is by constant forgivingness to
undo
undo the
undo the limitation
undo the limitation of
undo the limitation of perception
undo the limitation of perception and
thereby
thereby allow
undo the limitation of perception and
thereby allow the
etheric
etheric cortex
etheric cortex to
etheric cortex to predominate
etheric cortex to predominate the
etheric cortex to predominate the right
brain
brain predominate
etheric cortex to predominate the right
brain predominate over
brain predominate over left
etheric cortex to predominate the right
brain predominate over left and
brain predominate over left and we
etheric cortex to predominate the right
brain predominate over left and we now
experience
things
things in
experience
things in a
things in a more
experience
things in a more in
things in a more in a
experience
things in a more in a broader
contextualization.
We
We see,
we
we intuit
we intuit it
we intuit it that
we intuit it that everybody
we intuit it that everybody we're
talking
talking to
we intuit it that everybody we're
talking to and
talking to and every
we intuit it that everybody we're
talking to and every place
talking to and every place we
we intuit it that everybody we're
talking to and every place we are
talking to and every place we are is
we intuit it that everybody we're
talking to and every place we are is in
a
a process
a process of
a process of evolution.
So
So ordinary
a process of evolution.
So ordinary people
So ordinary people don't
a process of evolution.
So ordinary people don't do
So ordinary people don't do that.
a process of evolution.
So ordinary people don't do that. They
don't
don't contextualize
don't contextualize where
don't contextualize where you
don't contextualize where you are
don't contextualize where you are in
don't contextualize where you are in the
evolution
evolution of
don't contextualize where you are in the
evolution of consciousness
evolution of consciousness both
individual
individual and
individual and collective.
individual and collective. They
individual and collective. They only
individual and collective. They only see
you
you as
individual and collective. They only see
you as Mary
you as Mary J
individual and collective. They only see
you as Mary J so
you as Mary J so and
individual and collective. They only see
you as Mary J so and so
you as Mary J so and so who
individual and collective. They only see
you as Mary J so and so who owes
you as Mary J so and so who owes me
eight
eight bucks
eight bucks and
eight bucks and I
eight bucks and I hate
eight bucks and I hate her.
eight bucks and I hate her. So
eight bucks and I hate her. So you
eight bucks and I hate her. So you know
short
short story
eight bucks and I hate her. So you know
short story they
short story they don't
eight bucks and I hate her. So you know
short story they don't see
so
so spiritual
so spiritual awareness
so spiritual awareness then
so spiritual awareness then it
so spiritual awareness then it broadens
the
the whole
so spiritual awareness then it broadens
the whole context
the whole context in
so spiritual awareness then it broadens
the whole context in which
the whole context in which you
so spiritual awareness then it broadens
the whole context in which you see
people
people as
people as representative
people as representative of
people as representative of a
people as representative of a larger
field.
field. It's
people as representative of a larger
field. It's not
field. It's not just
people as representative of a larger
field. It's not just Mary
field. It's not just Mary Doe
people as representative of a larger
field. It's not just Mary Doe or
field. It's not just Mary Doe or Jack
Peters.
Peters. It's
Peters. It's that
Peters. It's that person
Peters. It's that person now
Peters. It's that person now begins
Peters. It's that person now begins to
represent
represent a
Peters. It's that person now begins to
represent a whole
represent a whole segment
Peters. It's that person now begins to
represent a whole segment of
represent a whole segment of the
learningness
learningness of
learningness of human
learningness of human evolution.
learningness of human evolution. And
learningness of human evolution. And all
I
I can
learningness of human evolution. And all
I can say
I can say is
learningness of human evolution. And all
I can say is it
I can say is it tends
learningness of human evolution. And all
I can say is it tends to
I can say is it tends to sort
learningness of human evolution. And all
I can say is it tends to sort of
generalize
generalize from
generalize from the
generalize from the particular.
generalize from the particular. And
generalize from the particular. And you
see
see that
generalize from the particular. And you
see that those
see that those are
generalize from the particular. And you
see that those are qualities
see that those are qualities not
generalize from the particular. And you
see that those are qualities not just
see that those are qualities not just of
that
that individual
that individual person
that individual person but
that individual person but of
that individual person but of you
that individual person but of you know
the
the downside
that individual person but of you know
the downside or
the downside or the
that individual person but of you know
the downside or the upside
the downside or the upside of
that individual person but of you know
the downside or the upside of humanness.
>> It's
>> It's hard
>> It's hard to
>> It's hard to forgive
>> It's hard to forgive it
>> It's hard to forgive it when
>> It's hard to forgive it when you
>> It's hard to forgive it when you see
>> It's hard to forgive it when you see the
degree
degree to
>> It's hard to forgive it when you see the
degree to which
degree to which it
>> It's hard to forgive it when you see the
degree to which it is
degree to which it is worked
>> It's hard to forgive it when you see the
degree to which it is worked sometimes.
You
You know
You know the
You know the deliberate
misrepresentation
misrepresentation of
You know the deliberate
misrepresentation of truth.
misrepresentation of truth. you
You know the deliberate
misrepresentation of truth. you know,
deliver
deliver it
deliver it for
deliver it for obvious
deliver it for obvious gain.
deliver it for obvious gain. Usually
deliver it for obvious gain. Usually you
have
have egotism
and
and so
and so it's
and so it's a
and so it's a little
and so it's a little hard.
and so it's a little hard. But
and so it's a little hard. But then
and so it's a little hard. But then you
see,
see, yes,
and so it's a little hard. But then you
see, yes, but
see, yes, but that
and so it's a little hard. But then you
see, yes, but that that
see, yes, but that that is
and so it's a little hard. But then you
see, yes, but that that is that's
see, yes, but that that is that's one
whole
whole purpose
whole purpose of
whole purpose of being
whole purpose of being a
whole purpose of being a human
whole purpose of being a human is
whole purpose of being a human is to
transcend
transcend that
whole purpose of being a human is to
transcend that temptation
to
to be
to be presented
to be presented with
to be presented with that
to be presented with that temptation
to be presented with that temptation and
not
not fall
to be presented with that temptation and
not fall for
not fall for it.
to be presented with that temptation and
not fall for it. And
not fall for it. And could
to be presented with that temptation and
not fall for it. And could take
not fall for it. And could take many
to be presented with that temptation and
not fall for it. And could take many a
lifetime
lifetime before
lifetime before you
lifetime before you learn
lifetime before you learn how
lifetime before you learn how to
lifetime before you learn how to handle
it
it without
lifetime before you learn how to handle
it without falling
it without falling for
lifetime before you learn how to handle
it without falling for it.
it without falling for it. You
lifetime before you learn how to handle
it without falling for it. You know,
>> there's
>> there's nothing
>> there's nothing that
>> there's nothing that feels
>> there's nothing that feels so
>> there's nothing that feels so good
>> there's nothing that feels so good as
being
being right,
>> there's nothing that feels so good as
being right, you
being right, you know,
>> there's nothing that feels so good as
being right, you know, and
being right, you know, and to
>> there's nothing that feels so good as
being right, you know, and to give
being right, you know, and to give up
give
give up
give up the
give up the payoff
give up the payoff of
give up the payoff of being
give up the payoff of being right
give up the payoff of being right is
give up the payoff of being right is a
tough
tough one.
give up the payoff of being right is a
tough one. Tough
tough one. Tough one.
give up the payoff of being right is a
tough one. Tough one. People
tough one. Tough one. People would
rather
rather die
rather die than
rather die than give
rather die than give up
rather die than give up being
rather die than give up being right.
rather die than give up being right. And
they
they do,
rather die than give up being right. And
they do, you
they do, you know,
rather die than give up being right. And
they do, you know, people
they do, you know, people die
rather die than give up being right. And
they do, you know, people die right
they do, you know, people die right and
left
left by
left by the
left by the millions.
Yeah.
Yeah. So
left by the millions.
Yeah. So that
Yeah. So that they
left by the millions.
Yeah. So that they can
Yeah. So that they can stay
left by the millions.
Yeah. So that they can stay being
convinced
convinced that
convinced that they're
convinced that they're right.
convinced that they're right. They're
right.
right. Yeah.
The
The other
The other thing
The other thing I
The other thing I wanted
The other thing I wanted to
The other thing I wanted to ask
The other thing I wanted to ask you
The other thing I wanted to ask you is
you
you mentioned
The other thing I wanted to ask you is
you mentioned karmic
you mentioned karmic merit
The other thing I wanted to ask you is
you mentioned karmic merit and
you mentioned karmic merit and I
The other thing I wanted to ask you is
you mentioned karmic merit and I was
you mentioned karmic merit and I was I
had
had the
had the impression
had the impression that
had the impression that it's
had the impression that it's better
had the impression that it's better not
to
to keep
had the impression that it's better not
to keep acrewing
to keep acrewing for
had the impression that it's better not
to keep acrewing for more
to keep acrewing for more merit
had the impression that it's better not
to keep acrewing for more merit even
to keep acrewing for more merit even if
your
your if
your if your
your if your desire
your if your desire is
your if your desire is release
your if your desire is release from
your if your desire is release from this
round
round of
your if your desire is release from this
round of birth
round of birth and
your if your desire is release from this
round of birth and wanted
round of birth and wanted to
your if your desire is release from this
round of birth and wanted to ask
round of birth and wanted to ask you
about
about that.
>> Well
>> Well that's
about that.
>> Well that's just
>> Well that's just a
about that.
>> Well that's just a descriptive
>> Well that's just a descriptive phase.
You
You know
You know you
You know you don't
You know you don't really
You know you don't really have
You know you don't really have a
You know you don't really have a bank
account
account with
You know you don't really have a bank
account with all
account with all your
You know you don't really have a bank
account with all your merit
account with all your merit merit
You know you don't really have a bank
account with all your merit merit units
in
in there.
On
On the
in there.
On the other
On the other hand,
in there.
On the other hand, actually
On the other hand, actually you
in there.
On the other hand, actually you have
On the other hand, actually you have a
bank
bank account
bank account with
bank account with all
bank account with all your
bank account with all your car
bank account with all your car units
bank account with all your car units in
there.
Why?
Why? Because
Why? Because they're
Why? Because they're calibratable.
So
So they're
Why? Because they're calibratable.
So they're accountable.
So they're accountable. So
accountability
accountability of
accountability of spiritual
accountability of spiritual reality
accountability of spiritual reality is
there.
there. It
accountability of spiritual reality is
there. It radiates
there. It radiates forth
accountability of spiritual reality is
there. It radiates forth as
there. It radiates forth as a
accountability of spiritual reality is
there. It radiates forth as a calibrated
level.
level. Just
level. Just the
level. Just the amount
level. Just the amount of
level. Just the amount of truth
level. Just the amount of truth that
level. Just the amount of truth that one
has
has owned
level. Just the amount of truth that one
has owned for
has owned for oneself
level. Just the amount of truth that one
has owned for oneself is
has owned for oneself is really
level. Just the amount of truth that one
has owned for oneself is really all
has owned for oneself is really all it's
about.
And
And that
about.
And that depends
And that depends on
about.
And that depends on the
And that depends on the amount
about.
And that depends on the amount of
untruth
untruth that
untruth that you've
untruth that you've just
untruth that you've just let
untruth that you've just let you
untruth that you've just let you know
you've
you've let
untruth that you've just let you know
you've let go
you've let go of.
So
So that's
So that's all
So that's all calibrated
So that's all calibrated level
So that's all calibrated level is
So that's all calibrated level is how
much
much of
So that's all calibrated level is how
much of truth
much of truth you've
So that's all calibrated level is how
much of truth you've owned
much of truth you've owned and
So that's all calibrated level is how
much of truth you've owned and um
identified
identified with
identified with and
identified with and how
identified with and how much
identified with and how much of
identified with and how much of untruth
you've
you've let
identified with and how much of untruth
you've let go.
you've let go. So
identified with and how much of untruth
you've let go. So it's
you've let go. So it's more
identified with and how much of untruth
you've let go. So it's more or
you've let go. So it's more or less
identified with and how much of untruth
you've let go. So it's more or less you
let
let go
let go of
let go of this
let go of this and
let go of this and you've
let go of this and you've owned
let go of this and you've owned out
let go of this and you've owned out to
this
this and
let go of this and you've owned out to
this and that
this and that way
let go of this and you've owned out to
this and that way you
this and that way you move
let go of this and you've owned out to
this and that way you move along.
this and that way you move along. see
karmically
karmically over
karmically over yons
karmically over yons of
karmically over yons of time.
>> It's
>> It's not
karmically over yons of time.
>> It's not an
>> It's not an impediment
karmically over yons of time.
>> It's not an impediment more
>> It's not an impediment more than
karmically over yons of time.
>> It's not an impediment more than it's
not
not an
not an impediment
not an impediment at
not an impediment at all
not an impediment at all to
not an impediment at all to have
not an impediment at all to have even
good
good karma.
not an impediment at all to have even
good karma. It's
good karma. It's still
not an impediment at all to have even
good karma. It's still you're
good karma. It's still you're moving
not an impediment at all to have even
good karma. It's still you're moving in
the
the right
the right direction.
>> Well,
>> Well, I
the right direction.
>> Well, I know
>> Well, I know what
the right direction.
>> Well, I know what you're
>> Well, I know what you're what
the right direction.
>> Well, I know what you're what you're
really
really saying
really saying in
really saying in a
really saying in a way.
really saying in a way. At
really saying in a way. At a
really saying in a way. At a certain
point,
point, there's
really saying in a way. At a certain
point, there's neither
point, there's neither good
really saying in a way. At a certain
point, there's neither good karma
point, there's neither good karma nor
bad
bad karma.
>> Just
>> Just is.
>> And
>> And from
>> And from the
>> And from the viewpoint
>> And from the viewpoint of
>> And from the viewpoint of radical
reality,
reality, there
>> And from the viewpoint of radical
reality, there is
reality, there is no
>> And from the viewpoint of radical
reality, there is no such
reality, there is no such thing.
>> And from the viewpoint of radical
reality, there is no such thing. Okay?
Because
Because good
Because good and
Because good and bad
Because good and bad are
Because good and bad are choices.
Because good and bad are choices. And
Because good and bad are choices. And uh
and
and for
Because good and bad are choices. And uh
and for a
and for a person
Because good and bad are choices. And uh
and for a person who
and for a person who chooses
Because good and bad are choices. And uh
and for a person who chooses bad
and for a person who chooses bad karma,
then
then good
then good karma
then good karma would
then good karma would be
then good karma would be bad
then good karma would be bad karma.
then good karma would be bad karma. You
understand?
You
You see
You see this?
You see this? Yeah.
You see this? Yeah. You
You see this? Yeah. You see
You see this? Yeah. You see this
You see this? Yeah. You see this in
prisons,
prisons, you
You see this? Yeah. You see this in
prisons, you see
prisons, you see this
You see this? Yeah. You see this in
prisons, you see this in
prisons, you see this in jail,
You see this? Yeah. You see this in
prisons, you see this in jail, see
prisons, you see this in jail, see it
You see this? Yeah. You see this in
prisons, you see this in jail, see it on
the
the street,
the street, being
the street, being a
the street, being a soft
the street, being a soft guy,
the street, being a soft guy, giving
them
them a
the street, being a soft guy, giving
them a break.
Yeah.
Yeah. That'll
Yeah. That'll put
Yeah. That'll put you
Yeah. That'll put you right
Yeah. That'll put you right at
Yeah. That'll put you right at the
bottom
bottom of
Yeah. That'll put you right at the
bottom of the
bottom of the pack.
Now,
Now, there's
Now, there's little
Now, there's little countries
Now, there's little countries where
Now, there's little countries where the
slightest
slightest gesture
Now, there's little countries where the
slightest gesture of
slightest gesture of sympathy,
Now, there's little countries where the
slightest gesture of sympathy, love,
compassion,
compassion, you
compassion, you got
compassion, you got bayonated.
bayonetted
bayonetted right
compassion, you got bayonated.
bayonetted right away
bayonetted right away for
compassion, you got bayonated.
bayonetted right away for that.
bayonetted right away for that. That
compassion, you got bayonated.
bayonetted right away for that. That was
considered
considered court
considered court marshal
considered court marshal offense.
>> Reflection
>> Reflection uh
considered court marshal offense.
>> Reflection uh in
>> Reflection uh in their
considered court marshal offense.
>> Reflection uh in their view
>> Reflection uh in their view of
considered court marshal offense.
>> Reflection uh in their view of that
society
society was
society was that
society was that you
society was that you should
society was that you should be
society was that you should be able
society was that you should be able to
bayonet
bayonet a
society was that you should be able to
bayonet a baby
bayonet a baby and
society was that you should be able to
bayonet a baby and not
bayonet a baby and not feel
society was that you should be able to
bayonet a baby and not feel a
bayonet a baby and not feel a quip
society was that you should be able to
bayonet a baby and not feel a quip about
it.
Leos,
Leos, right,
it.
Leos, right, Cambodia,
it
it was
it was illegal
it was illegal to
it was illegal to exhibit
it was illegal to exhibit love
it was illegal to exhibit love in
it was illegal to exhibit love in any
form
form and
it was illegal to exhibit love in any
form and would
form and would get
it was illegal to exhibit love in any
form and would get you
form and would get you executed
it was illegal to exhibit love in any
form and would get you executed as
form and would get you executed as an
enemy
enemy of
enemy of the
enemy of the state.
Your
Your staff
>> We
>> We think
>> We think we
>> We think we have
>> We think we have it
>> We think we have it tough,
>> We think we have it tough, huh?
>> Your
>> Your staff
>> We think we have it tough, huh?
>> Your staff suggested
>> Your staff suggested I
>> We think we have it tough, huh?
>> Your staff suggested I ask
>> Your staff suggested I ask you
>> We think we have it tough, huh?
>> Your staff suggested I ask you to
>> Your staff suggested I ask you to sign
my
my books
my books cuz
my books cuz we're
my books cuz we're leaving
my books cuz we're leaving for
my books cuz we're leaving for a
my books cuz we're leaving for a plane
right
right after
my books cuz we're leaving for a plane
right after this.
>> You
>> You bet.
>> You bet. You
>> You bet. You got
>> You bet. You got to
>> You bet. You got to catch
>> You bet. You got to catch a
>> You bet. You got to catch a plane.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Catch
>> Yeah. Catch a
>> Yeah. Catch a plane.
>> Yeah. Catch a plane. F
>> Yeah. Catch a plane. F planes
>> Yeah. Catch a plane. F planes is
>> Yeah. Catch a plane. F planes is fine
with
with me.
Uh
Uh I
Uh I won't
Uh I won't have
Uh I won't have time
Uh I won't have time to
Uh I won't have time to put
Uh I won't have time to put the
Uh I won't have time to put the date
Uh I won't have time to put the date in
though.
though. I
Uh I won't have time to put the date in
though. I don't
though. I don't even
Uh I won't have time to put the date in
though. I don't even know
though. I don't even know what
Uh I won't have time to put the date in
though. I don't even know what the
though. I don't even know what the date
is
is today.
>> It's
>> It's my
is today.
>> It's my birthday.
>> It's my birthday. It's
is today.
>> It's my birthday. It's the
>> It's my birthday. It's the 13th
is today.
>> It's my birthday. It's the 13th of
December.
This
This is
December.
This is December.
>> Yeah.
>> What
>> What year?
>> Uh,
>> Uh, today
>> Uh, today it's
>> What
>> What year
>> Uh, today it's
>> What year is
>> What year is it?
>> It's
>> It's 2003.
>> Huh?
>> 2003.
>> 2003. I
>> 2003. I knew
>> 2003.
>> 2003. I knew it
>> 2003. I knew it was
>> 2003.
>> 2003. I knew it was something.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Thank you so
>> Thank you so much.
>> Thank you so much. Appreciate
>> Thank you so much. Appreciate it.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Thank you so much. Appreciate it.
>> Thank you so
>> Thank you so much
>> Thank you so much. Appreciate it.
>> Thank you so much for
>> Thank you so much for saying
>> Thank you so much. Appreciate it.
>> Thank you so much for saying that.
>> Get
>> Get your
>> Get your I
>> Get your I think
>> Get your I think you
>> Get your I think you forgot
>> Get your I think you forgot your
>> Get your I think you forgot your pen.
On
On the
>> Get your I think you forgot your pen.
On the other
On the other hand,
>> Get your I think you forgot your pen.
On the other hand, says
On the other hand, says Rison.
>> Get your I think you forgot your pen.
On the other hand, says Rison. I'll
On the other hand, says Rison. I'll keep
it.
That
That was
it.
That was a
That was a donation,
it.
That was a donation, wasn't
That was a donation, wasn't it?
>> Yeah.
>> Uh
>> Uh I
>> Yeah.
>> Uh I wondered
>> Uh I wondered if
>> Yeah.
>> Uh I wondered if you
>> Uh I wondered if you see
>> Yeah.
>> Uh I wondered if you see any
>> Uh I wondered if you see any connection
between
between uh
between uh enlightenment
between uh enlightenment and
between uh enlightenment and selfish
selfless
selfless service.
>> Well,
>> Well, selfless
>> Well, selfless service,
>> Well, selfless service, you
>> Well, selfless service, you know,
>> Well, selfless service, you know, is
>> Well, selfless service, you know, is one
of
of the
>> Well, selfless service, you know, is one
of the traditional
of the traditional yogas,
>> Well, selfless service, you know, is one
of the traditional yogas, the
of the traditional yogas, the great
yogas.
to
to do
yogas.
to do everything
to do everything for
yogas.
to do everything for the
to do everything for the sake
yogas.
to do everything for the sake of
to do everything for the sake of and
yogas.
to do everything for the sake of and in
the
the name
the name of
the name of God
the name of God and
the name of God and not
the name of God and not look
the name of God and not look for
the name of God and not look for any
reward
reward or
the name of God and not look for any
reward or payoff
reward or payoff to
the name of God and not look for any
reward or payoff to do
reward or payoff to do it
the name of God and not look for any
reward or payoff to do it for
reward or payoff to do it for its
the name of God and not look for any
reward or payoff to do it for its own
sake.
In
In the
sake.
In the beginning,
In the beginning, it's
sake.
In the beginning, it's conceptualized
In the beginning, it's conceptualized as
doing
doing it
doing it for
doing it for God,
but
but the
doing it for God,
but the conceptualization
disappears
disappears after
disappears after a
disappears after a while.
One
One does
disappears after a while.
One does it
One does it because
disappears after a while.
One does it because that's
One does it because that's what
disappears after a while.
One does it because that's what you
One does it because that's what you have
become.
because
because that's
become.
because that's what
because that's what you
become.
because that's what you are,
because that's what you are, not
become.
because that's what you are, not because
it's
it's observed
it's observed some
it's observed some end.
Otherwise,
Otherwise, there's
it's observed some end.
Otherwise, there's a
Otherwise, there's a me
it's observed some end.
Otherwise, there's a me serving
Otherwise, there's a me serving a
it's observed some end.
Otherwise, there's a me serving a god.
You
You see
You see a
You see a dualistic
You see a dualistic conception.
In
In the
You see a dualistic conception.
In the end,
In the end, the
You see a dualistic conception.
In the end, the doing
In the end, the doing this
You see a dualistic conception.
In the end, the doing this be
In the end, the doing this be does
You see a dualistic conception.
In the end, the doing this be does it
unfolds
unfolds of
unfolds of its
unfolds of its own
unfolds of its own with
unfolds of its own with no
unfolds of its own with no doer
unfolds of its own with no doer or
unfolds of its own with no doer or act
of
of doing.
unfolds of its own with no doer or act
of doing. The
of doing. The doer
unfolds of its own with no doer or act
of doing. The doer and
of doing. The doer and the
unfolds of its own with no doer or act
of doing. The doer and the done
of doing. The doer and the done are
unfolds of its own with no doer or act
of doing. The doer and the done are one
and
and the
and the same.
and the same. And
and the same. And the
and the same. And the activity
unfolds
as
as an
as an expression
as an expression of
as an expression of the
as an expression of the essence
as an expression of the essence of
as an expression of the essence of that
which
which it
as an expression of the essence of that
which it is.
which it is. And
as an expression of the essence of that
which it is. And therefore
which it is. And therefore it
as an expression of the essence of that
which it is. And therefore it becomes
effortless
to
to go
effortless
to go through
to go through the
effortless
to go through the barrier
to go through the barrier to
effortless
to go through the barrier to go
to go through the barrier to go through
the
the 4-minute
the 4-minute mile
the 4-minute mile to
the 4-minute mile to go
the 4-minute mile to go through
the 4-minute mile to go through I
the 4-minute mile to go through I cannot
lift
lift another
the 4-minute mile to go through I cannot
lift another box.
It's
It's when
It's when you
It's when you hit
It's when you hit I
It's when you hit I cannot
It's when you hit I cannot lift
It's when you hit I cannot lift another
box
box that
It's when you hit I cannot lift another
box that you
box that you decide
that
that if
that if you
that if you will
that if you will lift
that if you will lift one
that if you will lift one more
that if you will lift one more box
that if you will lift one more box and
you
you discover
that if you will lift one more box and
you discover all
you discover all of
that if you will lift one more box and
you discover all of a
you discover all of a sudden
that if you will lift one more box and
you discover all of a sudden that
you discover all of a sudden that you
can
can lift
can lift any
can lift any box.
can lift any box. You
can lift any box. You can
can lift any box. You can lift
can lift any box. You can lift boxes
can lift any box. You can lift boxes for
days,
days, months,
eons
eons maybe
an
an effortlessness
and
and by
and by which
and by which things
and by which things the
and by which things the doingness
and by which things the doingness comes
of
of its
and by which things the doingness comes
of its own.
of its own. There's
and by which things the doingness comes
of its own. There's no
of its own. There's no longer
and by which things the doingness comes
of its own. There's no longer a
of its own. There's no longer a you
doing
doing a
doing a that
one
one is
doing a that
one is tireless
one is tireless and
doing a that
one is tireless and unless
one is tireless and unless you
doing a that
one is tireless and unless you have
friends
friends or
friends or family
friends or family you
friends or family you would
friends or family you would probably
extinguish
extinguish yourself
friends or family you would probably
extinguish yourself and
extinguish yourself and the
friends or family you would probably
extinguish yourself and the activity
keep
keep on
keep on uh
keep on uh lifting
keep on uh lifting rocks
keep on uh lifting rocks until
keep on uh lifting rocks until the
keep on uh lifting rocks until the body
falls
falls over.
Usually
Usually somebody
Usually somebody will
Usually somebody will come
Usually somebody will come around
Usually somebody will come around and
force
force you
Usually somebody will come around and
force you to
force you to stop
but
but people
but people who
but people who go
but people who go in
but people who go in for
but people who go in for uh
but people who go in for uh certain
sports
sports have
but people who go in for uh certain
sports have that
sports have that experience.
but people who go in for uh certain
sports have that experience. So
sports have that experience. So you
but people who go in for uh certain
sports have that experience. So you run
let's
let's say
let's say for
let's say for uh
let's say for uh God
let's say for uh God and
let's say for uh God and then
let's say for uh God and then a
let's say for uh God and then a certain
point
point you
let's say for uh God and then a certain
point you transcend
point you transcend that
let's say for uh God and then a certain
point you transcend that and
point you transcend that and the
runningness
runningness is
runningness is happening
runningness is happening of
runningness is happening of its
runningness is happening of its own.
Effortless
Effortless runningness
runningness is happening of its own.
Effortless runningness is
Effortless runningness is happening
runningness is happening of its own.
Effortless runningness is happening of
his
his own.
his own. And
his own. And you
his own. And you know
his own. And you know joggers
his own. And you know joggers and
his own. And you know joggers and other
people
people who
his own. And you know joggers and other
people who do
people who do sports
his own. And you know joggers and other
people who do sports will
people who do sports will tell
his own. And you know joggers and other
people who do sports will tell you
suddenly
suddenly there
suddenly there or
suddenly there or it
suddenly there or it can
suddenly there or it can happen
suddenly there or it can happen with
dancing.
dancing. The
suddenly there or it can happen with
dancing. The dancing
dancing. The dancing is
suddenly there or it can happen with
dancing. The dancing is happening
dancing. The dancing is happening of
suddenly there or it can happen with
dancing. The dancing is happening of its
own.
own. There's
own. There's no
own. There's no you
own. There's no you doing
own. There's no you doing any
own. There's no you doing any dancing
and
and the
own. There's no you doing any dancing
and the dancing
and the dancing can
own. There's no you doing any dancing
and the dancing can go
and the dancing can go on
own. There's no you doing any dancing
and the dancing can go on hour
and the dancing can go on hour after
hour
hour because
hour because one
hour because one reaches
hour because one reaches a
hour because one reaches a point
hour because one reaches a point of
tirelessness.
So
So karma
So karma yoga
So karma yoga then
So karma yoga then eventually
So karma yoga then eventually re
So karma yoga then eventually re reaches
that
that realization.
So karma yoga then eventually re reaches
that realization. When
that realization. When you
So karma yoga then eventually re reaches
that realization. When you let
that realization. When you let go
So karma yoga then eventually re reaches
that realization. When you let go all
resistance
when
when you
resistance
when you let
when you let go
resistance
when you let go all
when you let go all resistance
uh
uh it
uh it does
uh it does it
uh it does it of
uh it does it of its
uh it does it of its own.
uh it does it of its own. Everything
uh it does it of its own. Everything is
doing
doing it
uh it does it of its own. Everything is
doing it of
doing it of its
uh it does it of its own. Everything is
doing it of its own
doing it of its own doing
uh it does it of its own. Everything is
doing it of its own doing itself
doing it of its own doing itself of
uh it does it of its own. Everything is
doing it of its own doing itself of its
own.
own. That's
own. That's the
own. That's the the
own. That's the the end
own. That's the the end of
own. That's the the end of the
own. That's the the end of the eventual
realization
realization of
own. That's the the end of the eventual
realization of karma
because
because everything
because everything is
because everything is happening
because everything is happening of
because everything is happening of its
own
own and
because everything is happening of its
own and there
own and there is
because everything is happening of its
own and there is no
own and there is no me
because everything is happening of its
own and there is no me causing
own and there is no me causing that
because everything is happening of its
own and there is no me causing that to
happen
happen at
happen at all.
happen at all. That
happen at all. That was
happen at all. That was somehow
happen at all. That was somehow bizarre
idea.
idea. I
happen at all. That was somehow bizarre
idea. I believed
idea. I believed in
happen at all. That was somehow bizarre
idea. I believed in it
idea. I believed in it one
happen at all. That was somehow bizarre
idea. I believed in it one time.
You
You witness
You witness and
experience
experience the
You witness and
experience the reality
experience the reality that
You witness and
experience the reality that everything
is
is happening
is happening of
is happening of its
is happening of its own
is happening of its own spontaneously.
There's
There's no
is happening of its own spontaneously.
There's no you
There's no you causing
is happening of its own spontaneously.
There's no you causing it
There's no you causing it that.
So
So karma
So karma yoga
So karma yoga takes
So karma yoga takes you
So karma yoga takes you to
So karma yoga takes you to that
realization.
realization. Uh
So karma yoga takes you to that
realization. Uh when
realization. Uh when you
So karma yoga takes you to that
realization. Uh when you uh
realization. Uh when you uh when
So karma yoga takes you to that
realization. Uh when you uh when when
you
you think
you think about
you think about the
you think about the words
you think about the words of
you think about the words of Jesus
you think about the words of Jesus uh
that
that say
you think about the words of Jesus uh
that say uh
that say uh whatever
you think about the words of Jesus uh
that say uh whatever you
that say uh whatever you do
you think about the words of Jesus uh
that say uh whatever you do to
that say uh whatever you do to the
you think about the words of Jesus uh
that say uh whatever you do to the least
of
of these
of these you
of these you do
of these you do to
of these you do to me.
of these you do to me. It
of these you do to me. It seems
of these you do to me. It seems like
of these you do to me. It seems like he
was
was identifying
of these you do to me. It seems like he
was identifying himself
was identifying himself with
of these you do to me. It seems like he
was identifying himself with everyone.
And
And if
And if you're
And if you're just
And if you're just beginning
And if you're just beginning this
And if you're just beginning this work
of
of enlightenment,
uh
uh is
uh is it
uh is it wrong
uh is it wrong to
uh is it wrong to uh
and
and you're
uh is it wrong to uh
and you're having
and you're having a
uh is it wrong to uh
and you're having a hard
and you're having a hard time
uh is it wrong to uh
and you're having a hard time with
and you're having a hard time with it.
Uh
Uh is
Uh is it
Uh is it wrong
Uh is it wrong then
Uh is it wrong then to
Uh is it wrong then to uh
Uh is it wrong then to uh seek
this
this enlightenment
Uh is it wrong then to uh seek
this enlightenment through
this enlightenment through the
Uh is it wrong then to uh seek
this enlightenment through the service
to
to the
to the to
to the to those
to the to those who
to the to those who are
to the to those who are suffering?
to the to those who are suffering? It
seems
seems like
to the to those who are suffering? It
seems like in
seems like in in
to the to those who are suffering? It
seems like in in the
seems like in in the world
to the to those who are suffering? It
seems like in in the world that
seems like in in the world that we
to the to those who are suffering? It
seems like in in the world that we live
in
in today
in today uh
in today uh where
in today uh where we
in today uh where we have
in today uh where we have I
in today uh where we have I don't
in today uh where we have I don't know
what
what the
in today uh where we have I don't know
what the real
what the real number
in today uh where we have I don't know
what the real number is
what the real number is but
in today uh where we have I don't know
what the real number is but say
what the real number is but say three
out
out of
out of four
out of four people
out of four people live
out of four people live in
out of four people live in poverty
uh
uh even
out of four people live in poverty
uh even if
uh even if everyone
out of four people live in poverty
uh even if everyone in
uh even if everyone in the
out of four people live in poverty
uh even if everyone in the world
uh even if everyone in the world were
enlightened
enlightened I
enlightened I assume
enlightened I assume there
enlightened I assume there would
enlightened I assume there would still
be
be some
enlightened I assume there would still
be some people
be some people with
enlightened I assume there would still
be some people with Down
be some people with Down syndrome
enlightened I assume there would still
be some people with Down syndrome with
uh
uh Alzheimer's
um
um the
uh Alzheimer's
um the those
um the those who
uh Alzheimer's
um the those who are
um the those who are enlightened
uh Alzheimer's
um the those who are enlightened would
there
there be
there be some
there be some compulsion
there be some compulsion on
there be some compulsion on their
there be some compulsion on their part
to
to come
there be some compulsion on their part
to come to
to come to the
there be some compulsion on their part
to come to the to
to come to the to the
there be some compulsion on their part
to come to the to the knee
to come to the to the knee to
there be some compulsion on their part
to come to the to the knee to attend
to come to the to the knee to attend to
the
the needs
the needs of
the needs of those
the needs of those who
the needs of those who are
the needs of those who are no
the needs of those who are no cuz
the needs of those who are no cuz those
are
are perceived
the needs of those who are no cuz those
are perceived impairments
are perceived impairments perceived
needs
needs all
needs all of
needs all of which
needs all of which exist
needs all of which exist only
needs all of which exist only in
needs all of which exist only in the
mind
mind of
needs all of which exist only in the
mind of the
mind of the observer
said
said don't
said don't confuse
said don't confuse rest
cognitance
cognitance with
said don't confuse rest
cognitance with rest
cognitance with rest externa
said don't confuse rest
cognitance with rest externa don't
confuse
confuse the
confuse the way
confuse the way things
confuse the way things look
confuse the way things look or
confuse the way things look or appear
confuse the way things look or appear to
you
you or
confuse the way things look or appear to
you or you
you or you think
confuse the way things look or appear to
you or you think about
you or you think about them
confuse the way things look or appear to
you or you think about them with
you or you think about them with the
confuse the way things look or appear to
you or you think about them with the way
they
they are
they are because
they are because there's
they are because there's no
they are because there's no connection
between
between the
they are because there's no connection
between the two
between the two usually
they are because there's no connection
between the two usually Alzheimer's
between the two usually Alzheimer's is
suffering
suffering if
suffering if I
suffering if I don't
suffering if I don't remember
suffering if I don't remember who
suffering if I don't remember who the
hell
hell I
suffering if I don't remember who the
hell I am
hell I am I'm
suffering if I don't remember who the
hell I am I'm not
hell I am I'm not going
suffering if I don't remember who the
hell I am I'm not going to
hell I am I'm not going to suffer.
Suffering
Suffering is
Suffering is in
Suffering is in here
Suffering is in here witnessing
Suffering is in here witnessing eyes.
They're
They're not
Suffering is in here witnessing eyes.
They're not mine.
They're not mine. I've
Suffering is in here witnessing eyes.
They're not mine. I've been
They're not mine. I've been close
Suffering is in here witnessing eyes.
They're not mine. I've been close to
many
many people
many people with
many people with Alzheimer's.
many people with Alzheimer's. The
family's
family's all
many people with Alzheimer's. The
family's all upset.
family's all upset. Go
many people with Alzheimer's. The
family's all upset. Go and
family's all upset. Go and see
many people with Alzheimer's. The
family's all upset. Go and see mother.
She
She can't
She can't remember
She can't remember anything
She can't remember anything anymore.
She can't remember anything anymore. I
say,
say, "Mom,
She can't remember anything anymore. I
say, "Mom, I
say, "Mom, I went
She can't remember anything anymore. I
say, "Mom, I went to
say, "Mom, I went to every
She can't remember anything anymore. I
say, "Mom, I went to every nursing
say, "Mom, I went to every nursing house
in
in the
in the county
in the county for
in the county for 10
in the county for 10 years.
in the county for 10 years. Nobody
in the county for 10 years. Nobody else
will
will go."
in the county for 10 years. Nobody else
will go." So
will go." So anyway,
in the county for 10 years. Nobody else
will go." So anyway, I'm
will go." So anyway, I'm the
psychiatrist
psychiatrist there.
psychiatrist there. I
psychiatrist there. I said, "How
psychiatrist there. I said, "How you
doing,
doing, mom?"
psychiatrist there. I said, "How you
doing, mom?" "Oh,
doing, mom?" "Oh, fine."
psychiatrist there. I said, "How you
doing, mom?" "Oh, fine." I
doing, mom?" "Oh, fine." I said,
psychiatrist there. I said, "How you
doing, mom?" "Oh, fine." I said, "How
are
are they
are they treating
are they treating you
are they treating you here?"
are they treating you here?" "Oh,
are they treating you here?" "Oh, I
think
think very
are they treating you here?" "Oh, I
think very nice.
think very nice. How's
are they treating you here?" "Oh, I
think very nice. How's the
think very nice. How's the food
are they treating you here?" "Oh, I
think very nice. How's the food here?
Fine.
What
What is
Fine.
What is your
What is your complaints?
Fine.
What is your complaints? Oh,
What is your complaints? Oh, I
Fine.
What is your complaints? Oh, I don't
have
have any
have any complaints.
have any complaints. How
have any complaints. How old
have any complaints. How old are
have any complaints. How old are you
now?
now? Oh,
have any complaints. How old are you
now? Oh, I
now? Oh, I don't
have any complaints. How old are you
now? Oh, I don't pay
now? Oh, I don't pay attention
have any complaints. How old are you
now? Oh, I don't pay attention to
now? Oh, I don't pay attention to those
things
things anymore.
things anymore. They're
things anymore. They're not
things anymore. They're not important.
You
You know
things anymore. They're not important.
You know where
You know where you
things anymore. They're not important.
You know where you are
You know where you are now?
things anymore. They're not important.
You know where you are now? Oh,
You know where you are now? Oh, you're
just
just pulling
just pulling my
just pulling my leg.
just pulling my leg. You
just pulling my leg. You know
just pulling my leg. You know where
just pulling my leg. You know where I
am.
Is
Is she
Is she suffering?
Is she suffering? No.
>> The
>> The family
Is she suffering? No.
>> The family I
>> The family I have
Is she suffering? No.
>> The family I have to
>> The family I have to tell
Is she suffering? No.
>> The family I have to tell them
>> The family I have to tell them she's
Is she suffering? No.
>> The family I have to tell them she's not
suffering.
suffering. Yes,
suffering. Yes, but
suffering. Yes, but she
suffering. Yes, but she doesn't
suffering. Yes, but she doesn't remember
anything.
She
She doesn't
She doesn't remember
She doesn't remember you
She doesn't remember you folks.
She doesn't remember you folks. That's
why
why she's
She doesn't remember you folks. That's
why she's so
why she's so happy.
The
The only
The only way
The only way I
The only way I could
The only way I could get
The only way I could get away
The only way I could get away from
The only way I could get away from those
people
people was
The only way I could get away from those
people was to
people was to forget
The only way I could get away from those
people was to forget about
people was to forget about him
The only way I could get away from those
people was to forget about him and
disappear.
disappear. And
disappear. And I
disappear. And I I
disappear. And I I don't
disappear. And I I don't know
disappear. And I I don't know who
disappear. And I I don't know who they
are
are and
disappear. And I I don't know who they
are and they
are and they quit
disappear. And I I don't know who they
are and they quit visiting
are and they quit visiting me.
disappear. And I I don't know who they
are and they quit visiting me. Boy,
are and they quit visiting me. Boy, what
a
a relief.
No,
No, the
a relief.
No, the spirit's
No, the spirit's gone
a relief.
No, the spirit's gone over
No, the spirit's gone over already.
a relief.
No, the spirit's gone over already. See
the
the spirit.
the spirit. So,
the spirit. So, the
the spirit. So, the body's
the spirit. So, the body's still
the spirit. So, the body's still here.
The
The spirit
the spirit. So, the body's still here.
The spirit has
The spirit has lost
the spirit. So, the body's still here.
The spirit has lost interest
The spirit has lost interest in
the spirit. So, the body's still here.
The spirit has lost interest in this
whole
whole phenomena
whole phenomena here
whole phenomena here and
whole phenomena here and uh
whole phenomena here and uh is
whole phenomena here and uh is outside
of
of time
whole phenomena here and uh is outside
of time and
of time and space
whole phenomena here and uh is outside
of time and space and
of time and space and detail
whole phenomena here and uh is outside
of time and space and detail like
of time and space and detail like what
year
year it
year it is
year it is and
year it is and all
year it is and all and
year it is and all and how
year it is and all and how old
year it is and all and how old you
year it is and all and how old you are.
What
What year
year it is and all and how old you are.
What year is
What year is it?
year it is and all and how old you are.
What year is it? What
What year is it? What year?
year it is and all and how old you are.
What year is it? What year? What
What year is it? What year? What does
that
that mean?
that mean? What
that mean? What year
that mean? What year is
that mean? What year is it?
that mean? What year is it? I
that mean? What year is it? I don't
that mean? What year is it? I don't know
what
what year
that mean? What year is it? I don't know
what year it
what year it is
that mean? What year is it? I don't know
what year it is myself.
You
still
still knows
You
still knows what
still knows what year
You
still knows what year it
still knows what year it is.
You
still knows what year it is. Oh
still knows what year it is. Oh well.
We'll
We'll pray
We'll pray for
We'll pray for you.
Yeah.
Yeah. Uh
We'll pray for you.
Yeah. Uh yeah,
Yeah. Uh yeah, I
We'll pray for you.
Yeah. Uh yeah, I was
Yeah. Uh yeah, I was uh
We'll pray for you.
Yeah. Uh yeah, I was uh my
Yeah. Uh yeah, I was uh my question
We'll pray for you.
Yeah. Uh yeah, I was uh my question was
is
is it
is it would
is it would would
is it would would it
is it would would it be
is it would would it be helpful
is it would would it be helpful for
someone
someone who's
is it would would it be helpful for
someone who's initiating
someone who's initiating this
is it would would it be helpful for
someone who's initiating this journey
someone who's initiating this journey to
enlightenment
enlightenment uh
enlightenment uh to
enlightenment uh to engage
enlightenment uh to engage in
enlightenment uh to engage in those
kinds
kinds of
enlightenment uh to engage in those
kinds of altruistic
kinds of altruistic activities?
enlightenment uh to engage in those
kinds of altruistic activities? I
kinds of altruistic activities? I I
enlightenment uh to engage in those
kinds of altruistic activities? I I uh
spent
spent last
spent last summer
spent last summer um
spent last summer um up
spent last summer um up in
spent last summer um up in Nova
spent last summer um up in Nova Scotia
with
with some
spent last summer um up in Nova Scotia
with some uh
with some uh students
spent last summer um up in Nova Scotia
with some uh students there
with some uh students there who
spent last summer um up in Nova Scotia
with some uh students there who are
helping
helping with
helping with a
helping with a program,
helping with a program, the
helping with a program, the Cody
Institute.
Institute. And
helping with a program, the Cody
Institute. And uh
Institute. And uh I
helping with a program, the Cody
Institute. And uh I I
Institute. And uh I I I
helping with a program, the Cody
Institute. And uh I I I became
Institute. And uh I I I became aware
helping with a program, the Cody
Institute. And uh I I I became aware of
the
the um
the um of
the um of a
the um of a group
the um of a group that
the um of a group that help
the um of a group that help in
the um of a group that help in the
the um of a group that help in the large
communities,
communities, which
the um of a group that help in the large
communities, which is
communities, which is a
group
group homes
group homes for
group homes for the
group homes for the for
group homes for the for the
group homes for the for the for
group homes for the for the for the
mentally
mentally challenged.
>> Yeah.
>> And
>> And I
>> Yeah.
>> And I asked
>> And I asked them,
>> Yeah.
>> And I asked them, why
>> And I asked them, why do
>> Yeah.
>> And I asked them, why do you
>> And I asked them, why do you why
>> Yeah.
>> And I asked them, why do you why do
>> And I asked them, why do you why do you
come
come here?
come here? Because,
come here? Because, you
come here? Because, you know,
come here? Because, you know, to
come here? Because, you know, to spend
days
days and
come here? Because, you know, to spend
days and weeks
days and weeks around
come here? Because, you know, to spend
days and weeks around someone
days and weeks around someone that
come here? Because, you know, to spend
days and weeks around someone that can
uh
uh they
uh they they
uh they they can't
uh they they can't they
uh they they can't they can't
uh they they can't they can't talk,
uh they they can't they can't talk, they
can't,
can't, you
uh they they can't they can't talk, they
can't, you know,
can't, you know, some
uh they they can't they can't talk, they
can't, you know, some of
can't, you know, some of her
uh they they can't they can't talk, they
can't, you know, some of her they're
they're
they're in
they're in wheelchairs
they're in wheelchairs just
they're in wheelchairs just looking
they're in wheelchairs just looking up
at
at you,
they're in wheelchairs just looking up
at you, smiling.
>> And
>> And u
>> And u I
>> And u I asked
>> And u I asked some
>> And u I asked some of
>> And u I asked some of the
>> And u I asked some of the volunteers
>> And u I asked some of the volunteers why
why
why do
>> And u I asked some of the volunteers why
why do you
why do you do
>> And u I asked some of the volunteers why
why do you do that?
why do you do that? How
>> And u I asked some of the volunteers why
why do you do that? How can
why do you do that? How can you
>> And u I asked some of the volunteers why
why do you do that? How can you take
why do you do that? How can you take it
for
for a
for a long
for a long period
for a long period of
for a long period of time?
for a long period of time? And
invariably
invariably the
for a long period of time? And
invariably the response
invariably the response was
for a long period of time? And
invariably the response was it's
invariably the response was it's not
what
what they
what they do
what they do what
what they do what I
what they do what I can
what they do what I can do
what they do what I can do for
what they do what I can do for them,
it's
it's what
what they do what I can do for them,
it's what they
it's what they do
what they do what I can do for them,
it's what they do for
it's what they do for me.
Uh
Uh so
Uh so I
Uh so I was
Uh so I was just
Uh so I was just uh
Uh so I was just uh curious.
Uh so I was just uh curious. I
Uh so I was just uh curious. I I
Uh so I was just uh curious. I I I
Uh so I was just uh curious. I I I I
have
have this
Uh so I was just uh curious. I I I I
have this this
have this this idea
Uh so I was just uh curious. I I I I
have this this idea that
have this this idea that uh
Uh so I was just uh curious. I I I I
have this this idea that uh unless
have this this idea that uh unless we
get
get engaged,
get engaged, we
get engaged, we we
get engaged, we we see
get engaged, we we see ourselves
get engaged, we we see ourselves in
get engaged, we we see ourselves in and
in in
in in all
get engaged, we we see ourselves in and
in in all as
in in all as as
get engaged, we we see ourselves in and
in in all as as the
in in all as as the Buddha
get engaged, we we see ourselves in and
in in all as as the Buddha says
in in all as as the Buddha says and
and
and all
and all in
and all in us
and all in us and
and all in us and we
and all in us and we treat
and all in us and we treat others
and all in us and we treat others as
and all in us and we treat others as we
would
would as
and all in us and we treat others as we
would as we
would as we would
and all in us and we treat others as we
would as we would want
would as we would want them
and all in us and we treat others as we
would as we would want them to
would as we would want them to treat
and all in us and we treat others as we
would as we would want them to treat us
if
if we
if we were
if we were in
if we were in the
if we were in the same
if we were in the same condition
if we were in the same condition that
this
this that
if we were in the same condition that
this that this
this that this somehow
if we were in the same condition that
this that this somehow leads
this that this somehow leads us
if we were in the same condition that
this that this somehow leads us to
enlightenment.
Yeah,
Yeah, you
enlightenment.
Yeah, you say
Yeah, you say as
enlightenment.
Yeah, you say as a
Yeah, you say as a form
enlightenment.
Yeah, you say as a form of
Yeah, you say as a form of compassion,
as
as a
as a form
as a form of
as a form of love,
as a form of love, as
as a form of love, as a
as a form of love, as a form
as a form of love, as a form of
as a form of love, as a form of caring
service.
service. And
as a form of love, as a form of caring
service. And these
service. And these things
as a form of love, as a form of caring
service. And these things occur
service. And these things occur at
certain
certain points
certain points in
certain points in the
certain points in the evolution
certain points in the evolution of
consciousness.
consciousness. Let's
certain points in the evolution of
consciousness. Let's say
consciousness. Let's say in
certain points in the evolution of
consciousness. Let's say in this
lifetime,
lifetime, it
lifetime, it could
lifetime, it could be
lifetime, it could be a
lifetime, it could be a whole
lifetime, it could be a whole lifetime
devoted
devoted to
lifetime, it could be a whole lifetime
devoted to karma
devoted to karma or
lifetime, it could be a whole lifetime
devoted to karma or yoga.
devoted to karma or yoga. It
lifetime, it could be a whole lifetime
devoted to karma or yoga. It could
devoted to karma or yoga. It could be
brief
brief periods.
brief periods. You
brief periods. You see,
brief periods. You see, so
brief periods. You see, so it's
brief periods. You see, so it's um
whatever
whatever the
brief periods. You see, so it's um
whatever the soul
whatever the soul needs
brief periods. You see, so it's um
whatever the soul needs to
whatever the soul needs to evolve
brief periods. You see, so it's um
whatever the soul needs to evolve at
whatever the soul needs to evolve at a
given
given time
given time is
given time is what
given time is what I
given time is what I think
given time is what I think it
given time is what I think it seeks
given time is what I think it seeks out.
You
You see,
given time is what I think it seeks out.
You see, and
You see, and eventually
given time is what I think it seeks out.
You see, and eventually there
You see, and eventually there isn't
given time is what I think it seeks out.
You see, and eventually there isn't a
this
this seeking
this seeking out
this seeking out of
this seeking out of that
this seeking out of that to
this seeking out of that to achieve
that.
that. There's
this seeking out of that to achieve
that. There's just
that. There's just what
this seeking out of that to achieve
that. There's just what is
that. There's just what is being
this seeking out of that to achieve
that. There's just what is being what
that. There's just what is being what it
is.
The
The cat's
is.
The cat's just
The cat's just being
is.
The cat's just being a
The cat's just being a cat.
is.
The cat's just being a cat. Not
The cat's just being a cat. Not in
is.
The cat's just being a cat. Not in order
to
to accomplish
to accomplish something
to accomplish something by
to accomplish something by being
to accomplish something by being cat.
to accomplish something by being cat. It
just
just is
to accomplish something by being cat. It
just is what
just is what it
to accomplish something by being cat. It
just is what it is.
just is what it is. So
to accomplish something by being cat. It
just is what it is. So eventually
one
one is
one is con
one is con benevolent
one is con benevolent towards
one is con benevolent towards all
one is con benevolent towards all of
life
life because
one is con benevolent towards all of
life because that's
life because that's what
one is con benevolent towards all of
life because that's what one
life because that's what one has
one is con benevolent towards all of
life because that's what one has become
and
and then
and then one
and then one may
and then one may respond
and then one may respond to
and then one may respond to a
and then one may respond to a need
because
because it's
and then one may respond to a need
because it's because
because it's because it's
and then one may respond to a need
because it's because it's needed
because it's because it's needed there
in
in sort
in sort of
in sort of an
in sort of an impersonal
in sort of an impersonal way.
So
So I
in sort of an impersonal way.
So I think
So I think these
in sort of an impersonal way.
So I think these things
So I think these things come
in sort of an impersonal way.
So I think these things come as
So I think these things come as periods
in
in the
in the evolution
in the evolution of
in the evolution of a
in the evolution of a individual
in the evolution of a individual soul.
It
It may
in the evolution of a individual soul.
It may be
It may be whole
in the evolution of a individual soul.
It may be whole lifetimes
It may be whole lifetimes of
in the evolution of a individual soul.
It may be whole lifetimes of devotion
It may be whole lifetimes of devotion to
one
one pathway
one pathway and
one pathway and lifetimes
one pathway and lifetimes of
one pathway and lifetimes of devotion
one pathway and lifetimes of devotion to
another
another pathway.
And
And in
And in the
And in the end
And in the end the
And in the end the perfection
And in the end the perfection is
And in the end the perfection is the
perfection
perfection of
And in the end the perfection is the
perfection of the
perfection of the balance
And in the end the perfection is the
perfection of the balance of
perfection of the balance of them
And in the end the perfection is the
perfection of the balance of them all
and
and then
any
any subject
and then
any subject and
any subject and predicate
and then
any subject and predicate and
any subject and predicate and verb
disappear.
And
And one
disappear.
And one just
And one just is
disappear.
And one just is what
And one just is what one
disappear.
And one just is what one is
And one just is what one is because
that's
that's one's
that's one's nature.
that's one's nature. It's
that's one's nature. It's one's
that's one's nature. It's one's nature
at
at a
that's one's nature. It's one's nature
at a certain
at a certain level
that's one's nature. It's one's nature
at a certain level to
at a certain level to automatically
reach
reach out
reach out for
reach out for a
reach out for a hand
reach out for a hand that
reach out for a hand that reaches
reach out for a hand that reaches for
you.
you. It's
reach out for a hand that reaches for
you. It's just
you. It's just one's
reach out for a hand that reaches for
you. It's just one's nature.
You
You don't
You don't do
You don't do it
You don't do it because
You don't do it because there's
You don't do it because there's karmic
benefit.
benefit. You
You don't do it because there's karmic
benefit. You don't
benefit. You don't do
You don't do it because there's karmic
benefit. You don't do it
benefit. You don't do it because
You don't do it because there's karmic
benefit. You don't do it because there's
a
a you
a you choosing
a you choosing to
a you choosing to do
a you choosing to do that.
a you choosing to do that. It's
a you choosing to do that. It's because
one
one is
a you choosing to do that. It's because
one is automatically
one is automatically that
a you choosing to do that. It's because
one is automatically that which
one is automatically that which responds
out
out of
out of the
out of the nature
out of the nature of
out of the nature of that
out of the nature of that which
out of the nature of that which it
out of the nature of that which it has
become.
become. So
out of the nature of that which it has
become. So like
become. So like the
out of the nature of that which it has
become. So like the pollen
become. So like the pollen fertilizes
not
not cuz
not cuz it
not cuz it decides
not cuz it decides to
not cuz it decides to do
not cuz it decides to do that
not cuz it decides to do that as
not cuz it decides to do that as a
not cuz it decides to do that as a good
deed
deed and
not cuz it decides to do that as a good
deed and as
deed and as good
not cuz it decides to do that as a good
deed and as good karma
deed and as good karma and
not cuz it decides to do that as a good
deed and as good karma and you
deed and as good karma and you know
pollinating
pollinating things
pollinating things but
pollinating things but just
pollinating things but just because
that's
that's what
pollinating things but just because
that's what pollen
that's what pollen is
pollinating things but just because
that's what pollen is and
that's what pollen is and the
pollinating things but just because
that's what pollen is and the wind
that's what pollen is and the wind moves
it
it from
it from here
it from here to
it from here to there.
Yeah.
When
When becomes
When becomes that
When becomes that it's
all
all in
When becomes that it's
all in the
all in the wind
When becomes that it's
all in the wind as
all in the wind as well.
When becomes that it's
all in the wind as well. You
all in the wind as well. You know
>> to
>> to continue
>> to continue practically
>> to continue practically how
>> to continue practically how far
>> to continue practically how far do
>> to continue practically how far do we
>> to continue practically how far do we go
in
in serving?
>> How
>> How far
>> How far what
>> go
>> go in
>> How far what
>> go in serving
>> go in serving what
>> How far what
>> go in serving what we
>> go in serving what we believe
>> How far what
>> go in serving what we believe is
>> go in serving what we believe is serving
in
in my
>> service.
>> Yeah.
>> Serving.
And
And what
And what I
And what I mean
And what I mean I
And what I mean I see
And what I mean I see what
And what I mean I see what we
And what I mean I see what we do
And what I mean I see what we do society
do
do to
And what I mean I see what we do society
do to kids
do to kids taking
And what I mean I see what we do society
do to kids taking care
do to kids taking care and
And what I mean I see what we do society
do to kids taking care and what
do to kids taking care and what the
media
media what
media what they
media what they do
media what they do and
media what they do and how
media what they do and how far
media what they do and how far we
media what they do and how far we go
media what they do and how far we go in
stopping
stopping or
media what they do and how far we go in
stopping or trying
stopping or trying to
media what they do and how far we go in
stopping or trying to reserve
stopping or trying to reserve reverse
what
what they
what they what
what they what what
what they what what we
what they what what we do
what they what what we do or
what they what what we do or what
what they what what we do or what they
do
in
in one
in one example
>> you
>> you want
in one example
>> you want to
>> you want to change
in one example
>> you want to change what
>> you want to change what happens
in one example
>> you want to change what happens in
>> you want to change what happens in the
world
how
how far
world
how far we
>> first
>> first of
>> first of all
there's
there's the
>> first of all
there's the world
there's the world the
>> first of all
there's the world the way
there's the world the way it
>> first of all
there's the world the way it is
there's the world the way it is and
>> first of all
there's the world the way it is and then
there's
there's one's
there's one's observ
there's one's observ observations
and
and then
there's one's observ observations
and then about
and then about one's
there's one's observ observations
and then about one's observations,
one
one has
one has positionalities
one has positionalities about
one has positionalities about those
observations.
So,
So, it's
So, it's going
So, it's going to
So, it's going to mean
So, it's going to mean different
So, it's going to mean different things
at
at different
So, it's going to mean different things
at different times
at different times in
So, it's going to mean different things
at different times in different
settings.
One
One may
settings.
One may at
One may at one
settings.
One may at one point
One may at one point get
settings.
One may at one point get that
One may at one point get that the
settings.
One may at one point get that the karmic
lesson
lesson is
lesson is not
lesson is not to
lesson is not to get
lesson is not to get suckered
lesson is not to get suckered in.
suckered
suckered in
lesson is not to get suckered in.
suckered in by
suckered in by the
lesson is not to get suckered in.
suckered in by the glamour
of
of neediness.
You're
You're getting
of neediness.
You're getting worked
You're getting worked by
of neediness.
You're getting worked by neediness.
You
You get
You get worked
You get worked by
You get worked by suffering.
You get worked by suffering. Oh,
You get worked by suffering. Oh, look
how
how I
You get worked by suffering. Oh, look
how I suffer.
how I suffer. This
You get worked by suffering. Oh, look
how I suffer. This is
how I suffer. This is a
You get worked by suffering. Oh, look
how I suffer. This is a way
how I suffer. This is a way to
manipulate
manipulate God
manipulate God for
manipulate God for one
manipulate God for one thing.
Oh,
Oh, how
manipulate God for one thing.
Oh, how I
Oh, how I suffer.
manipulate God for one thing.
Oh, how I suffer. The
Oh, how I suffer. The collective
manipulate God for one thing.
Oh, how I suffer. The collective moans
of
of mankind.
So
So at
of mankind.
So at a
So at a certain
of mankind.
So at a certain level
So at a certain level of
of mankind.
So at a certain level of development
So at a certain level of development of
consciousness,
consciousness, one
consciousness, one has
consciousness, one has to
consciousness, one has to walk
consciousness, one has to walk by
consciousness, one has to walk by the
moans
moans of
consciousness, one has to walk by the
moans of the
moans of the suffering.
Who
Who asked
Who asked them
Who asked them to
Who asked them to suffer?
Who asked them to suffer? Did
Who asked them to suffer? Did you?
Who asked them to suffer? Did you? No,
Who asked them to suffer? Did you? No, I
didn't
didn't ask
Who asked them to suffer? Did you? No, I
didn't ask them
didn't ask them to
Who asked them to suffer? Did you? No, I
didn't ask them to suffer.
Therefore,
Therefore, I
Therefore, I don't
Therefore, I don't want
Therefore, I don't want to
Therefore, I don't want to be
Therefore, I don't want to be dominated
by
by their
Therefore, I don't want to be dominated
by their suffering.
by their suffering. Now
Therefore, I don't want to be dominated
by their suffering. Now they
by their suffering. Now they have
Therefore, I don't want to be dominated
by their suffering. Now they have a
control
control and
control and a
control and a hold
control and a hold over
control and a hold over me.
By
By my
control and a hold over me.
By my suffering,
By my suffering, you
control and a hold over me.
By my suffering, you are
By my suffering, you are now
control and a hold over me.
By my suffering, you are now obligated
to
to help
to help me.
to help me. So
to help me. So I'm
to help me. So I'm trying
to help me. So I'm trying to
to help me. So I'm trying to show
to help me. So I'm trying to show you
the
the different
to help me. So I'm trying to show you
the different lights
the different lights by
to help me. So I'm trying to show you
the different lights by which
the different lights by which suffering
can
can be
can be seen
can be seen as
can be seen as a
can be seen as a control
can be seen as a control issue.
can be seen as a control issue. See
can be seen as a control issue. See the
threat
threat of
can be seen as a control issue. See the
threat of suicide
threat of suicide controls
can be seen as a control issue. See the
threat of suicide controls people
threat of suicide controls people right
and
and left.
and left. They
and left. They I
and left. They I run
and left. They I run into
and left. They I run into it
and left. They I run into it every
and left. They I run into it every day.
So
So the
and left. They I run into it every day.
So the unconscious
So the unconscious purpose
and left. They I run into it every day.
So the unconscious purpose of
So the unconscious purpose of suffering
then
then is
then is for
then is for one
then is for one thing
then is for one thing to
then is for one thing to prove
then is for one thing to prove how
then is for one thing to prove how bad
you
you are,
how
how innocent
how innocent they
how innocent they are.
how innocent they are. the
how innocent they are. the whole
perpetrator
perpetrator victim
uh
you
you know
uh
you know has
you know has taken
uh
you know has taken over
you know has taken over our
uh
you know has taken over our whole
society
society and
society and in
society and in fact
society and in fact the
society and in fact the it
society and in fact the it reigns
supreme
supreme right
society and in fact the it reigns
supreme right now.
supreme right now. What
society and in fact the it reigns
supreme right now. What reigns
supreme right now. What reigns supreme
is
is the
is the perpetrator
is the perpetrator victim
program
program in
is the perpetrator victim
program in all
program in all its
is the perpetrator victim
program in all its guises
program in all its guises political
financial
financial legal.
financial legal. See?
So
So what
financial legal. See?
So what one
So what one would
financial legal. See?
So what one would see
So what one would see to
financial legal. See?
So what one would see to do
So what one would see to do about
anything
would
would depend
anything
would depend on
would depend on the
anything
would depend on the point
would depend on the point of
observation.
observation. The
observation. The point
observation. The point of
observation. The point of observation
would
would depend
observation. The point of observation
would depend on
would depend on the
observation. The point of observation
would depend on the level
would depend on the level of
consciousness
consciousness at
consciousness at that
consciousness at that point.
consciousness at that point. The
consciousness at that point. The level
of
of consciousness
consciousness at that point. The level
of consciousness to
of consciousness to a
consciousness at that point. The level
of consciousness to a degree
of consciousness to a degree is
impersonal.
impersonal. So
impersonal. So how
impersonal. So how one
impersonal. So how one is
impersonal. So how one is led
impersonal. So how one is led to
perceive
perceive that
impersonal. So how one is led to
perceive that by
perceive that by the
impersonal. So how one is led to
perceive that by the society
perceive that by the society and
impersonal. So how one is led to
perceive that by the society and by
perceive that by the society and by the
evolution
evolution of
evolution of one's
evolution of one's consciousness
evolution of one's consciousness at
evolution of one's consciousness at that
point
point in
evolution of one's consciousness at that
point in the
point in the evolution
evolution of one's consciousness at that
point in the evolution of
point in the evolution of one's
awareness.
awareness. So
awareness. So exactly
awareness. So exactly the
awareness. So exactly the same
reportable
reportable circumstances
awareness. So exactly the same
reportable circumstances would
reportable circumstances would mean
completely
completely different
completely different things
completely different things depending
completely different things depending on
the
the level
completely different things depending on
the level of
the level of consciousness.
completely different things depending on
the level of consciousness. At
the level of consciousness. At one
completely different things depending on
the level of consciousness. At one point
you
you should
you should intervene
you should intervene and
you should intervene and try
you should intervene and try and
you should intervene and try and save
the
the person
you should intervene and try and save
the person who
the person who is
you should intervene and try and save
the person who is going
the person who is going down
you should intervene and try and save
the person who is going down the
the person who is going down the tubes.
At
At another
At another that's
At another that's a
At another that's a fatal
At another that's a fatal mistake.
See,
See, but
At another that's a fatal mistake.
See, but there's
See, but there's two
At another that's a fatal mistake.
See, but there's two different
See, but there's two different lessons.
So
So the
So the first
So the first would
So the first would be
So the first would be one
So the first would be one of
So the first would be one of compassion.
But
But once
So the first would be one of compassion.
But once you've
But once you've learned
So the first would be one of compassion.
But once you've learned compassion,
But once you've learned compassion, then
it
it would
it would no
it would no longer
it would no longer serve
it would no longer serve that
it would no longer serve that purpose.
So
So then
so
so I'm
so I'm saying
so I'm saying is
so I'm saying is the
so I'm saying is the when
so I'm saying is the when you
so I'm saying is the when you ask
so I'm saying is the when you ask a
general
general general
so I'm saying is the when you ask a
general general question
general general question like
so I'm saying is the when you ask a
general general question like that,
general general question like that, the
answer
answer is
answer is also
answer is also quite
answer is also quite complex
answer is also quite complex because
answer is also quite complex because it
would
would mean
answer is also quite complex because it
would mean how
would mean how you
answer is also quite complex because it
would mean how you viewing
would mean how you viewing the
answer is also quite complex because it
would mean how you viewing the hol
would mean how you viewing the hol the
hologram
hologram from
hologram from what
hologram from what point
hologram from what point of
hologram from what point of view.
hologram from what point of view. See
>> can
>> can I
hologram from what point of view. See
>> can I be
>> can I be more
hologram from what point of view. See
>> can I be more specific
>> can I be more specific maybe
hologram from what point of view. See
>> can I be more specific maybe to
>> can I be more specific maybe to be?
>> Sure.
>> I
>> I see
>> Sure.
>> I see what
>> I see what we
>> Sure.
>> I see what we do.
>> I see what we do. You
>> Sure.
>> I see what we do. You take
>> I see what we do. You take young
>> Sure.
>> I see what we do. You take young kids,
pure
pure kids,
pure kids, children
pure kids, children either
pure kids, children either what
pure kids, children either what in
pure kids, children either what in media
or
or in
pure kids, children either what in media
or in school
or in school glorifying
pure kids, children either what in media
or in school glorifying uh
>> and
>> and I
>> and I can
>> and I can stop
>> and I can stop it
>> and I can stop it very
>> and I can stop it very easily.
>> and I can stop it very easily. The
question
question how
>> and I can stop it very easily. The
question how far
question how far not
>> and I can stop it very easily. The
question how far not easily
question how far not easily but
>> and I can stop it very easily. The
question how far not easily but if
question how far not easily but if I
give
give them
give them different
give them different books
give them different books to
give them different books to read
give them different books to read or
give them different books to read or if
I'm
I'm different
give them different books to read or if
I'm different magazine
I'm different magazine to
give them different books to read or if
I'm different magazine to read
I'm different magazine to read how
give them different books to read or if
I'm different magazine to read how this
is
is one
is one thing
is one thing how
is one thing how do
is one thing how do you
is one thing how do you my
is one thing how do you my my
is one thing how do you my my daughter
high
high school
is one thing how do you my my daughter
high school how
high school how do
is one thing how do you my my daughter
high school how do I
>> the
>> the dilemma
>> the dilemma of
>> the dilemma of the
>> the dilemma of the present
>> the dilemma of the present day
>> the dilemma of the present day parent
>> I'm
>> I'm so
>> the dilemma of the present day parent
>> I'm so happy
>> I'm so happy I'm
>> the dilemma of the present day parent
>> I'm so happy I'm not
>> I'm so happy I'm not the
>> the dilemma of the present day parent
>> I'm so happy I'm not the parent
>> I'm so happy I'm not the parent of
>> the dilemma of the present day parent
>> I'm so happy I'm not the parent of a
child
child right
child right now
child right now a
child right now a teenage
child right now a teenage child
>> it's
>> it's hard
child right now a teenage child
>> it's hard yeah
>> I
>> I mean
>> I mean I
>> I mean I think
>> I mean I think of
>> carry
>> carry I
>> I mean I think of
>> carry I mean
>> carry I mean it's
>> I mean I think of
>> carry I mean it's the
>> carry I mean it's the best
>> I mean I think of
>> carry I mean it's the best way
>> carry I mean it's the best way out
>> I mean I think of
>> carry I mean it's the best way out for
me
me as
me as a
me as a parent
me as a parent you
me as a parent you know
>> exactly
>> exactly and
me as a parent you know
>> exactly and not
>> exactly and not only
me as a parent you know
>> exactly and not only my
>> exactly and not only my child
me as a parent you know
>> exactly and not only my child let's
>> exactly and not only my child let's say
my
my high
my high school
>> Yeah
>> Yeah That's
my high school
>> Yeah That's even
>> Yeah That's even worse.
my high school
>> Yeah That's even worse. How
>> Yeah That's even worse. How far
my high school
>> Yeah That's even worse. How far you
>> Yeah That's even worse. How far you go?
Oh,
Oh, poor
Oh, poor man.
>> Let
>> Let us
Oh, poor man.
>> Let us all
>> Let us all pray
Oh, poor man.
>> Let us all pray for
>> Let us all pray for this
Oh, poor man.
>> Let us all pray for this man
>> Let us all pray for this man who
Oh, poor man.
>> Let us all pray for this man who has
high
high school
high school children.
>> Thank
>> Thank you.
high school children.
>> Thank you. My
>> Thank you. My compassion
high school children.
>> Thank you. My compassion goes
>> Thank you. My compassion goes out
high school children.
>> Thank you. My compassion goes out to
you.
>> This
>> This is
you.
>> This is only
>> This is only one
you.
>> This is only one example.
>> Oh,
>> Oh, that's
>> Oh, that's terrifying.
>> Oh, that's terrifying. The
>> Oh, that's terrifying. The idea
>> Oh, that's terrifying. The idea of
having
having a
>> Oh, that's terrifying. The idea of
having a high
having a high school
>> Oh, that's terrifying. The idea of
having a high school child
having a high school child right
>> Oh, that's terrifying. The idea of
having a high school child right now
would
would be
would be terrifying.
>> Yes.
>> Yes. The
would be terrifying.
>> Yes. The seduction
>> Yes. The seduction of
would be terrifying.
>> Yes. The seduction of the
>> Yes. The seduction of the media
would be terrifying.
>> Yes. The seduction of the media is
overwhelming.
overwhelming. The
overwhelming. The impact
>> do
>> do well.
overwhelming. The impact
>> do well. First
>> do well. First of
overwhelming. The impact
>> do well. First of all,
>> do well. First of all, do
overwhelming. The impact
>> do well. First of all, do about
>> do well. First of all, do about what?
First,
First, we
First, we have
First, we have to
First, we have to define
First, we have to define what
First, we have to define what to
First, we have to define what to do
about
about what?
First, we have to define what to do
about what? See,
about what? See, to
First, we have to define what to do
about what? See, to do
about what? See, to do about
First, we have to define what to do
about what? See, to do about what?
about what? See, to do about what? the
seduction
seduction of
uh
uh that
seduction of
uh that which
uh that which is
seduction of
uh that which is non-integrous
uh that which is non-integrous for
sensation
sensation and
sensation and for
sensation and for money
sensation and for money and
sensation and for money and for
sensation and for money and for gain
you
you know
sensation and for money and for gain
you know the
you know the impact
sensation and for money and for gain
you know the impact of
you know the impact of the
sensation and for money and for gain
you know the impact of the media
you know the impact of the media MTV
sensation and for money and for gain
you know the impact of the media MTV and
all
all these
all these programs
all these programs uh
all these programs uh the
all these programs uh the rock
all these programs uh the rock music
these
these things
all these programs uh the rock music
these things that
these things that glorify
all these programs uh the rock music
these things that glorify violence
these things that glorify violence and
desensitize
desensitize us
desensitize us to
desensitize us to any
desensitize us to any kind
desensitize us to any kind of
desensitize us to any kind of decency
desensitize us to any kind of decency is
you
you know
a
a grave
a grave uh
a grave uh danger
a grave uh danger to
a grave uh danger to the
a grave uh danger to the fabric
a grave uh danger to the fabric of
society
society as
a grave uh danger to the fabric of
society as we
society as we know
a grave uh danger to the fabric of
society as we know it
society as we know it now
a grave uh danger to the fabric of
society as we know it now and
society as we know it now and maybe
a grave uh danger to the fabric of
society as we know it now and maybe it
will
will have
will have to
will have to go
will have to go through
will have to go through an
will have to go through an excess
will have to go through an excess before
it
it rebounds
will have to go through an excess before
it rebounds in
it rebounds in the
will have to go through an excess before
it rebounds in the other
it rebounds in the other direction.
will have to go through an excess before
it rebounds in the other direction. In
Victorian
Victorian times,
Victorian times, it
Victorian times, it was
Victorian times, it was an
Victorian times, it was an excess
Victorian times, it was an excess in
Victorian times, it was an excess in one
way.
way. Now
Victorian times, it was an excess in one
way. Now it's
way. Now it's an
Victorian times, it was an excess in one
way. Now it's an excess
way. Now it's an excess in
Victorian times, it was an excess in one
way. Now it's an excess in the
way. Now it's an excess in the others.
So,
So, but
So, but but
So, but but that
So, but but that is
So, but but that is a
So, but but that is a tendency
So, but but that is a tendency of
society
society to
So, but but that is a tendency of
society to go
society to go far
So, but but that is a tendency of
society to go far too
society to go far too far
So, but but that is a tendency of
society to go far too far this
society to go far too far this way,
So, but but that is a tendency of
society to go far too far this way, then
react
react to
react to it
react to it and
react to it and then
react to it and then instead
react to it and then instead of
react to it and then instead of stopping
in
in the
react to it and then instead of stopping
in the middle,
in the middle, it
react to it and then instead of stopping
in the middle, it over
in the middle, it over swings
react to it and then instead of stopping
in the middle, it over swings and
in the middle, it over swings and goes
too
too far
too far the
too far the other
too far the other way.
too far the other way. So,
too far the other way. So, now
too far the other way. So, now we
too far the other way. So, now we have
the
the glorification
too far the other way. So, now we have
the glorification of
the glorification of libertinism
as
as liberty.
as liberty. Huh.
as liberty. Huh. the
as liberty. Huh. the uh
the
the exploitation
as liberty. Huh. the uh
the exploitation of
the exploitation of what
as liberty. Huh. the uh
the exploitation of what is
the exploitation of what is called
as liberty. Huh. the uh
the exploitation of what is called free
speech
and
and which
speech
and which is
and which is ultimately
speech
and which is ultimately designed
and which is ultimately designed to
destroy
destroy it
destroy it destroy
destroy it destroy it.
destroy it destroy it. You
destroy it destroy it. You see
destroy it destroy it. You see within
each
each excess
destroy it destroy it. You see within
each excess is
each excess is the
destroy it destroy it. You see within
each excess is the seeds
each excess is the seeds of
destroy it destroy it. You see within
each excess is the seeds of its
each excess is the seeds of its own
destruction.
destruction. So
destruction. So free
destruction. So free speech
destruction. So free speech will
destruction. So free speech will be
interpreted
interpreted as
destruction. So free speech will be
interpreted as free
interpreted as free expression
destruction. So free speech will be
interpreted as free expression which
will
will be
will be you
will be you can
will be you can have
will be you can have do
will be you can have do any
will be you can have do any vulgarity
will be you can have do any vulgarity in
public
public strip
will be you can have do any vulgarity in
public strip naked
public strip naked and
will be you can have do any vulgarity in
public strip naked and play
public strip naked and play a
will be you can have do any vulgarity in
public strip naked and play a band
public strip naked and play a band while
you're
you're doing
you're doing it
you're doing it and
you're doing it and uh
you're doing it and uh sooner
you're doing it and uh sooner or
you're doing it and uh sooner or later
you'll
you'll hit
you're doing it and uh sooner or later
you'll hit an
you'll hit an impact
you're doing it and uh sooner or later
you'll hit an impact and
you'll hit an impact and the
you're doing it and uh sooner or later
you'll hit an impact and the thing
you'll hit an impact and the thing will
swing
swing back
swing back in
swing back in the
swing back in the other
swing back in the other direction.
The
The difficulty
swing back in the other direction.
The difficulty with
The difficulty with um
swing back in the other direction.
The difficulty with um two
The difficulty with um two political
party
party system
party system such
party system such as
party system such as the
party system such as the United
party system such as the United States
is
is see
party system such as the United States
is see in
is see in a
party system such as the United States
is see in a European
is see in a European country
party system such as the United States
is see in a European country where
is see in a European country where you
have
have a
have a coalition
have a coalition you're
have a coalition you're representing
five
five or
have a coalition you're representing
five or six
five or six different
have a coalition you're representing
five or six different viewpoints
five or six different viewpoints and
then
then you
then you put
then you put them
then you put them together
then you put them together as
then you put them together as a
then you put them together as a group.
Here
Here the
then you put them together as a group.
Here the downside
Here the downside of
then you put them together as a group.
Here the downside of our
Here the downside of our form
then you put them together as a group.
Here the downside of our form of
government
government is
government is a
government is a duality
government is a duality is
government is a duality is automatically
war.
war. If
government is a duality is automatically
war. If there's
war. If there's only
government is a duality is automatically
war. If there's only two
war. If there's only two you
government is a duality is automatically
war. If there's only two you got
war. If there's only two you got this
one's
one's the
one's the enemy.
So
So a
one's the enemy.
So a dualistic
So a dualistic society,
one's the enemy.
So a dualistic society, a
So a dualistic society, a two-party
system
system always
system always viewers
system always viewers first
system always viewers first this
system always viewers first this way
system always viewers first this way and
that
that way.
system always viewers first this way and
that way. And
that way. And the
system always viewers first this way and
that way. And the only
that way. And the only thing
system always viewers first this way and
that way. And the only thing that
that way. And the only thing that can
count
count it
count it down
count it down as
count it down as I
count it down as I can
count it down as I can see
count it down as I can see as
count it down as I can see as I
count it down as I can see as I say
count it down as I can see as I say is
count it down as I can see as I say is a
coalition
coalition government
count it down as I can see as I say is a
coalition government where
coalition government where five
count it down as I can see as I say is a
coalition government where five or
coalition government where five or six
elements
elements counterbalance
elements counterbalance each
elements counterbalance each other.
elements counterbalance each other. Here
you've
you've only
elements counterbalance each other. Here
you've only got
you've only got two
elements counterbalance each other. Here
you've only got two obviously
you've only got two obviously they
elements counterbalance each other. Here
you've only got two obviously they got
to
to be
to be at
to be at war
to be at war with
to be at war with each
to be at war with each other.
to be at war with each other. So
to be at war with each other. So the
same
same with
to be at war with each other. So the
same with ideology
same with ideology that
to be at war with each other. So the
same with ideology that which
same with ideology that which uh
encourages
encourages uh
encourages uh youth
encourages uh youth in
encourages uh youth in this
encourages uh youth in this direction
you
you see
encourages uh youth in this direction
you see and
you see and then
encourages uh youth in this direction
you see and then on
you see and then on the
encourages uh youth in this direction
you see and then on the other
you see and then on the other side
encourages uh youth in this direction
you see and then on the other side is
that
that which
that which stands
that which stands for
that which stands for you
that which stands for you know
that which stands for you know ethical
values
values and
that which stands for you know ethical
values and more
values and more traditional
that which stands for you know ethical
values and more traditional ways
values and more traditional ways of
looking
looking at
looking at things
looking at things and
looking at things and what
looking at things and what can
looking at things and what can a
looking at things and what can a parent
do
do in
looking at things and what can a parent
do in the
do in the middle
looking at things and what can a parent
do in the middle of
do in the middle of it
looking at things and what can a parent
do in the middle of it you
do in the middle of it you know
looking at things and what can a parent
do in the middle of it you know was
do in the middle of it you know was what
you're
you're asking
>> as
>> as a
you're asking
>> as a parent
>> can
>> can you
>> can you attack
>> can you attack uh
>> can you attack uh the
>> can you attack uh the enemies
>> can you attack uh the enemies of
>> can you attack uh the enemies of uh
>> can you attack uh the enemies of uh of
what
what you
>> can you attack uh the enemies of uh of
what you see
what you see as
>> can you attack uh the enemies of uh of
what you see as your
what you see as your child's
>> can you attack uh the enemies of uh of
what you see as your child's uh
what you see as your child's uh you
>> can you attack uh the enemies of uh of
what you see as your child's uh you Now
spiritual
spiritual integrity
spiritual integrity can
spiritual integrity can you
spiritual integrity can you attack
spiritual integrity can you attack it?
spiritual integrity can you attack it? I
don't
don't see
spiritual integrity can you attack it? I
don't see how
don't see how you
spiritual integrity can you attack it? I
don't see how you can
don't see how you can attack
spiritual integrity can you attack it? I
don't see how you can attack it
don't see how you can attack it as
spiritual integrity can you attack it? I
don't see how you can attack it as an
individual
individual because
individual because it's
individual because it's a
individual because it's a whole
evolution
evolution of
individual because it's a whole
evolution of a
evolution of a phase
individual because it's a whole
evolution of a phase in
evolution of a phase in society
individual because it's a whole
evolution of a phase in society uh
evolution of a phase in society uh in
which
which extremes
which extremes you
which extremes you know
which extremes you know the
which extremes you know the extreme
which extremes you know the extreme only
finds
finds its
which extremes you know the extreme only
finds its end
finds its end when
which extremes you know the extreme only
finds its end when it
finds its end when it reaches
its
its overextension.
There's
There's this
its overextension.
There's this certain
There's this certain principle
its overextension.
There's this certain principle in
economics
economics called
economics called the
economics called the something
economics called the something or
economics called the something or other
principle.
that
that innate
that innate within
that innate within success
that innate within success or
that innate within success or like
that innate within success or like the
rise
rise of
that innate within success or like the
rise of the
rise of the stock
that innate within success or like the
rise of the stock market
rise of the stock market is
that innate within success or like the
rise of the stock market is already
rise of the stock market is already the
the
the elements
the elements of
the elements of its
the elements of its limitation.
So
So success
the elements of its limitation.
So success has
So success has within
the elements of its limitation.
So success has within it
So success has within it innately
the elements of its limitation.
So success has within it innately built
in
in that
in that which
in that which will
in that which will bring
in that which will bring it
in that which will bring it to
in that which will bring it to an
in that which will bring it to an end
and
and bring
in that which will bring it to an end
and bring it
and bring it back.
in that which will bring it to an end
and bring it back. Each
and bring it back. Each thing
in that which will bring it to an end
and bring it back. Each thing has
and bring it back. Each thing has within
itself
itself then
itself then by
itself then by virtue
itself then by virtue of
itself then by virtue of its
itself then by virtue of its own
itself then by virtue of its own excess
it
it pulls
itself then by virtue of its own excess
it pulls itself
it pulls itself back.
itself then by virtue of its own excess
it pulls itself back. So
it pulls itself back. So the
itself then by virtue of its own excess
it pulls itself back. So the stock
market
market will
market will only
market will only rise
market will only rise so
market will only rise so high
market will only rise so high and
market will only rise so high and then
has
has built
market will only rise so high and then
has built into
has built into it
market will only rise so high and then
has built into it the
has built into it the very
market will only rise so high and then
has built into it the very mechanism
has built into it the very mechanism its
own
own destruction
own destruction which
own destruction which it
own destruction which it then
own destruction which it then crashes
and
and then
own destruction which it then crashes
and then it
and then it does
own destruction which it then crashes
and then it does all
and then it does all over
own destruction which it then crashes
and then it does all over again.
and then it does all over again. What
own destruction which it then crashes
and then it does all over again. What to
do
do as
do as an
do as an individual
do as an individual parent
do as an individual parent of
do as an individual parent of a
do as an individual parent of a child
right
right now
do as an individual parent of a child
right now I
right now I don't
do as an individual parent of a child
right now I don't know
right now I don't know I
do as an individual parent of a child
right now I don't know I think
right now I don't know I think is
do as an individual parent of a child
right now I don't know I think is a
desperate
desperate situation.
desperate situation. I
desperate situation. I think
desperate situation. I think you
desperate situation. I think you do
desperate situation. I think you do what
you
you can
desperate situation. I think you do what
you can on
you can on every
desperate situation. I think you do what
you can on every possible
you can on every possible level
desperate situation. I think you do what
you can on every possible level and
>> hurry
>> hurry up
>> hurry up a
>> hurry up a storm.
>> hurry up a storm. that
>> hurry up a storm. that you
>> hurry up a storm. that you go
>> hurry up a storm. that you go to
>> hurry up a storm. that you go to the
>> hurry up a storm. that you go to the you
go
go to
>> hurry up a storm. that you go to the you
go to the
go to the principle
>> hurry up a storm. that you go to the you
go to the principle you
go to the principle you you
>> hurry up a storm. that you go to the you
go to the principle you you you
go to the principle you you you break
the
the TV
the TV uh
the TV uh or
the TV uh or you
the TV uh or you just
the TV uh or you just let
the TV uh or you just let go
>> the
>> the mtoric
the TV uh or you just let go
>> the mtoric uh
>> the mtoric uh you
the TV uh or you just let go
>> the mtoric uh you know
>> the mtoric uh you know what
the TV uh or you just let go
>> the mtoric uh you know what to
>> the mtoric uh you know what to do
the TV uh or you just let go
>> the mtoric uh you know what to do within
the
the world
the world of
the world of actions
the world of actions is
the world of actions is uh
the world of actions is uh I
the world of actions is uh I can't
really
really say
the world of actions is uh I can't
really say but
really say but you
the world of actions is uh I can't
really say but you can
really say but you can express
the world of actions is uh I can't
really say but you can express what
really say but you can express what you
know
know to
know to be
know to be the
know to be the reality
know to be the reality to
know to be the reality to the
know to be the reality to the best
know to be the reality to the best uh
capacity
capacity that
know to be the reality to the best uh
capacity that you
capacity that you have
know to be the reality to the best uh
capacity that you have and
capacity that you have and beyond
know to be the reality to the best uh
capacity that you have and beyond that
you
you can't
you can't really
you can't really control
you can't really control it
you can't really control it you
you can't really control it you can't
really
really control
you can't really control it you can't
really control it
really control it so
you can't really control it you can't
really control it so what
really control it so what can
you can't really control it you can't
really control it so what can you
really control it so what can you do
you can't really control it you can't
really control it so what can you do uh
when
when it
when it reaches
when it reaches the
when it reaches the outrageous
when it reaches the outrageous level.
Sure,
Sure, you
when it reaches the outrageous level.
Sure, you can
Sure, you can complain
when it reaches the outrageous level.
Sure, you can complain to
Sure, you can complain to the
when it reaches the outrageous level.
Sure, you can complain to the principal
or
or something.
>> I
>> I mean,
or something.
>> I mean, it
>> I mean, it seems
or something.
>> I mean, it seems to
>> I mean, it seems to be
or something.
>> I mean, it seems to be so
>> I mean, it seems to be so easy
or something.
>> I mean, it seems to be so easy if
>> I mean, it seems to be so easy if we
caught
caught those
caught those kids,
caught those kids, you
caught those kids, you don't
caught those kids, you don't have
caught those kids, you don't have all
this
this audience
caught those kids, you don't have all
this audience to
this audience to to
caught those kids, you don't have all
this audience to to be
this audience to to be age
caught those kids, you don't have all
this audience to to be age 50
this audience to to be age 50 and
caught those kids, you don't have all
this audience to to be age 50 and try
this audience to to be age 50 and try to
to
to become
to become as
to become as a
to become as a child.
to become as a child. If
to become as a child. If we
to become as a child. If we stop
to become as a child. If we stop it
to become as a child. If we stop it in
the
the if
to become as a child. If we stop it in
the if we
the if we reverse
to become as a child. If we stop it in
the if we reverse the
the if we reverse the the
to become as a child. If we stop it in
the if we reverse the the tribalization
or
or the
or the what
or the what what
or the what what we,
you
you know,
or the what what we,
you know, kill
you know, kill them
or the what what we,
you know, kill them when
you know, kill them when they're
or the what what we,
you know, kill them when they're young.
>> They
>> They say
>> They say the
>> They say the game
>> They say the game is
>> They say the game is over
>> They say the game is over if
>> They say the game is over if you
>> They say the game is over if you haven't
won
won by
>> They say the game is over if you haven't
won by age
won by age five.
>> What?
>> What? Five,
>> What? Five, you
>> What? Five, you say?
>> Yeah.
Well,
you
you say
>> what
>> what that
>> what that example
>> what that example is.
>> They
>> They either
>> what that example is.
>> They either I
>> They either I mean,
>> what that example is.
>> They either I mean, you
>> They either I mean, you know,
>> what that example is.
>> They either I mean, you know, by
>> They either I mean, you know, by that
time
time they
time they either
time they either recognize
time they either recognize uh
time they either recognize uh you
time they either recognize uh you for
what
what you
time they either recognize uh you for
what you are,
what you are, even
time they either recognize uh you for
what you are, even though
what you are, even though they
time they either recognize uh you for
what you are, even though they may
what you are, even though they may not
want
want to
want to admit
want to admit it,
want to admit it, but
want to admit it, but they
want to admit it, but they do
want to admit it, but they do recognize
the
the reality
want to admit it, but they do recognize
the reality that
the reality that you
want to admit it, but they do recognize
the reality that you represent.
>> Yeah.
>> Taking
>> Taking childs,
>> Yeah.
>> Taking childs, pure
>> Taking childs, pure childs,
>> Yeah.
>> Taking childs, pure childs, and
>> Taking childs, pure childs, and and
>> Yeah.
>> Taking childs, pure childs, and and and
>> and
>> and programming
>> and programming to
>> and programming to think
>> and programming to think this
>> and programming to think this is
>> and programming to think this is bad,
this
this is
>> and programming to think this is bad,
this is not
this is not a
>> and programming to think this is bad,
this is not a bad,
this is not a bad, this
>> and programming to think this is bad,
this is not a bad, this is
this is not a bad, this is bad.
>> and programming to think this is bad,
this is not a bad, this is bad. And
this is not a bad, this is bad. And how
>> yeah
>> yeah well
>> yeah well that's
>> yeah well that's a
>> yeah well that's a very
>> yeah well that's a very general
>> yeah well that's a very general overall
question
question about
>> yeah well that's a very general overall
question about society
question about society itself
>> yeah well that's a very general overall
question about society itself you
question about society itself you know
how
how society
how society operates
how society operates how
how society operates how society
operates
operates and
how society operates how society
operates and the
operates and the various
how society operates how society
operates and the various means
operates and the various means by
how society operates how society
operates and the various means by which
it
it does
it does operate
it does operate but
it does operate but we
it does operate but we say
it does operate but we say that
it does operate but we say that the
it does operate but we say that the lack
of
of that
it does operate but we say that the lack
of that which
of that which you
it does operate but we say that the lack
of that which you are
of that which you are decrying
it does operate but we say that the lack
of that which you are decrying you
of that which you are decrying you know
is
is getting
is getting to
is getting to a
is getting to a lower
is getting to a lower and
is getting to a lower and lower
is getting to a lower and lower age
is getting to a lower and lower age it
was
was for
is getting to a lower and lower age it
was for a
was for a while
is getting to a lower and lower age it
was for a while just
was for a while just kids
is getting to a lower and lower age it
was for a while just kids were
was for a while just kids were in
is getting to a lower and lower age it
was for a while just kids were in the
60s
60s you
60s you know
60s you know revoling
60s you know revoling in
60s you know revoling in high
60s you know revoling in high school
then
then it
60s you know revoling in high school
then it was
then it was in
60s you know revoling in high school
then it was in grade
then it was in grade school
60s you know revoling in high school
then it was in grade school uh
then it was in grade school uh then
60s you know revoling in high school
then it was in grade school uh then it
was
was in
was in the
was in the lower
was in the lower grade
was in the lower grade school
was in the lower grade school I
was in the lower grade school I treat
was in the lower grade school I treat a
couple
couple of
was in the lower grade school I treat a
couple of teachers
couple of teachers and
was in the lower grade school I treat a
couple of teachers and they'd
couple of teachers and they'd tell
was in the lower grade school I treat a
couple of teachers and they'd tell me
that
that now,
that now, you
that now, you know,
that now, you know, a
that now, you know, a few
that now, you know, a few years
that now, you know, a few years ago,
that now, you know, a few years ago, the
third
third graders
that now, you know, a few years ago, the
third graders would
third graders would attack
that now, you know, a few years ago, the
third graders would attack you,
physically
physically attack
physically attack you
physically attack you and
physically attack you and they'll
physically attack you and they'll curse
you
you and
physically attack you and they'll curse
you and uh
you and uh this
physically attack you and they'll curse
you and uh this kind
you and uh this kind of
physically attack you and they'll curse
you and uh this kind of thing.
you and uh this kind of thing. And
physically attack you and they'll curse
you and uh this kind of thing. And now
you and uh this kind of thing. And now I
see
see according
see according to
see according to this
see according to this week's
see according to this week's Time
magazine,
magazine, it's
see according to this week's Time
magazine, it's reached
magazine, it's reached the
see according to this week's Time
magazine, it's reached the kindergarten
level.
level. The
level. The kindergarteners
level. The kindergarteners will
level. The kindergarteners will now
level. The kindergarteners will now bite
you
you and
level. The kindergarteners will now bite
you and curse
you and curse you
level. The kindergarteners will now bite
you and curse you and
you and curse you and try
level. The kindergarteners will now bite
you and curse you and try to
you and curse you and try to stab
level. The kindergarteners will now bite
you and curse you and try to stab you.
And
>> what
>> what I
And
>> what I kind
>> So
>> So what
>> So what if
>> So what if all
>> So what if all your
>> So what if all your energy
>> So what if all your energy you
>> So what if all your energy you spend
>> So what if all your energy you spend not
on
on us
>> So what if all your energy you spend not
on us but
on us but on
>> So what if all your energy you spend not
on us but on kids?
>> Your
>> Your energy
>> Your energy as
>> Your energy as as
>> Your energy as as David
>> Your energy as as David Hawkins
>> Your energy as as David Hawkins of
trying
trying to
>> Your energy as as David Hawkins of
trying to change
trying to change Isn't
>> Your energy as as David Hawkins of
trying to change Isn't it
trying to change Isn't it easier?
>> What
>> What your
>> What your energy
>> What your energy is
>> What your energy is spent
>> What your energy is spent trying
>> What your energy is spent trying to
change?
change? Sure.
>> Uh
>> Uh I
>> Uh I don't
>> Uh I don't see
>> Uh I don't see that
>> Uh I don't see that one
>> Uh I don't see that one can
>> Uh I don't see that one can do
>> Uh I don't see that one can do it
directly.
directly. You
>> Uh I don't see that one can do it
directly. You know,
directly. You know, we
>> Uh I don't see that one can do it
directly. You know, we talk
directly. You know, we talk about
>> Uh I don't see that one can do it
directly. You know, we talk about doing
what
what we
what we can
what we can spiritually
as
as it
what we can spiritually
as it is
as it is accessible
what we can spiritually
as it is accessible to
as it is accessible to us.
what we can spiritually
as it is accessible to us. And
as it is accessible to us. And this
influences
influences the
influences the overall
influences the overall field
influences the overall field of
influences the overall field of the
level
level of
influences the overall field of the
level of consciousness.
level of consciousness. Then
influences the overall field of the
level of consciousness. Then the
level of consciousness. Then the field
has
has an
has an indirect
has an indirect effect.
There's
There's the
has an indirect effect.
There's the content
There's the content of
has an indirect effect.
There's the content of the
There's the content of the field.
has an indirect effect.
There's the content of the field. Then
there's
there's the
there's the approximate
there's the approximate field.
there's the approximate field. Then
there's
there's the
there's the approximate field. Then
there's the ultimate
there's the ultimate field
there's the approximate field. Then
there's the ultimate field which
there's the ultimate field which is
really
really consciousness
divinity
divinity itself.
really consciousness
divinity itself. Yeah.
divinity itself. Yeah. So
really consciousness
divinity itself. Yeah. So by
divinity itself. Yeah. So by doing
really consciousness
divinity itself. Yeah. So by doing what
we
we can
we can as
we can as individuals,
we can as individuals, we're
we can as individuals, we're already
doing
doing what
we can as individuals, we're already
doing what we
doing what we can
we can as individuals, we're already
doing what we can to
doing what we can to to
we can as individuals, we're already
doing what we can to to influence
doing what we can to to influence the
collective
collective the
collective the field
collective the field itself.
collective the field itself. Collapse
the
the wave
collective the field itself. Collapse
the wave function.
the wave function. So
collective the field itself. Collapse
the wave function. So the
the wave function. So the potentiality
becomes
becomes the
becomes the actuality
becomes the actuality which
becomes the actuality which at
becomes the actuality which at this
point
point we
becomes the actuality which at this
point we see
point we see as
becomes the actuality which at this
point we see as the
point we see as the rule
becomes the actuality which at this
point we see as the rule of
point we see as the rule of morality
rather
rather than
rather than that
rather than that of
rather than that of immorality
as
as we
rather than that of immorality
as we define
as we define morality.
There
There is
There is a
There is a political
There is a political definition
There is a political definition of
morality
morality that
There is a political definition of
morality that is
the
the only
the only thing
the only thing that's
the only thing that's moral
the only thing that's moral is
the only thing that's moral is the
destruction
destruction of
the only thing that's moral is the
destruction of morality.
That
That that
That that is
That that is the
That that is the ultimate
That that is the ultimate morality
That that is the ultimate morality is
the
the destruction
That that is the ultimate morality is
the destruction of
the destruction of all
That that is the ultimate morality is
the destruction of all morality
the destruction of all morality by
whatever
whatever name
whatever name it's
whatever name it's cause
whatever name it's cause called
especially
especially divinity
whatever name it's cause called
especially divinity by
especially divinity by the
whatever name it's cause called
especially divinity by the way
especially divinity by the way because
the
the very
the very word
the very word itself
the very word itself calls
the very word itself calls forth
the very word itself calls forth the
awareness
awareness that
the very word itself calls forth the
awareness that there
awareness that there is
the very word itself calls forth the
awareness that there is an
awareness that there is an overall
discipline
discipline of
discipline of reality
discipline of reality underlying
discipline of reality underlying all
discipline of reality underlying all of
human
human existence
discipline of reality underlying all of
human existence and
human existence and that
discipline of reality underlying all of
human existence and that which
human existence and that which would
seek
seek to
seek to destroy
seek to destroy it
seek to destroy it sees
seek to destroy it sees that
seek to destroy it sees that as
seek to destroy it sees that as the
enemy
enemy to
seek to destroy it sees that as the
enemy to be
enemy to be removed.
seek to destroy it sees that as the
enemy to be removed. You
enemy to be removed. You know
>> see
>> see what
>> see what I
>> see what I meant
>> see what I meant is
>> see what I meant is I'm
>> see what I meant is I'm I'm
>> see what I meant is I'm I'm I
>> see what I meant is I'm I'm I was
>> see what I meant is I'm I'm I was from
is
is I
>> see what I meant is I'm I'm I was from
is I was
is I was raised
>> see what I meant is I'm I'm I was from
is I was raised in
is I was raised in Israel.
>> see what I meant is I'm I'm I was from
is I was raised in Israel. I
is I was raised in Israel. I was
>> see what I meant is I'm I'm I was from
is I was raised in Israel. I was in
three
three wars.
three wars. I
three wars. I was
three wars. I was a
three wars. I was a soldier
three wars. I was a soldier there
three wars. I was a soldier there and
three wars. I was a soldier there and I
saw
saw how
three wars. I was a soldier there and I
saw how long
saw how long it
three wars. I was a soldier there and I
saw how long it took
saw how long it took me
three wars. I was a soldier there and I
saw how long it took me to
saw how long it took me to get
three wars. I was a soldier there and I
saw how long it took me to get rid
saw how long it took me to get rid of
the
the programming
the programming that
the programming that as
the programming that as as
the programming that as as Israeli
the programming that as as Israeli guy
that
that we
the programming that as as Israeli guy
that we are
that we are the
the programming that as as Israeli guy
that we are the best
that we are the best and
the programming that as as Israeli guy
that we are the best and we
that we are the best and we are
the programming that as as Israeli guy
that we are the best and we are the
best.
best. So
best. So if
best. So if if
best. So if if I
best. So if if I was
best. So if if I was caught
best. So if if I was caught like
best. So if if I was caught like in
best. So if if I was caught like in 50
years
years ago,
best. So if if I was caught like in 50
years ago, it
years ago, it was
best. So if if I was caught like in 50
years ago, it was much
years ago, it was much easier
best. So if if I was caught like in 50
years ago, it was much easier to
years ago, it was much easier to That's
what
what I
what I meant.
what I meant. How
what I meant. How to
what I meant. How to uh
>> Well,
yeah,
yeah, I
yeah, I see
yeah, I see what
yeah, I see what you
yeah, I see what you say.
yeah, I see what you say. Yeah,
>> it
>> it took
yeah, I see what you say. Yeah,
>> it took me
>> it took me a
yeah, I see what you say. Yeah,
>> it took me a long
>> it took me a long to
yeah, I see what you say. Yeah,
>> it took me a long to to
>> it took me a long to to get
yeah, I see what you say. Yeah,
>> it took me a long to to get rid
>> it took me a long to to get rid of
yeah, I see what you say. Yeah,
>> it took me a long to to get rid of these
things.
things. But
things. But if
things. But if if
things. But if if I
things. But if if I was
things. But if if I was if
things. But if if I was if it
things. But if if I was if it was
stopped
stopped like
things. But if if I was if it was
stopped like much
stopped like much earlier,
things. But if if I was if it was
stopped like much earlier, it
stopped like much earlier, it I
things. But if if I was if it was
stopped like much earlier, it I don't
have
have to
have to spend
have to spend so
have to spend so much
have to spend so much energy
have to spend so much energy about
have to spend so much energy about and
have to spend so much energy about and I
see
see what's
have to spend so much energy about and I
see what's going
see what's going on
have to spend so much energy about and I
see what's going on there.
Oh,
Oh, by
Oh, by the
Oh, by the way,
Oh, by the way, my
Oh, by the way, my my
Oh, by the way, my my other
Oh, by the way, my my other question.
Oh, by the way, my my other question. I
mean,
mean, am
Oh, by the way, my my other question. I
mean, am I
mean, am I crazy
Oh, by the way, my my other question. I
mean, am I crazy in
mean, am I crazy in going
Oh, by the way, my my other question. I
mean, am I crazy in going there
mean, am I crazy in going there next
month
month to
month to to
month to to work
month to to work in
month to to work in a
month to to work in a hospital
month to to work in a hospital in
month to to work in a hospital in a
Palestinian
Palestinian place?
month to to work in a hospital in a
Palestinian place? So,
Palestinian place? So, it's
month to to work in a hospital in a
Palestinian place? So, it's it's
Palestinian place? So, it's it's this
month to to work in a hospital in a
Palestinian place? So, it's it's this is
part
part of
part of doing
>> Well,
>> Well, it's
part of doing
>> Well, it's an
>> Well, it's an understandable
part of doing
>> Well, it's an understandable form
>> Well, it's an understandable form of
craziness.
>> We
>> We all
craziness.
>> We all we
>> We all we all
craziness.
>> We all we all do
>> We all we all do we
craziness.
>> We all we all do we all
>> We all we all do we all do
craziness.
>> We all we all do we all do those
>> We all we all do we all do those things
that
that we're
that we're karmically
that we're karmically called
that we're karmically called to
that we're karmically called to do
that we're karmically called to do at
the
the time
that we're karmically called to do at
the time we're
the time we're called
that we're karmically called to do at
the time we're called to
the time we're called to do
that we're karmically called to do at
the time we're called to do them.
the time we're called to do them. Yeah.
In
In one's
In one's life,
In one's life, there's
In one's life, there's times
In one's life, there's times when
In one's life, there's times when you
risk
risk your
In one's life, there's times when you
risk your own
risk your own life
In one's life, there's times when you
risk your own life for
risk your own life for the
In one's life, there's times when you
risk your own life for the sacrifice
risk your own life for the sacrifice of
a
a higher
a higher principle.
a higher principle. So
a higher principle. So it's
a higher principle. So it's in
a higher principle. So it's in the
a higher principle. So it's in the name
of
of the
a higher principle. So it's in the name
of the it's
of the it's in
a higher principle. So it's in the name
of the it's in the
of the it's in the sacrifice
a higher principle. So it's in the name
of the it's in the sacrifice to
of the it's in the sacrifice to a
a higher principle. So it's in the name
of the it's in the sacrifice to a higher
principle
principle that
principle that we
principle that we earn
principle that we earn karmic
principle that we earn karmic uh
advancement.
advancement. Yeah.
To
To selfless
To selfless serve
To selfless serve some
To selfless serve some higher
To selfless serve some higher principle.
Yeah.
>> Okay.
>> And
>> And uh
>> Okay.
>> And uh the
>> And uh the nature
>> Okay.
>> And uh the nature of
>> And uh the nature of that
>> Okay.
>> And uh the nature of that principle
changes
changes from
year
year to
changes from
year to year,
year to year, culture
changes from
year to year, culture to
year to year, culture to culture.
changes from
year to year, culture to culture. So
what
what one
what one feels
what one feels called
what one feels called upon
what one feels called upon to
what one feels called upon to do
what one feels called upon to do now
what one feels called upon to do now is
what
what you
what one feels called upon to do now is
what you should
what you should do
what one feels called upon to do now is
what you should do now.
Good.
Good. By
Good. By the
Good. By the way,
Good. By the way, I
Good. By the way, I saw
Good. By the way, I saw you
Good. By the way, I saw you say
Good. By the way, I saw you say dolphin.
Isn't
Isn't common
Good. By the way, I saw you say dolphin.
Isn't common the
Isn't common the dolphin
Good. By the way, I saw you say dolphin.
Isn't common the dolphin are
Isn't common the dolphin are much
Good. By the way, I saw you say dolphin.
Isn't common the dolphin are much higher
or
or it's
or it's just
or it's just a
or it's just a it's
or it's just a it's like
or it's just a it's like a
or it's just a it's like a like
or it's just a it's like a like a
there's
there's a
>> dolphins
>> dolphins and
>> dolphins and whales.
>> You
>> You said
>> dolphins and whales.
>> You said dolphin
>> You said dolphin are
>> dolphins and whales.
>> You said dolphin are very
>> You said dolphin are very high,
>> dolphins and whales.
>> You said dolphin are very high, but
>> You said dolphin are very high, but it
seems
seems that
seems that in
seems that in York
seems that in York it
seems that in York it was
seems that in York it was like
seems that in York it was like very
seems that in York it was like very low
compared
compared to
seems that in York it was like very low
compared to dogs
compared to dogs or
seems that in York it was like very low
compared to dogs or something.
compared to dogs or something. So,
seems that in York it was like very low
compared to dogs or something. So, is
compared to dogs or something. So, is it
just
just a
just a meat
just a meat that
>> We
>> We just
just a meat that
>> We just did
>> We just did a
just a meat that
>> We just did a quick
>> We just did a quick survey.
just a meat that
>> We just did a quick survey. We
>> We just did a quick survey. We asked
whales
whales and
whales and uh
whales and uh a
whales and uh a lot
whales and uh a lot of
whales and uh a lot of people
whales and uh a lot of people were
upset.
upset. They
whales and uh a lot of people were
upset. They want
upset. They want dolphins
whales and uh a lot of people were
upset. They want dolphins to
upset. They want dolphins to win
whales and uh a lot of people were
upset. They want dolphins to win the
game.
Exactly.
>> All
>> All I
>> All I can
>> All I can tell
>> All I can tell you
>> All I can tell you is
>> All I can tell you is what
>> All I can tell you is what we
>> All I can tell you is what we got.
Wheels
Wheels is
>> All I can tell you is what we got.
Wheels is whales
Wheels is whales and
>> All I can tell you is what we got.
Wheels is whales and dolphins
Wheels is whales and dolphins is
dolphins.
>> We'll
>> We'll do
dolphins.
>> We'll do it
>> We'll do it again,
dolphins.
>> We'll do it again, though.
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't care.
>> I don't care. I
>> I don't care. I don't
>> I don't care. I don't I
>> I don't care. I don't I I
>> I don't care. I don't I I don't
>> I don't care. I don't I I don't do
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't care. I don't I I don't do
>> I don't want
>> I don't want anybody
>> I don't care. I don't I I don't do
>> I don't want anybody to
>> I don't want anybody to be
>> I don't care. I don't I I don't do
>> I don't want anybody to be upset,
>> I don't want anybody to be upset, but
>> I don't care. I don't I I don't do
>> I don't want anybody to be upset, but uh
yes.
yes. Uh
yes. Uh some
yes. Uh some people
yes. Uh some people say,
yes. Uh some people say, "Yeah,
yes. Uh some people say, "Yeah, but
aren't
aren't the
yes. Uh some people say, "Yeah, but
aren't the dolphins
aren't the dolphins higher
yes. Uh some people say, "Yeah, but
aren't the dolphins higher than
aren't the dolphins higher than the
whales?"
whales?" I
whales?" I don't
whales?" I don't know.
whales?" I don't know. Whales
whales?" I don't know. Whales are
whales?" I don't know. Whales are maybe
better
better mothers.
whales?" I don't know. Whales are maybe
better mothers. Dolphins
better mothers. Dolphins do
whales?" I don't know. Whales are maybe
better mothers. Dolphins do a
better mothers. Dolphins do a lot
whales?" I don't know. Whales are maybe
better mothers. Dolphins do a lot of
fooling
fooling around,
fooling around, you
fooling around, you know.
Dolphins
Dolphins do
fooling around, you know.
Dolphins do a
Dolphins do a lot
fooling around, you know.
Dolphins do a lot of
Dolphins do a lot of fooling
fooling around, you know.
Dolphins do a lot of fooling around.
Dolphins do a lot of fooling around. I
don't
don't know.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
don't know.
>> Thank you very
>> Thank you very much.
>> Thank
>> Thank you
>> Thank you for
>> Thank you for asking
>> Thank you for asking me
>> Thank you for asking me such
>> Thank you for asking me such a
>> Thank you for asking me such a complex
question.
You
You force
You force me
You force me to
You force me to think
You force me to think it
You force me to think it through.
You force me to think it through. You
know,
know, I
You force me to think it through. You
know, I have
know, I have to
You force me to think it through. You
know, I have to think
know, I have to think through
You force me to think it through. You
know, I have to think through the
evolutionary
evolutionary the
evolutionary the karmic
evolutionary the karmic evolution
evolutionary the karmic evolution of
evolutionary the karmic evolution of all
of
society
society and
society and human
society and human consciousness
to
to answer
society and human consciousness
to answer some
to answer some questions.
society and human consciousness
to answer some questions. Yeah,
>> I'm
>> I'm asking
>> I'm asking it
>> I'm asking it this
>> I'm asking it this on
>> I'm asking it this on behalf
>> I'm asking it this on behalf of
>> I'm asking it this on behalf of our
class.
It
It came
It came up
It came up um
It came up um a
It came up um a month
It came up um a month or
It came up um a month or so
It came up um a month or so ago
It came up um a month or so ago from
It came up um a month or so ago from two
credible
credible sources
It came up um a month or so ago from two
credible sources that
credible sources that we
It came up um a month or so ago from two
credible sources that we have
credible sources that we have no
It came up um a month or so ago from two
credible sources that we have no free
will
and
>> what's
>> what's a
>> what's a credible
>> what's a credible source
>> what's a credible source for
>> what's a credible source for that?
Well,
Well, there
>> what's a credible source for that?
Well, there are
Well, there are two
>> what's a credible source for that?
Well, there are two ladies
Well, there are two ladies that
>> what's a credible source for that?
Well, there are two ladies that have
done
done a
done a lot
done a lot of
done a lot of spiritual
done a lot of spiritual work
done a lot of spiritual work and
done a lot of spiritual work and have
been
been doing
done a lot of spiritual work and have
been doing kinesiology
been doing kinesiology for
done a lot of spiritual work and have
been doing kinesiology for 20,
been doing kinesiology for 20, 30
done a lot of spiritual work and have
been doing kinesiology for 20, 30 years.
And
And they
And they each
And they each had
And they each had had
And they each had had this
And they each had had this realization
at
at different
And they each had had this realization
at different times
at different times and
And they each had had this realization
at different times and in
at different times and in different
And they each had had this realization
at different times and in different ways
that
>> but
>> but there
that
>> but there is
>> but there is no
that
>> but there is no free
>> but there is no free will
>> that
>> that there
>> that there is
>> that there is that
>> that there is that we
>> that there is that we have
>> that there is that we have no
>> that there is that we have no free
>> that there is that we have no free will.
>> Well,
>> Well, that's
>> that there is that we have no free will.
>> Well, that's the
>> Well, that's the end
>> that there is that we have no free will.
>> Well, that's the end of
>> Well, that's the end of their
>> that there is that we have no free will.
>> Well, that's the end of their promise.
No
No free
No free will.
Yeah.
Uh,
Uh, all
Uh, all right.
Uh, all right. So,
Uh, all right. So, of
Uh, all right. So, of course,
Uh, all right. So, of course, the
question
question is,
Uh, all right. So, of course, the
question is, is
question is, is there
Uh, all right. So, of course, the
question is, is there such
question is, is there such a
Uh, all right. So, of course, the
question is, is there such a thing
question is, is there such a thing as
free
free will?
>> Well,
>> Well, we
free will?
>> Well, we tested
>> Well, we tested it.
free will?
>> Well, we tested it. It
>> Well, we tested it. It tested
free will?
>> Well, we tested it. It tested the
philosophers
philosophers I
philosophers I have
philosophers I have at
philosophers I have at home,
philosophers I have at home, the
philosophers I have at home, the great
books
books of
philosophers I have at home, the great
books of the
books of the western
philosophers I have at home, the great
books of the western world.
books of the western world. And
philosophers I have at home, the great
books of the western world. And the
whole
whole problem
whole problem free
whole problem free will
whole problem free will has
whole problem free will has been
struggled
struggled with
whole problem free will has been
struggled with for
struggled with for many
whole problem free will has been
struggled with for many centuries.
struggled with for many centuries. See,
>> it's
>> it's answerable
>> it's answerable on
>> it's answerable on multiple
>> it's answerable on multiple levels.
First
First of
>> it's answerable on multiple levels.
First of all,
First of all, it's
>> it's answerable on multiple levels.
First of all, it's how
First of all, it's how you
>> it's answerable on multiple levels.
First of all, it's how you how
First of all, it's how you how you
define
define it.
define it. What
define it. What do
define it. What do you
define it. What do you mean
define it. What do you mean by
define it. What do you mean by free?
define it. What do you mean by free? And
what
what do
define it. What do you mean by free? And
what do you
what do you mean
define it. What do you mean by free? And
what do you mean by
what do you mean by will?
define it. What do you mean by free? And
what do you mean by will? Do
what do you mean by will? Do you
define it. What do you mean by free? And
what do you mean by will? Do you mean
choice?
choice? Do
choice? Do you
choice? Do you mean
choice? Do you mean operationally
choice? Do you mean operationally and
pragmatically?
pragmatically? Operationally
choice? Do you mean operationally and
pragmatically? Operationally and
pragmatically,
pragmatically, you
pragmatically, you cannot
pragmatically, you cannot decide
pragmatically, you cannot decide to
pragmatically, you cannot decide to be
pragmatically, you cannot decide to be a
mouse
or
or a
or a tree.
or a tree. So
or a tree. So obviously
or a tree. So obviously you're
karmically
karmically already
or a tree. So obviously you're
karmically already restricted
karmically already restricted by
or a tree. So obviously you're
karmically already restricted by that
which
which you
which you have
which you have become
which you have become to
which you have become to certain
which you have become to certain choice
choice
choice of
which you have become to certain choice
choice of range.
choice of range. You
which you have become to certain choice
choice of range. You cannot
choice of range. You cannot decide
which you have become to certain choice
choice of range. You cannot decide to
choice of range. You cannot decide to be
you
you know
you know to
you know to be
you know to be a
you know to be a dandelion.
you know to be a dandelion. It's
you know to be a dandelion. It's not.
you know to be a dandelion. It's not. So
choice
choice doesn't
you know to be a dandelion. It's not. So
choice doesn't mean
the
the ridiculous.
the ridiculous. It
the ridiculous. It means
the ridiculous. It means within
the ridiculous. It means within an
operational
operational possibility.
the ridiculous. It means within an
operational possibility. So
operational possibility. So a
the ridiculous. It means within an
operational possibility. So a calibrated
level
level of
level of consciousness
level of consciousness already
level of consciousness already denotes
sort
sort of
level of consciousness already denotes
sort of limitations
sort of limitations of
level of consciousness already denotes
sort of limitations of choice
sort of limitations of choice intrinsic
to
to consciousness
to consciousness level
to consciousness level of
to consciousness level of let's
to consciousness level of let's say
to consciousness level of let's say the
mid
mid 400s
is
is already
is already the
is already the operation
is already the operation of
intelligence.
So
So an
So an intelligent
So an intelligent educated
So an intelligent educated person
So an intelligent educated person is
So an intelligent educated person is not
really
really free
So an intelligent educated person is not
really free to
really free to make
So an intelligent educated person is not
really free to make the
really free to make the choice
So an intelligent educated person is not
really free to make the choice of
really free to make the choice of being
stupid
stupid anymore.
Nor
Nor if
stupid anymore.
Nor if he's
Nor if he's stuck
stupid anymore.
Nor if he's stuck in
Nor if he's stuck in the
stupid anymore.
Nor if he's stuck in the intellect
Nor if he's stuck in the intellect can
is
is he
is he free
is he free to
is he free to make
is he free to make a
is he free to make a choice
is he free to make a choice to
is he free to make a choice to see
is he free to make a choice to see that
reality
reality is
is he free to make a choice to see that
reality is represented
reality is represented by
is he free to make a choice to see that
reality is represented by subjectivity
and
and you
and you know
rest
rest ka
and you know
rest ka does
rest ka does not
and you know
rest ka does not rest
rest ka does not rest external
so
so the
so the range
so the range of
so the range of one's
so the range of one's choices
so the range of one's choices then
so the range of one's choices then so
so the range of one's choices then so if
you're
you're only
so the range of one's choices then so if
you're only 4t
you're only 4t tall
so the range of one's choices then so if
you're only 4t tall you
you're only 4t tall you can't
so the range of one's choices then so if
you're only 4t tall you can't reach
you're only 4t tall you can't reach 5t
away
away for
away for you
away for you know
away for you know piece
away for you know piece of
away for you know piece of apple
away for you know piece of apple pie
you're
you're limited
away for you know piece of apple pie
you're limited to
you're limited to your
away for you know piece of apple pie
you're limited to your range
Freedom
Freedom of
Freedom of choice
Freedom of choice can
Freedom of choice can be
Freedom of choice can be looked
Freedom of choice can be looked at
Freedom of choice can be looked at from
so
so many
Freedom of choice can be looked at from
so many ways.
so many ways. We
Freedom of choice can be looked at from
so many ways. We could
so many ways. We could really
Freedom of choice can be looked at from
so many ways. We could really spend
so many ways. We could really spend the
rest
rest of the
rest of the afternoon.
rest of the afternoon. You
rest of the afternoon. You can
rest of the afternoon. You can look
rest of the afternoon. You can look at
it
it as
rest of the afternoon. You can look at
it as Pavlovian
it as Pavlovian conditioning.
rest of the afternoon. You can look at
it as Pavlovian conditioning. You
it as Pavlovian conditioning. You can
look
look at
look at it
look at it as
look at it as operant
look at it as operant conditioning.
Ultimately,
Ultimately, it's
look at it as operant conditioning.
Ultimately, it's an
Ultimately, it's an epistemologic
dilemma.
What
What does
dilemma.
What does it
What does it mean
dilemma.
What does it mean by
What does it mean by free
dilemma.
What does it mean by free and
What does it mean by free and what
dilemma.
What does it mean by free and what does
it
it mean
it mean by
it mean by choice?
it mean by choice? And
it mean by choice? And who
it mean by choice? And who implied
it mean by choice? And who implied is
making
making the
it mean by choice? And who implied is
making the choice.
making the choice. And
it mean by choice? And who implied is
making the choice. And what
making the choice. And what do
it mean by choice? And who implied is
making the choice. And what do you
making the choice. And what do you mean
by
by choice?
by choice? Options,
hypothetical
hypothetical options
by choice? Options,
hypothetical options or
hypothetical options or real
by choice? Options,
hypothetical options or real options?
You
You know,
You know, neither
You know, neither one
You know, neither one of
You know, neither one of us
You know, neither one of us can
You know, neither one of us can decide
to
to fly
You know, neither one of us can decide
to fly right
to fly right now.
You know, neither one of us can decide
to fly right now. So
to fly right now. So our
You know, neither one of us can decide
to fly right now. So our obviously
to fly right now. So our obviously our
options
options are
options are limited
options are limited by
karmic.
karmic. What
options are limited by
karmic. What is
karmic. What is it?
options are limited by
karmic. What is it? So
karmic. What is it? So it
options are limited by
karmic. What is it? So it also
karmic. What is it? So it also implies
what
what does
what does karma
what does karma mean?
what does karma mean? It
what does karma mean? It means
what does karma mean? It means that
what does karma mean? It means that one
is
is the
what does karma mean? It means that one
is the consequence
is the consequence of
what does karma mean? It means that one
is the consequence of the
is the consequence of the history
what does karma mean? It means that one
is the consequence of the history of
is the consequence of the history of the
entire
entire universe
entire universe up
entire universe up to
entire universe up to this
entire universe up to this moment.
entire universe up to this moment. Took
the
the entire
entire universe up to this moment. Took
the entire the
the entire the history
entire universe up to this moment. Took
the entire the history of
the entire the history of this
entire universe up to this moment. Took
the entire the history of this entire
universe
to
to be
universe
to be what
to be what it
universe
to be what it was
to be what it was through
universe
to be what it was through all
to be what it was through all of
universe
to be what it was through all of time
for
for this
for this very
for this very instant
for this very instant as
for this very instant as the
for this very instant as the two
for this very instant as the two of
for this very instant as the two of us
sit
sit here
for this very instant as the two of us
sit here speaking
sit here speaking to
for this very instant as the two of us
sit here speaking to each
sit here speaking to each other.
Now,
Now, for
Now, for somebody
Now, for somebody to
Now, for somebody to pipe
Now, for somebody to pipe up
Now, for somebody to pipe up in
Now, for somebody to pipe up in the
middle
middle of
Now, for somebody to pipe up in the
middle of that
middle of that and
Now, for somebody to pipe up in the
middle of that and say,
middle of that and say, "You
Now, for somebody to pipe up in the
middle of that and say, "You have
middle of that and say, "You have no
free
free will.
And
And what
free will.
And what would
And what would it
free will.
And what would it be?
And what would it be? What
free will.
And what would it be? What would
And what would it be? What would it
free will.
And what would it be? What would it mean
if
if you
if you had
if you had no
if you had no free
if you had no free will?
if you had no free will? It
if you had no free will? It would
if you had no free will? It would mean
that
that all
if you had no free will? It would mean
that all choices
that all choices are
if you had no free will? It would mean
that all choices are predetermined.
Consequently,
Consequently, there
Consequently, there is
Consequently, there is no
Consequently, there is no karmic
consequence
consequence to
Consequently, there is no karmic
consequence to any
consequence to any action.
So
So what
So what would
So what would that
So what would that be?
So what would that be? That
So what would that be? That would
So what would that be? That would be
spiritual
spiritual nihilism.
Na
Na n
Na n i
Na n i h
Na n i h i
Na n i h i l
Na n i h i l i
Na n i h i l i s.
Na n i h i l i s. Spiritual
Na n i h i l i s. Spiritual nihilism
would
would mean
Na n i h i l i s. Spiritual nihilism
would mean that
would mean that nothing
Na n i h i l i s. Spiritual nihilism
would mean that nothing means
would mean that nothing means anything
because
because nothing
because nothing would
because nothing would have
because nothing would have any
because nothing would have any meaning,
would
would have
because nothing would have any meaning,
would have no
would have no value.
because nothing would have any meaning,
would have no value. If
would have no value. If it
because nothing would have any meaning,
would have no value. If it has
would have no value. If it has no
because nothing would have any meaning,
would have no value. If it has no karmic
consequences,
consequences, then
consequences, then it
consequences, then it has
consequences, then it has no
consequences, then it has no intrinsic
value.
value. Neither
consequences, then it has no intrinsic
value. Neither merit
value. Neither merit nor
consequences, then it has no intrinsic
value. Neither merit nor demar.
It
It really
It really would
It really would negate
It really would negate the
It really would negate the value
It really would negate the value of
existence.
existence. So
It really would negate the value of
existence. So you're
existence. So you're looking
It really would negate the value of
existence. So you're looking at
existence. So you're looking at the
bottom
bottom side
bottom side of
bottom side of art
bottom side of art Sartra's
bottom side of art Sartra's philosophy.
You're
You're looking
bottom side of art Sartra's philosophy.
You're looking at
You're looking at the
bottom side of art Sartra's philosophy.
You're looking at the bottom
You're looking at the bottom side
bottom side of art Sartra's philosophy.
You're looking at the bottom side of
Sartra.
The
The existence
Sartra.
The existence is
The existence is meaningless.
Sartra.
The existence is meaningless. etc.
>> Um,
>> Um, another
>> Um, another question
>> Um, another question I
>> Um, another question I had
>> Um, another question I had was
>> Um, another question I had was I
>> Um, another question I had was I had
understood
that
that uh
that uh like
that uh like kamicazi
that uh like kamicazi pilots
that uh like kamicazi pilots and
that uh like kamicazi pilots and those
who
who give
that uh like kamicazi pilots and those
who give their
who give their lives
that uh like kamicazi pilots and those
who give their lives on
who give their lives on behalf
that uh like kamicazi pilots and those
who give their lives on behalf of
something
something bigger
something bigger than
something bigger than they
something bigger than they are
something bigger than they are God
something bigger than they are God or
whatever
whatever they
something bigger than they are God or
whatever they perceive
whatever they perceive to
something bigger than they are God or
whatever they perceive to be
whatever they perceive to be bigger
something bigger than they are God or
whatever they perceive to be bigger than
they
they are
>> that
>> that they're
they are
>> that they're in
>> that they're in the
they are
>> that they're in the 500s
>> that they're in the 500s when
they are
>> that they're in the 500s when they
>> that they're in the 500s when they go.
But
But what
But what I
But what I understood
But what I understood you
But what I understood you to
But what I understood you to say
But what I understood you to say while
ago
ago was
>> the
>> the act
>> the act itself,
>> the act itself, the
>> the act itself, the act
>> the act itself, the act itself
uh
uh to
>> the act itself, the act itself
uh to surrender
uh to surrender life
>> the act itself, the act itself
uh to surrender life itself
uh to surrender life itself to
>> the act itself, the act itself
uh to surrender life itself to that
which
which one
which one understands
which one understands to
which one understands to be
which one understands to be divinity
then
then it's
which one understands to be divinity
then it's an
then it's an act
which one understands to be divinity
then it's an act of
then it's an act of the
which one understands to be divinity
then it's an act of the will
then it's an act of the will and
which one understands to be divinity
then it's an act of the will and it
certainly
certainly catapults
certainly catapults one's
certainly catapults one's level
certainly catapults one's level of
consciousness.
It
It catapults
It catapults you
It catapults you certainly
It catapults you certainly beyond
It catapults you certainly beyond 200
and
and of
It catapults you certainly beyond 200
and of course
and of course 200
It catapults you certainly beyond 200
and of course 200 is
and of course 200 is the
It catapults you certainly beyond 200
and of course 200 is the big
and of course 200 is the big barrier
It catapults you certainly beyond 200
and of course 200 is the big barrier and
then
then subsequent
then subsequent to
then subsequent to that
the
the other
then subsequent to that
the other ones
the other ones are
then subsequent to that
the other ones are barriers.
the other ones are barriers. 500
then subsequent to that
the other ones are barriers. 500 becomes
a
a barrier,
a barrier, but
a barrier, but only
a barrier, but only long
a barrier, but only long after
a barrier, but only long after you've
passed
passed 200.
a barrier, but only long after you've
passed 200. The
passed 200. The willingness
a barrier, but only long after you've
passed 200. The willingness to
passed 200. The willingness to sacrifice
one's
one's life
one's life for
one's life for a
one's life for a higher
one's life for a higher principle
one's life for a higher principle has
profound
profound karmic
one's life for a higher principle has
profound karmic implications.
It's
It's been
It's been the
It's been the main
It's been the main value
It's been the main value of
It's been the main value of war.
It's been the main value of war. You
know,
know, the
It's been the main value of war. You
know, the male
know, the male has
It's been the main value of war. You
know, the male has sought
know, the male has sought to
It's been the main value of war. You
know, the male has sought to cross
know, the male has sought to cross that
barrier
barrier from
barrier from fear,
barrier from fear, being
barrier from fear, being ruled
barrier from fear, being ruled by
barrier from fear, being ruled by fear
to
to being
barrier from fear, being ruled by fear
to being ruled
to being ruled by
barrier from fear, being ruled by fear
to being ruled by courage.
And
And traditionally
And traditionally the
And traditionally the man
And traditionally the man has
And traditionally the man has used
And traditionally the man has used war
where
where men
And traditionally the man has used war
where men crush
where men crush the
And traditionally the man has used war
where men crush the barrier
where men crush the barrier you
And traditionally the man has used war
where men crush the barrier you know
where men crush the barrier you know cuz
dueling
dueling was
dueling was a
dueling was a fashionable
dueling was a fashionable way.
dueling was a fashionable way. War
dueling was a fashionable way. War has
been
been the
dueling was a fashionable way. War has
been the traditional
been the traditional way
dueling was a fashionable way. War has
been the traditional way and
been the traditional way and I
dueling was a fashionable way. War has
been the traditional way and I say
been the traditional way and I say women
do
do it
do it through
do it through childbirth.
She
She sac
do it through childbirth.
She sac she
She sac she s
do it through childbirth.
She sac she s you
She sac she s you know
do it through childbirth.
She sac she s you know she
She sac she s you know she puts
do it through childbirth.
She sac she s you know she puts her
She sac she s you know she puts her life
on
on the
on the line
on the line every
on the line every time
on the line every time she
on the line every time she she
on the line every time she she brings
forth
forth new
on the line every time she she brings
forth new life
forth new life and
on the line every time she she brings
forth new life and the
forth new life and the death
on the line every time she she brings
forth new life and the death rate
forth new life and the death rate you
know
know childbirth
know childbirth is
know childbirth is very
know childbirth is very sizable.
In
In family
know childbirth is very sizable.
In family Bible
In family Bible I
know childbirth is very sizable.
In family Bible I have
In family Bible I have at
know childbirth is very sizable.
In family Bible I have at home,
In family Bible I have at home, at least
a
a third
a third of
a third of the
a third of the women
a third of the women died
a third of the women died during
childbirth
childbirth and
a third of the women died during
childbirth and many
childbirth and many a
a third of the women died during
childbirth and many a man
childbirth and many a man had
a third of the women died during
childbirth and many a man had three
three
three wives.
three wives. First
three wives. First dude
three wives. First dude died
three wives. First dude died in
three wives. First dude died in child
birth
birth and
three wives. First dude died in child
birth and the
birth and the third
three wives. First dude died in child
birth and the third one's
birth and the third one's pregnant
three wives. First dude died in child
birth and the third one's pregnant for
the
the fifth
the fifth time.
the fifth time. God
the fifth time. God bless
the fifth time. God bless her.
the fifth time. God bless her. Good
luck.
>> So
>> So even
>> So even if
>> So even if the
>> So even if the cause
>> So even if the cause is
>> So even if the cause is erroneous,
>> So even if the cause is erroneous, it's
the
the person's
>> So even if the cause is erroneous, it's
the person's heart.
>> Yes,
>> Yes, it's
>> Yes, it's the
>> Yes, it's the heart.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. that
>> Yes, it's the heart.
>> Okay. that you
>> Okay. that you choose.
You
You choose
You choose to
You choose to risk
You choose to risk life
You choose to risk life for
You choose to risk life for the
You choose to risk life for the sake
You choose to risk life for the sake of
life
life and
You choose to risk life for the sake of
life and for
life and for some
You choose to risk life for the sake of
life and for some higher
life and for some higher principle
You choose to risk life for the sake of
life and for some higher principle and
it
it puts
it puts you
it puts you in
it puts you in an
it puts you in an integrous
in
in the
it puts you in an integrous
in the level
in the level of
it puts you in an integrous
in the level of integrity.
It
It means
It means that
It means that cowardice
It means that cowardice you're
It means that cowardice you're no
It means that cowardice you're no longer
run
run by
It means that cowardice you're no longer
run by cowardice
run by cowardice but
It means that cowardice you're no longer
run by cowardice but by
run by cowardice but by courage
It means that cowardice you're no longer
run by cowardice but by courage and
run by cowardice but by courage and uh
so
so it's
so it's a
so it's a great
so it's a great step.
Thank
Thank you.
>> Yeah.