Today, I've talked to Dr. Hawkins, and I can tell you he's in rare form.
So put your hands together and welcome again our mentor and teacher, Dr. David Hawkins.
You'll see, according to the schedule, what is today called?
Questions and answers.
Traditional dialogue between teachers and students.
And that's what we'll do today primarily.
We, of course, have new slides, which we promise not to subject you to today.
Exciting new developments, because the consciousness research just keeps pulling up amazing information
and how it all correlates is rather staggering.
So I'll control myself and try not to show you a new slide that's just mind-boggling.
We might show them one.
The one I'm holding in mind is okay to show them.
Okay.
And so we're going to do it a little differently.
We'll go up here and we're going to discuss things in greater detail.
All the questions that, of course, now wonderful season.
All these flowers seem to indicate something coming up in a couple of weeks,
which we will avoid mentioning in public, of course.
Sort of a special day that comes.
One of a number of special days.
Actually, we're the only secular spiritual group on the planet.
I mentioned no religion.
If you stick to the Rhapsody of the Soul stunningly, it doesn't represent any particular religion.
It doesn't represent any school.
It teaches stunningly, starkly, totality of all, the source of all.
Its nature shines forth from all that exists and makes it difficult to function in the world,
so we won't talk about it too much.
All right, the lecture will come to an end.
So it's not necessary to get caught in the trappings of tradition
with all of the incrustation that has occurred to it over the years.
It starts out as some kind of a purity,
radiating forth from someone who has realized the presence of God is the source of all existence,
and then it becomes institutionalized.
And within the institutionalization, then it becomes encrusted and rigid.
Sultifying.
And then people are brought up in it as children,
and they become antagonistic to it,
and don't want to hear about it again,
and become champions of the opposite of truth,
having been disillusioned or suffered some kind of discomfort
due to the way in which it was presented to them.
They avoid it altogether.
And therefore, we can say truthfully,
we are the only secular spiritual group that I know of.
Truth needs no external authority.
Truth speaks for itself.
The devotion to truth is the devotion to the essence of the source of all existence,
which in some quarters and historically has been called God.
I agree with the Buddha it's better not to mention such a word,
because it has become imbued with so many meanings.
So many meanings that there's opposition to its use in.
And so many meanings that there's opposition to its use in.
Because it seems to those people
that it represents some kind of an oppression or loss of freedom.
So that which is the true source of freedom
now becomes pictured as the enemy of freedom.
And therefore, I can understand how they think and feel.
And some of the patients I've had
who were the most rigidly opposed to any kind of religion or spiritual teaching
had traditional religious upbringing,
and so on.
And they say I, come to think of it,
I became an atheist myself, I forgot about that.
Come to think of it, yeah.
That's because religion didn't really differentiate between the ego and the spirit.
And, blame God for really for that which is the production of the ego
which is what I did.
And I think I've told you I was extremely religious as a boy, scrupulous.
I was a boy soprano,
the bishop's acolyte and um tubulus and i lived in dread of sin and accidentally accidentally
committing a sin was very scary so there was this fear fear that stood in the way and then there was
the guilt of all of it and i think as i told you one day i was walking through the woods and
suddenly the totality of all mankind's suffering throughout all of time i don't know how else to
describe it it was like i realized that it was like it's like the realizations that come forth
as you advance spiritually they have no content to them they're just a massive realization
and when i was struck by that i thought god was creator of everything including all of that
and therefore i became an atheist
and a devoted atheist devoted and some people become atheists because they are devoted to the
truth and because the manner in which suppose the truth has been presented to them has been
objectionable they would rather maintain their own integrity and so i respect that i respect the
atheist and the people who are made uncomfortable by the word god
and i don't want to be uncomfortable so we'll avoid it so there is the ego that evolved since
the beginning of time there was when this planet spun off from the milky way or whatever
that it was too hot for life molten so life didn't really exist on the planet until it cooled down
and when it cooled down it then developed over eons of time a cool enough crust
that consciousness interacted with the crust and the first evidence of life appeared historic
research as we have been able to discover it the first form life forms were algae and viruses
and we asked this virus have a consciousness it says no you don't get up to consciousness do you
get the bacteria
the virus merely reproduces its own dna and it doesn't do anything think or go anywhere
that's all it does is reproduce itself maybe it calibrates as a virus virus calibrates less than
one calibrates less than half calibrates over half calibrate does not calibrate viruses we've
asked that a couple times conscious the first conscious life is bacteria and then we track
the evolution of life over the eons and we do have a new slide today let's have the slide out over the
eons eons of time with the advance of the complexity of life the only way life could survive was it had
to be oriented towards life it had to be oriented towards survival can you hear me yeah all right so
the essence of life then here's a hostile planet
nobody was happy to see it here well there's nobody here to be happier or not happy and it's
struggling just to survive so the essence of life itself is self-directed towards survival
we can forgive it for that because without that you wouldn't exist we own our existence and our
physical existence at least the evolution of consciousness over great beyond the time
in which it was directed primarily
to its own survival the core of the ego then is me me me my survival my gain my victory my winning
my reputation my money my image it's all directed towards me and if it wasn't we wouldn't exist long
enough to be here so instead of vilifying the ego labeling it sin source of punishment guilt and hell
you see it as the animal without whose instincts none of us would be breathing so we at least owe our
physical survival to the evolution of consciousness and its expression as the animal kingdom
isn't this interesting to some kinds of people to other kinds of people it is not interesting
we could go down a little bit i promised i wouldn't do any slides today
but then i got carried away because of the correlation of this with with uh slide number 19.
all right so you see if we start out at the beginning
which is down at the bottom here right at the beginning we have to raise this can we
raise it a little bit okay so the age of the oldest is uh it's so so big a number i can't tell
you what it even is in english
trillions of years or something anyway the first signs of life
algae they don't have it correct here it shouldn't be bacteria it should be viruses but they didn't
know any better when they did this dictionary because i stole this right out of the dictionary
by the time bacteria at this so this era this era here first signs of life consciousness level
is really one bacteria then two then the first marine invertebrates you see consciousness is
that's the cambrian age this is the consciousness level of all of all of life on this planet at
that effect of time in that era consciousness level of life on earth was eight first fish the
ordovician era whenever that is first fish and trilobites remember trilobites from bacteria
biology calibrates it 12. first trace
is the scorpions, if I remember correctly, 40 million years ago, crawled out of the sea
and walked on land, the first traces of land life. 17 is the level of consciousness. Then
the amphibians, first land snails. And the climax of brachiopods, that's exciting, isn't
it? Urines of brachiopods, anyway, you should probably put that out of there. I don't want
kids seeing that. 27, shell-crushing sharks, primitive automobiles? No, ammonites. 33,
first reptiles, 35, rise of reptiles. Isn't this interesting? Because, you know, we calibrated
the evolution of animal life on the planet, and it showed this evolution, and then we
went just to the archaeological ages, and here you have an exact correlation of it.
Wow.
The dinosaurs in the 60s and 70s. 80, first mammals, last of the dinosaurs. So the mammals
don't get too much of a chance until the dinosaurs sort of exit. Then we get to rapid
development. We're up to 112. And isn't it interesting how this era, out of a completely
different source, correlates with our animal evolution on a scale? Modern animals and plants,
212.
Rise and dominance of man, 212. But isn't this, we just, you know, did it according
to the ages, the archaeological ages, and these are the numbers we came up with, and
that's, let's see number 19, because it makes such a, I mean, it's such a great correlation,
because, you know, several months ago we had done this one, and here you see exactly
the same correlation, only just asking about the animal kingdom.
This is the elephant. This is the female elephant. This is an elephant that is just
there, which is just a little bit smaller than the elephant itself, and you see this
amazing break-in, this content of consciousness at consciousness level 200. Below 200, life
survives at the cost of other life, and as we've said, the lion doesn't kill anybody,
he just has lunch. And he can't make his lunch stand still, which is very frustrating, and
he finds if he bites it, it stands still and he can have his lunch. So, as far as he is
concerned, the rabbit is a lunch delivery system.
that he's learned to master and killing is in a mental in a human mind see the mind says oh the
lion killed that but the lion does not kill anything he just has his worm lunch and that's
the package it comes in fuzzy fuzzy packages he says so if a lion had had his way he would have
non-fuzzy lunch delivered anyway you see that for life to survive then it had to be
self-directed towards survival it didn't have any time to think about you or your survival because
that would have interfered with its survival it can't think about the bunny spirit can't worry
about others so the ego is not worried about others it's interested in myself and me it's
essential to the animal kingdom and many people on the planet today in fact whole cultures whole
cultures in fact
whole countries calibrate at this level in here these are the levels that whole countries and
cultures and societies and civilizations including their entire population calibrate the same level
there all right so it's only when you get up the consciousness level here you see the wolf eats
other people hippopotamus I didn't think would calibrate that low but he does because he kills
the hippo we mentioned kills more people than the other animal on the planet which is surprising
the javelin javelina and then peculiarly you know we didn't know anything about any correlation
I was just amazed at consciousness level 200 which of course is the critical level on the
scale of consciousness suddenly you see a total change in the nature of of life on the planet
from the killers to the munchers a munchers took over and the munchers of course
are much away eat grass and then fertilize the grass so the best thing a lawn can have is a
bunch of sheep or deer or elk on it and they fertilize it as they eat it so their survival
does not depend on the destruction of others so here you see in the animal kingdom the transition
the critical one that we saw on the level of human consciousness which we
again when we correlate the eons of archaeologic time. So it's just amazing
how all these things correlate together. Archaeologic evolutionary time, the
consciousness level of animals, the consciousness level of man, and how they
all correlate and corroborate each other. Suggesting that we are on a secular
track. The discovery of God is hidden in all these things because you see that
the source of all existence then manifests as life and this life evolves
over great eons of time. Okay, so we can put that. The nice
thing about it is once you understand it then one can be comfortable with
the ego. One can see that it is just a name that is
been...
Let's try it again.
given to a whole collection of survival mechanisms
that have been learned over enormous lengths of time.
We have respect for the ego,
and we see it represents the peak of the evolution of consciousness
throughout millions and millions of years.
To get to learn how to hate people and be greedy and selfish
took us eons.
We're worn out.
Eons of time it took to learn how to bully people
and lie about them and slander them and poke them in the eye
and tell them, you can trust me.
You can trust me.
How to calm people.
So the animal ego then evolved over eons of time.
We can see it for what it is.
We can appreciate its biologic value.
So instead of feeling guilt,
you can name your ego.
I call mine Fuzzy.
And I compliment Fuzzy on having learned
his lesson.
Because what does the animal do when you give it intelligence?
Well, we see that when you add, evolutionary-wise,
the prefrontal cortex,
you're not removing the old animal consciousness
and replacing it with a prefrontal cortex,
which would make life extremely simple with none.
No.
As bait would have it,
we get a prefrontal cortex
pasted on to the old animal brain.
Ha!
A makeshift job, at best, engineering-wise.
Wouldn't you say?
We don't put an engine in a horse cart.
We remove the horse in the cart and give it a new venue.
So here we are, human beings stuck with a prefrontal cortex
on top of an old animal brain,
which would be all right if it weren't for religion.
Now it comes down and tells you how guilty and terrible you are,
a great sinner.
I mean, sackcloth ashes, suffering, self-flagellation.
You should crawl on your knees from here to someplace in penance.
So you get the worship then of guilt
and the demonization of the ego.
There you've got an intense conflict
and one which pretty much precludes enlightenment.
Ha!
If your drained from childhood
reinforced by society to hate your own instinctual nature you're in trouble right from the beginning
so some people vacate the whole conflict by becoming an atheist therefore i respect there
that that was the way they resolved it at the time i remember myself after becoming an atheist
i felt for one thing much freer than ever i felt like i was finally free of chains
and some kind of morbidity uh i could be my own person be my own person accountable to myself
accountable to society but not to some big prevailing sense of guilt that stalks you
all the time progress then in understanding the way to self-realization the realization
of the presence of the source of all existence which exists as your own inner self
we have to stop vilifying the ego stop demonizing it
denouncing it but give sinification it's prevailed for thousands of years and we see
what it's produced then so the worship of sin then has kept the evolution of spiritual awareness
slowed down to the few the few would have to have the courage to transcend all that you can imagine
the courage it takes to transcend all that and do it on your own scare the wits out of anybody
christ
so the essence of the pathway devotional non-duality means one trust that there is one
quality of god that one can discern and accurately confirm like one ray of sunshine one ray of light
and you just follow this one light and if its source is that which you are seeking you only
need one ray of light to follow you don't need 12 different pathways to go in one time devotion to an
absolute dedication to the truth and to be willing to sacrifice anything that is not true again takes
an enormous courage because you're going to transcend 99.9% of the belief systems of all
of society throughout all time it's just what it happens early courage then to accept that truth
itself is an essential quality of divinity and if you actual that love so if you add devotion to
the truth the love of truth will grow forever and ever they are reached at that moment frame ant
of truth you have both heart and mind and then out of that awareness one is
willing to be of service to life out of one's appreciation and love for life so
you have the three great pathways to God through heart your heart your mind and
through service selfless service combine the three great pathways simultaneously
because one automatically opens the other doorway all three of them work
together to become a love as one becomes more and more loving it happens because
as you remove the barriers and the blocks to it because that's your because
that is your nature being loving is not something you have to work on you don't
have to work on being willing the realization of truth as it unfolds one
automatic runs to
appreciate support to love all of life in all its expressions so we saw how
life evolved since the beginning of time and we all appreciate it and love it you
know I'm really impressed with the Komodo dragon I mean it is the ultimate
killing machine it's just impressive in the perfection of that which it is
clever just gives you one little nip and then lays it on waits for you to go
away
lunch is gonna arrive in a few days genius biologic genius okay so the ego
then represents instead of a vilifiable source of sin and self-hatred and guilt
and killing of others and justification for murder and what they call bombing
Americans jihad or something one can instead become its champion it's
biologically extremely impressive is it not when you look at your ego you
say you say it's impressive I mean I can cheat and lie and I can be
selfish all day long and boy can I hate people can I ever be angry and can I
file on the guilt in the self-attack it's perfected itself what happened in
Man then is the prefrontal cortex gets tagged onto the animal brain and now the
animal brain the animal instincts use intelligence for animal클
intelligence autonomous for survival limit.
man's. There you got man's difficulty. Because we didn't remove the animal brain, so what
we did is we gave a 10-year-old a high-powered rifle. The prefrontal cortex is a high-powered
rifle, and a 10-year-old is your animal brain. So we gave a 10-year-old idiot boy who's been
seeing a therapist for a lot of troubles, and we gave him a loaded gun, high-powered
rifle. So the intellect then became the tool of the ego, which explains what goes on in
society, which explains the nature of society, and the rarity of truth. The rarity of truth.
The ego takes over self-servingness and now uses the intellect and vocabulary and public
language, goes on television, and does its antithesis.
It's the animal thing disguised as an intelligent human being. It's somebody's ego up there you
see every evening. What is the ego doing? Well, we know it should be self-seeking. It
should be self-seeking. So instead of vilifying it, we could say, boy, that guy really knows
how to lie up the storm, don't he? I find I'm not angry at liars, I'm angry at bad liars.
I mean, it's so implausible. Some of the things that are said, I say, did I hear that?
You know, that's what you get angry about, you say. I don't believe anybody can think that we
were just insulting to the public. So there we see the evolution of consciousness as life itself.
Life itself below 200, we give a bad name from a human viewpoint. From their viewpoint,
it was very successful. From our viewpoint, we condemn it when it
appears in human society, the same motives we condemn. Because we're interested here
in evolution of our own consciousness, then we can jump over the whole block, which takes
many, many lifetimes, many lifetimes to get over the vilification. Let's see if that's
so. That, in its effect, takes many lifetimes, hundreds of. It often takes you hundreds of
lifetimes to disappear.
To discern how to get off self-hatred and the dualistic conception of self and others
that arises from attacking the prefrontal cortex on the animal brain. Therefore, by
recontextualizing it, everybody here has been saved many lifetimes. Many, many, many, thousands
of lifetimes, tens of thousands of lifetimes. It takes like forever. You can see how much
how long it took consciousness to creep up a couple of points. Well, that isn't them.
That's you.
Not them. It's us, folks. It's us that's been climbing up over here on the slide. Slowly,
slowly, slowly. It's us. We've earned the right to speak for ourselves. We want to evolve
at least as far as cats and dogs.
Let's have number 19. I love 19.
19.
Number 19. We're going to talk for a little while and then we're going to take a break
and then we're going to really spend the day in traditional questions and answers. No question
is too absurd. On second thought, there might be some.
So we saw how life evolved. Here we are. We saw it on the scale of the evolution of the
age of the planet.
Then we saw it appearing as a human being. Then we saw it as a human being. Then we saw
it appearing as life.
So here is the corroboration and the scientific verification of everything I've said thus
far today. In fact, here are the numbers. Here are the actual numbers of how this life
evolved. And here you have this right here is in your brain. This is in your brain. All
of this is in your brain. All this is in your brain. All this is in your brain. All this
is in your brain sometimes i feel like a hippo don't you you don't identify with them too much
and zebras i'm not i mean i'm not tall enough to identify with a giraffe they look
and to have a drink of water seems very awkward so i just sort of reject my giraffe nature
but i do love my deer nature and they come and visit us very frequently the other day outside
the office stood this incredible stay beautiful gorgeous day and the whole office staff came out
we all and we all talked to him he's just exiting out there he's supposed to be scared of people and
run away the staff's all talking to him telling how handsome he is and chatting with him and this
deer just loved being talked to i don't know we're just all sitting there loving him i guess
just uh loving him and this deer is just like he can't move away from it all the deer was transfixed
really by the energy of love now he was transfixed he really couldn't move and in fact we had to stop
looking at him and we had to stop looking at him and we had to stop looking at him and we had to
stop looking at him and talking on it talking to him and sending him love why because you saw his
stunning beauty he just stood there like an incredible artistic masterpiece so we appreciate
the beauty and now we begin to love all these things and they become part of our family
people have pet pigs all these animals become our friends we train our elephants
and elephants are more intelligent than a great many people on the planet
it's kind of cool yeah even a pig is smarter than lots of people
the dairy cow is smarter and so as we go here then we begin to identify with them as fellow animals
don't we we all will develop an affection for the domestic animal the farmer and all of us
has a certain affection for all of our horses and our cows and our sheep and we begin to care for
them and we hope that people in الح n sane when they have the opportunity to help us grow and health
and we hope that people in the world who do this can help us grow it with a certain amount of real
that people will evolve, at least as far
as cats and dogs, the family
cat at 245.
The dog, we said, we saw that
the great, the top
of the animal kingdom here
has actually reached 500.
Literally, through the animal kingdom,
you see
unconditional love.
Unconditional love. We've calibrated the same
dog.
He's 505, but anyway.
The dog I'm thinking about now,
but the dog's wagging tail,
so here, through the animal kingdom,
instead of putting it down, we see
there is the evolution of the
heart, because here is the heart coming
through as the kitty's purr,
the songbird's song,
and the dog's wagging tail.
So, the animal kingdom
is not just the pathway
of the eagle, the killer,
the Komodo dragon, but
on up here becomes the grazer,
that becomes the mother.
So you see the bursting forth
of love as the maternal instinct
in the feminine.
That which is classically
called the masculine
is not too
a cheery place to hang out with, because it'll
kill you off.
Life doesn't really
get safe until you see the emergence of
the feminine principle as the maternal.
The caringness for the
survival of others.
The caringness for the survival of others
you can see is the evolution
of the feminine. The man then
learns it from the woman.
But left to his own, he never would have thought
of it.
The male lion thinks that cubs make
dinner, so it takes a mother lion
to teach him that those are
yours, boy.
Expect a little support money
around here.
Some animals have even learned to be intelligent,
have really learned how to
utilize the frontal cortex.
You see Alex and Coco
both at over 400.
You are safer in a cage
with Coco than
all these people on all these
continents and all these countries
in the world today.
These people will booby trap you
and blow off your legs with a landmine.
And Coco will merely
ask you why you have that shirt
on today.
Like shirt, like shirt. Blue,
blue shirt. Alex knows colors.
So Alex would say blue
shirt, blue shirt.
Dark blue shirt.
Is that blue shirt? Alex says blue.
What's this color? Blue.
Blue. This blue? That blue?
And he looks confused because
this is light and this is dark, but they're both blue.
So it takes training
to train him. Light blue,
dark blue. Oh. I don't know
if you haven't seen him on
TV, but he's out of the University of Arizona.
Alright, so
that's enough of the slides
for today. So, what I want
to retract is the evolution
of consciousness throughout all
of the eons.
It's evolution through the
animal kingdom.
Our inheritance
of it is so obvious, I mean, you've
laid it out in spades
for anybody to see
that the evolution of your ego
is the evolution of
nature itself, its expression
is life, and its qualities
are critical and essential to
survival. Consequently,
you can stop feeling guilty about them.
Then you can see how
the inner instincts
grab intelligence
and education and begin
to use them.
Utilize it towards its own end.
And that's where spiritual
awareness and commitment and teachings
come in.
We also showed
at the last lecture how
now, with the beginning of, once you get
over consciousness level 200,
then love
in its various forms and
utilization of intelligence
in the interest of love
becomes more and more
powerful. And eventually
it begins to change brain function.
Did we show that at the last lecture?
How? Brain function?
Yes? We had the brain?
Right? Alright. So you
see, the likelihood of the
mind and the intellect reaching truth
is extremely slim. I'm writing
about it right now, and I
thought, how do we ever get to know the truth about
anything? It looks
almost impossible.
And the reason is
because spiritual intention
then comes forth as a radiation,
like the radiance of a new energy.
Field.
And we are attracted to
and we follow that field.
And thereby transcend our
identification with the animal kingdom.
We can't really get rid of
a thing until you own it. You can't
get rid of an addiction
unless you admit that
it's got you. So,
we can't get rid of the ego by denying
it, by demonizing
it, by making it
our enemy, but by
owning it and beginning to see
and appreciate it and respecting it.
It's a wonderful mechanism
without which life wouldn't survive.
Without which there wouldn't
be any Komodo dragons.
They're one of the great wonders of the modern world.
Here's this dragon from
four million
BC still with us in the zoo
or wherever they keep Komodo dragons.
No, they live in Indonesia
on a little island there.
So it's a wonderment. So we can
wonder at the evolution
of the animal kingdom.
I would now tell people
give your ego a name, something
that you can own, that it's
my Fuzzy. And of course Fuzzy
you hate them. Of course Fuzzy
you hate them.
Of course Fuzzy you want it all.
Of course Fuzzy you want to kill him.
He deserves it, don't he?
So you begin to own. As you own
then you don't have to be in denial.
You don't have to project it on others.
When you own it yourself, you stop
seeing other people as evil and
you see that they're caught in the same
animal way of thinking.
Because they're caught
in the same evolution,
evolutionary stall out
of the brain. They're caught
in the same trap. Happily
you've seen the light and have learned
how to move beyond it.
So there is a transition period
where you go through
a difficulty in confronting
the ego
because before that you project
it onto others or you deny it or
you project it onto God or somebody.
And now you have to own it yourself.
You can own it if you see it
so you contextualize
it differently.
The reason to appreciate it, I spend
so much time on the evolution of consciousness
is because when you really and
completely and totally understand it
it loses its power over you.
It's lost its power to
really know the truth of that which it is
and how it got to be that way
you can say
good old Fuzzy.
Of course you want all the cookies on the plate.
Of course you want to drown your little
sister in the sea.
Little Edie Wibletree
drowned her playmate in the sea.
Mother looked quite grave and said then
Edie, don't do that again.
Can't you see my little pet?
You've got your tootsies wet.
Edie Wibletree
wants to drown her playmate in the sea.
She hates her.
So we respect our animal
evolution. We stop
glorifying it.
If the universe is created by divinity
then that's how it
unfolded.
We are serving some purpose
to connect this evolutionary
line with
a life that
takes over on a non-physical
level.
The devotion to truth then.
The truth is that the ego
is nothing but one's biologic
ancestry.
It lives on in the very
structure and anatomy
of the human brain.
Without it you wouldn't even be alive.
So you can give it credit.
If it wasn't for good old ego
I wouldn't be standing here today.
However,
the spiritual energy which also
surrounds humanity
begins to pull us even beyond it.
And we begin to say,
isn't there something more?
Isn't there something better?
But I want you to be aware
that the ego is not
adhering to any religion whatsoever.
And never even mentioning it.
Not necessary to mention it.
As you let go now
that this is the animal
if you didn't understand anything about the ego
and I just told you
the human mind is not at the service
to the animal
and you become a student of your own mind
and get a little notebook
and you notice what your animal did today
what it did today
you become
a psychologist by here
being a student of your own nature
how it shines forth
and how it shines forth in everyone.
So it doesn't have to be
secret, it doesn't have to be mystical
it doesn't have to be
couched in foreign languages
you don't have to pull it out of antiquity
it's observable
rediscoverable right now
in the immediate present.
Begin to own it for what it is
and begin surrendering it.
And as you
as it comes up
you can forgive it
you can let it go
you can let go wanting to control it
there are all the mechanisms
that all the various schools and workshops
teach various mechanisms
meditation and contemplation
and the one that I
recommend because
it's unstoppable
is contemplation
meditation you see
you gotta sort of take yourself out of it
and go someplace
like it and give yourself tendinitis
and stuff
you know every orthopedist says
practicing meditation eh?
knees twisted up
your back all warped out
so people will take a course
on meditation become intensely involved
in a weekend workshop
and be with some teachers
etc and then
you visit them again in Chicago three years later
and they've given it up long ago
why is that? Because
you gotta take time out from real life
you might say real life
to do this
and you just don't have time to do that
for the same reason you gave up playing
Parcheesi years ago
you just haven't got time to get out
the game board and go someplace
and say you wanna play Parcheesi
eh? Chinese marbles
or whatever it was
I was gonna say scruple
scrapple what was that?
in my childhood
it was called scruple not scrapple
scruples
scrupulous
scrapless
so we don't have time to take out
so we skip it
therefore a contemplative way
of being in the world
when you get to consciousness level 500
this happens anyway
one just begins
to appreciate more and more
the beauty of life
one becomes sensitized to beauty
and beauty itself is one of the
pathways to God
the virtue of one's spiritual commitment
therefore
you open doors
experiential doors
and the progression of experiences
that would not have occurred
had you not made that commitment
to be spiritually committed
is to automatically
bring into your presence
into your existence
into your experience of your own existence
things sequencing
themselves
in a way that would not have happened otherwise
doors open
that wouldn't have opened
you say I don't know
just I got there and the door opened
I don't know
what is it a miracle
call it miracles
but that again is going in the other direction
no
it isn't a miracle
it's what's normal
that's reality for a spiritually committed person
things should work out
one should uncover new sources of joy
these are all part and parcel
therefore spiritual commitment
pulls into you
a field
the field then begins to support you
it's not you
it's not miracles
it's nothing special
it's the automatic consequence of the field
an ocean without salt
has different buoyancy
than an ocean with salt
all you've done is add tremendous salt
and now you're more buoyant than you were before
so you float higher
as a consequence of your spiritual commitment
and of course you think differently
you see things differently
because spiritual commitment
automatically changes brain function
it changes brain function
it automatically creates an etheric brain
one now has an instrument
through which all experience is
filtered or processed
which is not present
Komodo Dragon doesn't have an etheric brain
he doesn't really worry about things
lucky from a certain viewpoint right
lucky Komodo Dragon
I appreciate and give reverence
to our own spiritual nature
that we have owned it
and acknowledged it
and in so doing
we have benefited all of mankind forever
a group like this
by merely owning
the reality of your own spiritual power
and truth
changes the consciousness of mankind
changes the consciousness of mankind forever
not disconnected from it
because you are the consciousness
the infinite field
is here present
within all of us
and as we move our spiritual commitment
to the field
the field itself becomes more powerfully influential
in all of us
with each other
because of each and every one of us
each and every one of us benefits
I benefit by you sitting right there
I benefit by you
every single person here
we all enormously radiate
enormous power
to each other
which I never speak of
but today I thought I would
that's a fact
we are all moving along
not just as a consequence of our
being so wonderful ourselves
but the fact that we are surrounded by people
who are wonderful
and we are included in their field
so all of life benefits
and by our commitment
and we automatically bring the miraculous
into our life
as the everyday
things
when other people drop a button
from the bureau
they don't find it
and you say Holy Spirit
I have to have that button
you find it
you think everybody does that
no they don't
they don't find the button
if it wasn't for the Holy Spirit
we would never find our cat
he keeps getting lost
we have staff in and out
and the office is attached to the house
so we have to have that button
thus far
Holy Spirit has answered every prayer
I ask God
where is the kitty
and the next thing you move over
and there underneath the pillow
a little tail sticking out
is the kitty
I just want us to really appreciate ourselves
for this holiday season
and it should be nameless of course
because this lecture could be heard by others
in this bleep season
which is
the day of the rising
it just increases our awareness
of the presence of love
as a prevailing quality
of all of life
you begin to see it in all that exists
it appears as beauty
stillness
silence
going over the mountain
yesterday the snow
and the divinity
you just see the divinity of
expressing itself as existence
in that beauty of this incredible form
when we go out
coming to your restaurant
and we begin calibrating
Chinese fortune cookies
did I mention them to you
yes or no
no
oh
well I lecture in various places
so I guess this was in
where are we in California
and Пượcка
you know everybody's worrying about truth
So I say truth is
It's just that if you have the capacity to see it, we found that Chinese fortune cookies calibrate around 350.
And as you look at one, for the first time you begin to really look at one,
you'll see something like, a kind thought can change your life forever.
Wow!
One kind thought.
They calibrate Chinese fortune cookies calibrate at 350.
A single kind word will keep one warm for years.
Let's see, will come to you by mail.
This side's in Chinese. I can't read it. Oh, here it is.
You have at your command the wisdom of the ages.
As you begin looking at Chinese fortune cookies, we calibrated them generically, they calibrate at 350,
which beats a large proportion of the world's
literature and spiritual literature.
Yeah, if you would just read Chinese fortune cookies.
Now tell him, he said, what should I do to become enlightened?
Here, this is what you do.
Call me in 20 years, tell me how it worked out. To be kind at all times,
to be kind at all times towards all of life and all of its expressions.
Do you need anything more than that? No, because as you are,
it begins to change its occurrence to you.
And what you thought was just a dumb animal, you see, is the radiance of God.
I use that word, the radiance of the source of life.
One Chinese fortune cookie, you do it consistently as a way of being is all kind of read anything,
do anything, go anywhere. You just do that as a way of being in the world.
So contemplation is owning a reality,
it alters the way you are. To be kind towards all things,
transforms all of life. Is that what it's saying? To see the truth of it, and it shines for it.
And you make it your way of life.
Make it your way of life. And as you do that, everything around you begins to get transformed.
Everything around you seems to change.
So that is our wish. That's my present to you for this coming holiday season.
It's a Chinese fortune cookie, fortune, which has the power to transform all of life.
So we'll take a break and then we'll just do questions and answers.
If I don't run a fortune cookie.
Different format today, we set up everything differently, the microphones, the cameras.
And so we'll have people come up and sit here and we can have a dialogue, discuss things.
Also, we have questions that are already presented on cards.
We'll try to answer them.
We'll try to answer everything as best we can, or at least I'll give you my response to it.
My response to it, which may not be the answer that you're looking for.
But I'll give you the response.
Some of them ask technical questions, the answer to which I really don't know.
But they're not too relevant anyway.
We'll try to sort out the relevant from the irrelevant.
See, the mind likes to think in terms of content.
And the intellect,
which is in the 400s, with the prevailing energy, which brings us all here,
is because we're all articulate, we all read, we follow reason and logic.
And we pretty much mastered, mastered in the operational sense, the mind and the intellect.
And so we're interested in what is beyond that.
The mind and the intellect will examine how it sort of developed over time in the next lecture.
You know?
We calibrated all.
The great books of the Western world.
Every contributor to the great books of the Western world.
The greatest intellects that have ever lived.
But that'll be next.
So we'll track where the intellect can take us.
So anyway, the intellect thinks up questions and we'll try to answer them.
What can a group like this, this is one of the cards, do to raise the consciousness of mankind?
And as I explained this morning, we've already done it.
Ha!
The collective intention.
To raise consciousness.
That's not our intention.
I mean, we don't all take up spiritual work in order to raise the consciousness level of mankind.
I mean, it's not your province.
Leave that for the Avatar.
That's why the Avatar is here.
That's his responsibility.
You worry about yourself.
Transcend the level of the hippopotamus.
To be kindly and loving towards all things.
To follow that Chinese fortune cookie will take you the whole way.
Because...
Each one opens the door to the next revelation.
And the next revelation, you move from that level and that takes you to the next revolution.
See, once you begin opening the doors, they open up their own.
And when you do that, you collapse the wave function.
There was a question, what does that mean, collapse the wave function?
There, on the internet, Henry Stapp, S-T-A-P-P, professor out of Berkeley, advanced theoretical
physics.
Does about as good a job.
He explained it, you know, from the potentiality, which is the Schrodinger equations, time dependent
and time independent, then arises.
That is the state of the universe.
Any condition of the universe is obviously potentially the source of the next stage,
is it not?
The fact that there I'm here, I can decipher this with the Schrodinger equations, it now
has a potential.
By exercise.
By exercise of the Heisenberg principle of observation, and especially that of intention,
I now potentiate the potential to an actuality.
Now I have a new state of the universe.
I've collapsed the wave function.
And now, to mathematically discover what's happened to my arm, you need the Dirac equations.
All that happens through the von Neumann process, process one and process two.
And if you're interested in that, read it.
It's very interesting stuff.
Very interesting stuff.
You don't need it, but it's interesting.
Here, I'm telling you how to transcend mind, and now I'm giving you all this mind fodder.
Giving me a guilt panic thing here.
Okay.
Now, the reason I like to bring those things in is because you don't have to desert intelligence.
You see, one objection of the atheist is he has to transcend confirmable, verifiable truth
and go to that ooh-la-la stuff, all that ooh-ooh-ooh stuff.
He's the director of a big clinic, not too far from here.
And any time many of the staff wanted to bring any kind of spirituality, he'd go,
all that ooh-ooh-ooh stuff.
Yeah, all that ooh-ooh-ooh stuff has stopped the greatest intellects of history.
Sir Isaac Newton at 499, Sigmund Freud at 499, Albert Einstein at 499.
So it is a great barrier.
And my job as a teacher is really how to
contextualize things so that the transcendence of the intellect becomes an automatic consequence
of the process itself.
Because the intellect is the great trap.
Very few people get beyond it.
You remember from Calvary, love is the consciousness.
Only 4% of the world's population ever gets to the level 500.
Only 4%.
And that's love, which is a different paradigm.
So you're moving from the supposedly objective intellect,
the world of content, and you're moving to the subjective.
So the movement from the describable Newtonian paradigm to the paradigm of spiritual reality
means you move from the out-there-ness of what you think life is about to the in-here-ness
of pure subjectivity, which is where life is.
Life ain't out there.
It's in subjectivity.
So we just got a new...
fire from a new conference on science and consciousness and all the intellectuals.
You calibrate the level of that particular conference.
It's about 405, 410.
You can't take an instrument that calibrates in the 400s and use that to understand a universe
that begins at 500.
It doesn't dawn on people.
It's a paradigm jump.
It's a paradigm problem.
You can't use the tools.
You can't find ghosts with Geiger counters.
You see it all the time on TV.
You know, they've got the Geiger counters, the infrared things, and looking for ghosts.
It's the wrong instrument.
It's like trying to tell the temperature with a barometer.
You know, the barometer is for something different.
So you move from the supposed out-there-ness described by Descartes as res externa,
so-called out-there-ness.
You move to the source of subjectivity because the intellect is only true to the degree that you're
experiencing it.
It's true.
So even if you worship the intellect, you're only doing so because on the subjective, it
seems to you, convincing, important, and real.
You cannot avoid subjectivity.
That's the source of the awareness of divinity within you.
So if you look to the content of mind, you'll never find spiritual reality because it's
not in the content of mind.
It's in the subjective awareness of experience.
You have the emanation of consciousness and divinity shines forth.
As awareness consciousness.
And then you can say consciousness of what?
But the of what?
This is what it's all about.
The of what-ness is irrelevant.
It's always aware of something.
So who cares what the something is?
The sense of joy is the sense of joy and it stems from the expression and experience of
its own nature.
And the ultimate source of joy is the awareness of the existence of God as the very source
of your own life.
And that's the essence of human existence every instant.
Yeah.
I don't know how I got off that, but somebody asked me a question.
Somebody asked me the correct question about the collective, you see.
So that's what happens when you start off on the intellect.
You end up just describing quantum theory.
The collapse of the wave function.
You see what happens to your mind?
It easily grabs you and sucks you in.
All right.
So let's see.
Maybe people would have some other questions, but that is a good question.
So the collapse of the wave function, it's the potential becoming the actual.
And our own spiritual intention collapses it.
And as we defined this morning, we're all influencing the consciousness level of humanity,
hopefully in a favorable way.
Hello.
My question comes from my contemplation process in
releasing judgments.
And a lifelong judgment I was raised with was judgment towards wealth.
And in reading the I.
Towards wealth?
Yeah, towards wealth and abundance.
People who control abundance.
Oh, yeah.
It's good or bad about it.
Right, right.
It's a great thing, right?
Yeah.
Yeah, it is.
Yeah, it's good.
Yeah.
So.
You can do it as long as you feel guilty about it.
That's right.
I think you have plenty of charity, huh?
Okay, good.
Well, an interesting thing happened with the death of Mother Teresa.
And learning about karmic merit.
And parallel to that, I never really thought of the collective spirit, what its level is
throughout its lifetimes.
And so it led me into a curiosity where I began trying to calibrate karmic merit.
And I don't know if any of it's accurate, but it posed really interesting questions.
So Mother Teresa came up at something like 240.
And then Oprah came up at like 500.
Yeah.
And so that made me think of the three avatars of Buddha, Christ, and Krishna.
And that Buddha had a really stunning experience in that you had said he had had many lifetimes
before and Christ had none.
And I thought that was so interesting because Buddha gave up royalty and Buddha gave up
wealth.
So it seems like wealth is the ultimate human challenge to differentiate or to actually
leave behind.
And so it gave me compassion for the wealth.
It gave me.
And understanding that that is like a very, or my thinking was it was a very advanced
experience on the earthly realm to have the karmic merit to be born into that capacity,
that ability.
So I just wondered if you could elaborate on karmic merit because I'm just kind of coming
into that knowledge through your work and its correlation to wealth.
He got loose and got out of the cage one time and experienced.
The life within the surrounding world and was shocked at what he discovered.
And that began his research is was for the explanation for old age, sickness, suffering
and death and his inner research into the nature of the ego itself really has nothing
to do with wealth as a way of observation.
You see wealth, you know, it's really a critical part of understanding, which we won't get
into today.
The great wealth.
The wealth of this country, you know where it exists, you know why this is the richest
and the powerful country in the world, not because it's the evil demon, but because wealth
comes from here.
Wealth, the mind of Thomas Edison created more wealth than the total output put total
product that most of the countries on earth, just from Thomas Edison, electricity, Henry
Ford, and they had one industry after an industry after another.
So these industries are nothing but the consequence of creation.
They're nothing but the consequence of creativity and along the way, you can get caught up
moneyness of it.
But I think most of the creative geniuses are moneyness is irrelevant, you know, because
they're so busy with the next invention.
So a whole company takes over and does that.
So Tesla, you know, when he died, this flat rope, no money at all.
He ended up discovering the alternating current.
So between Edison and Tesla and the inventor of the telephone and.
Computer chip and so America was the source of that the airport airline industry, the
automobile industry, electronics, electricity, why are things like electricity that totally
transformed the whole planet?
So the capitalist, the capitalism of this country is the capitalism of creativity and
genius.
One thought of one genius is greater than the total product of all of your.
The moneyness that arises out of that is, of course, what a physical universe does with
it, because moneyness is the trade and barter.
You know, it's hard to trade six camels for a wife anymore when you're just ready.
You can write a check, you know.
So, so, so, all right.
So it isn't wealth.
It's the attachment to wealth and the.
Right.
Perhaps ego inflation that goes with having the wealth.
Actually, wealth is very helpful if you view it as, you know, it's a time saving economy.
It's easier to walk out the front door of the hotel and go like this and have a cab
pull over than it is to walk all the way to the subway.
Yeah.
So it has certain practical advantages.
So it isn't necessary to renounce wealth.
Now, the Buddha, because he went, went within.
He saw that the world as it was presented to him was not the real world.
And he wanted to know what is the source of.
So that led him to the study of karma.
Karma, and I'll just give you the understanding of it that exists here at this time, is because
you see consciousness evolves over great eons of time, it collects onto itself learningness.
Now, evolution does not take place in the physical world.
The physical domain is where you see the expression of creation, evolution, because
evolution and creation are one and the same thing.
It is a quality of consciousness to evolve.
So the animals consciousness then plays out, plays with what it's learned.
It doesn't create an improved animal.
It doesn't create an improved grasshopper at all.
It munches it over on the etheric floor.
plane and who's out with a new creation you don't see transitory forms in the physical domain
because the transition is on the level described by sh what is it then the level of formative
causation is schildrich schildrich so evolution is occurring on the level of consciousness so
consciousness then has is within the non-physical domain within it consciousness evolves because
that's its intrinsic nature you see that the emergence of life on this planet over great
eons you just see that consciousness keeps evolving it you know up through the animal
kingdom on through mankind and on through the level consciousness levels of man by design
apparently by intrinsic
quality of nature consciousness evolves evolves it does so on the invisible level and then
emerges so the potentiality becomes an actuality by virtue of intention the unmanifest becoming
manifest has always been presumed to be the intention of divinity out of nothing appeared
everything out of the animate unmanifest appeared a universe which is infinite and
dimensional
and which grows infinitely throughout all of time and has no beginning and has no end
which the mind cannot think of the what mind cannot comprehend it has to have a beginning
and end to comprehend it so foreverness and alwaysness was what the buddha began to look
at and he began to unravel the ego by observation the mind unraveled itself by sheer observation
if you're doing to watch the mind you'll see it will slowly disintegrate but the mind is
disintegrated but just by being watched and ramada maharishi no nisargadatta maharaj
always recommended that his guru told him just watch the mind that's what he did and
after three years of watching the mind continuously it collapsed so the buddha was on a journey
of uh karmic merit growth just like everyone else and had lived many lifetimes and had
gotten to that point of wealth and uh his uh potentiality of reaching enlightenment which
is so rare you're saying it's in the 0.03 or 0.04 percent less than that so apparently
then the spirit lives on and accumulates this wisdom because that's the nature of consciousness
so if you segment off a personal spirit ego personal soul et cetera it partakes of the
same quality of the nature of consciousness itself and also learns and grows over time
over great periods of time, great eons of time.
And so we go in and out of body,
but the spirit remains the same.
So the spirit is accumulating a learningness,
a learningness over great expanses of time
until it becomes aware eventually
of the source of its own existence and its own reality.
And so that challenge of giving up the palace
is probably one of the greatest human challenges.
I guess it goes back to my original question,
is when you get to that point,
that's a fairly advanced state of karmic merit.
Yes, and it isn't wealth, it's the attachment to wealth.
Because wealth is just a useful tool.
So to Einstein or any of those people,
wealth was just a means of doing the necessary engineering.
So creativity was what they're committed to.
So the wealth of this nation is creativity itself.
Because it seems to be a society which potentiates, underlines,
and values individual creativity from Alexander Graham Bell to...
Gates.
Bill Gates.
Is that his name?
Bill.
Big Bill.
So see, all that comes out as an automatic consequence.
If you design an automobile to get you from one place to another,
the world throngs to it and wants more, so...
My observation just comes from, like you're saying,
trying to get to my own enlightenment, not so much,
to try to understand money and that,
I'm trying to understand the system in which I'm observing.
So it's as if I'm trying to gain compassion,
because I'm trying to look at everything with compassion.
And this is something I used to not look at with compassion,
so I can see the beauty and the struggle of that challenge
of the birthright to brilliance, like Gates, and brilliance and money,
and the fact that separation of money is one of the most challenging things.
And as a writer, someone who doesn't write for money,
I'm trying to understand the system in which I'm observing.
Someone who doesn't write for money,
someone who writes for the joy of being inside my head, inside my mind.
That's why Gates enjoyed computers, but there's a byproduct of that of wealth.
And the byproduct of the wealth in the human experience is,
what do you do with all of that power and be separated from it?
Well, I wouldn't say wealth is power, wealth is convenience.
Right, grace, oil on the tracks, something like that.
Society creates the wealth, the person doesn't create the wealth.
I mean, how many of you know that?
How many automobiles did Henry Ford make?
He never made one, probably.
He just made the parts.
Now, society came in and demanded it.
We want this thing.
Then society provides the workers and the incentive.
And the banks, of course, you need to make money.
So, to create an automobile factory, you've got to make money from the banks to do it.
So you could look at it as mutually beneficial to everyone.
See?
Right.
You don't see a capitalist and a worker as a perpetrator and victim at all.
That was Marx's great error, disaster's error.
Because he separated it that way, he doesn't see that everything is mutually beneficial.
Without the worker, the factory can't be there.
Without the factory, there's no way to build factories.
And without that, there's no capital.
Without that, there's no bank.
And without that, there's no grocery store.
And without that, the kid's still hungry.
I see the value in all of that.
So, I see sustainability.
I see sustainability.
I see society as mutually beneficial, a mutuality to it.
How you look at it, holographically.
From this way, politics looks wrong.
From this way, politics looks, how could you live without it?
From this way, capital looks wrong.
From this way, what would you wear today without the rich capitalist pigs?
Right.
You'd have to sew your own clothes.
I tell you, you'd be a busy person if it wasn't for all the rich capitalist pigs out there.
So, the last thing on Karmic Merit, I really enjoyed the chart that you did on the consciousness evolution.
And one of the things that helped me unravel layers of my unproductive programming, or productive, whichever it may be,
was trying to track Karmic Merit to see the expression of that life.
Like, I would love to know what Mother Teresa's Karmic Merit is versus Donald Trump's Karmic Merit,
to see where they come in and what that expression is.
Well, it's like they've de-perfected different energies within the psyche.
Right.
And it could be one can't go beyond a certain level until you've mastered it.
So, you've now created this world until you've mastered it.
So, it's one thing to leave the world, another thing to come back in and master both the spiritual and the physical domain.
And so, I just look at, these are people who've mastered this area, this area,
and maybe in the next lifetime, he's already done that one.
Like, I liken it to martial art belts or something like that.
It's just various belts.
Could be so.
Various signals.
Well, you know, I see Karmic Merit as the result of the spiritual will.
In other words, karma doesn't, you know, the scale of consciousness,
you don't fluctuate up and down the scale of consciousness from moment to moment,
because the decision of the spiritual will seems to be the one thing that steadies the boat.
You know, your karma and your consciousness level doesn't go up and down with every wave.
But the intention of your, the way you set your compass, the way you set it,
that's your Karmic Inherence, your Karmic Merit, you see.
Right.
And then you learn through experience.
All right, thank you.
Thank you a lot.
I've got an easier question.
You're describing the whole universe.
Don't count on it.
Well, my questions have to do with the ego.
I've been practicing what you teach about observing and dismantling and making a pet of the ego,
and I find that very liberating, and I thank you for that.
And that works for me.
But I'm curious about the experience that you describe as the death of the ego,
whether that's a once-for-all thing that happens at a high level that most people won't experience, or what?
You want to know?
Do you have a word about that, the ego?
I probably, if I'm honest, am imperfectionistically wanting all that there can possibly be in spirituality.
Well, what you're doing is all that's necessary.
In other words, you just dismantle the ego by familiarity, by observation, by all what you learn.
You see that it's got a spirituality.
I mean, the young man who was just here, at one time he was positionalized about, well, it's good or bad.
So now he sees that that was positionalizing it, and it's neither one.
So he transcends that.
So as you see each barrier arise, you are willing to surrender the truth to God, to whatever you want to call it.
Surrender it to devotion towards the evolution of your own consciousness, because that's really a way of worshiping God.
One's own potentiality is itself a worshipful act.
The ego then, we said it's the derivation of the evolution.
But it doesn't become really a difficulty until it acquires mind.
It's once mind that comes in, that now ego has a reborn, it's reborn.
So the animal ego is reborn.
So the prefrontal cortex then gave it a new tool for survival.
Just when it thought it was about done there with loving dogs and cats, in came the ego, and boy, the new ball game.
Because the intellect now is a whole new playground.
So the four hundreds are very difficult to transcend.
But they are for the naive person.
But once we begin to study it and see what its nature is, it becomes just something else with the same.
It wants to be right.
It wants to control things.
So we see the ego does exactly the same thing as the animal did.
It becomes competitive.
It wants to swell up with pride.
It wants to scare others.
And in the world of thinkingness, it uses thoughts as an attempt to control others.
So as you give it less and less worship, you begin to get dubious about the mind.
You begin to get...
The first step to its undoing is humility.
To begin to realize the limitations of the intellect.
As we said, the intellect can't get beyond 499.
So that's not all that impressive.
You know, there's people in this room that are well beyond 499.
They've already transcended to a different paradigm.
So once you see a thing for what it is, it loses its power over you.
And then the mind and the intellect, the style of which you've already adopted,
if you just continue it as a style, then you worry about the end of the ego.
You don't have to worry about the end of the ego because the ego is not a reality.
What you mean is the end of the illusion of the ego as reality, which appears fearsome.
You know, all that I think and believe and experience and think is factual
is based on something that is non-factual.
Now, not necessarily that way.
It's more like that which you've always felt is you,
this very core and essence of your own being, existence,
from your very first memory in life up to this very moment.
You see that that which you think is the very core, the essence of you,
the real, real, real you,
has to be surrendered to God.
And that is where the fear comes in.
It's only until that moment when you think you are beyond all doubt
is what has to be surrendered to God.
And you see only that stands in your way.
Does that happen once for all?
Happen once for all.
Meaning it's an event and then after that you don't have to have Fluffy anymore?
It's profoundly obvious that what you thought was you isn't you.
I don't know how one would reawaken it.
It takes many years to learn how to even function in the world again
with that peculiar phenomenon.
Because that which you were convinced is the core and the essence of the real you
disappears.
Instead, a presence that is all-prevailing, all-knowing,
beyond all time, etc.,
is the source of what the world would call happening.
How to remaster language and expression of a reality
which cannot really be adequately expressed in a worryingness.
If this does not happen, does the ego go on lifetime after lifetime?
That's what it does.
Until it finally does happen.
Yes, because death is not a possibility.
People don't understand karma
because they think every time you leave the body you've died
and that's the end of that story.
That's not the end of that story at all.
Does the ego go on from lifetime to lifetime?
Yes, that's what we call it. That's our languaging of it.
That energy, you see.
And the reason for that is because death is not possible.
So, the very fact that death is not possible,
what happens when the body tatters over?
There's the law of conservation of matter,
the law of conservation of energy,
which can be destroyed.
They can only take form.
I don't know why it dawned on mankind,
but it's invidious to me.
There's the law of conservation of life.
Life cannot be destroyed.
It can only transform.
Move from one form to another.
And if getting reborn in a physicality as a human
serves its progression,
then it chooses to do so.
I don't think it has to do so.
It's an option.
The basic law of the universe is not only that life is not destructible,
but that all of evolution is based on free choice, free will.
Otherwise, there's no karmic merit.
If you're forced to be merciful or else I'll shoot you,
then not too much karmic merit to that.
You have to have the option to shoot the person
and choose otherwise, then you have karmic merit.
Thank you.
I find all of your teachings very liberating.
I, like you, grew up with a scrupulously religious background.
And this is indeed liberating.
Thank you.
You don't have to become an atheist to escape it.
No.
You just get the truth by it.
First, thank you so much for making it okay to ask these questions,
because I never would have had the nerve to ask them.
And I've asked you this once before.
I asked you this a few months ago,
but I'm so stuck there that I've got to ask about it again.
I have a 32-year-old son who's struggling out there in the world,
having a hard time.
He goes up and down.
In your viewpoint.
Right, yes, true.
You're going through it with your own observation
and the deduction and conclusion that your mind jumps in with.
He's fulfilling his karmic pretension and doing exactly what he wants to.
Anyway, go ahead.
For a second, I almost saw that.
You see, because hitting bottom is the fastest way to God, I know.
People who come in with, you know, develop addictions,
they put themselves on a one-way walkway to God.
There's no way off.
You either die or you surrender to God.
Your name is the third choice.
You can't back it up and undo it.
You either surrender to God or you die of that addiction,
which means you'll come back again with the same addiction
and do it over and over again until the ego surrenders and says,
of myself, I cannot save myself.
And, of course, we see from brain physiology a marvelous diagram.
That's a factual truth of brain physiology.
Until you put in spiritual intention,
the left brain is unable to even come up with a suggestion
that you surrender to God.
And when you say, God, I need your spiritual meeting,
suddenly the right brain gets activated.
Your third brain begins to emerge, and you say,
how could I have ever thought I could do it on my own?
It's obviously an impossible tool, you know.
The great revelation.
So hitting bottom, you can't get to hitting bottom without going there.
It's nice to hit bottom from your viewpoint, see?
Read a nice book on all about it, go to Stop Being an Enabler,
and everybody recovers.
It could be this week.
It could be Sunday.
So one surrenders one's will
to control another person's karma.
Because, you see, let's say enforced sobriety has no karmic merit.
You see guys in prison.
In 35 years we're killing somebody,
within 24 hours they already killed somebody else again.
Enforced, forcing people to behave in a certain manner
robs them of karmic merit.
So what you do is pose the,
in case they've missed it somehow in our society,
you pose this as an option.
And then you walk away from it.
The more you try to put it on them,
the more they resist.
So I used to have a huge practice of addiction,
you know, back east.
By the thousands.
And people would call me up and say,
you know, tell me this story.
What can you do for Joe?
And they'd tell me all about Joe
and how he's got fire and liver's going and all.
Yeah, right.
And what can I do for him?
And I'd say, you want truth or not?
They all said they want truth but they lie.
It might possibly,
it might be possible that you're,
you're asking me an honest question.
What can I do?
I said, buy him a case of whiskey,
put him in a motel and leave him be.
And go on vacation.
Goodbye.
That's the truth, isn't it?
Buy him a case of whiskey and leave him be.
So you leave it to the nature of the illness.
It's a pathway to God.
In fact, it's one of the most effective pathways
to God on the planet today.
I think more people discovered God
through the 12 step movements
and those self-help groups
than they do through former religion anymore.
How many people do you know say,
well, I just discovered the so-and-so church,
you know, hardly ever.
Tens of millions discovered God
through the necessity,
either find God or croak.
That's where you get the message across.
Box so related.
Surrender or die
and have convulsions go insane in the meantime,
which is, you know,
you start seeing things in the air
and you're trying to eat you.
Yeah.
So you can possibly present something as an option
but not try to help.
You really hate this guy, don't you?
You're going to drive him to the real pits,
make him suffer,
helping him all the way.
What's the first step in honor?
I don't remember.
I admitted I was powerless
over other people's addictions and problems,
and I decided to surrender my will
to God.
My will to God.
That's step one.
Because without that,
you don't have the power.
You don't convince me about anything.
You haven't got the power.
You have to have been there.
Once you're there,
once you've been there,
once you, out of despair,
surrender your survival to God,
then your victory
will raise your level of consciousness.
And when you speak to it next time,
you'll speak from authority.
You've got to be there yourself.
Don't be anguished.
Be willing to surrender your fear
and control to God.
You've got to be there.
Don't be anguished.
Be willing to surrender your fear
and control to God.
And if he's going to die,
let him die.
God is empowering us
with the divinity
that you have to surrender to within,
which then has the power
to convince him.
Right through the door,
a quick call.
Just as your car
flips over the highway.
That's called foxhole.
Give me foxhole
and we'll leave you
with anything.
Be responsible, foxhole.
How does one live successfully
in the world
and at the same time
follow a spiritual path?
Well,
there's no conflict.
To see conflict
is always a duality
that's being projected.
It's to be the best
whatever you are
in the instant.
By doing that,
you are glorifying God.
Potential.
You become
the actuality
of your potentiality
to the best
of your capacity.
Dear God,
I ask
the best teacher
of this subject
that I can have
the potentiality
to be
and I can only trust
that out of that
devotion
there is
something
that I can trust
to be
the best
within
speaks
as it speaks
because
other than that
there's no intention
involved.
I couldn't care less
with people
expressing
that one
knows their thing.
So you do
the same thing.
She's like,
I gotta answer
her questions.
You give her
the same answer
to the same question
and then one day
you accept it.
She says,
God,
so you think
but it's like
we have to karmically
work our way
to a certain point.
There's a point
in life
that's pretty much
automatic.
It's just like
hitting a lot of people
couldn't work for you.
It's natural
to hate them then
and it's natural
to love them now.
In World War II
we all hated
the Japs
and the Germans.
The vets
on both sides
of each other
totally
forgave each other
50 years ago,
you know.
Quit hitting them
50 years ago,
easy.
So,
but that wasn't
an artificiality.
It was
that you now saw
the people differently.
It was out of
a valor
as mistaken
as that valor
might have been.
That they were
the best warrior
they could be.
You respect that
in them
and they respect
that in you.
And now you both
transcend it
but you can't transcend
it until you master it.
Both sides
remastered it.
walked into the bullets
willing to surrender
one's life
to God
or country
whatever.
So,
for instance
in the world of business
if you see
the people
that they
trust
can be
at who they are
Yeah.
that's a way
of being
that would allow you
to operate
in that world
but not get caught up
in it.
No,
the purpose is to wear it
like,
you know,
like you said
the light
you wear the world
lightly
and see
it's entertainment
and it's very transitory
so whatever
seems overwhelming
at the moment
you know,
and so
you try to be the best
that you can be
from moment to moment
the best husband
the best father
the best student
the best doctor
the best mechanic
big pride
and you're worth
to the company
not because
they reward you
but because
I know I've been
the best answer
both for myself
my own judgment
I feel
not theirs
I can buy and sell
theirs
I've read mine
when I got
I'm worrying about
what you think of
like yourself
you know
Goodness can be
a wonderful arena
of experience
I don't divide
the world
in the spiritual
and non-spiritual
because all of life
is spiritualized
to the degree
that you see it
as so
even if you're
the headsman
you chop off
his head
to the best
of your ability
Dear God
I pray that I
chop this man's head
precisely
going down
his spirit says
boy that was a good one
he's over
he hacks away
at you
you see life
in a certain level
then becomes
you comprehend life
on a different level
you see like
the gamesmanship
of it all
and how people
are convinced
of the reality
of it at the moment
of the game
it's a game
each one's being
supposed to be
going
that guy is
supposed to be
hating it
and he's not
what's the matter
with you
goes to be
the heck
with you
if you guys
care
about the world
you talk
about this
and you talk
about the worlds
you think
about the heavens
and you just
think
that's about
what the world
is
and you're
not
you're not
talking
the world
to the
world
I'm telling
you
that's
how
you
way to god but what does it take to learn a lesson see so we sometimes despair over the extremes
why is it so extreme ego is so tenacious you see if life only survives for millennia out of the
sheer power and the tenacity of the ego to hang on to life under extreme conditions you know there's
bacteria coming out of the molten core of the earth are the molten core of the earth so life
must have a ferociously tenacious grab so we can respect that too instead of vilifying it
be mourning it i know this guy's not going to give up i i don't know what his addiction is
but i know he's not going to give up the last thing until he strangles on it
practically his eyes bulge out and he sees things and thinks he will render
his own throat out of terror and horror then why is it so severe oh what do we do for mankind
by our collective advancement of our own spiritual awareness and knowledge we try to raise the bottom
so that people don't have to go that far more advanced consciousness of our society people
don't have to go to that extreme as they once did they hear the truth earlier in the game
so truth becomes an option now that you can choose
earlier in the game
that doesn't mean it will be chosen earlier but presented to you as an option and now you have the
karmic uh option then you could have you could have done it a while ago or sympathy at the bottom
of the barrel because you had the option you had the option how extreme the ego gets is just really
mind-boggling look at the green river killer how many people 38 people in a row
does it take 38 for some
interactive chronic lesson ego so tenacious because it's the very source of the survival of life on
this planet its tenacity had to be extremely powerful so that will to existence is you know
on the one hand the source of our survival support of our survival on the other hand when it attaches
itself to non-truth it becomes a formidable enemy enlightenment is extremely rare you get to the 500s
is extremely rare you just you know get to love newton einstein and flory couldn't make it this is
the time couldn't make it there's no point in beating your own breath poor me i can't make it
no it's a willing to surrender to divinity to love and to the reality of subjectivity
it's a willingness to surrender to a journey fortunately person has the humility to see the
wisdom of that and thunder their life to it i'll tell you they're three quarters away already