contrasting calibrations.
We have some things that don't calibrate
as well. Fatalism 110,
secularism 195, accidentalism,
mechanistic reductionism.
It's bad to make them wrong,
but they're very bad.
Trying to reduce everything to the
complete absence of
spirituality, atheism 185, agnosticism
195, Dionetics 195. Meline Murray I
thought was interesting because her life
was so catastrophic
and she managed to take u prayer out of
the classroom
was one of the most hated uh people one
of the hated most hated Americans that
ever lived and her own life was actually
a terrible disaster towards the end 95
then so there's a I get something from
somebody who says he's a master of the
course of miracle 65 then there's muon
That's a mutual UFO network. They get
together with and compare uh UFO
experiences 155
a local lecture the coming of 10 the
extraterrestrials. So these all these
predictions of end of the world
and extraterrestrials all calibrate low.
There are somebody's fantasy,
imagination,
residual LSD left in their tea,
whatever.
They have no reality. So I'm not saying
they couldn't. Therefore, we didn't
scoff at anything or refuse because
mankind is still rudimentary in its
evolution.
We are still rudimentary. The evolution
of man homo sapien is still we have
permission to ask this is still
extremely rudimentary.
We are rudimentary folks.
more you study consciousness, the
evolution of you realize we've just got
our head out of the water.
We're just
primitive.
You realize that we belong to a race
that doesn't know the difference between
truth and falsehood.
You realize the implication of that?
That's why you can't make anything
wrong.
were born with the lack of a capacity to
tell truth from falsehood. If that's the
case, how can you fault anybody? This
lady who allowed this man to die through
her windshield,
she went off and got stoned and had sex
or whatever while he's dying and
bleeding all the garage. When you look
at her, you can tell how responsible is
this entity.
I mean, she's not even there, right? IQ,
what? 75. I don't think she even gets
what it's about. Stoned at the time as
well. How responsible is an entity at
that? Did that person have free choice?
Not what you and I call free choice.
That person probably dimly was aware of
what the possibilities were.
So I look at
karmic consequence, spiritual
responsibility
within the context of where man is at
the present time.
When man had no compass, he got lost all
the time.
How many sailors are at the bottom of
the sea for lack of a compass? We never
asked that one. Can we ask that one?
For the lack of a compass, lack of
navigation.
How we have permission to ask this? It's
over 10,000, 20,000, 40,000, 60,000,
100,000,
90,000, 95,000.
Right? 95,000 people dead at the bottom
of the sea for lack of a compass.
So how harsh can our judgment be about
chocolate and vanilla
if the person lacks taste buds?
Idiot doesn't know that vanilla
chocolate. Why would he?
So out of that compassion for the
ignorance of man, we now understand what
Jesus Christ meant and what the Buddha
meant that there's only one sin. sin in
quotes and that is ignorance.
Because of his profound ignorance, he
needed a savior. He needed the great
teachers and the great avatars
were the only sources of truth. There
was no other source of truth.
No source of truth anywhere. You ask a
bear, he doesn't know. You ask a tree,
it doesn't know. You ask your neighbor,
they don't know.
Ask your teachers at school. They don't
know. Look up the encyclop encyclopedia
bratanica. It doesn't know. Look on the
internet. It isn't there.
What's your rally factor?
So where has man
been? Where could he go without a
compass, without any kind of truth to
guide him? No. So we're very grateful
that we exist today. Although maybe our
karmic responsibility now goes up. Uh
oh.
Yes. Maybe our karmic responsibility now
does go up that we know that it is
possible to discern truth from falsehood
that the way has been
uh mapped at least a rough map that such
a discernment is possible
and that it's available to people who
value it.
Jesus said, "Don't throw your pearls
before a swine." And we get the people
who calibrate that. I never liked that
quote because it sounds insulting, but
maybe in those days swine were just, you
know, nice animals like sheep and cattle
didn't mean anything insulting.
But not to give it to those who fail to
appreciate it. And people who calibrate
less than 200 really can't use uh this
particular technique. But what they
could do is ask people who can for the
answers. uh they can read the books in
which all this is calibrated. And
so
uh
so there we go down the fairy new age
festival we said was 45.
Talking to angels is sort of an iffy
thing. Um people write me glowing
letters about things that I know
calibrate like 140 or 90 or something
and I really don't know what to say to
them.
They've they've put all their faith and
emotional commitment and investment in
something that calibrates, you know,
like near death or something. What can
you say about it?
The former Raj Nishis, you know, by
their own history,
which is the survivors of the Nash
Nishes, were the ones who like poisoned
the community water so they'd all get
sick and they could outvote them. So
you could say, "By their fruits, you
shall know them." So certainly unless
one is spiritually extremely
one would get that those people would be
below 200. Newians are are those people
uh that fellow in France they're waiting
for various things. Then there we notice
a lot of things that are called new
thought or or peace. There's all kinds
of organization
uh the universal world foundation
college university and uh something or
other of peace and you calibrate it's
like 160. They're all about 160 150 and
you find out they have nothing to do
with spirituality. They don't mean peace
like the peace of God. They don't mean
peace as a level of consciousness.
They're talking about politics. Oh,
that's not a spiritual organization. So
you get misled thinking, oh this is a
wonderful sounding spiritual
organization going to save the world and
have peace universal peace foundation or
something. You all got great names. The
universal peace and humanitarian
foundation. You calibrated 155. You know
what I'm saying? See how can it be such
a disparity between the stated purpose
in the name and what they actually are?
It's because they're spiritual pressure
groups and they're very much into
chocolate and hate vanilla.
So, okay, animal psychics. We ask,
they're on the animal channel, and we
ask, "Is this lady really a psychic?"
Because I've known a few animal psychics
that seem to have something on the wall.
And I said, "No, it's more like a circus
act. It's entertainment."
And we said, "Were colonics the best way
to God?" And we got there 195.
things that focus on purifying the body
are well-intentioned but naive.
Taking uh blood purifiers and colonic
irrigations and following strict
physical hygiene and all is extremely
good for the body and I no doubt that it
is fine for the body. However, you
remember from the course of miracles
this says you're only subject to what
you hold in mind. So if you think that
such a thing is injurious to you, it
will be by virtue of the fact that you
believe it will be because in and within
itself it has no power.
The power of belief then is what you
project onto a belief system and you
give it power over you. If you think a
certain thing is going to kill you, then
please don't do it because it will kill
you.
On the other hand, it's a good way to
pick how you want to go.
>> Well, you reach a certain age, you begin
to wonder, I mean, how do you get out of
here?
As people get older, they keep closing
one door after another. You know, you
used to get out of here with Dther
Theory, bang, polio, bang. All these
exits out of here have been closed off
one after another. You're stuck here
till you're at least 80 now.
Likely 90 96 would not be unlikely.
You say, "How do we get out of here,
folks?
I don't know."
All right. Animal psychics colonics.
There's a very weird It's also on the
internet. You pick up some of this on
the internet. It's sent to us. Anti-US
corporation movement which pictures all
um capitalism as evil. This is also part
of the uh universal peace kind of
movement which sort of pictures that the
antichrist is American industry.
Of course, what we say is that
a free country has brought the most
advanced economy
uh and opportunity as is possible
probably in the human domain right now
and it has a consciousness level at 421.
So the free enterprise system then which
benefits all of society. So there's no
point of demonizing industry when what
you wear is made by industry. What you
eat is made by industry. Your haircut is
done through industry. Your eyeglasses
are industry. You're breathing in and
out through what's produced by industry.
You're standing on what introduc and
here's a building produced by industry.
Speaking on the microphone. So what
about your your debt to industry? Dear
God, I give thanks for industry and what
it has provided for me. Look what I've
done. All I do is stand here and I
benefit,
you know, by the efforts of mankind
generation after generation. So all of
us are blessed by the sweat and output
and suffering of all the generations
that preceded us. We take for granted
what to another person would be
miraculous and is still denied to
twothirds of the world at least.
Those people that we were looking at the
map can't go and buy this. I've been in
their country. I've been in the f what
they call them fllas on the side of the
mountain
in Brazil in Rio de Janeiro
where if you've got a couple of strings
and a twig and an old rag maybe the top
of a piece of tin can that's where you
and your 12 brothers and sisters live
and you take turns sleeping
on the side of the mountain
and there on the side of the mountain is
the great statue of Jesus Christ looking
over all
So before you curse American industry,
look at its opposite.
Look at its opposite. Starvation,
malnutrition, agony, suffering. There's
no medicine for their sickness. There's
no coding to make their broken leg feel
better.
So
we can be grateful to our own culture,
our own society.
We can be grateful for it and say it's
got chocolate and vanilla and
it doesn't fly without wings, but it
doesn't necessarily have to. It'll serve
us for the moment.
So that's the anti-corporate. This is
the DNA promises of God. I don't know.
We just took it out of local ads
190.
You see these things on television, the
telephone psychics who get on there and
give you a reading right off the bat.
They calibrated at 95.
At $20 a minute, their job is to keep
you on the phone as long as possible and
get you intrigued with these wonderful
stories.
New age shamanism is very iffy. And here
was another local, this is just a local
ad. This every time I see a quarter
pager with all kinds of fancy gibberish
about it, I know it's where about it's
going to be. And teach schools that
teach shamanic
magic again are also questionable. Why?
Because they're appealing to
superstition. Um people think spiritual
means uh the occult really uh mysteries
and magical things. They are impressed
by the so-called miraculous.
Well, the miraculous
first of all is not something you do.
There isn't anybody that that performs
the miracle. Ain't nobody that performs
a miracle.
What happens is this lady sits down
across from you at a table. She's
paralyzed in one side. You don't know
why she's here. The friends look over at
you expectantly and then telepathically
you get what they're hoping for.
You look back at the lady and she either
gets better or she doesn't get better.
If she gets better, then the stories go
out.
It's got nothing to do with you. That
energy plus her karma is transformative
and the miraculous occurs or it doesn't
occur but it does so of its own nature
as the effect of the field.
So it it's a field effect. See there's
no you that performs a miracle because
that's dualistic. The field then brings
about into manifestation the
potentiality which is karmically there.
and she looks at you and she smiles and
you realize that she's all right.
It's simple. Remember that the way to
God is through joy,
givingness, surrender.
Say no to selfishness, personal gain. If
a 100 people genulect when you walk by,
watch out because you're that spiritual
ego. You have to be alert for it at all
times. alert for it.
See, because the more involved you
become, the more attractive you become
to people.
People think that they're in love with
and attracted to and love you. If you're
naive, you will believe that. No, it's
the presence of God within you that they
are in love with.
It's the presence of God within you, you
see, reflected back to you. It is not
the mirror that you're in love with.
And many of these fell because they fell
in love with the mirror and the teacher
thought
took personally the adulation on a
personal basis instead of seeing that
the worshippers were worship worshiping
the presence of God which you are only
an avenue.
to think that it's you.
So even if you do the course of
miracles, you will see people will be
far more attracted to you than they used
to be. They want to be in your presence.
They feel high. They feel joy.
And the idea would naturally be it's
because of you. It's me, Pete, or me,
Susan, that's doing that to them. No,
it's the presence of God within. So,
you've removed the barriers to the
presence of God. And now that is what
they're attracted to. They're not
attracted to you. You're the same idiot
you always were.
As proven by all the fallen gurus, isn't
that correct? You were the same idiot.
You all you didn't know any better. You
thought it was you.
Oh, golly. All right. All right. So,
let's look at some of the better things
of life.
Uh, the great cathedrals, Westminster
Abbey, Shark Cathedral, Notredam
all 790. The great Buddha of Coyota 780,
the Taj Mahal, its sheer beauty alone,
750. The Al This is misspelled. The
Alhham Humber, that's my fault. A L H A
M B R A 720 Basilica of St. Peter in
Rome, 710.
Beneath the Basilica of
St. Peter are some relics of one of the
great apostles and we asked are they
true relics and the answer is yes they
are indeed much like the relics that
came through here of the Buddha turned
out to be 900
um the chapel of the holy cross here in
Sedona 565 no wonder it's attractive the
Ganges river by sheer worship of the
Hindu followers is 560 stone Stonehenge
599, the Vatican itself 570, the PA 590,
Angor Watt 550, Lords 510, Pyramids of
Egypt 520, and the Great Sphinx 520.
Uh, here's another misspelling. It
should be the great Buddha now to which
the Afghanis blew up. the great uh
Buddha in Afghanistan which was the
biggest in the world uh did calibrate at
St. Patrick's Cathedral New York City
now the biggest cathedral biggest church
the cathedral in the world the Cathedral
of St. John the Divine in New York City,
which is still unfinished even though
it's they've been added 100 years is
5:30. The Washington National Cathedral,
which Betty was telling us about uh she
said it was exquisite. 530.
This is Romano Mahari's Anen Chula
mountain. I can't pronounce it. He
always has thought there was something
divine about that mountain and never
left it his whole life. Calibrated 500.
Those of you who have been to
Machapicho, it's at 510.
Those of you who have been to see the
great temple at Carneak, 4:15. The
Crystal Cathedral in LA is 410.
The Sakya Monastery in Tibet 390. Lassa.
What is the energy of Lassa itself
currently? 320.
Now we come to what people give up so
much to reach Mecca and Madina, the holy
cities of Islam. 205 and 225.
It'd be better to go go up Mount
Everest.
460.
The relics of Christian saints 750.
Shinto shrine 650.
Tibetan Buddhist stupa in Sedona,
Arizona is already 640 which is quite
amazing is it not?
That's right here in Sedona. 640. Are we
in Sedona? Yes. Yeah, we are. Okay.
>> Relics of the Buddha. There's We a
class, went out and calibrated. Uh we
calibrated in class and we found out
what it was. We all left class and went
over.
He said, "Anything is 905. We're going
there and visited." It was true. And at
the same time, the relics of St. Peter
allegedly under the floor of the
Basilica in Rome is actually a fact and
they do in fact calibrate at 910.
There's two relics we've been able to
verify. The Buddha and amazingly St.
Peter.
Now contrasting calibrations out of
spiritual curiosity. We're going to stop
in exactly five minutes and take a break
and after that we'll have questions and
answers in law for recovery.
The shroud of Trin is a true relic. It
says no. Crop circles are due to
extraterrestrials. It says no. Crop
circles are actually a human product. It
says yes. Area 51 in Nevada. I mean,
it's always on TV with a spook music.
Area 51 Nevada is actually only 2011.
>> All right. So, some things we did
discover of interest. In other words,
Area 51 is not, you know, 85 or
something. you know, it's not full of
secret uh aliens in their secret weapons
or something. So, that's an imaginary uh
program there. All right. The Easter
Island statues are a mystery. Nobody
ever really knew what they want were.
People have mystified about them and we
calibrated them. Let's just do it again.
Want to do them? No. Okay. She doesn't
want to do them. These are island
statues actually come out at 70. These
are these big monolithic things that
face out the sea. Okay, if you read
about I didn't understand it until you
read about the history of the Easter
Islands, what preceded that and then now
you get why they're 70.
It's a very interesting story. the
society that lived on Easter Island ate
up everything and everyone until it was
all gone and left and these are the
um so we don't know anything about it
except that
um they were 70 current Bethlehem people
you know go to great sacrifice to visit
the holy lands good luck
current e Bethlehem is at 70 Jerusalem
is at 100 the holy lands in Gentler at
70, Israel 190, Palestine weigh 185, and
you would do better to go to the
playground in Central Park, which is at
least 400.
It's obvious why those energies are so
far down because they've been the focus
of hatred, hatred, jihad, and all the
rest.
Uh the US court ruling under God
violates the First Amendment
is false. It does not violate the first
amendment.
But the energy that would like to see
that come about is at 185, which is
non-intigorous.
>> So let's remember then simply that the
way to spiritual truth is through
the joy of the source of one's own
existence.
It doesn't come from elsewhere.
It comes from the knowingness
that existence would not be possible
were it not for the source of one's own
existence.
And the proof of the existence of God
and the proof of the reality of God is
your own existence where nothing can
come into existence except out of
creation which requires a creator.
that we'll take a break and then after
the break we'll have questions and
answers and any further discussion and I
thank you for your forbearance and
patience this afternoon for some of you
it was a bit of a trial but we'll all
survive
so we've done enough presentation of
data everybody is in a overwhelm and
therefore I thought we would just do
questions and answers
at the end of which time
Um I'll be happy to greet all of you who
came and wanted to greet me and know
we'll u can sign books whatever like
that.
Of course the number of questions that
the mind can manufacture are endless.
To begin with we will answer a lot of
questions at once.
There is no answer to the question why.
The question why requires omnipotence
and when you're omnipotent
you know that the question why is
unanswerable.
Why? Because it exists only as a
mentation.
When people ask why this, why that?
It's because that's how evolution came
out in a certain expression.
People ask for instance, is ADHD
a spiritual condition or is it a medical
condition for which you need medication?
Having treated thousands, I would say
it's a medical condition that requires
medication without which the child will
suffer rejection, guilt, anxiety,
will be punished, ridiculed by their
children, excluded.
He will be so savaged by the side
effects of the disorder that it's not
worth having the disorder.
And if it was a spiritual condition, it
would be karmic, wouldn't it?
So
although though there's some com I think
a popular book that popularizes some
particular view of it non-medical
being both spiritual and medical and a
psychiatrist for 50 years I would say
with my child I would put him on
medication that would allow him to be
normal so that he can operate at his
fullest capacity
and there's nothing special about it.
People tend to make something special
about ADHD.
If you got diabetes, you take insulin.
You know, if you got other disorders,
you take something for it. If you got
asthma, you take anti-pasmmonics. So,
what is so special about ADHD? I don't
see anything uniquely special about it.
Without it, the child is obviously going
to fail, feel guilt, sense of
inferiority.
What happens is they end up
traumatized by the conse not
as a result of the conse No, not as a
result of the disorder, but as a result
of the social
impact of the disorder.
The same is stuttering.
You have not only stuttering, but you
have years of being ridiculed for being
stuttering. So, if there was a pill that
cured stuttering,
I would take it, wouldn't you?
What is the purpose of a disorder when
so the evolution of consciousness you
know is it evolves into medical
you might say medicine is part of the
good karmic inheritance of mankind that
he no longer suffers from the things
which he used to suffer from.
Most of the diseases that I studied and
treated and was responsible for in the
early days of my own early days of
medicine no longer even exist.
They don't kill anybody because they
they aren't even there. Nobody dies of
the or typhoid or anything. They used to
come in and die on you, dehydrate and be
dead before you could
get back to them. Um so there seems to
be a positive karmic inheritance of
mankind as a result I think of the
evolution of consciousness. The
spiritual work of all the of everyone
lifts all of mankind
and the karmic inheritance is we keep
discovering new cures for new things all
the time. And I have a couple of
patients who have never recovered from a
couple of simple things. And I tell him,
at the rate at which the pharmaceutical
industry is pouring money into these
discoveries, don't forget the discovery
of any single common ailment is worth
multi-millions, if not billions of
dollars, you can be sure they're going
to find a cure for it.
Uh so just hang on until the cure
appears. So I try to energize that
thought form that a cure for whatever
you're not recovered from so far will
appear will appear. So that's how things
appear, aren't they? They held they're
held as a possibility in human
consciousness
out of
out of compassion for the suffering of
mankind and that in that way they tend
to manifest. So the doctors in the
audience remember most of the things you
don't see syphilis anymore people
waiting in line for injections with
arsenic.
Uh they used to be lined up around the
corner, the veterans arsenic shots and
other doctors
for hopeless syphilis and um General
Parises of the Insane was the first
mental disorder I had treated at the
Milwaukee County Asylum for the Insane.
It was called It was called the
That was the name of it. They didn't
deal in euphemisms in those days.
And I told you I also interned at the
Hospital for the Ruptured and Crippled
in Brooklyn.
That was the name of it. Hospital of
ruptured and crippled.
I mean, you know, there wasn't this uh
feeling uncomfortable neurotic
sensitivity that pervades people now.
You know, they can't mention if you're
male or female or if you're short or
long or what your religion is or how far
you went in school, all those things.
Somebody's going to get feel
uncomfortable about it, you know.
There's a book out and I'll call
something the thought police anyway
tells you
how these big publishing houses screen
especially in the academic world
anything that might be taken as
offensive by anybody. So their books are
getting smaller and smaller
find that be four or five pages because
something everywhere is going to make
somebody nervous. You see that is really
your problem and to project it onto
society of course is one of the great uh
less integrous movements of current
society. You know if something makes me
uncomfortable we have to remove God from
any mention in society because it makes
some people uncomfortable.
Never dawn on them that removing God
from any reference in society makes me
uncomfortable. You understand?
The fact that removing it makes 70% of
the population uncomfortable doesn't
dawn on the egocentric person who says
because it makes me comfortable. All
street cars should be removed from the
streets. All buses should stop. Train
whistle should stop.
Because it makes me uncomfortable.
The people that are made uncomfortable
by the factual events in society need a
psychiatrist. That's what we're for.
That's what we're for, folks. If it
makes you uncomfortable, call us up.
Don't forget, psychiatrists make a lot
of people uncomfortable, and I'm sure
they would like to.
On the other hand, people who don't see
psychiatrist and need to make a lot of
other people uncomfortable. So
what makes me uncomfortable is people
who are made uncomfortable.
I feel very uncomfortable about people
that are always uncomfortable
because you know you're going to make
them uncomfortable. It's just a matter
of time.
Even mentioning that there's people who
are made uncomfortable by everything
already makes them uncomfortable and
they're going to complain and ask for a
new law to block people from making
references to people who get
uncomfortable
because to do so makes them
uncomfortable. You understand? So we end
up into this
nonsensility
which keeps the trial lawyers societies
going.
So we have some questions and hopefully
some answers.
>> What is the cause of addiction chemical
and behavioral? And what is the
solution?
>> Good god.
The answer to that is uh you have to go
to an Elanon meeting and they'll tell
you
there's genetic karmic has to do with
brain chemistry has to do with genes
both addiction and depression t are
genetically linked a family with a lot
of depression also usually that has a
good deal of addiction in it and they're
very often crossed and
uh you know having treated 10,000
alcoholics And uh I knew Bill Wilson
back many years ago and then ran a
clinic in the east where we treated tens
of thousands literally
um
and in uh out here one day a week. I
spent all day one day a week for 10
years treating addiction. So from that
experiential background, one can say
there certainly seems to be a genetic
disorder. It certainly runs in families
and it's certainly a lifestyle and it
certainly the the rate of addiction
increases as your ancestors come closer
and closer to the North Pole.
If your ancestors come from Scandinavia,
the likelihood is extremely higher than
if they come from Italy or Spain or the
Mediterranean. So there's genetic,
ethnic, I'm sure there's karmic reasons.
A lot of people I know a number of
people who died of alcoholism one death
after another and finally they came
back. Yeah, I know of one and the sixth
round of a lifetime of addiction. They
finally surrendered it to God and became
sober. Don't forget sobriety was not
accomplishable before the 1940s.
Nobody ever recovered from alcoholism.
And when they did, they were such an
oddity that they were written up as sort
of a medical oddity. And
we owe the recovery from addiction to
the humility of the Swiss psychoanalyst
Carl Young. Because when Roland, who was
wellto-do, went to see Carl Young in
Switzerland for psychoanalysis,
he finally stopped drinking and
went back to America. After a short
time, Roland got drunk again and became
severely depressed and he went back to
see Carl Young in Switzerland and Young
think we all are thankful for his
humility. He said, "Alas, unfortunately,
neither my art nor my science can be of
help to you. However, it has been
reported from time to time throughout
history that there are those who have
thrown themselves wholeheartedly into
some spiritual organization and they
have recovered. I think at the time was
an atheist. So it was not exactly great
news.
Roland came back to America and he
discovered the group uh that uh formed
the essence of the 12 steps of AA. I
forget what the name of the group was at
the time
and Roland threw himself wholeheartedly
into this spiritual group to surrender
everything to God and to
honestly honestly etc. what became I
think they were at that time only eight
steps. They became eventually 12 and
Roland conveyed this to Evie who
recovered and Evie then gave the message
to Bill W.
who u scoffed at it and said it was
ridiculous
because Bill was an atheist and he was
not ready to hear anything about the god
business
and he told Ebby don't come back about
this god business and uh and then Bill
had a great black despair and he
listened to what Evie had said and being
an atheist at the time he surrendered to
only what he could assume would be God
and then went through a profound
transformation in which The room lit up
with a holy light.
The energy field of that moment has
saved millions of lives and will save
million more. So that one instant which
I never calibrated but it's obviously
over 700 or so radiated out through all
of society. So you see what I say that
each one who reaches a high low, Bill W
himself who an atheist suddenly went
into the presence and through him
radiated sufficient energy for millions
of people to recover from hopeless
diseases of all kinds. And of course the
basic principles of spiritual honesty
are now utilized in many of man's
disorders from anger management from
child molestation
uh to all kinds of acts of brutality and
hopeless sociological
disorders.
So what the person who enters a 12step
group is really hoping for is the
miraculous
and hope and because cal aa calibrates
at 540
the miraculous is quite possible and it
happens with sufficient frequency that
it's become the greatest organization of
its kind in history.
It's the energy field of AA that
calibrates at 540. So once the person
attends the meeting and and links up
psychically with the group they recover
they recover because of the field. The
person himself is probably about 140
140 but the field is 540. So as long
he's so he's sustained by the field. So
but that is not his own level of
consciousness. It's a borrowed level. So
he's under the protective umbrella of
the group karma, the group
consciousness. So long as he stays
aligned and committed with the group,
the sobriety persists without any energy
or effort. Person never even thinks of a
drink. Life is smooth, beautiful. Then
the ego comes back and says, "You don't
need a anymore." And therefore, he walks
away from the 540.
If the energy fueled of the recovered
person is over 540, he doesn't need to
go to meetings anymore. But if it's
under 540, which is the great likelihood
probably 99.9% of the time, The minute
he walks away from the group, he
relapses and now the agony is worse. So
because the more advanced you are
spiritually, the more grave is the
consequence of a mistake.
>> As one progresses spiritually, how does
one distinguish revelation from ego
creations?
>> Ego creation. Well, revelation is a
peculiar experience.
Uh it's like advanced intuition in a
way.
It's a nonverb. First of all, it's
nonverbal. The ego verbalizes.
It's a nonverbal knowingness which
arises spontaneously from the field.
It's a knowingness. It's g n o s i s.
It arises from the field. From the ego.
It's arising from here. From here. It
arises in form in logic.
The knowingness has no words to it.
One time in walking out in the field
there suddenly came out of nowhere
because there was no thinking about it
like the revelation of the totality of
human suffering throughout all of time.
The totality of the all of it, allness
of it of such immense dimension that it
cannot be described even at this moment.
Just it was the knowingness of it like a
great overwhelming
recall those things before a tornado.
A knowingness that revealed itself in
that moment. this intense devote because
I was
an intensed Christian,
an acolyte,
voice, soprano, all the rest.
Suddenly
the belief in God went
disappeared just like that.
any god that could allow the totality of
that
because I thought God created that. So I
held God responsible for the total agony
of the creation of the collective
consciousness of the ego.
A grave spiritual mistake. And that
knowingness that it was the ego that
created the total suffering of mankind
and not God
was like telepathically transmitted. And
in that moment, the patient got up and
stood and walked away like normal.
And the nurses and all would faint when
they saw all this kind of stuff.
So it was neither purposeful nor
intention nor was there any
verbalization.
In that case the bringing forth of that
awareness was itself spontaneous and
nonverbal. There was no verbalization.
It was like the presentation of a
picture and the patients own spirit saw
the picture and forgave God and
came out of hell because when they came
in they were in hell.
It was their moment of salvation from
hell.
So realization revelation occurs of its
own energy. It's a presentation. It
comes to you. It's not something you
seek and find.
It's like a gift.
because it's a gift. One can take no
credit for it because you were thinking
about squirrels maybe at the moment and
all of a sudden all of that disappeared
and the infinite presence of God reveals
itself as though everything
is turned on to the technical and three
dimension and the significance and the
meaning and the reality of that which it
is because all stands forth as an
expression of God.
comes forth of its own.
If it comes from the ego, there's a
thinkingness that precedes it or
accompanies it. Or there's a
verbalization, all which I've just said,
I put into words. But the experience of
it is totally wordless.
And if you look at the beauty of a
setting sun, there's no words about it.
In fact, anything you can say about it
is enormous detraction.
It's just a total experience of stunning
beauty which has no words for it.
What is a parent's responsibility and
what can parents do in guiding their
children about uh the violence and video
games and TV and all of that?
>> That's a tough one.
>> I am very glad I don't have children
right now.
>> Huh?
Society is being attacked in two
dimensions.
It's only the spiritual power of groups
such like such as this to prevent it
from being destroyed.
It gets it from the luciferic by the
distortion of logic and reason and
misrepresentation
of facts and demonization of that which
is integrous
as we saw this morning when we
calibrated some of those things. It gets
it from the satanic energy
which is that of violence, seduction,
rape, beheading people, serial murder,
the joy of killing.
It's sometimes expressed quite subtly. I
was quite dismayed to find a new woman's
group called B.
And the purpose of the group was to
learn how to go out in the field with
shotguns and kill feeasants and be just
like men.
The number of fallacies involved there
is stacked upon each other. See,
first of all, they picked if that is
supposedly masculine,
it's lowest expression. If you want to
be like a man, don't pick his lowest
denominator. Try to pick the highest.
They picked the lowest denominator
because the women were enjoying the
death of the feeasants. In fact, they're
practicing holding the feeasant in it
their hands as it took 15 minutes to die
and sharing the experience of feeling
its squirming death spasms. I thought
this is manly grotesque, you know,
really grotesque
and cloaked on the idea of first of all
that the feminine is inferior to the
masculine which is bizarre and a
delusional distortion of truth to begin
with.
Yeah.
Why rise above that which you are not?
So that's a false
straw man to begin with. In the world I
grew up, nobody ever considered a woman
less than a man that I ever noticed. You
said anything disrespectful in front of
your grandmother. God help you.
I tell you who ranked in the home.
Frank. Frank don't your the drapes. My
grandfather walked through and he hide
his pipe like this. He walk through the
living room. My grandmother would be
after Frank, Frank, the drapes. And then
she'd wave the drapes and she'd want the
smoke in the drapes. You know,
he was confined to his smoking room. You
know what I'm saying? So, the illusion
was a socioeconomic distortion because
she wasn't out in the workplace. Well,
she wasn't supposed to be out in the
workplace. You died of shame if your
wife had to go to work. And I don't know
if a single woman's interest in their
job. She feel very badly for the poor
old Spinster lady who has to work.
So we grew into that which was the
social expectation of the time. Each one
of us perfectly fulfilled whatever was
the expectation of the time. One thing
was not better than another. What was
the question?
>> Huh?
>> Are you going to tell our
>> what?
Huh?
Good idea.
>> So, I don't know. Maybe maybe
>> is a calibration that you come into the
world with the one you left in your last
incarnation.
>> I never asked that. Um I would assume
that you spent some time in the inner
planes
and could have made some progress there.
I don't know. I never asked that. I
don't even know if we have permission to
ask that. Uh let's see. We have
permission to ask that in public.
Okay. Between lifetimes, one has the
opportunity for spiritual advancement.
Resistance. I guess we have the
Yeah.
I don't know.
>> What does healthy sexuality look like?
>> Look like
Looks like a lot of fun if you ask me.
People wonder what sexuality calibrates.
It calibrates about 205.
Also, money calibrates 20 around. So it
seems that that which is necessary for
physical survival and the expression of
physicality and having a human body such
as eating and things like this
calibrated at a rather neutral level
like 200 to 205.
The reason it has a bad reputation in
certain spiritual groups is what they
mean is the attachment to it. The
attachment being run by it. Being run by
that energy field.
um
as an expression of devotion and love.
The mutual experience of pleasure is
nothing but you might say
a beneficence to each other like a
blessing to each other or reaffirmation
of
loving each other. You say intimacy and
closeness when it becomes a pursuit
driven driving a person then you're
being run by it. So anything collecting
antiques is the same. You can be run by
it, you know, collecting pancakes.
>> Collecting old tools. Well, all right.
Collecting old tools can also be in a
session.
That's how you can hardly get in the
tool room. All these wonderful old
antique tools, you know.
Well,
so these things are amusements, they're
proclivities, they're hobbies.
So the traditional view is um
that the downside of anything is one's
attachment to it and the ascribing of
magical qualities to that which is which
is not so. It's only a projection, a
glamorization. So what we see is the
glamorization and the exploitation of
sexuality
which is a different story than actual
sexuality. Yeah. Sexuality is certainly
a delightful pleasure without which
there would be no human beings on the
planet
be the end of the race. So I guess it
must be okay or we wouldn't be here.
Yeah.
Created by God. And uh the physicality
then is merely the expression of
um a physical craving or an emotional
commitment. So it can be one of many
things.
And of course everything is the karmic
consequence of everything is determined
by the spiritual intention behind it. So
it isn't the sexuality, it's the
spiritual intention behind it. To
exploit the weak, to take advantage of
people, to slip on sleeping pills and
have violent sex with them while they're
unconscious are obviously
severe perversions of what should be a
natural instinct.
Yeah. And people in spiritual work go
through a couple of things. It's first
comes vegetarianism and then the next
comes celibacy.
And I think celibacy and vegetarianism
are wonderful and you should do them.
Why did everybody leave the room?
It's because of its meaning to you. If
you think that you're killing, you see,
if you believe in death, then you think
that this animal is being killed for you
and now you can't eat an animal because
you believe in death. You think it just
died.
Same with sexuality if you think it's
evil and etc etc. So these things as you
evolve u in consciousness have different
meanings and significance. So you can't
say anything's right or wrong. You can
say does it serve your spiritual
progress at this point or does it not
serve it. There may be a point at which
you feel guilty about sex and it's not
serving it. However then you have to get
off the guilt about the sexuality. So
the same with thinking that you're
killing things in order to in order to
eat them.
Killing feeasants for fun is like
shooting prairie dogs for fun. I think
that's a perversion of the sporting
instinct.
Man, like every other animal has sort of
an innate desire to kill things. And
it's one of the things we transcend.
When you think that 40 million
Buffalo roam the plains and there's not
one left. Not one. You say out of 40
million. There's got to be one buffalo
somewhere.
We hunted all over Sedona. We didn't
find one. All over Yeapai County, all
over Arizona.
Out of 40 million magnificent creatures.
Man did not leave even one. No, not one
wild buffalo love. Not one.
>> What do you do if it's obvious that many
of your immediate and extended family
members are below 200?
>> That is a problem. You're adopted.
That's what it is. You're adopted.
>> No, it it is a problem. It is a problem
especially in 12step groups where one
person is forced by the severity of the
calamity to
uh join a spiritual group and they are
obligated and to become intensely more
spiritual or die under the duress of
either you surrender to God and
and learn to be honest etc. or croak. A
lot of people choose God.
They then become quite spiritually
oriented. They start telling about easy
does it, live and less live, first
things first, forgive instead of
revenge. And this can put you at
considerable disparity and it certainly
leads to divorce very often.
If only one member of the family starts
getting committed to spiritual
evolution, there may be considerable
disparity with other members of the
family and it is a frequent cause of
divorce.
If salvation and enlightenment both lead
to the same end and enlightenment is a
more demanding road to follow, what is
the reason one would focus on the path
of enlightenment?
Oh, we explained earlier salvation and
enlightenment are two different things.
Salvation means to reach the level of
love, especially unconditional love.
Enlightenment you're looking at 800 to
a,000.
Enlightenment is just as more advanced,
more difficult, more arduous and
extremely difficult to
extremely difficult on this planet. Now
it's extremely difficult.
It's extreme consumably difficult to get
to 540 to get beyond 600 we said happens
one in 10 million.
To get to 700 is less than even that. To
go beyond that is practically never
happens.
Centuries and centuries go by without a
single individual going that high. And
when they do reach such levels, it is
extremely arduous. And without special
help and special inside knowledge, one
would never make it. And thankfully, the
Buddha described what it was like that
his bones felt like they were being
broken.
and Christ sweat
blood. And so the human nervous system
is not really made for anything beyond
540 to 600. It's not made for it. And uh
under special conditions with an
intensity
of rockhard steel like immutable
commitment
is not possible. So you know it must be
a rather unique peculiar
uh
thing to do. You know, how many times
has anybody reached over 850, 900 in
man's history, you know, on the
occasional centuries go by.
It has to do with the evolution of
consciousness and how it chooses to
express itself. It has to do with
commitments that were karmically made
and
the willingness to be of service to God
no matter what.
Beyond the ordinary beyond the ordinary.
Who knows why?
>> Yes. We'll stop. One more question.
We'll stop.
What can you do for your children? I
think that question was there.
>> What's the best way to educate children?
The public schools or mass private
schools teach the Old Testament and
other religious fallacies.
What's the best way to teach questions
are about children and families?
>> Yes. Well, it's no different than one's
own individual. It has to do with
picking what you think is the most
truthful
beneficial pathway to God and sharing it
with the children.
Now the children are going to learn in
school
things that are considerably different.
There are many laws and rules that come
laws and rules and belief systems that
are inculcated into
behaviors and laws that come out of
books of the Bible that we found were
below 200, right? Fellacious, right?
That which fellacious is now the law of
the land. So what can you do about that?
Well, you're only responsible for the
evolution of your own consciousness. And
in so doing, you lift others. So I would
say you become the most beneficient,
loving, forgiving, compassionate being
you can be and thereby inspire the
children. Now the children may are at
the same time under the pressure of MTV
and fallacies of both luciferic and
satanic dimension, seduction by perverse
sexuality,
the profanation of the sacred
Um, one can watch the extremely erotic,
glamorized images seductively displayed
with very advanced and a unique
technology
to an to capture the energy of the
viewer who is then attracted by that
which is dilitterious.
First of seduction then is to pull into
a certain energy field that which is
dilotarious spiritually and the field
that dominates you and you become its
servant and victim.
So
the
downside of our current society is
severe the distortion of reality which
is presented as truth.
the seduction of such things as video
games.
When you hear what the story is behind a
certain video game, you say nobody in
their right mind would buy it. It's a
big seller.
A big seller
to track down,
rape, murder, and seduce, rape, and
murder a lady and then take her money.
I mean, what a gallant image for
manhood. Yeah.
Certainly different than the image of
integrity that we grew up with. And it's
the biggest seller there is. Grand Theft
Auto 3.
And there's a newer one out, far more
wicked than that one. Calibrates at 70.
70.
So, the child is being brainwashed with
that.
And certainly being a parent today is
scary because you've got to counter
that. So you counter it by the
presentation of truth as you know it and
try to surround them with a culture that
respects love and the dignity of man and
the dignity of woman
etc. And hopefully by identification
with that which you are and by the power
of that which you have become
they will choose that. In the end
however they have their own karma and
the most difficult part of being a
parent is to surrender them to God.
Their salvation is not up to you and
consequently you pay play a part in
their life hopefully positive in the
beginning but from that point on they're
really on their own. So I myself was
guided let's say into high Episcopal
church. My greatgrandfather was the
Episcopal bishop in Milwaukee.
And I had the most uh
what you would say ethical,
you know, being an acolyte and the choir
of the of a great Episcopal high
Episcopal Cathedral.
uh part of the choir and the music and
the pageantry was as uplifting and be
the you know the beat the attitude the
beauty of it the stained glass windows
the incense the
pageantry it was incredible incredibly
magnificent and beautiful
and
10 or 15 years later I became an atheist
poor mom and dad they never knew it
thank god God God took them away out of
his mercy of their mercy. So they did
know it for a while and my father was
quite distressed. So you see and yet
what happened to the atheism was it led
to the pits of hell and in the pits of
hell the entity said if there is a god I
ask him to help me and then
unconsciousness
and non-conciousness
and then the opening of divine
revelation and the transformation
which you witness to this day.
So how could a parent have helped
on this hand and on this hand and on
this hand. But then this came out of the
reality of the presence of divinity. And
so what happens with the children
is maybe 5% what you do and 95% karma
and 5% the environment. Huh? So we pray
for direction. We ask for God's help for
for ourselves as parents. We ask for the
guidance of our children and we do all
within its power. Don't forget we're
you're only answerable to yourself. Only
you know that you've done what you can
on on their behalf. As a physician, I
was sometimes in presented. Here's the
sick patient and I know something that
is not within traditional medical
approval at the moment, but I know it
will help the patient recover. So at
that moment I have to decide am I going
to be answerable to my colleagues and
popularity with my colleagues or am I
going to help this patient who without
this is certainly going to die. And in
that moment you decide on death's bed
you're going to be answerable to God for
what you did with this patient.
Your con colleagues are not going to be
at your deathbed to cheer you on as our
favorite colleague.
Now, the reality of God, you're
answerable then only to yourself,
knowing that in the presence of God, the
truth
is what you must live by. You must know
that to yourself, you have done all you
can to help these children in the best
way you know way.
And I think that's all we're answerable
for.
We have 10 after 4.
Do you want Nico to chant for five
minutes?
>> And then we'll stop and anybody wants to
say hello can say hello. We'll sign any
books. In that case, you're ready.
>> Buckle your seat buckles.
This person
You know what? I know.
I know
day. I know there
Rockchech.
Going
for
night.
I could
go no
Oh
go.
Thank you.
Thank you. And we will glad to greet
anyone who wishes to say hello to us.
Yes.
>> Now we have to turn this off somehow.