It's always in your way.
You can see the trouble we're having with the body right here.
Look at all this.
This is all because of the body, understand?
Because of my mouth and your ears.
You see, if we didn't all have bodies here,
we'd just all be together in one big spiritual space,
and you would all know what I know, see?
Because we'd have one mind,
and we'd just all know what everybody else knows,
so you don't even have to verbalize
and go through all this whole talking-ness business,
which I do for the sake of the audience.
But it takes an espresso to do it.
Are the healings that people have,
the result is not the time for them to leave this earth?
If you're destined to leave at a certain time,
then you can either leave in good condition
or not such good condition.
I told you about the old people in the nursing home,
you know, saying, help, help, help, help, help.
You know, and they got a stroke on this side
and a stroke on this side,
and they're paralyzed with rheumatism all over.
Their kidneys are gone, their heart's gone.
They can't hear or see or smell anymore,
and they're still going on.
They can't get out of here.
Can't get out of here.
And then when the time comes, you can't stay here.
You can't stay here.
The door to the airplane opens up at 36,000 feet.
One person is withdrawn from that airplane.
Remember, that was in the papers,
about 10, 15 years ago.
I think it was the stewardess.
D.C., whatever it is, at 36,000 feet.
The door suddenly blew open,
and exactly one person was extracted
out of the 350 passengers.
So when karmically it's your time,
you ain't going to hang out.
And if it isn't time, you can't leave.
Thank you.
Yeah.
But you're conditioned at the time.
Yes, you do.
So the time of leaving is karmically set.
But you're conditioned,
and the other factors,
they're up to personal choice.
And my question is,
what will be helpful to keep in mind
if one leaves a higher level of consciousness
and moves to a lower level of consciousness?
You change your expectations.
Just like somebody only went to fifth grade.
Right away, your expectation,
you shift your intellectual presentation to them
so they can comprehend it out of compassion.
So out of compassion for somebody
who's struggling,
with the barest minimum of existence,
I modify how I present a concept to them
so that it is mutually, meets mutual needs,
not just my needs.
You know, we like to tell everybody
how democracy is so wonderful and this kind of thing.
That's meaningful to somebody in the 400s.
To somebody who doesn't know where dinner is going
to come from tonight, it's so much palaver, you know?
And I've been in places, you know.
I'm thinking about South America on the coast.
I'm not very left-brained right now.
I can't tell you the name of the country.
Ikenema Beach, or what is that?
What country is that?
Brazil.
Brazil, yes, yes.
On the side of the mountains there,
the favelas where the peasants live.
Look how they live.
A whole family of 10.
This is where they live.
There's a piece of tin here.
Then there's some string.
There's some paper.
There's some paper there.
Over here, it looks like some used toilet paper, if you ask me.
Behind that is a piece of cardboard.
Behind that is a couple of bricks.
Behind that is some stones.
Ten people live there.
Shall I give you a lecture on democracy?
You stated that you had been to hell, and you felt this terror,
but you never saw an entity.
So what created terror?
You see, the Buddha and Jesus Christ recommended,
and Jesus and the Buddha both said,
avoid that which makes you go weak with kinesiology.
I said that because they said that the spirit, after it leaves the body,
will pay the karmic consequences for your decisions and choices in this lifetime.
Consequently, it wasn't like they were trying to create a fear of hell,
although religions have done so.
In this particular lifetime,
the extreme, there's been great spiritual extremes.
As I say, at age three, there was a confrontation that only occurs at level 850.
It came out of many lifetimes as a Hinayana Buddhist,
in which I followed the pathway of negation with great dedication.
And to me, at that time, the ultimate reality was the void.
And so, each lifetime, I would go out into the void, you know.
If the void was real,
the ultimate reality,
there would have been nobody to report such an event.
In any case, because it's not real, you can't stay there.
So the void is very, very impressive.
It's very impressive.
And if you constantly negate everything,
you eventually go into a state of nothingness.
And it is so overwhelmingly impressive, you're sure,
this is the ultimate goal of enlightenment.
Is that what a terror is then?
No, no, no terror.
There's nothing there to be afraid.
Yeah.
No, there's no terror in that.
But I turned away from it in this lifetime,
because already at age 12,
I'd had the experience of the infinite oneness,
and the most memorable quality was
you're melted by the,
by the divine love.
You don't think any words in that state,
but the love melts any,
so the mind is silent.
It's like it's melted out by divinity,
the presence of divinity.
Then,
the state was not recoverable.
I didn't talk about personal experience today,
because it did not seem relevant to the lecture,
but later on,
oh yes,
well later on,
I'll give you the sequence of events then,
so it makes some kind of sense.
Well, walking through the,
I was very religious spiritually,
high Episcopal,
I was a boy acolyte,
a boy soprano with a cathedral,
and extremely religious,
and scrupulous in fact.
One day walking through the woods,
all of a sudden the world was silent and still,
like an infinite presence.
And all of a sudden out of nowhere came
a non-verbal awareness,
and I saw the totality,
I don't know how to describe this,
I saw the totality of the suffering of all of mankind
throughout all of time.
It was a massive,
non-verbal,
massive awareness,
and I grasped the totality of the suffering of all of man
throughout all of time,
beyond all description.
In that instant I became a profound atheist,
I said,
any God that can allow that,
or create that,
in the mind of the child,
see,
especially Christianity in the 1930s,
the idea was that God creates everything,
see,
therefore all tortures,
suffering,
pain,
and sin is the product of God.
I wasn't sophisticated,
I didn't realize that all the suffering of man
is the product of the ego,
not of God,
see.
So what I was looking at was the totality
of the production of the ego over time,
which is the mass of suffering
is beyond description.
But I held God responsible for that,
so I instantly became an atheist,
and I didn't realize I was looking at the product of the ego
and not the product of divinity,
see.
But anyway,
I became a very intense atheist.
I then went to a Jesuit university
where I got straight A in theology.
The better to argue the stupidity of theology
and the idiocy
of Aristotle
and St. Thomas Aquinas,
et cetera,
of primary cause
and all that idiotic childish intellectualization,
which I blew out the window.
But there was like an intense preoccupation
with a knowingness
that there was an essential truth
that was reachable,
but I was unable to reach it,
and thereby intense effort
and meditation,
et cetera.
I finally went into a sense of despair
about the inability to contact
the core of truth of existence,
I guess driven by the phenomena
that I experienced at age three,
but I'd forgotten about that.
Anyway,
in searching for
some kind of an ultimate answer,
I went into a profound state of actual hell.
I investigated all the levels of consciousness,
including the depths of hell,
and driven into hell,
as a Dante,
how Dante knew the nature of hell,
I don't know.
I never asked whether he'd been there,
but it was absolutely accurate.
As I went into it,
the upper layers of hell
have to do with chopping people up and torture
and sort of Saddam Hussein's son's kind of deviltry,
which are just jacks for openers,
chopping people up and torching them to death.
You think that's hell.
That isn't hell.
That's just the warning
that you're getting close to hell.
Then it really gets severe,
and then it gets agonizing.
And when the agony reaches beyond what you can bear,
it suddenly gets worse.
And at that point,
there's a knowingness,
almost like you see a sign that says,
abandon all hope,
ye who enter here.
I think Dante wrote those exact words,
and I saw those words.
And then you enter a level of hell
beyond imagination.
Nobody's imagination can imagine it.
It's one of horrific despair,
and it's forever.
Just like the highest levels of consciousness
are forever and beyond time,
the lowest depths of hell are timeless.
Now you are in the absolute hopeless despair
with no hope ever of getting out of this state,
and you begin to realize what forever means.
Forever agony.
Forever despair.
And then the horror of where you're at hits you.
At that level of hell,
beyond all description,
out of this consciousness,
the prayer arose.
If there is a God,
don't forget I was a profound atheist at the time,
if there is a God,
I ask him to help me.
And then there was oblivion.
Sometime later,
I don't know whether it was hours or a day or what,
consciousness returned,
and now it was a complete and total transformation
in which a personal self had dissolved.
There was only awareness,
being the totality and allness of the presence of God
as all existence.
The stunning beauty of it left one speechless.
The mind no longer existed.
The tail end of the mind disappeared into the silence.
The tail end of the mind
was struck dumb with awe.
The revelation of the splendor of the existence of God
as all existence and all of its stunning beauty
shone forth
and blew out whatever remained of the mind
and fried it out forever.
And it's never had the audacity
to think a thought since.
So what remains to speak then
is a presence,
which is silent.
If I listen to the mind now,
it says nothing.
It's just an infinite silence.
But the intentionality of expression
coming out of your question,
for instance,
the answering this is happening
of its own spontaneously,
and I myself have nothing to do with it.
Sorry you asked.
That's some heavy stuff.
Two quick questions.
Dr. Hawkins, I was wondering
if you and Werner Erhard
are familiar with each other's work?
Oh, okay.
I'm familiar with Werner's work, yes.
Werner Erhard.
Yes, yes.
Many people here have done this.
How many have done this?
Yeah, all the older people here have done this, yeah.
The younger ones are too young to do this.
It was great fun.
Everybody did it back in the 70s, I think it was.
Yeah, yeah.
It's by a different name now, but...
I was also wondering if you knew of the work,
the wisdom teachings of Avatar Adidas Samraj.
Wondering if you knew of the wisdom teachings
of Avatar Adidas Samraj.
No, okay.
There's a million gurus out there.
I can't calculate them all.
I thought you said Ramana Maharshi at first.
No, I mean...
That was one of his...
No, Ramana Maharshi and Asagadatta Maharaj
both calibrated in the low 700s.
700 is the level of sage, sage.
And it doesn't usually change.
The sage usually goes in at 700,
usually never leaves where they are,
and stays there.
See, consciousness tends to revolve of its own accord.
In other words, you can go into bliss state
and it's absolutely perfect.
There's no necessity to go any further.
And consciousness may or may not stay there.
As I said, 50% of the time,
the person just leaves the body.
Extremely rarely, extremely rarely,
extremely, extremely rarely,
only a few in every generation or century even,
does consciousness then start moving
from like 700 to 800 to 900 to 1000.
And it does it of its own accord,
unasked,
because there's no one there to ask it to move ahead.
There's no incompleteness.
There's no reason when you're sitting there
in a state of complete and total bliss
and the infinite holiness of the presence
to suspect that consciousness could move
anywhere than where it is
because it's complete and total from moment to moment.
One thing I forgot to explain about
how one experiences reality
is in the Newtonian paradigm,
everything is always incomplete
and moving to completeness.
Once you let go of that paradigm,
you stop projecting that onto phenomena,
you see that because all is,
all represents creation, continuous creation,
what you now see is everything goes
from completeness to completeness to completeness,
from perfection to perfection to perfection.
It does not go from imperfection to perfection.
The half-unfolded rose is absolutely
and perfectly and completely a half-unfolded rose.
It's perfect now, it's perfect now,
it's perfect now, it's perfect now,
it's perfect now, it's complete now,
it's perfect now.
You see?
How it transforms, how you experience the world.
You see that everything is perfection
every instant.
Everything that's going on in this room
is absolutely perfect right now.
None of it should be or could be
or is doing anything other than
what is at this moment.
And that's perfect.
We go from perfection to perfection,
from completion to completion.
So we witness that way, creation,
and realize that it's divinity,
that we're witnessing divinity
and the unfolding of creation.
I just wanted to thank you
for your contribution to humanity.
I really appreciate it.
Oh, my God.
Pepsi.
I have the problem of abundance.
You know, there's all these workshops on abundance.
I do workshops on the problem of abundance.
What do you do with abundance?
How can you drink three Pepsis at once?
You know what I'm saying?
This is just representative.
Because when you let go
of the sense of incompleteness
and see everything is complete,
you realize that you are complete
and total every instant.
And you have no further needs or desires.
There's nothing you want.
Somebody says,
What do you want?
I tell them,
I don't know.
I have to make up something
to make them happy.
I need a new bow tie.
Oh, good.
Now they're happy they have something
that they can get you.
But, you know,
actually I have no need for a bow tie.
I've got drawers full of things.
I've got drawers full of bow ties.
I've got the world's
greatest collection of bow ties.
You know what I'm saying?
So, everything,
once you see it correctly,
every moment you have all
that you need at that moment.
You know?
And if you don't have anything to eat,
then you have all that you need
in order to starve to death.
That's a hard one to see.
But,
if you're meant to starve to death,
then what you need
is the absence of food
and you're provided with that need
by the absence of food.
And so you can happily starve to death
full of self-pity,
resentment,
and remorse.
And hate God
and now feel vindicated in hating him.
With what you just said in mind,
I really don't need any answers to anything
and if you'd sign this book,
it'd be great.
And I'll give you a dollar, too.
Your desires are already fulfilled.
That's a divine dollar.
Mark this one.
This one is special.
We'll never spend this one.
You wrote special on that one.
That's a holy dollar.
A holy dollar, that's for sure.
I really don't have a question either.
I'd just like to thank you
and ask you to sign my book.
I would be happy to sign it
and that's a gift to me
to allow me to sign your book.
I might use this dollar to save my life
on the way home.
I would like you to sign my book.
But I also have a question.
The Middle East calibrates now
below the 200 level.
Do you have any theories or ideas
around how long it's going to take
or what could be the catalyst
to get them above 200?
I didn't explain that fully.
We really didn't get in
because of the shortage of time
how to transcend the ego.
You see, the ego is a substitute for God.
Yeah, we explained in the beginning.
Egocentricity is,
it seeks to displace God as the authority.
Now, The Course in Miracles explains that very well.
And that's the reason I like the Course.
Because it really explains the authority problem.
But,
what was your question?
Oh, yes.
All right.
So, the ego then feeds off of itself.
Because it is devoid of divine energizing,
it's self-energizing.
And the ego survives,
this is something important
I should have said this morning,
by the juice it gets out of its positionalities.
It gets so much juice out of hatred.
Why should it give up hatred?
You watch the two sides on the newsreel every night
shooting at each other,
throwing bricks at each other over the barricades.
You know?
Throwing rocks,
shooting at each other.
They're in a state of high joy.
There's no higher joy than throwing rocks at the police.
And you can then provoke the police
to finally let go of the dogs or shoot somebody.
Now, you can get on television with the victim.
This justifies shooting them.
You see?
So, the payoff on this is tremendous.
And the leaders of those countries
maintain their political position
based on playing this game endlessly.
You know that they've been at it
since I've been on the planet?
They've been at it since I've been on the planet.
Same boundaries, same people,
same justification, same ideology,
same motivation, same payoff.
So, it's going to go on to perpetuity?
It could go on another thousand years.
Because the ego will juice everything out of injustice,
remorse, revenge,
hatred.
The spleen is a very strong chakra in those regions.
So, you might say,
those are regions that live in the chakra of the spleen.
Hatred, envy, jealousy, untruth.
How long can they live there?
Thousands of years.
Hello, ma'am.
Just do nothing but signing books
after we get a few more questions.
Is that what we should do?
Yes?
All right, but the questions can go on,
we'll just have people sign books real fast
so we can sign a lot of books.
But you can still talk to me
and I'll be happy to hug you all
and answer as many questions as I can.
My ambition is to hug everybody who's here today.
I don't know if I'll make it or not.
Well, I was going to ask for a handshake,
but I'll take the hug.
Okay.
Here's my question.
Okay, so at the instant we're born,
we come in with a certain level of consciousness
and we come in with a predetermined time of our death,
so we might as well not think about it.
It's just going to happen.
All right, then for want of another word,
we come in with this soul that has karmic potential.
Okay.
And you said the soul or this karmic potential
is influenced by conditions
of the field of infamy, of God,
of whatever term you want.
I guess my question to you is,
in this karmic soul,
can I have any influence on that field
and is my influence based on will and choice?
I don't think you phrased it exactly correctly,
but you won't influence the field.
But in other words,
I picture this life as purgatorial.
In other words, we have a huge range of choice.
Huge range of choice at every instant.
Then we have our karmic potential
and we have our karmic obligations.
We're already born with a certain IQ.
We're born with a certain kind of body.
You're an endomorph, mesomorph, or ectomorph.
You're born with a certain IQ.
Some people are born genius.
Some people are born not so bright.
Some people are born strong.
Some are born weak.
Some are born rich.
Some are born poor, see?
So now, starting out,
you find yourself again in a physical body
in a human lifetime.
The choices that are karmically destined to come up
will come up.
And this time you have a choice to answer differently.
This time you have a choice to answer differently.
All the choices, all my choices,
are karmic choices.
I don't exist without choice,
so everything that I choose
and everything I think is a karmic choice.
Is that correct?
This is a very,
there's various levels to this question.
There are certain patterns which are inherent
within the energy field of the spirit
as it reincarnates.
Some of these karmic patterns
are going to be of greater importance
or greater pressure than others.
Some are going to be trivial.
Some are going to be surely optional.
Now, you see, in a complex pattern,
a small choice made here
will put you in a different realm.
Where other karmic propensities are going to come up
where if you don't make that choice, it won't come up.
So you see an endless series
like a mosaic.
If I say yes to that, that puts me over here.
Over here I have these options.
If I say no to that, it puts me here.
Over here I don't have those options.
So from moment to moment
I am constantly determining my own karmic destiny.
Understand that?
If I say yes to that,
I now have the option to say yes to this.
If I say no to that,
I can't say...
If I say no, I won't go to Europe.
I don't have the option of walking the maze
in Chartres Cathedral.
If I'm there, is it a maze?
Whatever it is.
It's an amazing place, anyway.
If I get there and I say,
I think I'll walk it while I'm there,
I get there, there's chairs all over it.
Obviously, the church authorities don't want
trails of people going out down the street
walking the maze, you know,
the complex or whatever it is.
So every choice then alters your options
from moment to moment.
And you see the endlessness and the complexity
of the energy field of consciousness.
But here's then the last point.
That being the case,
what's the difference between
constantly weaving your way through
all the choices
and the concept of surrender?
Because one choice you have is to surrender.
And that is a choice that's present all the time.
So when I'm experiencing pain,
I can surrender the experience to God
or I can resist it.
If I resist it, that intensifies the pain.
The way to disappear a thing is to
let go resisting it.
All experiencing comes out of resisting.
It's because of the persistence of the ego
that you experience.
Remember on that chart up there we put
there's the witnesser, the experiencer.
There's nothing experiencing what's going on here.
Within this entity whatsoever.
There's nothing to experience it.
What would it experience?
It's conscious and aware,
but it's not experiencing it.
It's a bugger.
All you can see is getting your way through
a whole endless complexity of choices.
And every choice determines your options.
You see, if I say yes to this,
that opens these options.
Now, a mouse cannot decide
to become a gopher.
It's karmically already bound to certain choices.
So you as a human being
inherit a body and a brain
and your own karmic inheritance.
So your choices are not unlimited.
You cannot decide to become
a champion wrestler right now.
Okay.
I wouldn't.
I guess then, I guess then,
this is pretty heavy,
but ideally, faith is realizing
that if you were to live only in the moment,
every single moment,
and every single moment you were to surrender,
that's as close as you're going to come
to enlightenment in this body.
There's nothing to surrender
and no one has surrendered too.
That's all an illusion.
You see, the fact that you need to become enlightened
is already a great illusion.
Okay, you have to forgive me.
I get very nervous in front of crowds
and I'm like, okay,
a newborn baby to all of this.
Once you become more nervous,
you're not nervous enough.
Okay, I'll try.
If you were really nervous,
you wouldn't be complaining about it.
Okay.
Good, all right.
Now, my question is,
I think the greatest lie of our time
right now that we have to be careful of,
Southern Baptist convert to Catholic,
so the fear of hell is ingrained, kind of.
Anyhow, is that there is no hell.
Don't worry.
God is all loving.
God is all forgiving.
And I had to narrow my faith down
to where it was something I could live with.
And what I finally came up with
was the face in front of my face
and intent is everything.
I mean, actions, you know,
that's what you always heard,
actions can't get me anywhere.
But what is it?
I mean, your description of hell
scared me to death.
I'm back to the fear.
Yeah.
It isn't like it's a realm.
It's like it's a level of consciousness.
You see, you're still within
the realm of consciousness.
To abandon God, you know,
is to throw yourself at the mercy
of word consciousness.
There are regions of consciousness
that you really don't want to experience.
You see?
What was it you said?
Well, I mean, you described hell.
So what you're really saying is
hell most definitely exists.
All right.
So it's personalized.
Hell is personalized for each individual.
Is that correct?
If they choose?
If they choose it?
All right.
But hell does exist.
And experientially,
both heaven and hell are experiential.
They're purely subjective.
Right?
It's only subjectivity that even,
could even say they exist.
You say they exist?
I've told you the experience.
Yeah, the experiential.
Yeah.
The experiential.
Jesus Christ, you know, said that.
Buddha said that.
And everyone can just sit back and relax.
Lean into it.
Doctor tells me this
counts out about seven, seven-fifty, so.
No.
Oh, that's what the whole lecture's about today.
You have to be willing to surrender the juice
that you get out of the ego's positionality.
You have to be willing to surrender the juice of self-pity,
the juice of resentment,
the juice of hatred,
the juice of getting even.
All the negative payoffs.
You're willing to surrender the negative payoffs to the ego,
you dissolve it.
Sounds simple enough.
Mm-hmm.
We didn't get into that in the lecture today.
Doc, thanks for all the help.
Yeah, yeah.
Can you sign a book and get a picture, maybe?
You bet.
So, Doc, how did you lose that thumb?
Well, karmically, there's a story behind it,
but actually I did it with a circular saw.
It kicked back.
It was so fast.
You always say, well, it's off here.
Oh, I couldn't get my hand out of the way in time.
If it starts to kick back, you don't have enough time.
It moves faster than the speed of light.
It's gone.
I didn't get a chance to make a decision.
So you got more books in your works?
I have one major book, yeah,
I've been working on it for a year or two already.
Are you going to keep writing, though?
Yeah, this one's going to take another year anyway.
It's going to be a major buster.
Thanks a bunch.
Yes, September 3.
Thank you.
Yes.
I'm grateful the field brought me to you.
Yeah.
Many, many things.
Thank you.
It's supposed to be short.
And this one's an angel.
Yeah, yeah.
So patient.
She's my angel.
Thank God for her.
Hey, there we go.
Reality is subjectivity.
We didn't get into that too heavily today, actually.
So are you going to have a cigarette later?
We're going to, yeah, if you're still here.
That'd be great.
I didn't want to get distracted.
Okay, here we go.
We have a ritual smoke together.
Oh, yeah?
Oh, yeah.
It's a tribal custom.
Everything's holy, right?
Thank you.
It's a Native American custom.
Hi, David.
Nice to see you.
I've been reading your book.
Yeah.
Keep reading.
Good, yeah.
Keep up the good work.
I have many questions, but there's too many people.
Oh, okay.
Has been a blessing.
Thank you.
It's been a blessing to hear you.
Yeah, I'm glad you enjoyed it.
I have questions, too, but I'll come back sometime.
If they ask easy ones, we can answer them.
Thank you.
If they ask easy ones, but they ask these hard ones.
They think of such complicated questions.
I don't know.
Anything that I would have asked had already been answered.
Are we going to calibrate the audience before and after?
Oh, yeah.
Thank you.
Okay, this audience at the end of the lecture was over 440, 444, 445.
10 points.
They went up.
444.
445.
10 points.
They went up.
435 to 445.
Is that an average calibration?
Yeah.
An audience, 10 points.
Some that are higher.
And there's some that are really low.
Some really got it?
Some got it.
Some got it this much lower.
Yeah, some people went down, probably.
And the smarter ones went up 20 points.
Okay!
Those who are really listening did go up more than 10 points, but the average is 10
points, which is pretty good for a whole bunch of people.
Okay.
Thank you.
Thank you, ma'am.
for a whole field.
What's going on?
Is he leaving right away?
You're leaving right away?
Ralph, did you come down by yourself?
No, he brought a friend.
Huh?
He brought a friend.
Oh, yeah, yeah.
You're looking good, Ralph.
You're looking better.
Thank you.
Your head is shinier.
It shows you're getting better.
I thought it was the reason you were here.
I knew I was a reflective mirror.
No, you do look better.
You look better, you know.
Yeah, it's good.
So what does one do when they're by themselves
for the questions and the testing?
Well, I would use this system.
I mean, you find somebody to work with.
You find somebody to work with.
And certain people work really well
and easy together.
And other people don't.
So find somebody you just sort of work easy with, you know?
And it sort of just automatically happens
when you find the right person.
Thank you for your contributions.
Did you get your flowers?
Yeah.
Thank you for asking me.
Thank you.
You bet.
Yeah, we sent you flowers.
We might have been out too.
We were.
Thank you.
Thanks.
Thank you, sir.
Yeah, you bet. Thank you.
You're asking me.
I love you.
I finished this book last night
when my dad died.
Yeah.
And it helped me to realize
how much more joyous I am
than I used to be.
And I'm very grateful.
Oh, thank you.
No, I'm not.
Thank you.
That's really good for you.
Hi.
Yeah, hi.
Can I ask you a very quick question?
Yeah.
I know you talked about
there was a set point
for the time of our death, basically.
that there's already a set time for our death.
What was your question?
Your question is, is there also a set point
for where we will be on the map of consciousness at that point?
No.
So freedom of choice, power of intention, free will,
all that plays a part in that.
You see, you come in with a calibrated level of consciousness.
That puts you somewhere in the field, see?
Okay.
Then you've got your options.
Then when you leave the body,
you're going to gravitate to that which you have become.
So a person who has gravitated to hatred and hating God
will automatically find himself in the realm of hatred.
God doesn't condemn him there.
The one who chooses gentleness and love
is automatically going to gravitate to people who are gentle and loving, you know?
Just like some people...
Thank you.
It's for real.
Some people like, you know, the quiet, peaceful, rural.
So they automatically are going to move there.
They're not going to hang out in New York City, see?
Other people like the excitement of New York City
and the high of the solar plexus.
So they live in New York City.
Can I ask you a question?
Yeah.
I know you've never alluded to this in any of your work,
but did Jesus ever come to you and guide you in the right way?
What will?
Did Jesus ever come to you and guide you in the right way?
No.
No, she was afraid of you.
She was afraid of you.
She was afraid of the end of the line, and then she didn't have the line.
She was afraid of everybody here.
Yeah.
Yeah, I just...
See, as a consciousness...
Do you need some more drinks, water?
No.
As a consciousness, a great consciousness,
the consciousness of Jesus makes itself known all the time
and is always available.
All we have to do is ask for it.
Jesus is present right here at this moment in between the two of us.
I need to ask you, but...
No, I don't drink that.
The body of Jesus.
You've got a lot on the body of Jesus.
The body of Jesus is just an illusion.
The body of physicality means nothing.
Someone, like, could go to bed or something.
Well, look that up for me.
The reality of Christ is
the consciousness that supports our consciousness as we speak
is already present.
It seems to me, when I was a little girl,
he came in my room.
Huh?
He came to me when I was a child.
He came to my room.
Yes.
And he comes in my dreams.
And he stands and he cries.
That's true.
It takes literal form.
To help guide?
To help awaken?
If he's always there, why does he show up in form?
And why do I feel closer when he does?
Why do you feel closer when what?
When he does.
Why do I feel like something profoundly is shifting inside of me
when he is in my dreams?
That would be a natural thing,
because of the inner consciousness.
Yeah.
It's a wonderful thing, because of the enormous amount of
spiritual energy and devotion devoted to Jesus and to his image
and to the whole concept of the Christ, yeah?
Anymore?
I enjoyed it immensely.
I'm a big fan of yours.
Yes.
I've read all of your work.
Thank you.
It's an honor to be here.
September 03.
Thank you.
Yes, thank you.
Dr. Hawkins, my God, there is no hell.
You know why? My God is only love and compassion.
I do not believe in hell, because he loves me no matter what I do.
He won't condemn you to hell, but you can condemn yourself to hell.
Oh, I won't, because I'm too much in love with him.
To be in love with God, it means to be in love with love.
If you're in love with love, then you won't be going near hell at all.
Okay.
music yeah you got more strength from two more oh you're no problem can you tell me where the
avatars are uh-huh where are the other 22 avatars i think it's 22 million
i don't know i just get the number of them okay
you can give me a hug it's one dollar okay
we're going to take a chair or three okay oh that's funny yeah yeah thank you so much
yeah the list you talked about of calibrating the corporations yes is that list available anywhere
because no but i'll tell you i'll give you the answer we did the fortune 500 world you know 100
world's biggest corporation
is uh they're all they're they're practically all around 204 205 all
you'll get a rare one a rare one it's rare to be anything more than 205
maybe uh what's the name of that clothing company that i like there you know and
no no the mail away did i get my shirts pants llb
beans yeah you'll get somebody who's a little bit higher
because i've started doing corporate responsibility work with companies
and that's the reason i was interested in that is
well you see responsibility is is genuine accountability
and that'll take you to 205 but that's not the same as uh caring right right how can i help you
it's a disease that's right over 300.
So a waitress at 200 takes your order, she says, yes, I was there, a waiter at 300 says,
hey Dave, glad to see you back, you want the usual?
See, I give her twice the tip, she makes twice as much money.
So there's, most corporations because they've got to comply with the law and they also got
to make money, will come out around 205, General Motors, all the big ones.
The thing that surprised me about Walmart is they put so many small businesses out of
business.
That's looking at causality.
That's describing it to causality.
Okay.
All right.
Thank you.
All those people would probably make more money if they worked for Walmart than if they
were if they run their drug store themselves.
Well, I just had quite a realization today.
Yeah.
We were introduced to the non-myoho rengi cure a while back.
I was diagnosed with my rengi cure a while back.
I had a rengi cure.
I said to my husband one day, I said, I need a healing chant.
So, he cross transitions up, and Ms. Ochken was speaking that night.
Who wrote a book.
He introduced to the chant and we started chanting
and then we stopped.
And then we went, we met somebody who was
part of the Shonan.
There goes Nico chanting at us, and I just realized that I had to believe in myself.
I didn't know anybody else.
And there's just such a thing as everything happens for a reason, right?
Right?
Is there such a thing?
I mean, is it?
Everything happens for a reason?
Yeah, yeah.
Yeah?
Are you doing fine?
Uh, I'm doing fine.
I just thought that this was quite an awakening for me.
You went very deep.
I couldn't understand half the stuff you're talking about, but somehow it connected us.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
And besides, you're in Sedona, right?
Yeah.
We just bought a house in, uh, in, uh, Peoria, Arizona.
Where'd you buy one?
In Sedona.
Okay.
Where'd you buy one?
In the Peoria, Arizona.
Oh, yeah.
Peoria.
Yeah, yeah.
It's gonna come someday.
That's near the university there.
Yeah.
Yeah, we give lectures there.
Do you?
We're like around there.
Yeah.
Every two months.
In Sedona?
Yeah.
And Nico, you know, comes from around in there.
Ah, yeah.
Nico and Betty.
Where are they?
Nico?
Okay.
Here.
Where did...
They live near...
Not too far from Peoria.
Oh, yeah?
Yeah.
And he's at every lecture.
more like close to outside of Phoenix okay all right yeah yes I'm glad you
enjoyed it
yes yes I'm glad you enjoyed it
I mean besides all the things you have to say I think you have a wonderful
sense of humor too thank you
I had a question have you done any calibrations with vegetariness
you know like increases it has to do with intention the intention behind it
it was done as a sacrifice and a devotion to God then it you know it's
very hard