Well, by saying yes, we got snow today,
didn't we?
We collapsed the wave function, folks.
Life is just collapsing the wave
function all the time, isn't it?
Well, we never did get around to what
the subject was for today. for today.
People uh it's always comical to me you
know uh people say what is the subject
going to be
the subject is going to be whatever
is spoken
and I don't know what the subject spoken
is until I hear it so how would I know
like saying to uh
Paul McCartney, what song are you going
to write next week? Well, I don't know.
Anyway, today was supposed to be about
what I call the zen of daily life.
Um,
spirituality and everyday life. Okay.
So, now I know what the subject is,
folks. And
we did talk about the zen of chicken
coop, didn't we? where intention, the
power of intention and of course in
spiritual work the power of intention is
the driving laser beam that carries you
through to your destination. Huh?
Somebody asked me about peace, you know,
and uh you know, I was joking when I
said, you know, peace and war, they're
all the same to me. Um
so that people wouldn't think I'm
serious, but frankly, they are the same
to me.
because one can be in in a state of
infinite peace right in the middle of
war and feel a profound state of peace
as you walk right into physical death.
Uh and that's because of the power of
one's alignment.
I don't join any campaigns for peace.
The reason is you cannot create peace
any like enlightenment. You see you
can't create enlightenment. Huh?
Can't create peace.
It's the state when that which opposes
it is removed. Then it spontaneously
stands there because it is there all the
time.
You cannot create peace. So a parade for
peace may be entertaining
but what we did this morning probably
had more profound effect on the
likelihood the potentiality of peace
than a parade, you know.
You cannot create peace because it is a
quality of divinity which stands forth
when you remove that which is obscuring
it.
When you remove the clouds, the sun
shines forth, but that does not cause
the sun to shine.
You remove the clouds and the sun shines
forth because it is there. So
what we're going to do is remove
the foundations out of which the
eventuality of war becomes
u a necessity by virtue of how it's been
set up to happen.
The underpinnings then are falsehood.
Consequently,
it is only by virtue of the stacking of
one falsehood upon another that war
ensues.
Consequently, the identification of that
which is false from that which is true
does more to service peace than anything
else you can do.
to remove the sheep's clothing from the
wolf and reveal the wolf
is what Jesus Christ said is the way to
peace.
The reason to understand the ego and how
its structure arises out of the animal
kingdom.
And because of survival, the animal must
of necessity be into mechanical duality.
When he goes to eat a rabbit, he has to
know where the rabbit is.
I'm here. The rabbit's there. He also
classifies things dualistically, edible
and noted edible. A stone is not edible.
And a rabbit is
so that intrinsic mechanism then
conditions uh the mind to a dualistic
to a dualistic way of perception.
And it's the difficulty of spiritual
work to transcend that propensity to
duality.
And the underpinning in the modern human
psyche is in that principle of
causality.
And that's why with every lecture we say
nothing is causing anything.
Everything is spontaneously becoming its
own potentiality.
And that likelihood then is made
possible by saying yes and collapsing
the way wave function so that it can
become an actuality.
Other than that it's a potentiality but
when you say yes to it it becomes an
actuality. Huh?
We're supposed to be talking about
personal life.
For many people it means relationship.
Personal life centers around
relationship. And what makes
relationship work?
Any bookstore is full of 150 books on
how to make your relationship work,
folks.
And if you knew, you wouldn't be reading
it, would you? So
if he knew, he wouldn't be reading it.
Anyway,
um what it has to do with what the world
fools around with is involvement.
Couples are involved with each other.
Boy, are they involved, but they're not
aligned. So, the secret of
what makes a relationship work
effortlessly
is
alignment. The two people are aligned
with each other in purpose and intent.
Now because the mind thinks in terms of
priorities
what you choose as your priority now
will organize everything underneath of
it. See
to win the argument is not really your
priority if you're aligned with the
relationship because your alignment is
with the workability of the relationship
rather than the egotistical
pleasure of being right.
the solar plex. Most couples get
involved in a solar plexus power
struggle over control and who's right
and who's wrong and they get into a game
of oneupmanship.
So any relationship not just marital but
with children with the world with one's
country then has to do with alignment.
A couple who are aligned with each other
means that their well-being
is primary.
whether her coffee is ready in the
morning becomes more important
than going to the bathroom right away.
You can wait and get her coffee going
and then you go to the bathroom. You
know this thing
that's the choice every morning.
She wakes at 6:00. It's quarter 6. I got
time to go to the bathroom. So the
alignment with the other person's
happiness. Why? Because that's your joy.
That's the source of your joy. The
source of joy is not winning an
argument. You don't feel joyful after
you win an argument. You usually feel
guilty or you're still poed or I should
have said that or I could have won if
I'd only said so. So
the a a relationship based on
winningness, who's got control, who's
got the power,
uh
is not going to be gratifying
because they both have an economic stake
and etc. Many of these dismal
relationships can, you know, survive
over time.
For the relationship to be gratifying,
you're both aligned. You're aligned with
intentionality.
Where is intentionality again? So
intentionality then becomes your the
priority is the alignment of your
relationship.
You're devoted you're devoted to
the lovingness of the relationship. You
devoted to be of service to the other
to their needs and their happiness.
That is their joy.
The purpose of the relationship then is
joy.
The purpose of the alignment with God
with devotion
is one of joy.
It doesn't mean an argument won't arise.
The argument is usually one of speed.
It's you'll find out you're both people
are too speeded up in their expectations
and they both head for the refrigerator
at the same time and bump into each
other.
Um but that doesn't change people who
are aligned. People who are aligned
though that bounces off of them. They
realize they were in a hurry. So we get
speeded up in the world. We have
multiple tasks we're trying to
accomplish by a certain specified time.
Lunch today is going to be at 12. You
know what I mean? That we've got this
pressure on us. Everything's got to be
said by 12. You understand?
We have to be back by 1. You know what I
mean? The bus leaves at 3:30. So, we're
all under this particular kind of a
pressure in our society. This is
cultural, by the way. Cultural.
There are many societies in which time
does not become a dominant part of the
ego. The sense of time is a programming
superimposed on
transitory perception. It's superimposed
by the ego. It's like a time track which
the ego superimposes.
And once you get out of that time track,
the relief is tremendous. When you're no
longer driven by time, it's fantastic.
There are cultures in which that is
endemic.
I remember being in Ecuador probably the
early 70s. It was uh tourists didn't go
to South America in those years much
less Ecuador. Nobody ever heard of
Ecuador.
And um but the minute you're in Ecuador
at about 10,000 12,000 ft time stops.
It's just not sort of heavily energized
in their culture. Nobody ever says what
time is it?
There was two planes out a week.
two planes a week out of Ecuador to the
US and uh they went to uh I forget where
they went. It's not important. Florida
someplace. Anyway, they're out of Keo,
which is the capital of Ecuador. Uh so
in this never land of no timeness,
uh I had to remember that the ticket
said we were leaving Wednesday.
So, we go to the airport at uh Wednesday
and uh this lady says, "The Wednesday
plane doesn't leave till Saturday." Oh,
if I was in Chicago, I'd be in a fit,
wouldn't you? I want my tickets
refunded. I'm calling my congressman,
emailing O'Reilly.
Didn't even Didn't Oh, so what? Just
didn't give a damn. Oh, the Wednesday
plane doesn't leave till Saturday. No,
not till Saturday. Oh, okay. It leaves a
Saturday at noon. Oh, okay. Fine. Oh,
okay. Back to the It didn't make any
difference at all. Go back there at at
noon. In the middle of the airport in
Keo, there's a big uh old clock. What's
it from the 1920s or something? Anyway,
it stopped years ago.
Nobody had fixed a clock in years. It
just was stopped at some something. So,
the Wednesday plane didn't leave till
Saturday and the clock stopped. And so,
you know, being an American, I get
there, you know, 11:15 or something like
that to catch the 12:00 plane and
waiting for the plane. There's only one
plane on the runway. As I say, there's
only two planes a week. So, here's this
um plane sitting on the runway and the
engines are running, you know, and so I
expect the quarter 12 we're going to
board or something. Quarter 12, all of a
sudden the plane's engine stopped.
I said to the the lady there at the
desk, there was one lady at the desk in
the airport. I said, "What is it?" She
says, "It's it'sa time.
They're not going to start the plane at
quarter to 12 and siesta is at 12." So
the plane shut down from 12:00 to 3.
I'm thinking to myself in my American
mind, think of what the overhead, just
the insurance, the maintenance, the the
the infrastructure to keep this stupid
plane sitting there for for 3 hours
while they wait for the siesta time.
Anyway, the Wednesday plane didn't leave
at Saturday. It didn't leave at 12:00.
We didn't pull off till 3:00 and they
forgot the baggage anyway. It was
running.
It ran down to Chile and had to come
home a couple days later. I don't know.
And and you see it just didn't matter.
Didn't matter. It was irrelevant.
Totally irrelevant. So, you know, we
take on that time pressure so endemic in
our culture. Our culture calibrates, you
know, around 430 or something and uh
everything runs by the clock. So,
I just wanted to point out that that
it's not um an imprinted reality in your
brain. It's very cultural. And all of
you know that there are experiences
which take you out of time and there's
no way of knowing what really what time
it is. So you stop clocking things in
terms of time.
So the alignment of a relationship then
is somewhat of that nature
in which the time part is not period.
your tasks are caught in time and
because of that the tasks begin to
cause interference in the relationship
and when the two of you realizes you're
just you know being programmed by time
right now it has nothing to do with the
other person it's only a matter of time
that this has to be done this has to be
done and we've only got 45 minutes to do
it it's not a personal matter
so can does everybody understand what I
mean by alignment your commit itted to
the integrity of the relationship to
truthfulness.
It means anything that is mispersceived
by the other person, you feel a
responsibility to clarify what you meant
by that.
You ask for a favor. The person says, "I
can't do it now." They get annoyed with
you. So, you go back later, that person
explains why I I'm sorry. I was annoyed
because I had to do this, that, and the
other. And then you I apologize that I
was um you know not not considerate
enough of the time pressure on the other
person. So there is a constant wanting
to heal misperceptions
heal misconceptions
heal misunderstandings. Why? Because the
happiness
of the other person is of prime
importance to you. Because that's the
nature of love. Huh? That's why we
sacrifice for our children. That's why
we get up in the middle of the night to
feed the cat because the cat's hungry.
You don't want the cat to be unhappy.
You know what I'm saying? So, our
alignment then with our with our uh with
our friends, with our country. You see
how that is being tested right now? How
aligned is one with one's country? And
what does one mean by one's country?
And what does one mean by one's
alignment with mankind?
And when's how does that fit in with
one's alignment with God? You know,
and what does it mean that peace and war
are all the same anyway?
Because the human experience is
purgatorial in nature.
The human dimension in this plane goes
all the way from the most agonizingly
severely cruel and awful that I wouldn't
even tell you the things I hear and know
about coming out of the personal
experiences of people right from let's
say the local area of Phoenix is there
all all the way to the most sublime the
most exquisite
the most ecstatically beautiful
all the way from the most exquisitly
ecstatic beautiful, joyful
to the most terrific. So here we have
the whole panorama
of choice
and within that great dimension then has
to be the opportunity for all the souls
that are here to evolve. So as a karmic
inheritance let's say the nature of
humankind on the planet takes the forms
that it takes.
If we eliminated all war, eliminated all
crime, eliminated all negativity and
eliminated all falsehood, you'd have to
create a whole new planet. Have to take
this one out. Wouldn't serve any purpose
anymore. What good would it be?
What good would
humankind be if it did not
offer us the range from the most
horrific to the most beotific?
It would be a deterministic world in
which there is no karmic merit nor is
there any karmic debt.
No, it's because of the capacity for the
yes response, the collapsing of the wave
function, we affirm this direction or
that direction. And in s so doing,
that's how we get a calibratable level
of consciousness. Uh as you listen to
their complaints are hooked here in the
solar plexus. Huh? They're miserable on
their relationship. Uh it's all sad. Uh
they're disappointed in their
relationship. They're antagonistic with
each other. They're both demanding.
They're prideful in that they're looking
to be right. They're looking to be
right. See, this is what's necess
essential to so many relationships to be
right. And they have so much anger about
this, etc., etc., etc.
They end up, and here's where they end
up, with scorn for themselves, hatred of
themselves. Any divorce lawyer will tell
you they've never seen anything like it.
H the venom that comes out of divorce uh
as everybody is very aware and all these
negative feelings that people feel they
are trapped in the relationship they're
depressed about it or they withdraw from
it they're enslaved by it they get very
aggressive
they get very aggressive
and feeding all this underneath of it is
the egoentricity of the infant
the core of the ego is egoentricity The
infant
who's in a rage that its expectations
and desires and wants are not paramount
not paramount.
One should have what one wants and the
other person should be the way you want
them want them to be. And if they're not
the way you want to be, you should
change them.
That's every wife's duty, is it not?
to domesticate this beast and turn him
into a reasonable husband.
And I'll say that women do a wonderful
job of it because when men are devoid of
women in their culture, they do become
animals.
It's true. You look at the Old West.
Before women arrived, it was gunslingers
and robbers and cattle rustlers. And it
was the law of the jungle, the law of
the gun.
Men degenerate quickly into the wolf
pack. See the instinctual evolution of
man out of animal nature.
We recently had three dogs come onto the
property and kill one of the sheep. And
each of those dogs when it's with its
domesticated family is a wonderful
rover. No doubt. You take away the
discipline of dis of the domestic
contextualization, they quickly revert
to killer pack.
Killer packs were so prevalent there was
in the Arizona Republic that they're
loose and south of Phoenix or some place
in Tempe. Ruving dog packs had everybody
terrified of them.
You see the behavior of the Japanese
after in the
in the slaughter of of Chungqing, the
when the military officership discipline
broke down and the troops
uh were let loose, they quickly reverted
to ravage, pillaging, slaughtering
30,000 innocent people, ch children and
women, looting and stealing and burning.
So the packed mentality lays underneath
there without the civility of
domestication
which is represented by the influence of
the feminine
with the masculine. Otherwise
testosterone would have destroyed the
world long ago.
Testosterone left to its own devices
would have killed off mankind a long
time ago. And of course, what the world
aligns through the UN and various other
cooperative efforts is to try to keep
some madman's testo testosterone from
going crazy and killing us all
because all the horrific rulers of of
history from Genghask Khan on down and
if you can calibrate them all, you'll
find they are all run by an almost a
psychotic level of egoomania.
It is only themsself that they are
interested in. The slaughter of the
millions of the thousands is totally
irrelevant.
It's hard for a normal person to even
imagine that such a degree of
egoentricity exists.
That's why politicians routinely
misdiagnose their opponents. They think
they're coming out of the same
contextualization of reality. They are
not. They think you're a stupid idiot.
And he you can hear
this thinking this this that democracy
is the stupidest thing on the planet.
They let all these immoral idiots get
out there, make these filthy movies, use
drugs, kill each other off, let gangs
run the inner cities,
and you want us to admire that.
You call yourself morally superior. What
a joke.
I'm speaking from China now.
We were civilized for thousands of years
when you were still hanging out in the
trees, chicken. Who do you think you're
talking to?
You understand that?
So alignment with what? With
superiority.
That's what pisses everybody in the
world off about America. It's so so
democracy is so superior. Our lifestyle
is so superior. Our way is so superior.
So superior that they all end us hating
us. Right? It's because of the attitude
of superiority.
So alignment means then to be aligned
with other countries to be aligned with
peace in the world requires humility.
This works for us doesn't mean it's
going to work for you.
Free speech is an idiotic idea. Don't
you understand? You can let every stupid
idiot get out there and get on CBS and
mild off with ignorance and distortions
of truth and give them equal time.
So you can see to other cultures what we
look like. Understand? With humility,
you begin to understand what works for
us
doesn't necessarily work for other
people.
Let's ask about free speech.
We have permission to ask about free
speech.
Now what I'm holding in mind is correct
resist. What I'm holding in mind I'll
verbalize. 80% of free speech is facious
resist. 80% of what's is sold to the
world is free speech is totally facious.
complete distortions coming from
where you hold, you know, you hold back
half of the truth and put it behind you
because to win the case, you can only
present this side of it. When you put
both sides of it, then you got a whole
different story, right?
All right. So that happens in all
relationships. Then the distortion of
the truth and that being the cause of
war. Therefore, the only way to bring
about peace is to discern
that which is truthful and that which is
not
and out of one's own integrity say so.
That is not correct. You know,
peace then comes about from the
elimination of that which interferes
with peace. Just like removing the
clouds from the sky reveals the sun to
be shining.
One's alignment with peace then
is not just a sappy thing appealing to
adolescent minded movie stars.
doesn't need to be politicized.
The making peace a political tool
degrades it. Now it's just another
political scheme
which will now be opposed because it's a
program. Every program then brings up
its opposition
in domestic issues. Then your alignment
is to integrity. If your alignment is to
integrity, then peace automatically
ensues.
So long as you distort truth for your
own gain, you will not have peace.
So you cannot achieve peace
and still have the prevailing energies
in the world that are dominating remain
the same because
the way they are precludes peace.
So peace is the automatic consequence
when you remove the obstacles to it.
Just like enlightenment is the automatic
consequence of the dissolution of the
ego and the transcendence to the
awareness of the presence within
which shines forth as your own
existence. the awareness of your own
existence and the source of that
awareness of your own existence.
Is that clear?
My alignment of course is with the truth
and um with the desire of this group for
truth
and the commitment to radical truth as
the most rapid pathway to God. You know
the experience of the presence of God
within shines forth automatically
when the obstacles to it are removed.
It is not something you do any more than
you can create peace. You cannot create
peace nor can you create the realization
of the self is God imminent as the
presence of God within you.
So
that solves everybody's marital
problems.
So it's always a matter of choice. What
happened to our choice? We'll have to
have choice back on again.
The choice is between being right
or surrendering the pleasure of being
right to the gratifi long-term
gratification of the joy of the
relationship.
You say, "Which is more important to me?
The joy of this of a working
relationship or being right?
I'll be right later after dinner.
I'll be right after dinner, but not
before dinner." Right?
All right.
With the Heisenberg process, intention,
the choice, you see. And through this
process, one, we can either say yes or
not yes to a thing. we say yes or not
yes. So if if you say yes, I'd rather be
right, I'd rather be right
and have the other one be wrong, then
you've made the choice. Then that choice
automatically limits you to the solar
plexus where being right is a profound
importance. The only thing important in
the solar plexus is getting gain and
being right.
When I when I look at a lot of of
our culture, it looks to me like a lot
of solar plexuses running around each
other.
Control freaks all trying to control
each other. You know, and there's always
a dogooder out there with a new program
that's going to be for my own good,
which always means a loss of my freedom
or my liberty. You know what I'm saying?
Why does it always have to cost me for
them?
Because they're not aligned with
freedom. They're aligned with being
right.
You can have bars where you can smoke
and you have bars where you don't smoke.
I mean, you know what's the problem?
No, they got nobody's bar that's in
Tempee. Tempe right now is having a big
war over that. Nobody's bar can smoke.
You know why can't a smoking bartender
working in a smoking bar with smoking
friends and take their smoking family
there. I don't know.
You see, if people are aligned with
freedom, nobody resists them. You see
that? But when you get aligned with the
positionality, now half of Tempe is
against that. There's some politicians
there that want to make all of Tempino
smoking or something. And of course, all
they have done is crystallize the
opposition, you know, over my dead body,
my cold cold hand. Are you you? So, you
see, oppositionality then creates
strife, conflict, and war. The war is
inevitable.
There it's not shooting, but on other
dimensions, it's shooting.
Positionality then creates conflict.
Conflict and duality of of right. right
versus wrong.
Uh, and the power freaks come out of the
woodworks and there's lots of them. Anal
control freaks. We never calibrated anal
control freaks. Can we do them?
>> Well, that's common psychological
jargon.
>> Okay,
>> we have permission to ask about them. We
did. They're over 170. 175.
They're over 180. 185.
Anyway, they're around 190 around in
there because it has to do with power
and pride and I'm right and you're
wrong. And you see freedom doesn't enter
into their calculation.
Why? Because it's your freedom. If it's
their freedom, that's a different thing.
So, they have the freedom and the right
to a smokefree bar if they like and
other people have equal freedom. So, if
you're dedicated to freedom, then you
don't get opposition from people. If
you're dedicated to freedom, uh you then
you don't get opposition because you
don't polarize people. So that's
alignment then and it tries to
circumvent the human weakness.
Um
all right.
So consciousness principles then are are
critical to success and happiness and
peace in any endeavor. It has to do with
what your align the alignment with your
purpose because saying yes intention and
purpose is so powerful. It determines
everything else. You see every the mind
prioritizes goals.
The highest purpose and priority holds
dominion. Everything then becomes
aligned underneath that.
In any relationship that's not working,
one can look and see
what is your what are you aligned with?
What is your the integrity of your
intention? I get a letter from a man.
He's very disturbed. He's discovered his
child is homosexual and what should he
do about that? I thought maybe he ought
to go to church or something. Do the
course of miracles. Join a 12step group.
gays u anonymous u friends or something
do the 12 steps at it you know what I
mean u what should he do about it you
see what I'm saying there's already it's
already judged to be wrong now there's
also the intention to change it wants to
change it if you want to change
somebody's lifestyle you're going to get
resistance right so what does he think
he's going to do you know
uh so the naivity of it so underneath
all of The strife and agony and pain
that we go through is the innate
innocence of mankind. The innocence of
consciousness.
Consciousness itself then is like the
hardware of the computer.
And the ego then is the superimposed
software,
the basic intrinsic innocence of it all.
The mind will believe anything it's
programmed to believe.
The Third Reich found that out. Gables
found out. They programmed the young
children in Germany from childhood in
which becoming a killer was like being a
boy scout with just good patriotism,
love of country and it was your honor to
die for Adolf Hitler.
How easy it is to program people and how
cleverly is done by those who seek
control over others. Huh?
That's why enlightenment is extremely
rare because when you look at the course
of human history, when you look at the
nature of human consciousness, when you
look at the structure of the ego,
you wonder how anybody makes it through
the minefield.
How can you make it through this
minefield? The temptations, the
seductions, the traps, the scenarios
hidden in the hidden the hidden agendas
behind so many pop sounding political
slogans and agendas and spiritual
supposedly spiritual groups etc.
You wonder how anybody makes it through.
You make it you wonder how anybody makes
it through.
Well, once devotion to truth then begins
to arm you. Because if that's your
priority, what it tends to do is expose
that which is not true.
When you're committed to actually
knowing the truth and following the
strict pathway to truth, straight and
narrow is the path.
Then it tends to uh unearth and reveal
by your intentionality
that which is detrimental to that
your goal. That which is detrimental to
your goal now becomes exposed.
You didn't realize that that person was
secretly undermining you. But now you
suddenly become aware of it.
All right? So integrity then begins to
shake out that which is non- integrous
and make it more visible. Make it more
visible.
If you want peace, you have to be
peaceful. Huh?
It means you can't get into better than
others. You can't mean that winning is
more important.
Making other people do it your way loses
any significance. Why would I want the
people in Ecuador to do it any different
way than they were doing it? I mean, to
me it was perfect. I should have moved
to Ecuador like an idiot. I didn't. I
came back.
That to me is a perfect place to live.
They forgot about time years ago. And u
equinimity. So there's a prevailing
peace and equinimity. And as you
progress in your spiritual work, you're
attracted to that which is peaceful and
equin and and aligned with that um
peacefulness
as a way of being in the world.
So like love which is not dualistic.
It's not a this loves that. It's
lovingness is a state of being in the
world. Consequently, peacefulness is an
inner choice.
And when one becomes
that which out of which peace arises,
peace does not arise out of
winning the argument.
Truth doesn't just stand by itself and
as a hypothetical possibility. It
becomes energized by devotion.
So devotional non-duality means
that one is aligned with the fastest and
straightest pathway to the realization
of the presence of God within.
One is willing to sacrifice everything
to it. And one is devoted to the task.
One is devoted to discovering what is
the truth or falsehood no matter what.
Therefore, the reason we redid the
kinesiologic test this morning is it
because it is the only way known to
discover the wolf in sheep's clothing in
today's world.
The argumentation is so ingenious.
Plus, it's often done by people who are
quite intellectually adept and the
structuring of the fallacy is so
cleverly done that a person of less
intellect and less education would have
no way of discerning that it's totally
corrupt and totally false.
I read scientific treatises all day long
that the minute you pick up the article
and get the energy of it and get the
stated objective, you already got what
it's all about.
I got what his agenda is and I don't
need to read the article because I
already got how I know it's going to
end. Yeah,
it's extremely cleverly done and today's
world is al often give a given a veneer
of acceptability by labeling it as
science.
Labeling it as science, huh?
Without the aid of some means of
discerning truth from falsehood, I don't
see any way through the minefield. It
can by karmic propensity
be a spontaneous occurrence but
statistically the likelihood of that is
extremely rare to come out of the pits
of hell and stand in the presence of the
infinite allness of
uh God is uh not statistical like likely
like likelihood
mankind to evolve more rapidly now I
think mankind's going to evolve more
rapidly just the news that there's a way
of telling truth from falsehood is
enough to shake the roof and rafters of
many. In fact, what we went through when
we connected it up with quantum
was considerable.
It is not going to be the favorite thing
of large masses of people and powerful
influences on the planet that there is a
way of discerning truth from falsehood.
That will not make you the most popular
person on the block. I guarantee you and
if you know how to discern truth from
falsehood, I would keep it to myself.
If you wish to long live a long life,
it's best to
hold it from the context of wisdom. See,
intelligence is one thing. Wisdom is
something else. Wisdom now
u incorporates uh into the overall
picture context.
So you'll see that most error is done by
distorting content at the expense of
ignoring context. We've made this point
in previous lectures because it is a
extreme point of discernment. Once the
third eye opens you see that uh that
what the error is one of
contextualization.
It's a loss of freedom to have your
baggage searched, but not in time of
war. Time of war is not a loss of
freedom because the meaning of freedom
and its definition shifts with
conditions, shifts with context,
shifts with context.
The lack of discerning the balance
between content and context is really
the biggest source of error in the human
condition.
To be so naive that a political system
that works for us must prevail on the
planet and other people must
go with it is why French taxi drivers
hate Americans.
You go to France, you get in the
taxi cab, say you speak English. Right
away, you got a hostile response.
American.
All right.
Our lack of humility.
So, it's the value of attraction rather
than promotion.
That is a valid concept used in
spiritual groups that are probably the
most successful spiritual groups on the
planet today.
The 12step groups survive and one of
their principles is attraction and not
promotion.
People come to America because we've got
a terrific system going
because they're attracted to it. you
know, doesn't mean I have to go to
Ecuador and if they're not going to
become a de democracy, kill them all.
You know what I mean? I don't know what
kind of government they even have there
to tell you the truth.
Uh they must had a recent volcano there.
So, the gods must be angry about
something then.
Peacefulness then means you're committed
and aligned with other people's freedom.
If you're aligned with their freedom,
then you are
enforcing your own. The only way you can
achieve your own freedom is by
commitment to the freedom of everyone to
be who they are. They're somewhere on
the karmic learning curve. They're
somewhere on the evolution of
consciousness of of mankind. And because
they're not on the same point of the
pathway as you are, doesn't mean you're
right and they're wrong. It means
they're at a different evolutionary
path. Everyone is learning something.
You know, for the majority of mankind,
it's questionable whether peace is
better than war.
Whether love is better than hate.
The most primitive axioms have not even
been agreed upon.
What is the value of human life? You
think you know, you don't know. Another
c culture thinks you're idiotic.
Break the law, execution.
That's the law of the land. They have a
drug problem, of course not. But you get
caught with drugs, you're executed.
They think that's the correct way.
Who's to say it's wrong?
They don't have a drug problem there.
Singapore, I think, right?
Drugs, death, instant execution.
They think that's what makes sense and
our way is stupid. You know what I'm
saying? How can we sell our way to a
people who see it differently? So you
see we're dealing in difference of
paradigms of the real versus the unreal,
the important versus the unimportant. It
has to do with content and context. It
has to do with where you are in the
evolution of consciousness. It has to do
where you are with the evolution of your
culture. As I mentioned before, when the
president of China was interviewed by an
American
interviewer on TV, I was embarrassed for
America to tell you embarrassed. The
disrespect of this
uh cocky guy against the ruler of the
greatest nation on earth, China is the
greatest nation on earth. Who do you
think he was talking to? That man is
extremely brilliant. got an IQ that outf
fox the interviewer. It's embarrassing
that lack of humility, you see. Um
because our cultural style doesn't work
for for them and and vice versa. So he
said, "Well, we may have some civil
rights violations in your viewpoint, but
what about the drugs, the crime, the
wars?
Uh
we have 3% of our population in prison
right now, the highest in the world."
You know, so he looked back at him. He
said, "You do have a few problems of
your own." I thought it was sort of a
subtle way to put him back down again.
But you see how arrogance then polarizes
the world. Arrogance is what polariz
polarizes world. They don't hate us
because we're successful. They hate us
because we rub their face in it. That's
why.
Um,
so what we need then is to pull in our
pseudopodia from everybody else's
business. Try humility. Try supporting
peace and peace is not supported by our
we're right and your own.
So we're just talking about a domestic
issue now because we're the human family
is just one huge huge family. So if
we're aligned with the freedom of other
people to be who they are then
u and stop um bullying them uh with
moral superiority
uh and the dogooderism
of people who want to restrict the
freedom of others so that their pet
positionalities can be forced on others.
So that's what prevails in all
relationships in the domestic. It
certainly makes the difference between
joy and a feeling of fulfillment. So a
successful relationship then is one that
brings joy, contentment, a feeling of
security.
If the relationship is working, you feel
emotionally safe with the other person.
Emotionally safe. What does that mean?
It means you can reveal your downside
and the other person will help you
overcome it. Reontextualize it for us.
So one of the greatest gifts we give
each other is we recontextualize it back
to the other person
instead of grieving over that la loss.
Don't you see that that which you were
attached to is tying you down and now
without that in your life your life is
freer. It's true when you lose one job
you now have the freedom to choose all
over again. It's not just loss it's gain
of freedom to totally reassess your
position your vocational choice. Do you
really want to stay here anymore? you
really want to work that are those the
work goals you really have is salary the
only thing that counts is the pleasantry
of the people you how important is it
you know the girls ranch arm chief of
staff you know the main attraction is
first of all my services are needed and
there's a shortage of doctors but the
other thing is the staff is joyful to be
with and as chief of staff that's been
my purpose to have a joyful staff to be
with in which we do everything out of
cooperation and love and mutual respect
so You naturally want to stay there
because it's, you know, wonderful place.
What they pay is sort of irrelevant, you
know. Um, it's secondary. It's the
feeling of satisfaction that you get out
of that particular workplace. So, you
lose a job, you say instead of grieving
a loss, this is maybe a call to
reexamine what are my goals in life?
Huh? What are my goals in life? What
really makes me happy? What makes me
feel satisfied? And there's a certain
point in which making money is very,
very important. And you should
It should be committed to that because
it is necessary to the achievement of
certain goals. So it becomes subsidiary.
It's not the money. It's the fact that
you know you can afford health insurance
and that has to do with your wife's
security and happiness and the safety
and security of your family. So all this
you see again subserves love. It's
because of lovingness that you want
those around you to be and to feel safe
and cared for and loved. And um that's
why the bread earner earns the bread is
for the joy and peace and happiness
security of the family and those that
they love. So one's alignment with love,
one's alignment with integrity.
So recontextualization then is one of
the greatest ways we can serve each
other. And uh if one of them one is down
in the dumps, the other one says
but what about and presents it. So
it's our love for each other that brings
us about peace. Our love for
each other and our love for our own
existence. You see, because you cannot
love God and hate your own existence.
Unless you glory in your own existence,
you cannot glory in the presence of God.
Because the evidence of God is the
subjective awareness of your own
existence and that is the source of joy.
And so out of your love for each other
and your alignment in the relationship,
you experience the joy of your own
existence just as I enjoy being what I
am to thee this day.
We'll reconvene at 1:00. God bless.
Fore! Foreign! Foreign!
foreign
go
Going
Fore
for we hope and Rick
Going
to go rainbow.
Womanch.
foreign.
No
more
in no
glor.
Thank you. Let's
do an
uh in the interest of equality we will
doctor and I would like to do an oh
could you uh actually all of us could
you uh put that up the oh that was just
on
just
it's yeah it's on that CDA
The second track
you can join with us. Find it yourself.
Oh.
If that don't make God happy, nothing
will.
I can hear him laughing as we speak. He
he talks it only in Sanskrit.
>> Thank you, Nico. You're a great gift to
us.
>> Well, I thought we might enjoy that. So,
anybody have any questions about it?
Questions arise in content but in
context there are no questions because
it's belong beyond languaging.
It's the subjective experience of one's
existence. Yeah.
And that's the radical reality of
subjective the subjective state.
The sense of eye is the radical state of
subjectivity.
When one lets go identification with the
physicality, the mind, the emotions,
yeah, and all definitions of self,
that which prevails constantly in all
times, in all places,
is why it's difficult to
become aware of. It's like space. We
take it for granted. It's the sense of
self, the sense of one's existence.
People
say what is the fastest way to that
space? The fastest way to that space is
to witness to notice
that the mind at all times is silent
except for a small talkingness space
and everybody focuses on the talkingness
space because that's where the action
is. That's where the entertainment is.
So, there's a little TV set in your head
that keeps you fascinated and hypnotized
because it talks all the time.
What you don't realize is that the
majority of your mind is silent at all
times.
Right this instant,
99.9%
of your mind is silent.
1% is tracking what's happening.
A tenth of 1% is tracking what's being
said.
The prevailing silence of the mind is
the source, the space, the presence, the
awareness
of the reality of that which you are.
The reality of that which you are then
is in the area of the silence.
So there's no point of looking for it in
reading another book because it's not in
the book.
It's not in the construct.
What the instruction does is show you
how to leave
the that dimension of distraction and
retreat into the inner reality.
That's the purpose
which in which mind serves no mind.
And therefore the only purpose of
the mind is to lead you to
where no mind is.
Yeah. No mind. Where is no mind? Good
God.
No mind is taking care of everything
today. So we don't have to worry about
anything because no mind is guaranteed
that it'll snow today.
and that Nico will do the chant and that
all will be well and that lunch will be
served
and that is all taken care of silently
because of the options because of the
things we have said yes to then
the potentiality becomes an actuality
to have chosen enlightenment as one's
goal is the only reason anyone is here
so by reason of choice or a reason of
saying yes one manifests into one's life
the way
and uh the company of people that are on
a similar way uh who mutually support
each other because they're aligned with
the same goal.
The field of consciousness then is a
field of infinite power. Infinite power,
stationary, unmoving
by choice. What we do is we allow the
infinite power
to take us effortlessly to where we're
going.
Therefore,
although intention is absolute, effort
is really minimal.
The only effort is then letting go of
the satisfaction out of the
positionality
which is blocking it.
As we let go the satisfaction,
what we're getting out of being right or
winning, whatever it might be, you will
you don't have to let go of being right.
You only have to get let go of the
satisfaction of it. So the attachments
that we talk about how to let go of
attachments, attachments to what? The
attachment is not to winning. The
attachment is to the satisfaction.
The attachment is to the satisfaction
of burying the dagger deep in the heart
of our enemy. How gratifying.
Earn
make him suffer for what he's done to
us.
That's what we're attached to. The
pleasure of that. Okay. We're not
attached to turning daggers in people's
hearts. I mean, it's a drag.
Get blood all over you. The guy screams.
I mean, Jesus, that
not exactly pleasant. No, what you're
you want is the gratification.
So, when you see that the ego is really
easy to transcend by letting go,
the gratifications we get out of its
temptations. So, what is temptation?
Temptation then is the attachment to the
gratification of the ego's positions.
That's all.
The shorter way is to let go of
attachment itself.
And therefore, I'll give you a secret
how to get enlightened before dinner
time.
Attachment itself is the attachment.
The Buddha Sarin
It's the senses. No, it's the attachment
to the senses. It's not sex and money
and fame and power and all those things.
It's the attachment.
All right? So, curiously, the mind is
attached to attachment.
So, you see what we look for is a common
root that we can cut that root and then
a hole.
immense dimension of the ego collapses.
We're attached to attachment itself.
Why so? Well, certainly in the process
of evolution,
attachment is how physical survival
comes about. One is attached to the
umbilical accord, attached to the
placenta, attached to mother's womb.
Outside the womb, then one is attached
to the mother, the mother's milk, the
mother's nurturance, etc. Attachment
becomes what we're attached to.
We're attached to attachment.
Now, the sophisticated child,
the more evolved child, because we're
all born with a certain level of
consciousness,
becomes attached to the love, the love
of the mother. The less evolved being
gets attached to the physicality of the
mother
is unable to discern. It's not the
mother that's keeping you alive. It's
the mother's love. To ascribe one's
survival then to the linear is the great
error because your survival is coming
from the nonlinear.
In World War II, the children, the
infants were taken out of London, the
time of the Blitz, and they were taken
out into
doiciles out in the safe country and
they died by the thousands. They stopped
eating, they became apathetic, they
became arasmic, they became depressed,
they stopped responding and they died. H
they died.
So
physicality then is not enough. It buff
it baffles science because nutritionally
they had everything vitamins and
balanced diets and germfree environments
etc. And they died right and left. And
then they brought in some nannies.
What's the matter with these infants?
And the nannies began to hug them and
cuddle them and jostle them on their
knee and box them on their ears when
they deserved it and they flourished.
So
survival comes from the nonlinear.
If you came from the linear, those
children would have thrived.
Scientifically designed nutritional
diets.
Good medical care, safe doicile,
and they died by the thousands.
a dirty, horrible old nanny with germs
all over,
jouncing them around and doing all kinds
of unhygienic things and the child
prospers.
All right? So, one's survival then is
coming from the nonlinear.
Attachment is the mistake of attaching
it to the linear.
To attach your survival to the linear.
To think that it's the ego that's
keeping you alive is making the mistake
of the child
who gets attached to the physicality and
fails to get that is the energy field of
the the love of the mother to which it
owes its survival.
One's survival is guaranteed until the
point of death.
The good news is
you came in with a certain calibrated
level of consciousness.
The good news is you didn't enter the
embryo until the third month of the
embryo's life.
The good news is that the time of which
you're going to leave the body has
already set at the time of birth.
So I worry fine.
>> Then we read of uh about 20 years ago,
the one I always liked was the
airliner at 30,000 ft and the door
suddenly came off and exactly one person
was picked out of the airliner. 300
people. She happened to be the
stewardist. The stewardist was picked
out.
No one else. Huh.
When is your time is your time. When
it's not, it's not. So why worry about
it? You understand?
If you project yourself forward to the
time of death, picture yourself laying
on the deathbed, families gathered all
around, doctor looks grave.
I was going to say the hers is waiting
outside, but that's not the room.
racing his engine.
Anyway, as you are there on death store,
I want you to realize that to get to the
your deathbed, you have to have
survived.
So when I say you have to survive all
the way to your deathbed, you can quit
worrying about it because somehow
something kept you alive and going until
that great moment. Okay? Great moment of
release.
If you don't have to worry about life
and birth and death, that's solves a lot
of problems
to be attached to attachment itself.
Therefore, attachment itself is a
process. It thinks that clingingness is
what guarantees your survival.
So the clean clingingness is to
cleanness itself.
And in letting go of the cleanness
itself,
there is nothing to which it can be
attached.
Then you're free forever.
Free forever.
The physic the physicality is sometimes
uh in the way of
the expression of ecstasy.
When we listen to that music, you want
to play the music,
we said we calibrated that music around
740.
When I talk about calibrating things,
we're talking generally about a range.
Um, I wanted to clarify that also
whether a thing is 735 or 740 in the way
in which in the context in which we're
using it is irrelevant. What you want to
know is it in the 700s, low 700s, high
700s, is it over 500? Maybe there's a
critical line of 200 or 500. But in
general, what we're asking is what is
the general range of where this is.
The calibrated levels of consciousness
are therefore sort of rough generalities
in a way. There is probably a great deal
of difference between
402 and 404. So if we got into m more
microscopic research,
we could have a whole class of people
researching out for a number of years
what are the differences in every area
of life. Love, relationship, earnings,
uh your preference for uh TV programs,
what channels you watch, which
commentators you prefer, which
newspapers you read, what magazines.
There's probably quite a lot of
difference between 402 and 404. When you
look at it in microscopic analysis,
annual earnings, the number per thousand
of people who have doctorates in that
particular field, etc. So microscopic
analysis is different than the way we're
using it. We're looking at generalities,
you know, in what level in what level
does that range so that we can get a
feeling and a sense of it.
If we calibrate the music we had this
morning in the 700s
then we know you know about it's in the
mid 735 738 something. If you're going
to do more microscopic uh analysis which
we occasionally do do uh then one has to
be extremely specific in the way it's
languaged. one has to be aware of
whether you're talking about the memory
of it, the sense of it, the feel of it,
the identity of it, the
or the uh definition of it etc. So
that's much more concentrated,
not suitable for demonstration purposes.
We want to know what does the 700s feel
like? The 700s feels like the music that
was played before and we'll play it
again. The 700s feels like Nico's
chanting. Nico's chanting calibrates
around 740, 750 around there.
That's what the 700s feel like.
That's what they look like.
If we want to know if a politician is
coming from
honesty or not,
we get, let's say he's at 450, 455. It
doesn't make any difference whether he's
452 or 455. You understand? We get that
he's coming from the mid-range of what
in our world is accepted as reasonable,
logical, provable,
ethical,
and integrous. Huh?
Sometimes all you really want to know is
whether a thing is over 200 or not.
There's lots and lots of spiritual
books.
Some of them are frankly quite deranged.
But anyway,
you can walk through any bookstore. No,
not their book. Your books there. Most
people in the spirituality have
accumulated tons of books on everything.
And we've mentioned before if you
calibrate is whether they're integrous
or not. Just do integrous or not. The
books that make you go strong and the
books books that make you go weak
and you put them in two different piles
and then you sort of after a week or so
walking around between them you get what
is imagination and what is reality. You
know,
as I say, many of them are convincing.
So, the main thing you want to know is
it over 200 or not. And many people send
me books they want me to calibrate.
And you know, it's really irrelevant.
They're either integrous or they're not
integrous because the only important
thing about the spiritual pathway is
whether you're on it. Not really
important how far you are on it. It's
the fact that you're on it.
78% of the population hasn't made it
out of the water onto the beach yet.
Huh?
Hasn't come down out of the trees yet.
Yeah.
78% of the population is hasn't even
gotten to first base yet.
See what's important? What's important?
What's important is to cross this line
here at 200. You know what's important
is to be
is to begin to value integrity, to value
truth, to value honesty, to value love.
Now, as incredible as it may sound, I
say a great part of the world's
population cannot decide whether love is
better than hate.
There are many countries in which you
can be executed for lovingness. Do you
know that that it's illegal?
To this day,
certainly in Paul Pot's
country,
any
exhibiting any degree of love was
considered weakness and a crime
punishable by death.
a weakness.
When it's time to skewer your enemy, if
you hesitate out of mercy, you get you
get shot in subordination.
They have a very clear idea of right and
wrong.
Love is wrong.
Love is a weakness.
whether peace is better than war.
Most of the people on the planet would
say no, it's not.
78% of the pe people on the planet
don't want peace at any price.
How do we know that? Because if people
wanted peace, they would have it.
Simple.
If they said yes to peace, then they
would have peace. The fact that we don't
have peace means that most people do not
want peace.
There's no point of parading in the rain
and the snow, folks.
78% of the people out there having the
slightest interest in peace.
Why? Because you would have to give up
the satisfaction of being right.
Who's going to give that up?
Most people would rather die than admit
they were wrong. And they do by the
millions. By the millions. By the
millions.
So the main cause of death is not war.
War has got nothing to do with it.
War is just the mechanism by which
you've killed yourself by worshiping
falsehood instead of truth.
Anybody can have peace anytime he wants
it. All he has to do is be willing to
sacrifice being right to peace. There
you go. How long did that take?
One second. If the world wanted peace,
it would have it right now.
You can't sell people peace.
It doesn't have much appeal.
Peace as a political slogan.
As a reality, people despise it.
People do anything to avoid it.
People hate it.
Brings an end to their dreams.
brings an end to their illusions of the
source of their power,
the value of their lifestyle.
Peace would invalidate most of the
positionalities that holds their whole
mind together.
Winning and gaining, being right,
subverting the truth under distortions
of truth would destroy the whole
political system.
Where would you hide?
If this side is against this and this
side is against that and obviously 50%
are wrong right to start with. Right?
So truth is not something you can vote
for.
So the value of integrity in today's
society and those of you in the audience
who are trying to take spiritual
principles into business know that
integrity is now becoming the you the
new yard stick.
That which is respected that which the
world is be is learning is the best
investment.
The best investment we can make is in
that which is integrous.
So we invest in our own commitment to
truth.
We ask God for help to overcome the
obstacles of which we are aware and
which we are unaware that stand in its
way.
And as each one of us chooses
truth over falsehood,
we transform the world into the state of
peace.
That is how peace comes about.
It comes about as the con the automatic
consequence of each one of us
rejecting falsehood.
To reject it, you first have to be able
to identify it.
So in a way the pathway to truth
devotional non-duality is the same as
renunciation.
Those who are committed to enlightenment
are by definition renunciates.
You're renunciates of falsehood.
You're renunciates of idols.
You're a renunciate of the
gratifications of the temptations of the
ego.
So renunciation is an inwardness
commitment.
It can be symbol uh it can be symbolized
by joining a saga. It can be symbolized
by joining a monastery.
It can be symbolized by dietary
regulation and prayers,
styles of haircut, dress, sandals, the
whole deal. Though what they symbolize
is your commitment in and of themselves.
They are meaningless
as symbols of what you are committed to.
They're merely a confirmation.
The true spiritual devote then is a
renunciate of all that stands in the way
of peace and renounces it because of its
falsehood.
To be able to see that it's falsehood is
the purpose of the kinesiologic test. So
the purpose of the test is to subserve
the removal of that which is false upon
the planet. And by removing that which
is false only the true remains
and that which is true is not different
than peace.
The way to peace then is to be able to
identify falsehood. Let go your
attachment to it even though you're
enamored of it
and be willing to sacrifice the
gratification that you get out of that
positionality
and surrender it to God. Therefore, the
devotion is to truth.
No matter what you're attached to, you
say
to thee, oh God, do I deliver this.
The choice is always between God
or that positionality.
Out of devotion to God, one is willing
to lay down
the gratification and satisfaction of
that positionality
of getting even, being right.
indulging in woe. Indulging in guilt.
Guilt is egocentric.
Following in guilt is really
self-indulgence.
It's being like a skinny aesthetic with
his hair hanging down to his knees all
filthy and dirty.
That's an intelligence, folks.
getting off on aeticism, right? Oh,
no. Bagging bones himself. I know. I've
done it. You go for weeks without
eating, bathing, shaving, sunshine,
combing your hair.
And I told you, I think one time I
walked right into the wall in that
state. Body just disappeared. I didn't
know it was there. And walked around and
there was this person in the mirror.
shocked the wits out of me that somebody
was in the house with me.
And I I I couldn't understand what that
was. And then I realized, oh, oh yes.
And I walked away from it and walked
right into the wall. Smack into the
wall.
Complete disidentification with the
physicality. Huh.
Well, that doesn't serve the world too
well.
It came that that was a
self-gratification, a narcissistic
self-indulgence and piety.
You know, work in piety for all the
spiritual ego you can get out of it,
right?
It's like looking down on people who
aren't humble, right?
You're looking down at people who aren't
spiritual, right? Yeah.