the lectures with the same realization, the same statement about reality. Can you still hear me?
All right. Certain spiritual information in and of itself is transformational. To have merely
heard it already leaps one ahead in one's understanding of reality. And so I always
start with something to help us jump the whole level of the 400s, which is such a big block to
the average spiritual seeker. So we begin with the observation that nothing is causing anything.
The theory of causation calibrates around 460. It's central to the scientific paradigm.
It's central to the Newtonian paradigm of reality. But enlightenment doesn't happen in
the Newtonian paradigm of reality. It happens when you do it.
It happens when you transcend it. I do have a bad throat, don't I?
We call 9-11 and they're sending somebody. They'll be here in a minute.
Nothing is causing anything. Everything is what it is of its own self, of its own self.
Because each thing is coming out of creation at this moment, being what? It's
full of
It's fulfilling.
It's fulfilling its karmic potentiality.
The only question that's raised here today is do I know anything about reality
all along the history of God's creation?
Just to build your own reflection from the movies of education,
even might be a Spritzer programme,
You know I have pressure on my memory around my head and voice as much as I can,
It consists of not only years in a up and down process,
but it also consists of ten years with the transcendent of it everything.
to become a rose.
And if the conditions are appropriate,
it fulfills its potentiality.
So this petal is not causing this petal.
This stem is not causing the flower.
The roots are not causing, nothing is causing anything.
So what we witness is everything fulfilling its destiny,
its karmic potentiality,
to the best that it can under prevailing conditions.
Consequently, evolution and creation
are one and the same thing.
What we witness is the unfolding of creation
from instant to instant.
Isn't that simple?
The reason it's critical is,
the other reason it's critical to know this
is because if you reverence the concept of causality,
what you establish then is there must be an I causing that.
There must be,
you create the duality of a personal separate I
from the infinite reality of the presence of divinity.
Consequently, causality firmly then establishes
a duality in your mind.
People who are somewhat naive will remark
that the doctor is channeling something.
You know, he does great channeling.
That comes from that same idea of duality.
You see, channeling is in duality.
There would be an entity on the other side
like whispering in my ear,
and then there's a me that hears that
and announces it to you, you know?
That would really freak me out.
Dave, come on, listen, you know what I'm saying?
Yeah.
When you see reality, you see then
that everything is merely being what it is.
So the speaker at this moment is spontaneously being
what it is, speaking for the knowingness within,
which is a presence which is silent.
I can ask questions all day, I don't hear anything.
So each thing stands forth to the fullest extent
that it can be what it is at that moment.
We may see it as limitation, but that's our perception.
It's being as good as it can be at the moment.
Even though we would say it's being bad.
You take the package and you can't open it,
you get angry.
Things are now packaged to make sure
you can't get them open.
There's no way to get them open.
I struggle, I try.
So each thing is being what it can be
to the greatest extent it can be that.
I want to calibrate something.
What I'm holding in mind is 500.
505, 506, 508. My god, that's some dog. We ran into a wonderful loving dog in the
corner there who looked up at me and says, I'm over 500. Turned out he's 505.
Usually a dog's wagging tail is right at 500 or a kitty spur. I said, there's
something about that dog, 505. The fastest way to discover the intrinsic
reality of that which you are and the true nature of the universe is through
reverence. Through reverence for all of life, however it may appear to us at the
moment. Each thing is being the best it can. You watch a videotape of a bank
robber and you see he's got his mask on and he's waving his gun. I mean he's
being the best possible bank robber he can be at the moment. He's doing a
magnificent job. I mean some of them should be on Broadway. They're
fantastic. He's acting out some fantasies, some positionality, and so it's
irrelevant to say whether what he's doing is good or bad. Good or bad has
nothing to do with it. Somebody's got a gun in your head, let's not worry about
good or bad. You see that mostly what
you're doing is good or bad. You see that mostly what you're doing is good or bad. You see that mostly what
the mind says about things is a luxury and when you're seeking enlightenment you
have to forego the luxury of constant commentary on life and evaluation,
righting and wronging it, trying to decide whether God is a liberal or
conservative. So we have some interesting new things today. We always have
new things, but I don't want to shock people too much with too many new things.
What happened to eyes? All right, so let's do eyes. I was going to do movies today
and then I decided to do eyes. We did 150 movies at the end of which Susan couldn't
lift her right arm for about a week. Devotional non-duality means devotion to truth, devotion to vintage,
to divinity as it reveals itself by truth. It means to witness the sacredness of all of life.
If you treat all of life with reverence and witness the sacredness of all of life, you
will soon identify yourself as the field and not the content of the field. Formally the
project is to transcend the ego and one's identification with it. So I thought you'd
like some new research we've done and we'll verify it this morning.
We're speaking out of the other side of my mouth now? Yes. I'll speak out of the other side of my mouth.
I'll have to be good enough the way I am. I'll have to look into that. We said that, we say all the time,
that at all times the majority of the mind is actually silent. And so if we calibrate if that's
true, let's calibrate if that is true. At all times ninety-eight percent of the mind is
silent.
What we hear is the clatter of one or two percent. Ninety-eight percent of your mind
is silent at all times. So why complain about it? You're only talking about two percent.
Well that cuts down the project, doesn't it? I just saved you ninety-eight percent of what
you thought you were going to have to do. You're welcome. Yes.
So why does the, why does the remaining two percent seem to be such a problem? And we
discovered it's because you are in a hypnotic state, hypnotized by that two percent. Resist.
You are in a trance. Resist. Everybody is in a hypnotic trance at the effect. You've
become the prisoner through hypnosis of that two percent. You've become entranced with
it, fascinated with it, and now you've let two percent of your mind run all of you. And
that's not a good investment. Ninety-eight percent then would reveal the true nature
of reality. So when I say try to find the silent part of your mind, first of all you
have to know it exists. Right at this moment, right before you just had that last thought,
your mind was silent. Yep, and now it's silent again. And now it's silent again. And then
a little word goes across.
Hypnotic state. One can pray to God to relieve you and return you to sanity from being at
the effect of hypnosis, a hypnotic trance from the content of one's mind, and pray for
liberation. Liberation means to be liberated from the illusion that you are the two percent.
Let's see where the two percent gets its juice from. Huh. If nonduality is, you know, the
state of enlightenment, then duality would be the state one wishes to transcend. So we
found the way through the eyes. The I-Z-E of life. We polarize, stems from the process
that we're going to call eyes. This two percent eyes-es you all the time. And how does it
eyes you? Well, you'll see. When it looks at something out there, it has the habit of
politicizing it. Everywhere I speak, everybody asks me to do George Bush. What do they think
he's going to come out? Ninety-two or something? Not the same as Roosevelt, Truman, the same
as every other president. Okay, so we ask, is God a liberal? We go, no, he's not. The
Buddha said, wisdom is the middle way. Okay. All right. Because either extreme is insanity,
right? So politicize then causes dissension and conversation in your mind. You read the
paper, you argue with the news, you argue with the editorial writer. So to politicize
is instantly to create a duality and create conflict. That's one of the great enemies
of peace. The next great enemy of peace is to moralize. So if we politicize and moralize,
which is everybody's habit when they read the paper or watch the news, you can see why
everything is divided into good or bad.
Moralize. What if you didn't moralize? What if you were just the witness? Let's say you're
from another planet, another galaxy, and you're here to witness the phenomena in this place
and report back, but all you can say is things seem to be happening. Things go up, things
go down, things live, they fall over, something is born, they clap or they cry, depending
on the circumstances.
Yeah.
When it passes out of existence and they call it dying,
people clap or cry depending on the circumstances.
Glad to see that one go.
The best thing he did for mankind is pass on it.
Well, you say it shouldn't be that way.
Shouldn't be.
The best way to politicize is to moralize and idealize.
It shouldn't be.
Now you get on a soapbox.
So this is the soapbox eyes, a great trap.
Once you get your ankle in it, it's very hard to get it out
because any way you move, you trigger another response.
Once you're in duality, every move triggers a response.
Even if you decide you're wrong and back up,
you will now be attacked for changing your mind
and backing up.
And if you don't, you'd be criticized
for not having done it.
So it's a no-win situation.
Yeah.
And once you get into duality, you cannot win.
Even if you win, you will get punished, highly taxed,
and criticized.
Maybe be bombed and assassinated.
What's the explanation for 9-11?
Americans work hard, save their money,
and try to live an integrous life.
That made them hate us.
Well, because America had wealth.
How do you get wealth?
You work your butt off, right?
All right.
So if you're political.
If you're politicized and moralized and then idealized,
you've set up the next war.
This is the basis of war right there.
War has nothing to do with guns, munitions, bombs.
Those are just the aftermath, the mechanics of it.
Once two guys decide how they're going to kill each other,
it doesn't make any difference whether you use swords, guns.
I mean, the weaponry is irrelevant.
Looking around for weaponry is a real waste of time.
So I worry about this guy, I'll have to search through his 10
and see if he's got a dagger in there.
I don't think I want to worry about whether he's
got a dagger in there, because I'm
reading where this guy's at, and he's
going to get me one way or the other, you know what I mean?
All right.
So we politicize, we moralize, we idealize.
And this is how we set up war.
This is what war comes out of, the first three items.
Then out of that, we speculate.
And so we begin to hypothesize.
It should be this way, it could be that way.
People ask you the hypothetical question, but what if?
Never answer what if.
There's two questions you never answer.
One is why, and the other is what if.
Those are the bear traps, all set for you.
The minute somebody says what if, you know they're out
to get you in their bear trap.
What if?
But what if?
But what if everybody ate an ice cream cone
at the same time on the planet?
Wouldn't that cause a shortage of, I mean, you know what I
mean?
The hypothetical has absolutely no grounding in fact.
The hypothetical is the grossly distorted pseudo-scientific
studies that prove that this is dangerous, or that's dangerous,
or this is dangerous, and keeps everybody frightened,
and programs everybody with negative programs.
If it wasn't so before, everybody's believing it,
and makes it happen now.
As you know, you've done the course of miracles.
You're subject to that which you hold in mind.
So if you think this is going to kill you, it's going to.
Actually, there's no way around it anyway, folks.
Because statistics show more people who ride in the passenger seat die than in the rear
seat, therefore you better not sit in the passenger seat.
However, more people who sit on the right-hand side in the passenger back seat die than on
the left side.
So you can't sit on the right side either.
More people who park on highways get killed on the highway than park in parking lots.
lot so you can't park in there. You get what I'm saying? More people die in the
bathroom than die in the kitchen so you can't go in the bathroom. Then you
gotta go to the bathroom and then you find out more people get killed in the
kitchen than do in the bedroom. You got to stay in the bedroom. More people get
killed coming down from the second floor bedroom than the first floor bedroom so
you can see how if you're gonna run your life by hypothetical
statistics it gets really awkward, you know what I'm saying? The best thing to do is
live your life as you see it this way you can and you remember from previous
research that the time of your death is already preset so there's no trying to
no point trying to doubt guess God. Karmically the time is determined at the
moment you are born. We reaffirm that is a fact the Lord. That is a fact we
reaffirmed in every lecture. You don't have to worry about death because it's
already taken care of. The other thing you have to worry about is you're never
going to experience your own death.
Anyway it's not possible. The instant of death, bang, you're out of the body, you
witness it, you feel sorry for the people there but you're fine. I should have done
this a long time ago, comes to you. That motorcycle accident, I should have said
to hell with the respirator and anyway. So you see the karmic unfoldment then of
potentiality. Karma then is, you're not controlled by karma but it does set up
let's say a condition.
Let's say extreme guilt over something you've done in some lifetime gets you left
in a hot car, a little toddler with the windows closed and after an hour you're dead. Everybody
sentimentalizes about that. Oh poor little tyke. If you look at poor little tyke in a
previous lifetime you won't think it's poor little tyke. What is the karmic consequence
of that?
See either everything is happening by accident which would negate the possibility
of divinity or nothing is happening by accident because accidents are not possible. An accident
really denotes an intellectual limitation. What it means is you don't understand the
reasons for it. In the infinite power of divinity no such thing as an accident is possible. This
comes around.
Here swoops down there and in my own lifetime having gone through extreme agony out of a karmic
obligation which I've already told you about, the recall of the reason for what I was going
through was clear as a bell. You remembered the extreme guilt about not having killed that guy,
not having killed him. The warrior I wounded in the groin and left him to die of the wound.
I would have put him to sleep and didn't though. I was in linha infirmum and brought
a herniography with no anesthesia once I햇rproud. Which wouldn't recommend unless you have
gored someone to death and still feel guilty about it. In this case you will have undone
that guilt by the time you're through.
Divinity means that one can grab sort of the overall context, divinity field out of which
universe happens with
within it is evolving. The quickest way to do it
is to look over great expanses of time. Look over great expanses
of time. Don't look at just this little thing. But that this little thing
is happening, you know, in a progression of
time that runs millions of years.
All right, so we hypothesize
and out of hypothesis
we get all kinds of fallacious answers.
The next thing we do is we romanticize. We romanticize
about all kinds of things and create a flowery
imagination of how it could be, should be,
and then become dissatisfied if
it does not compare favorably with our
romanticization of it. So to romanticize
that,
what we do is to project onto it. So all these
examples you see,
something is happening out there, and then the mind projects this
interpretation
onto it. Then believes that what it just projected onto the world is happening
out there.
So through this little example, you'll quickly see
that any commentary you can make about life is
always a projection. Because when you experience a rejection,
there's nothing to say about it.
There's nothing to say about it. It just is what it is.
So to romanticize, then, is to set oneself up for fallacy.
To elaborate, where no elaboration is really necessary.
It means to exaggerate certain qualities.
To romanticize, you have to distort it.
As compared to romanticizing, you have to distort it.
To romanticize, there's reverence.
There's reverence for the beauty of a relationship.
There's reverence for the intrinsic innocence of the animal.
You don't have to romanticize it, which
means to distort and to exaggerate.
The next one is rather obvious.
And, of course, it follows from the previous ones. To criticize,
of course, is,
is a rather glaring, obvious ego function.
This should be that. They shouldn't have done this.
They should have done this. They shouldn't have done that.
I can look at the black beetle laying on his back,
his little legs wanging around in the air,
and say, you shouldn't have done that.
You should have looked where you're going.
You shouldn't have walked...
So you can see how absurd criticize is.
So at the end, we're going to give you a little mnemonic.
The fastest way to God is to become aware of the eyes
and see that your mind is eysing out there,
and thereby become wise.
All right.
So the progression through the ego is primarily one of self-observation.
And many teachers, you know, say the same thing.
I think it was Mr. Gadara Maharaj.
They would tell the students, watch the mind.
Watch the mind.
I don't know if that worked or not.
In what way?
I'm trying to define in what way.
You watch how it begins to criticize,
and you watch how it begins to emotionalize.
See, first it politicizes, then it moralizes,
then it idealizes, then it hypothesizes,
then it romanticizes, then it criticizes,
and now it goes into indignation.
Emotionalizes.
Or oo-ah.
Sentimentalism.
Poor baby in the car.
Wah, wah, wah.
Cries over everything.
Or it's indignant over everything.
It sees everything as tragedy
or something that needs to be corrected.
And who should correct what is criticized?
Who should do that?
You.
You should take care of it.
And how are you going to take care of it?
You're going to take care of it by telling the people
who are wrong how wrong they are.
And how they should have done it.
Everybody tries that with their spouse, don't they?
And the children, your mother-in-law.
You know he doesn't like blue,
and you bought him the blue shirts.
So we emotionalize.
Emotionalize is another form of exaggeration.
Emotionalizing is exaggerating.
Emotionalizing is a way to dramatize.
Dramatize.
If you're connected with reality, let's say,
and somebody says, you know,
you're probably going to die of this thing
in a couple of days or so.
Yeah, good. Glad you told me.
I'll call and shut the phone off
and tell them to hold the mail.
You know what I mean?
What's to emotionalize about?
You want to emotionalize because you want to dramatize.
You want to dramatize.
So emotionalizing is trying to make things bigger than they are.
I see somebody in the office.
She's all broken down and crying.
She's carrying on.
I said, what's the problem?
My mother-in-law is having her gallbladder out.
She said, help me God.
That's what she says.
Why is she blubbering all over the place
when it's her mother-in-law having her gallbladder out?
You see, the poor boundaries.
The poor boundaries.
The dog is sick, so you're depressed.
The bird gets hit by the windshield of the car.
You know what I'm saying?
Sometimes you're the windshield.
Sometimes you're the bug, you know?
It happened just recently.
Driving along at high speed and all of a sudden a bird flew right into the windshield.
Bye-bye birdie.
The only concern was that she would be upset by it.
Well, it is shocking if you run over an animal by mistake.
Everybody who's done it knows it's sort of a horrible feeling.
All right, so we see that the mind, the 2% then,
how does it become so dominant?
These are the mechanisms by which it becomes dominant.
It's opinionated about everything.
It's always right and wronging things.
That creates enemies and friends.
It idealizes how it should be, which of course it can't be or it would be.
It hypothesizes.
When you look at the nature of the world we live in
and understand what it is,
there would be no point to change it.
The human world we live in is the ultimate perfect place
for spiritual evolution, just as it is.
Everything is as it is because it offers the most possible alternatives.
It offers the greatest karmic opportunity.
Almost from instant to instant one can say yes or no, yes or no.
One can reverence life or despise it.
One can curse or bless.
Every instant then.
So the soul, I always liken it to an iron filing,
you know, with polarity and a charge on it and all, or a molecule.
So every moment this little molecule is saying yes to this, no to this,
yes to this.
Last night the story of the ocean depths was on.
It's a stunningly beautiful thing
in which you see these incredible things floating through the air like this
and it's long.
And at the same time it's luminescent.
And it's incredible beauty, incredible beauty.
Incredible beauty.
When you don't project criticism, romanticism,
when you just witness these little, smaller than protozoa or whatever they are,
I didn't get the name of them.
Their beauty was too great.
I didn't want to call them anything.
And like little umbrellas that go like this, you know,
it's just entrancing, magnificently, incredibly beautiful.
A couple thousand feet below the sea is a world of incredible beauty.
And it also, and they also eat each other.
Isn't that awful?
No, because if you don't get eaten, you don't get to evolve into something else.
If somebody doesn't eat the cow, the cow's spirit,
how will it birth itself as a living entity in a world of life?
If everybody becomes a vegetarian, what should we do?
Kill all the cattle, let them die of old age, you know?
Millions of cattle won't be out there going moo.
I go to the girl's ranch in the morning, I pass through a herd of them.
And I'll stop and say hello to them.
They stand there and look at you, go on by, you know.
And I also have to stop and greet them and tell them good morning, etc.
And I tell them, if it wasn't for McDonald's, you wouldn't be here.
You see, if you don't do all of this, then you can just love the cow
and see that somehow its spirit evolved by being of service,
by laying down its life for some kind of a higher creature.
And somehow, because the evolution of consciousness then proceeds
over vast amounts of time,
and expresses itself in a great multitude of life forms,
and of course when we calibrate the energy fields of living things
starting maybe 400 million years ago and coming on up,
you see that consciousness is evolving.
Well, some horse has got to become a cow, doesn't it?
It has to become a mammalian, which births,
which then releases the maternal,
which begins to express love and nurturance.
You don't see love and nurturance in the dragon family.
You've got to be a cow, you've got to be a sheep,
you've got to be a bird, care about the egg.
Somewhere in evolution you've got to come out of the reptilian,
which calibrates very low.
The Komodo dragon is still around, see?
So how does love birth itself on the planet?
You can't do it through a Komodo dragon.
The Komodo dragon automatically kills you
because it doesn't know any other way of being.
It just bites you and it waits until you die, see?
That's as far as it could go in evolution.
You don't see a Komodo dragon becoming a warm mother cat.
No, it stays a Komodo dragon.
Something else comes off and evolves and evolves.
The world as we see it is perfect, perfect, perfect.
There's no point to change it.
And the world that you bemoan is all a projection.
Isn't it too bad? Isn't that sad? Shouldn't that be better?
Don't you see those are all mentations?
All mentations, those are all mentations.
If you stop the mentations, you merely witness it as it is.
So we like to emotionalize and dramatize
and in doing that we exaggerate
and now everything becomes a catastrophe.
Catastrophize.
Everything is a catastrophe.
The newspapers specialize in it.
The news channels love catastrophes.
They can't get to a big accident fast enough.
Fourteen people killed on a so-and-so.
Man, the helicopters are right out there.
They're just sucking up the drama of the catastrophe.
Grinding it out.
Catastrophe.
So to exaggerate.
Say your mother-in-law is having her gallbladder out.
So?
They're not going to do it while she's awake.
She's going to have Demerol afterwards.
She's going to have sterile fields.
She's going to have stuff.
Our great-grandmothers didn't have,
or my grandmother didn't have.
They were lucky if they survived surgery.
Lucky if they survived surgery.
She's going to have anesthesia, which is more than I had.
So we catastrophize and we dramatize.
We say this world should be a different world.
And we begin to theorize about it.
This is how we're going to change it.
This is the new direction.
And we theorize.
And universities are great at that.
Yeah.
We just calibrated all the universities last weekend.
The Big Ten, man.
Come out really about the highest.
Big Ten.
Big Ten universities.
Come out higher than the Ivy League.
Yeah.
Anyway.
So we begin to theorize about how we could
solve men's problems, what we conceive as problems.
First of all, because there isn't a problem there,
or any solution that you can come up with
and
coerce the world into following is going to be disastrous.
So you have Marxism.
You have all these isms, which are all hypothetical solutions
to hypothetical problems which don't exist.
All you can say is in every barrel of apples,
some apples are going to be near the top
and some are going to be near the bottom.
Unavoidable.
You can say, well, it shouldn't be that way.
All children should be able to run as fast as others.
That's how it should be, right?
Focus it in that way.
I only got one F in my life, and that was in sports.
I forgot to bring my 50 cents or my towel card
for the semester, and I got flunked.
And they used to have what they call field day.
That to me was horror day.
I used to try and think up a headache or a sick stomach.
No, you're going to school.
One of the things you had to do in sports day
is they would have a rope from the ceiling of the gymnasium,
and you would have to climb this freaking rope.
Second.
I never got past the middle of the rope much to the top.
Is that fair?
I mean, mesomorphs are going up there like this.
Not fair that I wasn't born a mesomorph.
There's a young gentleman here who I love dearly.
He was a great fan of ours, and he is a mesomorph.
And every time I hug him, I say, God, that's incredible.
This guy can probably lift a safe or something.
You know what I mean?
And I'm having trouble opening a package of light bulbs
from the dime store.
I can't get through the plastic.
Is that fair?
Recently we did a recording for a big company,
and the people that came from the company,
the vice president of the company, was 6'6".
I'm looking up at him like this.
Is that fair?
One of the fun things about being in Korea is the average height there.
The average height there is much less than here.
So when I was in Korea,
I got to feel what it's like to be a tall guy.
Everybody's head's about this high.
Then you feel like Mr. Big.
Is that fair?
Hypothesize. Is that fair?
That's not right.
And I've got a political solution.
Everybody's going to get chopped off at the same level.
The Bantus and the Watusi, so help me God, did that.
Historical fact.
The Bantus cut the Watusi's legs off in their war.
Now we're all the same size.
So that's catastrophizing.
And out of that we theorize wondrous solutions.
And we do that by intellectualizing.
All right, rationalize is making excuses.
Everybody knows that.
All these things that we're talking about today,
if you witness your mind,
you'll see it's doing one or the other of these things all the time.
It doesn't hold you in thralldom.
By being stupid.
It has fascinating dilemmas, fascinating solutions,
great dramas, great emotions.
All right, so we rationalize our behavior.
We rationalize.
This is a three-year-old.
You say to the three-year-old,
did you knock that over?
No, I didn't do it, Mom.
The cat did it.
Excuses.
So that's the world of excuses.
Excuses are a waste of time.
But it satisfies the three-year-old in us.
Because we've created such an impossible dilemma for ourself now,
we need relief.
And that's called fantasize.
You go to the movies, you read the novels.
We daydream and we fantasize
because we've made life so painful and unrewarding
that we now have to create an imaginary world.
Where things are more dramatic, more right,
more the way we want them to be.
We fantasize about how it should be, could be.
Another thing we tend to do is infantilize.
We infantilize people.
There's always political solutions to non-problems
because we've infantilized the people
and pictured that they're helpless and hopeless.
And now we can be the good person
and come in and bail them out.
Bail them out.
The purpose of the first step in Al-Anon
and those types of recovery programs
is to allow them to sink on their own.
If they're going down the tubes,
cheer them on.
They're going down the tubes.
Because the only way you can hit bottom
is by going down the tubes.
So if you infantilize them
and see them as helpless and hopeless
and begin to support them and hold them up,
you can keep them physically surviving
long past the endpoint.
And their recovery then is allowing them
to take responsibility for their own actions.
We rationalize and then another form of that
is called intellectualize.
This is why some of the universities
didn't come out too well.
If you're in the practice of medicine,
this one is the one that really blows you away.
Because the massive dilemma of practicing medicine
is all coming out of intellectualization.
Intellectualization.
Recently the government passed some new regulation,
which was totally, completely fraudulent,
called the HIPAA regulation.
H-I-P-P-A.
The public thinks that the privacy of their medical records
is now being protected by these HIPAA regulations.
No, quite the contrary is true.
Since the time of Hippocrates,
every doctor has guarded the privacy
of his patient's information.
In fact, a lot of them will go to jail
rather than review it, you know.
And they have periodically.
No, what they've actually done with the Privacy Act
is make your medical records available to anybody.
Any company, anybody with a vested interest
in your health, welfare, etc.,
now has access to your medical records.
The great HIPAA Privacy Act was exactly the opposite.
It's the non-privacy act.
And you're not gaining privacy, you're losing it.
Isn't that interesting?
You could do all that in one sentence.
Well, for months and years I've been getting piles.
My HIPAA file, I am not kidding, is this thick.
This is all bulletins and issues and regulations.
The granddaddy of them all came last week.
It's a whole notebook.
Magnificent production.
And if I sign this and return it to the company,
they will give me a certificate saying
that I'm complying with the HIPAA regulations.
They never heard of Hippocrates.
They never heard of the oath of Hippocrates.
I don't know a single doctor that doesn't guard
his patients with a paranoid ferocity.
So that all comes out of intellectualize.
And the one thing about intellectualize
is the more complicated you can make it, the better.
So that Medicare regulations run 10,000 pages.
10,000 pages.
So the proliferation of complexity then
comes out of intellectualizations
and also, sorry, legal experience in courts.
That everything has to be documented
to the point of absurdity.
And for some years,
I was the only psychiatrist that would go around
to the nursing homes.
So I saw zillions of old people.
And their charts were magnificent.
Here's this old lady who doesn't say anything
or do anything.
She takes a couple pills a day.
And her chart is this thick.
Weighs 10 pounds.
Every time she goes to the bathroom,
asks for a glass of water.
Everybody has to sign for everything.
The intellectualization then.
In the meantime, everybody's complaining
about the cost of medical care.
Yes?
Just remember that from the book,
the cost of medical care is 9% is the physician's fee.
The rest is bureaucracy.
9% of the total medical bill is the physician.
93% comes out of this.
It comes out of this plus what if.
Well, what if you didn't document
that you went to the bathroom?
She might die of constipation.
You'd be sued for death by constipation.
In as much as we know,
karmically, when she's supposed to leave this world
is set already.
To even blame anybody is,
from a higher viewpoint,
of course, idiotic.
Nothing causes anything else.
So intellectualize then means to complicate things
so they become cumbersome and manageable,
inefficient, and extremely costly.
Extremely costly.
People worry about the end of the world.
There's all kinds of people always predicting
the end of the world, you know.
There's always a workshop somewhere
on the end of the world about something.
And people don't really know
how the end of the world is going to come about,
but I do.
A giant massive gridlock
becomes so overwhelming
that finally a complete paralysis,
nothing can move any further
because all the regulations make it so that if you...
Yesterday I was trying to get an older patient
into an emergency into the hospital
in Cottonwood, Verde Valley Medical Center.
And the complexity of such a simple accomplishment,
you know,
it's better to let them die, you know.
All right.
Before this intellectualization
caused such enormous complexity,
when I had a huge practice,
I'd call the hospital and say,
this guy's coming in, send the ambulance.
That's all it took.
Now it takes me dozens of phone calls.
I was on the phone for hours
trying to get through the bureaucratic complexity.
And actually a person could have died
long before you get them in.
This complexity.
So everything then...
You eventually hit a gridlock, a log jam,
where effective functioning becomes almost impossible.
And apparently that's what happened before 9-11.
The government agencies were so bogged down
with their interfacing rules.
You can't speak to him
unless you get permission from so-and-so,
but that's against Rule 62 and you have...
So finally it just became stultified.
All the information was there,
but nobody had, like, permission.
I don't have permission to call him and tell him that.
You got a permission.
All right.
So intellectualize then means eventually great complexity.
And it's the whole process is mentalizing.
So we say the way to enlightenment is to observe,
that your mind is constantly mentalizing.
What you think is out there is a mentalization.
The belief in causation, causality,
the Newtonian paradigm, right and wrong,
these are all mentalizations.
They only exist as the thought.
All these things that you presume exist,
you cannot find in the world.
You can only find them as a thought process.
They have no concordant reality,
no concordant reality.
So mentalizing then is what the 2% is doing,
keeping us hypnotized by the process,
the process, the phenomena,
all these indignations,
moralization,
romanticization,
erotization.
I didn't put that up there.
Erotization.
Yeah, a lot of that going on.
And fantasize, mentalize,
and then, of course,
we said idealize,
and it went up there twice.
It must be serious.
Because this is how it should be,
and this is how it should be.
So I guess how it should be must have been the problem
when I wrote that list.
This is how the list should be.
I better have idealized on there.
Well, I'm glad I got it up there.
Now we get to another great trap.
And this one is a little harder to see.
This is something people don't realize
goes on all the time.
And this is called glamorize.
Glamorize is somewhat a product of emotionalize
and romanticize and idealize.
We glamorize phenomena.
We glamorize political positions.
The way you give this firepower
is you glamorize it.
You glamorize it.
You give it pseudo-importance.
You get somebody with a big name.
You present it as a dramatic presentation
with all kinds of color and a full orchestra.
You ever watch some nature program on television?
And while this nature program is going on,
all this dramatic music is going on in the background.
I can't hear what the announcer is talking about.
Why, when they're showing an ant walking across a leaf,
do you have to have this drama music in the background?
Doesn't that ever annoy you?
There's drama music put in as background to everything.
Things that should be incredibly of themselves,
overwhelmingly beautiful,
now are brought down by what the producer thinks.
So you get this drama music in the background.
Da-dum, da-dum, da-dum, da-dum.
Sometimes just a fly going along.
And there's this drama music.
You would think this is the end of the world about to happen.
So the dramatization, the romanticization,
then leads to a glamorization.
So many political positions and many ideologies
become glamorized.
Glamorized.
Workers unite.
You have nothing to lose but your chains.
Boy, that sounds great, doesn't it?
They don't get you out to the barricades.
You've got no heart.
If you're out to the barricades, you've got no head.
Because you're just going to get blown away.
And frankly, everything's going to go back the way it was before anyway.
Anyway, you can go down as a hero,
and that's a glamorization right there.
To glamorize, again, means to make it bigger than life,
to overemphasize,
to make that which is less than salutary a pure attraction.
M.T.V., of course, is the stunning ultimate example of that.
And various video games.
Some video games are so incredibly non-integrist
that I don't want to even describe what they're about.
You say, nobody would produce anything like that.
Nor would anybody buy them.
Then you find it's the biggest seller.
The biggest seller.
The glamorization of that which the world calls evil, then,
is glamorization.
It, of course, fills up the TV channels every night.
The glamorization of all the criminals.
Bonnie and Clyde,
they become romanticized and glamorized.
Now they're attractive.
You say, how do these young kids all get into lives of crime?
Why would they want to do that?
Because it's glamorized.
You wear your hat this way, right?
You collect all the symbols, the gang symbols.
You be Mr. Tough.
Mr. Tough.
Make big money doing drugs.
That's very glamorous.
So the downside of glamor is that it is something sprayed onto life
to make it look attractive.
And if you take that away, you see it's quite ugly.
Quite ugly.
The next thing the mind does is demonize everything.
It likes to do that out of politicize, moralize, and idealize.
The next thing it does is want to demonize.
And we said the way around that is to catch your mind at it.
You see, if you're pro-vanilla,
it doesn't mean you have to kill chocolate.
You don't have to get up the barricades and the machine guns.
You don't have to assassinate chocolate.
I hate chocolate clubs.
You can declare chocolate is un-American.
It's not fair to the great masses.
It's elitism.
It's elitist.
Vanilla is the flavor of the masses.
And chocolate is the fete elite.
You see, we can demonize anything.
Of course, we know that everything is bad for you.
If you think something is not bad for you, it's because you haven't heard yet.
Everything is fatal.
Everything you eat will kill you.
Yesterday's psychiatric newspaper I'm reading, it says,
a certain antidepressant makes people depressed.
I've used it for 20 years and a thousand people.
I never saw anybody get depressed on this.
What it means is the guy doesn't understand what he's talking about.
Prozac went through the same thing.
It caused people to commit suicide.
They misdiagnosed the depression.
It was actually a bipolar depression.
And when they relieved the depression,
the person now had the energy to kill himself.
To kill an undiagnosed bipolar is to give them an antidepressant.
Now he feels good and he can do it.
But the naivete of the press is unbelievable.
And when you read the press,
I want you to notice something unique that will help you
undo your fascination with it.
You'll notice there's always a writer.
You ever notice that?
It's not just a story by Ellen Lou Smith,
Mary Jane Peabody, Jack Collier.
This isn't the news.
This is a story written by some yokai.
A local who doesn't know anything about the news.
I guarantee that.
An article about psychiatry is not written by a psychiatrist.
It's written by Jack Peabody.
You'll notice that.
I want you to notice the authority that we give
to what we think is news is nothing but a story.
There's an internet address I could give you,
but I forgot it.
All the media, the articles they want
on all different kinds of subjects.
How to bake a cake, how to kill an Arab,
how to cure your own pneumonia.
There's something out there.
It lists page after page.
Articles wanted by all the media out there.
So some joker who's a writer sits down,
he pulls out some data,
a little bit of data from here and there,
and he quickly writes an article.
Now it becomes the authority.
We live our life imprisoned by fear
created by the lack of understanding
of writers who don't get the depth and the background
and comprehension of what they're writing about.
And it now becomes called truth.
That more people were killed in one passenger car
than the other means none of us can sit in that seat anymore.
I mean, is that a conclusion or what?
Is that stupidity?
All right.
So then we intellectualize, we mentalize,
we idealize, we glamorize.
Now we demonize things.
We get into the chocolate and vanilla problem.
See, once we redefine these things,
you'll see they're not that difficult to transcend.
Unless you see through the illusion,
they're very difficult to transcend.
Very difficult to transcend.
You can see hardly anybody becomes enlightened.
Hardly anybody even gets to 500, much less enlightened.
It's because these are formidable.
You know, they look simple to us
when we put them up there and start taking them apart
because they're like pick-up sticks.
And as you begin to get the sense of it,
these are all projectile.
These are all projections.
These are all imaginations.
These are all mentations.
None of that exists in the world.
There's nothing to challenge out there.
You can walk up to a tree and say,
how come you look the way you look?
You know what I'm saying?
People like to argue with consciousness research.
I said, it's like asking a tree,
why are you what you are?
I don't know, it just is that way.
So we tend to demonize.
And then the flip side of demonizing
and making everything black and white
is we begin to prize.
We prize certain things.
So there it brings forth the solar plexus
and its wantingness.
I'm proud to announce
that I've given up my desire
for a 1946
Packard converter,
Cadillac convertible.
I was afraid somebody might give me one.
The way I got over it was yesterday.
And its caliper went down the road.
I don't want a 46 Lincoln-Continental anymore.
Man, it was sleek.
It looked like 1936 in spades.
It was fantastic.
Red on top of it.
That'll keep me in the world a while longer.
You've got to want something.
At the last minute,
you think of the Excalibur.
You're doing all right
when you just got it down to an Excalibur.
All right, so we begin to prize.
So we could let that grow.
We could let that grow.
And you can see how it's just
even one desire
could begin to run your life,
begin to prize certain titles,
certain addresses,
certain lifestyles.
It becomes more important
than anything else.
And, of course, success in the world
is what has been prized.
In the world I grew up,
in the world in which
almost all of us grew up,
you know,
what was prized was success.
The college degree,
the good address,
all the appurtenances,
a reasonably new car.
Except, thank you,
younger than 1984.
And we begin to prize those things,
and now they
run all of the world.
The last one is the greatest
of them all.
And this is the
fabric of today's world.
It is victimized.
There's the
wondrous suction
that pulls everybody into it.
The great victimization.
So these become,
all these become tools.
Tools of victimization.
So we have
the incredible
legalities that go on
which can be heard on every night's television.
That somebody who
admittedly was witnessed to drive over
18 people and kill them all
is innocent because
because
he's a victim.
You see how the badge of victimhood
is so sought after today.
It is the plushiest,
juiciest plum.
If you can become victim,
you got this world by you know what.
The race to be victim is
rapid.
Everyone pictures themselves as victim
and there's great competition
in victimhood
to see who is the biggest victim.
The way the story goes
and we'll see what happens with victim.
A cop's walking down the street
and he hears a rustling.
He goes in and says, young man, what are you doing?
The man goes like this.
The cop shoots him.
Well, the kid is now the victim.
Then the cop gets sued.
Now he's the victim.
However, in the meantime,
the kid gets drunk and kills somebody else
who is now the victim
and goes to court.
The witness now becomes the victim.
Who is the victim?
You see it's like a ball bouncing around.
Whoever it hits is now the next victim.
The victim of the judiciary,
the victim of the perjury.
Everybody is the victim.
The 9-11 bombers are victims.
I'm sure if they hadn't died
there'd be parades of lawyers
talking about how their civil rights
are being violated.
Never mind 3,000 people
blown out of the sky.
So the game of victim now,
everybody gets to be victim.
Every legal situation,
every political situation
is a trade-off on
who is the victim.
Who is the victim?
That comes right out of politicizing,
moralizing, idealizing,
hypothesizing, criticizing.
It comes out of all of them.
So victimization now
is the world's
biggest problem.
Everybody is the victim
of something else.
I'm the victim of not being
6'4".
Everybody is the victim
of something.
The adjective now
describes the victim.
The refinement now is
you cannot mention a person's age.
There's a book out about it in fact.
A new book about it.
The truth police
or something like that.
Anyway, you can't mention age
because somebody is going to feel victimized
and it's going to make them uncomfortable.
Victimization and being uncomfortable
go hand in hand.
Everything makes you uncomfortable.
You can't mention gender.
You can't mention any physical data.
You can't mention any
data of any kind
because that might make people uncomfortable.
If you're bald, you're not bald.
That can make you uncomfortable.
So you can't say a middle-aged bald man
because you would feel uncomfortable
if you called a middle-aged bald.
The gender police
would be after you.
It would be a middle-aged
you were going to say a man or woman
but you can't, person.
Yesterday on the news
we talked about a waiting person.
It used to be a waitress.
Honkers or hooters.
What is that?
Now you don't dare
refer to him as a waitress.
It was a wait person.
You can't have a gender
and you can't mention a gender.
It's a wait person.
So you see how
everything makes you uncomfortable
is the position of actually paranoia.
So what all this
really leads to
is the prevailing
paranoia of today's society
in which you can't make a move.
The conversations back and forth
with the hospital
and with the admitting doctor there
were endless.
Every one of them was a move
about whether we were
going with regulations,
requirements,
whether this was all being documented.
I have to keep carefully
the time they called me,
the time they called me back.
Then I called them back
to say the doctor didn't call me back.
He called me to tell me
he tried to call me back
but the phone was busy.
I had to document that.
How does it sound in court?
Neglect.
I couldn't get him,
he couldn't get me.
Somebody is going to be the victim.
So the victim industry
drives our economy right now.
Politically, war, politicians,
everybody is into the victim game.
Is the American public
the victim of George?
George's distortions
of reality?
That's what they want to know.
Is Saddam the victim
of these horrible Americans?
Are Americans the evil Satan?
Maybe they are, right?
They drive cars and we don't
so we hate them.
Somebody who is nobody
in a nowhere country
still living the Stone Age,
to go from nobody to somebody.
To go from nobody to somebody.
Who is the victim?
His innocence.
We know that the basic nature
of human nature,
that the mind intrinsically,
the hardware of the mind,
consciousness itself,
is unable to tell truth from falsehood.
We know that the programming coming in,
which we call the ego,
is the software.
We know that because of the intrinsic
innocence of consciousness,
we cannot tell truth from falsehood.
Consequently, the Buddha,
Jesus, Krishna,
and every great teacher that ever lived
said, forgive them for they know
not what they do.
The one sin and the one sin only,
the Buddha said, is that of ignorance.
However, don't you see that ignorance
is inborn?
You're born with the incapacity
to know truth from falsehood.
That is the most devastating fact
in all of human history.
Morally responsible
for every decision,
karmically,
and yet
with no compass
to know what direction to go.
This throws mankind into
an extreme situation
where he can only hope
that that which he's been taught
is somewhat near the truth.
However, the likelihood is slim.
The likelihood is slim.
Let's do what I usually do
is number two.
So, the wise then
wise up.
And here's
the world's population again.
We're trying to get a different view
as spiritual students,
as devotees,
or whatever we want to designate ourselves.
What is the nature of the ego
and what is the nature of the world
and what's the relationship between
the ego and how it sees and experiences
the world?
Here we have a human population
which over
hundreds of thousands of years
still can't even tell truth
from falsehood.
It's not even on the first rung
of the ladder,
despite that profound ignorance.
So,
78% of the world
is still in the dark.
has not reached the level
where even to know truth from
falsehood would be valued.
Isn't that phenomenal?
People say, well, it isn't fair.
These people are suffering the
karmic consequences of their ignorance
and shouldn't we tell them
about that, etc.?
I'll tell you what, they're not interested.
If you go into the inner city
and talk to the gang kids and tell them
this way is integrity
and this way is not, they'll say,
yeah,
good luck.
Good luck.
But I gotta stay alive, if you don't mind.
And if I don't join the gang
and if I don't do what they do,
if I lose my rank
or respect for me,
I'm gonna get eliminated.
So, it's very good to
pontificate about
how they should be,
moralize about it, idealize about it.
So we look at the evolution
of human consciousness.
At the present time,
we see that
only 20 some odd percent
is capable
of discerning truth from falsehood
if they had a mechanism
to do so.
The rest don't even care about it.
Okay, let's put that previous one back on.
What do the rest care about?
People of integrity are excited.
They say, wow, there's a way of telling truth
from falsehood and even calibrating it?
A lot of people get so excited
they can't eat for a week,
when I read that.
Yeah.
So these are the mechanisms.
Where do the 78 percent live?
Where do they live?
They live because politicized,
moralized and idealized,
all these things create hate.
They create greed.
They create depression.
They create conflict.
So there's where the lives are lived.
If you say to them,
we've got a way to discern
spiritual truth from falsehood,
integrity from non-integrity,
and levels of consciousness,
they try to figure out,
well, where can we sell it?
Got a new product to move, folks.
Let's move this new product, called
the diggity.
That's the thing that's out there.
Let's move this new product.
Well, we should take a break.
It's been a tough morning.
I thought,
we'd like to see the dog.
Can we take his picture?
Here's the dog,
calibrates at 505.
And we saw this morning,
78 percent of the population
of the world is below 200.
The first characteristic,
I know another dog
that calibrates at 500.
And I was saying,
what is the difference?
There's another dog
that calibrates also at 500.
Its tail wags.
It just loves people.
But it wants something from you.
It comes up to you,
and it wants you to acknowledge it.
You notice this dog doesn't want anything from me.
See, that's the difference.
In order to get attention,
he merely, if I look at him
and tell him he's a wonderful dog,
he wags his tail.
He doesn't want anything from me.
He's not trying to control me.
Obviously, he doesn't care what we think about him.
So, you see,
the animal is,
he takes his joy from his own existence.
And then the interactions
add to the joy.
But he doesn't need my attention.
You know, as many a dog,
he will run up to you, he's wagging.
But he wants your attention.
He doesn't want anything from me.
He just ignores me.
Anyway, I think you're a sweetheart,
and we thank you for coming up.
Thank you so much for letting us meet the dog.
So the joy comes from
one's own existence.
And without all
the puzzling things going on
mentally that afflict humans,
he's free to just
enjoy his own
existence.
So that's the source of joy
as we become more and more enlightened.
That we begin to sense
that the source of joy
is our existence in this moment.
It's just this moment
right now.
It's sufficient unto itself.
So one gets outside
of the time dimension.
Because subjectivity
does not live within the dimension
of time. It just
is.
So we remember Ramana Maharshi says,
there's no point in trying
to change the world, because the world
that you see doesn't even exist.
It's a rejection
of your own perceptions.
There's no one to save.
And people are always, we're affronted by that.
Because they thought we should
be doing something.
So all these illusory
mental states drive
people into doing things.
Doing things about what they
imagine is wrong.
In a forest where a lot of the trees
have been killed off by the bark beetle,
what should you do with this
vast forest with these dead trees?
So some people say, well
we must do something about it.
The fact that the tree's dead, we must cut it down.
You have to cut it down.
If it's a dead tree in the forest,
you leave it be. And in 20 or 30 years,
it just falls down.
You don't need to do anything.
So when people say that,
I say, how long do you suppose
that forest has been there? 100,000 years or so?
Nobody bothered
cutting down the dead trees
over 100,000 years.
I guess we don't need to do that.
So man is always interjecting himself
in nature and trying to improve
on that which does not need improvement.
To really see that,
though, means to be totally
accepting, totally accepting.
And therefore, I thought we'd talk a little bit
about the field
and the content of the field.
And then I thought we'd do something
we did someplace recently
we talked.
Instead of questions and answers coming up
by cards, although we do have cards,
or a microphone traveling around
the audience, we found that was not satisfactory,
we had people just come up
and we started discussing
things.
I thought today we'll try that.
I'm going to present a few things.
And I thought people that want to talk
to me, why don't you come up
and talk to me. We'll ask questions
and discuss things as a small group,
but the whole audience will hear the discussion.
Is that okay with you?
Because many people have questions,
and I don't read
so well, so a 3x5 card,
if somebody just tells me
what it is that's on their mind.
Because an interview
is artificial. Somebody has written down
questions, but that's not really
what's bothering them.
So what I like is the authenticity
of the one-to-one
people asking a question, because that is
a real question to them. It's a real question,
not something that was written down by an editor.
And therefore they get a real answer.
So we did that
at Mile High. We didn't know that
the microphone was on, see?
And people were coming up with these questions,
and of course I'm just being my real self,
you know what I'm saying?
She's
lamenting the illness of her daughter,
and I'm telling her, well, you should go to a
12-step group, you should go to Elman
or something. She says, I've been going for 12 years.
So, because there was nobody witnessing
this, I thought, I said, well, for God's sake,
why don't you take the first step?
And I'm shaking her, it's about time to take
the first step after 12 years.
Oh, she went into shock, you know.
And so
my natural state is more like Zen
than a Christian saint,
you know. And then after
this is all over, all these people came up
and we had, you know,
a go-around with everybody, and the group was all
involved, and everybody was listening, you know.
And then when it was over, we found
the hall was full of people sitting there
just fascinating.
They were, you know, right in the middle of
these conversations, and we didn't even know
this was on, you know.
But then I thought,
you know, maybe that's a good thing to do.
We haven't tried it with this audience, so maybe we should
do that.
All right, so first I'll explain
a few other things I always want to clarify,
and then I thought, well, people
will ask us real questions. We'll start
with the ones that we...
Uh-oh, real good one, uh-oh.
Oh, yes.
Betty prompted me, said,
you mentioned the 12-step program.
How many people are not familiar with it?
Okay, so there's more than I thought.
It's so prevalent in our society
that almost everybody has a relative,
a friend, a fellow employee,
their boss, or somebody,
and the 12-step idea,
you know, came out of
the Oxford Groups.
The Oxford Groups.
And, um,
the Oxford Groups lived by
a certain set of spiritual principles.
It was just a spiritual
pathway.
It consisted of
the Oxford principles,
I think there was only six, not 12,
and it had nothing to do with alcoholism.
But when Roland, who was
a hopeless alcoholic,
went to see Carl Jung in Switzerland,
Carl Jung was, of course,
a very great and famous psychoanalyst.
And after seeing Jung
for some time, he moved to Switzerland
in order to be in psychoanalysis
with Jung.
And he became sober.
So Roland went back to New York City
and within a short time
was drunk again.
And so Roland went back
to Switzerland
to see Carl Jung.
What should I do now?
His great hope was Carl Jung
and his psychoanalysis,
and now he had collapsed again.
So in the depths of depression,
he pleaded with Carl Jung.
Carl Jung, to whom we are all grateful
to this day,
he calibrated 520.
Anyway, Carl Jung said,
he was honest, he said,
alas, alas, he said,
neither my science nor my art
can help you.
However, it has been recorded,
rarely, but it has been recorded
by people who have recovered
by throwing themselves wholeheartedly
into a spiritual group.
So Roland went back to the United States
very dejected and very depressed.
And I guess he was
not a very spiritual person.
Anyway, he threw himself in
wholeheartedly into the Oxford groups
and lo and behold, Roland became sober.
Roland passed this on to
Evie, who came to Bill W.
And Bill W
was in the same state of despair
and they told him
that only by turning himself over to God
could he have any chance of hope.
Well, Bill was an atheist
at the time, so it didn't
appeal to him too much.
But also, at death's door,
Bill W did surrender
all of the ego to God
and the room lit up
with a great light.
And he went through
a profound transformation
out of which arose all the 12 step
recovery groups.
The power of that one moment,
the room lit up.
Out of that, millions
of people have recovered
from all kinds of diseases
by following these 12 basic steps.
The first demonstration
of this efficacy
was in the curing of alcoholism,
which many people here don't understand
because in the modern era
it's considered to be recoverable.
In the old days, it was a sentence of death.
Nobody recovered.
You died of a wet brain
because of insanity and convulsions.
So here was witnessed
by everybody around
the miraculous recovery
from a hopeless progressive disease.
So the word spread
and AA grew
and of course it now is worldwide.
Well, if these 12 steps
could bring about recovery
from hopeless progressive diseases
for which there was no cure
because medicine, psychiatry
and psychology have no cure for it
and neither does religion,
and the Catholic priests
who have an alcoholism rate
of 10 or 15 percent
to get sober and go to AA.
So there was something about
the 12 steps then
had great power.
People began to apply this
to other illnesses
and so now the 12 step recovery
principles
which calibrated 540
are applied
to many of life's intractable problems.
Drug addiction,
alcoholism,
drug addiction and loss
and people who are prone to violence
and anger and rage
and all kinds of victimhood
and spending people
are compulsive spenders etc.
All kinds of things
for which there really is no cure
hopeless illnesses.
So it was found then
that the energy fuel
that calibrates at 540
had the capacity
if you did the steps,
therefore I have a great interest in it
aside from alcoholism
just the 12 steps themselves
much as I have an interest
in the course of miracles
which calibrates at 600
and in the course of which
I've seen recovery from
endless numbers
of hopeless diseases
from multiple sclerosis
to myasthenia gravis
to all kinds of incurables.
So we know that spiritual power
then has the capacity
when it's karmically okay to do so.
A woman called me
I'd seen and she said
you know
I went through a spiritual transformation
and she said
the cancer of the breast had disappeared
she called me up to tell me
the x-ray showed
it was now gone.
Rather everyday occurrences
within the power of the spiritual field
anything may recover
and if you do
the 12 steps
or you do the course of miracles
thoroughly
it doesn't matter whether you recover or not
because recovery
is trying to control God
once you surrender to God
if this is the way you're going to go
then this is the way you're going to go
so let's look at the 12 steps
for those who are not familiar with it.
I recommend the 12 steps
to anybody in the world
for anything
because it is merely
a spiritual way of living.
The Oxford groups
the Oxford groups were not religious
they said what is the spiritual core
what is the spiritual core of truth
because they were disillusioned
with traditional religion.
The first one
we admit we are powerless
and in our case
as seekers of enlightenment over the ego
and that our lives have become unmanageable
and you say
my life is unmanageable
my life is not unmanageable
and I say well let's see
let's stop your mind
from thinking for a second
you didn't think it was unmanageable
you just learned in one second
that it goes right on
it thumbs its nose at you
your mind and your ego
thumb their nose at you
you can tell it not to do this
and it will promptly do that
do not forget to put the butter
back in the refrigerator
you get home from the movie
and the cat's been licking it
while you were gone.
and you want to
change the world
they want to change
all these people want to change the world
can't remember to tie their shoelaces
ok so first is the surrender of humility
so the secret of success
of the course of miracles
or this spiritual pathway
or devotional non-duality
is humility
you realize the profound limitation
of the ego
and the great difficulty
the slightest thing
therefore when we looked at ourselves
honestly
so the first step is one of honesty
people that are in hopelessness
and down below 200
step one takes you to
integrity right away
step one you're honest with yourself
left to my own devices
there's really nothing I can do about this
condition therefore
through experience
it doesn't say through experience
but it says came to believe
that a power greater than ourselves
could restore us to sanity
sanity doesn't mean lying in bed
worrying about everything
doesn't mean trying to anticipate
tomorrow's disasters
it doesn't mean ruminating
about the wrongs of the past
it means
people don't know what sanity is
the mind itself is silent
still
it says nothing
it doesn't say anything to you
to think God is talking to you
something is talking to you
space doesn't talk to you
but in space
a knowingness begins to arise
it arises
in the outer fields of consciousness
through the knowing
there's a knowingness of the field
it comes about through the knowingness of the field
if God spoke to you
it would turn you into a cinder
in a second
if an archangel even hears a prayer
and passes a thought to you
it would blow you out for 30 years
stunned into silence
the mind never speaks again
and if God thought of you
holy catfish
came to believe that a power greater than ourselves
could restore us to sanity
step three
we made a decision to turn our will
and our lives over to the care of God
as we understood them
turn our will
and our lives over to God
so you see
the power of the crux of this
is the profound humility
it means no matter what
the no matter whatness
arises again just as you break through
into the state of enlightenment
no matter what
one gets at the last door
that one
is expected or needs to
or the field
lets you know
that at this point you turn your life
itself over to God
and you surrender your life
that which you think is your life
you believe that all these lifetimes
all these hundreds of thousands of lifetimes
you think this is the me
the source of life
you think the ego is you
is the source of your life
and now you're expected to surrender that
having surrendered everything else
that's all that's left
without profound humility
you wouldn't have the courage
to make the last step
made a decision to turn our will
and our lives
life itself over to God
as we understand him
in that moment
as I've said before
the Zen teaching to walk straight ahead
no matter what
the faith of the vibrational field
of the guru came back
and I knew I could
place even my life
in the truth of that saying
and so a teacher should prepare you
for what is going to arise
made a decision to turn our will
and our very life
our very life itself
in the case of enlightenment
over to God as you understood
and at that point
God is the unknown
to turn over that which you believe
most profoundly and most intrinsically
is the source and essence of your life
to the unknown
requires great faith and humility
step four
the steps are practical
made a searching and fearless
moral inventory of ourselves
it doesn't say of other people
laughter
made it for
we looked within ourselves
so we became
we began to witness the mind
we followed Nisargadatta Maharaj's
instruction watch the mind
begin to look at the mind
this is what we did this morning
we said 98% of the mind is silent
it's only 2% that's giving you a problem
what about that 2%
so we made a searching and fearless
moral inventory of ourselves
two people with more advanced consciousness
people seeking enlightenment
is not just rights and wrongs
and goods and bads
once we are aware of certain knowledge
now we feel sort of morally
obligated to
see it through to its conclusion
once you can see the mind
is prone to criticizing
and fatalizing idealizing
glamorizing
etc now one feels
called upon to call it at
that and see how it's doing it
because as you do
the underlying motive will arise
reveal the underlying motive
so we became
morally integrous
so it says we became morally integrous
so you can see every step takes you above 200
it's impossible to do the 12 steps
and still be below 200
it's not possible
nobody can do the
spiritual steps and still calibrate below 200
it's not possible
the 12 steps themselves
as I mentioned
calibrates at 540
which is the energy field
and healing itself
so we admitted to
God to ourselves
and to another human being
the exact nature
of what we call wrongs and quotes
to more advanced
people a wrong would be like
intellectualizing you know
to people down here it would be stealing from the boss
or killing your neighbor's cat
maybe
the exact nature of our wrongs
now
people resist
step four
they say well if I do step four
I'm going to go into a guilt bag
and people
do step four on paper
they write down all the nature
of all their wrongs
they say I'm going to get into a guilt trip
and they're scared of it
so step five is the resolution
of that guilt trip
in which you share
your list of horrors
with another human being
who is spiritual
and you respect
and because you want to have
first of all secrets
will destroy you
a moral secret that you've never shared with anybody
eats away at you
no matter how
no matter what
we find someone
and if you think this is a good person
to be with
you can check it out with kinesiology
yes this is a good person I can be with
somebody who is spiritual
integrity
you respect
so you admit to God
to yourself and to another human being
so step five is where some people
weasel out
four in five
shakes the sheep from the goats
winnows out the shaft
so if you really want to go
the whole way then you wouldn't
let fear and guilt about sharing who you are
with somebody else stand in your way
and so then you're forced to
confront spiritual pride
your fear
what people think about you
how you project your self
assessment onto others and then expect
they're going to see you the same way you're seeing yourself
and this is certainly
putting faith and trust in another human being
this is of course traditional
in many spiritual pathways
the Catholic has their
confessor and AA
one has a sponsor
so it's traditional then
instead of walking around with your
hidden horrible little secrets clutched to your
bosom
that you share them with somebody
and I've heard everything
you can hear on this planet
so you could have a good doctor
you could have a good psychiatrist
you could certainly have a good priest
you could have a confessor
and one hears everything there is to hear
and you know after hearing all of it
all those years
when I think about it
it's a so what
and I ran over five kids
and they all fell down
and then I killed my mother-in-law
and robbed the bank
and cut her throat
and I said yeah
and what's bothering you now
why
because that's the way it was at that time
what that person was at that time
that's what that person did at that time
because each one is being what they can
only being what they can be at the time
if you're run by a criminal mind
then you do criminal things
and now when you've given
up being a criminal
it looks horrible to you
but you weren't the person you are now
at that time
so at that time
everybody did what they could do
and nothing better and nothing worse
if you could have been more honest
you would have been
you didn't have the moral fortitude
you didn't have the support
now you've got support
you see the karmic benefit
of inner and outer honesty
and now you're willing to change
so there's a profound benefit
in doing five
and once you go after five
you can breathe easy
four and five is the tough one
step six is another one
of surrender
we're entirely ready
to have God remove
all these defects of character
have God remove these
so we surrender them to God
so all the things we did on the list
this morning
dear God I really need help
criticalness
my constantly politicizing everything
idealizing everything
moralizing about everything
can't anything happen in this world
without my having an opinion on it
do I have to keep hating chocolate
or can I just let chocolate
be chocolate and say
I prefer vanilla
ok so if politics
was cheering on your favorite
championing a belief system
it would be great but it tends to take on
attacking chocolate
alright
continue to take personal inventory
we asked him
to remove our shortcomings
so you see that's the essence of it
now one could use
a mechanism you ask God to remove
your shortcomings
and the next thing your mother says to you
is maybe you ought to see
a psychiatrist
that's how God wants you to remove
that shortcoming
so the mechanism here the psychiatrist
he's only the mechanism
when you ask God for help
with something and a guy
screeches up to you and says
you got a flat tire can I help
I mean that isn't God but
I've had it happen in the middle of nowhere
completely deserted
and a guy pulls up next to me
he says you got problems
the tire is flat
he puts it on his truck
he drives it into his town
gets it fixed brings it back to me
and helps me put it on
humbly ask God to remove our shortcomings
and God may suggest a mechanism
you need Prozac
well of course
the miracle says physical mental and spiritual
and AA and the 12 step group
say physical mental and spiritual
if you really want to stop being depressed
then you wouldn't be resistant
about taking an antidepressant
if you really wanted to be undepressed
then you would take an antidepressant wouldn't you
the very fact that you don't want to take it
means that you're getting juice out of being depressed
getting to be the sick victim
and the old poor me
okay so resistance
so each step brings up resistance
next to undo the guilt
we made a list of all the persons we harmed
and became willing to make amends to them all
it doesn't say in that step that you do
it doesn't say you write your boss yeah
it says you became willing
so willingness
willingness on our calibrated chart
is in the high 300's
so you see
as you do the steps it's automatically
going to take you up the calibrated scale of consciousness
into humility
into willingness
so we became willing
to make amends to them all
then where possible
we made direct amends whenever possible
except when
to do them would create scandal
injure them
or others
there's some things that to reveal it
would be so disturbing to people
that out of compassion for them
then out of compassion
for them
so this is another reason to have a counselor
or a confessor
or a priest or a doctor
psychiatrist psychologist therapist
good friend
one's parents can sometimes
under unusual circumstances
even one's spouse
you can admit to a spouse
I wish I did such and such
and I sure wish I hadn't
and if there's real love there
so a true relationship
where you're aligned
with one as therapeutically
and loving as possible
so people who have a good relationship
or a good marriage relationship
or a very good friend
you can reveal almost anything
and they will try to recontextualize it
so you see it differently
spiritual work is considerably
as you know by now
recontextualizing a thing
so what you thought was the worst thing in the world
when recontextualized
you realize is due to the weakness of human nature
including your own
the weakness of human nature
and the limitation of human nature
is what accounts for most of the things
we shake our heads over
so we tried to make amends to people
when we could
except when to do so
would injure them or others
so that precludes dumping
because you feel guilty about
the affair you had 32 years ago
you don't have to blow your wife away now
and tell her about that night
you got drunk in Chicago
I mean you wish it hadn't happened
agonizing you for 32 years with guilt
but to dump it on her
is dumping
it's misusing her
it's going to hurt her
and it doesn't really mean anything
it's better to discuss
with a confessor
should I bring this up
what's your purpose
just so you don't feel so guilty
well good for you but what about her
so you have to look at the consequences
and avoid
dumping your stuff
on others
we made direct amends
then step 10 is what
makes this different from many others
we continue to take personal inventory
on a daily basis
and when we were wrong
promptly admitted it
just think of poor old Nixon
thinks a lot of people
that have gone down the tubes
that if they told the truth
and admitted it right at the beginning
everybody said well I was pretty dumb
but so
promptly admitted it
so we don't have to walk around
with guilt
because when we were wrong
we promptly admitted
and couples do that all the time
I'm sorry I snapped at you
I'm sorry I forgot to bring home the butter
I'm sorry
people apologize for
character logic problems
so that's consideration of others
we continue to take personal inventory
and when we were wrong
promptly admitted it
just think of poor old Nixon
thinks a lot of people
that have gone down the tubes
tend to eğ
thing would have blown away and everybody would have forgiven them so we
find that in the long term to admit when you're wrong right off the bat is
actually the best way to go the most practical and certainly politics has
proven that over and over again hiding a thing away and sooner or later comes out
and now and now the cost is great can cost you the the office itself and you
have to resign so instead of a slap on the wrist you have a major catastrophe
so it's very practical step 10 also you can stay in integrity step 11 is the
backbone of many a person's spiritual work sought through prayer and meditation
to become more conscious we all move towards enlightenment conscious contact
with God as we understood him praying only for his knowledge of his will for
us
oh that's different then please God do this and please God do that that's the
child in us running for the bus with your violin you're gonna be late for
your violin lesson and you're praying up a storm God please hold the bus I can
remember that the violin flying through the air and running like a mad dog less
school late and now it's gonna miss the bus and miss my violin listen dear God
please hold the bus yeah
so in this we surrender our will to God and we ask for knowledge of his will for
us so you're asking for spiritual intuition a certain knowingness so
you're trying to transcend the ego the ego lives in this box and the ego says
well I'll figure it out but surrendering it to God is not figuring it out it's
not figuring it out at all in fact it may look quite hopeless and a
but we continue in humility.
We seek through prayer and meditation.
And what then happens is it suddenly comes to us
a recontextualization of what we thought was a problem.
And then we see it wasn't even a problem in the first place.
And if you'd gotten that job, you would have gone down
because you didn't know what that company was
in its last few months.
And so step 11 then, prayer and meditation.
And step 12 is one reason many of us are here.
Having had a spiritual awakening
as a result of a spiritually integrous life,
we tried to carry this message to others
and practice these principles in all our affairs.
So we then began to uplift others
by sharing our experience.
Now, sharing your experience
is not trying to change the other person.
I think I'll tell this person this for their own good.
Don't do anything for anybody's own good.
For instance, say, I went to Course in Miracles
and I saw people recover from myasthenia gravis,
cancer, tumors, convulsive disorder.
And you leave off, and therefore,
I think you ought to be going.