Did you turn the voice down?
Well, the energy was very strong this morning.
And spiritual energy is too much for the human nervous system.
It's more comfortable to stay stupid.
You can just get in there and fight and kill and have a hell of a good time.
We realize, those of you who have been here before,
that nothing is causing anything.
The primary illusion to get over is that there is anything causing anything.
So long as you believe in causality,
you will be unable to disidentify with the ego
because you will presume there is a this called an I
causing a that called actions or so.
The fastest way to make rapid spiritual progress is to meditate and realize
that everything is happening spontaneously.
Everything is occurring.
As a natural consequence, there is an infinite field of power similar,
let's say, to gravity and everything
within that field responds to the field.
This is not causing that.
On the contrary, these two things are moving within the field.
The source of this moving this way is the field.
This is not causing that to move.
Everything is happening spontaneously.
Every word that is spoken.
I don't know what's being spoken until I hear it.
You understand what I'm saying?
You ask me, what am I going to talk about today?
How would I know?
We make up things because the audience wants to know what you're talking about.
If I told him the truth, how many would come?
He says he doesn't know what he's going to be talking about.
The world can't handle reality.
So we make up fictions.
So they're happy.
Today we'll talk about truth and falsehood.
There you go.
The presence of God manifests as creation.
Creation is what seems to perception to be a progressive unfolding.
Actually, there isn't any unfolding.
But that makes people happy to tell them that.
There is this.
Stopwatch is your point of observation.
And there's this.
Each movement arises out of nothing.
This movement did not arise out of this movement.
Instead, this movement arose spontaneously out of nothing at all.
And this movement arises out of nothing at all.
Because of the intention,
that intention and the presence of an infinite power called divinity,
then appears forth as such.
Creation is continuous.
every word spoken this morning
is the effulgence of creation as it appears
to get beyond the idea of cause and effect
cause and effect is a calibrated energy field at 460
that means it's an intellectualization
where's our wonderful map
what would we do without our map, we'd be screwed
anyway, reason, evolution
evolution about 450
causality about 460
quantum mechanics about 460
these are all explanations
but they have no basis in
subjective experiential reality
they're abstractions
nothing is causing anything
and if nothing is causing anything
then evolution is a limited concept as you can see
let's see if everything we've said so far is true
everything we've said so far is true
the absolute truth
and so evolution has brought us to the point
where the first time in all of human history
there is a means of discerning truth from falsehood
that is such a staggering realization
the first person that I'd shared my work with
who I sent it to him
took off two weeks and went to Europe to get over the shock
he said it totally blew everything I'd ever believed in
totally recontextualized my whole life
the meaning of everything
so it took me 30 years to even approach the subject
for 30 years the presence within
was never spoken of
there's nothing you can say about it
and in the 90s arose a means of explaining spiritual reality
in ways that are definable and describable and verifiable
so then that came about
as a means of explaining spiritual reality
the writing of power versus force
and the impact of that information is overwhelming
sort of like the discovery of electricity
or the computer chip or the compass
the telescope, the microscope
because it was a new instant with which to examine
everything mankind believes
or has believed throughout history
it was a way of discovering that
just think in the middle ages
where the black people
plague wiped out like half of Europe or something. They didn't even know it was germs. They didn't
know it was germs. They didn't know it was bad air, wicked people, all kinds of things.
Nobody discovered germs. There wasn't any microscope. So the discovery of the microscope
totally revolutionized human life. We don't die of great plagues anymore. So an instrument
to discern truth from falsehood then reveals things that are somewhat shocking and quite
dissimilar to common human belief. If common human belief was credible, we wouldn't have
the problems that we have today. Consequently, what people believe and their opinions are
worth nothing. That's the happy news. Everybody is free and entitled to be wrong, and they
are.
So all we're saying is that the plague is not caused by bad air, darkness, leaving the
windows open or shut. The plague is caused by a bacillus. Oh, boy. To discover anything
new usually subjects you to a good deal of hostility from large quarters. And some of
the things that we'll say this morning I'm sure will do the same.
Everything is occurring spontaneously of its own, just like the discovery of the
microscope, how to tell truth from falsehood. It was a spontaneous discovery, a sudden
like realization. It happened in a flash. A tenth of a second I saw it instantly. And
then when we begin to apply it to common human problems, we get a different viewpoint of
what the problem is all about. And so before we can solve a problem, what the world calls
a problem, we first have to be able to define it.
In medicine, we call that diagnosis. So this morning we'll do some diagnostic work, and
I thought we would start with one that's quite prominent in the world today. Before we do
that, however, there's a gentleman in the audience who I have challenged to a duel.
In order to do this correctly, I have to have a gentleman. Come up, gentleman. Has to be
a bona fide gentleman. And in my bag is something you're going to need to see. And the gentleman,
the gentleman will stand there, and I will stand here. You're going to need that. All right.
We are going to have a duel. You stand here, Susie, and wear your thing. All right. When
she goes like this, do a practice. She does the white scarf, we will, bang! We'll practice.
Bang! So we will keep our gun store aside, and when Susie gives us the go-ahead, we'll
see if we can kill each other. Okay?
Are you ready, Susie?
Yeah.
Get ready with it. Bang!
Now we're going to...
Thank you.
And now we're going to have a fight with the daggers. But here, you come over here,
back up this way. Okay. All right. Now, this way. Now we will take four steps forward,
and then turn and fight. Okay? Go! Okay, let's put War and Peace up. Now that we've gotten
rid of that stupid thing, we're going to do the next one. We're going to do the next one.
You're a stupid idiot.
You understand the causes of war. Peace is the natural state when truth prevails, and
war is the state when falsehood prevails. So the opposite of peace is not war. The opposite
of peace is falsehood. To eliminate falsehood, you have no war. That's why the propagators
of falsehood are so vociferous. That looks a little fuzzy.
Why do we keep ringing?
War and Peace.
So peace is not something you can cause. Peace parades don't cause peace. Everybody's
for peace. You know what I'm saying? Peace parades are dangerous. They're too dangerous
to go to. I don't want to go to a peace demonstration. There's dogs, police, people knocking each
other over the head, being dragged off to jail. It's violent. Peace demonstrations
are too violent for me. I don't want anything to do with them. You're safer in your regiment.
You're safer in your regiment than you are in a peace demonstration. Nobody's getting
you with clubs arresting you. There's no dogs biting your legs. The basis of war is
ignorance, and the basic problem is that men cannot tell truth from falsehood. The consequences
politically is that because they cannot tell truth from falsehood, the populace cannot
tell a leader from a megalomaniac. The same phenomena happens over and over and over. If
it isn't Genghis Khan, it's Caesar or Napoleon.
Or Hitler or Mussolini or Hirohito. It's one megalomaniac after another. The basic
problem is that people worship a political leader instead of God. Your allegiance is
due only to God. Therefore, to pledge allegiance to the Fuhrer or to the State or to Saddam
or anybody else already puts you in a non-integrist condition. Those who worship anything but
God are below 200, because that is a basic falsehood. You cannot be integrist and worship
that which is secular. You can pursue it. You can even reverence money. Holy money.
Anyway, we're going to get to business later today. It's a tough day. Today we're starting
with war and we're ending up with business, and then we're getting on to science, and
oh boy.
Someday, the citizens have no capacity to tell truth from falsehood. Therefore, they
are easily propagandized. Why? Because of the intrinsic, the trap for mankind is the
intrinsic innocence of consciousness. As we've described before, the nature of the human
mind is like a computer. The basic consciousness is like the hardware of the computer. You
can program anything into it, and the ego, then, is all the software that's been programmed
into it. Forgive them, for they know not what they do is a fact. They don't know what they're
doing. If they think they're honoring God by killing innocent citizens, we say how pathetic,
but they don't know any better. Okay. So, we come out with compassion, then. If somebody
kills you out of some mistaken belief, you bless them. You say, brother, you're going
to die. You bless them. You say, brother, I forgive you, right? And thank you for taking
me out of this vale of tears. Okay. So, innocence is easily programmed into polarized ego positions.
As Goebbels was the master of that, I once calibrated him. He was like 40 or something.
But what he documented is if you repeat a lie often enough, you program people, and
they will believe the lie, no matter how outrageous it is. Leave everything and go out in the
desert, and the UFOs will pick you up. They do that. Thousands of the time. Okay. So,
we have a different way now. Let's remove all opinion. The way to enlightenment is not
through opinionation. I guarantee that. It's through divine stupidity. When you realize
the limitation of the mind, you see, the mind can only know about something. It cannot
know anything. To know anything, you have to be it. The only thing in my household that
knows a cat is my cat. I can know about the cat, and over time, we learn more about cats,
but only kitty knows kitty. No. To know, you have to be that. The world that we talk about
is the world of science and power.
The world of politics and the daily newspaper. All these opinions. On the one side, we hear
the doves, and on the other side, the wolves. What is it? Doves and eagles, foxes, eagles
and hawks. Eagles and hawks. Okay. No, no, not eagles and hawks. Doves and hawks. You
have the doves. If you don't vote for peace, I'll kill you. Okay. And you got the hawks.
Kill them. Throughout the lectures, we've shown how the
world evolves out of animal instincts. What you see is a display of animal nature as it
is acted out within the human domain. Territoriality being one of it. Major ones, dominance, the
dominant cat fighting for territoriality. So, the daily headlines are not much different
than the wilds of Africa or 40 million years ago. You just see one species fighting for
more space. And mating opportunities. They seem to be obsessed with mating. And food
and dominance. And therefore, you kill anything that invades your space. In 40 million years,
however, things change. Not much, huh? Oh, God. We don't have fur. That's one of the
main distinctions between us people. Just a little fur. Not much.
Okay. So, let's say we don't know anything about this world. We come from some other
star. And we say, let's study what these people are all about. And the only instrument we
have is a way to tell truth from false, other than that we don't know anything about these
people here. So, what happens if we calibrate? Let's put opinion aside. You can save your
booze for later and your cheers for later. The doves and the hawks can take turns. Doves
and then hawks. I'm going to do it that way. Okay. If we just calibrate, let's say we don't
care about personalities. President Bush's address to the Congress, the annual address
was 460. Secretary Powell's position in all this war, and this is 460. The Secretary of
Defense is 460. The U.S. military, 450. The U.S. military, 460. The U.S. military, 450.
The U.S. State Department, 450. That's their intention. The solicitude for the unintended
victims of all this, the reluctance to take, even have it happen. So, in the mid-400s,
the mid-400s is about the highest you can expect in ordinary life. The presidency of
the United States calibrates around 450 to 460. So, whoever fills that void is going
to have a different role than whatever the circumstances. This is the level of the intellect.
Reason, meaning, wisdom, beginning of wisdom. The Supreme Court calibrates about 480. So,
this has to do with reason, logic, thinking a thing through, understanding, the capacity
to abstract concepts, ethics.
So, 460 is the rule of ethics, reason, balance, doing the intelligent, expected thing, and
fulfilling one's obligations. I do a lot of radio programs and they tend to be quite polarized
politically. And they always get mad when they say, well, what does President Bush calibrate
at? Well, he calibrates at 460. Oh, that can't be. Everybody's mad at that. The presidency
of the United States, to get there and to handle it, you better be around 450 or 460.
You couldn't handle it otherwise. The high 500s, you'd be out of it. In the high 500s,
you wouldn't be able to handle all that, power brokering and detail and all. So, the ideal
president, the ideal president at this time would be around 460. That would be ideal.
I think the highest president we've ever had was 499. To be able to handle it all, you've
got to be around 460. The Supreme Court calibrates at 480. The Supreme Court is not on the firing
line. They're into philosophizing and intellect and reason and learnedness. It's a little
bit too academic at 480 to be president of the United States. You can't be that academic.
You have to be able to relate to the people. You can't be too high or you become sort of
ivory tower intellectualism.
So, we'd say, actually, that's pretty ideal. All right. The Congress itself is at 450.
The United States population has been at 431. I didn't recalibrate it. The U.S. media has
a different mission at 320. The 400s are a little bit too intellectual for the public.
So, if you're going to do a TV show, you've got to bring it down to closer to the populace.
And what happened to the – oh. Okay. The U.S. media is around 320. In the new book
I'm doing, we've calibrated all the networks and network news and all the commentators
and Time and Newsweek and calibrated all the major media. It's like we have a new instrument
with which to study civilization.
Okay.
And that's what this new book is about, studying every aspect of human civilization
from its early onset to its present presentations, everything included, from the Polk to the Dixie
Chicks.
All right. So, the media has to be – you can't be too erudite, and you'll notice that
when you look at the editorial page.
All right.
In this whole thing that's going on, we have the peace vigils. As I said, peace protest
parades calibrate pretty low. But peace vigils are 305, and 300 is goodwill. Goodwill, willingness,
it's benign. A peace vigil is benign. It threatens no one. We're supposed to have
freedom of expression. So, there you express yourself, but you're not trying to coerce
other people or force them to think your way. You're not trying to proselytize. You
stand there and you make a statement, like a mudra. A mudra makes a statement non-verbally,
but you're not trying to coerce others by your statement.
The UN Security Council calibrates it 202. It's not a star in this whole thing, but
it hangs on to integrity.
So, 200 is integrity. 202 is the level of functionalism. Many government agencies calibrate
it 202, many of them, the IRS. That's bureaucratic functionalism. And 202 is the waitress who
takes your order, but she doesn't smile and she don't remember you, and you don't feel
compelled to return to that restaurant. I mean, I want somebody that says, hi, doc, the
regular.
There.
That's sort of a liveness.
Now, 202 is you crawl up and you get a message. If you want so-and-so, press 1. If you want
so-and-so, press 2. You press 2, and now you've got a whole new menu. You go down to that
menu, now press 6. So, it's functional, but it's not exactly warm, you know?
All right. So, the UN Security Council did not really warm the cockles of my heart, the
way they handled this whole thing.
Okay.
Now, we keep on examining this.
And we come to the revelation of some other phenomena in calibrating the energy levels
of everything in the world.
Wow.
I feel like I'm rewriting the Encyclopedia Britannica.
I'm only up to M already.
So, anyway, what were we going to say?
Oh, yes.
What I wanted to do for these lectures, and I haven't gotten to it yet, is a map of the
world.
I need, like, two slides.
One this side of the world and one slide this side of the world.
And you calibrate the energy levels of the different continents, the different countries,
different locations, and you'll find that much like human, I mean, much like animal
species, mankind, certain species tend to congregate together.
You'll find areas of the world, such as America, 431.
We take 431 for granted.
431 is amazingly high.
431 means that you give reason priority over emotion.
As you get down around the 200s and below 200, emotion is what counts.
Hatred is more important than reason.
No, we're constrained by reason.
That was the gentleman's fault that I killed before.
He's constrained by honesty and reason.
You see how deadly it is?
Because I'm a street fighter.
I don't have a knife in the guy before he's ready for the goal.
You understand?
Because I play to win.
In the street, you play to win.
This world is not run by Marquis of Queensberry rules.
Now we get to, we left the Marquis of Queensberry rules up here.
These people are run by the Marquis of Queensberry rules.
They all went to college.
They all think that a thing is fair or not fair.
In street fighting, whoever heard of fair?
In the jungle, whoever heard of fair?
Fair?
What do you mean fair?
Not fair to eat a little cub?
Why not?
It's delicious.
Different law.
The law of the jungle is not the law of the Harvard rowing team.
All right.
So now if we turn the, if we shift the slide, which I haven't done yet, to other continents,
you'll find that whole continents calibrate incredibly low.
Let's do Africa as a continent.
We have permission to do Africa as a continent.
It's over 40, 50, 60.
The whole continent, 70.
If we're in the western continent, the places I've been, it's obvious at first sight that
they calibrate below 70.
The poverty in some areas of South America is absolutely stunning.
People talk about poverty in the United States, they haven't the slightest idea what poverty
is.
All right.
Now if we look at the Middle East, which historically has been at war for thousands
of years, and still is, now we get different calibrations.
We see Iran 185, Palestine 180, and Israel 180.
So here you got two 180s, both below integrity.
They can pontificate all they want, but frankly, they calibrate 180.
All right.
Peace demonstrations, unfortunately, as I said, are too violent for me.
They only calibrate 170.
Because they represent force.
Everything below 200 is force.
Trying to force others to see it your way, forced by intimidation, forced by demonstration,
like the Ku Klux Klan.
By demonstration, intimidate.
Okay.
Turkey calibrates at 165.
It's a waffling country, isn't it?
It waffles.
The Iraqi population is 140.
The Iraq media is 140.
France, who is in bed with these people, not surprisingly, calibrates their political position
is also 140.
The Syrian regime, at this point, is 130.
These have made change over time.
A couple thousand years, even.
The consciousness level of mankind stood at 190.
At the time of Jesus, it was 100.
And by the Middle Ages, by the year 1200, 1420.
By the year 1200, 1400.
On up to the late 1980s, it was 190.
The whole world was non-integrist.
Human history is not pleasant to look at.
In the storybooks of history, they pick out the flowers that survived.
Mozart, the great heroes, etc.
But that was unusual.
It was so unusual that it's in the history books.
If it was usual, it wouldn't be in the history books, would it?
Syria, right now, 130.
The Middle East in general, the whole Middle East as a region of the world,
if we just do a world map, is 110.
110.
Now, you expect peace in a region that calibrates at 110?
Billification of the U.S. and the presidency has become a common political positionality.
Hmm.
Non-integrist for reasons that we will get into later.
It calibrates at 70.
Saddam Hussein, God bless him, is 65.
And the Iraq military leaders are 65.
All right.
The real worry, the real worry in the world is jihad.
That's the real worry.
It sets up the entire Muslim, Arabic, Middle East world against the rest of the world.
That is the real, that is the real worry.
Of course, it takes expression in Saddam Hussein.
And Iraq and bin Laden and various things like that.
But to declare war against the rest of the world, then, is causing a deep division.
So jihad, in my view of it, is the most serious threat to peace in the whole world.
The Islamic terrorists are just coming out of this.
And the Taliban at 45 and bin Laden at 40 are the expression of that.
The energies of war, let's see.
The energies of war, we can look at fallacy.
We said that the enemy of war was falsehood.
Falsehood.
The enemies of war are falsehood.
And they become politically expressed.
The far left is Luciferic and the far right is Satanic.
And there you have the display of non-integrity.
Luciferic then denies the sovereignty of God and seeks grandiose control over others.
And to do so, it distorts logic and truth.
It's the great enemy of truth.
It's the Trojan horse in the newest book I did.
How many of you have read I?
Okay, so there's a certain familiarity.
The Trojan horse is to first present the lie.
And I presented the lie to you before, this morning.
The two of us had a duel.
He's an honest, integrous gentleman.
Sitting duck.
You saw it happen, right?
So you saw a recapitulation of what led into World War I, World War II, and every other war.
I grew up, you know, World War I has just ended and the veterans with battle shock and all were staggering around.
And World War II was now arising.
And then the obvious danger was ignored.
The League of Nations was about as effective as the UN is now.
Did nothing at all.
As this giant war machine built up, the greatest war machine the world has ever seen, built up right on the doorstep of Europe.
At that time, there was all kinds of vociferous protest about peace and isolationism.
Lindbergh and Charlie Chaplin, all kinds of people got up there.
But the actual diplomatic negotiation was handled by Neville Chamberlain.
Yeah?
Neville Chamberlain at the time calibrated at 180.
So this morning we played the part of Hitler versus Neville Chamberlain.
I was Hitler and he was Neville Chamberlain.
A gentleman who believed that I would be bound by a non-aggression treaty.
So Neville Chamberlain went to meet with Hitler and they signed a non-aggression treaty.
And he came back with a signed peace in our times.
At the same time, Churchill saw that the truth of it was that this guy is a gangster, is going to laugh at a contract, and he's building up a giant war machine for what?
Not just for entertainment.
So Churchill was vilified as a war monger.
War monger.
To be saying these kind of things.
The price, then, of the Trojan horse, of the fallacy of peace, which calibrated at 180.
At the time.
Cost 70 million lives.
Though political opinion is not all that innocent, is it?
70 million people dead.
Blown to bits.
Their homes blown to bits.
Their country blown to bits.
Dresden, Cologne, all the magnificent beauty of medieval Europe destroyed.
The inability to tell a megalomaniac from a leader.
So the Trojan horse, then, is the doorstep.
The doors to war are opened by a consciousness level of 180, which distorts truth because it's in denial about human nature.
It's some kind of a schoolboy, Girl Scouts view of things.
If we just be nice to them, they will change.
In World War II, I was in dives in Shanghai waterfront.
And for entertainment, the war was just over, so suddenly there was no excitement going on.
So the crew would go ashore and get into fights in various bars.
I had two cronies.
One was Big Red Hawkins, who played in for Pennsylvania.
He was about six foot five and weighed 290 pounds of solid muscle.
A walking battering ram.
And red hair.
And he quickly got angry.
The other guy was Jimmy Sanders, who was not all that tall.
Jimmy Sanders was a bosun's mate.
And he was champion of the third fleet.
Deadly.
When I went on that ship, which is a minesweeper, the bosun says to me,
Hey shorty, you know how to box?
I said, gee, I took lessons with Richie Mitchell, who had been the former medium weight champion.
Have I told you this story before?
No, sorry.
So I'm a new recruit.
I was sent out on hazardous duty.
Anyway, I'm the new recruit.
So Sanders says, well, let's do a couple of rounds in the gun tub.
So I go into the gun tub with him.
We put on the gloves.
And he knocked me cold with one sock in the jaw.
One shot and I was cold.
Then they told me after, he was the champion of the third fleet.
He was deadly.
So fast you couldn't see him move.
He had a left jab that was so fast you didn't see it coming.
And you were grogged by his left jab.
And then he hit you with the upper right.
This was so fast that you were jarred by it.
And while you were jarred, he hit you out.
Well, he was something marvelous to watch, I tell you.
And we would go ashore, the three of us.
Trouble.
I was the bait.
So we go in these waterfront bars.
And my role was to, you know, we had a patch.
And being on a minesweep, you know, our whole crew was only 18 people.
We were all under 22.
We were all kids.
And so we had a minesweep.
And we were in a big port there.
And there were battleships that had 2,200 guys on them, et cetera.
So they called us kiddie sailors.
So we'd go into this bar.
And they would say, Shorty, go and talk to these people.
So I'd go up to them, sit over this.
And they would sit over there.
Pretty soon, a battleship sailor would look at me and say, hey, kiddie sailor.
Immediately, these two guys would come out of the wall.
And they'd say, hey, are you insulting my friend here?
And they'd push Shorty aside.
My job was to stay the hell out of the way.
Shorty, you go over here.
And then pow, the whole place would be ripped up.
The mirror.
Stools flying.
Bodies flying.
Mirrors crashing.
It was murderous.
I only saw Jimmy Sanders.
He only got stopped once.
He had a guy up against the wall.
And he was about to cream him.
And the guy pulled out a French 45.
And he said, OK.
Well, he knocked me out a couple other times, too, for one thing or another.
One time, I went up to the top of the mast.
And he says, don't look down.
I had a fear of heights.
He says, don't look down, Shorty.
Well, I got all the way up to the top of the mast.
There was a paint bucket.
And I made the mistake of looking down.
Instantly, the body froze to the mast.
Beyond volition.
My body did not respond to volition.
I tried very, very hard to let go.
And I couldn't.
He says, Shorty, I'll have to cold cock you.
I hope he comes in the bosun's chair.
So life in the arena of what's real is quite different.
It's quite different than the arena of political pretense.
Political pretense.
What's deadly, then, is that that which is fallacious and presented as truth
numbs you to the real truth.
And consequently, so the war starts with Lucifer distortion of reality.
And then that opens the gates for the satanic, which is waiting.
And when the time is right, the satanic, which represents death, war, destruction,
rape, pillage, murder.
The rape of the then king was the satanic let loose.
The far left then is Luciferic.
The far right is satanic.
The door, nobody votes for war.
The satanic can't get elected.
You can't say, all you people, I want you to vote for war.
Nobody's going to vote for war.
The satanic doesn't win elections.
No.
Luciferic sets the stage.
And that's the Trojan horse.
And then the door opens.
And then the satanic comes out with the guns and the murder.
So we just want to see how war evolves.
And if that is the case, if that is the case, if the prelude to all war is the distortion
of truth, if all war is set by falsehood, so the enemy of war, then, is truth.
All right.
And the essence of all the lectures we've given is that you really can't trust anything
in this whole world at all, historically or currently, unless you calibrate this level
of truth.
Why?
Because out of the humility, out of humility, you realize the nature of the mind is such
that it cannot tell truth from falsehood.
You cannot discover the cause of plague until you realize the beginning of truth.
And you realize, to begin with, that you do not know what the cause of plague is.
So long as you think it's overcrowding or night air coming into windows or something,
you won't find it.
So the beginning of all great discovery is humility.
The human mind is not capable of telling truth from falsehood.
A politician doesn't become a great leader because he's stupid.
He becomes a great leader because he is extremely clever in how to persuade people and make
them sound logical and reasonable.
And what the great leader appeals to is your solar plexus and your spleen.
Hitler appealed to the spleen.
And the course is always to right a wrong.
Mankind is led to slaughter by righteousness.
It's righteous to undo the wrong of the Versailles Treaty.
It could have been stopped very easily.
By the French, when he invaded the Sudetenland, that would have been a snap.
It would have saved 70 million lives.
But that requires integrity and the capacity to know the truth.
So we cannot fault mankind, present or past, because it was blind.
It didn't know the cause of plague.
It was simply a bacillus carried by the rat.
It's rat flea.
It's a bacillus that's caused and is carried by the rat flea.
So the rats don't cause the plague.
And the flea doesn't cause the plague.
It's the plague bacillus carried by the flea.
So we start out saying, I don't know anything.
We only have one instrument.
We let you loose in this strange culture here.
We let you out of the spacecraft from this other civilization.
And you only have one tool here.
And that's how to tell truth from falsehood.
You'd be way ahead of the game, wouldn't you?
You don't have to do the Encyclopedia Britannica.
You realize when you look at the Encyclopedia Britannica,
you've got to let all of that stuff go to become enlightened.
Oh, boy.
All the belief systems, all the prevailing attitudes.
So we start out saying, I don't know anything about anything.
That makes it easier to let go of positionalities.
The idea that I know and the idea that I must win,
that what I think my opinion must win,
whether people like it or not, is really the height of egotism.
So we see in the current political world spectacular displays of egotism.
Freedom of speech means I can tell you what I think.
To go beyond that is to exploit the freedom of speech
and now to try to coerce others with moral indignation.
The weapon that's really destroying our current American society
and threatening the fabric of it
is the business of moral indignation,
which we'll get to later when we talk about business.
It's a new industry.
It's a self-propagating industry, extremely well funded,
and its basic work is one of disquietude, complaints,
grievances, moral indignation.
Are we satisfied that we know that they're seeing war and peace
and how they come about?
Anybody have any doubts or questions?
Anybody differs with me?
Anyone wishes to have a duel about the matter?
I'd say the populace, the populace of this country at this time,
calibrates over so-and-so to get where it's at.
I mean, there we've seen endless decades
of mutual provocation.
Anybody who wants peace gets assassinated.
The way to have a short regiment is to...
So you see mutual provocation.
I think I did write about that in the book.
As you watch the clash, you see the provocation.
See, because all this takes us into victim, victim, perpetrator and victim.
All this is tied in with a whole fallacious belief system
which prevails on our society,
having to do with perpetrator and victim.
The way you start a thing off is by playing the victim,
you force the perpetrator to attack you.
This is like suicide by police fire.
I force you now so that you can take the moral blame.
I feint that I have a gun,
and now when the cop in self-defense shoots you,
you're the innocent victim.
This is an extremely non-integrist
and rather malignant development in our society.
And you see how it's based on cause.
If we look at the entire world as if it was one human being,
one human being,
in the practice of medicine,
you have to decide when you're going to operate on an appendix.
It's impending,
and if you wait too long,
the appendix will burst.
Now you've got a real problem,
because you've got an infection,
and you've got peritonitis looking in the face.
It's the physician's duty
to anticipate an obvious process.
You can see that the appendix is getting hotter and hotter
and hotter and hotter.
And you know that if you don't take action,
it will burst,
and now you will die of peritonitis.
You understand?
To save the body,
to save the whole of mankind,
how far can a responsible person
let an appendix develop?
World War II, we saw,
70 million was the death rate
for failing to remove the appendix
in a timely manner.
If the League of Nations was a physician,
he'd still be paying off his malpractice.
You can't wait until it ruptures
and costs 70 million people
or the death of the patient.
Over and over,
my feeling,
people say,
what do you think about Bush?
My feeling about Bush is,
he states his position publicly
over and over again.
If you ask him,
what is his position?
His position says,
he says,
my position is 460.
No, no, you don't say that.
What is 460?
He tells you over and over again,
I took an oath of office
with my hand on the Bible.
Here's a man who's recovered from the war.
Here's a man who's recovered
from a fatal illness
by means of spiritual,
the reason he favors
spiritually oriented recovery groups.
Integrity then.
He says,
I took an oath on the Bible
to fulfill the obligation,
the oath of the President
of the United States of America,
which is to defend its citizens
against all external aggressors.
My feeling is,
he is so profoundly committed to his oath,
he'll forego the next election,
he'll forego anything,
because he knows he's answerable to God
for the oath.
Let's see if that's so.
We have permission to confirm my intuition.
My intuition is correct.
Yes.
Third step in AA,
you surrender your life to God.
You're answerable only to God.
You're not answerable to the poll takers.
You're not answerable to the politicians.
Having taken an oath of office
and sworn in the name of God
to uphold the Constitution,
he doesn't have any freedom to move.
That's how I see his moral position.
His moral position is he's pretty much stuck.
You're the doctor in charge of the case.
When you're the doctor on call,
and they call you for a hot appendix
at one in the morning,
you're it.
Well, as a physician,
you take an oath.
Many a time in my own career,
I had to decide,
am I interested in my popularity
with my colleagues?
Or am I answerable to God
for fulfilling my duty to this patient?
And many of the techniques I used many years ago
were not currently in favor
with the medical establishment.
And I would look at the patient,
and I'd say,
is my obligation to be popular with them?
Will I be answerable on my deathbed
for my popularity with my colleagues?
Or am I going to be confronted
with the face of this man?
God says,
I took an oath to serve this man,
and that is my oath.
Medicare regulations and all,
aside the point.
It's very comical now.
What the government calls HIPAA regulations.
You're supposed to protect the privacy of your patient.
I mean, it's so stupid.
I've protected the privacy of my patient
with my life since I started practicing.
It's been done since the days of Hippocrates.
Now the government wants to come in and
make it a law.
You have to,
I say,
where have these people been all this time?
Without integrity,
you cannot be a great practitioner.
So integrity then is the rule.
You follow your oath.
And if you want to change that,
then you have to disclaim that oath.
You turn in your medical license
and say,
I will not abide by these rules anymore.
I don't worship God.
I worship the Medicare rules and regulations.
Sometimes there's a difference between the two.
All right.
So one is integrous
so long as one states one's position
and then is aligned with it.
What is non-integrous
is to make a statement
that this is my position
whereas actually you're devious
and have a hidden agenda.
Some of the news media,
some of them that are controversial,
I calibrated them
and they were higher than I thought they'd be
because he states you right in the beginning.
States right in the beginning.
This is my position.
And from that position,
this is how it looks.
This is how it looks.
So he's not pretending that he's in the middle.
He's telling you,
I'm a conservative.
I grew up in the Midwest,
conservative.
And from that viewpoint,
this is how it looks.
That's integrous.
To say that you're unbiased
and that you're going to give
an absolutely accurate accounting of the news
and then give it a slant,
that is not integrous.
And that's how some of the networks have gone down.
They've actually gone down in the last year
because pretending to be
objective where you're actually up to something
is what's called a hidden agenda.
So to be integrous,
you can be as loony as you want.
All you have to do is state that.
There's nothing wrong with those positions,
whether they're practical or not is something else.
It's quite easy to look at it
from a Buddhic monastic viewpoint
that no violence under any circumstances
is allowable.
That's fine
if you're living in a monastery.
If you're living on the streets
of various cities in the world,
it'll get you dead quickly.
So there's not a lot of old Buddhist monks
hanging around in the streets.
All right.
So if you want to be a real proponent for peace,
let's have a piece of work again.
If you want to be a real one
and not just one of these talkers,
then you become a champion of truth.
Truth makes war impossible.
When truth prevails,
no war is possible.
So what can we do
as a spiritual warrior
who is pro-peace,
which I presume most people here are?
As you grow in spiritual maturity,
you start out as the,
ooh, isn't it all nice,
pretty flowers and blossoms.
We'll sing hymns
and we'll pray for peace
and we'll tell him
that we want to be nice to him
and we want him to be nice to us.
And that'll work.
So we start out as spiritual innocents.
We're not aware of the downside of human nature.
Then we become adolescent.
We become adventurous.
We have to explore all the New Age fairs,
get a million true psychic readings,
throw the runes, the marbles,
the stones, the jacks,
whatever.
Throw the cards,
throw the picture card,
get your fortune told,
and we play around with that for a while.
Well, that's the adolescent exploring the world.
You know, let's see the world.
What goes on here?
You know, what goes on?
And of course in our teaching we say
don't fool around with it,
stay away from it,
because you're naive,
you don't know truth from falsehood,
and you don't know what you're talking to
on the other side.
That which is non-integrous
wants to control and persuade others.
When you think of it,
why would you want to persuade anybody
about anything?
I don't care if anybody believes anything I say,
frankly.
I only have one obligation.
That's to myself.
To speak of truth is I know it experientially
and through research.
That's my only obligation.
Whether anybody buys it is irrelevant,
because on death's door I've done
what I see I am to do.
My only obligation is to myself.
I'm only answerable to God.
So with that as a yardstick, then,
one becomes,
after the adolescent exploration,
one then starts to become more involved
in spirituality as a lifestyle.
You become sort of a champion of it.
And then we hit the level
of the spiritual warrior.
Spiritual warrior can be incredibly great
or incredibly horrendous.
The children down there with their hearts
and flowers are no threat to anything.
You can just wipe them out and dismiss them.
The warrior now,
you're getting enough power
due to dedication and inspiration,
you can be pretty dangerous.
So the warrior now
can be either integrous or non-integrous.
There are black warriors
just as there are white warriors
speaking certain kinds of language.
Those who stand for peace, then,
and integrity, then,
have to be the champions of truth.
And at some point in some lifetime,
you may have to walk into the bullets.
And it's a so what when you do it.
And then it's ecstasy on the other side.
So on the other hand,
there are warriors that go in the other direction.
Jihad is the spiritual warrior
of the dark side.
Dangerous, where is he?
Dangerous, religious wars
are the most bloody of all.
Here you are at 50.
Jihad is 50.
That is very, very dangerous.
Because when you think you're killing people for God,
you see, the minute you add for God,
now there are no restraints or limitations.
For God, you can do anything.
You can kill millions.
You can torture people to death.
You can blow their heads off.
You can operate on them without anesthesia
while they're still alive.
The most demented things are now
permissive, permissive.
So that's where the danger lies in this world.
The danger is not Iraq and Saddam Hussein
and all those others.
Those are nobodies in the overall
historical evolution of consciousness.
Now here's what's going to hold up mankind right here.
And I don't know how they're going to get over it.
If you polarize a good part of the world's population
in religious war,
now you're going back in history,
you know, close to 2000 years,
the great religious wars of Islam,
et cetera,
pitting Christians and others,
anybody who's not a believer
of whatever they believe.
So the human mind, then,
is easily programmed.
So a person who is really pro-peace, then,
becomes a champion of truth.
There's only one guidepost to reach enlightenment,
and it's the core of all the lectures
and teachings and writings.
There's only one thing you can trust,
and that is truth itself.
That's all you can trust.
All the good books,
you can go to any spiritual bookshop,
it's lined with good books.
Lined with them.
Dozens of mantras and physical exercises.
Breathe in here,
now run the energy down your left leg,
now go out your left nostril,
and pray to the angel,
and chant,
I mean, you know what I mean?
And they charge big bucks for those things,
and the next level will cost you
another couple hundred.
And then after that,
it'll cost you another 500.
All right.
There is absolutely no guidepost at all
in the world we live in
with the human mind,
other than to know
the absolute truth of something.
The human mind is not capable
of knowing truth.
So the way to peace, then,
begins with humility.
The human mind is not capable
of knowing truth from falsehood.
Therefore, we can't hate anybody,
because if they get caught in a bad place,
these jihad people are caught in a bad place.
They're caught in the spleen.
How do you get to heaven and God
through your spleen?
You'll get to someplace,
but it's not celestial realms.
We have names for the lower astral realms.
So those go to the lower astral.
That which really denies God
and blasphemes the name of God
by labeling evil,
as divine.
The ultimate darkness
is to label truth as falsehood,
to deny God and substitute the opposite.
God is not found through the spleen.
Let's see if that's a fact.
You cannot find God through hatred,
through killing people,
through demonizing people,
by hating people.
So should we hate jihad people?
No.
Why would we hate them?
The Hitler Youth under Hitler.
You ever watch any of those great documentaries
on the History Channel?
You end up with a great compassion
for the German youth.
It was like the Boy Scouts.
They sat around the campfire
and sang wonderful songs,
and it was fantastic.
And it was patriotic,
and it was togetherness.
It was,
you could form an image of yourself
as an adequate person.
It was incredibly great.
Except that it worshipped
a megalomaniac instead of God.
That's the only difference.
But as you watch how
the whole culture was inculcated
into these belief systems,
you couldn't have thought otherwise.
If I had grown up in pre-Nazi Germany,
I would have become
a follower of Adolf Hitler, no doubt.
He was the savior of the German people.
He was going to right the wrongs,
and he was the savior of the
recognizing the existence of man
in the first place.
It was not a
reason and a means
to scream and shout
and go to the crossroad.
It was a plan.
It was an integralist.
So you can be an integralist
in your intention,
even though you are going
in the wrong direction.
And Krishna says that.
The difficulty there
with that society
is it was secular.
If they had acknowledged God
And after the Great War, both sides ended up forgiving each other.
German soldiers and American soldiers became close buddies after the war.
Everybody transcended the positionality.
We saw each other just as other human beings.
I used to respect the kamikaze pilot.
I thought, here's a guy who's willing to give his life for his country.
I mean, I've got to salute that guy.
I mean, I may think his plane is going in the wrong direction, but...
I mean, his intention was valorous, was it not?
I mean, what more can you ask of a person?
You give up your life for your country.
So each person then, as Christ said, and as the Buddha said,
everybody, whoever, anybody has said,
that we end up forgiving people and we're compassionate
because we see the limitation of human ignorance.
Intrinsic to the whole structure of the human psyche
is the incapacity to tell truth from falsehood.
And for that reason, we are willing to...
forgive anyone, no matter how,
far from the truth they may appear to us to be.
All right, so we get to the level of the spiritual warrior.
You know, Bush is in a spiritual warrior.
Powell is more to the heart of the spiritual warrior.
But that is carrying forth, let's say,
as he sees it, his Christian duty,
based on his oath of office, his integrity to himself
and to his fellow Americans.
And so one can have an opinion about it one way or the other.
But our job is not to have an opinion about things.
Our job is to try and avoid opinions.
Because if the way to peace is through truth,
then we have to know what truth is.
At first observation, we noticed that 78% of the world's population
is against truth.
Let's have our calibrated levels.
From here up, the commitment is the truth of increasing degrees.
From here down,
it's to falsehood.
Therefore, you can see,
you want peace in a society, in a world,
in which close to 80% of the people
would rather have anything but peace.
Why is that?
Why? Because it's more important to be right.
Isn't it?
Celebrities get up there, make idiots out of themselves.
You know, it's their big ego wanting to be right.
So we say, people like that can't help it.
People would rather be right, even if it costs them their life.
The ego doesn't care anything at all about truth.
It cares about winning and being right at any cost.
Be right at any cost.
All right, let's have the calibrated levels of consciousness
because we're going to see where does mankind go then.
So first of all, only 20% of the population
even gets to the opening doors to truth.
Where you're committed to integrity greater than gain,
which is a solar plexus, winning solar plexus.
And as you go down then, you go down through the pride,
arrogance, greed, fear, all the way down.
Vindictiveness, hatred, polarization.
We've been talking today mainly about the Middle East phenomenon
because it's in today's current news.
Today is spirituality and the world, so I feel obligated to.
Fulfill that title.
Well, what we've been looking at is the high side of life, folks.
Middle East calibrates at what?
What did we say, 140 or, huh?
We were talking about the Middle East.
What did we say it was?
Well, the Middle East then is a region that calibrates at 110.
A festering appendix.
The decision of the government had to be
how long should we wait for the appendix?
Should we wait until it erupts?
Like, how long should we wait?
That's what happened in World War II, World War I.
Or should we try and nip it in the bud?
Like it or not, you've got to operate.
I think that's what his practical,
pragmatic decision was.
All right.
So that's how the world looks at 110.
We look at Israel and Palestine, calibrate 180,
something like that.
You see that that war goes on and on and on.
It's going on since I've been on the planet, frankly.
What happens if we look at the really bad part of the world?
What if we look at Africa?
Rwanda.
Civil war has been going on there for decades.
The U.N. has the slightest interest
that they slaughter each other,
cut each other's legs off,
torture each other to death.
The main way of death in Africa,
which is at war all the time,
is to hack people in small pieces.
That's the best way.
So when we take sort of a calm, detached look at the planet,
we see that
probably for karmic reasons,
certain levels of consciousness
seem to congregate
and get themselves born
in various regions around the world.
See?
The elephant herds don't hang out in New York City.
You know what I mean?
That's been human nature.
The way of animal life
for 40 million years or more,
400 million years,
is that groups tend to congregate
in certain places on the planet.
Right now, the darkest place
is really Africa,
and the Middle East is quite a bit advanced
from where Africa is.
In Africa,
I forget what percent of children die
before age two or something.
They do survive. They probably have AIDS.
And it's doubtful that they'll live long enough
to die of malnutrition.
It's so staggering
that it never hits the news.
You don't see television commercials
or television documentaries
on current life
at the bottom in Africa.
Probably couldn't get on TV.
It's just too horrendous to look at.
So we can look at 110.
110 makes great news.
I don't know what the media's going to do
when the war is finally over
and cleaned up.
We've got, what's her name,
Peterson.
That saved him.
The war came to an end
and happily they discovered Peterson's body
just in time to save the news media.
What are we going to talk about now?
They squeezed every last little bit
of news out of that.
I was going to get a kick out of them
because they'll tell you something that happened
and then they'll tell you what they just told you
and they told you it's a repetition.
They're really squeezing the last
lemon out of the news.
So that's what we call
juicing a phenomenon.
Juicing it.
There's nothing that suits
the ego better than war
to really juice it.
The third chapter,
I think it was chapter four
of the current book I put out
took the longest to write
because it was
the ego and society.
How to look at society
and see it as a projection of the ego
so that like a student
you can impersonally and detachedly
just study it as a phenomenon.
And a great deal of what we've done
in these classes
is to just study
behavior and its expression throughout history
from a somewhat detached
objective view
just as we tried to diagnose
the war this morning.
And what we see is an endless game
an endless game
the players in the game
and we see the different moves
that they can make.
Now the position I played with the gentleman
I had the advantage
I'm a street fighter
that means I can hit you from any direction
I can move in any direction
on the board.
I have no limitation.
You're dead already
before the fight starts
you haven't got a chance.
So I have unlimited movement.
So you look at the chessboard of life
I have a unique piece
I can move in any direction
any time I want.
This piece over here
the gentleman can only move
in this way or this way.
See how the gentleman
is already limited?
I think the religionist, the bishop
he can't move this way and this way
he can only move this way and this way.
So you see the limitation of motion
the limitation of options
goes down.
So when we watch social phenomena
the world is the ego's game board
in which it plays
these different players
each one you have to see
what are his options, what's his upside
what's his downside.
Is somebody who calibrates at 130
going to honor
a contract?
Hitler signed the non-aggression
treaty with
Neville Chamberlain
his intention was to keep it.
After they signed
the whole thing
Hitler thought Neville Chamberlain
was a stupid idiot.
He thought he was a stupid idiot.
We're talking about war man
we're talking about survival
we're talking about death
and this idiot thinks I want to
honor a piece of paper?
Let's see how Lindbergh
and all that ilk
leads to the blindness.
Let's bring in the Trojan horse
it's just a horse
looks peaceful
and out comes the Jihad
So the spiritual warrior then
has to give up naivete
the spiritual maiden
can go around saying
oh isn't that wonderful
we'll have hearts and flowers
and we'll sing songs
and wear long robes
the world doesn't change
they don't have enough power
so the spiritual warrior now
has to give up
has to give up naivete
and I warned you
as spiritual work takes you higher and higher
you get into the 500's
and in the 500's
one can only see innocence
and love
that's all you can see there
everything is beautiful
everything is spontaneous
the fear that there could be
anything else out there
is not thinkable
so the downside of the 500's
the bliss state
is to close your eyes
to the fact
that this is not a celestial realm
we're living in
so the vulnerability then
comes about by naivete
by naivete
you can turn that off for a second
it comes about by naivete
wishful thinking
aspirant then has to go through
some difficult times
and letting go of these illusions
letting go of these illusions
in order to
be a champion of truth
you have to do things that
to the spiritual maiden
sound just awful
oh, how could you do that
how could you take a knife
and cut open a person's belly
you do
to save a life
you gotta cut open the belly
and if you don't clamp them off
they exsanguinate
right on the table
or they die of shock
and if you don't they die of peritonitis
so like the
like the physician, like the surgeon
then the spiritual warrior
reaches the point
where you have to realize
that there are areas
where in almost a surgical precision
you have to be willing to transcend certain illusions
they seem painful
but let them go
to reach spiritual maturity
by hanging out
in naivete
naivete is one thing
maturity is another
we become more realistic
so we stand for then
the dominance of
spiritual truth as the way
to God, the way to realization
of the self, the way to enlightenment
the way to truth then
is to let go of positionalities
war and peace are neither good nor bad
you can't say that to a normal
audience
what do you think about
or feel about war and peace
you want me to be honest
they are all the same to me
it doesn't make any difference one way or the other
why?
because beyond perception
they don't have any particular reality
nor do they have any moral loading
ethical loading of goodness and badness
in the reality which is this instant right now
there is no war, no peace
no anything else
those are all programs and stories
you know whether you go out of
a body like this bang
or you go out
what the hell is the difference
people who have survived heart attacks
people who have had near death experience
know what I am talking about
it's all the same folks
happily I had a near death experience
in teenage
during the war death didn't mean anything at all
there is this mind
with what you would call sticking out
like this and starting to bump against
the star of our ship you know
because you are going to blow up
any second you are going to just go up with
this fine thing
so all I am worried about is it is going to scratch
the paint on the side of the thing
and blow us all the kingdom come
you know what I mean
hey man get a boat hook and help me will you
no fear of death at all
so it is comical
so if you get outside of this instant
then you have fear
I still see a few old patients that I have seen for umpteen years
they are too old
they slowly die off so I just figure
I will just wait
they are all as old as I am
so anyway
those that are walking in one banana peel
I tell them look call me for the next appointment
so one of them
of course I adore them all
that is why I don't chuck them all
I adore them
this old guy is sitting there
and he has got this oxygen tank
he has got his oxygen tank
and he is older than nails older than dirt
she calls me older than dirt
deficit post and older than dirt
she tells all the nurses
so anyway he is older than dirt
and he comes in and he has got his oxygen tank
and he has got this thing around his nose
and he sits down and he says
you got a light
I said yeah
he put his cigarette in his mouth
and I said
are we going to blow up
he says I don't think so
I said ok
he didn't think so
I suppose you should shut off the oxygen before hand
I am sure it has got a
got a warning on the tank
I said what does it say on the tank
he says I don't know I never read it
the manufacturer I am sure doesn't want to get sued
if we blow each other up
but it is that living in the moment
you see
and it really didn't make any difference
if we both went sky high
we went sky high
you got to get out of here somewhere
you want it slow and horrid
alright
so to die for one's cause
then is
of course the hero of the war
is that young lady who got captured
and beat up
so she stands for something
that is
embedded in the core of America
the
warrior but not just a warrior
a warrior with commitment
so the difference
between the killer and the warrior
is that the warrior is doing it for a principle
doing it for a cause
doing it for something greater than themselves
and in World War II
the greater than oneself
was not just one's country and all
and of course everybody wanted to win
but it was more a loyalty to one's
shipmates
the loyalty to one's shipmates
was the
integrous core
if that mind blew up
we blew up
but that didn't stop somebody else
from coming over and helping
so you see in the midst of war
that which
we would think would be highly
you know not really a very spiritual
kind of a place
the midst of war is sacred indeed
in the midst of war
is sacred
the midst of war is where a bonding goes on
of a lifetime
of those shipmates
sixty years ago or whatever it is
those that still
remain
are the same as they had always
been and I remember when they
called me up
they located each other
after fifty or sixty years
everybody started to cry
and when you hear this person's voice
they say this is so and so
and instantly the tears would come up
and you see that veterans of World War II
when they're interviewed about the war
so you see that patriotism is of the heart
to not love your country
means to be dead
if you cannot love the source
of your survival
my father and my mother
doesn't mean biologic
those two people
it means to honor your heritage
the evolution of mankind
is now expressing itself
and the karmic upside of the human
is that you've inherited
that which is
the willingness
to share
to be responsible
to forgive each other when the chips are down
when World War II is over
all of us
forgive each other
what could he do except do his best
for the Weimar people
so we saw the basic integrity
and because we saw the ignorance
under the integrity
where he willingly forgave each other
we don't have any resentment
left about anything
about any fact of war
so in the end compassion then
takes us beyond war and peace
it brings us to the awareness
of our reality
that all that goes on there
that brings itself out there
as human society
can't help be what it is
at the moment it's being what it is
if it could be something else
it would be
the fact that it isn't
means it can't
if the person with an IQ of 90
could get straight hundreds
in school he would
with an IQ of 90
you're lucky to get straight C's
and that's all we expect of them
so you see
on this planet
we share a common commitment
the karma of being a human
is staggering
just be a human
therefore I honor and respect
any human being that walks this planet
because to be a human being
is extraordinarily difficult
extremely painful
extremely challenging
uncertain at every second
one second of inattention
and your car rolls over and you're dead
so we all live one second from death
more people have died on the highways in Arizona
than have died in Iraq
this last month
since the time the war's been on
more people have been killed on the highway
in the US military
but it's not dramatic
see how we just accept
well death by automobile
that's not a big story
50,000 people die a year
in automobile deaths
where's the excitement
where's the drama
where's the parades
there's a lot of different politicians out there
with a big make wrong
so you see
the tendency of the ego then is to
take a position
then dramatize it
then put a lot of energy in it
it gets polarized against people who think differently
than you do
the positions that people represent then
about the war
are reflective of their level of consciousness
we need a level of consciousness back again
alright we said 80% of the people live
below here
so if we calibrate people's level of consciousness
we can see
they're not reflecting reality
they're reflecting their own level of consciousness
people who live down here
come out of hatred
these people come out of gain
we're going to reconstruct Iraq now
you can see all the bottom feeders coming in
with those contracts
get them contracts
when the fight is going on
they'll disappear
when it's time to start
when they're missing the pumps
everybody's out there with their hands out
so there you got the solar plexus in greed
you see how pride plays into the whole thing
how rage, anger
how fear drives people
then we have the courageous
you know
really make the headlines
that girl will be a hero forever
then you get into neutrality
which is beyond it all
the position I gave to you before
sounds like neutrality
it's okay if we have peace, it's okay if we have war, don't bother me
the detachment
then the willingness to enter in
and own the bottom side of it
then the acceptance that this is human nature
so what we're seeing is human nature
expressing itself out there on the game board
of the evolution of human consciousness
at this point
then we see the intellect and reason
the intellect and reason is the doctor
it says
how far can we let this appendix go
before we do something
then we see love surpassing all of it
we see that love
is unlimited
unlimited love at 540
is rare, rare
it means to love everybody no matter what
can we feel sorry for Ben Loudon
and all these people
it's pathetic isn't it
there's no point in hating somebody
that is so weird
what's the name of that dragon
Komodo dragon
let's see if we can find out
my friend the Komodo dragon
calibrates over 40
if you have permission
the Komodo dragon calibrates about 40
can you believe a guy going in there with his shoes off
to make nice with the Komodo dragon
he did it so help me
he took his shoes off
and he thought he was tame
you saw the game we started with
well I was the Komodo dragon
and he was the movie star
or the husband of the movie star remember him
takes his shoes off
and hangs out with the Komodo dragon
and he's still living
beyond imagination
oh let's have the war and peace
back again now that we have the Komodo dragon
we really should have Komodo dragon
on there for contrast
so help me God there is a human being
that calibrates the same as the Komodo dragon
we should really
enter into peace negotiations
with him don't you think
I will invite him to a duel
me and Ben Loudon
will demonstrate
how to do that
gentlemen would you like to come up again
we'll have another duel
thank you
we'll have a break
we'll have a short break and then we'll resume