we share our spiritual experience and what has come about in the transformation of our own life
with others so what we do is we carry the message and we carry the message primarily
intuitively and in the non-verbal although we describe the events within the verbal
the person gets from your aura what that is and it's the energy that you bring to the person
and not your conversation so the conversation is because you got to say something in this world
and you hope the message might grab them but you only share it because spirituality grows by
attraction and not promotion which is another principle of the 12-step recovery groups you never
see 12-step groups proselytizing nobody tries to get you to give up smoking drinking sex or whatever
they tell you i
used to be an abusive person and i had a terrible temper and i hit my wife a couple times and i
landed in court and and i really was scared and i couldn't stop it i couldn't stop it
and then i went to such and such a group and now everything is healed and i've learned how to handle
it and i learned a lot about myself in the process and i'm a different person and the
person i've become now doesn't hit people so it's by transformation so spiritual steps then
are designed to bring
about a transformation so we thought i thought i'd give a little time to the 12 steps because
they have such a profound effect on our society beyond people's awareness
people who are familiar with this very these various groups pick up a concept just like that
and i hear people in extremely high places in the world just with a simple remark i know
how he cuts over and why he feels spiritually committed to what he's committed to
because
just one word will tell you what their background is spiritually
so that pervades a great part of our current society see our society was at 190
human society was at 190 it's now at 207 well it didn't pull itself up by its bootstraps you can
see that by the pure nature of the ego in and of itself the ego isn't going to give up any turf
whatsoever so the spiritually committed
people in our society are influencing others by virtue of that which they have become
not by proselytizing not by preaching but by by that which they have become in the presence of a
more spiritually evolved person it is quite difficult to be vulgar and violent and selfish
you start to feel uncomfortable about it you felt okay with it on the street where it's the style
but as you start to present the same story
to more spiritually evolved people you see them change at the girls ranch where i've been for 12
years i'm going to have to resign from there do like a time but we see hopeless i found another
doctor to come in so i've treated you know a thousand thousand teenagers highly resistant
savage backgrounds brutality brutality so extreme you say this is not possible this is not possible
and i won't even describe it here the experience is not possible and i won't even describe it here
the experiences are so grotesque so extreme you say that's not even possible i don't want to even
hear their history social workers starts to tell me this is their history i said i don't want to
hear it i just accept it's catastrophic and how can anybody recover from that how can anybody
possibly recover from that it went on for years for instance and how can they well i'll tell you
they can't ptsd dude that said savagery you can't recover
there's no psychological technique there's no medicine there's no physical healing you cannot
so how can you recover from it only by the miraculous the power of love
so each month the girl comes in and you watch the transformation from ferociously angry ferociously
depressed assaultive suicidal they cut on themselves all the time they try to overdose
kill themselves and you watch gradually the flower blooming so you see that which is possible
only by love only love could bring it out of that savagery into become a beautiful young person
so the damage then is spiritual and the recovery then is spiritual the people below 200 are
you can look at them as severely damaged spiritually whether it's by their own election
whether it's by karmic fate or by what up for whatever reason we now see that they are
spiritually damaged people other than a powerful field this powerful field here is so powerful
that it pulls the miraculous forth in those who have karmic permission to do so
it doesn't always happen in this lifetime and you don't know with the reason for it you would have to
see the karmic path away so you don't know what the reason for it you would have to see the karmic path
of all the lifetimes, all the decisions, the context of it all,
the karmic pattern of the country, the ethnic group, the family.
You would have to know a great deal.
That's why all the steps that are profoundly powerful then
all require surrender of one's willingness and they all require humility.
I don't know why this one recovered and that one didn't.
But the miraculous is commonplace.
They should never have been able to get up and walk again.
So we surrender, we start from the ego position.
Guilt, we share our shortcomings with other people, we look at ourselves
and we constantly refer what's in the field to the field itself.
We ask God for help. We constantly turn our life over to God.
We pray to God for understanding. We pray to God for direction.
So we're constantly moving our tentacles out into the field
and we say, in and of ourselves, we are unable to help ourselves.
It's only by the spiritual truth of those who have evolved.
Therefore, everyone here, by merely being here to this day,
is already serving all of mankind. You understand?
Just the advance, just your own willingness.
Your willingness to advance your own consciousness already uplifts mankind.
People say, what can I do for the world?
You're doing it. You're doing it.
The power of spiritual commitment uplifts by its own nature
because it uplifts the field.
In previous lectures, we tried to align that for the skeptical
with Henry Stapp's email or what do you call that website thing
coming out of Berkeley with the quantum mechanics.
How he correlates quantum mechanics with how everything works.
So every spiritual decision uplifts the field of mankind
and that the field then lifts each one of us.
So each one of us then is contributing to the rise of the water, you might say.
And as the water rises, it lifts all the ships,
no matter what their size, that are afloat.
So consciousness is like the sea. We uplift everyone.
So every girl at the girl's ranch recovers, helps every other recover.
And we see great inspirational stories of people
who have been savaged early in their life.
Instead of falling into and buying victimhood,
they bought the spiritual way out.
And we see people of great prominence,
some of the most famous people in the world had savage backgrounds
and they stand for the recovery through spiritual principles.
It's only through spirituality that recovery from that
and these things can come about.
All right, so we've got a short time before lunch.
I thought, let's try something different.
Instead of just reading the questions out loud,
anybody who wants to come up and talk to us, let's talk to us.
And we're going to be on, you know, everybody's going to hear it.
So we're going to share what goes on with everyone and come on up.
So we'll just come on up and gather around
and we'll just begin to really discuss things.
We've got 15 minutes and then we'll take a break for lunch.
We'll try it. We'll try it for 15 minutes.
So everybody who's got a question, come up at once.
Because we want people to hear how it really goes
and not just in a lecture format.
I mean, just exactly how it is.
You'd like to sit down?
Yeah, sit down, right there. No, we'll just sit right here.
Let them sit there and I'll sit here.
Yeah, they need a chair too.
Yeah, what's up?
Two quick questions.
Yeah, can you hear me all?
They all want to hear your question.
Can you hear?
Hello?
Two quick questions.
Yes, indeed.
I'm scheduled for surgery next week and I'm wondering to know,
is having a local or a general anesthetic,
is there any spiritual risk associated with that?
I don't see any spiritual risk.
Okay.
No.
Okay, that's a great answer.
Second thing is I've been suffering, I have constant fatigue
and I've had it for about the past two years.
I'm going through the various programs and things you recommend.
Yeah.
They still seem to have it.
And I'm just wondering, is there something I'm holding in mind?
That's causing me to manifest this fatigue.
Have you tried psychopharmacology?
No.
Well, try it.
Okay.
If you're knocked down all the time,
what happens is you can get like spiritually, psychologically depressed.
Then the neurotransmitters in the brain change.
Now, even though you've solved the original problem,
you can't come out of it because now it's taken on a life of its own
in the brain chemistry.
So let's say you go through a tragic thing you've really recovered from,
but a couple of years later you're still depressed.
That's because your serotonin level or some neurotransmitter got knocked out.
Sometimes you just take it briefly, you come out,
and then you can taper it off and you don't need it.
So everything is physical, mental, and spiritual.
It's all integrated.
So you can't say, well, I just want to do only a spiritual way,
because if you're really spiritual, you wouldn't resist recovering.
See?
And I did tell you that before.
Yeah, right.
Well, people do because of certain belief systems.
See, that's intellectualizing.
Okay.
You know, if I was really spiritual, I wouldn't take Prozac.
Oh, why not?
Yes.
If you're spiritual, you would take Prozac.
Why?
How can you serve God when you're depressed and in bed all day?
Okay.
And that's of much use to anybody.
Yes.
Yeah.
Thank you.
So if you're up and around and being with people.
So do anything that might help it.
Maybe just do something mild, you know.
Thank you.
Again, very brief, too.
I think a lot of times the neurotransmitter goes out.
You see, genetically, the human, don't forget,
genetically, you know, about a third of the population,
lack sufficient neurotransmitters to not be depressed.
About a third of the population becomes depressed,
sometimes seriously.
So there's a genetic defect in the human gene pool,
and they're depressed for no reason.
You know, it's not like your mother got run over by a truck
and you're depressed about that.
That's a reactive depression.
No, it's endogenous.
There's nothing happening out there to be depressed.
That's why families give them a hard time.
They say, well, you've got nothing to be depressed about.
You're president of the company.
You know what I'm saying?
Yeah, he's thinking about killing himself.
He's very depressed, you know.
And so, you know, denial coming out of pridefulness,
when we're humble, we accept the limitations
of our own physiology.
You know, I can't jump six feet high.
You know what I mean?
I can't jump six feet.
I couldn't climb that rope in high school,
you know, grade school, or whatever it was.
So I'm an ectomorph, and an ectomorph,
you can't climb that rope that fast.
You know what I'm saying?
I understand that.
Thank you.
And then away for one of those strength courses,
you know, Charles something or other.
He was the world champion.
Charles Atlas.
Yeah.
Well, this is back in the 30s.
So I got lesson one, which was free.
And then for $6, you could get the whole course.
Well, $6 in the 30s was, you know, like a thousand now.
So it was only one lesson,
how to strengthen your gastrocnemius muscles.
So I did that one over and over.
I had the greatest gastrocnemius muscles.
Later on, I ended up with an 18-mile trip
to the paper route, the biggest in Wisconsin.
So those little gastrocnemius came around, didn't they?
One free lesson, and I had the biggest paper route in town,
you know.
So we don't know what the payoff is on these things, you know.
But you see how you've helped a lot of people,
because a lot of people out there have the same problem.
Yes.
You know.
And I had denied that opportunity.
Well, look, people believe it in all these spiritual programs.
Even AA, they'll tell you,
well, you shouldn't take Prozac.
Why not?
Yeah, I thought I shouldn't,
so that's why I said to heck with it.
Yeah.
So what should I do, kill myself?
Should I kill myself or take Prozac?
Okay.
Well, death is going to be on your head.
All right.
So that would be the advice.
Everything is physical, mental, and spiritual,
including alcoholism and many spiritual things,
because the body, mind, and spirit are integrated, you know.
And we know through the acupuncture system
and the flow of the chi energy and all that
that we're influencing our physiology all the time, you know.
In fact, the whole kinesiologic response is based on that.
So every negative thought or feeling is impairing the energy flow
down some acupuncture meridian and impairing some body organ.
You understand what I'm saying?
Mm-hmm.
So you can't separate the physical and the mental or spiritual.
You know, they interact together almost as one.
Thank you for answering the question.
Thank you.
Because I'm sure a lot of people out there have had that question.
In fact, it does arise.
I see a lot of people in the AA, and that does arise.
One of my sponsors says I shouldn't take Prozac.
Yeah, right.
The question I have is,
you say that death is a physical thing.
Yeah.
You say that death is...
Oh, sorry.
Yeah.
We'll put this so that people can hear.
We should put it on .
We should put this on the other side.
Yeah.
That death is predetermined before we're born.
No, I said at the moment of birth.
Or at the moment of birth.
Moment of birth.
And if that's the case,
really there is no wrong way to die,
and that you can't really kill yourself,
then is that correct?
What do you mean, wrong way to die?
Well, the other thing we've found is that
death is predetermined before we're born.
Oh, I see.
I see.
Well, the other thing we've learned so far
is that the moment of death is already preset.
How you do it is your own choice.
You have a big influence on the how of it,
but the time of it, we know, is set.
Yeah.
The time.
So if you tried to kill yourself,
and it wasn't your time to go...
I think...
I don't know if we've got permission to answer that.
We have permission to answer that.
No, we don't have permission to answer that.
Okay.
We're just trying to figure out...
Yeah.
...then really there's...
If it's not our time to go, it doesn't seem like any way could make you leave.
Yeah, well, that's bringing the question.
If it wasn't the time to go, how could you go?
Right.
It's a hypothetical impossibility.
Yeah.
So the problem is how you're phrasing it.
It's not a real question.
Oh, okay.
You're asking me the hypothetical.
If a thing wasn't what it is, then how come it isn't something else?
You can't leave the earth.
I mean, I can't answer that.
So I say it like a statement.
You can't leave the earth.
Why are you worrying about it?
I'm not.
I'm just a question because...
Oh.
You're just trying to stump the expert.
Is that it?
Yeah.
Oh, okay.
Thank you.
I'm just trying to figure it out because people do kill themselves, and then I'm
wondering...
Yeah.
But this is only hypothetical to you.
I can't answer hypothetical questions.
Oh.
Okay.
I can only answer the real.
Are you thinking about killing yourself?
No.
Oh, okay.
Okay.
Anybody got any other questions?
No.
Okay.
Anybody got any other questions?
How does...
Thank you.
All right.
My question is, how does the I am teaching calibrate?
I don't know.
And how does the Don Hawk teaching calibrate?
Can you?
Thank you.
We're working on that.
Okay.
I'm going to have to change this over to this side because...
I'll start.
You have a question?
In this world, there's 1000 spiritual teachers, techniques, practices, mantras, ashrams, ringing
of bells, gongs, incense, robes, shaving one's head, standing on one's head, 20 ways of breathing.
Million things.
The reason we talk about non-duality is we want to avoid all that.
You see, if you follow the pathway of strict non-duality...
you don't get embroiled in that, because those are all dualistic.
Non-duality, you avoid getting sidetracked into the carnival.
The spiritual carnival out there is endless,
and the stuff that comes into my office is so mind-boggling,
I say, nobody would publish this or follow it.
Strange belief systems.
The more bizarre and strange and non-verifiable,
the more skeptical you have to become.
See, the spiritually committed are notoriously naive and easily taken, I'll tell you.
And some parts of this planet, it has become a great skill over the centuries.
How to fleece the spiritually naive.
It's a skill.
It's done with masterful techniques,
so convincing that hundreds of thousands of people swear this must be a living saint.
The great avatar.
It's come to rescue mankind, you know.
Every day, I get the name and some book by some great avatar that's come to save mankind.
They calibrate 298.
If you can save mankind from 298, I don't know how you do it.
So, that's romanticizing, you see.
It's glamorizing and romanticizing.
And here's the great avatar, you know, the great avatar.
And then the next thing is they have many followers.
Well, don't forget 78% of the population,
the population is below 200.
So, anybody who's even at 205, if it's already an avatar, you know what I mean?
To be decided to be honest in a world of crooks makes you almost a Christ, right?
Yeah.
So, my question is, do every human being come to this earth to grow our consciousness?
Do every one of us share the same path?
That's my understanding.
Everybody's here for the same reason.
That we were, if we'd reached absolute enlightenment,
that we're here for the same reason,
for absolute perfection, we'd be in some celestial realm.
If we were hopeless, we'd be committed into hell.
No, this is more purgatorial because you see the whole range of opportunity.
You can go from saint to sinner at any moment.
You can make a choice.
The freedom to recover.
So, this is to me like a self-healing opportunity.
Obviously, we had good karma to have earned to be in a realm
where we have the option of undoing our past errors.
our past errors and creating good karma for ourself.
The downside of that is you also have the opportunity to create bad karma for yourself.
You can go up or down.
So to me this is a realm of great freedom.
At any instant you can choose to go up or go down and complete great karmic cycles,
great karmic cycles.
So in this lifetime we see all kinds of transformations in all directions.
You look at the immense freedom, you see the immense range here, all the way from the most
pitiful bottom of the pit to the highest possible levels of enlightenment.
All of that is possible here.
What a great opportunity.
Where else could you go?
People want to come to America because here they see it on an economic level.
So we represent the world as more than just economic.
It's greater than that.
So people are attracted to freedom.
What we mean by freedom is it's up to your choice to move yourself up or down.
So this world offers the maximum opportunity.
People want to wipe out something.
They're wiping out that as a karmic opportunity because people were counting on that to get
them out of that last bad karma they had.
You got a law of war, now what are you going to do?
I don't know, you're really stuck.
So some clarification.
Yeah.
Tell me about that.
I don't know.
The law of karma specifies that if what we do right now will affect the potential of
choice we can make in the future.
Yes, because of the simple definition, you see.
It's very hard to get beyond the dualistic thinking.
Everything merely is what it is because it is what it is.
The sole reason for it being what it is is that it is that.
To try and jump that and create an explanation or a rationalization is moving out of reality.
It is what it is because that's what it is.
So the self-identity is very hard for the mind to see.
It always thinks it is this because of that.
No, it is what it is because that is the fulfillment of its potentiality as it is created at this
instant.
So what is the position for free will then?
If we just come to here to fulfill our potential?
Well, because free will operates with limitations.
You don't have the free will to be a millionaire by tomorrow, right?
No.
Okay.
So we say we have free will, but the range in which we have free will or options is already
limited karmically, see?
You've become what you are.
Well, now, what you are now has a certain range of options, and by other choices you
may move yourself into another level where you have a different range of options.
A child who's half beaten to death and left to starve and sexually raped and etc. as happens
to these young children has no example of love, no experience of love, and it doesn't
have the option to become loving tomorrow, you know?
No, you have to put them in a whole field of love, and now they begin to experience
what that is, be considerate of others, they never thought of being considerate of others.
You grab what you want and what you get.
And hating others, they don't see anything wrong with that.
They come from a world of hatred, so it's only now they begin to experience a whole
different dimension.
They begin to see different options, you know, to let a thing go and not hit the kid
back.
Wow, they never even thought of that, you know?
I just feel sorry for the kid instead of hitting him.
Whoa, what a move.
Well, that option wasn't there before.
So somehow they have the sufficient karmic momentum to carry them into a therapeutic
and healing environment where they can come out of it and survive, you know, spiritually.
Yeah?
Can you talk about spiritual vision?
How do we get that?
You got one?
Well I just wanted to tag something on what you were just saying.
If that's true and this person, like the girl at the girl's ranch, is in this certain
circumstance that she was born into, and in your book you say the average person only
can move maybe five points in a lifetime.
That's the average.
Statistical average, yeah.
Yeah, but then I saw on the twelve steps you're talking about somebody moving from
a very low scale to a 540 where healing can happen.
And so I'm wondering, okay, how do you do that?
Yeah.
How do we know what's possible for us?
Because what I'm really hearing is all things are possible.
We don't know.
You see, the miraculous is merely completely surrendering to God and then the possible
becomes an actuality.
So there is no actual limitation.
So is it the person that moved or is it the event that moved?
The consciousness moves.
And you know, when I said they move five percent, five points in a lifetime, that was just a
statistical average for mankind.
How fast does mankind grow?
But the individual has no such limitation, you know.
Very often a person, you can go from the pits of hell all the way up to a state of enlightenment
in one shot.
Heaven and hell are a tenth of an inch apart as a fact, and experientially that's precisely
the fact.
From the pits of hopeless hell, eternal agony, if there is a God, I ask him to help me, suddenly
into the revelation of this divinity itself as the only God.
That's what I'm trying to say.
I'm trying to say that the self as the allness of existence and the personal self went up
in smoke.
So one can travel hundreds and hundreds of points.
People in these rooms, let's say if we do a before and after, you know, the average
is maybe 10-15 points, something like that.
But within the audience, you can say and what was the maximum that any one person jumped,
you can probably get a couple hundred.
So people go through huge leaps.
And of course, the reason...
Don't forget, for all the people who make a positive choice and advance in consciousness,
there are a greater number who make a negative choice.
Seventy percent of the population is choosing to hate the SOB because it deserves it.
So when you measure somebody like Carl Jung and he's 5'40, he's 5'40 at that given
moment that he was measured or he's...
Well, I mean, if we ask now, see, don't forget, we're just sketching out.
It was just like the telescope was just invented.
We're giving a rudimentary idea of the cosmos.
I'm sure.
Everything we're saying is very naive.
Many of the things that we've discovered, you know, would in themselves just be a whole
research project.
For instance, you watch the evolution of consciousness and how it's spread across the map over time.
And you can take just minute little, small little things.
We don't have time.
We're just...
So we're trying to give a rough scale that you can roughly...
What you're trying to get is a general feeling for consciousness itself and how it grows
and what it means.
And the awareness that certain spiritual environments are sustaining a spiritual growth and others
are deleterious.
And also what to watch for on the downside.
Yeah.
So does karma come from fear?
Is fear the base?
No, no.
Karma is a principle.
It's a principle of consciousness.
Everything that exists then reflects the quality of its existence.
And this is outside of time and space.
So, when the entity leaves the body, that you take with you, that which you have become,
which is the result of spiritual intention.
Spiritual intention is what sets your karma and sets your calibrated level of consciousness.
It's the intentionality.
It's the intention and not the outcome, so we become the consequence of our own spiritual
decisions.
Right?
Spiritual will sets up karma, not just getting mad because your fingernail broke or the filling
station was closed and it's too late or something.
Those don't change your calibrated level of consciousness because your commitment, whatever
your commitment is, is strong and it doesn't vary from second to second, you know.
Major changes will change your calibrated level of consciousness, but it's not aligned
with the trivial from second to second.
It's the decisions you make to forgive instead of to hate.
All the twelve steps take you through the evolution of consciousness, to look at myself
instead of the world, to make a decision to do something about it, to admit to myself
that I unaided and lack sufficient power to overcome this.
So you ask for God's help and understanding and then the miraculous occurs that people
suddenly appear in your life who just seem to have the answers you're looking for.
A five-oh-five dog just happens to show up.
All right, it's five after.
So now I just thought we'd try this and if you like it as a teaching technique rather
than a didactic lecture, we'll do it again.
We can group, more of us group around and I can even go up and down the aisle as long
as I've got this thing with me, you know, and we can ask if there's any questions.
Do you think it's a good idea?
Yeah, it's very interesting.
It's wonderful.
Absolutely.
You know what I mean?
It's biblical.
Yeah, well, it's real that way.
So that's what we're going to do is we're going to try it as a different experience
collectively.
You know, we're all together on this ship at this time and it affects one of us, affects
us all.
So I'm concerned with the happiness and spiritual growth and welfare of everybody here, everyone,
every single person without exception.
Thank you so much.
So we'll reconvene.
Is this thing on?
Yeah.
Is it on?
Is this on?
Yes.
Is it on?
Some people don't know whether it's on or not.
That's not a good sign.
Okay.
Is everybody here?
Who's here?
That's what I want to know.
All right.
We had a few questions arise during lunch, a few explanations.
And we're going to do more gathering together and having informal discussion and have it,
you know, on the sound system.
So we all get together.
All right.
We all get to hear it.
Some lectures, just the two people up in front are talking to each other and the whole audience
sits there wondering what's going on.
All right.
The audience, we calibrate, you know, the audience has gone up 10 points already.
People ask what is the calibrated level of the audience.
The difficulties some people have is in correlating the content of these lectures, which is called,
don't forget, devotional non-duality.
Okay.
So they come to me with a dualistic question out of a dualistic pathway.
This morning's, can't wait.
The lectures calibrate around 980.
Let's see.
What is the lecture?
The lecture calibrates around 975, 980, 985, 986, 986.
All right.
So we're describing a pathway which is extremely advanced.
985.
You can't always integrate that with a teacher.
Okay.
It's a teaching that comes out in the 400s, 500s, or 600s.
Because it's coming from a different paradigm of reality.
Is the world that we perceive, does it have actual existence?
No.
We already cleared that up this morning, that the world that we perceive.
So it really brings up the problem of perception.
Because of the positionalities of the ego, we have perceptions and then we presume that
our perceptions are the reality.
And duality means one transcends all positionalities and begins to see that everything is what
it is.
That's a dramatic jump in consciousness.
If you can just see everything is perfectly what it is, period.
It's putting the period on that is very hard for the mind to take.
The mind doesn't want to hear about periods.
It wants to go back.
It wants to go with why, delve into the hypothetical.
But Baba so-and-so says this, and the course of yuckety-yuck says this, and how is it group
says that?
Well, I don't know.
That's their problem, frankly.
There is a certain teaching that the physical world itself is an illusion.
And the next time you bark your shin, you ask yourself that.
It isn't that this dimension is unreal.
It's that it's a different dimension, a different dimension that includes physicality and the
experience of physicality.
What is really being meant by somebody like Ramana Maharshi, let's say, is easy to see
from this morning's lecture.
Once you stop saying anything about the world, there's nothing to criticize, nothing to correct,
nothing that needs to be changed.
You see that it is what it is.
This tree is like this.
This doesn't mean this is a bad tree or this is a twisted tree.
What many people want to do is take these trees and straighten them out.
You hear the snapping of vertebrae as they do that.
Straighten you out so you see it their way.
All right.
When you see everything as it is, there's nothing you want.
There's nothing you want to change.
You don't perceive anything as being needful of change.
You see each thing being what it is at the moment because each thing is fulfilling its
karmic destiny and its existence is coming out of divinity.
The capacity to move through one's karma into the fulfillment of one's potentiality is the
consequence of the enormous field of power which, like gravity, stands there, and in
the power of gravity.
Each thing goes where it goes by the nature of what it is.
That's all.
Each thing goes where it goes as a consequence of that which it is.
Gravity is not forcing it to do so.
To think so is an invention of mentation.
Gravity is just standing there.
It's not doing anything.
The little iron filings with their charges and polarities are not really doing anything either.
Right?
They're just automatically shifting in the field as a consequence of that which they
have become.
So the calibrated levels of consciousness are merely how the little charged up iron
filings filter out.
Just as you go to the bottom of the sea, each thousand feet down you have a whole different
dimension.
All kinds of systems depend on the pressure of the water being four hundred times that
which it is on the surface.
There's different consequences.
On the other hand, the sea is not causing it to do that.
It's being that as a consequence of the reality in which it is surrounded.
I always forget what these lectures are about.
Somebody reminded me this morning.
It says enlightenment, dedication, goals, and commitment.
Oh, okie doke.
I thought we sort of hit that this morning.
Dedication, goals, and commitment.
All right.
Actually, what happens is the field, you're caught up in the field, and the field brings
you to a greater and greater curiosity, commitment, a certain fraternity with like-minded individuals.
The goal is to advance one's consciousness, eventually to reach God, which brings about
a dedication which expresses itself.
Which expresses itself as commitment.
Well, the commitment eventually becomes more and more intense.
There's no linear way to describe it except that if we use the analogy of the sea, the
water pressure becomes enormous depending on the depth.
As one gets closer and closer to the surface, transformational changes are the consequence
of the total field.
See, it's difficult for people to get out of a dualistic linear causality.
That my dedication is going to cause me to go here and reach that goal.
You know?
Reach goal one.
Got to forgive my mother-in-law.
Okay.
So, it's more a non-linear subtlety, but it is and can be and eventually becomes extremely
intense.
It becomes more intense.
The desire for enlightenment becomes overriding of everything else.
But that's really the consequence of the field.
As you keep surrendering the obstacles, the field gains greater and greater power.
And many people have walked away from what the world calls the ultimate, the ultimate
of success, etc.
The ultimate in every department.
Status, money, everything.
Power.
And completely walked away from it.
And walked into some little chapel somewhere.
And got the, to me, the top job is the janitor.
The top job is to be the janitor in Shark Cathedral.
That's the top job on the planet.
And when the congregation and the incense and all clears away, you have the entire cathedral,
which just knocks you out.
And therefore, you don't do anything for hours at a time.
And you hire some kid to sweep the floor and dust everything.
And you bliss out.
So, you can get just so close to the spiritual reality.
And then as you get near level 600 or so, there's a tendency to bliss out.
I have to watch with certain music as they start the music.
There's a certain phrase there where it takes you right through that phase.
And it's just easy to just bliss out and begin to cry and forget the audience.
Yeah.
Sure, beauty does that to you.
It wipes you out.
So, the presence of God is sensed as beauty.
And there was a few other questions.
And then I thought, we'll go on to, we'll do sort of like we did this morning.
And we'll try it out this time.
And there's a confusion between intention and causality.
Causality is an operating principle made up by the mind.
It calibrates around 460 to explain perceptual phenomena.
It doesn't explain phenomena.
It explains one's perception of the phenomena.
The subtlety of moving from pseudo-objectivity to realizing that everything is subjective,
is very, very subtle.
And people can study the subject for a lifetime and miss the whole point.
That the thought that causality explains things neatly within the Newtonian paradigm,
still remains an explanation.
And within that which exists itself, there is no such operational principle as causality,
which would be explicable in terms of physics.
The flower is what it is and becomes this potentiality
due to, operationally, an infinite number of factors.
And as we've calibrated in public before,
the number of factors necessary to completely explain
why one speck of dust is sitting here in the middle of the air
is infinite, infinite, infinite number.
You have to have the room here.
You have to have the very magic pressure.
You have to have the wind.
You have to have somebody that observed it in the first place.
And for this building to be here, there has to be this state.
There has to be this planet.
There has to be this galaxy.
You have to go back to creation.
So the explanation for this piece of dust here
takes us back to the question of creation itself.
Inexplicable in terms of ordinary consciousness.
When one first goes into a very advanced state,
one of the strange things,
not in a very, yeah, it's a very advanced state,
around 600 or something, high 500s or 600s,
somewhere around there,
during the course of miracles,
it's a very not uncommon phenomenon.
As you're walking about,
you notice that you're in love with everyone.
You begin to notice how everybody looks handsome,
everybody looks well-dressed,
everybody looks beautiful,
everything is gorgeous,
and everything is happening perfectly.
And you also notice that everybody seems
to be in a dream.
You notice that people are completely unconscious,
that there's two dialogues going on.
There's what they think is being said and happening,
and then there's what's really going on
of which they are unaware.
And they seem to be in a dream state.
What is the dream state they're in?
This morning we came up with
what percent of the mind is silent?
98?
Okay.
So they're unaware of the 98 percent
because they're so focused on the 2 percent.
So focused on the 2 percent.
So that's what gives them the dream-like quality.
They're like oblivious to what's actually,
what actually is.
And instead they're like focused on the dialogue
of the 2 percent.
So as you go through the course of miracles
as a common experience,
or through 10, 12 steps, either one,
that you can reach a state
where everybody seems to be walking around
completely unconscious
in some kind of a dream state.
And the reality that surrounds them,
they seem to be oblivious, oblivious of.
It's sort of strange.
Everyone seems to be asleep.
Which tells you to walk around anonymously
because they don't see who you are
or what you're up to.
Which is just loving them,
which if they were aware of would scare them
and they might call 911.
Love frightens people, you know.
When you pull up to the next stop and go light,
look over at the driver at the next car
and smile and send him a love.
Mildred, is that man smiling at me?
I don't know.
He's either a lecher or a robber.
Just try it. It's just fun.
The next stop and go.
Whoever's in the other car, you look over and...
Absolute consternation.
Yeah, you're gonna be a carjacker or something.
Yeah.
So, now there's other questions
that we didn't get a chance to answer this morning.
Did everything we explained this morning
seem rather clear and obvious?
Right.
All right.
So, it's a great relief to realize
that you can experience your own death.
The time of death is set anyhow.
Ninety-eight percent of your mind that you're worried about,
the ego, already doesn't exist.
Ninety-eight percent of what you thought
you're gonna have to do is done.
You only got two percent left.
What great karmic good fortune
brings us all here to hear this lecture.
When I discovered it, I said,
oh, wow, remember?
Wow, everybody's 98% of the way already.
Well, that certainly isn't heartening.
So, there's only this lingering,
like these little clouds,
of the two percent
that we have to unhook now.
And as we see the mechanism,
you see, once you understand
the nature of a thing,
it begins to dissolve.
It begins to dissolve
as you become aware of its nature.
Because you're merely holding in place
a perception.
And as you examine what is the reality,
there's nothing holding that perception
there anymore.
And behind that perception
is an intentionality.
There is the payoff to the ego,
which we didn't recover this morning
because we recovered it before.
You say, if all these things
are what is blocking us from enlightenment
and a state of peace and harmony and love,
why would people persist in them?
Because all those positionalities
that we looked at
all have a payoff.
They all have a payoff
in the form of juice.
And to be the victim
is so juicy,
it's really hard to give it up.
To be right is so juicy,
it's hard to give it up.
Revenge is so juicy.
Oh, to turn the dagger
in the bastard's heart.
Who's deserved it all these lifetimes
and I finally got him.
You know what I mean?
You look at the Middle East,
the glee with which they kill each other.
Look at the faces on the television.
All the young men, man,
throwing rocks at each other.
They're in a state of emotional ecstasy.
Killing each other for God,
for Jesus, for Allah,
whoever you want to kill them for.
Whoever's popular in that culture.
I mean, just the payoff of that
is so enormous.
To ask somebody to relinquish it,
to relinquish it.
How can you get this,
now somebody,
to hand over his gun
and become nobody
when by killing you,
he's somebody.
You understand?
The payoff is so enormous.
And so we see that the core of the ego
in all of its stratifications
that we described this morning
is a profound egocentrism.
The egoistic core of the ego
is what underlies all the things
we described about.
And the ego,
because it does not live on love,
has to get juiced somewhere
and it gets its energy
by juicing negativity.
That's how it lives.
There are some organisms
that live only on dead bodies.
And so,
the ego then,
because it is cut off from
that which we might call
the love of divinity,
now, as though it lives in the dark,
must learn how to suck juices
out of that which is negative.
Its subsides,
its subsistence,
its source of ongoingness then,
is the juice it gets out of negativity.
Therefore, if you ask the ego
to let go of the juice,
you're asking it to die.
Try to get somebody to give up
being the victim.
Good luck.
There's no way out of it.
You watch people on television
every night.
They have made a career
for a lifetime
juicing being the victim.
And if you're not the victim,
you can make your child the victim.
You get strange psychiatric disorders.
Wunschhausen by proxy syndrome.
Yeah.
If you can't be the victim,
you become the quasi-victim
by having a child as a victim.
So you see the degree of pathology
to which the ego will resort
to ensure its own survival.
All right.
When you see the power
of the negativity of that,
the tenacity of it,
is the better word,
the tenacity with which the ego clings
to being right, righteousness,
seeing others sinful, wrong, and guilty,
punishing them.
Punishing them.
Why do we want to put somebody
to death for anything?
People get a glee that he deserves it
and they punish him.
The only trouble with that is
that which you think people out there deserve
is what your unconscious holds for you.
If they should die for it,
unconsciously then,
your own fear of death,
so you cannot get away with projections.
So the ego survives by the paranoid mechanism
of seeing evil and all these things out there.
What it thinks everybody out there,
the sentence that it puts on everybody out there,
is the sentence that you've put on yourself.
In psychoanalysis, the first rule is,
to soften up the superego,
that is the conscience,
before you start bringing stuff up
from the unconscious,
because the superego is quite vicious.
It wants to execute its enemies
and gloat over the execution.
Extract every bit of pleasure it can out of that.
Consequently,
the homicidal fantasies
which are plunged down into your id,
which come out of the animal evolution,
an animal doesn't want to,
you know,
prevail over the other,
he wants to kill it.
So the unconscious thinks in terms of killing enemies.
Alright, so,
the more we soften the conscience,
then, towards others,
we're actually softening it towards ourself.
The more we're willing to forgive others,
the more we're forgiving towards ourself.
In the end, they become one and the same thing.
And we become more and more benign.
So we ask ourself,
could I give up the pleasure
in watching this guy fry in the electric chair?
Lots of people like to put it on TV and watch it.
You know what I'm saying?
The macabre, the gruesome
of the ego is really immense.
Alright, so the willingness to give up
the payoff of negativity
is what releases it.
When you don't get pleasure
out of the suffering,
when you don't get pleasure out of being right,
when you see that everybody is doing the best they can.
So forgiveness comes out of the real,
the realistic understanding
that everything is only being what it can
at the time that it's being that.
So if the flower is only unfolded at this point,
should we punish the flower or not?
Cut it off at the stem?
Maybe we should beat it
because it's a bad flower.
You understand what I'm saying?
You begin to see the ridiculousness
of the ego's positions.
As you do that, you weaken its structure,
you start pulling the sticks out.
The ego gets weaker and weaker.
Everybody in a group like this
is farther ahead than what they think they are.
Why?
Because they focus on the areas
that they're not pleased with.
You know, you're focused on what you're working on.
So everybody has a view of themselves
as being worse than they actually are.
I haven't met anybody who's really awful.
No.
But there are sort of warped individuals
who need help, I'll say that.
A little on the warped side.
However, they can't help being warped.
What kind of genes?
What kind of karma?
Who knows why they are the way they are.
So you end up with a full understanding.
The reason,
we describe all this,
non-duality,
is to transcend the ego,
you have to understand it.
The more you understand the ego,
the more it begins to collapse.
And you find that compassion is a constant.
It already exists within you.
Just as devotion already exists within you.
There is already within you
a well and a reservoir
of intense and powerful devotion
that is far more powerful
than what you realize yet.
Because when the great obstacle arises,
much to your amazement,
there comes out of you an intensity,
an absoluteness
that is willing to walk through anything
to reach God.
It is like the gravity of God.
So the closer you get to God,
the more powerful becomes the gravity.
And at the last door,
where you have to surrender,
very life itself,
the gravity is so powerful.
There is a moment hesitation,
the words of wisdom that you recall
from some lifetime come to you,
and then the trip is over.
That which you need
is already waiting for you.
You don't have to have it here.
It's like mountain climbing.
That which you need up there
is already sitting up there waiting for you.
So you don't have to look at yourself and say,
I don't have within me
what it takes to make this whole trip.
You don't have it now,
but you don't need it
until you get up to this elevation,
and you don't need that
until you get up to this elevation.
So everything that you need
to go the whole way spiritually
is already provided for.
Fact. Fact.
So you don't have to look within yourself and say,
I don't have that much commitment,
I don't have that much drive,
I don't have that much certitude.
But as you get to the next block,
you'll suddenly have it,
and you turn the corner,
you go down the two blocks,
and now it gets more intense,
and so the gravity increases its power.
So nobody has to worry about their spiritual evolution.
It's already certain.
If spiritual evolution wasn't certain,
you wouldn't be here.
Nobody would be here
unless they were scheduled karmically to evolve.
Nobody else would be here.
The very fact that you're here
is a statement of intention and dedication.
And a good 505 is back for a number of years.
It's going to be another trip.
It's going to go around and answer the questions.
And you see how it answers questions?
It just is what it is,
and the joy of its being what it is
reveals to you the absolute truth
that you're looking for.
Its joy is coming out of its own existence,
and it shares its joy of existence with you.
Interestingly,
this one asks for nothing in return.
So this is like unconditional love.
It just is love
and asks for nothing,
doesn't ask you for a pet.
Very interesting dog
that God sent for the purpose of the lecture.
So as I said,
what you need to explain the thing
is waiting for you,
so that at the moment
when you need a dog to demonstrate
what you're talking about,
the dog appears.
You know?
If only for a dog,
then why not even more so for you?
Okay, so we realize that we are blessed
by our being with each other.
The other thing I wanted to mention,
and then we're going to go to questions
and do it sort of so everyone can hear it.
I'd gotten a couple of letters of consternation
when I said,
it's best to have somebody who knows you
realize that you're on
a seriously committed spiritual path.
That person got sort of frightened.
Family, friends,
somebody should realize that,
you know,
you're serious about spirituality.
And people who get serious about spirituality
are known to go into certain
and rather advanced spiritual states
which are not understood by everybody,
including psychiatrists.
It's best to have a spiritually,
some spiritually aware friends
who realize what you're doing.
As I say,
you sit there and begin to meditate,
you start surrendering everything as it arises,
one can go in a state of bliss.
That is in ecstasy beyond all description.
Nothing's going to get you to come out of it.
And at that point,
you need somebody to know,
is he blissed out or is he catatonic?
We need a psychiatrist or a guru, right?
And I think in the last book,
I described how you can tell the difference
with kinesiology.
Is he in a divine state?
Yes.
Is he catatonic?
No.
Or you may get it the other way.
Yeah.
I've had several people tell me
they were higher than Jesus Christ.
And in the kinesiology, they were wrong.
So I'll repeat that.
Nobody has ever existed
who's been higher than Jesus Christ
or Buddha or Krishna.
Anything that tells you
that it has been or is higher than any of them
is not coming from the right place.
Needs a psychiatrist, really.
Such things do occur.
And, you know,
explain certain rather peculiar phenomena,
why people are impressed by them.
You know,
I'm not going to justify such statements.
That it's a possibility.
No.
It is not a possibility.
So if you ever hear it said to you,
no,
you already know in your mind
that this is not a possibility.
And by the divination of spirits,
we would know that this is not of God.
Okay.
So those are the only things
I wanted to make sure I'd said.
And I thought,
now we just ask questions
and go do sort of a spiritual free-for-all.
And the way the,
the way this is set up,
we're setting up the sound system
so that everybody can hear this.
We'll do a little better
and different than this morning.
We have a different sound system today
and we finally have it readjusted.
So everybody will be able to hear the questions
and hear the answers.
And everyone,
I want everybody to feel free
to come up and ask anything.
And we'll see what shows up.
In a way,
we're moving more towards the end of the year
where we said,
it's going to be more and more like that.
More and more spontaneous questions dialogue
because it's actually what's on people's mind.
If you don't want to be in the photograph,
you don't have to be.
Cover your face with a napkin.
I don't want to be photographed with that dog.
By the way,
any photographs that are taken
are just personal for our scrapbook.
Nothing gets put out to the media.
And I just thought you'd like that reassurance
that you will not appear on the internet tomorrow.
Yes?
I have two questions.
In a previous lecture,
you had made a statement that about 23% or 24% of the time
we were unconscious.
And you had cautioned people who were into extreme sports.
Can you elaborate on that?
Extreme sports?
Oh, I'm trying to get people used to...
You see, getting out of the Newtonian paradigm,
you have to move through quantum mechanics
where you don't have certainty,
you have probability and likelihoods.
The likelihood is
if you make 32 high jumps with a five-gainer
that you're going to make it.
The likelihood, the certainty is not there.
The 33rd jump, you can break your neck.
So I gave an example right here in Sedona.
A couple of nice guys that ran an animal place up there
in the back of the Pizza Hut.
And they would...
When you called them,
they would come over and get the rattlesnakes.
And they were great.
I mean, people are scared of rattlesnakes
and a lot of this is becoming sort of suburban in a way.
So people just called them
and they would come over and get the rattlesnake, no charge.
And one of them got bit 19 times.
Rattlesnakes bit him 19 times.
And the 20th time, he just assumed he was immune and he died.
He was not.
In other words, I'm saying don't push your luck
based on the Newtonian paradigm of reality
because the Newtonian paradigm is not the total reality.
As we see from quantum mechanics and nonlinear dynamics,
what we're dealing with here is probability and likelihoods,
but not certainty.
I think we have that here.
Is it too late to put that up?
Where is the Newtonian paradigm?
Let's put that up
because I just wanted to see what I'm saying.
You see, once you begin to expand
beyond the Newtonian paradigm of reality,
this is the Newtonian paradigm of form.
It's decipherable by the differential calculus.
Sir Isaac Newton was the source of the differential calculus.
It calibrates in about 460,
which is the same level as the idea of causality.
This is a world of certainty,
linear certainty.
It's certain because of the limitation of its own self-definition.
As you begin to move to the next higher level of consciousness,
now you're dealing in quantum mechanics,
quantum reality.
You see, in the Newtonian,
this causes this and there's an absolute certainty about that.
That's only the macroscopic world.
In the microscopic world now,
of quantum mechanics,
E equals MC squared,
you start going from
the Schrodinger equations,
time independent and time dependent.
You're going through the Heisenberg principle.
You're ending up with the Dirac conclusion.
And through the von Neumann processes,
A or B, one or two,
what you have now is you don't have certainty
at the submicroscopic level.
You have probability.
So when we talk in spiritual language
about the influence of the field,
what you're talking about now
is not causality on a one-to-one linear basis,
but in the field.
Let's say if you have a drinking problem,
if you just go to AA and sit in the room,
the field begins to alter your thinking.
So this is a predictable world.
If this is the way the world is,
after 19 rattlesnake bites,
you'd be okay on the 20th.
That isn't the way the world is.
This is the way the world is.
Likelihood.
It's likely that 19 out of 20 times,
the 20th time you'll make it.
You see, in the quantum mechanics,
this linear certainty is beginning to loosen up
now a little bit.
This is 100 times out of 100 times.
This is 99.9% out of 100 times.
And now you begin to see disorderly, illogical,
unpredictable, free, creative.
We've got space for free will.
If this is Newtonian,
there would be no karmic merit in any decision
because this caused you to think this way,
that caused you to think this way,
and that's what caused you to make this conclusion.
No room for karmic merit.
No spiritual freedom.
There has to be room for the unpredictable,
the illogical, to be free, to be creative,
imaginative, progressive.
You see, this field is diffuse.
It's diffuse.
It's not causal.
It's not local.
This world is provable.
This world is comprehensible,
but not provable.
I get oddball letters all the time from people
that get lost.
They miss what the whole book's about,
and they start to argue with the
mathematical analogies that I make.
I think I made it quite explicit.
These are just analogous.
They're not literal.
And they start to argue about provability.
You can't actually prove anything
any time except something that you mentalize.
Nothing in reality can be proven.
What's called provable is a mentalization.
It's provable within a structured mentalization.
It is not provable within the world
because causality doesn't exist within the world,
so you couldn't prove it because it isn't there.
It's a conception.
So you can comprehend it,
but you cannot prove it.
It's observable.
Everything is simultaneous.
Past, present, and future are not sequential.
In the Newtonian paradigm,
that was yesterday, now is now,
and there's tomorrow.
In the microscopic world,
tomorrow has already happened,
and yesterday won't get here till tomorrow.
The reason everybody's here is because of their future.
They think they're propelled by their past.
People are attracted because their future
has already been decided.
If your future hadn't been decided to become enlightened,
there would be no reason for your body
to drag itself here.
Like an electromagnet,
you're being pulled by the future.
You're not being propelled by the past.
The past is over already,
so where would it get the power to propel you?
The past is already dead.
Because it's dead,
how would it be activating you in the present?
Obviously, it's not.
We said time-dependent and time-independent.
That's the two Schrodinger equations.
Stochastic meaning unpredictable.
It's unlimited.
You see, it's altered by observation.
That's the Heisenberg principle.
As we explained before,
Einstein calibrates at 499.
This is where he bucked.
He bucked right here because he said,
after the Copenhagen Convention,
he said,
I prefer to think that there is an independent,
objective universe independent of human consciousness.
Because the Heisenberg principle
forces you to a metaphysical,
philosophic shift,
the whole basis of science,
and it requires a shift of paradigm.
At calibration level 500,
you move from the literal,
provable Newtonian paradigm
into the non-provable subjectivity
of spiritual reality.
And Einstein just refused to go there.
He refused to go there.
At the same time, he was quite religious.
Quite religious, and yet,
not yet ready to make a paradigm jump.
That there is a reality
that is not objective, etc.,
but subjective.
So, this then becomes unlimited.
You see possibilities.
So, the fact that
it's altered by observation,
the only thing that intervenes,
intervenes in the two,
between the Schroeder and the Dirac equation,
is the Heisenberg principle of observation.
Once you've really looked at it,
once human consciousness has touched it,
it's already changed.
It's already changed.
You've collapsed the wave function.
And because you've collapsed the wave function,
you have altered
the collective consciousness of all of mankind.
Every time everybody here says yes
to something that's integrous
and no to something that's not integrous,
you've made it more and more difficult
for the non-integrous
to continue the way it is.
So, the field, as it moves from 190
back in 1980,
suddenly shifted to 207.
The total field of human consciousness
will not tolerate now
things that it tolerated when I grew up.
When I grew up,
if you didn't get their money,
somebody else will.
That's what they told me.
Get their money,
you don't get them,
somebody else will.
I said, this is not integrous.
You know, this old farmer's
never going to get his money back
out of the peanut vending machine.
He says, if you don't get their money,
somebody else will.
That went back in the 50s
or whenever that time was.
It wouldn't go now.
It wouldn't go now
because after Enron and all that
and Martha Stewart and all,
people now see that integrity
is what you're going to be nailed up there for,
friends, not profit, integrity.
I mean, they made plenty of profit.
They should have been
a Fifth Avenue ticker-tape parade for them,
these guys that made billions
for all the investors.
Instead, their heads rolled.
So, the world has shifted.
So, every time we are integrous,
we increase the likelihood that integrity,
the likelihood that integrity
is going to be continued.
So, you can see you're dealing with uncertainty
and, of course, the difference is
you're dealing with power.
Here, you're dealing with force.
Here, you're dealing with content.
Here, you're dealing with context.
So, this is the context,
the field out of which the power is coming,
and this is the content or form.
Therefore,
all spiritually evolved people
or spiritually committed people
by the sheer commitment
is they are already in the process
of changing the world.
People say,
what can I do to change the world?
I tell them, stay out of trouble.
Say your prayers, stay out of trouble.
You're doing a lot for the world.
Seventy-eight percent of the world
is doing otherwise,
not doing what they can for each other
or for the world, you know.
And I try to teach the girls
that the girls aren't, you know.
Just one little smile
will change somebody else's whole day.
And, you know,
if you want to be surrounded by love,
that's all you have to do
is acknowledge people
as you walk through the day.
You know, you say thank you,
and the telephone operator,
I said, boy, you really took that order.
That was terrific.
You can just hear them light up.
They just light up.
So, they're sort of like the dog, you know.
When you give it a pat,
everybody just blossoms.
It's so simple.
And that's why New York
is a wonderful and friendly place.
Because as you smile,
literally walking down the street,
they just go,
that little flower just blossoms,
and you become part of the conditions
which allow them to blossom.
Okay, so that sort of cuts.
Of course, you asked that.
Aren't you sorry?
So, we'll shut this off.
She said she's sorry she asked.
That's it.
Next question.
As a participant in the health field,
and being in a very evidence-based period,
am I adding negatively
to the collective unconscious effect
on disease process?
On what?
Maybe I'm making wrong assumptions,
but my understanding
of the collective unconscious
on disease processes
is that our diseases,
a lot of it,
are the result of the collective unconscious.
Well, certainly,
the kind of disease that we're dealing with
is not the disease that we're dealing with.
It's the disease that we're dealing with.
It's certainly the kind of disease that we see.
Of course, the miracle says,
you're subject to what you hold in mind.
Well, if you think smoking's gonna kill you,
I advise you not to smoke.
You have stopped smoking, haven't you?
Oh, definitely.
Oh, thank you.
I haven't started.
Okay, we'll go on to the next person.
Go ahead,
because you had a couple questions.
We've got to get another.
People ask that question, you know?
You're subject to what you hold in mind.
I think you may have already answered this,
but...
When it's time to leave, you leave,
and many people with pure lungs
leave this planet every day.
If bad lungs don't get you out,
karma will find another way,
a CVA or a stroke or, you know.
Once the moment arrives,
you will not be here afterwards.
I think you may have already answered this,
but if in amongst all those ego messages
there is this sensation
of wanting to transcend that,
that can't be coming,
that message of wanting to transcend the ego
can't be coming from the ego,
is that coming from...
Spirit, yeah.
Okay.
So, like a field of gravity,
this field is like attracting,
pulling us towards it.
And meantime, the ego is struggling
to prevent that from happening.
Okay.
Because as you transcend it,
that's the death of the ego,
that's the end.
Right.
And it loses its grip on mankind.
So, as you try to move up,
it tries to counter it, you know,
tries to counter it.
I'll get back.
The more you understand it,
the weaker it becomes.
Okay.
See, it's not operating in the dark.
And light and dark are not opposites.
But you see,
as you hold the light on something,
the darkness disappears.
Right.
Because darkness is not the opposite of light,
it merely is its absence.
So, the calibrated scale of consciousness then,
the degree to which divinity and love predominate
is why the calibrations are high.
The more it tends...
The more the light goes down,
the more towards darkness,
that's the lower end of the scale.
But they're not opposites.
The top is not the opposite of the bottom of the scale.
So, it's just a gradation.
So, every conscious decision we make then
moves us up and down in the water,
like little quarks, you know.
I always figured like little quarks
with little things like this.
And when we go this way,
the quark goes up.
the quark goes down.
You know what I mean?
And then...
But what's making those choices?
Is it the field making those choices,
this desire to transcend,
or is it the ego making the choices?
The spirit.
The spirit's making the choices.
Okay.
Can I ask you a health-related question, too?
If the goal is to completely surrender,
as you were talking about
when you were going through
the 12 steps,
then aren't efforts of searching around,
looking for healing kind of things
sort of resisting that?
Resisting having completely surrendered,
if it is in my karma
to have a particular physical condition?
Well, it's sort of an ambiguous question
because the intention to get well
would lead you to seek out the means to do so,
which would be the natural thing to go.
The capacity to completely,
totally surrender
and allow it to be however it is
would be a different level of consciousness.
And a higher level of consciousness,
whether it persists or does not persist,
is irrelevant.
So that's a choice?
That would be a choice,
but you see,
at this level is yes,
at this level is no,
at this level is yes.
So you have to know in what context,
what calibrated level of consciousness
you're arriving at this decision.
Because at one level,
it doesn't make any difference
whether you live or you die.
See?
Right.
But that's how it seems from that level.
Okay.
But it makes a difference to whom,
whether you live or die,
et cetera.
So one constantly chooses life
in whatever form it may express itself,
including the non-physical.
So you say,
it was time to leave the body, goodbye.
And one function I used to have in the nursing home
is I would say to some old lady
with all these tubes stuck in her,
and she'd be going up and down the wheelchair,
saying,
help,
help.
And they're putting more tubes in her
and more things,
and she must need more narcotics.
And I said,
what do you want help with?
She said,
let me go,
let me go.
Nobody lets her die.
It's against Medicare rules.
Do you know it's against Medicare rules
to let anybody die?
Yes.
Okay.
It's against Medicare rules.
It's illegal to let anybody die.
The most natural thing in the world,
to get born,
to die,
the two things that are inevitable,
is against the Medicare rules.
What she means by help is let me out of here.
They won't let me die.
What is the natural end of life?
The natural end of life
is you reach a certain feeling of inevitability.
And at that point,
you have no interest in eating anymore.
The natural way to leave the planet
is to realize that and to stop eating.
That's nature's way.
When the animal gets sick enough,
it goes off,
it wants solitude,
it wants to stop eating,
and be left alone in peace
to slowly let itself out of there.
And this poor old lady is pleading for that.
Please put me somewhere in the corner
and leave me alone
and stop trying to hydrate me,
tube feed me,
et cetera,
and let nature take its course.
The natural way to leave is to stop eating.
You see?
If anybody says they want to die and commit suicide,
and I say,
how was lunch?
It was very good.
They're right here.
I've been working on,
thank you,
on spiritual realization for the last three years,
and I have gotten to the point
that I understand that there is no causal,
that it isn't my past.
I don't blame anyone or anything that happened,
and I do see the unfolding and the blossoming.
When I start thinking about the past,
sometimes I don't think about it,
and when I do,
I have to kind of think
because I've really firmly put it behind me.
But in your last book,
you said that it can be an advantage
to have past life regression
in order to find out what the karmic residual is
that is causing the things to happen in your life
so that you better understand.
If you're up against a block,
a block,
and you can't seem to overcome it,
and you try prayer,
you try everything,
you know,
it's usually something specific.
And, yeah, past life recall,
past life regression can sometimes,
well, sometimes take it right there.
And there's very simple techniques,
just self-hypnosis.
You get off at floor 18,
and all of a sudden,
all of a sudden the movie starts,
and only it's you in the movie.
And it's quite obvious now
what the whole story is about,
and what you suspected is not only so,
but it's very, very so.
And each of those lifetimes,
if you do past life regression,
as you come to in that lifetime,
it's always you that's there.
So you had experience.
It's always the same me each time.
There he is, a blacksmith.
In that lifetime,
he's got huge muscles like that,
and he's got an apron,
and he's a very powerful guy,
a very strong guy.
So each lifetime that one recalls.
So there's only certain critical ones
that are of any, you know,
karmic consequence
that tend to come in people's minds.
But it sometimes solves self-possession,
self-pity.
Why me?
Why this pattern?
And the usual answer is
because it's exactly, you know,
you're playing the other role now.
And many a person says, you know,
I must have been an SOB in another lifetime.
Well, I'll tell you, that's a fact.
You were an SOB in other lifetimes.
The other thing I would like to say
is about the 12 steps I did.
I was an alcoholic,
and I did use the 12 steps.
And a lot of the things that,
and I did stop drinking.
I'm very thankful to it.
But it was very much giving over
the idea that I had no power over it.
So I basically answered my own question
that what you were going through
is that all I have to do now
is surrender the rest of the blocks to,
I need to continue that.
I think I stopped 15 years ago
when I stopped drinking.
I stopped to continually take that inventory.
And I think now that if I just more surrender myself
to the idea,
I wouldn't have to go through the past life regression.
Yeah, because, you know,
a lot of people, let's say,
if they have,
if they belong to something like AA,
where the sobriety indicates sort of an endpoint,
then they may just maintain the program.
But Bill Wilson, you know,
said that the AAs don't really realize
that the 12 steps,
that sobriety is just the,
jacks for openers.
That's jacks for openers.
You do the steps, you get sober.
And most people think,
well, I'm done now.
He says, no,
that's what leads to the great discoveries
and the great spiritual growth and experiences.
So he used to think that was maybe an error
that they should not have indicated
that sobriety itself,
although I think for practical reasons,
that's good enough for this lifetime.
I'm doing one excellent job today.
It's okay to do a wrestling point
for a lifetime or two
and then start up your momentum again.
Kind of a follow-up to that is,
could you expand a little more
on a technique for accessing previous lives?
I don't do past life regression.
However, it's a very simple thing.
I can tell you how to do it.
You just do self-hypnosis.
You know how to do that.
No.
All right.
So you got to go learn self-hypnosis.
And you have to ask,
what is your motivation?
Is it worth?
Well, it may be.
And first of all,
to realize that one is at a certain point
in a continuum of an endless series,
an endless life, actually.
It's just one life.
And then there's these various chapters and episodes.
Each one you dip into the physicality
as a very definite karmic purpose.
You see it quite clearly.
And then the next lesson comes around.
So there's a certain benefit to it.
There's people who have written books on it.
They're accessible.
I forget the names of them.
It's primarily self-hypnosis
and then your intention, intentionality.
You hold in mind a certain intentionality
and you walk down the dark steps.
And you take the elevator
and you find your answer on level eight.
You get off the elevator
and then the whole lifetime begins,
experientially.
It's not like you're watching a movie
where that's happening there.
You are the movie
and everything moves around you as it did.
And you're, I mean, the self is there.
It's very much like out-of-body experience
in which you go out of body.
It's very much you that's out of the body.
The physicality is there,
but the you is here.
And in fact, there's techniques
using out-of-body experience
for karmic research.
Because you go in realms
where there is no past, present, or future
and you merely go back and visit.
So there's...
Who wrote Journeys Out of the Body?
Monroe, yeah.
Monroe Institute.
Various places like that.
So with a little inquiry,
you can find places that specialize
in past life recall
and various techniques,
hypnosis, out-of-body experience.
Okay, thanks.
My 2% is very active.
And...
And I keep getting to this point
where I think,
why isn't this just maybe
the ultimate ego trick, all this,
and that we're all experiencing
the same ultimate ego trick?
Well, that is a psychiatric problem.
I can go sit on that.
And the answer comes to you
just out of nowhere.
So you're looking somewhat,
I feel like you're pressing the linear.
You're trying to press logic, you know.
And that's not going to work
in the spiritual domain.
It's more your intention to know,
your prayer and dedication, etc.,
will finesse.
So you see in the world,
the Newtonian paradigm,
you cause things to happen.
In the spiritual paradigm,
it's more like you finesse them.
Through prayer and meditation,
you increase the likelihood
that when you get your gas
at the next station,
the guy giving you the change says,
and by the way, so-and-so,
and that's just what you're asking for.
So you have to be open
to hear the answer to the question.
And they'll come through, you know,
and just sit next to somebody on a bus,
and he looks from this paper,
and he says, yackety-yack,
and man, that's just what you're looking for.
So you give the universe a chance
to respond to your question.
And don't look for a linear cause and effect.
Because once you pose the question out there,
the answer will come back to you.
Yeah, somebody will just walk up to you
and say, yackety-yack,
and you say, whoa, hey, that's it.
My question is about prayer.
So when people say they're praying for me,
should I worry about that?
That's a good sign.
So really, what is prayer,
or how would we best pray?
Yes, prayer, yes.
You see, through devotion and dedication,
one's commitment to God becomes quite intense.
And you see, in the 12 steps,
it addresses prayer directly.
Sought through prayer and meditation
to increase our conscious contact with God.
So you're like permitting,
you're taking,
you see, the ego is very much yang,
papo,
and the spirit is very much yin,
allowing.
So it's hard for those who live in a world
of the harder you push,
the harder you try,
the greater you bring home the bacon, you know?
So spiritual work is more like yin,
in which you get out of the way of it
and you float back with it,
and the answer comes to you.
It comes to you out of nowhere.
And the answer came out of nowhere
the other day driving along.
I thought, what's the best way
to present a certain piece of material?
And then it was just obvious.
Not question and answer, you know?
I posed the question at breakfast
and at noon I'm driving along
and the answer just revealed itself.
So you learn how to finesse using yin.
So the power of yin is equal to the power of yang.
It doesn't get the publicity.
Nuclear submarines get the publicity.
No, it's the power of yin that summons forth
that which is needed for survival, see?
So that's the power of prayer,
is that it summons to itself,
summons, attracts to itself.
Is there any such thing
as praying for another person?
Of course.
People pray for each other all the time.
Dear God, please let them see the right way to go.
We all, we pray that God's will be done, you know?
That God's will be done.
We ask for what is God's intention.
You see, because if a person is going through a karmic lesson
and you want to interfere with the karmic lesson,
you know, you're destroying the person's spiritual integrity.
You know what I'm saying?
So if people get sober because you have them arrested and jailed
and put in prison and then into a forced program,
there's really no karmic benefit.
He hasn't said yes to that.
No.
It did not come of his own volition through his own surrender.
So that sobriety will last till he gets out of jail, you know,
and on the way home it'll disappear because it's forced.
So there's no karmic merit.
So the first step in the Al-Anon program, for instance,
is in a way saying,
don't try to rob others of karmic merit
by acting, you know, in what you think is their best interest
using force and coercion.
That's what it's saying.
Allow people to derive the karmic benefit
that comes only from saying,
I surrender to God.
I ask God for help.
Yeah, I ask God for help.
That's a totally different thing.
Thank you.
Yeah.
And some people that are forced to, let's say,
discontinue certain behaviors may also shift later on
and now do it by agreement and understanding.
So maybe they're forced to go there by the court,
and then much to their surprise,
they become enthusiastic about it, you know?
I have a question that I'm having a little bit of problems wording it,
but I think you'll pick up real quick.
Throughout the history of mankind or humankind,
we have avatars and the great enlightened ones,
Krishna, Buddha, Jesus, as you've mentioned.
I would assume that there have been females
that have reached these levels.
Yes, the answer is no.
The question is politicizing it, you understand?
No, the reason I was asking, no, my thinking is,
was that perhaps there were,
but because of the nature of the civilization,
they weren't recognized.
I haven't been able to detect it,
but the minute I am, I will announce it.
The other question was,
going through the dark night of the soul,
which you relate to about the agony,
the emotional and mental agony,
how does one discern that between an ego conniption fit?
Well, the ego can take you places.
One is transformative and the other is not.
The dark night of the soul takes you to,
the resolution to it is a spiritual experience,
without which that likely would not have happened.
Then you've answered my question, thank you.
The question about men and women,
as far as being God,
the question, because we've asked it,
it has to do with the strength of the nervous system,
that to go over 600, to go over 700 especially,
is extremely difficult for the human nervous system.
And what we got is,
the only reason that men go the whole way,
statistically more than women,
is because the nervous system
is sufficiently strong to handle.
That's all I got.
Although I bet you're going through childbirth,
I can't imagine that women don't have an equal...
I was so glad I wasn't born a woman, I'll tell you.
They go through and survive a lot.
So I think we can ask it again,
because it has nothing to do with gender.
It has to do with nervous system.
The answer I give is permitted.
The answer I give is correct.
It's only because of the nervous system.
For the same reason,
moving rocks is usually given to men to do,
rather than women, you know?
Yeah.
Because you...
Am I...
Yeah, I'm live.
You talk, and we all are aware of Mother Teresa
and the tremendous ability that she had to do what she did.
And I just thought, perhaps,
maybe there's some other females in history
that I'm not aware of.
There's a great many Christian saints.
And, you know, Saint Teresa of Avila,
many...
Many Christian saints that were women.
And, you know, in our lifetime,
Mother Teresa calibrates over 700.
I mean, that's about as good as you can get on this planet.
Rarely, rarely ever does calibration ever go over 700.
And if it does, you don't...
You see, as each level is reached,
you don't hear from them.
At 600, you won't hear from...
50% of them are going to leave,
because you don't have to breathe,
you don't have to do anything.
And you realize that...
Your reality...
So what's the point of, you know,
to please your relatives breathing this body again?
So 50% of the time, they don't do it.
And then as you get higher to the 700s or 800s,
hardly any of them come back in the world.
And when you get beyond that,
it's once in a number of centuries
that anybody will persist.
I got my answer.
Women are smart enough they don't come back
as often as men do.
They got the brains to leave.
I don't disagree with you.
They're too smart.
Who needs this?
Bye.
Go ahead.
I think I have the answers to these questions,
but I also think I might be intellectualizing,
so that's why I want to present this to you.
I, too, am an ex-drunk,
and I work the steps,
and amazing things happen as a result.
And I listened to your tape
on alcoholism and consciousness,
and if I understood you correctly,
your theory behind that was
for those of us that are alcoholic,
the reason why we drink
is because we're actually addicted
to the God experience that we get through alcohol,
because alcohol or the drug
kind of pushes the ego out of the way
that's blocking it.
You sedate the ego.
So you get to feel the euphoria,
and the euphoria is really the...
the self with a capital S
that you're sensing now,
because the block to it has been sedated.
So what you're addicted to,
you're not addicted to the drug,
you're addicted to
that wonderful state of consciousness.
What you've experienced
that you're never satisfied with any less.
So is it that those of us that become alcoholic,
do we perceive that
state of drunkenness differently
than those that don't?
Because I would think if everybody got that after a few drinks,
or is that a karmic thing?
Everybody is a drunk,
they just haven't drunk enough yet.
You have another lifetime
or two out at sea,
and by golly,
we used to hang out in the dives in the front,
and by golly, we had friendship,
and we hugged each other,
and we got boffed to the gills,
and we had fraternal love, you see,
and camaraderie, we didn't feel lonely,
we didn't feel fear,
we felt fantastic.
Now why wouldn't anybody in their right mind
want to repeat that?
I don't know, I never could figure it out.
So ultimately,
does that have to do with just the karma
and where your soul is in its evolution
in that particular lifetime?
I think it has to do with a number of factors,
physiologic and karmic,
and many of the people that,
if you ask with kinesiology,
how many lifetimes have they died of alcohol
before they finally got sober,
and finally the sixth time around they got it.
So you see a lot of people
that have been in places like that,
in recovery groups,
and one of the fastest ways to God
is to hit bottom.
If you want to get to God fast,
give a guy a couple cases of whiskey
and leave him alone.
I'll do anything,
I'll do anything.
Help, I'll do anything.
That's what we used to tell him.
He said, what can I do to my husband?
I said, send him another case of whiskey
and he'll sit back and wait.
He'll be happy to go to the recovery home.
The other question I had,
and I may have misunderstood this,
but I was under the impression that
people who have near-death experiences
have a choice as to whether or not
they want to come back.
Is that true in that moment?
Yeah.
And if that's true,
then was that their time of death
and the rest of the time after that
is like bonus time?
It's punishment for not having left.
Yes.
Well, things are not all that cut and dried.
Again, we want to differentiate
between near-death and out-of-body,
that they are completely different.
I think everybody in our classes
are quite clear about that.
Out-of-body, there isn't such a thing.
Near-death is transformative.
And out-of-body, you calibrate the same
after as before,
which always seems surprising.
Because now that you realize you're a spirit,
it seems to me your consciousness
is a little bit of a jump, but it doesn't.
Near-death is quite something different.
Near-death
is not exactly the same.
Well, it's similar
to illumination,
but that's a near-death
kind of illumination.
There's an illumination that comes on spontaneously.
Well,
that would be level 600.
One is more
the witness to the phenomena
of whether or not this spirit
is going to re-enter this body or not.
Although love,
can be the determining factor.
And several times,
experientially, it was love
that decided
to breathe it again,
two or three times, in fact.
It was love for somebody
who would view it as a big loss
because they believe in death and all that.
And they would think you died.
So for their sake, you breathe.
So the time of death that was determined
when the soul came into the body
is the time when that choice is made
as to whether or not they're going to come back?
This is too detailed
a question. Whether in the near-death
experience you are represented
with an opportunity to reprogram
the date of death
could be so, but I'd have to research
whether that's a fact.
It's almost like you're given a chance
to shift the
time date or not.
Well, when it comes on,
in fact it came on as I walked down the aisle here
one time, there was
the permission to leave that was very strong.
It was like a powerful
magnet pulling it to
exquisite realms.
And in that experience you have
the knowingness of complete and total
permission. You have permission,
absolute permission to leave.
Almost an invitation to leave.
And one doesn't know
what is going to happen out of it.
If the body walked to the end and managed to
come back around the room, I guess that was the way
it was going to go. And if it fell down,
it was going to fall down.
And I'd say, would I keep on walking or not?
Well, keep on walking, and if you're dying
then the body falls down, that's all.
So, it didn't fall down,
so I presume that was not the time to leave.
Thank you.
Next time, I don't know though.
Hi. A number of years ago
I went to the front door of the home
where I lived, and I tried to take a
left into my room.
And all at once, right here on the right side
of my head, I heard a yellow note
in the kitchen. And I tried to ignore it,
and turn left into my room.
You heard what? A yellow note
in the kitchen. It was right
here, I could hear it. A yellow note?
In the kitchen. What's a yellow note?
What's a yellow note?
It was just, I just heard the words
right here. I got into, I went through the front
door of my home, I tried to turn left
into my room. And all at
once, I heard the words,
a yellow note in
the kitchen. And I heard it
from right here. So, I kept
ignoring it, and three to four times,
I tried to turn left,
and it was almost as if I couldn't turn
left into my room, I kept hearing
the same thing. So,
I decided, I stood there alone and out loud,
I said, oh, alright, alright.
And I decided to
just walk into the kitchen to see what was
going on. So, I did,
and I turned on the light, and on my
fruit bowl, there was a little yellow note
from my roommate, Jim.
It said, Crystal, your pineapple is ripe.
There was a yellow note
in the kitchen. And then,
last May, I awakened
one morning, and I wondered
what time it was. And I
heard, instead of on the right, I heard right
in the middle of my head,
I heard, it's ten o'clock, in a
very clear voice. And I
thought to myself, oh no, it has to be eight or
nine. So, finally,
I put my head up, and I
looked down across the room, and I looked
at the clock, it was ten o'clock.
What's the question? The question
is, where are these
things coming from? Why was I no
notified that there was a yellow note in the kitchen?
And why was I told it was ten o'clock
when I couldn't visibly see it with my eyes?
Oh, well, that's just your spirit.
You know, it's like out-of-body experience. Your
spirit can go all over the place and go back in the
body and report what's going on out there.
Okay. Let me have one more question.
Okay. I used to go into a box.
You know, you go to the Monroe Institute.
My spirit box. Anyway,
one of the things they teach you is how
to, you know, astral projection
and projection of consciousness.
So I remember the training itself,
and the ten-hour toilet was set around.
And you were supposed to project
your spirit into the box, read what's there,
and come back in, come back out again.
So you go into the box, and it said,
hello. And I came back, and I said, hello.
And I said, yep, that's it.
So you can train
yourself to do it at will.
My other question is, a number
of years ago, I was with a friend in
the living room in my apartment, and
almost at the same time, we both
perceived a screen of energy that was
right between us.
And then a number of years after that,
I was sitting in someone else's living room
talking to this person, and all at
once, it's as if, I guess, from the
third eye, all at once I perceived
a being up in the corner of the
room, and
that same screen of energy, which I had
forgotten about, was going across the room
behind the person I was talking to.
Now, I've been told that you should
not be in contact with these
beings, and I've been told that
you should. So I don't know
if that's right, or even why it
happened to me. I don't know anyone else
who has perceived that.
Do you think these are spirits?
Well, I could see it. It was very different.
It was a different perception that opened up,
as if you couldn't hear before, and then
all at once it was shocking, because it
just opened up, and then you didn't have it.
It was like clairvoyance, you mean?
It could have been. It was like an
altered state of consciousness.
It wasn't through my eyes, but it was
through here. It was in the corner, and
the image was about this big, and it was waving its arms.
It was pointing to astral domains,
and various
entities that you meet there.
You can learn to do it at will.
My explanation is
correct. You're pointing to various
astral domains, and you can
train yourself to do that.
I'm telling you about the Menorah Institute. You can become
an expert at this, and travel all around
the world, and
join the circus.
I knew I was going to get it for that one.
No, it's because
I'd say the aura can be trained
to leave at will,
and also to investigate
other domains.
When I was at Monroe,
I liked Bob Monroe. He had the most quiet,
beautiful voice.
You felt like you were in the presence of Jesus
or something when he spoke. It was like a calmness.
He didn't want you
getting into too many games out in the astral
domains, so he
trained you. You put on earphones,
and they
get picked up by the energy of the
cross speed. Let's say you got
a frequency at a certain
level in this ear, and a frequency level
in this ear. He was an engineer,
a sound engineer.
What you're picking up is
the energy field of the dissonance.
You can train yourself to go
into consciousness state 10, 12,
14, 15.
I think they went 10 to 15.
You go into an altered state of consciousness.
In an altered state of consciousness,
you can leave the
body and explore various realms.
He had a whistle.
When you hear this whistle,
you had to come back in the body and come home again.
People get involved
in all kinds of adventures out in the astral
domains, all kinds of entities and
energies. They've got weird programs.
There's all kinds of places.
With training, you can get two or three of you
and you can astral project together
and decide where you're going to meet, what domain
and what dimension and what point.
He had this whistle. Of course, we got
earphones on. You're out of body
having various adventures and all of a sudden
you hear this beep, beep, beep.
That means you've got to come back in the body. Bang!
You go back in the body.
I'm just telling you it can be
trained.
It can be used
for certain things.
One of the things it can be used for is
past life recall. You can actually
project yourself into that dimension,
relive the exact experience.
It can be useful.
Some people leave only
when they want and others will go out
spontaneously.
Some people have a hard time staying in their body.
They have the will
to be there because they tend to drift off.
Sitting in the dentist's
office, they go off.
There are other dimensions and other time frames
and the dentist is waiting for them.
That's very interesting.
You're discovering what's possible
within the human psyche.
That's sort of an advancement
because you start getting more evolved
as you start becoming aware of those things.
Astro projecting dreams.
Spiritual experiences
bring...
There's also a level
of spiritual evolution
which was quite interesting
to go through
in which the so-called paranormal
what classically call
the cities, S-I-D-D-H-I-S
certainly call them powers.
It's not actually powers
but you become clairvoyant.
You have a clairaudient.
There's something
where you hold something
and you know everything about who the person is
and I'll forget the term for it.
Psychometry.
Which came on spontaneously
and somebody left
a scarf in my office
and I picked up the scarf
and instantly it was like a loud knowingness
of whose it was.
I said, this is Estelle's.
I said, look what I found.
She said, give me my scarf.
So it came on spontaneously.
But there's a long period of time
where you have your clairaudient,
clairvoyant.
You have distant vision.
You can drive
in a state you've never been before
without a map
and instantly know how to get past
all those lakes and all those complicated highways.
All you have to do is picture where you're going
and you automatically go there.
And there's all kinds of different things.
The thing is not to get glamorized by them
or caught by them
and not to get fixated in them.
And not to have the ego
think who it is because of it.
Because it's not you that's doing it.
It's the aura,
this energy, the auric field
is doing that.
So you're the witness of it.
So you witness the very miraculous things
happening all the time.
And also it had the power to heal things.
People would sit down next to you
and barely able
to stand it
and after five minutes they'd get up
and walk away perfectly fine.
Left their cane there, everything.
So that energy field is transformative.
But it's temporary,
at least in myself.
It was very strong for at least five years.
It could also affect
electrical circuits
and electrical phenomena.
Electronic equipment, essentially.
You could turn strobe lights on and off
on various things.
Amplifiers, you know.
A hundred watt amplifier,
a Macintosh amplifier went out.
The guy came to fix it
and as he walks toward it
I saw the amplifier is perfect,
there's nothing wrong with it.
In my mind I'm thinking,
it's perfect, there's nothing wrong with it.
Instantly the hundred watt amplifier went on.
The guy says, holy smokes.
He said, how did you do that?
So I started talking to him about
the Course in Miracles.
I said, I don't know, I was doing the Course in Miracles and all of a sudden this kind of stuff happened.
So I had exactly one copy left.
I had bought 50 of them
and given them away to everybody.
I had exactly one copy left.
So this guy came to fix the amplifier,
witnessed what he thought was the miraculous,
says I want the Course in Miracles,
got the one book, walked out, said thank you.
And that's obviously the karmic reason
why he came that day.