Is this thing on?
Questions about, we had some questions
about the spiritual warrior.
As we evolve up through the various archetypes,
you see Jung talked about the archetypes.
In the beginning, we're the child.
The spiritual world is wondrous.
We go to the New Age festival
and we're just blown away with it all.
Then we get more serious, we get more aligned,
we get more power, we give up the adolescent,
and we become dedicated to something.
Out of dedication arises the spiritual warrior.
The spiritual warrior, as it expresses itself
in these classes, is extreme dedication
to the truth no matter what,
the willingness to die for the truth,
to give up all positionalities.
It's called devotional non-duality.
All right, so in the beginning,
the spiritual warrior starts from his solar plexus.
He knows what's right and he's willing to kill the infidel.
He can kill the infidel.
And many of the jihad people are in their spiritual warrior,
energized by their spleen, unfortunately.
To kill the enemy out of hatred
is a totally different karmic consequence
than doing it out of one's dedication to principle.
So the more evolved spiritual warrior
is the archetype within you,
which becomes dedicated to the truth.
You're a warrior to truth.
Jesus Christ was a warrior for truth.
He said, I brought a sword.
I did not bring you peace on earth,
but peace in heaven.
Is that correct?
I did not bring you peace on earth.
Idiots.
They deleted idiots.
But I got the original and it said idiots.
To have any impact on mankind, you gotta be real.
You gotta know where mankind is living.
Speak to where we all live, you know?
We all live where it's real, you know?
We talk from the intellect and spot all this fancy stuff,
but where we live is the real.
And on a certain level, everybody knows the real.
We discovered, for instance, which,
well, that's this afternoon.
I don't want to shock you with that one this morning.
Oh, God.
No, we don't want to shock you with that one, no.
All right, then the warrior,
he comes up out of the solar plexus
and stops being confrontational,
and he moves into his heart.
So you have the,
the warrior who also has a heart.
That pretty much represents the U.S. position right now.
Although it's a very ferocious and fearsome
and very powerful warrior, it also has a heart.
Right behind the guns is the food for the populace.
You know what I mean?
Who ever heard of a warrior doing that?
Dragging a wagon load of grub for the,
for the evil ones out there, you know?
No, so America has more evolved.
It has a heart about the whole thing,
and then he begins to speak of the truth,
and then the warrior moves from warrior to a higher level,
because the archetype of the warrior
is not the highest of evolution.
But that is the phase of the warrior.
Now, the warrior can also be,
the downside of the warrior is the denouncer
and the polarizer, you see?
I said, once you speak for the truth,
that's different than demeaning.
Those who disagree with you.
So to vilify the president because you disagree with him
is not integrous.
To say you disagree with him, that is integrous.
But to vilify him is a fault.
So I don't vilify Bin Laden.
I don't vilify Saddam Hussein.
These are people that are run by energies
of which they have no awareness whatsoever.
They have no awareness of what is running them.
Therefore, intrinsically, everyone is innocent.
What enables you to face the truth, you know, is, you know,
the downside of things is the devotion to the truth
because the fastest way to God is through truth,
the fast way.
One has to be devoted, so devotion brings in the heart.
So the Zen-like exactitude
is because of the devotion to God and truth.
Understand what I'm saying?
It can look ferocious.
It is ferocious.
There's an enormous compassion then.
Out of compassion, one can see the downside,
the mistaken side of the kamikaze pilot or the shoe bomber.
The shoe bomber, God bless him.
Like the idiot child, you know.
He's doing his bit for the cause,
getting on a plane with his shoes loaded with bombs.
Oh, God bless it.
Oh.
All right.
The reason that you have to take surgical action quickly,
you know, talking as a pragmatist,
after all, I'm a physician,
and I see things as a physician sees things,
is that the dangers to the world have become more,
the dangers to the world are more than they ever were
because of amplification.
Because of amplification, a mad dog who used to be a weirdo
that lived out in a trailer camp someplace and he looked weird,
and when he came to town, everybody thought he was a weirdo.
Nowadays, he has access to enormously powerful weapons,
not just a little harmless weirdo anymore.
The deviant politics that comes through
through philosophical distortion used to be some guy ranting
and raving in the bar and you all figured he's a local nut.
No, now he's on international television and he's talking
to six million people at a time.
Therefore, it is now far more important to detect,
falsehood early in the game, early in the game.
And that's one of the things that propelled, I'm sure,
our administration to take action is because the capacity to deal
in nuclear weapons is so enormously powerful
to huge numbers of people.
You can't just fool around with these people anymore.
You can't just say he's a local nut.
We'll just ignore him because he's carrying bombs
and he's carrying nuclear weapons.
And you can't just say, well, he's a local nut.
You can't just say he's a local nut.
You can't just dismiss the purveyors of falsehood
as harmless nuts who are carried away by mistaken enthusiasms
because they're influencing the opinion of millions of people.
So amplification then means that falsehood
in a way is more dangerous than it ever was.
Falsehood is more dangerous than it ever was.
It has always had a high price.
Denial is falsehood.
You say if you don't learn from history,
you're condemned to repeat it, huh?
And that's why I use some historical examples
because we're not so polarized about history
as we are about current events.
You can look at past history with a little more cool head
and not get your solar plexus all in an uproar
over current events.
If we looked, you know, my generation was World War II.
So after World War I, the espionage system
in the United States, the intelligence system,
reported constantly to the Secretary of State.
And every morning, the Secretary of State got a report
from the intelligence departments.
After World War I, Secretary of State Stimson was appointed.
When Stimson took office, they served him up on his first day
as Secretary of State with the intelligence report,
which kept track of the Japanese especially.
And he said these fateful words, gentlemen do not read other
gentleman's mail.
That cost us Pearl Harbor and millions of men
because the intelligence was, I learned it from my,
I learned it in grade school.
My teacher said Japan with a swarming population like that
and lack of, what do you call it, rubber tires, oils,
all that, what do you call that, whatever it is,
is going to have to expand.
It has no choice.
Nobody ever thinks of controlling the population,
by the way, in which you wouldn't have any shortage.
But anyway.
It demands proclivity.
You know what, we have a constantly expanding population
that is straining everything in every direction.
So Stimson played by the rules that we,
that the doctor and I did this morning.
And he said, gentlemen do not read other gentleman's mail.
So intelligence reports to the State Department,
which were rife with all the intelligence
of what Japan was preparing for, were completely ignored.
And the results were Pearl Harbor.
America is always being surprised, surprised.
It's always surprised by Pearl Harbor,
surprised by the Bay of Pigs.
Surprised, people are always being surprised.
The only way you get to be surprised is to be stupid, right.
You have to have your head in the sand.
And now you're surprised when somebody gooses you .
He was surprised when kids...
Like, so beware of people that are surprised.
You won't live long on the streets ofines.
Change often.
New York City, being surprised, friends.
I remember walking at midnight
on 10th Avenue,
and I heard the footsteps
behind me. It's like one in the morning.
The sound of the footsteps,
I knew what was on their mind, and what
they intended, and who they were,
without turning around. It would have been
a mistake to turn around.
If you don't have your antenna up, you don't
survive. Okay,
to be virtuous and holier than thou, you've got
to survive so you can get on TV and be
virtuous and holier than thou.
So somebody's got to protect your butt while
you're mouthing off, you know.
You need a realist somewhere.
And what's a realist? The realist
then is willing to
accept the downside of
human life, because
he's compassionate towards it.
If you're not compassionate,
that means you're in a
make-wrong, and if you're
in a make-wrong, you don't want to look at it.
You understand what I'm saying? Compassion allows
you to see that a lot of the people
that walk the planet will
skin you alive, right?
They will. And if
you love them enough, you realize
that that is a fact. That's a fact.
They'll skin you alive. We'll get to more
of that this afternoon. This afternoon we're going to talk about
business.
Skin you alive.
Where naivete,
the downside of naivete
costs everybody their life savings
and retirement accounts.
All the old folks are working
at Walmarts right now.
The 401k
went west.
So we'll talk about that this afternoon.
You see then that love
opens the door to the awareness of
truth, because you don't have to take
a positionality. You can
care for people
no matter what they might be,
because you see that that's
only where they've evolved to at this point
of time. They've only
evolved to the point. So,
the people who are the mad bombers
are in the
spleen of their
spiritual warrior. A dangerous
place to be. A very dangerous
place to be. Therefore,
they're very dangerous people.
And to turn your
back to them and think that a prayer
vigil is going to stop and they ain't going to do it.
So what can we all do as
individuals? We can all be
champions of the truth. We can all come
out of denial. And we
can all evolve ourselves
spiritually as best we can.
Now, we're talking about the spiritual.
We've talked about truth as
descriptive in form,
which is content, but
that content is with an overall field
called context.
There is no such thing as a statement,
a verifiable statement of truth,
that ignores context.
That's how all the
fallacies that run this world arise.
It's true,
but not in this context, folks.
Not in this context.
Our devotion to truth,
then, because truth is the expression
of God. God's expression
within the realm of human knowability
is via truth
and via love,
right? Via compassion,
via understanding,
and benevolence.
We try to
wage war in as benevolent
a style as we can.
That's all you can say for the way.
A lot different than a war we've all
lived through, or a lot of us older have lived through,
where it was done out of vengeance and
hatred. That was a whole different energy.
Vengeance and hatred.
This is not done out of vengeance and hatred,
although some of the aftermath of 9-11
is vengeance and hatred.
It's pretty much
mellowed out.
No, 9-11 let loose
the dogs of war.
9-11 let loose the dogs of war
and changed the game forever.
None of us are going to just hop
on a plane anymore.
I think the rest of our lifetime,
we're going to stand in line
and have our tick off our shoes
and say, oh, that mad
shoe bomber. He really
screwed us up. I'm glad
I wear Dr. Scholl's because
I can zip them open, put my shoes back
on like that. And the other kind
of people have to do their shoelaces.
They're black shoes, of course, with shoelaces.
We'll get to the black shoelaces
people this afternoon.
They're either businessmen or FBI. You know that right away.
Yeah, I never trust anybody with black
lace-up shoes, folks.
The afternoon good, one way or the other.
All right, so now
in this world, then, to be
mistaken is more dangerous than
ever. It's more dangerous
because the
effects are so amplified
by electronic communication,
by proliferations
in science,
bomb making,
et cetera, has become
anybody in his backyard
can brew up some
germs that'll kill off millions of
people. So,
you can't allow
people to be as deviant as you
used to be.
The mad guy in the bar, you know,
his only dangerousness
was he'd get behind the car and
kill somebody on the way home.
No, the mad person now can
with a little chemistry
set, stir up enough germs
to kill half of the people in this
planet. So,
we can't allow deviance
and negativity to
reach the point of dangerousness.
We're too close to the ruptured
appendix now. You've got to
operate a little earlier in the game.
Better to make a mistake
and take out a healthy appendix once in a
while than to lose
a teenage girl.
So, the surgeon gets
criticized. Well, we looked at it
in pathology and there was nothing wrong
with that appendix. It was really
mesenteric adenitis.
But at the time, it sure looked like
appendicitis. So, what's the guy going to do?
So, he takes a
risk that he gets criticized
and he has to go before
the hospital board to explain
how come you took out
a healthy appendix. Well, he didn't think
it was a healthy appendix, but he didn't
want to take a chance. So,
the margin of error now, in a way,
is less than it used to be.
The margin of error. Everything moves
much faster because of the media.
Everything is amplified.
So, error as well as truth
gets quickly amplified.
Because it's quickly amplified, then,
our own spiritual work has a
greater impact. And as
we mentioned before, when we were
talking about going
from the linear to the non-linear, from
Newtonian science
to quantum mechanics
and beyond,
you saw that each
choice that you make then
collapses the wave function, speaking
from the viewpoint of quantum mechanics,
and reinforces
the field.
Reinforces the field.
So,
therefore,
your own integrity in
striving for truth raises
the consciousness level of all of
mankind. And that which
makes falsehood
weaker instead of stronger
is the prevalence
of the consciousness of mankind
in general.
The consciousness level now at
207 is going to
surface that which is negative.
You understand? As you move
from 190, which was non-integral,
to 180, which is non-integral,
to the non-integral, which is
non-integral, which is
non-integral.
So, I mean,
I don't want to jump the story of
business, but...
I mean, what I was taught, I
remember a sales guy who was trying
to get me to sell peanut vending
machines. Did I tell you my peanut
vending machine story?
That's really this afternoon's
story, but would you give me a
little preview?
I had 1,001 jobs, you know,
1,001 jobs. People think they're
underpaid now. I worked as an
intern 100 hours a week.
That's 400 hours a week.
That's 400 hours a month for
$100 a month, so that's a
quarter an hour, right?
Anyway, in the summertime,
you had to find a job.
Anyway, in the summertime, you
had to find a job.
So here was this ad to be a
sales representative.
So the job
So here was this ad to be a
sales representative.
So the job was you work for
this sales guy.
He comes in.
He checks in a hotel.
You meet him in this hotel.
He gives you the pitch.
The pitch is you get these
retired farmers
retirement money,
and you get them to invest in
peanut vending machines.
And
and
from the viewpoint of honesty and integrity.
And I brought this up, and he said,
I said, that's really not right to fool these guys
out of their retirement when you know
it's not going to be emptying every week or something.
He said, if you don't get their money, somebody else will.
There you go.
So that was the world of the 30s or 40s.
I don't know what it was.
Because the prevailing level of consciousness was 190.
And at 190, business was business.
And ethics was ethics.
And you don't miss the two.
If you don't get their money, somebody will.
There you got the rationalization.
So nonintegrity survives by virtue of rationalization,
making it sound OK.
But truth cuts through that.
So my intuition told me that I really
didn't have the heart to take people's retirement money.
At death's door, you're going to be reviewing your life,
and I'll be looking at all these poor old guys,
and I'll take the retirement money.
I really didn't want to look at that.
So people now that are dedicated to spiritual truth
have a great impact on the collective consciousness
of mankind, because it went from 190 to 207.
Well, 207 is a whole new ballgame.
At 207, nonintegrity begins to surface,
like the good begins to drive out the bad.
So at 207.
You see how we conduct a war, even in a world that's at 207,
although the US is at 431.
We try to, as ambiguous as it may sound,
we try to conduct an ethical war.
An ethical war.
As ethical as you can make it, surgical precision.
Try to be benevolent at the same time.
Snare the Komodo dragon before it kills any more.
So that is the moral.
You might say the moral predicament of the US.
And the way I see the US handling it at the present time
is best it can with an unpleasant condition.
Now, has anybody got any questions about war and peace,
seeing as we just straightened out Sun Tzu, who
wrote The Art of War?
The classic is The Art of War by Sun Tzu.
The Art of War.
It's an art form.
I think it's.
I like this title, The Art of War.
The Art of War.
You see how it looks at it as a game board.
Everybody had a question?
We'll do it.
We have a few more minutes.
And then we're going to have lunch.
And then this afternoon, I want to do business, science,
and many other areas of human life.
You can stand up and speak, please.
Yes.
OK.
They're both the same.
It's just a quality.
You see, from here down, what you're really talking about,
are negative energies, which classically, theologically,
religiously, spiritually, have been called either Luciferic
or Satanic or demonic.
This is the beginning.
You see, non-truth, then.
And those are just different qualities.
Satanic has been, it takes two forms.
Our society is attacked by both ends, by the way.
The Satanic takes the form of bloodshed.
Killing, murder.
The ultimate Satanic energy is the serial child killer,
who calibrates around seven, by the way.
The pornographic addict child killer
calibrates probably the lowest of all, around seven
or something.
It has to do with cruelty, savagery.
You saw it in Nanking in the 30s.
30,000 innocent civilians slaughtered, raped, murdered,
et cetera, et cetera.
It preys upon the weak and the innocent.
Therefore, oh, while we're talking about ethics,
it is unethical and non-integrous to tempt people
with weakness.
To purposely place temptation in front of people,
you must handle the karmic consequences.
If you have a new maid to clean your house,
and you leave a pile of cash sitting out there,
who is the perpetrator?
And who is the victim?
You're the perpetrator.
Why?
Because you're provoking human weakness.
Lead us not into temptation.
So to lead people into temptation.
So weakness leads people into temptation.
To be in denial makes you a choice, plump little victim.
And if I hadn't had paranoid alertness,
I would have got mugged on 10th Avenue that night,
and many other times in New York City.
No, you can't be into denial, because that
makes you the provocateur by virtue of the temptation
and attraction of weakness.
That's the predator-prey response.
That's why weakness does not work
in international politics.
Weakness just pulls forth the predator.
He just can't resist the fact that you've
got all that money, all that vulnerability sitting there.
And you have to take moral responsibility
that you tempted the predator.
So the victim doesn't stop being victim
until the victim takes responsibility
for the part they play.
If you want to go jogging at midnight in Central Park,
you have to take responsibility that you're
a luscious little victim that is going
to be beyond the self-control of half-drunken or intoxicated
people with no sense of honor or ethics.
You're going to get raped no matter what.
You keep doing it.
If not tonight, tomorrow night, sooner or later.
So we see that weakness then has a moral downside to it
and that you are tempting those who are weak.
Now, how do we know they're weak?
Because they calibrate below 200.
You're tempting 78% of the population.
Vulnerability and weakness tempts 78% of the population.
78% of the population.
Yeah.
And the rest of the population is not
interested in peace, ethics, or honor,
unless it's a pop political slogan.
Just like the peace movement is not about peace.
It's about politics.
In other words, it's using peace as a slogan.
And therefore, it denigrates the true meaning of peace.
Because that which is peaceful does not denigrate,
does not marginalize people.
That which is contentious.
Contentious is not peaceful.
Peace does not come out of contention.
What comes out of contention?
War comes out of contention.
So if you make peace contentious, you're declaring war.
To declare war in the name of peace is lucifer.
You see how you take what sounds like truth
and you turn it into its opposite.
You polarize the people in a contentious war of ideology,
power politics.
And it deviates.
And it divides people.
That which divides people into war and camps
does not represent peace.
Because that which is peace unites people.
So 78% of the population, then, is
run by what we call dark energies.
Those on the right-hand side are called, in politics,
keep the calibrated level up.
In politics, we call the far right fascist.
The far right is fascist.
The far left is Marxist.
The far right is cruel, fascistic, and dictatorial.
It's savage.
It's merciless.
It's without compassion.
In China right now, to even voice certain things
gets you not only arrested, but executed.
Executed.
The same as in Arabic countries.
Even do or say certain things brings
automatic, instant execution.
Forget about trial.
Forget about lawyers, martial law.
It precludes all those things.
So the far right is fascistic, sadistic.
Another aspect of the satanic, which
may not look the same to you, has
to do with sexuality, sexual perversion, sexual obsession,
drugs, the kind of music put out by certain groups.
Kick your pregnant wife in the belly, hate rock, and obscenity.
Great names celebrated by the media are overtly profane,
overtly sacrilegious, overtly, overtly attack
that which is sacred, that which is divine, that which is holy.
Especially innocence.
That which attracts the satanic is innocence.
Innocence in our culture is youth.
Therefore, it's very easy to program youth with programs that respect
or decency, is being white, is being uncool.
The contempt for that which is holy and sacred comes out of the satanic.
So we have the satanic attacking our culture via the media.
The main avenue of the satanic attack is via the media,
in which many of these musical things calibrate 70 or 80.
For instance, this week, I was at a concert.
I was at a concert.
The media announced a new video game.
It's called a game.
Drop your guard, folks.
It's just a game.
It's called Postal 2.
Postal 2 is worse than Postal 1.
Postal 2 and 1 is worse than, what's that name, auto something?
Huh? Grand Theft Auto, yeah.
Well, Grand Theft Auto is bad enough, but Postal is trying to win the game of seeing
how depraved can you get.
Let's see what Postal calibrates.
We have permission to calibrate in front of this audience, Postal, a video game, which is over 30.
Now, there is an innocent game, which is programming your unconscious at a calibrated level of 30,
which is contempt for all that is decent, holy, or integrous.
Savagery at its extreme.
That's satanic.
So we have satanic in the political realm.
It's fascism.
We have it in the realm of the lower, what do we call it, the bottom of the barrel of society.
Drug addiction, savagery, murder, pimps, prostitutes.
Pimps don't do very well calibration-wise either.
They do about 30.
I said 30?
Yeah, 30.
Said sadism.
They like to beat up the girls, you know, and savage them, terrify them, stab them.
They get out of line.
So you got six girls in your stable, one gets out, you cut her eyes out.
That scares the crap out of everybody on the street.
And after that, they do what the hell you say.
I know, I once treated a pimp back in the East, and I know the extent to which they go.
He would come in and say, God, I'm exhausted.
You think beating up girls all night is easy?
You should try it.
He's trying for my sympathy.
These girls have forced him, forced him, they forced him to do this, is the way he looks at it.
She misbehaved.
What else could I do?
You know, can't keep this.
All right, so that's satanic.
Now, the Luciferic is something different.
So the satanic can take you all the way down to seven, the serial child killer calibrates
at seven.
They're usually possessed from lower astral domains, and really not in a certain way,
not really responsible.
All right, the Luciferic is something else.
The Luciferic, what is Lucifer?
Lucifer's sin was pride.
So the Luciferic stands for the denial of the sovereignty of God, therefore it is the
ultimate of arrogance and pride.
So the Luciferic is at 190.
In our society, the far left calibrates at 190.
The refusal to accept divinity.
So that particular energy wants to wipe God out.
In human society, and turn it into a secular society.
Well, the reason our society calibrates as high as it does is the Constitution of the
United States is over 700, because the rights and equality of all men are a result of the
acknowledgement of the divinity of our creator.
The reason we're equal is because we are created that way by God.
That's what makes 720.
The Constitution of the United States is the highest.
So it's over 700.
All right?
highest of any government on the planet.
So the Luciferic would like to remove any acknowledgement of God because Lucifer's pride
was he did not want to acknowledge that there was any power greater than him.
So the Luciferic, to begin with, hates God and wants to remove any reminder of God in
every place in America.
I remember when Madeleine Murray wanted God removed as, I think it was prayer in the school,
isn't that prayer in the school?
She became the most hated, despised woman in America, and I saw a documentary on her
subsequent life, and it was abysmal, down to the trailer park, then down to degradation,
then down to murder and suicide in the family, and then family murder.
It was downhill.
You see, to say that, to destroy God is a different intention.
So the energy of a thing comes out of its spiritual intention.
To destroy God is to restore God.
I refuse to acknowledge the source of one's own existence, which is a Luciferic error.
To arrive at that, you have to do a great deal of alteration of philosophy, and so the
philosophical and ethical basis upon which these things rest are always gross distortions.
And one way you can tell they're gross distortions is because they're contentious.
One way they're contentious.
One way they're contentious is they demean the opposite view.
You see, in a debating class, each person presents his side, and he presents his side.
In that which is contentious, you don't present your side, you attack their side, which is
a different approach altogether, you understand?
So I don't care whether anybody agrees with anything I say whatsoever.
Why should I care?
Why would you want to influence other people?
Have a parade?
Make speeches on TV?
Why would anybody want to control anybody else, control what they think, control what
they believe?
I'm sure these people believe that what they're doing is for God when they blow up a whole
airplane full of innocent passengers.
They probably felt virtuous as they killed 3,000 in the Twin Towers.
Well, Pearl Harbor only killed 2,000 in 2400.
Pearl Harbor only killed 2,400.
And it was a military target.
The Twin Towers killed 3,000, not military target, innocent civilians, blown up without
any chance to prepare for death, no confession, no absolution, no nothing, out of body, 3,000
innocent civilians.
I didn't see any peace parades after Pearl Harbor, nobody told me it was unintegrated
to counter attack Japan.
I didn't see any peace parades after Pearl Harbor.
A littleTIN.
Why no?
All right.
So, if we calibrate the level of truth of that particular distortion of truth, we see
it calibrates at 190.
190 is putting one's own ego above the reality of God.
See?
So, the reason it's below 200 is because it's a denial of truth.
So, the left end is characterized, that...
Lucifer is characterized by arrogance.
Arrogance and remorse.
replacing facts with opinions and by distorting the truth,
distorting the truth.
So that's the difference between Luciferic and Satanic.
One form of the Luciferic is to distort truth
so that you cannot tell good from evil.
In our society, many people cannot tell good from evil.
One side of conflict is demonic, calibrates at 70,
and frankly, after it's juiced you, it will kill you.
So people parade to the defense of that energy.
Lenin said they're useful idiots.
Lenin was the one that introduced terrorism
as a legitimate way of achieving one's goals.
It was Lenin that popularized terrorism
in the Western world.
Those who supported his position,
he called them useful idiots.
And after the revolution,
they're the first ones to be extinguished.
The first ones you're gonna execute after the revolution
because if a person is not aligned with their own origins,
if they don't respect their father and mother,
their own culture,
they turn against their own.
If they turn against their own, you can't trust them.
So after the revolution, you kill them all.
The first people extinguished after a revolution
are the revolutionaries.
The intellectual revolutionaries,
who sell out their own integrity
for the gain of being superior.
So Stalin said he called them useful idiots,
and after the revolution, they're all shot.
So they don't bring about freedom,
they bring about their own execution.
The devotion to the truth, then,
means the willingness to look at some painful facts of life.
Painful facts of life.
The ostrich head in the sand,
is a wimp. The wimp is unable to look at the downside of human life.
Gentlemen don't read other gentleman's mail.
It wasn't other gentleman's mail he was reading.
The Japanese were planning Pearl Harbor
and the destruction of the United States influence
in the entire Pacific.
And kill as many Americans as possible.
So you see in the interacting balance of power
how these levels of consciousness
which tend to manifest in various places geographically
force certain moves.
You see how the victim forces the perpetrator.
The victim forces the perpetrator
to take action against them.
Suicide by police is the name of the game.
The second atomic bomb
after World War II
was forced upon themselves by Japan.
If you don't get the implication
that a second atomic bomb
that doesn't stop you.
They forced a second atomic bomb
before they got it.
Is that stupid or what?
The two atomic bombs they get
that the war is over.
We have met our master.
He was correct.
We awaken the sleeping giant.
Once you wake up the sleeping giant
the game is over.
So we looked at this morning at the realities of war and peace.
We use consciousness research to find,
to get to the core
of what is the truth of these things.
One way to get to the truth of it is
being personal about it.
Don't have any position about it.
I don't care if this side is right or that side is right.
It's immaterial.
Because where I live all that is just nonsensical drama anyway.
It's all the games of the ego out there
and I'm not the ego and neither are you.
So who cares about it?
Everybody wants to kill each other.
Let them.
Why should you interfere?
People get a wallop
by killing themselves and others.
Have a game.
That's going to be difficult.
I don't know that it's possible.
We have historically, I always go back to history
because if you don't learn from history
you're going to repeat it.
The difficulty with the Russians of course
is they had no knowledge of ways of freedom.
How to hold title to a house.
How do you buy a house?
How do you open a bank account?
What do you mean checking account?
What do you mean mortgage?
They had no idea what we're even talking about.
It made no sense to them.
So generally what you have then
when you remove a fascist regime
is you have a period of political unrest
and instability and chaos.
And then the warring factions come out again.
The communists will try to take over.
The fascists will try to take over.
The different religious factions
will try to take over.
And I expect chaos.
I imagine it's going to be a mess for a long time.
Because our idea of living with those who differ from us
don't forget it took us hundreds of years.
America was old by the time
we even settled blacks and whites, right?
When I was young
the blacks had their own bathrooms and bus stations.
And I just as a kid thought that's the way it is.
I thought that's the way it is
because black people are poor.
I didn't think it was because they were black.
I just thought in terms of black and white.
I just thought that they must be poor
that they don't have washstands that work.
The toilets don't work.
And the filling station was dilapidated
that they used.
And then the white man's
either was all about money, you know?
So it took us hundreds of years
to even settle that simple an issue.
And the Catholics and the Protestants
warred for thousands of, you know,
a thousand years, right?
They're still at it in Northern Ireland.
So even a society
at 400, you know,
it takes it hundreds of years to settle out.
So I would guess Iraq will
settle out in four or five hundred years.
Well, those factions have been at it
for thousands of years already.
They all hate each other with a vengeance.
They're all coming out of the spleen.
You know, the Palestinians kill a busload of kids
and then the Israelis
kill a busload of pregnant mothers.
You know, the more pathetic the better.
I'm going to answer that
and then we're going to have to break for lunch.
I don't know.
I'll answer it this way.
From my general knowledge
of the evolution of consciousness,
which I went into somewhat in the last book
and which we'll go into more in the future,
the evolution of consciousness
since the beginning of time
has been an upward trajectory.
And at a certain point,
you might say the accumulated positive karma,
the karmic merit
of mankind has earned it
the right to go over 207.
Karmic merit has evolved
because, you see, at the time of Buddha,
the level of consciousness of mankind was 90.
At the time of Jesus Christ, it was 100.
By the 1600s, it was up to 185,
and then you saw it at 190.
And when I came into this world,
190 ran everything.
And then suddenly in the late 80s,
it jumps to 207.
And, of course, what's significant about that,
is that you're on the other side of the,
you're on the other side.
So on a ship,
you know, I steer the ship
a half a degree off,
and the compass doesn't seem like much.
But a half a degree
after a day or two of sailing
across the Pacific Ocean,
you're a couple hundred miles off.
So just a few degrees
makes the difference between success and failure.
So, as I say, the reason you see
a lot of non-integrity surfacing in Ron,
and we're going to get to that this afternoon,
big corporations falling,
congressmen being nailed
for dishonesty and stuff,
is because 207 will not tolerate
that degree of non-integrity.
190, we said, business is business.
Steal a little, just don't make it too much.
And 207 now calls for a different action.
I remember I had a housekeeper many years ago,
and she used to do the shopping for me,
and I would then later check with the grocery,
and she padded the bill 10%.
And I figured, so it's 10%.
I didn't fire her.
She padded it a little bit.
I know she's running about 10%.
She'd tell me the groceries were $22,
and actually they're only $18.90.
So I figured, she's only stealing 10%,
so I never said anything.
Now you'd feel you have to say something.
You can't just sweep everything under the rug anymore.
Now, now integrity would say,
I'd have to tell her,
listen, you're going 10% on top of the bill.
Now, I may negotiate with her and say,
look, if you want a 10% raise,
tell me, and I'll give you 10% more.
But I've got to get myself out of integrity,
and I'm going to be non-integrity
if I don't call her on it.
At 190, I'd say, look,
she's only stealing 10%.
Good.
Good housekeepers are hard to get.
But now I've got to live with that
because I realize there's a karmic consequence
to saying okay to non-integrity.
So, okay.
So it's a new world.
So eat well because this afternoon
we're going to hit business.
A difficult morning.
Only a couple of deaths along the way.
Nobody got outraged with what I had to say
and left enough.
So I consider that a great blessing.
To try and contextualize compassion
for all positions.
To be compassionate for your enemy
who is walking under some kind of an understanding
just as you're walking under some kind of an understanding.
And I'm sure on some other plane,
some other day, we'll all laugh about it.
And I think I've shared with you
the laughter I had with the fellow
that I skewered with a sword and he skewered me.
He did it for Allah and I did it for God.
And I mean, we killed each other good, too.
I remember exactly both experts.
And boy, did I kill him.
And did he ever kill me.
We were just fantastic.
At the zen of weaponry.
And we both went out of body and got hysterical.
I killed him for Jesus and he killed me for Allah.
I mean, it was the funniest thing.
And in that moment, you transcend your warrior.
You understand the warrior?
We transcended the warrior.
But I was willing to die for God, Jesus.
I died for Jesus and he did it for Allah.
So I've respected the enemy ever since
because he's just like I am
in some different level of
karmic working out.
You know, this is the karmic theater of
the universe.
How can there be such a variation?
And shouldn't the world be different than it is?
We can do without the garbage cans.
I get carried away with their beauty
and then I can't remember what I'm saying.
Where did that come from?
Let's see.
It's in the lower right.
Tom Lincoln sent us that.
Okay, thanks.
The world is perfect.
The world is perfect as it is.
I have no intention to change it
because if this is supposed to be
the perfect school for all of us to evolve,
to undo bad karma, achieve new karma,
then we need the whole panorama
from the very worst to the very top.
And that's what our world represents.
If it's the perfect world, you know,
for what it is, purgatorial in nature,
where else would you go?
If it wasn't for this world,
where would I have killed that guy for Jesus?
And where would he have killed me for Allah?
You know what I mean?
You've got to be someplace that tolerates this craziness.
This world rewards you for it.
So we both went out here, went out as heroes.
We were both heroes.
And so we transcended the warrior at that time.
So each of those archetypes then represent
evolutionary steps in the evolution of consciousness.
At one point, I didn't mean to say
this is the ultimate, but it's not.
But it's just the way it is.
It's the way it is.
I've tried to try to make clear this morning,
and it'll carry over till this afternoon,
is the difference between authority and authoritarian.
There's a purposeful misinterpretation of authority
as authoritarian to justify demonizing authority
by purposely distorting it as authoritarian.
dictatorial there is such a thing as true authority by virtue of the nature
of that which it is it is intrinsically the authority the authority and what it
is to be the cat is my cat and anything I say is not coming from the authority
because the the authority of being that which you are psychoanalytically I always
viewed the fact your relationship at least amongst men the relationship you
had with your father will pretty much set your political position later on if
your father was cruel unloving at Sarah you will hate authority and be therefore
against all that stands for authority big business institutions the government
and whatever please hmm view all authority as evil and get out on a
bandstand and parade against authority and so authoritarian is the
abuse of power. Authority is the true nature of power because truth is power
and the true true authority comes from integrity. So if you had a father who was
fair and yet firm but loved you at the same time, you will view authority as
both friendly and to be respected. Patriotism is the respect, the love, the
acknowledgement. At the same time, the limitation of society is accepted and
the police are seen as somebody who will protect you, not just, you know, somebody
who in an authoritarian, abusive way unleashes the dogs
against innocent victims, you see, because the victims are not innocent. You don't
get the police dogs released on you because you were having a peace vigil.
Takes a lot of rock throwing before you know it.
You get the police to get out the water hoses, etc. So you see the
provocation, and you see that especially in the Middle East, where one side
provokes the other into action so they can then blame the other and hold the
innocent baby in her arms as the mother cries, which they keep a whole bunch of
those videos on hand at all times. We played first on one side and then the
other, you see. So that's the victimization of the public by the abuse
of the power of communication of the media to
purpose.
This is the, bring up maudlin distortions of the reality. So how you view authority
then? If you hate authority because your father was cruel and authoritarian, or
whether your father was benign and loving and supportive at the same time demanded
that you finish your homework. So positionality about authority then has
something to do with many, many things, one of them being childhood experience of
how you were parented.
If your mother and father were unfeeling and cruel, then you'd be very hostile to
it. So our host thought a lot of people who protest authority, even in its
legitimate form, probably had a very bad relationship with their fathers, you know
what I'm saying? So there's many psychological, psychoanalytic, as well as the nature of
the ego itself, which tends to positionalize us and get into right and
wrong. So this afternoon we're going to talk about business. Let's have business up here.
They say if you got through war, business will be a snap.
If this morning didn't blow you out, you'd probably be okay. Now this looks pretty, is
that readable? All right. Because of its importance to our culture, war and peace has to do with
staying alive. Now that you're staying alive, how do you survive? So survival then takes
us into the world of a job, business, commerce, money, abundance, abundance, abundance, abundance,
abundance, abundance, abundance, abundance, abundance, abundance, abundance, abundance,
abundance, and all of those then are experienced depending on one's level of
consciousness. So we want to talk about success. There's many workshops on
success and making money, and I could never afford to go to one of them when I
was younger. It's 350 for the weekend, then I figure, you always say you stay
poor. Okay, that's great. That's all right. Everybody can cock their head a little
bit. We can tell who's paying attention.
Who's paying attention? Who ain't? That's fine. That's fine. That's good. That's good.
Good. That's good. All right. So the demonization, the vilification of business then comes from
the same source as that which denigrates the United States and its presidency and the flag
and God and the Constitution and all that.
Because business is seen as a source of power, it's hated and stigmatized, and every time,
there's an international business conference. They parade up and down the sidewalk with
signs. They hate business, and they hate big business. So I always get a kick out of
these guys. Here he's got glasses on made by some business. He's got a shirt on made
by some business. He's got pants on made by some business. His shoes were made by some
business. His watch, he's looking at his business-made watch, standing on a business-made
sidewalk while he holds a business-made placard made out of business-made things.
And of course, it's business. Well, okay. So now, when you croak, what are they going
to put you in? Because business makes caskets, too. You know what I'm saying? So we have
to accept that and see business for what it is. The corporate culture, you know, is really
the out-picturing of abundance. People talk about abundance. Well, here it is. Here we
are in this magnificent room, magnificent carpet, all kinds of electronic equipment.
I got these books. I got these books. I got these books. I got these books. I got these
books. I got these books. I got these books. I got these books. I got these books. I got
these books. I got these books. I got these books. I got these books. I got these books.
You know, it's sort of stupid to sit here and vilify business when my whole survival
from moment to moment is dependent on business, isn't it? Without business, there'd be
no electric. We would all be sitting here in the dark. You wouldn't hear any of my voice,
and none of us would have anything on.
So the alternative to that is to live in a cave and spin your own clothes. And if anybody
wants to try that lifestyle, you have the severe ascetic, I'll tell you, it's cold in
cold in winter and it's hot in summer. No. So, what industry and business represent is
the collective enterprise. It's the collective abundance of all of us. The total business
output of America belongs to all of us. Now, technically, you may be only legally entitled
to this little piece of stock or whatever, but you get, we all get the benefit of the
all of it. And to say, how much of it do I own, you're coming from the solar plexus
because you can all walk in here for free. It doesn't cost you anything to walk into
this hotel and walk around and go to the men's room and walk out on the sidewalk. All of
that costs millions of dollars. So, from moment to moment, we all benefit by an infinite trillions
of dollars of productive output of our society. So, when you vilify industry and business,
you're vilifying yourself because that's your own energy pouring out there and that's
the source of your survival. Without penicillin, you're going to be dead. Without a hospital
to go to when you have a heart attack, you're going to stop breathing and stay right there.
Without an ambulance to come and get you, without an oxygen tank. So, every single instant,
you are benefi-, benefiting by the total output of the industriousness and integrity of the
society.
So, we've inherited a certain momentum from our previous generation. So, the previous
generation already had Model A Fords, Model T Fords. We had a 29 Model A Ford Roadster
with a rumble seat. It was fantastic, but it wasn't a streamliner. So, in the 30s, when
the first streamliner car came out, and also the railroad, you know, we had the old locomotive.
Well, then the streamliner, the Hiawatha came out.
And the train went by once a day, 4 o'clock. We lived on the sticks. So, we'd take our
bicycles and drive a couple of miles and we'd wait until 4 o'clock. And the Hiawatha would
come through. That was the high point of our day and then the, then it was gone.
Okay. So, the hard work of all of us, generation after generation then, we collect a certain
amount of capital behind us. The accumulated infrastructure of our society, the amount
of money we make is a free gift. Sidewalks don't cost you anything. They're paid for
by your parents and your grandparents. The automobile industry has already worked itself
to death to produce the car that you just walk in. You can buy a better used one now
for practically nothing than you could buy brand new .
So, everyone benefits by the total collective output of all of us. Therefore,
we should reauthenticate it, reappreciate it, and re-contextualize the value and building
But the importance of that to all of our survival.
We as a nation are enormously productive, and we are like a bastion, we're like a sign
to the rest of the world, this is what's possible.
This is what's possible.
Of course, we say it arose according to a certain economic system, which we would like
to see other people incorporate.
I don't really care whether they incorporate our free enterprise system or not, what do
I care about it, as long as I get penicillin when I'm sick and oxygen when I can't breathe
anymore and I've got a car to park, and a parking lot that somebody paid for, who paid
for all that pavement out there?
So you ride around all day on the back of corporate production and industry through
a number of generations.
So to vilify it is sort of stupid, isn't it?
To vilify it, okay.
You can vilify it and stigmatize it.
By warping it, by projecting certain misinterpretations.
The image of the victim and the perpetrator is so inculcated in our disruptive society
right now, it's first of all very, it makes you sound very important to stigmatize something
and criticize it.
So if your self-esteem is not too high, what you do is you go about criticizing everything.
The government, state and federal.
The military, industry.
Ford Motor Company, you name it.
Part of this criticism comes out of distortions of Marxism.
The distortions that see authority as authoritarian.
That see authority as exploitive.
Exploitation like any judgmental thing depends on your point of view.
Henry Ford introduced the first five dollar a day workplace.
Five dollars a day.
It was overwhelming.
The downside of Henry Ford.
you weren't allowed to smile or go to the bathroom.
You got paid good money,
but you weren't supposed to have a good time at it.
Anybody who joked around was the foreman quickly told you.
And if you wanted to go to the bathroom twice,
you say you went already this morning.
I worked in an automobile company, a factory,
and I remember how it was with the production line.
Well, you can picture that production line any way you want to.
So you see, when we talk about the world,
we're always talking about perceptions.
Was that production line my road to freedom,
or was it my road to captivity?
Depends on your political prejudice in the matter.
It was my means of working my way through medical school
and therefore freedom.
So the assembly line then was to me a road to freedom.
You could say, well, the assembly line
is symbolic.
It's a symbolic of captivity.
You're the captive worker who's chained to his post,
and time did go very slowly,
because this auto body would come down,
creak, creak, creak, creak, creak, creak,
and then I was supposed to go bzzzt on it,
and then it went creak, creak, creak, creak,
down to the next person.
Well, you had to wait like 45 seconds.
I'll tell you, that was the longest 45 seconds.
I did my bzzzt, and I had nothing to do.
I mean, nothing to do for 45 minutes.
Oh, my 45 seconds.
Oh, I'd almost want to run over and grab that thing,
but I'm here, you bastard.
Tedium.
All right, so instead of demonizing industry
and business, et cetera,
let's say we realize that you wouldn't even exist without it.
Few of the people would be alive in this room
if it wasn't for industry or business.
Industry and business is what puts out pharmaceuticals.
That's why we don't have the plague anymore.
It's why we don't have tuberculosis anymore.
When I was an intern,
infantile paralysis was,
all these diseases were rampant,
whooping cough and diphtheria and typhoid.
What's that one where your arm went weak
and then you were paralyzed?
President Roosevelt had it.
Polio, yes, polio.
My job then, I was the only doctor on
in this infectious disease hospital.
The head doctor had an alcohol problem,
and he disappeared and left it for the intern.
So here I am, an intern,
right in the middle of a polio epidemic,
and I'm here.
And there's no laboratory technician,
so the mother brings the child in.
I can tell from across the room,
he's got polio.
You can see the one side out on the kid,
and I can see the terror in the parent's eyes.
So I was by myself,
so I quickly ran in.
First I was the doctor,
then I was the lab technician.
I ran the back, and I did a spinal tap on this kid,
and I spun it down in the centrifuge,
and I counted, and I looked,
I saw all the white cells there,
and I had to go out and tell the parents.
They would drop dead,
just drop over on the floor,
and the father would bring us out
because it was hopeless,
hopeless paralysis.
And if you got up to the thoracic region,
the diaphragm, you went in an iron lung.
And life in an iron lung is not fun.
You lay on your back inside this iron thing,
and you can't breathe when you want to breathe.
You breathe when it breathes you.
And boredom, talk about boredom,
talk about 45 seconds waiting for the next auto body
to come down.
You imagine spending years that way.
Industry and commerce has saved us from that.
None of us have to spend our life
in an iron lung.
If you need oxygen, an ambulance will come
and bring it to you.
Carefully trained EMTs are experts.
I've watched some EMT teams work together.
Impressive, I'll tell you.
It was like a ballet.
Each one just moved like they were telepathically connected.
Magical.
To save your life.
So, we owe our life to industry.
We owe certain allegiance to it,
and therefore we owe a certain
thankfulness, gratitude, and respect.
That off the backs of all these workers,
we have
the gift of our society.
Therefore,
I think
business and industry needs to reinvent itself.
I'll tell you why.
Because it has bought
a lot of the criticism against it.
It's incorporated the negative values.
It itself
comes from guilt and apology all the time.
Please forgive us.
An apologetic,
defensive, guilt-ridden,
shame-based kind of
coming out of, really,
the distortions of reality.
If you're integrous, and you've done the best
you can, and you know your company's doing
the best you can, you can look everybody in the eye
and you don't have to give an apology
for anything. You can give an explanation,
but you don't need to give any apologies.
There's nothing to apologize
for. What they're usually
hit with is the distortion of truth,
and now they have to apologize, not for
reality, but for some distortion of truth.
It's like, when did you
quit beating your wife, you know what I mean?
Well, he never did beat his wife.
Alright, the most powerful nation
on Earth came about as a result of
the free enterprise system,
of which enterprise industry
and business,
and I'll get into
some of these examples.
So all the people who denigrate
our form of life,
hate capitalism, hate the free market system,
hate the presidency,
hate all that, I notice that
they don't move.
So, why
are you still here, freako?
If you don't like Gonsaville,
why are you still living in Gonsaville?
Because the positive payoff
of living in America is so tremendous
that people are willing to die to get here,
and they cross the Mexican border,
they die by the hundreds every year,
to get to the land of free enterprise,
which everybody else ungratefully
and non-integrously
is busy attacking and trying to
denigrate.
My feeling is that business
and industry should recontextualize
itself to itself.
They don't even realize to
themselves who they are.
Somebody has to tell them.
Without you, practically everybody in this room
would be dead.
Before the days of industry, the average age of death
was like 45 or something.
Because there was nothing to keep you alive.
There were no pharmaceuticals, there were no
diagnostic, there was no x-rays,
there was no bacteriologic laboratories,
there was no hospitals.
Without industry, just about everybody
would be dead, frankly.
The death rate in childbirth
amongst women was a third.
A third of women died in childbirth
due to puerperal fever.
There were no antibiotics,
no sterilization procedures.
So the medical industry then came forth
with all ways to save
human life from suffering
as well as disfigurement
and death.
The average healthy, reasonable
human being lives to be
what, 80 now?
Yeah.
When I grew up, 65 you retired
and at 66 or 67
you had your heart attack
and it was goodbye.
That's true, everybody retired at 65
and they had a heart attack within the first few years.
The average age of death
was around 67, 68.
I would have been dead 10 years already
and more.
To respect then
the American public should respect
the very source of its own affluence
instead of trying to attack it
and denigrate it.
To do this, corporate America has to
understand its own value to the world
and to each other.
So we need to recontextualize
the value of human life
as it expresses itself
in business and commerce
which is, after all,
at least eight hours of most people's day
five days a week
you're in that world.
In the world that you denigrate and hate
your life is going to be miserable.
So we have to value
the value of our own work
the value of that business
to society.
So I say we need to recontextualize
the significance of corporate America
to itself.
To do that, you have to first of all
look more at the context
than the content.
A lot of times business makes
actually horrendous mistakes
coming out of this apologist, defensive attitude
partly due to the trial lawyers association
and various other things.
But, hmm
I've watched a lot of really painful disasters
and therefore I always recommend
first understand who you really are to the world
and stop being apologetic.
Stop being guilt ridden
because you make profits.
Who gets the profits of business?
The country gets the profits of business.
If I'm a multi-billionaire
I don't put it in a coffee can
in my backyard
I put it in some industry.
I put it in a bank.
And that capital goes back out into the world
to be
of use for making
building universities and things.
When you get old and guilty
you can start a society
a beneficial society
but during
our lifetime
does anybody keep their money in the mattress here?
Anybody hide it in the mattress?
All your dirty capital
that you've accumulated
you rotten capitalists
you keep it in a coffee can in the backyard.
Anybody here keep your money
in a coffee can in the backyard?
Nobody.
Anybody keep it under the mattress?
No.
Anybody chop it up and flush it down the toilet?
Alright, so the money goes right back
it flows right back out.
It's nominally yours, nominally.
Functionally it's not yours.
The minute you put it in the bank
it's really the bank's isn't it?
The bank decides what it's going to do with it.
Here where I live
they're going to start a new 125
house development project.
That's going to cost millions and millions of dollars.
They've got to run water, basic things,
electric, all that.
So what we need is
a consciousness coach.
Now the word coach is sort of over abused
in business and all.
So we need a better word than consciousness coach
but frankly that's what they need.
Somebody to re-contextualize back
first of all to the company
as a whole
with the executives and the people
that interface with the public.
And I don't mean public relations people
because they're a lot of times idiots.
They're worse than anything.
They're a lot in their 20s and they're abrasive.
They put out advertisements
that make you disgusted.
That cracking duck.
If you don't shut up that cracking duck.
I hate Affleck.
I really hate Affleck.
Now there's a guy, a new TV commercial
this guy can't get his computer to work
so he screams at you.
But the sound of screaming
if you calibrate the sound of screaming
it's way down low.
Loud cracking ducks it's way down low.
Affleck I telepathically communicated
with Affleck and I said
oh god this is awful fellas.
I really did sort of hold a
corrective view of the duck.
And I do notice that
the duck now comes on
and he's much quieter.
You can get more customers
with a happy quiet duck
than an abrasive one.
Affleck was coming to
the girls ranch where I'm at
and they're providing the health insurance
and I said I don't want to see the guy
when he comes here.
I said I hate Affleck.
What I'm talking about more seriously
is the awareness
you see they get backed up against the corner
and they come out of guilt
and then they start using deception.
And what we found out with consciousness research
is
we have permission to ask this
in front of this crowd.
Unconsciously everybody knows
when they're being lied to.
Consequently
the company executive
the CEO gets on TV
and then stonewalls
and flatly lies
is fooling nobody at all.
So this recalls a couple of
painful interviews.
In as much as that which is
like defeat on plump juicy
innocent things
we can say that a successful corporation
automatically draws to itself enemies
by virtue of its success
out of envy and sheer hatred
for that which is integrous.
So Sam Walton and I
used to correspond and of course I calibrated
his principles and we calibrated Walmart
and all that. And as we said last time
we predicted in 95 what would be
and sure enough Walmart turned out to be
the biggest corporation in America
built on integrous principles.
Proof that integrity pays on the bottom line.
Well Sam Walton died
and Walmart calibrated
around 380 I think when
he was alive.
It's dropped to maybe 15 or 20 points since then
because anyway
the next president came up was black
and I watched the most painful interview on TV.
At that time those who like
to attack big business and find something wrong
were attacking Walmart
that they were employing child labor
in third world countries.
They were like the dirty old
men thriving off
these poor little children's
work and sweat and labor.
Oh boy, oh boy.
So Black gets up there
and he defends himself
and sort of
flat out, oh we don't do that
or some idiot like that.
That was really painful
because I thought you know I wish I had a chance
to talk to this executive before he got up there
because you look at the evolution
of an industrial society.
Third world countries are not industrialized yet.
They're coming out of agrarian.
And as we came out of agrarian in America
we went through the sweatshop phase.
Everybody does.
The children in the needlework, the seamstresses
you remember the one in Boston
the seamstresses were all in New York City.
They were locked into their
factory
with the sewing machines and they all burned to death.
Remember that?
So as you come out of an agrarian society
you go through that phase of child labor
women laborers
seamstresses
and sort of as you move into industrialization
so you have a phase there.
Now people don't realize
what poverty is
and you look at some of the favelas
on the sides of the mountains
in Brazil
what's the big city in Brazil?
Rio.
You visit those shacks on the side of the mountain
and you realize what poverty is.
Now if those children
could get a job at 10 cents an hour
the whole family's economy
would jump like this.
They could support the whole family.
So in a third world country
you have a need for needle trades
the children are available
because that's their phase
coming out of an agrarian society.
Alright so to support
the evolution of a third world country
into an industrialized society
if American capital
like let's say Walmart
goes to a country like that
and says look we'll give you
what to them is huge amounts of money
to do this
and needle work
in return for which
we want the children's work hours
limited to 8 hours
we want to have fresh air
they must still have medical coverage
every child must have at least 2 hours a day of school
you're in a bargaining position
you're holding the big bucks
and they want your big bucks
so you can trade business
for humanitarian principles
you understand?
So Walmart could be the liberator
of these exploited third world children
they brought the whole culture up
to abundance
the respect for human life
that no door should be locked
with children in there
in case of fire etc
so they could have been the hero
they could have been the savior
of the beneficial savior
of the exploited
third world children
instead they came on
and stonewalled it
what happened to our explanations
the Red Cross
did the same thing
New Coke did the same thing
Coca Cola Company with the New Coke
the bald dead disaster
all these are
blatant examples of
not being able to contextualize
the thing in such a way
so it's coming from
guilt and lying
which we just demonstrated
this morning
everybody knows when they're being lied to
so you come out rotten
you come out rotten instead of a savior
and now you vindicate
the vilification of industry
because you've just been
industry at its worst
where's our piggy
there you have
American capitalism
as viewed from the Marxist position
exploiting the worker
workers you have nothing to lose
but your chains
and what is the fate of the worker
in Russia, China
all the communist countries
ok
there you got the downside
of capitalism
you exploit her
ok
so a coach would
coach people on how to recontextualize
he would coach you on timing
this week American Airlines
after the union
settled the contract
then tells you that the top executives
are about to get 1.5 million bonuses
that are exempt from
what timing huh
what timing you don't need enemies
when you do that against yourself
you know
I mean stupid I mean really
even they realize it was really
dumb dumb dumb and they've retracted it
but the bad news you know
the bad image is out there already
so there's Mr. Pig out there
running American Airlines
now we'll leave Mr. Pig out hidden away
ok
alright so to recontextualize the thing
first of all you got to come from truth
to have integrity
everybody knows when you're speaking the truth
so you can come out as a big company
and say you know that was a bad mistake
and we learned from it
nobody holds you that's against you
you hear anybody
criticizing any past business mistakes
that the businesses came out and said
well you goofed on that one
no because when somebody admits the truth
you're willing to forgive them
when they stand there in stonewall
and frankly lie on your face
you lose your respect for them
ok so we want to integrate
business into the overall human
community
instead of setting it aside
where it's vulnerable to attack and criticism
ok
there is a thing I wrote about
in power versus force
called critical factor analysis
we haven't spoken about
calibrating the levels of truth
in the various aspects of business
but you can calibrate the level of any corporation
every department in that corporation
all the key positions
you can ask
the correct calibration
and all this job is blank
so you've got to find somebody that has that
instead of hiring somebody that doesn't have it
and then firing because they don't have it
well you shouldn't hire them if they don't have it
we said this morning
the perfect calibration for a presidency
of the United States of America
is 460 that's perfect
if you ask the question
what is the most perfect calibration to fulfill
the duties of that job you get 460
people would say wasn't 510 better
no 510 is not better
people would say it's all idiotic
we're not interested in politics
who cares about that
420 wouldn't be able to have the moxie
to grab the complexity of the overall situation
so
alright you can calibrate every aspect of business
and
show its application to research
marketing, advertising, production
there is a thing called critical factor analysis
which I mentioned in power versus force
most of these corporate interactions
are with multiple corporations
interacting here with the government
here with the public, here with sales
here with marketing, public image, publicity
it's highly complex
so how can you tell where
an alteration
can change the whole thing
in critical factor analysis
means in a non-linear
because now we're out of the linear
and into the non-linear
the complexity is already out of the linear
beyond the capacity of a computer to figure out
the multiplicity of factors
now run into the millions
how can you find out where in those millions
and millions of factors
most of which you can't even get on a computer
because a large percentage
of them are coming out of the unconscious
and therefore not available
to put into a computer
how can you tell where can we
touch this complex interaction
and bring about a desired result
the example
I used in the book was a huge locomotive
carrying billions of
pounds of
freight behind it
15 freight cars
a mass, a huge staggering mass
and a very complex
powerful engine, let's say
two or three diesel engines
we've seen them go by out here in Arizona
through the Navajo lands
etc. with three locomotives
and a mile and a half
of freight cars
do you know you can stop that whole thing
with one finger like this
all you have to do is know where to
touch the control and this entire
thing comes to a stop
one light little touch
less than half an ounce can stop
this entire monster
get in its tracks
that's the critical point
the critical factor analysis
if you know where to put just a half an ounce of
pressure the whole system
changes
so it isn't a complex thing
a slight shift of image
and your entire company and its impact
and the response to society totally changes
just the slightest
implication
you are coming from good will
rather than greed already impacts
people quite considerably
that you're concerned
this is different than advertising
advertising to me is made up by
young people with insufficient wisdom
to be able to contextualize the advertising
so that it has any impact
if you calibrate a lot of
I mean the companies spend
enormous amounts of money on this trash advertising
you can tell it came out of
a 24 year old's idea
of what would be cute or smart
and it's losing 90% of the audience
because first of all
they presume everybody out there
is 22 years old and grew up with computers
so the average commercial
was like this
and I say to Susan
what are they advertising
how many times have I said that to you
I said what is it they're advertising
it was a cute frog and then a locomotive
and then somebody stabbing somebody
and then some rock music and then all these flashing lights
and it's gone
I was trying to catch the label who made it
what is it
there's one that says
we don't actually even make anything
we only improve things
so why are they wasting their money on me
if they improve tennis shoes
but don't sell tennis shoes
then they should be advertising to manufacturers
to use their product
to improve their tennis shoes
and why am I sitting through their commercial
we don't make tennis balls
we make them better
that's good for them
pointless advertising
the speed of processing information
and then we see commercials
that really grab you in the heart
there are some commercials that are stunning
stunningly brilliant
stunningly poignant
leave a lasting message
and totally change your image of that company
and how you feel about it
so American products don't belong to companies
they belong to America
when you recontextualize who you are
business and corporate America
you are America
therefore the lack of respect
for the company's symbols
to me is also outrageous
and obviously done by 24 year olds
log cabin syrup is supposed to be
in a tin log cabinet
Aunt Jemima's pancakes
is supposed to be a nice chunky dark lady
I don't want to see some slim blonde
because she's been modernized to modern America
those things
those symbols have become sacred to us
New Coke found that out
you mess with us and you got trouble
so America is saying
you mess with us and you got big trouble
people hate the new Coke
I wouldn't buy it
these people do bad enough
they keep changing the
at least they stay with red white and blue
but I just get used to Pepsi this way
and then they turn it this way
I mean why are they doing that
so if business views itself
as semi-sacred to the public
we hold these things in a semi-sacred way
I still long for the Burma shave sign
little shavers take it easy
your driving is driving me crazy
something like that
the Burma shave sign
I've never cared for that president's wife
who took down all the roadsides
in the image of beauty
this is somebody rather
well she was a do-gooder of some kind
now you got to look at boring miles
of nothingness or apartment buildings
or something
we used to have a big sign
a Janssen lady swimming suit
thirty foot long
yellow swimming suit
life is exciting
well let's see
integrity show itself in business
first of all we know that goodwill
is an energy
it's an energy
they either got it or they ain't
you can't fake it
goodwill and good intention
it then spills out into the workforce
so that the workforce now
begins to represent
who they are via their work
so
we
using critical factor analysis
we show that
these principles
results in
benefit everywhere
lower
sick time off the job
lower employee turnover
greater productivity
why because
you have to believe
your product and your company
has to have integrity
for you to put forth your best
if you're just punching a time clock
that's perfunctory
and that may calibrate at 2.02
is sort of the IRS
they do it but
you're not happy to see from them
you're not happy to see them
they're not happy
when you learn from the IRS
you don't feel cheered up about it
congratulations we appreciate
the fact that you have now sent us
an accurate tax return
for 35 years doctor
one time I got one of those
taxpayer compliance dragnet deals
this is some years ago
in which they take a certain category
and everybody gets audited in that category
the computer picked them out by
somehow so I mean
you know this was draconian and I had to
pull out a receipt for every time
I went to the bathroom and prove every gallon
of gas so it was a lot of work
you know it took a week or two to get all this crap
together and
when he got through he found that it was
perfect so he gave you a letter
that you had
showed 100% perfect
compliance that's the only good
news I ever got from those people
you're a good guy
you're ok
the next year would you know
out of sheer chance the computer
picked me out again so I got one of those
taxpayer compliance audits
two years in a row
ok
so the way it went was I knew he was
coming so I laid everything
out like you would for a king
he's the IRS guy
I had everything laid out categorized
I bought special folders for each thing
and I scheduled
it being shrewd at the same time
not stupid I scheduled it
for a Friday afternoon
I know Friday at 5 they're due back at the office
so we scheduled it for
2.30 on a Friday afternoon
which means he would get his butt in and out
so facilitate
his work so the way to be
successful is to make other people
a success so what I did is I laid
it out that it would be a snap for him
easy
any anxieties or worries that he might
have I documented it
so his afternoon was
a snap and he left in an hour
and a half and I got another taxpayer compliance
letter and my life was a snap
so you see how
supporting each other pays back I supported
his job his integrity
I made sure that when he went back
he was bringing back
truth and he saw
to it that I got acknowledgement for the hard
work I tried to make his
work easy you understand so
how business works so
the more we work to make our supply
as business
a success the more ours is a success
so success
then feeds on itself people say
how do you get success in this world
and there's many many a workshop
on it and I certainly don't want to
pretend to have any
knowledge of the subject I
just know experientially
that if you put out
excellence if you put out the best possible
can job you can do
no matter what it is
the benefits of this world come to you
automatically not in a linear fashion
it's not because you do this
that you get that but you
create a field and the field brings
you abundance I used to
lecture all over the place all over
travel all over and
people would say well aren't you
going to charge for that and I
said I never charge for lecture well you're not
no because
you're
explaining to an interested audience
the most advanced knowledge on a subject
available on the planet and
consequently their families
and their relatives and
cities they came from
would call up and want to refer their patients
in see in other words the field
brought in patients I don't have to advertise for patients
in those days
the way you built your practice was through
integrity the best possible
service
the most perfect way you could be
and that creates a field
and then the field built
your practice or not
nowadays doctors advertise I mean if I
had to advertise for a patient
please give me a break
I saw you because I read your ad in the
yellow pages alright
so then integrity then is its
own self reward let's see
alright so we can go through a company
we can calibrate the energy
field of all the departments whether people
are fitting that department
you see that employees build
your image in the world
and what we're talking about here is
context now
the unenlightened person the
less evolved person
is only concerned with content
not concerned with context
do we understand
context
do we
somebody might be lying out there
give me this thing here
I was just going to dive in I got my water wings on
ok we'll put it up here
it's critical to
understand all spiritual work
especially spiritual reality
and truth
you see
there is the content
this is specific
this is called the world of form
see
this is the world of form
that's the world of the ego this is that
and therefore that's wrong
but this world
which is there
is within a field
yeah
what the uninformed
and what science doesn't understand
is that
the power of this is completely dependent
on the field
the truth of this
is completely dependent upon the field
without the field
this has no meaning
it's the field that gives it meaning
alright so
if you think you're just going and punching a time clock
you're not getting much reward
you get a paycheck
so big deal
you can get a paycheck in any company
I can walk down any city street
at the height of unemployment
the headlines are screaming
I can walk down any street
anywhere in America
and within a block get a job
and I've done it over and over
at the height of unemployment
there's no such thing as unemployment
when unemployment is going on
you open the daily newspaper
and there's 14 pages of jobs
what do you mean where's the unemployment
there's 14 pages of jobs here
what you mean is you don't want to do that
oh that's different okay
oh you don't want to work
okay
if you're willing there's always a job
because if there's no formal jobs
you create one
so in school I'd go down the street
I didn't have a nickel for coffee
literally in those days
and all the kids from college hung out
in the coffee house you had to have nickels
so I'd go down the block from the college
state teachers college
and knock on doors
and sooner or later somebody would want their windows washed
and I'd wash their windows for 50 cents an hour
or whatever it is
and I'd have the money to go back to the
job yourself
so that comes out of willingness
so the willingness then was the power
this is a critical thing to understand
because this is what science doesn't understand
see this is where Newtonian science stops right here
then quantum mechanics starts to tickle you to go out there
and this is the world of non-linear dynamics
this is the world of the linear Newtonian paradigm
and this is the world of spiritual reality
okay
power is coming from the field
this is the source of your power
the unenlightened person thinks
if I just strive harder
I'll make more money
I'll work harder longer
spend more money on advertising
cut down my employees wages
push the envelope as hard as I can
that's looking at it from causality
if I push harder here
I'll win more there
I'm too lazy to do that
I mean
I'd rather be good at winning
what I do
and let them come to me
why should I push for customers
so context brings you effortlessly
what you cannot achieve with effort