We'll resume. Can you all hear me? We'll resume and I'm going to sign books and as I sign books
people will ask questions and I'll answer them, not as complexly as we did before.
We just calibrated the level of aesthetics because in a way aesthetics are part of the
partial answer to some of the questions. Aesthetics becomes a prominent part of the
human psyche around calibrated level 360. Just beyond Chinese fortune cookies.
Aesthetics. So you know many could give many answers to the questions
but one of the appreciations of life is the awareness of beauty and the part that it plays
in your decision making and your values of life. You know we saw a dog during the
lunch break, stunningly beautiful, this black stunning dog. Not only its lovingness
but its stunning beauty you know and so you begin to appreciate the beauty of life.
If you blindfold somebody and take their blindfold off I can tell you the consciousness
level of where I am by looking about two feet around me because when you're in certain dangerous
parts of the world they all look the same. There's litter, there's trash, there's
graffiti, there's a complete lack of appreciation for beauty and when you see the emergence
of respect for beauty then salvation is not far. So in answer to a question that came
up this morning, what can we do for the children individually and collectively? I think teaching
them the appreciation of aesthetics. If I look back at my own childhood what the visual
do I value most? Well, Midwest lifestyle of the 30s, etc., had a certain profound inner
value of itself. But the things that accrued to that was an intense appreciation for beauty
in all of its forms. So the fortunate part of my own lifetime was my parents were musical,
my father was a musician. We were all very sensitive to aesthetics and traditional religion.
To be in a great cathedral, there I am a boy soprano singing Pontus Angelicus with a full
orchestra in a full cathedral, with the stained glass windows and a full choir and a full
audience hanging on every obbligato-soprano note. It was ethereal. It was like unreal
and it imprinted.
It imprints beauty. So one of the expressions of divinity is aesthetics and beauty. And
I think the answer to the gentleman's question, what can we do for the children that are under
such assault by that which is non-integrative in our society, is to expose them to real
beauty and aesthetics. The appreciation for opera. As a boy, I listened on Saturday afternoon
Milton Krauss from the Metropolitan Opera.
And, you know, I knew all about the Nibelungen Ring and the Wagner and the Bizet, all those
things just as a boy, as a boy. So if I had to do it over again, I would express as much
energy as I can in directing the children in aesthetics. Ballet dancing, there's nothing
more exquisite than seeing a pas de deux from a great ballet, you know. And we have tickets
for it this year.
The only time I rode to Phoenix to see La Boheme, you know, in the spring, or a great
ballet, the Sadler-Wells Ballet. So in a small town, in Wisconsin, which I'm sure from the
viewpoint of LA or New York is the sticks, we never missed a thing, you see, because
we didn't take it for granted. So when the Sadler-Wells Ballet came through or when,
you know, Paderewski came through or Gala Kirche or somebody great came through, we
went.
So that was great.
So the answer then I wanted to give was aesthetics would be the counterbalance to ugliness. So
the dominion of ugliness is negated by the inner appreciation of beauty, because once
you have an inner appreciation of beauty, ugliness stands forth as ugliness. And it
may be stylish, it may be hip, it may be cool, but the fact that it's ugly is quite obvious.
Teaching our children aesthetics and communicating…
You know…
…and communicating our appreciation and love and value of aesthetics, I think is probably
the best counter for us, a counterbalance we can give to ugliness and the danger of
ugliness to the psyche of the children. I know you didn't ask me, but I know you'd
like that.
Okay, let's proceed, yeah?
And I can say, you know, my obligation to you is to be that which I am to the greatest
extent as I can be to a greater extent.
Thank you.
to you, to be radically all that I can be, and thus serve you is my joy.
And I would like to thank you personally, and this is a token of my appreciation of all the
good things you've done for me this year and for everyone else. This is the latest Robert Gass CD.
This is the music we listen to, Kyrie and Alleluia. Yes, he's wonderful. This is his
latest and greatest, and I'd like to offer it to you as a Christmas offering. Thank you so much.
Thank you so much. Yes. First, thank you very much again. I have not been very comfortable with
the calibration or the kinesiological process. I was hoping that you might do two calibrations
for me if you'd have a problem. No. You'd have a problem. All right. There's a spiritual
teacher in India by the name of Gurinder Singh, and I'm curious where he
calibrates. I'm curious where he calibrates. I'm curious where he calibrates. I'm curious where
his teachings calibrate at. I can't really do that right now. You know, we prepared quite a huge
volume about it. To answer these things correctly, they have to be contextualized in a certain way
so as to avoid judgmentalism. See? Otherwise, you think 440 is better than 420. I understand.
Not necessarily so, because the task of 440 is different than the task of 220.
It's not better than. Each level of consciousness addresses its own level.
So, a person at 420 can be an excellent teacher at 420, and somebody at 480 can be a very bad teacher.
So, you see, the excellence is on its own level. So, I can say, well, Einstein only reached 499.
On the other hand, 499, the Einstein level that he reached, you know, has changed the whole world.
So, it isn't just a calibrated level of consciousness, but the whole contextualization of it and the
timing of it. See?
I guess what my intent is, it's not so much to place a judgment on where he is as much as a protection
that I'm not with the charlatan one way or the other. And, I mean, I don't feel that at all.
Oh, oh.
So, more my curiosity is...
Then why are you asking?
Well, it's been 20 years, and I haven't, you know, there's four requirements.
The fourth one being initiation, which he gives you a mantra.
It's been 20 years.
I've danced around him.
I have not made that plunge.
Oh, oh.
I see what you're asking.
I'll ask you in a different way later and not in full.
Okay.
See, what you really want to know is the appropriateness of where you're at is really the question you're asking, right?
Well, by that you mean?
What's the reason you're asking me the question?
It's the appropriateness of where you're at and the step you want to take.
That's right.
You're not asking me about him.
You're asking me about yourself.
That's right.
Okay.
That's a different question.
All right.
Okay.
I'll answer you afterwards.
Fantastic.
Thank you.
You know, is a certain move appropriate for where you're at at a given time is really the question you're asking, see?
Yeah.
It's got nothing to do with him, see?
Fantastic.
Thank you.
Because at the wrong time, Jesus is the wrong person to worship, understand?
Because you'd be seeing him in a way that would not be helpful.
Yeah.
Hi.
I don't have a question.
I wonder if you can send these books.
I just really enjoy being in your presence.
Because I feel that my mind is quiet when I'm close to you.
Can I give you a hug?
Boy, he's got a lot of muscles.
Look out when you scream.
This guy's a mesomorph.
I once had a buddy, and he'd had a couple of beers, and he dropped in to visit me, and
he gave me a big hug and broke three of them on one side.
I didn't tell him, because I knew it would hurt his feelings, and he'd feel guilty about
it.
So I just kept it to myself.
But I tell him, go, crump, crump, crump.
They healed.
It was a tough winter, though.
To celebrate, I went country riding.
I went to a lot of places.
I went to Western dancing, and I turned this girl who's called a dip, I think, to go underneath
my arm.
She ducked under her arm, or she missed, and her head hit me, my ribs on the other side,
and broke them on the other side.
It was busted rib winter.
First three on one side, then three on the other.
So I went to see an orthopedist.
I said, what is this with the busted ribs all the time?
He says, you need more calcium.
So I've been taking calcium ever since, and I haven't broken a rib since.
I'm careful who I hug, that's all.
Thank you.
What's happening when you have a spontaneous movement out of form, and then you get pulled
back?
Years go by, maybe it happens, I guess, two, three times versus working at this and getting
to it?
Well, because that's the way it usually comes on.
It's like feelings, like you'll suddenly out of nowhere have a presence of light within
yourself, and it illuminates all things, and you're beyond all time.
It's stunning.
It's stunning, and it's very distinct.
And then the next day, it's gone.
You say, well, where'd it go?
So that's the great night of the soul.
Oh, Lord, where hast thou gone?
What have I done wrong?
How come thou hast deserted me?
The Christian saints, you know, the bridegroom, what have you left me?
No.
Those are the wings of the soul.
And they soar.
And what you see is your own destiny ahead, that's your destiny.
So you just go back to doing what you're doing and working your spiritual program to the
best of your ability.
And then it becomes more and more predominant, but it may come very intensely and leave a
number of times.
You know, it first came on to me at age three, then it came on again at age 12 in the snowbank.
Then it came recurrently.
And it would leave for five or six years, you know.
And I learned, do not pine for it.
Just do whatever you're doing with the same devotion and stop looking for dessert.
So I say, oh, Lord, let me surrender my appetite for that delicious dessert and serve you during
the ordinary meal of everyday life, see?
Because in that state, you can't function anyway.
You're useless as a human being.
You sit there smiling sweetly at everybody, embracing them.
Pray for peace.
So it could be that you've got something else of equal importance.
It's only to tell you that, yes, you are on the pathway, and it gives you like a preliminary
assurance of the reality of that level of reality, that even if you experience it for
seconds, you now know it, and it leaves an imprint in your consciousness that will never
leave.
Oh, yeah, it leaves a vibrational frequency in your aura, and it doesn't ever forget it.
Never forgets it.
You'll never be satisfied with anything less.
Thanks.
Yes?
Could you elaborate on the psychic attacks that you endured and how you endured them?
Psychic attacks were something I didn't believe in.
It sounded very New Age-y and yah, yah, yah, baloney stuff.
And it was only when they became...
I'm sorry.
It was only when they became severe, then I used the diagnostic consciousness techniques
to discern what it is, and also through prayer, how to undo it, what the error is.
Beyond a certain level, consciousness is like you're not allowed to hang on to an error.
It's like your commitment has already demanded that you let go of that error.
Let go of that error.
I found that anguishing, it didn't happen up to a certain level.
A certain level was exquisite bliss.
Everything was miraculous.
Everything was love and exquisite beauty and oneness.
And then beyond that, I forget what started the movement beyond that, but then started
the feeling of...
It's like that which you have become is viewed as competitively dangerous.
Yeah.
dangerous for the dominion over mankind. When you start unveiling the lies and
you start taking the sheep's clothing off the wolf, you start to get bitten. And
I was distressed by it. I found how to transcend it to find out what
chakra in which archetype was out about what. And through prayer and forgiveness
and asking God to see it differently, then I would feel that pain leave me. But
it was like your whole body was on fire with a sub-lethal level of electricity.
Like it wasn't enough to kill you. They slowly fried you. So we were in Korea
when Susan found the answer. She pulled out. I said, God, what is this? What is
this? What is this? And she reached in the drawer, pulled out the equivalent of the
Christian Bible, a book of verses, and she ripped it out of the drawer. And Jesus
Buddhist Bible, and she opened the page, and it says, the Buddha said that he, on his way
to enlightenment, he was wracked with pain and attacked by the demons, and attacked by
the demons and wracked with pain, like his bones were broken.
Instantly, I felt better.
I said, that's what's going on.
That's what is going, or what's going on.
That's what's going on.
So, now, instead of feeling bad about it, you say, well, you've chosen this, and now,
you see, the human nervous system isn't made for that kind of consciousness level.
The human nervous system is comfortable up to about 700.
Beyond that, it's not, the human nervous system is not made to handle those frequencies and
those high energies.
Therefore, the nervous system, in this case, the nervous system had to actually become
heavier by accretion of proteins and various other things.
The nervous system literally had to adapt to the taxation of that energy frequency.
That's a fact.
Resist.
It's finished doing that now.
It's finished doing that?
It's finished doing that.
Resist.
So, putting 220 volts through 110 wiring system, I guess, is the problem.
And now, it's adapted.
I have permission to ask this.
It has now adapted to that requirement.
Oh, that's first of God, doesn't it?
Well, that's relief.
But hearing that from the Buddha.
So, sharing our spiritual experience with each other, see how meaningful it is to all of us.
For all of us to hear of others' experiences, you know, we all benefit to know that that
advanced glimpse of what's coming up spiritually in the future for you can come and go.
When it happens to you and it goes, you say, well, I've heard of that.
You know, you're getting it.
It comes and then it goes.
And not to feel bad.
Not to feel bad about it, that you've done something wrong, you know.
Just to hear of it, see.
Because the minute she read from the book, I felt instantly better, see.
Because it's not something commonly spoken of in our society, you know.
I was a psychiatrist 50 years and I never heard of it.
I read all the great intellects of all time and I never heard of it.
So, hear an obscure Bible in a drawer in a hotel in South Korea.
There was the answer, you know.
Waiting.
Waiting for you.
So, you say, dear God, you know, whatever.
God leads your wife to open the drawer and she pulls it out and she says, here's what
the Buddha said.
That was very nice of the Buddha to leave the message for us.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Yes.
Hi.
I have a question.
Yes.
And what it has to do with, I guess, is when you spoke about, or when you speak about enforcing
or enforced.
You spoke.
When you were talking about sobriety earlier, enforced sobriety.
Oh, enforced, yes.
Are you, are you, is that, are you speaking the same way as when you speak of force?
And?
Yes.
In other words, karmic, you know, what's traditionally called good karma, only comes about as a
result of your own personal choice, not because you're coerced to some move by somebody else.
Although, in the beginning, you could be coerced by somebody else.
And later, of volition, by it.
That happens to people in prison.
They're put in prison, and there they go through a transformation of consciousness, and some
reach almost sainthood.
But that was out of the choice of free will.
In the beginning, it wasn't their free will.
Same as some people who get sent to 12-step groups, say, A, by the judge, and they've
got to have other people sign that they attended.
So in the beginning, it may be with resentment, and then much to their own surprise, suddenly
they become an enthusiast.
Now they're a genuine member.
But of their own free choice.
So that ties in with discipline?
I like how.
Well, okay.
This is really what I'm wondering about, is that I have a belief that not eating meat
is probably better than eating meat.
I don't know this because I'm not a vegetarian, but from a perspective, I can see that as
a good thing.
Yes.
And I tend to think that...
That that is a process that comes, and that the desire for and the tolerance of meat falls
away, versus a choice just to become a vegetarian out of a discipline.
So at various times, depending on where you are and your level of understanding, it means
different things, and therefore your behavior would mean different things.
At one point, it would be adherence.
When I was a Buddhist, strict Buddhist, you know, I kept the butterfly net.
I would sit behind the grapes in my office, and between patients, I would take the butterfly
net and catch the flies and put them out the window, because I didn't want to swat one.
In those days, I believed in death.
Death was a possibility.
So I thought, if I'm killing the fly, I'm killing life.
Well, if you think that you can kill life, then you shouldn't be killing life.
Once you realize that life cannot be killed, to the fly, it doesn't make any difference.
Then you're different.
So it all depends on how you're seeing it.
Because, see, each level...
You're expressing the reality of where you were at spiritually.
You're being honest.
See, while you think of this, you should be doing this.
While you're doing this, you should be doing that.
Right.
And I guess I still have input from different levels at the same, maybe not the exact same
moment, but from moment, or a relatively short moment to moment.
Because it's not a linear process.
It's a non-linear process.
And so one day, you see this scintillation more than this scintillation.
One day, I was sitting.
I was sitting at dinner, and they say, what do you want, steak or fish?
I always order fish.
Suddenly, I looked at my meat, and I said, I am meat.
I'll have steak, thanks.
I'm doing the cow a favor.
If I don't eat steak, there's going to be no cows out there.
Millions of cattle will not have a life.
You see?
So it all depends on how you contextualize it.
I completely understand that.
You can serve life by eating it.
See?
Yes.
Okay.
So, as I said before, the Rig Veda says that each level of life is sacrificial to that
above it.
So, you reward the animal by allowing, by when you eat the animal, you're allowing it
to evolve to a higher level of consciousness by uniting with you and your blessedness.
And in so doing, you bless the animal, you see.
So, it depends on how you wish you envision it.
I can give you half a dozen of the ways, but that's enough for today.
Okay.
I understand that.
The only thing I'm wondering now, then, because I do...
No, no, no.
I'm sorry.
I do understand that.
Yeah.
And I'm going to walk away with this.
Go ahead.
And that is the should.
There's a should that's coming out of ego or judgment or something that I'm still working
with.
The should that eating meat is not a good thing.
Yeah.
Well, don't eat it while it's a good thing.
Not a good thing, no.
Right.
I got it.
Thank you.
That's one of the things.
Money, sex, eating meat.
Those are the big ones that hit all spiritual students.
Money, sex, work, eating meat.
Those are the traditional.
Hi.
Yeah.
I have a question on the chart that you put up earlier, and this probably comes straight
from my mammalian ego, but could you account for the difference in calibration between
the...
Chimpanzees as a species, which you say calibrated around 400 and...
I didn't say it's a species they calibrated 400.
Perhaps I misunderstood.
I said cocoa reached 400.
Cocoa.
Cocoa is a gorilla.
Let's take dairy cattle then.
Do you remember what...
Dairy cattle, yeah.
Was that about...
In the 200s.
250 or so, if I remember.
Yeah.
But still...
Herbivores.
And mankind as a species calibrates now at 207.
So what is the problem?
Fox News instead of ABC, that's my advice.
No, because...
No, the problem is that you're trying to understand many things with the intellect.
The intellect is not the right tool.
Observation and intuition would be a better way, because then the significance of it dawns
on you as you're driving along, not even thinking about it, you suddenly see it.
The intellect is not the right tool to understand many things about consciousness.
Okay.
Yeah.
That's what I said.
I said that's what the...
No, that isn't what I said.
What did I say?
I said the Rig Vida states, Krishna states, that each level sacrifices itself to the evolution
of life by serving the next level.
I said that's what the Rig Vida says.
So do these levels...
I said the Rig Vida says.
Okay, the Rig Veda said that.
Do you think these levels correspond to the calibrated levels of consciousness or of life?
That what?
Do the levels referred to in the Rig Veda
correspond to the calibrated levels of the species that you had on the chart earlier?
I would imagine, yeah.
God created the animals and he created the humans and he created the fishes and the sea.
Back to my original question about humanity calibrating at 207.
Yes.
And a dairy cow calibrating at 245, which is the lower level.
Oh, some humanity calibrates lower than cattle?
Oh, yes, of course they do.
I got the statement.
Have you ever been in a Nazi torture camp?
No, I haven't.
Well, you won't have any question about it.
Whole civilizations calibrate at 60 and 70.
You realize there's whole civilizations where you would be executed right now.
Or even having challenged me with a question.
Do you understand that?
Now you're a brave man.
I do.
Well, he's been brave.
But I have the potentiality of reaching a level in the...
I understand what it is.
The content of your question is not the problem.
The problem is using the wrong tool to address it.
To think that these things are going to fall within explicable logic or reason.
They don't.
They just are.
They are what they are.
The inference of it only sort of dawns on you, but it does it in a sort of a non-logical way.
Why is it that a donkey calibrates higher than a lot of people on the world...
in the planet?
I don't know.
A donkey's harmless, see?
You're safer with a donkey.
You're safer with Coco, the gorilla.
I can take you to neighborhoods in New York City that are far less safe than being in a cage with Coco.
And she's the only gorilla.
The dog I met at lunch.
You're safe to be with.
Loving, friendly, trusting.
Good sense of humor.
Okay.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Like I said, I'm just...
I'm just to thank you.
That guy's a pal.
He comes up in public and gives you a hard time.
You know, who...
It's a good friend, you know.
Anybody can come up and just be friendly and I'll get out.
Thank you.
Easy going.
I think.
Yeah.
We're trained to rely on the intellect to solve our problems.
And it's hard to get that the intellect will only take you so far.
Many years ago, first reading about Buddhism and Zen and all, in the great dismay, I discovered
that trying harder won't do it.
Studying harder, reading more books and trying harder wasn't the answer.
I can remember the feeling of defeat because the intellect is what I spent all these years
perfecting.
and now I'm told
they won't do me any good
I had a follow up question
to the free will question
I think you
explained that all things happen
spontaneously according
to its karmic propensity
so do we choose at the level
of form that
you can pick up that pen
or is it a more abstract level
that you choose truth or illusion
not in the
physical world
for potentiality become actuality
yeah
in a generic way it depends on
intention
in a generic way
in the ultimate generic
way it's
the expression of
the nature of divinity itself
the energy of divinity is such
that anything you put in
its field
its potentiality now is
realizable
as an actuality
just like magnetism
on an iron filing
it's not personal
but the quality of the field
is for that
which has potential
to mature
so is it my free will
to walk up here
or was my free will
at a different level
did this just arise spontaneously
the fact that you're here means that that was
a potentiality that was realized
before you were here and that's why you're here now
it's not possible as an actuality
but only your intention made it happen
so my choice is my intention as well
right
so it's all intention
it's intention not the action
the action is just
appearance of
it's the appearance of creation
as it unfolds to the witnessing
of observation which is its
expression and physicality
the senses you know what I'm saying
without the senses nobody would know
you're here so that is on
a means of
signaling information form is nothing but
information
form is information
the story you tell where
you
speared the man in the groin and you could have given him a merciful death
was that simply his karma to die on the battlefield
I don't know about his karma I never asked about it
I had enough karma of my own to worry about it
well we challenged him to die on the battlefield
so the warrior is...
oh my gosh
the warrior in the warrior
they're behind the псie
they really challenged each other y'know
these are archetypal levels of
the evolution of consciousness
since it your collective unconsciousness
the warrior is one of the great ones
the warrior is a great archetypal level
see
like the mother
I mean these are all the great archetypes
Carl Jung
y'know
specified them
the warrior is one of the traditional
great archetypal levels
so you can do it in the physical warrior
the spiritual warrior
you know you can do it on the level sports
you can do it on the intellectual level there a lot of intellectual warriors
that's fine just keep them alive
warriors out there the war of words you know the warriors of of words it's just trying to understand
if that was your free will could you have chosen differently could you have killed him or was that
simply what arose due to everything the the option was i don't remember whether i was aware of that
as an obligation at the time i may not have been sufficiently evolved as a warrior my suspicion is
i was not sufficiently oh yes i wasn't sufficiently evolved as a warrior to have adopted the
warrior's ethical code that's correct all right so i wasn't evolved enough to own the code of
obligation to each other as a warrior as a point of honor i only saw it as winning so that's the
viewpoint of the ego the viewpoint of the ego is i downed him i won and i walked away feeling
victorious
in the ego except then the spirit hit me with guilt because there's a higher level of obligation
beyond winning anybody can win i mean you know i can train anybody to win at anything
it's a dime a dozen winning no to adopt the code and enclosed within the that field
so since your intention one thing to make money it's to know the other is the ethic of how to use
it for the benefit of of mankind etc see anybody can make money i can show anybody how to make
money in no time right
i work 80 hours a week instead of 40 i'll double your income no time that's what i did all through
as an intern resident i'll work 100 hours a week that's all so since your intention was to win you
didn't have the choice to give him the merciful death i wasn't conscious of that as an option at
the time okay why because of the limitation of the evolution of consciousness this consciousness
here did not see that as an obligation or an option when i bet went back into the i have to
what were you understood by this crowd and back into a primarily spiritual
domain and then reflected and came back again now I felt obliged to correct that
error and I chose the obligation because I'd gone through surgery without
anesthesia with no problem at all then feeling you know it was an ecstatic
state this was agonizing severely agonizing in the middle of it I saw what
it was and that was your choice awesome that you would feel the pain it was an
unconscious undoing of the tremendous guilt of that because when I saw the
agony of suffering of all mankind my contribution to that was surface so I
had been the contributor to his agony of dying by not having been involved enough
to the ethics that I owe my fellow warrior the honor as he lays dying on
the battlefield in World War two
you don't leave them there to die you hand them a pistol with one bullet in it
the dying man still has strength in one arm your obligation is to put a pistol
in his hand you know that well I'm telling you now in case you ever find
yourself your obligation now the pulling of the trigger is his option but it's
your option it's your obligation provide that opportunity for him now you're a
trained warrior yeah that is a fact that is a fact
that's the honor of the warrior I owe it to him in adding to what you just said
about the warrior giving the person the pistol to see if what they want to do
with that is that same symbolic way to answer somebody's request for help as in
they're not asking for help okay they're just laying there unable to help them so
they're lying in agony so you give them the freedom of option now which way they
take depends on where they are karmically see and there at one point it would be a
mistake for them to kill themselves and at another point it would be a mistake
if they didn't understand mm-hmm two different levels one the obligation
would be to surrender to God and learn how to disappear the suffering and
another you'd say that's ridiculous so in our society
that looks down on suicide depends on the conditions that's not necessarily
conditions you know there's a Harry Carey there's honor there's a certain
honor to a certain ritualistic so also in my lifetime I remember Harry Carey's
explicitly it's an extreme memory I'll tell you you don't forget it but having
accomplished it I remember the ecstasy went out of body in a state of ecstasy I
had surmounted the power of the power of the power of the power of the power of
the power of the power of the power of the power of the power of the power of
the power of the power of the power of a being who had wanted that forever
them forever never again would I have to face that
fear of death if I can do the ultimate when I met did you a confidence because
to go the whole way you need profound confidence in yourself because along the
way to the realization of the absolute truth you have to let go of every
anchor and security and illusion that you know or have every placed yourself
in overtime every little anchor that you've hung on to that's that you let go
up so that takes profound conviction and that conviction is only earned through I
think extremes perhaps what seems to the world extremes subjectively frankly it
wasn't extreme severe extreme there's another way to get there I take it
advises thank you so much yes please I didn't want to waste your time you've
spoken about the great possibility of spiritual growth by means of having an
addiction yes I wanted to ask you about other mental health disorders such as
schizophrenia bipolar that kind of thing what is the role of
therapy and what is the role of therapy and what is the role of therapy and what is the role of therapy and what is the role of therapy and what is the role of therapy
those every one of them offers innate opportunities that are spiritual some
are quite direct and quite obvious on the surface others are not so direct or
so obvious and you know with a bipolar I'll tell you the difficulty in treating
them is their egotism not their bipolar the bipolar is easy they're so
egotistical that in between episodes they tell you well they don't need to
take the lithium I say good luck you're the
first bipolar on the planet they'll get away with it probably just to prove me
wrong so if it's they go into denial so it's the arrogance of the denial that's
the difficulty so to me the spiritual lesson bipolar is the humility to
realize that genetically whatever genes you've inherited have a certain defect
and a certain limitation and you have to acknowledge that in limitation the same
as if you've got functional hypoglycemia you just got to stop eating sugar and
sweets you're gonna keep sweating passing out and
collapsing and having convulsions or whatever your symptom is so each illness
represents the opportunity to learn a certain self-discipline every illness has
a discipline asthma no you can't be with cats they gotta stay outside as much as
you love cats and in other words each illness has a innate lesson of
self-discipline if nothing else no I won't ask him we're going to we want to
stop in time for Nico to chant too.
Everybody who's in favor of Nico chanting anybody in favor doesn't want
Nico to chant you can leave the room now you don't have to where is Nico oh there
he is okay all right I want to save enough time because I want to answer
everybody's questions sign everybody's books and also Nico chant which is we can
accomplish it all no problem.
It's in the potentiality.
We'll just collapse time and it all fits in.
Can you tell us what's next do you have any books in the pipeline and when they'll be due?
I have a book I'm working on now I have actually three books I'm working on now
one it's called the crisis of truth which I gave sort of a push that hit on
my schedule because society doesn't know what the truth about anything doesn't
have the slightest idea what is truth is it knowable and how would you identify
it even if you knew it one side gets on and babbles you calibrate them there at
160 the other side gets on and babbles they calibrate them at 180 both sides
are lying who's the most convincing well no I just thought the crisis of truth is
was prevailing as a pressure after that comes devotional non-duality which is
just more going to be dialogue perhaps and then after that is one in which
we've done like 6,000 calibrations already of everything that ever was and
I'll publish that right now.
I'll publish that right before I leave the planet and this is the truth about everything bye
no that's cowardly isn't it that's cowardly however there's nothing wrong with being cowardly
I let go feeling guilty about being cowardly I'm proud to be cowardly I can best serve God by being cowardly
divine cowardice they call it.
When can we look forward to the next book?
I'm looking forward to the next book.
to this not not you're leaving the body but the books i can hear people say i wish you'd need the
body because i really want to see that book you know i'm on chapter nine of uh the crisis of truth
so i think 2004. this is 2003 right oh yeah you know the people who want to eliminate god it's
so funny you know you want to eliminate god jesus christ christmas great what year is this by the
way 2003 2003 what 2003 a.d idiot anno domini the year is 2003 in the year of our lord you're
going to have to eliminate the calendar as well this is comical you know thanks doc appreciate it
dogs god spelled beverage his dog anyway so guy's name is going to be up there those of us in the
know just know his name is god's name probably friends jesus christian know jesus christian
thanks my доп наверное spies jesus christian know jesus christian love you jesus christian
know you jesus christian love you jesus christian love you jesus christian love you jesus christian
know read it backwards we'll pass a slip around to each other read dog backwards and we'll take
god down from the courthouse and put dog up there where is john's everything god left to go
underground hi doctor my name is john and this is linda yes we were just married yesterday at the
chapel at the sedona creative life center oh yeah so we just want to spend our first day here with
you in this group so i think that's wonderful
there we go i did sign the chapel of the holy cross i think you're talking about creative
life center i know chapel of holy uh going on the chapel of holy which will go on
look at this right here you want me to sign this sure yeah just oh my gosh i haven't seen
one of these what is it that is myself
i'm
there. There's his picture too. Wowzy. Thank you. I guess it just came out. Hard work that was by the way. Hard work on their part. Hard work on our part. Hard work on Nico's part. Hard work on all of our parts. Yeah. And they did a good job on it too. They're devoted jobs.
I just want to say thank you so much for doing this for all of us. At the pace you do it
too. Because it must be so exhausting. And I just appreciate it so much. I'm sure everyone
does. Thank you. Quick question. You and I think it was Eye of the Eye or Eye were speaking
about how Freud is at 499. Yes. The level of the intellect is limited there. Yet Young
is at 540. 520. Yes. 520 or something. And surpassed the level of the intellect.
Yes. Could you just explain a little bit about what he did that got him past that?
Well Carl Young was just more evolved. Don't forget he was looking at different aspects
that were more aligned with spirituality. Freud was looking more at the animal nature
of the ego. So he saw the animal drives. Of course the deepest level of the unconscious
he called the id. Or all the socially objectionable. The desire to kill other people. And then
the ego, etc. was because of guilt, which he called the superego, driven to the level
of unconsciousness, which is the id. The ego then had the job of how to keep things repressed.
So Anna Freud described a very useful, I thought Anna Freud's work was great, the mechanisms
of the ego. Undoing, identification with the aggressor, projection, repression. So repression,
you just have amnesia. You don't even remember it. Projection, it isn't me that's that way.
It's those selfish people out there. Splitting means you split people into the good and the
bad, see? But these are from your own unconscious. The shadow gets projected onto the bad people
in the world. So these mechanisms are to a spiritual student. You run across them because
you're doing spiritual work to undo the ego. And you see yourself utilizing the same mechanisms.
You see? And interjecting things and identifying with them. People get overly upset about
what goes on in society because they're interjecting that society. That society isn't you. It's
got nothing to do with you, for God's sake. It's, you know. So the identification with
society. So all these mechanisms, I think in what I write, I do mention them because
I think every spiritual student comes face to face with them. Come face to face with
them. See?
And what Freud would say is the world that you see is all projections from your own unconscious.
The evil doers that you see out there now on the other side of the world, that's your
own dark shadow projected onto the world. And you see it as being out there. That's actually
your collector. That's really in you. So there's a lot of value in understanding
evil mechanisms, I think.
And so Jung just took it.
Well, Jung investigated it somewhat differently.
See? Jung...
Yeah.
He was looking at the collective, the collective consciousness, and he saw that universally
there were certain symbols and things recurring throughout societies, recurrently, the archetype
of the good mother, the archetype of the bad mother, the warrior, which we mentioned here,
the warrior, very important for the spiritual people.
He saw the recurrence of the symbols over and over in society, primitive society, more
advanced society, the recurrence of these symbols, and so he studied the part that they
play in unconscious mechanisms and symbolization, you know, but he validated the spiritual as
a reality, and Freud really viewed it as an escape from reality.
The spiritual in him was more an escape, a denial, and so each one contributed, you know,
in a different way.
Each one contributed of great value.
Thank you.
Freud saw the negative depictions of God as projections of the bad father.
The father from the unconscious.
I'm watching it.
Yes, I'm watching it.
We'll be just about done.
No question.
Okay.
If there's no questions, we'll finish up.
We're going to have Nico.
Nico Chen.
Sounds great.
Yeah.
What?
Aha.
That's weird.
So wonderful to meet you.
Thank you.
I had a quick question as to what makes the difference between, like someone can have
a vision and a mind.
What's the difference?
I mean, you're on a very low consciousness level like Hitler, and yet he could have a
powerful influence on the world.
Yes.
What makes the difference in who has a big influence and who doesn't?
What's the question?
What makes the difference in the field of influence that a person has?
It's not their consciousness level because both high consciousness and low consciousness
people have influence the world.
Don't forget the power that is given to a politician is projection from the populace.
So, Hitler in the beginning…
The same as Napoleon, calibrated around 450.
Both Napoleon and Hitler started out as integrists for socialism, the betterment of Europe, mankind.
They both made great contributions to society.
Hitler helped the economy, created the Audubon system, many other things that are beneficial,
zoos or something good.
And then at a certain point, he turned, you see, but the world doesn't know that he
turned.
The world sees him the same as they always saw him.
See?
So, Napoleon crowned himself emperor, put himself above the church.
The pope always crowned the emperor.
Now, Napoleon crowned himself as emperor.
When he did, his calibrated level of consciousness dropped because he was usurping what was understood
as a right that emanated from God and he took on that godness himself.
You know, Hitler made the same mistake, see?
So megalomania.
So, having great power, you know.
Power corrupts absolutely.
That's why even somebody like Mohammed, see, once he gets a certain amount of power, unless
you're trained how to handle that power, it takes you over.
It takes you over.
So, that's why everyone needs a very advanced spiritual teacher as they move along.
You need to understand not in the person of the teacher but in some teaching, what is
the pitfall?
Each level has its upside.
Each level has its downside.
So, I think that's the question.
Thank you.
The intellect, then, is a great and wondrous gift.
It also has a downside in that it also has its own limitations.
So each level has its upside and its downside.
To think it's mankind's salvation, it's also its downfall, its pitfall.
Yeah.
I have a question.
Yes.
I just wanted to thank you.
Okay.
Thank you for thanking me.
Thank you too, Susan.
Thank you for, thank you for, thank you.
Thank you.
The opportunity.
Yes.
No questions.
Unless you just wanna tap out an anapestic beat for me real quick?
I keep hearing how negative the anapestic beat is and I look on all these websites and
they never give us an audio example.
So is it like da-da-da-da-da-da-da-da?
Does anybody know a song that has a beat?
I'm just curious.
That's all I wanna know.
Anapestic, you know, it's supposed to be bad with kinesiology.
I'm just curious.
it's supposed to be bad with kinesiology oh the anaphystic beat yeah just what does it sound like
oh that's a beat that makes you go weak right
makes you go weak there's an acoustic beat that beat in music will make you go weak
the anaphystic beat the the pulse of that sound will make you go weak with it
with kinesiology it's inherent in certain music it's inherent in uh what's it out of detroit
sound or what do you call it huh no not rap motown first it first emerged in motown certain
music started making people go weak with kinesiology even though the music aesthetically
was pleasing i just heard about you about a week ago and i hear many good things about you have
many wonderful gifts and i want to ask you a question for my sister uh she was diagnosed
yesterday with five different
um what do you call them modules nodules in her lungs different places of melanoma and she has a
lot of decisions to make you know there's uh treatments in mexico and caribbean there's uh
william center in houston and uh you know if i can act as a vessel and if you can give me any
words of wisdom to take with me to her anything that you might feel that's a picture i don't i
want to think about that but i'm thinking you're right to say that when you say protocol
what you consider correct or incorrect if that's even in your world i see what i see
all right so there is no advantage to going outside the united states for esoteric treatments
i've not seen any of them pan out to be an advance philippine psychic surgery all those things turn
out to be upon examination be sure to pray for herself and accept whatever the karmic intrinsic
lessons are in all this
that is very frequently a fact I just want to say a few things that this is my
third time here and I think we may be going to Toronto this coming year okay
thank you yeah we're gonna do Toronto Nico where is Nico please it's Nico's
gonna chant for us now Nico do you need this mic you want this mic I'll give it
to Nico this one here you can have this one no you can keep coming up Nico's
gonna start chanting well we're not gonna stop chanting just sign books we
need Nico here we are test you one see if we can bring the Buddha out go ahead
Nico you got it it's all yours
then Mona come on so stop with the thing got over to Mario doho in your
talking your off on my daughter didn't mean that all the way he thought it to
be so long as are you to call you top of the weed I do doing and to do we you go
and go come on to open in the do do do do dig it away to turn your eye hoping
chicken and it means a guy who took a target all right chicken all right in
number 2 okay we keep on saw it and now get off some
mitin you must I told you he's a man it's our whole side or I know Joe Joe
for medical days all gone in you know that got to then tell you to do your
country Maria mo amita or both either now do these are useful to both either
though is our God both are out to die together you know me see how you ever do
you with a night of golden dog how do you know how no that's all no that's all
no they die no day we get out there's a no day and no day and no day gone all
day all night on my Google don't know that's all no day so no day I know they
Ricky no they don't know they know they I know they got no they all know they
I'm not good y'all don't know they don't know they don't know they don't know they
Ricky no they I know they know they I know they got no they all know they home
I could go home building a yo-yo that do you and I sure look at you got to go
buddy I'll go go go go Mario you get in Monica die I'll talk it all that book
okay but you walk it over on your own with the door near I'm ready I'll call
it I'll do that go hoping and they are needed to form without out of duty that
bomb
oh god oh oh oh hey he's holding the liquid out and now to the other we got
any book and you can come into the Google you're already getting guide and
money dog at the garden the dog is in the kitty kitty key ain't no no need in
your camera before they took it in me all they got good to go good you're
doing all you got you told all that you for me to a whole very call can all
matter for me to go to the cookout in your dog a boy doing the tomorrow I'll
not all for my day turning I'm in the dog and I'll do that what did I all go
can't go for you again
menu and I don't get a 0 and I'm going while you do it it's a bird in the
lucky that they don't know okay and I'll go there you're getting all those are
you doubt through the king of the night I don't know they got it all I want to
end I'll show my man that I'll take you through to all are gone would you talk
about you don't tell you how you look at those things I couldn't go though the
cookie woman not okay I'm a good at with other for Kenny to get out and off
okay no no they used to do man I do that to the way I could go in and go big off
Thank you for watching.
If I can still walk, we'll close up just at 4 o'clock.
Yes, we will sign the remaining books.
We've got two minutes.
I'm from Maui, and when we spin with the whales and the dolphins,
we feel the way we feel when we chance and when you speak,
and I don't understand it, but thank you so much.
Thank you.
No question it means you've heard me, huh?
Mm-hmm.
You've heard me, there's no question it's love.
Thank you, sweetheart.
I know, I know.
Okay, so, then love for our fellow man.
We will be out of here at the requested time of 4 o'clock,
just as we started at the requested time of 9 o'clock,
out of love for our fellow humans,
that we respect their time,
the personages of their time,
you understand?
So, that love takes many expressions.
Not only cleaning up the trash on the street,
but being on time because everybody makes an effort to be here,
and therefore our obligation out of love
is to respect that effort on your part.
So, you see how the mutual recognition
springs forth of its own nature, yeah?
And therefore, I'm very blessed to have been here with you this year,
in this place.
I thank the Radisson.
It's been very gracious to us.
They provided a very beautiful venue,
wonderful lunches, etc.
And plenty of parking space.
They were thankful for them for providing for us
such a wondrous place,
and this wonderful holiday decorations,
nameless holiday decorations.
And I thank you all for being with us.
Those of you who wish,
I guess have already gotten the brochure
of the next year's lectures.
We're doing them in Sedona.
We're doing them every two months.
And the reason we only do them every two months
instead of monthly is because we do a lot of traveling now.
So, at least once or twice a month,
we travel someplace in the country
and address pretty sizable audiences.
And so, that is a privilege as well.
So, we spend a lot of time on the road now,
and therefore, we cut down to every two months.
But this is the old home group, you know?
.
Like your home boy scout troop, you know what I mean?
Your own grade school class.
So, we have a certain feeling of family about each other already,
you know, certain family, feeling of family.
And I'm sure comically, you know, if we saw the sweep of it all,
I'm sure we sweep in and out as a family.
And we have done so many times, you know.
So, I thank you very much.
I thank you for being here.
I thank you for all your love.
And I'm very grateful for it now and forever. Amen.
They're wonderful audiences.
How could you help?
Just be the state of joy, because we're here basically.