requested and a great deal of enthusiasm for Nico's chant so we're going to
resume the program Nico's going to chant at the end of which he will come up and
and we'll greet them and answer questions sign books and whatever else
you'd like then to jig oh everybody just relax into this you can close your eyes
open your eyes or open your heart or the last thing I want you to do is try and
understand it understanding is the booby prize in this exercise
we do not need to go to the we do we do we need to do he you go and I'll come
over and I'll do the roadie so they can do it again your I hope a chicken and
it's a guy who took it out of your door I didn't go right in I'm not the only
okay we could both always and okay that's a
mighty new mode I told you he's I mean I'll tell you the door I know so to form
and I got a dog I mean you know Nick I do then that is to do you can't be
mario mo and me though oh boy did I do these are useful to boot it at all he's
a couple
all out argue die to gay own longer see how yo what do you all tonight recording
so What Did Joe Do and I Love You
Thank you.
Oh, there's a wire holding it. Look out. There we go.
Oh, yes, I hadn't thought about it.
Please consider it.
Yeah, okay, we're all fine. We're fine.
So now we just want people to come up and say hi,
and we're going to answer any questions anyone might have.
We're going to share the answers with the audience.
Hi.
I think you said that our decisions influence our karma,
and our spiritual will also,
our intention and spiritual will also set our karma.
Where does this,
who or what,
what is the spiritual will?
I mean, where does it come from?
Who makes the decision as to what it's going to be?
Innate, within one's karmic inheritance.
See, this is, I look at it as a purgatorial existence.
Why?
Because everybody who comes here is obviously not in a celestial realm,
and it's the maximum opportunity for maximum karmic benefit.
Why?
Because one is provided with infinite choices,
and we're going to need you.
So you need to be nearby, better be sure.
Okay.
This is the ultimate,
I, you know, the Buddha said,
one is greatly fortunate to be born a human.
And then he laments the price of being a human,
sickness, old age, and death.
But fortunate one is.
Why is one fortunate?
If this, if the ego is going to lead you into sickness, sadness, poverty, and death, etc.
So the great good fortune, karmically, that I see, being born as a human,
is that this is the world of probably maximum karmic benefit.
He says, that is correct, he says.
You see, the knowingness is correct.
First I get the answer, then I ask the question.
It's a world of maximum opportunity and benefit.
To succeed spiritually, this is the perfect setting.
So people who want to change the world,
I say, good luck.
Because then you would have to create another world exactly like this,
where you are provided with maximum temptation on either side,
maximum payoff on either side.
We all walk forward into the next instant completely blind.
You realize people don't know where they came from.
They don't know who they are.
They don't know where they're going.
They don't know what their ultimate fate is.
They don't even know what's deciding the fate.
That's long term.
Short term, they haven't the slightest idea what's going to happen in the next instant.
So with blinders on, with earplugs in,
totally blind, unknowing and stupid,
you walk straight ahead into the storm.
Wow, I think there's great karmic merit just to choose the life of a human.
And if I was St. Peter, I would give anybody who's been here a pass.
Pass.
You live the life of a human, did the best you could,
what more do you want?
There are other realms, celestial realms, other astral realms, other dimensions.
This one is for maximum spiritual opportunity.
Here the provocation is intense and constant.
You're not going to be able to escape.
There's no way to escape it.
The barrage of communication is incessant around the clock.
So this is like a hotbed.
This is where...
the burner is turned up in spiritual evolution.
And great advances are made here.
Don't forget, entities can spin eons
at a specific level in other dimensions.
Eons.
That is correct.
Eons in other dimensions.
And here, in a short term,
we saw just what happened during the recent war, saving that private...
What's her name?
Jessica Lynch.
Somebody commented, you know,
did you jump 350 points just from one decision?
In other dimensions, you don't have an opportunity to do that.
No such choices are possible.
Or your understanding is so fixated, you don't see that as a possibility.
You understand?
So the great reward, I think, of putting up with the pain of human life,
the pain of human life, the fear of it, the guilt, all that goes with it,
is the enormous spiritual benefit to be gained here.
Which is not really available elsewhere.
Also evolutionary-wise, the reason it's so optimal
is because we are right at the link between the animal and the angel.
You know?
We inherit the instincts of the animal
and the knowingness of spiritual reality.
And now,
We've got the animal nipping at our heels, and hellfire scaring us from the future.
It's quite a task.
So I think only those who are spiritually courageous are here, courageous.
Let's ask that, I've never asked this before.
Only those who are spiritually courageous are here, he says.
Only those who are spiritually courageous are here to face the pain of not knowing this
from moment to moment, not knowing who you are, karmically you're cut off from your past
memory up to consciousness level 600, you don't even remember that you were before.
That's quite a commitment.
So I'm proud and honored to meet you, another human being who has taken such a vow to do
the best you can.
Thank you.
Hi, Dr. Higgins.
Hi.
I think my question connects with the last gentleman's.
The question has to do with the value of suffering, and in literature there's what's referred
to as the dark night of the soul.
I'm wondering, is that a necessity for giving up the personal self, and if so, at what level
does that occur?
Well, it can be looked at in a number of ways.
Advanced spiritual states tend to come and then disappear in the beginning.
Satori, you know.
One can be meditating.
These states sometimes begin to occur when you seriously meditate, and the state, sort
of a satori, will remain so long as you sit still with your eyes closed.
But when you start to move and open your eyes, the state disappears.
That's disappointing.
What have I done wrong, oh Lord?
You know.
At that point you're not thinking about God because God is your God.
You're not thinking about God.
God is just another word, and you've dismissed that as well.
Anyway, the dark night of the soul also comes from when one begins to look within oneself
at the shadow side, and if you haven't looked at the shadow side, it will.
You will, because as soon as you look at love, it brings up non-love, and a greater awareness
of that which is interfering.
I think the great night of the soul, as it's written up in classic Christian literature,
means one goes into a divine state, and then the divine state disappears, and one crashes
back to the ordinary state of consciousness.
How hast thou deserted me, O my beloved?
The bridegroom has left me.
In the things to prepare for, which I addressed earlier this afternoon, I should have added
that one.
That the state may come.
In the beginning, it will come.
And then disappear.
Another way of explaining it is you've used up all your good karma.
You've transcended your garbage.
You've transcended your garbage, and now your garbage is catching up with you again.
Anyway, the states tend to become longer and longer, and then eventually you reach a state
where the satori, the advanced state of consciousness, exists even if you get up and walk around
with your eyes open.
Yeah?
That's right.
All those have various names in Sanskrit, and they're classically known in Hindu spiritual
literature.
The thing is not to worry about it.
The fact that it came at all is indicative of the future.
All you saw was what the future holds for you, and that should increase one's spiritual
commitment rather than discourage one.
It doesn't really stay in the beginning.
It doesn't stay in the beginning.
Very infrequently.
Yeah.
It doesn't go from just ordinariness into a profound state, period.
More commonly, it's advanced states.
Even the Buddha didn't go from nothing from ordinary into a permanent advanced state.
Those who have had a lot of experience experience.
The states come and go, and not to worry about the fact that they come and go.
What you do see is like an advanced assurance that that is your destination.
Yeah.
It may only come in a few seconds of an inner illumination, but the quality of that inner
illumination is very, very distinct and unforgettable, even if it lasts a few seconds.
That's like a preview of what's to come, and one just continues on the pathway no matter
what.
You surrender everything to God, including that.
Now, if that happened on the subway to Brooklyn, the tendency is to catch the same train, and
it's not going to happen again.
Yeah.
It's the same train, the same station, and you can't recreate it.
Everybody's had those advances and has done it.
Everybody here laughs because everybody's done it.
You're on the Ferris wheel, and suddenly you saw God, and now you go back on the Ferris
wheel over and over, and it's sad, it's sad.
But the heart's longing for the return of that, and you make that subserve your overall
spiritual purpose.
Yes?
Yeah.
It's a natural thing.
Not a bad thing.
Yeah.
Just like severe downs will come, but they don't stay either.
Sooner or later, the court will bounce back up.
Move over.
What do you want me to do?
I want you to slide with your leg over there.
What?
The body over there?
Yes.
Move the body.
Okay.
Well?
Fuzzy wuzzy, that's what they call my body.
It looks like a teddy bear.
I just hug him.
I need a name for mine, too.
Yeah.
What's up?
I, in reading your book I, and you were talking about surrendering, letting go of entire belief
systems at once, surrendering belief systems, and then you had that sentence.
You said, I can't decide whether to commit suicide today or go to a movie.
And it's just, it struck me that that's my whole life.
That's what I'm...
I try to be funny.
Nobody ever laughs.
laughs but when I'm not trying to be funny. I mean that's the extremes of the
ego, the extremes. I mean that's what I'm doing every day with my belief systems
that I think I have to have, why I have to feel bad. Oh. And so it's like every
day I'm committing mental and emotional suicide and not choosing that as opposed
to. How does one get rid of that faster? Get what? Rid of the feeling bad? Of
continuing to choose those belief systems that are self-destructive.
Because of the payoff we get out of it. Everything that we cling to, we're not
clinging to the thing itself. We're clinging to the payoff of it. Like people
are not addicted to drugs. What they're addicted to is the sense of euphoria.
Yeah.
The addiction is to euphoria. The addiction to things that are negative is
because of the payoff we get out of them. The hardest one is being victim, being
martyr, being right. Each one of those has a payoff. So the question is not, am I
willing to give up being right? Or am I willing to give up being the martyr? The
question is, am I willing to get to surrender to God the payoff I get out of
that?
Reason will tell you.
That you should. But the willingness is something deeper. The willingness to
surrender to everything, everything to God, even the pain of being the victim
and being wronged, etc. Sooner or later, you have to let it go. I had people ask me
questions a couple months ago someplace. She was asking me about something that, you
know, is over already 20 years ago. But I can tell she's clinging to it, still trying
to juice it.
Trying to juice some kind of an injustice, you see. And I said, haven't you noticed that
what you're talking about is already at the top of every single aspect of humans, of
society? The old days of being the downtrodden minority, forget it. You've
juiced it. So sooner or later, you've got to give up the juicing of it, of having been
wronged, whatever it may be. Being dumb and ugly, you know what I mean? You've got to quit juicing it.
As unconsciously, we get satisfaction. And that satisfaction is where you've got to be willing to go.
So it's always the same thing. It isn't multiple things you have to let go of. It's only one
thing, that one is deriving satisfaction out of that positionality. Positionality being
wrong, being slighted, being overlooked, being the victim of injustice, etc. It's always
satisfaction that your ego gets out of it see the ego doesn't live on love like
the spirit does it it extracts emotions and lives off the energy of those
emotions doesn't have its own emotion it has to extract it human life yeah I'm
gonna teach a course starting in January at the servant leadership school in
Washington on the nature of divine power and I plan to use this book and there's
a couple issues there in terms of I obviously don't have the same kind of
understanding about this that you do should I be doing this at all and if so
how should I prepare since it's sort of a left brain activity to be teaching and
we're trying to move towards right brain do I make detailed outlines or do I
meditate a lot before I go in? The power of leadership is that what you're talking about?
The servant leadership school in Washington has a department of divine
power and I'm going to be teaching their course
Yeah
on the
Yeah.
divine power well let's see you have to take fortune magazine and calibrate all
the all the businesses in it you'll find that some come out extremely high and
many of them are right on the border and some are below those that calibrate high
are the most successful in the world yeah leadership by example leadership by
example you see we talked today about high energy well I corresponded with Sam
the reason I use Sam Wallings I correspond with him
and I've watched the calibration of Walmart over the years you know it was a
man of enormous energy he said as your spiritual energy comes up you have
enormous energy you have enormous energy enormous goingness which the world
considered ambition but it wasn't ambition it was fulfilling the gift that
he had and he was probably the world's best retailer the best retailer the world's
ever seen that was his gift so he just did that 24 hours a day seven days a week because that's what
he was and that's what he did so he would he was trying to set an example and show by
example the leadership in the business world of what he understood as integrity and at
the time it was around 385 see fairness etc etc of course it gets vilified in the meantime
the reason is anything that's successful in this world gets vilified see if you carve the
pie does some admin will come along and try and blow it up you create the biggest
Buddha in the world somebody will blow it up people hate the successful so we
envy success and we hate it and seek to destroy it it depends on what you mean by
leadership you mean specific leadership you mean by example by inspiration to me
leadership is the one who inspires and by their inspiration recontextualize is
the entire enterprise and uplifts
everyone where your chief of staff you're the function you serve is the focus of the
energy of the commitment to the cause like Winston Churchill did at 510 he really focused
the spiritual energy of the entire populace and you imagine bombs going off seven days a
week around the clock month after month all night long bombs going off around you
and how do you keep up the spirits of the people who've run out of food electricity water and
everything else and are being bombed around the clock you certainly can't do it through reason
you can't do it through reason no through the heart of the lion which he represents the heart
of the lion at 5 10. by our God we will not give up to the the Bulldog grip on his cigar
God bless him he smoked we won't miss it
by the various aspects of leadership or multitude in this
thing these people are peace and justice people and they wouldn't want to hear
about business people being powerful and so what I'm hoping to do this to
recontextualize that a little bit but I guess you're giving me the answer they
integrities i think the full column is integrity and when we went over 190 to
207 the Passover was an integrity and you see since we went from 90 to 207 you
You see that which is non-integrity falling left and right.
Heads of all the CEOs of the big corporations, all the banks, last week's fortune was all
the banks involved in the deception, et cetera.
You see that integrity is the new paradigm of success.
Profit, anybody can make profit, you know, anybody who owned a little bit of stock became
a millionaire, a paper millionaire, and they lost it in an instant.
So I think the new paradigm of success and true leadership is integrity.
Integrity to your company, to your fellow worker, to yourself, to the job description.
And if you're not willing to do that, then I wouldn't commit to this job or this company
or this position, you know?
That would work for being committed to the poor as well?
The poor?
That's what these people would be interested in.
Oh, they're going to be for the poor.
Yeah, they're going to be for the poor.
All right.
How do they be for the poor?
Well, that means they will...
That organization will survive for many centuries, because the poor are always with us.
The reason is, if you list the income of everybody in the United States, you take the bottom
10%, you got the poor.
Then at the income base shifts up here, you take the bottom 10%, you got the poor.
So you've always got the poor, because the poor is the perception you project out there.
They don't know what the poor is.
They think the poor are people without money and assets.
You're right.
Poor is the level of consciousness.
It's the bottom there.
Mm-hmm.
I can tell you who's poor and why they're poor if I'm really walking through the neighborhood.
I can tell you within an instant.
I don't care who lives there.
Just show me the sidewalks, and I'll tell you what they're like.
The people here are poor.
There's crap all over the street, dog poo, garbage, newspaper.
They say, well, they don't get the right education.
No, that's not at all.
The field, the field, the broken window, the broken window theory explains it.
The field is down, and everything that comes into the field is attractive.
The downness of the field is attracted by the downness of the field, and the behaviors
within that field are one of abuse of children, abuse of responsibility, drugs, addiction,
crime, devastation, inconsideration for others, rudeness, confrontationalism.
The raising of the level of consciousness, then, is what you can do for the poor.
Giving them money makes them worse.
Well, I think you just made my job harder.
Giving people poor, the poor, money makes them worse.
Yeah.
It makes them worse.
They saw that in Haiti.
The more money a poor poured into Haiti, the worse it got.
It's because that is not the cause.
That is the consequence.
So that's mixing up cause and effect, see?
Poverty is the consequence of a certain level of consciousness which is non-integrous, which
only thinks in terms of me and goes out of the solar plexus animal-wise.
When you're in a low-level neighborhood, you're in the world of animals, and animal instinct
is how you survive it.
You can walk down 10th Avenue at 1 o'clock in the morning.
If you can't tell by the footstep behind you what's about to happen to you, you won't survive
there.
And if you live in New York long enough, you get antenna.
1 o'clock in the morning, I can tell by the footstep of what's across the street what
it is across the street.
And I know from the footstep to cross over and go this way.
That's why I live to tell the tale.
See?
You live by animal instinct, not by intelligence, not by education.
Your animal instinct is what tells you whether this elevator is safe to take or not, whether
this floor is safe to get off.
The door opens.
You see what's out there.
Waldorf is starting at 4 in the morning, and you push the elevator, you know?
The door opens, and here's six big guys looking at me like...
And I looked at them and I went...
And we all laughed.
We all laughed.
I saw what they were, they saw that I saw what they were, and it was all okay with us.
It's okay with me if you want to mug people.
I mean, I'm not a moralist, you see?
It's just that I don't want to be the one you do tonight.
They were 6'6", and I was 5'5", so there was no contest.
It was okay with me if they won.
They intimidated me, which is fine.
I said, I am intimidated.
Why?
So, in terms of what I tell these people, making this little haven, maybe, in the middle
of this neighborhood of animals is some contribution where people can at least...
It's a spiritual energy of integrity, of caringness.
The caringness is you care how it looks.
You care that it's neat.
You care that it's provided for.
You care that there's not excessive noise.
You care...
It's a caringness about the whole culture.
So, that caring...
That caringness is really the message.
That caringness is where the leader comes in.
Exhibits caringness about others.
And then it may ignite or may not ignite.
With that, you can't do it for the effect.
You have to do it because that's what you are.
So, the person goes into a community like that because of what they are.
They do what they do.
Not in order to cause an effect.
That seeing yourself as cause and effect.
No, it's what you are that radiates out.
So, you become that.
You become that which you wish others to become like and you do that by being that
yourself because that's what you are where you radiate that energy into the neighborhood
and the energy is of those around you pick it up.
So, to the extent it works, that's what's working.
It's not...
That's working is the field.
Right.
The field.
Yeah.
Can't think of it in terms of cause and effect.
Give poor people money and they make them worse.
Yeah.
Okay.
I noticed that in the Navy when I was 17 and people would shoot craps on payday.
Yeah.
By the following week, the same guys were broke every week.
Same guys, always broke.
It wasn't just chance.
It's who they were.
Yeah.
Okay.
Good luck.
Thanks.
Leadership.
Oh.
Boy.
The world of infinite karmic opportunity.
Yeah.
Teach a leadership class.
What?
I keep losing you in the camera.
Yeah.
You're losing me in the camera.
There you go.
Good.
I was told to sit between these two pieces of tape.
Thank you.
Go ahead.
What's on your mind?
I work with a lot of suicidal people.
What?
Yes.
And despite medications, they still tend to have a lot of suicidal thoughts and feelings.
What is the best position that I can take in that job to assist?
Assist?
Yeah.
Just no therebyу
Notxtures?
Just what?
Help them commit suicide?
No.
Legally, I can't do that.
Well, I want to know why you haven't committed suicide so far.
Make them argument.
Why haven't you committed suicide?
I mean, are you stupid or what?
Are you weak?
Most of them have tried.
Numerous times.
Yeah.
Not succeeded.
No, they haven't, because they've been dead.
You see?
Yeah.
So they left themselves an opening.
It's a psychiatric problem to begin with and then spiritually each one is different.
Spiritually, each one is different, and you can't really answer it generically.
What's the answer to suicide? It's so multifaceted.
A shocking confrontational approach, which you have to have a lot of self-confidence to do,
will get them past a certain point.
I wouldn't do it unless you have 50 years in psychiatry.
If you're going to kill yourself, well, do it, damn it, do it.
Don't just stand there trying to, you know.
So, how come you're still breathing?
If you want to commit suicide, you'd be dead.
No, part of you doesn't want suicide, and that's the part you work from.
The one that has hope is the hope realistic, and you try to build on the hope.
But are they not in a place of apathy, like on the chart, down around 50 or something?
If they're apathetic, they won't kill themselves.
They're better to kill themselves.
That's the paradox.
You know, Prozac people commit suicide, or Paxil people commit suicide.
They were in apathetic depression.
Now you energize them, and they've got more energy.
Now they've got the energy to kill themselves.
That's a fact.
Because they're on all these medications, and it doesn't really seem to do any good.
It doesn't change anything.
You have to intuit, I think, the answer.
In this case, it's unique.
I think I would follow my spiritual intuition with each one and ask God,
what should I reflect back to this person?
Is there an opening for me with this person?
I think it's a very intuitive job.
There's no way you could design that left brain and do this, do that.
It's an intuitive job, I would say, very intuitive,
in which your caringness for the person opens the intuition,
and you see in what space to intervene.
You like the courage to kill yourself?
I'll do it for you.
You've got to have the spontaneous knowingness that I've had with, see?
I'm willing to do that, grab them by the neck and tell them,
if you're not willing to kill yourself, die, I'll help you.
No, I want to live.
You want to what?
You want to live.
I mean, you see, but I have the self-assurance of a great deal of clinical experience.
But I would come from some kind of an intuitive, intuitive.
Of course, the agency you work for wants it left brain and linear, typewritten.
I don't think you can treat suicidal people and do that.
Frankly, I don't think the job is a possibility, but good luck.
Well, and I think that's part of the problem I have,
is that I contract with agencies, and they're coming from a totally different place,
and so it makes it difficult trying to find the inroads.
It may not be possible to do that.
I don't know.
It may be an impossible task.
Frankly, I wouldn't want to do it.
I don't want to treat suicidal people and have my hands bound.
I want free reign or go elsewhere,
because I want the free reign to do the kind of thing
I just did with you, because that's spontaneous, intuitive.
And the direction is coming from a knowingness that knows what's going on there,
because my intellect doesn't know what's going on there.
It can only describe it, but it doesn't really know it.
Knowingness is being it, and only omniscience is it.
So listening to the spiritual awareness from within
is listening to the omniscience, which is already within this one psyche,
communicating what's going on to my knowingness.
But it's bypassing the intellect and the left brain altogether.
That's why it's a very intuitive position.
I wouldn't try it unless they gave you free reign.
I wouldn't take the risk of downside of people's lives without free reign.
No way.
I'm not going to steer the ship and then have them tell me
I can only turn so many degrees this way and so many degrees that way
because it's cheaper gas.
F you and your company.
You know what I mean?
I'm going to turn this ship the way I want it,
because this is my typhoon and I'm going to drive it through.
Or you get somebody else at the wheel.
Why?
I don't want 18 lives on my soul.
You know what I'm saying?
I'm going to take the risk.
If they want you to take that kind of responsibility,
then we're going to give you that kind of liberty.
Otherwise, I wouldn't take it.
Am I saying that in public to people?
That's the truth.
I wouldn't take a job like that.
Let's just say, look, you give me free reign or it's no game.
All right.
I'm going to tie your hands and then tell you what's what.
Today is 11-1-0-3.
Oh, my God.
I just have one question.
Does the field ever encounter resistance?
The ego is one in this resistance machine,
because it would see spiritual evolution
as its eventual being voted out of office.
And it's not willing to give up its sovereignty.
So, yes, the ego is quite resistant,
even when there's excruciating pain.
As she said, the person who is suicidal
because they're holding on to certain positionalities.
Holding on to that positionality is more important to them
than the physical life.
Rather than give up that positionality,
they will actually kill themselves.
And that's a rugged opponent.
So, without a free hand, I don't think she ought to tackle himself.
Yeah, that answered my question.
I don't know if that was the answer, too.
You know what?
That's all right.
I love you, without a question.
I did want to thank you for today.
Huh?
I wanted to thank you for today.
Oh, thank you for thanking me for today.
Yeah.
You talked about the resistance of the ego
to spiritual progress and how it reacts.
I wonder if you would comment in a moment
about whether you see a collective reaction
of the egoic human mind
to the advancement of spirituality.
Do you see a process of consciousness within humanity?
Are we seeing a backlash of the collective insanity
to some of the advancement,
or is it just the evolutionary process at work?
I think it's the normal ebb and flow
of the evolution of consciousness, you see,
which reflects the karmic inheritance of mankind,
mankind,
plus ethnic groups and collective spiritual groups,
individual interfacing with a preexistent civilization.
When we got here, there was already society here
and a prevailing level of consciousness.
The only thing we're going to influence, I think,
is the field,
and the field is going to lift people up.
As you add salt to water,
every ship floats higher in the ocean,
but you're not pushing any one boat.
You're not pushing any one boat.
But as we add...
So what happens is the buoyancy begins to lift people.
So people around you that are integrists
make it more difficult to be non-integrists.
You start apologizing for things
that you wouldn't have done before.
You take your feet off the furniture and say,
Oh, sorry.
Before that, you just was Mr. Slovenly,
you know what I mean?
Mud on the shoes and the shoes on the table.
Who cares?
You see people live that way.
They take the beer cans, throw them out the window.
The beer cans are all down below.
A few integrist people begins to shift the balance,
and people start saying,
Excuse me?
What? Excuse me?
They haven't been sitting around here for 23 1⁄2 years.
Excuse me?
So we begin to transform it by transforming ourself.
And then we help to uplift others by doing that.
Yeah.
Thanks.
Yes.
Hi.
I think you're the right way to ask.
I'm finding it increasingly difficult
to be with people who I'm uncomfortable.
I guess my question is,
how do you walk the line out there
in staying in integrity,
doing the work, doing the practice, doing whatever,
and still maintaining relationships
or should I not be responsible
because sometimes you don't have a choice
to maintain these relationships
with those people who are not in integrity?
Thank you.
Well, your own priorities begin to take over the field.
And as you evolve,
you'll find certain environments are no longer
where you feel comfortable at all.
Right.
And characteristically,
a lot of people leave the big city
and head for rural areas.
Classically, they move up in elevation.
You go from the city to the country,
then you move to a higher elevation.
I don't know why that is,
but there is a certain tendency to do that.
So certain relationships will no longer be tolerable
and you'll have to say goodbye to certain people
in certain environments.
I mean, I had to say goodbye to certain jobs
when I was young.
I wasn't enlightened,
but I found the lack of integrity
created a constant sense of guilt.
Yes.
And the rationale was,
well, this was a crooked scheme.
This one's just like it on TV right now.
And the idea was,
well, if you don't get their money,
somebody else will.
That was the rationalization.
Yeah, I said,
go to the old farmer.
You know, if you empty this peanut butter machine,
peanut machine,
you just drive around,
you empty the money.
Wow.
You see the farmer looking up.
He's going to take his money out of the sock
from under the mattress
and invest in these peanut machines.
But you don't tell him
it's empty once a year,
not once a week.
You see it on TV.
The ATM machine,
you just go there
and take out your money
at 25 cents a minute.
Now, you figure it out.
25 cents a minute,
how much is that an hour?
On your investment,
you just go around
and take out the money.
That was the pitch
I walked away from
when I was 17 years old.
In those days,
they called it
peanut vending machines.
You just go around
and collect your money.
Even at 25 cents a minute,
you figure out
how much is that an hour.
You'll see,
it's already stricken
in no time.
As you go on,
you become increasingly
introspective
and being out there
in the world
with some people
becomes increasingly
undesirable.
Yes, you'll end up
making changes.
Or people around you
will make changes.
You say,
Dorothy,
you don't seem to be
all there anymore.
That's right.
We're going to have
to replace you.
Thank you.
You can't be
a blackjack dealer
and be doing a mantra
at the same time.
Keep track of every
card displayed.
If you're a card shark,
you're not.
Card shark days
are over, I guess.
I was wondering
if you could speak
about the phase
where we get the cities.
I wondered if,
in your experience,
that's something that passes
or it's just another
phase of growth
or if the cities
stay with you
when you continue.
It's a concomitant
in certain levels
of consciousness.
It comes and goes
of its own.
Not only does it come
but eventually it'll leave.
Once ego can get involved
in it and glamorize it
and commercialize it,
and some entities
have done that
for many lifetimes.
A lot of the entities
that you play with,
that's why I say
don't play with
new age games
because they've been
at it a long, long time.
You're just a beginner.
They read you like a,
they just read you
like that.
Oh, I see
your grandmother's arthritis.
Oh, how'd they know that?
How'd they know
my grandmother had arthritis?
Oh, Mr. Baba
on the other side
says,
and I think
you should do,
you know what I mean?
It's all so mysterious
and entrancing
and it sucks
one in,
you see?
But even when
the capacity
is genuine,
it fluctuates.
It fluctuates.
And it's a trap
for the ego.
So a person
who's headed
for enlightenment
bypasses it
as a,
you know,
first of all,
it's quite impressive
and it's quite real
and it's literally so.
So that boggles
you right there.
You know,
the scripture says
the supernatural
doesn't deny,
die and deny.
It says just
don't go there.
It doesn't say
that it isn't so,
that it doesn't work.
There are psychics
you can walk in
and they'll give you
a reading like
they'll blister
your hair
and the back
of your head.
Then you go
to the next psychic
and they already
on the other level
got a reading
about you
reading about
the reading.
That's very impressive.
It's impressive
when you're coming
from left brain
that there's
some other reality
other than the Newtonian
paradigm.
That's what's impressive.
That there's
another reality
other than
the Newtonian
paradigm.
Therefore,
the naive person
thinks all that
psychism
and occult
is spiritual.
It is not.
It is occult.
People have had
those gifts
for years
that are not at all
spiritual.
In fact,
my question
was specifically
on the gift
of healing
that comes through
that the field
uses vessels
to come through.
In that case,
is that something
that passes as well?
It may or may not.
It happens occasionally.
It comes about
as a result
of the energy
and the person's karma.
During that phase
of the cities,
it was very strong
and frequent.
It's like
that energy
pulled it
to it.
The miraculous
was commonplace,
continuous,
almost every day
and every day.
It was part
of that phase
of evolution,
part of that phase
of evolution
of consciousness.
Whether it does it
or doesn't
is irrelevant.
As you
witness it
happening,
you say,
oh,
I see
why that person
was brought
to see me.
You witness
that
it's just
the miraculous.
This side
of the brain
begins to function
again on the person.
But it's got
nothing to do
with you.
There's no volition
on one's part.
One doesn't intend it.
It happens
spontaneously.
When the apple's
ready to fall
from the tree,
with the right wind
it falls.
See?
So it has
nothing to do
with choice,
with a spiritual choice then?
No,
not on the part
of the spiritually
evolved person.
It's a result
that had been
made by the person
who was ill
that now may have
undone so much
negative karma
that all they need
is some positive
energy and
the recovery
will take place.
Because one sees
recovery from
every illness
that walks
the planet.
Multiple sclerosis,
all kinds of cancer,
all kinds of
diseases
and illness.
Thank you.
Except old age.
I don't know
what they're called.
Time marches
on.
People do not
know.
Oh yeah.
There,
that's a
wonderful
looking book.
Wow.
I have trouble
with the ego.
It seems
to me that
the reason
I'm here
is because
of my ego.
Because I want
to get better.
Because something
is driving me.
There's an aspect
of the ego
called spiritual
ego.
In other words,
the ego,
which is intelligence,
now discovers
that there's
another domain,
gets excited
about spirituality
and pulls us
into it.
Pulls us
So it's very
valuable
in that aspect
of curiosity,
wanting to know.
So it's
the evolution
of consciousness
pulling your
interest
in that direction.
So it's
demeaning
to just call it
ego.
It's not just
It's spiritual
endeavor
and curiosity
and inclination
because one
is pulled
by one's future
and not just
propelled
by one's past.
The cause
and effect,
the Newtonian
paradigm reality
thinks that
what you are
now is a
consequence
of your past.
So your past
then becomes
the cause
and you're
the effect.
That's the
Newtonian
paradigm.
Now,
the field
and where
you are
in the field.
So one's
going to
go
in a
spiritual
direction.
You've
microwatched
your little
iron filing
and now the
magnet is
pulling you
in this
direction,
see?
It's automatic.
You can say,
no,
I won't
go in a
spiritual
direction.
No,
no,
no.
So I want
to thank
you again
for everything
that you've
taught us
about the
quantum
mechanics.
String theory
seems to be
something new
that's untested
because they
can't really
reduce it
to a
provable
theory.
But then I
can read
spiritual
things like
the Lotus
Sutra,
for example.
It seems
like there's
some of
those same
ideas
have been
talked about
for
a long
time.
And I think
that's
a good
example of
how
consciousness
went before
to 207.
Isn't it
now about
time to
do that
again?
I don't
know.
There's
more enlightened
people now
than there
were 10
years ago.
That's
true.
Consciousness
is a
continuous
track
from the
Newtonian
paradigm
directly
into advanced
spiritual
awareness.
There is a
continuous
track and
evolution
of understanding.
The big
jump is
from the
linear to
the non-linear.
That's
the big
jump at
499 to
500.
To see
that reality
is
subjectivity.
Knowledge is
from the
pseudo
objective
to
radical
subjectivity
is quite
a paradigm
jump.
Einstein
didn't
make it.
Young
did.
was
520.
Young
made the
jump.
I think
the facility
to make
the jump
would be
also
influenced
by the
people
in the
world.
I think
that opens
that door
for you.
If the
people in
your life
were skeptical
and cynical
that tends
to hold
you back.
On the
other hand
karmically
that's
where you
brought
yourself
with
cynical
atheistic
people.
One of
the purposes
of the
work
is to
understand
when
you
want to
go
left
brain
with
it.
Do
you want
me
to go
left
brain
with
it?
No.
I want
you to
calibrate
it.
String
theory.
We
have
permission
$4.99. Calibrates over $4.99.
S-string theory, matrix theory, calibrates over $4.99.
I would think $4.98, $4.96, $4.97.
It's very high, $4.97, $4.98. It's right on the very edge.
Does the Lotus Sutra, which talks about that same spiritual concept,
wouldn't that really be the essence of that same theory?
I don't know. You'd have to ask the Buddha.
I don't know. It's his sutra. I didn't make up that sutra.
I don't seek scant script.
I appreciate your help. Thanks.
I know what you're asking, though.
There is a continuity, but then there is a leap in faith
where one has to leave the intellect.
One has to desert the intellect, and one mourns that briefly.
One had all one's faith.
The savior of mankind was reason and the intellect.
So you feel a little...
You feel a little guilty abandoning it, you know?
It's a hard jump to make. It's a hard jump to make.
Thank you.
Few people make it, don't forget.
Only 4% of the world's population ever crosses 500.
96% won't make the jump.
Thanks.
Thank you for bringing up that question.
I'll have to look into it later.
Bootstrap theory.
I don't know what he's talking about.
Yes?
Oh, wow, so loud.
It's Matrix Theory.
I just really need to sign the book.
I have like a million of them.
Oh, a million and one questions.
Yes, I don't even know where to start.
I need to sign my book.
I don't think it's the second to answer a million and one questions.
How about a silly question?
Huh?
Did you see the movie Seabiscuit?
Did you see that?
Has anyone seen it in here?
A French version called Seabiscuit.
Seabiscuit?
No.
Did you see Seabiscuit?
No, no, no.
You have to see Seabiscuit.
But I don't have to see it.
Yes.
I have to see it.
You've already seen it.
Yes, he has.
Doesn't he?
Who's seen Seabiscuit in here?
Seabiscuit.
Yes.
Yes, it's so inspiring.
It's beautiful.
It's right brain.
It probably calibrates, what would you guys say, 800?
Oh, it does.
It's wonderful.
Go see it.
He has to see it.
God in his form as horse, right?
Yes.
So that was it.
Thank you.
Yes.
It's a movie that reflects the heart, yeah?
It does.
That's what you're telling me, yeah.
So it's 500 or over.
It's the heart.
I was wondering if you would share with us what or whom you've had as a spiritual mentor in this lifetime.
I don't follow any spiritual tradition.
Many teachers are the fifth reincarnation of so-and-so, you know,
or the legacy.
The legacy of some pathway.
This one comes out of nothing.
The stunning reality came out of nothingness.
Out of nothingness it arose.
In childhood, there was Episcopalianism, but I later became an atheist.
Went to a Jesuit university, during which time I wasn't an atheist.
Went from atheist to agnostic.
As agnostic, I studied some Zen and various, you know, readings and things.
But then went into a different inner state all together.
The inner state led me to Dhani's, what was described by Dhani.
The inner state, the inner drivenness, drove me literally into the very depths of hell.
And the very timelessness, eternal, foreverness of hell.
Well, the voice came out of the spirit, because the mind was an atheist.
If there is a God, I ask him for help.
Then oblivion.
Then the stunning reality of waking to see the divinity of all that exists.
But this lifetime was strange anyway.
It started out at age three.
Out of nothingness, having been a devotee of Hinyana Buddhism,
of the pathway of negation.
Each lifetime went from existence into void.
Non-existence, nothingness.
So there was no connection with the next lifetime.
And then, suddenly in this lifetime, out of nothingness, absolute oblivion, nothingness,
suddenly at age three or four, I was hit like a stunning light.
Suddenly, in the darkness, somebody turns on all the Klee lights with the shock of existence.
Existence as such, the knowingness of existence, no word for it.
Three-year-old has no verbiage, no wording.
This.
For it.
Towards the shock of existence.
From nonexistence to stunning existence.
Nor was I pleased about it.
No.
Because instantly, with the realization of the reality of existence,
came up the fear of nonexistence.
So at age three, at calibrated level 850,
existence versus nonexistence is the ultimate polarity duality to be resolved
before you can go beyond that level.
So a great deal of spiritual work obviously went on for many lifetimes.
So each entity gets born at a certain puzzlement.
So that was the puzzlement, that was the puzzlement.
But it was unforgettable. It was very striking.
And I also have never been happy about physicality since.
There was this little body in this wooden cart
that went with existence.
Exist as a body.
My question is about teacher-student relationship.
You said in past lectures that for a student to reach enlightenment,
that students needed a teacher.
And then it seemed like today you were talking about many of us
belong to different groups and we share.
Is it important to have a formal relationship with a teacher
for a student to reach enlightenment or what's best?
The influence of the teacher that first of all is to share the truth.
And to share it within an energy field of a certain level.
The same truth spoken by a bartender will not have the same effect.
That's the truth.
I used to be a bartender so I know.
I would say things to guys that was very good advice.
Yes.
But they didn't pay attention.
Later when I was a psychiatrist and it's $75 an hour,
I said the same thing but they paid attention.
Yes.
If it's costing you money, you do what the doctor says.
If it's just a bartender talking to you, you know.
Apparently the vibrational frequency, the energy of the field
is what is picked up by the aura forever.
The energy of hearing the Lotus Sutra, Chanda and Sanskrit
is a permanent imprint on the aura.
So that aura will not be the same again.
Like the stripes on a tree, like the rings on a tree.
It's got a ring on it now it didn't have before.
So it tends to recognize its own.
So light goes to light because you leave the body.
That which rings at a certain frequency is attracted to that
which rings at a certain frequency.
The conviction of truth, you see.
I'll tell you there's a difference in advertising.
You see an actress come on and tell you how taking so-and-so pills
have cured her hyperacidity.
She's not very convincing.
Why isn't she convincing?
Because she didn't have hyperacidity and these pills didn't cure her hyperacidity.
What they need is just some dumb gons who had hyperacidity.
He took them and he cured his pills and he gets on and he says,
I took these pills and boy, I got it better.
That's got a convincingness like that.
It's got the power of truth.
I don't invite anybody to go any place unless I've been and can profoundly
and with karmic responsibility be willing to say,
yes, it's safe to walk straight forward no matter what.
All fear is illusion.
To walk into all fear, even surrendering one's life,
that can't be said unless you've done it.
And the aura knows the truth that it's been said.
It's different than reading it in a book to hear it from that which has lived through it.
You can go through surgery without anesthesia.
I'm telling you that. It's possible.
The ring of truth is profound, see?
That's what convinces people.
The ring of truth is what convinces people.
So the sailor who sailed the seas has an authority over somebody who read a book on sailboating.
There's a difference.
Yeah, my question has to do with the more formal relationship.
Like in the past it seemed like there was the guru and the student,
or the India-Indian type of relationship.
Yes, that's a paradigm coming out of this.
The ashram and the guru and the whole thing.
And I'm sure it's valid up to a certain point.
All you have to do is calibrate the energy field of that ashram and that teacher.
And that teaching.
And then if it suits you, fine.
The other thing is in the spiritual evolution we tend to go here, learn this,
go here, learn that, go here, learn that.
Isn't that right?
And each one serves a purpose.
It takes you from here to there.
Then you outgrow it.
So you leave the teacher because you've outgrown that.
So people who, many of us, go here, go there, pick up this, pick up that.
You know, sometimes we stay with one program or teacher for a while.
Sometimes it's...
Yeah, well, see, as you evolve, new possibilities open up.
In the beginning people don't really think that they're going to reach enlightenment.
Oh, yeah.
But as you get more adept at the field and you begin to see things do fall away,
blocks do fall away, and your energy is increasing and increasing,
then one day you get the, what should we say, the enthusiasm to go the whole way.
And from that instant on you do nothing but surrender everything to God
every instant around the clock, no matter what.
But you know what's interesting?
And then, bang.
You cross into a new arena.
That sounds like the energy is coming from the students' spiritual choice or choosing or...
And I always held it in mind as the teacher said.
The teacher what?
The teacher said.
The teacher said, yes, I will take you as a student.
The teacher said, yes, you're ready.
But you're speaking more like...
I'm sure there's certain, you know, spiritual organizations
in which that is the design.
A formal arrangement, a formal arrangement.
I depend on the teaching of the truth itself
and the energy with which it is spoken to suffice.
Those who desire the truth and are committed to the truth
and recognize it when they hear it and then put it into practice.
So the teacher serves more as an inspiration, confirmation of what you suspect and what you know.
Do you suggest that those of us that are students,
reading your material, learning and growing, that we stay with this?
Do we jump around?
I'll answer it like other spiritual pathways have developed.
See, like AA or the Course in Miracles or Unity and those things.
There's usually a basic text which starts people off.
Then they tend to form discussion groups all over.
They form the discussion groups.
And the discussion groups interact with each other.
And the teacher will come around and visit the various groups.
And that way it sort of spreads and the energy spreads.
And it pulls to it that which is needed.
It tends to spread of its own energy.
When I calibrated power versus force, I knew I would have to do nothing.
I could just leave it in the closet and it would spread out.
Because anything at that level is going to automatically pull to it what it needs to radiate.
So nothing needs to be done.
So I don't believe in promoting anything.
I believe in describing as accurately as possible the truth of one, of the reality.
And people are attracted to it or not.
If they're attracted to it, they begin to pick up on the energy and the vibration of it.
What they don't really pick up on,
I guess what you're describing might be handy at a very advanced stage.
There's a stage at which you're willing to leave the world
and do nothing but surrender anything and everything,
no matter what it is,
and stay on the edge of the knife.
And if you do that, in a way you need a protected environment.
And you want to know that you're a truth is truth.
Yes.
So at that point it would serve such a purpose.
That's good clarifying where one is on the path,
where one is on one's spiritual path.
Yeah.
Thank you.
There's a point at which you're free to leave everything
and you're willing to say,
I'm not going to leave this rock, period.
Yeah.
And you might die.
You say, yeah, right.
So you die.
Bye.
At that point, you probably are ready for a,
at that point, a protected,
I see the ashram as protected, see?
Yeah.
Protected environment where you can go the whole route
in a protected environment.
And there's somebody around to make sure you eat once a week.
Right.
Every time you say that, I re-tape it all, right?
Okay.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Between the tape.
What?
We're hurrying.
They're hurrying us up.
I can't read it.
Oh, I see what it says.
Yes.
I'm watching it.
First of all, thank you for not leaving.
Yes.
Thank you for staying.
You think I stayed, but that's your illusion.
Well, I mean, okay, but you know,
that illusion is working for me.
Most of my questions got answered as I was waiting in line.
Good.
But now that one is, one of my questions is,
now that I know that there is this etheric brain,
kind of up here, that I feel throbbing,
is that can I, is it valid to say that I can set my intention
that the input I get from the world I live in and operate in,
that I will funnel everything through that with intention?
The intention would be to spiritualize every aspect of life
as it is experienced to the best of your ability.
That would be the commitment.
Okay.
All right.
The other question I have,
I've been hearing about a phenomenon in the heavens
called the harmonic concordance,
which is supposedly taking place next weekend
in conjunction with the lunar eclipse.
It's being likened to the harmonic convergence of the late 80s.
Yes.
And I would like to hear your take on such a thing.
This is November 1st.
Yes.
When is it?
November 8th, 9th.
I don't know anything about it.
Oh.
Okay.
Look it up on the internet.
It's an alignment of planets.
I got you.
That's supposed to bring special stuff to the earth for spiritual waking.
That's causing effects.
So this physicality within the Newtonian paradigm
is going to cause a big shift in the non-Newtonian spiritual reality.
Boy, that's quite a job, isn't it?
I don't know.
It's like if we line up enough bulldozers,
we're going to raise everybody's level of consciousness.
So does the physical world do anything?
It's not cause and effect.
It's not that this is going to cause that,
but that something beyond both and encompassing both,
there will be a simultaneity.
The last time I think it was a simultaneity,
I will do a diagram for the lectures,
and that week Time magazine will have it come out.
It's happened over and over.
So it's not that time's causing it.
I'm not causing it.
But we're responding to a progression of interest
and the understanding of this, of that.
Okay.
So it's not a lot of hooey.
I don't know whether it's hooey or gooey or pooey or what.
If everybody's going to pray together, I'd do it.
Oh, there you go.
That's it.
Anybody's going to pray together for peace and God knows what.
Absolutely.
I would certainly participate.
Okay, good.
Why not?
Thank you.
Yeah.
So much.
Keep your eye on them planets, boy.
Thank you.
Yes, ma'am.
What I want to know is have you ever noticed
with people on their spiritual path as they advance,
have you ever noticed any difference in their handwriting?
In their handwriting?
Yes.
It gets worse.
I mean, I don't know.
No, I haven't.
I actually haven't.
You haven't noticed.
Well, it's pretty fascinating.
No.
Most of that's inscrutable in this case,
but I noticed this probably gets better.
It doesn't have to do necessarily with being able to read it.
It's just the forms of the letters change automatically.
I haven't noticed it, no.
No, I haven't studied it.
Could I have your autograph anyhow?
You can have my autograph.
It's just a little.
I could write anybody's name and she would know the difference.
11-1-0-3.
That's very gracious of you.
Thank you.
I think it's probably because the unwillingness
to put the energy into form, detailed form.
Hi.
Yeah.
So when I read your book, I'm going along,
and I would like you to explain to me, please,
the field, the divinity in everyone, and God.
All right.
That took 2,000 years the last time I was explaining.
Just minor differentiation.
You got time.
Sure.
Thank you.
The reason we couldn't explain God today,
we'll have to take care of God next time,
Please.
is because we didn't have a
White one.
No.
We didn't have a Whiteboard.
We didn't have a Whiteboard,
so that'll have to wait till the next lecture.
The relationship between the field,
the content of the field,
the Newtonian paradigm, the ego,
and the infinite power of spirit, you see,
is that, you know, it really helps to write it on a Whiteboard.
The ego then is form and content.
Spirit is the field in which that form or content
finds itself.
It finds itself for one karmic reason or another.
And truth is not definable in terms of content only,
but only in terms of content plus field.
Context.
Yeah.
Only in what context?
Certain company is under, you know, paying low wages to people.
What people?
What do you mean by low wages?
They're getting $8 an hour.
Who are the people getting $8?
They were making $3 a day.
They're making $80 a day.
So are they underpaid?
It depends on the context.
If this is a union and this is New York City,
they're underpaid.
So it depends on context.
So truth then depends on the context in which it is occurring, see?
Is a certain thing a crime in times of war?
No.
Times of peace?
Yes.
So you can't state anything as a fact
unless you state in which context.
That which is a virtue in one circumstance
is a crime in another, and vice versa.
That which is virtuous in one position
will get you court-martialed in another,
executed on the spot.
So the truth of anything is not known by content and form,
but only by the field which illuminates it.
Illumination.
So states of illumination and lightening
mean the light lights up the totality of the field,
and everything is witnessed
by the essence of the field itself.
Rather than from the form.
Okay?
That'll take you 2,000 years to figure out.
And a whiteboard.
Thank you.
You bet.
Thank you for asking that.
I'm sorry we didn't have the whiteboard today,
but heads will fall.
What?
We have about 20 minutes.
Thank you.
I'm watching it.
I saw your video, Power Versus Force,
and there was a part in there
that kind of made me think.
Correct.
Well, in many parts,
but this one really kind of threw me,
was you mentioned something about Sai Baba.
There's something in his conscious...
Which video are you talking about?
Hm?
We were talking about the recent Internet data about him,
you know? Yeah.
Yeah, I don't know anything about that.
Yeah, why ask the question?
Well, I asked the question because I think you said something
to the effect that his consciousness was negative,
I think, something to that effect.
And what surprised me with that was,
I don't personally get anything from him,
and it's neutral,
but many of my friends,
my energy healing teacher,
and other spiritual leaders that I know
are very drawn to Sai Baba,
so when I heard that, I went home.
Yeah, his writings were about 510 in the 500s,
and therefore he was a great leader for a long, long time.
Where is he calibrating now?
I don't know.
I haven't calibrated him now.
Hm.
And people ask what had happened to him.
I said, there's a whole story on the Internet.
You can look it up for yourself.
Okay.
Mm-hmm.
And what about Mother Mira?
Where is she?
I don't know anything about her, apparently.
I don't know who Mother Mira is.
All right.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
Does the ego experience radical subjective reality?
No.
Who does?
What?
Enlightened person.
He realizes that the source of conscious awareness,
which is the sense of self with an I, with a capital S,
is divine in nature, by nature, by nature.
Called self-realization classically with a capital S.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
Thank you, sir.
We talked about the evolution of consciousness,
that at certain points, certain tests come up,
and certain challenges come up.
I wonder if I could ask the question or ask you to talk a little bit about non-causality
and especially addressing it with respect to what probably many of the people here,
myself included, have read books, everyone from Deepak Chopra to Louise Hay to Wayne
Dyer, who, by the way, is the reason we're here, he speaks very highly of your teachings.
But in their context, in any of their teachings and their programs, they speak, a lot of the
thrust of their program is that we have, that our intentions create our lives, yet it sounds
like a lot of what you're talking about, non-causality, it almost sounds like we don't, our intentions
don't create our lives.
We don't really feed into that.
So I'm wondering if you could talk about how our personal intentions...
That was the diagram I wasn't able to finish the other night.
Thank you very much.
You're not getting away.
The state, the state, the state, the current state of what is, definable mathematically
as the Schrodinger equations in quantum mechanics, has a potentiality.
Now, the actualization of the potentiality...
The potentiality, which we did describe today, depends on multiple factors.
First of all, local conditions, intention, there is karmic opportunity as well as limitation,
the interaction and the multitudinous factors, in which a spiritual intention is one factor.
When it reaches a certain threshold, it will express itself in actuality, whether intention
is good or bad depends on one's level of consciousness.
If you're below 200, then intention to become a better person is going to be powerful, it's
going to be transformative.
The play of intention then is the motivation behind it.
There's a delineation of the intention in the beginning, later on there's a surrender
of all intentionality and a surrender to God.
So in the beginning, one prays for abundance.
Then one leaves the place.
One leaves abundance up to God.
Then eventually you complain about what to do with abundance.
Is that where you're at?
So you're saying that...
Can you help me with what to do with abundance?
Yes, I don't know.
So the questions are different.
There's no room left in the refrigerator, do you understand my problem?
Got it.
There is no more room left in the garage.
Right.
The attic is stuffed.
The basement is full.
That's what I'm talking about.
There's no more room in the clothes closet.
There's no more room in the closet.
Yeah.
Never mind.
Help me.
Thank you.
Got it.
I understand.
Thank you.
Okay.
We'll move faster.
We've got to be finished in a matter of minutes.
Yes.
My question is...
Don't ask me a 2,000-year question.
My question is that I am a soul engaged in this body and trying to go back to my source.
Was there ever a time...
Yes.
So how did that happen that I was with my source and wanted to get away with it, get
away from my source?
How did I first pick up an ego and get to where I am?
And I'm trying to go back.
The err is in the way the question is stated.
Right.
The err is in the statement of the question, the way in which you contextualize it.
First of all, you presume that you're like a spark of God, right?
Yes.
whoever told you you're a spark off god did god tell you
no did you ever know that yourself no something you've written a book
people chase spiritual fiction all over the place there has to be that which is experientially
verifiable did the buddha tell you you're a spark off of the god block
mr god of maharaj did it say that in the upanishads does it say it in the gita
where does it say that in the gita says your spark you are a part of the whole you're you're
oh a part of the whole of course you're part of the whole
you are the whole is nothing so you're part of nothing that's for sure
it is it is you you why do you need to know that that you're sparked off the whole
i mean
No, I guess I read the Gita written by a person who is not a dvaita, who does not follow a dvaita, who follows more dvaita, that you are a servant of God.
Those are all programs and belief systems.
That's stuff you memorize out of a book.
Experience the truth of who you are, and that answers all that.
You're stuck in books.
Forget about all that.
Then you'll be free.
Otherwise, you're trapped.
Trapped in books, writings, teachers.
Yeah?
Yes?
I was going to write October.
It's 11-1-3.
Okay.
Okay, almost, huh?
Trying to get them all quick.
You talked about how once we make a spiritual intention and a spiritual decision, that health and immunity improve.
Yes.
And my experience appears to be the opposite of that.
Yes, that may well be.
You can just kill yourself right off, even.
Look at all the bad karma you brought up, eh?
You live it through, pray your way through it, just use spiritual techniques, and it comes and it goes.
So is it sort of like the ego resisting the spiritual movement?
Well, there's multiple causes.
Today we went in.
We went into the physiology, brain physiology, et cetera.
Then there's karmic consequences.
There's genetic consequences, which are part of the karmic, et cetera.
So it's which acupuncture meridians you're blowing and for what reason, out of what chakra, out of which archetype.
So it's a complicated question.
It requires a little specific work.
Generally, you just go on with the spiritual work the best you can.
And these things come and go, and then it's suddenly revealed to you what it is.
And with kinesiology, you can also...
You can also research it and find out some details about it.
One can be...
One is usually suffering the consequence of something one has done to others in the past.
So I would pray to whatever might have been the likelihood of bringing this on,
for forgiveness and understanding and asking God to reveal to you what it is.
If you have lots of pains in your bones, you may have caused pains in the bones to others.
You understand what I'm saying?
Okay.
When you drove people beyond their endurance until they dropped from exhaustion.
So I would ask God to forgive anything or anyone in me that ever was so unloving as to demand that of others.
I would presume that it's the reverse of some past life karma and start from there.
If everybody's cruel to you, you can assume that you've spent a lot of lifetimes being cruel to others.
And so you start praying there as a likelihood.
But, you know, kinesiology, you usually get, yeah, that's what's going on.
It's a shortcut.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Yes, ma'am.
I have a question about, I guess, terminology or language.
Yes.
You're referring to the etheric brain.
And in the Western spiritual tradition, it's been...
There is a thing that is referred to as the higher mental body.
Or the Christ self, the Christ consciousness.
Would that be the same?
I only told you what I know.
You've never tested that.
You could ask with kinesiology if that's what's so...
Right.
It doesn't make a difference anyway, does it?
Not really.
But we're glad you have it in your ear.
Thank you.
Cross...
See, I don't have a doctorate in comparative religion and theology, which I have sometimes regretted.
I would have loved to recharge.
I've spent about five years just buried in every spiritual treatise, visited every ancient place that there's ever been.
But the time has passed for that.
Thank you.
Yes.
On the internet, I found a recommendation that you wrote on brain respiration by Dr. H.H. Lee.
And I was wondering if you recommend those exercises to your students.
I just wrote what I wrote.
What I wrote is what I wrote.
Okay.
You said it was true to some degree, something like that?
I was, yes.
Yes.
Okay.
It's true to the degree within what I said.
But I wouldn't extrapolate it to, I mean, you should sell everything and join somebody's ashram or something.
I didn't say that.
No, you didn't.
No, okay.
Okay, thank you.
Hi.
Thank you.
If someone once calibrated above 200 and now are currently...
Destructively acting below 200, how can we help friends and family?
How can you help what?
Friends and family.
How do you mean help them?
If they're acting through anxiety, depression, self-defeating type behavior.
Which person are you talking about?
The one who's gone down below 200 or the family of the people, of the one who went below 200?
The one who's gone below 200.
What can you do for the one who's gone below 200?
Right.
I join Eleanor.
I take step one.
Wish them well.
Saludos.
All right.
If the...
Another question.
If the time of death is determined, why is not the how?
Don't ask me why questions.
First of all, why questions are hypothetical and they're creations of the intellect to keep the ego propagated.
As long as you can keep asking why, you never have to face the real.
Because the hypothetical is not in case of the real.
You can ask me.
What was your question?
I forgot.
Why is the time of death determined, not the how?
I don't know.
All right.
Thank you.
Because that's the nature of divinity and the nature of creation.
I don't know why.
It gets you ran out of spiritual money.
You have to get off the bus.
You only paid for a ticket to age 87.
Do enlightenment and the balancing of all one's karma occur together?
I don't know.
Of all one's karma occur together, a certain percent of one's karma?
Technically, I think one comes in with a propensity, see, as we explained at the beginning
of today's lecture.
Everything has a propensity, a potentiality now, subject to the interposition of will
and under suitable conditions, it becomes an actuality.
One theoretically has the capacity to become enlightened, hypothetically.
Practically that's not the case.
We can see 85% of the people aren't even up to 200, so the chances of going to enlightenment
are slim indeed.
The capacity, the propensity.
So then we cross a certain threshold where one more yes is sufficient to drive you through.
It needs one more yes.
One more...
Does that have to do with the percent of balancing one's karma, that one more yes?
Are you looking like a scoreboard when you've got more positives on this side of the wire
than on the negative?
No, I don't think it works that way.
Like making amends?
I think that one works one's way through karma because different things are weighted far
more than others.
Blowing up a busload of children I'm sure doesn't weigh the same as killing a mother
with a mouse in a mousetrap, see?
So it may require a good deal more to undo.
So these are not, I don't think these are quantifiable, really I'm looking for a quantifiability.
I don't think there's quantifiability.
I think there's thresholdness when the ripeness, it reaches a certain degree of ripeness, the
apple falls off the tree.
And there's no cause of it, it's just the totality of the circumstances facilitates
it.
I know in spiritual work, suddenly there comes an onrush of spiritual energy, a drivenness
to leave anything, everyone, and all of it, even the physical body, even death itself.
One's either going to reach truth or that.
Let me drive you to the depths of hell before the heavens open up, but you're willing to
even go there through agony, through suffering, through terror, and the depths of hell are
terrorizing.
So, you see, you develop a certain spiritual momentum that left, that momentum will carry
you through the blocks, the momentum.
And the words that you've heard and the vibrations you've incorporated into your aura will come
back to you.
Just when you're about ready to give up, it'll say, ah, suddenly a great power comes into
you, like a piledriver, you go right through the wall, there you are in an infinite space.
Yeah, thank you.
Yes.
I just want to express my gratitude for the work that you've done, the benefit my friends
and I have got from reading these works.
Thank you.
I'm just asking if, intuition, if there's anything that needs to be said to help speed
me along or help me progress.
I think you're doing fine.
Can't ask for better than that.
Yes.
Hi.
I work in a market where there's rap music
and other harsh types of music being played.
Yes.
I've taken to bringing a personal CD player
and listening to Arvo Part and the Omnima.
Sure.
I keep that in my ear with hopes that that's going to negate
the effects of the music that's here and there in the store.
Does it do that?
You may not be able to tolerate a certain environment
when your own spiritual awareness reaches a certain level.
Too much noise, too much confusion, too much detail,
too much demand in this, too much chaotic energies,
too many solar plexuses interacting with each other
will drive you back into the woods again.
I'd rather truck manure than put up with this.
And so you do.
And you're happy as a clam.
Going down the highway with a truckload of manure.
Thank you.
They've made 40 bucks a trip.
Happy as a lark.
Free as a bird.
Yeah.
Thank you.
You said when we started this morning
that the collective consciousness of this room was probably 441.
Does attending these type things help the collective consciousness?
Yes.
Have we raised our collective consciousness today?
The consciousness of the world?
Of this room.
Oh, the room.
Oh, before and after the lecture.
We forgot to do that, didn't we?
We did them before and after.
Yeah.
The consciousness level of this group.
Wow, I was already starting to breathe.
Went up over five points, eight points, nine points, ten points, twelve points, twelve points.
Consciousness level of the audience went up over eleven points today.
Twelve points today.
Eleven points today.
Okay.
About ten points every lecture.
Four out of ten lectures.
Woo.
Now, the truth is individuals, you see, is very individual.
In the audience are people who will stay the same for long periods of time,
and then suddenly they'll make a leap.
There's other people who constantly go up like this,
and then there's people that make very sudden leaps.
So it varies from person to person.
Also, the group reflects the collective, too.
It's not only the individual.
It's not only the individual consciousness of the people here,
but that the people here, you know, represent the collective unconscious of mankind, see?
So it's not just the individual, but the collective unconscious of mankind that is holding everybody down.
I didn't get off that one that came up this morning until I detected which archetype in the unconscious,
what lifetime it was, and which shock it was coming out of.
So it could take quite a while to research a lot.
I just intuited it, you know, because I remember exactly the moment when I felt it.
And I thought, oh, you know.
May I have a hug?
You can have a hug.
Thank you.
Hugs are a dollar a day.
Okay, I'll give you that.
Okay.
You know.
And I've been grateful for your work since I first got Power Versus Force when you first published it.
But I have a couple questions.
I get what you say about karma being said about our death when we're born.
Yeah.
You also say in levels of enlightenment, it's okay if we come and go at any time.
Now, is there a level of consciousness between the two where we gain control over our karmic destiny around death?
No, you don't have control.
You see, if you understand quantum mechanics, all you're dealing in is probabilities.
You're only dealing in probabilities, likelihoods.
It's like you're weighing the dice in the favor of this direction rather than this direction.
But you can't cause the dice to go in that direction.
So, karmic, I mean, spiritual commitment increases the likelihood of certain propensities.
Got it.
Thank you.
When it reaches a certain height, what the world calls miraculous is almost continuous.
Yeah.
Nothing's causing it, though.
Okay.
So, there isn't a calibrated level of consciousness where we reach the ability to have a real strong propensity to influence that?
To influence what?
The karmic time of our death.
Why would you want to do that?
You see how the ego wants to control everything, life and death?
You see how it wants to be God?
You don't want to surrender the time of your death to God.
You want to have control of it.
You understand what I'm saying?
Yes, but...
Forget about it.
Surrender the...
What difference does it make the time of your death?
It's an idiotic figure.
Okay.
Well, I made a commitment...
12, 22, 20, 23.
How's that, Greg?
I made a commitment.
Oh.
And I want to know if I'm going to keep it or not or have the influence to charge things to keep it.
Oh, you would like to know all that, wouldn't we all, eh?
Okay.
Now, the other question...
No, because one has to go on with blind faith.
It's the not knowingness that gives you the karmic merit to walk on unknowingly in the face of the storm and the unknown.
It's the...
But you have the courage to live in the face of the unknown that is the karmic merit.
If you had guarantees, there'd be no karmic merit.
I can guarantee you guys are going to get sober.
All I have to do is lock them up where you can't get it.
What's this karmic merit?
Zero.
You understand?
No.
You can guarantee if you walk on...
The willingness to walk on unknowing is what gives you spiritual integrity and power.
I get that.
Okay.
And I do that.
At the best of my spiritual ability.
Now, the next question is, is there a level of consciousness...
We're going to change it.
No.
Is there a level of consciousness we get to where we can do projects that affect the earth and they are good in the field,
they are part of the field, and they are beneficial to all mankind?
Yeah.
Could we calibrate what level that would be?
I want to know if the major project I'm doing is...
Good for the planet, or I should just bag it, based on what you said about not doing anything.
See, I go to a movie or commit suicide.
Well, let's see.
Okay.
Let's see if we got permission.
Let's see.
We have permission.
Resist.
No, we don't have permission.
Okay.
Thank you very much.
It's been my pleasure.
Yeah.
Yes.
I wanted to say how grateful we all are for your teachings.
And how marvelous it's been to be here.
And I'd like to ask if the words we speak actually create our reality.
Or when you reach a higher level of consciousness, it doesn't really matter.
You can just say whatever you want.
You just did, didn't you?
Yeah.
Yeah, I did.
I didn't see any smoke.
I didn't see any smoke rise up.
You're free to say anything you want to say.
Each thing, however, has a consequence.
So does...
Do the words we speak, the matrika shakti, create our reality?
Well, that's...
The error is in the construction of the question.
When you say construct our reality, what do you mean by reality?
Well, that's it.
Your sequential perceptions?
Your subjective...
Yeah.
Subjective experiences?
So obviously in the absolute, you're not creating anything.
That's why I meant you could say whatever you wanted to say.
Let's see.
What did you say in English?
Yeah.
What you hold in mind is the way you experience things, you see,
because that's determining perception.
So positionality will tend to reinforce itself
because you're holding that positionality, you project it into the world.
Now you think you see it in the world,
and therefore you bring it back to reinforce that you were right to begin with.
Give an inch, it'll take a mile.
If you hold that in mind, you know what's going to happen?
You give them an inch, they're going to take a mile.
Yeah, yeah.
That's what I...
Yeah.
You say, see, that's the way people are.
Give them an inch, they're going to take a mile.
Mm-hmm.
We say, give a sucker a break, you know, give a sucker a break.
Then we would experience a different world.
You know, a guy comes back and says, gee, you gave me a break.
What can I do for you?
Now, three lifetimes later, when you've got a flat tire on a snowy night,
and a guy comes over and says, hey, you got a flat?
Can I help you?
Where did that come out of, you know?
A million miles from nowhere, there it is, an icy night,
and the old truck has a flat tire.
One of my best friends suddenly appeared out of nowhere,
many miles from where we were living, just happened to be driving by.
I said, happened to be driving by, yeah.
I saw you with a flat, and he came over and changed it, and there you were.
So where did that come out of, huh?
Maybe some kindness you did to some person in some lifetime, see?
So that sets it in the field.
And then when the time is right, it comes back to you, see?
It's not cause and effect.
It's that the apple falls from the tree at that moment.
So all the good we do to others, you know, comes back to us in some way.
The ripple goes out in the pond, and then the ripple comes back to us.
Great. Thank you so much.
And then we're going to be done.
So that people can go.
I think the previous question was very much like the one that I was going to ask you,
but it's to understand this idea of cause and effect more.
If I understand you correctly, it's that there are no,
there are no causes at this level, and that everything is effect.
There's a cause at an invisible level that we don't see.
Everything, let's put it differently.
Everything is a consequence of the totality of all that is.
And all that is, you see, goes back into infinity, does it not?
Right.
I mean, this room here requires the existence throughout all eternity of this cosmos,
this planetary system.
This world, this country, this state, the ground we're on, you know.
So an infinite number of factors coalesce in which the propensities of all those things
that are involved tend to influence the outcome.
Don't determine the outcome, but influence the outcome.
Okay, but in a quantum reality, things are only influences, they're not causes.
Increased likelihoods, you know.
But at a very simplistic level, we live in a world of cause and effect, obviously.
No, we do not.
We just, you just got to, you can't, you see what you're doing with your head?
Yeah.
No, I mean, if I...
You just got through negating the thing that you want me to prove to you.
Right.
And negated it in the process.
No, you're not going to trick that one on me.
Okay, I'll have to give that some more thought.
Thank you.
A quirk goes up, not, a quirk goes up because of the field, you understand?
Because of what the quirk is, in the presence of the field,
the quirk rises.
The quirk rises thusly.
Nothing is causing it to be that way.
So as you make good intentions, your quirk rises faster.
As you do bad intentions, it sinks lower.
It's the interaction of the field.
Nothing is causing it.
No, that's another illusion.
You haven't caused anything.
That's more sophisticated.
That's in lectures one or two or three this past year.
The billiard ball.
Each thing comes out of nothingness to be what it is.
Would it be all right to get a picture?
You can have a picture.
Nobody wants to take my picture today.
What am I, ugly today or something?
Some days everybody wants my picture.
Today nobody wants my picture.
Wow.
I'd go home sad and blue.
Now I'm happy somebody took my picture.
I don't have any question.
I guess you've already told us how to find out the answer to any question.
Well, my question is, I don't know.
My fuzzy inner animal likes to have his picture taken.
Thank you.
You see how your ego gets to be a pet?
Your ego gets to be a pet.
You don't have to feel guilty about vanity.
Your fuzzy wuzzy loves to have his picture taken.
Fuzzy wuzzy.
Yeah.
I'm not sure what my question is, but I, I have, uh.
That was easy.
I have just, when I saw the map and you were, you said people in Africa had a consciousness
of 200 and people in other states, Australia had a consciousness of 400.
I felt uncomfortable.
It seemed to conflict with the feeling that all people are born equal.
There's an illusion, isn't it?
Everybody's born with a different calibrated level of consciousness.
Why?
Because this is not the only life.
The lifetime you've had, everybody arrives and settles based on that which it is.
Each thing is attracted to its, to its own, to its own sake.
You see, because each thing deserves the greatest possible karmic opportunity.
Therefore, what we, what we grieve over and feel sorry for about is their salvation.
Do you understand?
How's it?
What you want to eliminate.
The possibility of salvation.
If you had forbidden slavery, I would not have discovered that I am not a physical body.
Because it was as a slave, in exhaustion and pain and agony, that I suddenly realized, screw them.
I can leave the body, and I left.
I knew I was spirit, but this is the first time I took a chance.
I let myself die purposely.
Discovered that I'm a spirit.
Nobody can ever.
Never enslave me, or imprison me again.
Would you have deprived me of that opportunity?
It was a huge karmic jump.
In that lifetime, I remember it severely.
All the other things that I remember that were enormously spiritually beneficial, probably
better be illegal or banned nowadays.
Would you say the same with the Holocaust?
Or any other?
The only explanation for those mass phenomena is mass karma.
Whole cultures.
You know what that means.
The whole culture says, we will kill all those people in the name of so and so.
The whole culture now owes that karmic debt.
You see?
Whole cultures come in and prosper and leave, and then hit the pits, and then come back
and start from the bottom and re-earn karmic integrity.
Don't forget whole cultures have committed grave acts.
Whole cultures.
Not just one or two.
Not just one or two people, thousands.
And the families cheering them on.
Now they're all obligated by the spiritual error, yeah?
To deify a politician instead of God.
You don't say to a person,
you bow only to God.
That's the mistake.
I serve thee, O Lord.
To serve God instead of a megalomaniac is a great lesson.
Yeah, that's very hard to say.
Oh my goodness.
I do have a question.
If my intent is to be loving and kind and forgiving,
and yet maybe there's at times I'm not.
There better be times when you're not.
Will my intention, like if I act as if,
will my intention overcome my execution,
my level of execution?
Yes, the intention will bring,
yes,
the intention will bring up the opportunity.
You see, because the intention, what it does,
is call forth, you can figure it simply.
It calls forth an answer from heaven.
O thee, O Lord, I ask, to reveal it to me.
What is the underpinning of this?
The person says, I'm angry all the time.
I'm angry all the time.
Why are you angry?
I hate people.
I'm angry, I hate myself because I hate people.
Why do you hate people?
And you ask, you ask God, why is it I'm so angry?
Why am I hating people?
Then you find your discovery.
You hate anything that creates fear.
Oh, your problem is not hate.
Your problem is fear.
We all hate that which makes us fearful.
So your problem then is not hate at all.
Your problem is fear.
So you see, layer by layer, you unwrap the onion.
And what is the fear then?
Then you look what underlies the fear.
I'll physically die.
Are you willing to physically die?
For God?
That's a hard one.
Sooner or later, you'll get a yes.
Then that fear dies.
OK, we'll see.
Great, thank you.
It's layer after layer.
So you meditate, and you pray.
And then you get it by osmosis, by revelation.
My willingness is over.
Well, the intention makes the field
begins to answer the intention.
Because you pull to it.
You pull to it out of the field, that which knows.
Wow.
And then that's someone's fourth,
the knowingness within yourself.
So you're walking along thinking, anger is my problem.
Anger is my problem.
Then you realize, oh, I'm angry because I'm scared.
I'm angry.
I hate anything that makes me frightened.
Oh, that's what it is.
My problem is fear.
So you see how it unravels itself.
So the spiritual work is sort of like pulling
the thread on a sweater.
As you pull it, this iron comes off,
and then this iron comes off.
One thing leads right to the next.
So it's a continuous process, and it's an ongoing process.
And once you start it going, it tends
to an ongoingness of its own.
Once you start getting spiritually committed,
the questions just start coming up
about yourself, and human motivation,
and the desire to know.
Boy, I had no idea intention unleashed that much.
Oh, it unleashed it.
All you have to do is pull the thread on the sweater,
and that starts the whole thing going.
Thank you.
All right.
They said we've got to be done.
We're done by 5.
It's two minutes to 5, so I'll have to climb up here
and say how much I've enjoyed being with you all today.
You know that I adore you all.
I adore you all, each and every one.
Thank you.