The first principle we're talking about today, that nothing is causing anything.
The first illusion, the illusion that holds back most of the people in an audience such as this,
in a world such as this, Chicago calibrates at 430, that is very advanced, relatively advanced intellect.
The thing that holds people back is the belief in causality,
the thought that something out there is causing, responsible for, blamed for, should be punished for,
arrested and imprisoned, or thrown into hell.
Something is causing everything to happen.
We spend our lifetime looking for the culprits,
and that belief system is the very foundation of the Trial Lawyers Association.
Our court system.
That something is causing something out there,
and all we have to do is find it, punish it, and life will get better.
So it's the world, you see how causality sets the world up into the duality of perpetrator and victim.
Belief in causality sets up a perpetrator and a victim.
It creates endless contention and war.
The illusion.
If something is causing something, it's based on an illusion because the intellect lacks humility.
It doesn't actually know at all why anything is happening.
Hasn't got the slightest idea.
But it can't handle that.
So the child says to the teacher, why does the flower turn around and follow the sun?
The teacher says, heliotropism.
The child says, oh, he doesn't even know any more than he did before.
Neither does the teacher.
You still don't know why the flower follows the sun.
So the interjection of pseudo, pseudo-knowledge is the specialty of the intellect.
Thus we have creation versus evolution.
Because to explain how phenomena occur,
the explanation of evolution, you see, is causal.
You have the billiard balls, A, B, C, D, E, all hitting each other in a sequence.
Causality, as an explanation for the phenomena of the world,
calibrates, in my vernacular, at a miserable 450 or 460.
Causality calibrates around 450, 455, 460.
Newton's law of evolution calibrates around 450, 455, 460.
Not Newton.
What's his name? Darwin.
Darwin's law of evolution.
Based on causality.
Causality on our calibrated scale of consciousness,
which we'll get to as soon as we have the machinery set up,
is the middle of the intellect.
Very few people in our world ever transcend the intellect.
The intellect calibrates in the 400s.
Spirit, love, the subjective reality of the world,
really starts at 500, which is love.
The other downside of the belief in causality
is first of all it's dualistic.
So the pathway I teach, called devotional non-duality,
is to transcend duality,
to transcend the mind.
So long as you believe there's a this causing a that,
you will believe that there is a separate self,
separate from the one.
There is an it,
causing that.
This it should be guilty,
thrown in hell, punished,
rewarded, worshipped.
So the belief in causality
anchors the belief in a separate self
and anchors the idea,
the reality of the ego
as an actual it.
It's the it causing you to do all these things.
And all kinds of spiritual pathways
are set up to destroy the it.
Vanquish the ego.
Vanish it.
Conquer it.
It's much easier to dissolve it
by removing its structure
and then it falls to its own accord.
If things are not happening
due to causality,
if there is no it causing a that to happen,
then how do phenomena occur?
Then how do phenomena occur?
How do they come about?
To understand better an analogy
to the reality of divinity
it would be
divinity is like an infinite field
of infinite power
whose characteristic
is more like gravity
than anything else.
Its power is infinite.
Its domain is infinite.
It has no beginning, no end.
It has no parts.
It has no opinions, no feelings.
It doesn't get angry at people.
Not interested in vengeance.
If you're not respectful of gravity
be interested in vengeance.
However, if you're not respectful of gravity
you're in for difficult times.
Alright, so if divinity is infinite
I just got cut out.
Thank you God.
If divinity is an infinite power
it's an infinite field
and
we'll draw the infinite
we'll draw God's picture this morning.
God doesn't mind, easy.
So God is actually this whole
field here, this entire board.
How's that?
God is the infinite field.
So this is a giant electromagnetic field.
We're using this as a closer analogy
than most of
traditional religions.
In the middle of this infinite
powerful field you have
the ego, which is
structure, see?
We're not having technical
successes this morning.
Here we go.
In the middle of it
you have an ego.
It has some kind of form.
It's got belief systems,
it's got structures.
I was born in 1927
in Chicago, Illinois
and I'm son, this and this.
So it's got definition.
It's got form.
So that which we call
the ego structure then
is form within an infinite
field of non-form.
That door of this building
this morning.
An analogy to God.
Here was this big
giant electromagnetic crane
out back here,
whose power is infinite
compared to the scrap metal
it's picking up.
Guy throws the switch,
tremendous power picks it up.
Now, what happens
to every little piece of scrap metal
from the tiniest to the largest
is completely at the effect
of the power of the field.
It doesn't decide
where it's going to go.
It's not punished.
The electromagnetic is not punishing
this little ball bearing here,
but zap, it's pulled right into the field.
So, over lifetimes then,
karmically,
what we acquire as a result
of spiritual intention then
are energy fuels
with patterns within them
which becomes our karmic destiny.
We become like little
pieces of
little molecules of metal.
We have a polarity
and we have a molecular structure
and this is a composite
over many lifetimes.
So what you have become now
is within this
infinite field.
It's obvious that the field will
have complete influence
over the destiny of this thing
depending on how it changes
its own polarities
and its own opinions
where it will go in the field then
is now up to
the content of the field.
But the field is not going to change.
The field is not arbitrary.
Therefore,
as spirit leaves the body
where it goes, obviously,
is within the field
where it feels comfortable
where it's appropriate.
Every human being
when they're first born
already has a calibratable
level of consciousness.
The instant you're born
you can calibrate.
Every newborn infant already has
a calibrated level of consciousness.
Also,
the moment of birth,
the exact moment of death
is already defined.
Not the means, not the how.
The exact moment.
So you have two interesting phenomena.
Nobody is born equal at all.
Some people are born with
consciousness level 200,
others 400.
How long we'll be
within a physical body is already determined.
Let's see if what we said is a fact.
We have permission to ask this.
What I've just said is a fact.
So,
in kinesiology what we do is
confirm things
that are not within
the ordinary belief system of people
and yet they answer
many questions and phenomena.
Because people who are
in the Western world are unaware
of the whole phenomena of karma
are busy feeling sorry for themselves
and resentful all the time
because
they don't see that everything
is the result of an ongoing phenomena
over vast periods of time.
So things don't come about by
causality.
There's no this causing of that.
Then how do phenomena occur?
Each thing within
creation then
has its potential.
It has its phenomena
and its potentiality.
And within the field of divinity
its potentiality
becomes an actuality
and unfolds.
So what you don't see is causality.
What you see is
the ongoingness of creation.
Creation is continuous
and unfolding.
And to the sequential
perception of the ego
it looks like sequence.
Sequence then demands
an explanation cause causality.
So let's just look at how
a rose unfolds.
The rose within it
has a karmic potentiality.
It's born
with the potential
to become a magnificent
rose. But it's not
a rose now.
Nothing can force it to become
a rose nor can anything cause
it to become a rose.
But under appropriate conditions
of the field, under the
conditions of the field,
it then begins to
fulfill its potentiality
and present itself
as an actuality.
You understand?
It's unfolding its potentiality.
Nothing is causing,
nobody here can cause
a rose to do anything.
Whether a thing will manifest
its potentiality depends
on local conditions.
So you have
that karmic potentiality.
You have reality.
You have the field.
And then manifesting
depending on local conditions.
Therefore, creation
and evolution
are one and the same thing
in that you see
that evolution is nothing
but the unfolding of creation
to perception.
There is no conflict
between creation and evolution.
They're identical.
Is that obvious?
All right.
You see the field
tends to manifest
the potential
of that which is within it.
That was
an interesting example.
Even scientists
begin to suspect
that there's more than
the linear domain.
Because in explaining
what happened to one of these
rockets where the
insulation fell off or something.
Shuttle deal.
Yes.
You see they started
looking for causality.
They couldn't really find
the answer in causality.
They had some quasi examples
but they didn't have
anything definitive.
And finally they got
and I saw it the other day
it says it's the climate
of NASA that allowed
for this to happen.
The climate. Aha.
They breached certain
negligences or routine.
It's the climate. Aha.
The climate.
It's out of a climate
that war arises.
This person doesn't cause a war there.
It's out of a whole climate.
You have to have a whole population.
The climate of a whole population
willing to say
let's kill everybody
or let's chop up
the other side.
You have to have a climate
that can grow.
Joseph Goebbels was
a great master of that.
He knew that it was fertile out there.
He knew how to fan the breeze
and get everybody inflamed.
You see.
So you look there
where is the cause?
Well you can't have a flame
without tinder.
There is the tinder.
People willing to fan the flame
of war.
You see war isn't just a simple cause and effect.
It's a net effect of a total climate.
A whole climate.
And the climate of course changes with the times
and the evolution of mankind.
Political sophistication,
education
and a thousand other things.
So that's my
first obligation
to dissuade you of the
devotion to the
belief system of causality
because so long as
you believe that
you're reinforcing
the ego constantly
everything we do think and believe
is the manifestation
is like the consolidation
of a whole field
which is evolved over great
periods of time.
Great periods of time.
So you see
the evolution of mankind.
You look at the evolution of consciousness
of which I spoke last night a little bit.
How many were here last night?
Oh quite a few.
Do you remember I said
in the beginning on this planet
there wasn't any life on this planet.
See if that's a fact.
I'm going to check that out.
We have permission to ask that.
What could be called before the beginning
in the beginning?
There was no life on this planet.
There was life on this planet.
There was the potential for life on this planet.
Oh there was the energy of life on this planet.
There was the energy of life on this planet.
There was the energy
coming out of
coming out of the energy field of consciousness
was the light
the light of energy resist
as light resist.
We never asked that before.
In the beginning then
we look back in history
and we see that life forms were extremely primitive.
And here were these primitive life forms
on a you might say
hostile planet
in other words it wasn't necessarily
friendly to life
but life began to evolve then
by serving
itself.
Here's a planet with no life on it
at that time that just the beginning of life
was merely an energy
as yet no form.
And as it begins to take form then
it has to find a way to survive.
So the first rule
of the emergence of life then
in the biologic domain
was survival.
That's a fact.
I didn't introduce Susan.
It's because she's my right arm
I don't feel like introducing my right arm.
This is my right arm here.
She's become my right arm.
She's like one with the work
one with the work.
So we're asking things
we never asked this morning
because we're always discovering
something new
or a new way of looking at things.
So then life began
in a very primitive form
in which its survival
was not at all guaranteed
in fact quite unlikely in form
and so life then had to be
devoted to its own survival.
You see how
life then starts
in its most primitive forms
a germ let's say
and it's only interested
in its own survival.
If we landed on Mars
and decided to colonize
you can see we would have one preoccupation
and that is survival
getting oxygen, food, water, etc.
So life was obsessed then
not obsessed but
as a matter of speaking
devoted to survival
its survival
not yours.
The bacterium under a rock
is not interested in the rock's survival
it's interested in its survival.
So life from the very beginning then
is egocentric is it not?
Me, me, me.
So in the early life forms then
you see the bug is interested
in eating another bug
you see the primitive life forms
are interested in eating
so life then
gets its
foothold by virtue
of eating you
so that I can survive.
This becomes extremely well developed
in the dinosaur
in the reptilian world
the dinosaur is the ultimate
me
doesn't care anything
lays an egg and walks away
not much maternal instinct
don't even hang out to see if the eggs hatch
it takes off
it's busy killing
and eating other people
such people
are still quite active
on our planet
interested in killing other people
let's kill them
by the thousands
so the reptilian
the dinosaur
is still alive
so in fact
the Komodo dragon calibrates
about 70
so the Komodo dragon is a living example
of that
it is so deadly
it just bites you and walks away
and waits till you die
it's perfected
really perfected
yeah
then we see life evolve
to higher forms
you don't begin to see
the evolution of love
until you really see
you see the bird mother
begins to pay attention to the eggs
hangs around
the evolution of the mammalian
and the maternal instinct
the appearance of love
the consideration for something other than just my survival
in fact
you see in maternal love
risking their own survival
for the life of the offspring
and then you see the evolution
on up through hominid
through Neanderthal man
who calibrates around 75
Cro-Magnon man
Piltdown man
on up through the hominids
calibrated around 70 to 90
at the time of
the birth of Buddha
the consciousness level of mankind
as a whole
totality of mankind was 90
the consciousness level
of mankind
at the time of the birth of Jesus Christ
was 100
so that was the audience
he was speaking to
that calibrated at 100
let's give some
depth to the field
of understanding his words
then over the centuries
the 12th century, 13th, 14th
15th, 16th, 17th
if you calibrate all the centuries
you find it calibrated
level 190
1600s, 1700s, 1800s
1900s
the time I was born 190
because
integrity
and spirit of truth doesn't start
till calibrated level 200
then the consciousness level
of mankind was
non-integrous
it was devoted to
falsehood
and the history of mankind
makes sense
if you say well throughout the ages
the consciousness level
during the dark ages was 190
now
the inquisition and all those things
don't seem quite as despicable
the reading
of the vikings
the great hordes of the savages
coming in the lombards
and Genghis Khan and all
at 190
that's the way consciousness
perceives survival
is we have to kill you
to survive
then in the late 1980s
the consciousness level jumped to over 200
to 207
where it exists till this day
which means mankind now has a new
future
has new standards of conduct
the field of 207 then
contextualizes
life in a completely different way
than does consciousness
level 190
consciousness level 190
in which I grew up
had to do with success
you went to college to be a success
your parents said I hope you'll be a success
you were supposed to be a success
you were supposed to stay
as principled as you could
but when it comes to giant corporations
you have to bend that little bit
to influence the stock price
so you can do your stock options
so
heads began to roll
so after it went to 205 then
or 207
where it is today
where is consciousness level today
let's see
consciousness level of mankind
we have permission to resist
is still at 207 resistance
went to 208
well not yet
pray harder folks
look at the vast amount of time
over which consciousness
then manifests as life
and then life evolves
and it isn't until
the late 1980s
that it even gets over 200
which is the level
first level of truth
on the calibrated scale of consciousness
anything that calibrates under 200
makes you go weak
anything over 200
which is truth
makes you go strong
until the late 1980s
the energy field of mankind
of mankind
made you go weak
so in a way that sort of
recontextualizes history
doesn't it
you know
instead of criticizing and faulting
and putting down
what happened in the past
you were doing what they thought
was ethical
you were supposed to get ahead
and be successful
and therefore that was
the great world of materialism
materialism
success, possessions, cars, address
how much money you were worth
now the calibrated level
has reached 207
now you see
that's the level of integrity
so we see
integrity then
and it's the beginning of empowerment
before that
you see inflation and pride
so at 190
the world was coming out
of prideful indifference
to the rights of others
so
when the Germans lost the war
Adolf Hitler said
they didn't deserve to live
and he ordered that Germany
should be destroyed
Paris should be burned down
the Eiffel Tower should be burned down
you say that in that kind of a field
to us it would sound like insanity
because the field here
is probably 435 or so
so at 435
that sounds like insanity
with the masses
who are living down below
so you can see
if the masses of humanity
are living down here
how easy it is to control them
with falsehood
because their consciousness
is dominated by falsehood
grief, apathy, threat
you can appeal to their desires
so it was the world
of the solar plexus
we grew up in the world
and we were angry
and they got our way
and we were prideful of our accomplishments
so it was a different world
than what we live in today
now we have a new paradigm of virtue
and that is as I spoke of last night
integrity
the courage to tell the truth
and to spill the milk
and I'll take care of it
get my check tomorrow
so I just wanted to first address
the totality of the level of consciousness
of all of mankind
which is slowly evolving
and at the same time
take us beyond the polarity of good and evil
because
what should we say
all the bacteria are evil
because they are only interested in themselves
if you superimpose
on this phenomena
of evolution of consciousness
a moralistic code
you can see how ridiculous it looks
and yet that's what mankind has done
and traditional religion in a way
has done, reinforced
if we see that it is
critical for the establishment of life
to be self-interested
then you see how the ego
became so powerful
the ego became in its own view
the source of survival
and mankind to a degree
worshipped the ego
when it didn't worship the ego
he took its basic characteristics
and projected them
anthropomorphically onto a god
that was exactly like the ego
angry, jealous, spitful
punitive
judgmental
all you're talking about is the human ego
that's the human ego
you don't have to call it god
with an E
the capital E for God's ego
and a small E for man's ego
divinity would have to be
something devoid of
the characteristics of form
and
what we call the ego
alright, so
we don't usually start
the lectures with that
but we did it today
because that's the way it happened
it's the field
it's everybody's fault here
you made me do it
alright, so now you have
a more benign view of the ego
it's not an evil it
that you have to battle
and struggle against
and feel guilty about
you don't have to wallow in guilt
and penance
and self-flagellation
psychically or physically
you see that the structure of the ego
is primarily animal
and it's interested in that
which an animal is interested in
survival, serving oneself
and progresses
you see the beginning of
pack formation
loyalty
you see the animal behavior
in competition for mates
for territory
territoriality
you see aggression in all of its forms
and so that's really the basic structure
of the ego
is actually just an animal
alright, then as man learned to think
then he
see man still has the animal structures
but then along came the frontal cortex
and now he could think
so what did man do?
he still stayed an animal
but now he's a thinking animal
he used to do it with teeth and claws
now he does it with bombs and tanks
nothing has changed
now his intellect
he seeks to dominate other tribes
with his intellect
the democrats and the liberals
and all these people
are just an animal
a talking animal
he did what it had fur
I want your territory
I want power over you
I want you to follow me
I want you to join my pack
and like monkey island
they divide in
and they throw you know what at each other
in monkey island
typical political discussion
yeah
as we said last night
as spiritual people
how can we accept
what is and
it's because once you see that the ego
is nothing but a manifestation of animal nature
and that the intellect is merely an expansion of that
you can get off good and evil
and that's one of the most difficult
of all polarities to get off of
you probably don't get off that duality
until about consciousness level 850
let's see
you transcend good and evil
when you're over 800
825, 840
850, 855
alright so it's a very difficult
polarity
duality of the opposites
to begin to dissolve
the demonization
of that which we call evil
yeah
and to see it then
from a more forgiving and accepting
viewpoint without having to demonize
it and vilify it
because if you demonize it and vilify it out there
you will do it
within yourself
you will do it against yourself
those who do the course of miracles
know that forgiveness
is the ultimate answer to just about 99%
of every problem humans have
and the question is
how can you forgive something
that looks dead evil
says the Holy Spirit will
recontextualize it for us
that's my languaging for what the Holy Spirit does
recontextualizes it
so this morning what we've tried to do is
recontextualize
to understand the evolution of consciousness then
so we can witness
that which we consider to be spiritually unfavorable
not as evil
not as horrible
not as something to beat ourselves about
or other people about
but a natural consequence
of the evolution of consciousness
as it came up through
and developed into form
higher and higher form
began to express itself in the human
and
then it expanded its animal nature
and really used the mind
as another tool of its animal nature
so you don't really
become man
in its true meaning with a capital M
until you begin to see
that the mind has other uses
other than subserving animal instincts
subserving animal instincts
and a group
like this has discovered that
yeah
because here you've got
people in
advanced in the 400's
discovered that
the use of the intellect
is to discover spiritual reality
and the ways to God
and it has other uses
other than killing other people
for profit or fun
for fun
alright so
I'm going to go back to
I didn't talk about slide one yet
we talked about slide one
as it is applied
but we didn't talk about it
because it's a more abstract viewpoint
the development of the
calibrated levels of consciousness
resulted as a consequence of
rather profound inner experiences
that went on in this lifetime
beginning in this life at age three
and becoming more
profound in teenage
and eventually through life
so that
when I saw
kinesiology for the first time
I just merely understood it
from a different viewpoint
perhaps other people had
they saw it as a local phenomena
you put the fig over your
stomach and if your arm goes weak
you're allergic to figs
was sort of a very primitive
first application of it
so it saw it as a local phenomena
and tried to give a local
explanation
when I saw it
I saw wow
this is connection between mind and body
and I saw that
what is answering the question is not
the body at all
but consciousness
the body doesn't know anything
there are books that tell you
your body knows everything
I got news for you
your body doesn't know anything
it's a complete idiot
I don't ask my body anything
it's a stupid thing
what did I have for breakfast this morning
it doesn't say
it doesn't know what I had for breakfast this morning
don't look to the body for salvation
it's there for fun
pleasure
it's a pet
I discovered my body as a pet
because after I came out of a
state in which
the mind became silent and still
the mind is still silent and still
if I listen to it now
I don't hear anything
it doesn't say anything
it doesn't think anything
it came into that state
and here is this body walking around
it seemed to do fine by itself in space
there's nobody running it
there's no you running it
it's running itself
it doesn't need you at all
you see what it does by itself
it doesn't need me at all
see what it does by itself
it does it by itself
I never know what it's going to do until it does it
wow
actually the body is a nuisance
to me it's a nuisance
why people price it
it's always in your way
no matter what you want to do
your body is in the way to do it
you've got to keep it there
you've got to park it someplace
think what it costs you to keep this thing going
it's a phenomena
I'll be happy goodbye
you don't have to drag it around every place
it's like luggage or something
so what I saw was
the consciousness was
responding just as you saw
with Susan this morning
the answer then
is that consciousness recognizes reality
anything that calibrates over time
that which is below 200
then makes you go strong
which is fallacious
which has no truth
it's not right and wrong
or yes and no
the kinesiologic response is
yes and not yes
nature cannot answer with a no
it can answer with a yes
or it doesn't answer at all
so when our arm goes weak
that's not a no
it's a not yes
we have a slide here
I don't know if we'll get to it
on quantum mechanics
connecting quantum mechanics
with kinesiology and consciousness research
but in line with quantum mechanics
the theory of quantum mechanics
the universe can only answer yes
and it cannot answer with no
through the Heisenberg principle
you can collapse the wave function
through consciousness
and that's how we as spiritual people
influence the collective consciousness of mankind
as each one of us makes a positive
we can collapse the wave function
of potentiality into actuality
and actually change the field
we actually have an influence on the field
so everybody
praying quietly
every forgiveness
every act of kindness
every time you see a little beetle
that you have to just turn him over
so he can get on his way
and give him a twig
so he gets a foothold again
that changes the universe
every act of kindness is noticed
and it's true
scripture says every hair of your head
shall be counted
that's an absolute fact
every hair of your head
is known and counted
not only is it known and counted
but it's knowable and countable forever
within the field of consciousness
every single thought
feeling, decision, action
is registered forever
outside of time and space
because it is beyond form
and time and space
it is indestructible
how can you destroy that which has no form
the thing has to have form
to destroy it
so that means that everything that ever happened
in the history of the universe
is retrievable
now
in one instant
what Napoleon thought or felt
when he walked in the pyramid
what he thought and felt
when he walked out of the pyramid
how he felt about whoever his girlfriend was at the time
what they had for breakfast
we used to check on Saddam what he had for breakfast
when we did these
we used to check what he had for breakfast that morning
everything is knowable
everything is knowable within an instant
the only requirement is that the people
asking the question are doing so
from a position of integrity
they themselves have to calibrate
over 200
and the question itself has to be integrous
that means your devotion
is to the truth and not to
finding some agreement
you don't have to ask me
what about President Bush
there's also some idiot in the back
what about Saddam Hussein
so if you're looking to reinforce
a belief system
you've got your own ideas of good and evil
and then you want to use it to
prove what you already believe
that's not the way you do science
you do science with no presumptions
to begin with
you're devoted to the truth
because the pathway to God
is through
truth, absolute truth
devotional non-duality means then
to go beyond the ego
to transcend the ego
and one's devotion is to truth
so if the intention
of asking a question then
is to discern what is the absolute truth
then the results
are relatively accurate
the test is done quickly
it's a very fast test
the answer only lasts a few seconds
and if you delay you won't get a
good result
what you'll get is what I call
the falling out of the tree recovery
because the arm when it falls
in the primitive ape in you
think it's falling out of a tree
and it begins to try to right itself
so you have to catch the response quickly
otherwise the body will
let's say a flash of weakness
it will begin to resist that weakness
and it wants to hang into the tree
and not follow the tree
so the trick is done very very quickly
people ask us about it
this is the technique we're telling you
you use very little pressure
two fingers and you press down
and I say resist
and so I'm not using a lot of pressure
and she's not pushing back
with a lot of pressure
you can do it delicately
so because I compare it with other things
I can tell
so if I say a bear is a friendly animal
resist
see it's a very quick response
a bear is not a friendly animal
he can be taught to be semi-friendly
not really friendly
he's good because he gets rewarded for being good
but he's not really friendly
as we said last night
when you're in a spiritual despair
you've got two little friends in the universe
ready to rescue you
one is to know that a kitty's purr
calibrates at 500
and that a dog's wagging tail
so those are two things I said last night
and I wanted to repeat them again today
how can it be that
through the evolution of consciousness
that a kitty
a kitty's purr is 500
where's our
somebody keeps taking that off on us
every time we try that
a kitty's purr is 500
you know
love
a kitty's purr is 500
the essence of love
and the dog's wagging tail is 500
a dog that just loves everybody
and makes friends with everybody
who comes to the house
has to greet everybody
so instead of some long gone
the statue of some long gone saint
when you're not feeling too good spiritually
it's better to picture
a purring kitty
get into the kitty's purr
because there you've got unconditional love
in the dog's wagging tail
so how is it that these two animals
bypass
something like 90% of humanity
90% of humanity
never gets to be a purring kitty
or a wagging dog tail
that's a curiosity
why that happened
alright
so on the calibrated level of consciousness
then what we discovered was
I forget how we started doing it
we used kinesiology then
we started using it
in abstract questions
and things throughout time and space
we did all the Greek atheism
we did cathedrals
we did countries
writers, authors
movies we've calibrated
just about everything on the planet
current book we've done 3000 calibrations
and we're only half way through
if she holds up
we'll finish the book
well we do a run
when she's in the mood
then she'll say I can't do anymore
we did 100 movies I can't do anymore
I know
we found that then you could calibrate
these are the classical levels of consciousness
which have been traditional throughout the centuries
at the very bottom
we've got the very lowest
shame and guilt
apathy, grief
then it comes up to fear
then desire, greed
anger, rage, hatred
pride, courage
these make you go weak
this is the domain of the ego
this is where most people on the planet live
most of the time
and from a spiritual viewpoint
traditionally these have been condemned
not only do you have this
but you feel guilty about it
in case you don't
the nearest church will inform you
you should be doing penance
there's another way of looking at it
you see the way to God is through joy
through happiness
and through truth
it's not through self condemnation
anger, self pity
resentment and guilt
crawling on your knees from here
to the nearest cathedral
may be impressive
I don't know if it will make you enlightened
another way of viewing these things
from a positive viewpoint
is each one of these is an improvement
over that which is below it
alright
in the office they bring in a patient
I've done psychiatry for 50 years
they bring in an old lady
who sits there and rocks and won't eat
looks off into space
take this pill mother
it will make you feel better
she just rocks and looks off into space
way down here
apathy
apathetic
as we'll see later
if we ever get to the slides
whole continents live here
continents
not just individual people
we'll show you continents
that calibrate at 60
whole continents
where the entire population
this is where they calibrate
not enough energy to feed themselves
not enough energy to control their
own behavior
dying right and left of AIDS
and disease
and starvation
and malnutrition
and infection
and if they manage to survive
a neighboring tribe will slaughter them anyway
average age of death 12 and a half
average age of death in those countries
12 and a half
the survival very slim
now
you can see
that we say fear is awful
but you see
if you had the energy
enough energy to be fearful
you could do something about the apathy
you can run like hell
in fear right
in fear you can build buildings
fortresses
if you're scared of starving to death
it's amazing what you can do
just with your fingers
it's bad viewed from here
but viewed from here
this is a great improvement
a major jump is to desire
when you get people out of apathy
so the benefit of television
to the world is that
cultures that live down here in apathy
look on television
and they say
whoa look how those people live
you begin to want something
so for them to awaken the solar plexus
is a major improvement
these people are down here
they don't have the energy
to go to the bathroom
it's true
in a nursing home
they don't have the energy
to go to the bathroom
so if you can get them up to fear
fear of starvation
fear of overpopulation
overpopulation
will drive you into starvation
you begin to desire
a higher level of living
and now you get angry
that you don't have it
anger then
has a lot of energy
you can do a lot out of anger
and a lot out of desire
and then pride
feeds more energy back into it
so you enlist people into the Marines
based on pride
but the Marines
don't want you to hang out in pride
because people in pride
are a pain in the neck
you want to get them up to courage
pride gets you into service
but courage is what it takes to face the enemy
so then
you finally have launched over
first step in the 12 step program
this is
the courage to tell the truth
that without God's help
it's unlikely that my consciousness
is going to evolve
much less become enlightened
without God's help
I'm helpless without God's help
so you see weakness then
comes from the ego
dealing with the ego
and power comes from the field
and when this says
I am myself and I'm unable to accomplish this
and I must turn to the field
well the power of the field
is infinite
there's nothing the power of the field can't do
so as we surrender
our will to God
and ask God to
we ask to understand God's will for us
now we're invoking
the power of the field
the ego within itself
is looking to its ego
and other egos
vote for me
buy my product
fear my gun
whatever it is
now we're invoking
the power of the field
so as you begin to surrender
to the power of the field
when you fall overboard
in the ocean
and you give all this up
and you surrender to God
suddenly you find that you can float
I was in the navy
and a minesweeper
I got swept off
and all I had to do was float
whoa
I was in the Huangpu river of all places in Shanghai
with dead bodies
and God knows what else in the water
you had to not think about that
but
I floated along and what do you know
here was a warship
they were docked side by side
and I'm carrying down this strong current
and here's the prow of a warship right ahead of me
and I'm headed right for this thing
and I just went like this against the prow
and the water kept me there
and then they came and got me
so you see the power of the field saved my life
if I kept struggling I would have killed myself
so the power of the field
so our survival then
is up to the field
so the ego claims credit
for our survival
but the power of our survival
is within the field
it's the field that decides
to pull the chocks out
when the moment of physical death
arises
so there's a lot of good news this morning
one is that the moment of your death
is already set
so you can forget worrying about it
you don't have to worry whether asparagus
is going to shorten your life
I mean it's not going to shorten your life
if it's death by a scary asparagus
that's what it'll be
everybody is so fearful in our society
and you know
science in the public interest
is something I was telling you
some new horror story
when you get out of the car
you have a higher case of being killed in an accident
so everybody moves to the left rear
being on the highway in the first place
is a risk factor
so why are you driving if you're so scared of everything
you've got to eat this
with kernels on it
you get blocked in by all these fears
and belief systems
because the ego is telling you
I'm going to save you boy
I'll tell you
in the end it's not
the other good news
is that it's not possible
to experience your own physical death
that is not a possibility
those of you who have died
and decided to come back in the body
are aware of that
how many people have had near death experiences
not so many here
anyway
those who had near death experiences
those who calibrated over 600
and remember past lifetimes
remember that in one instant you're in the body
next minute you're out and you're looking at it
and there it is laying there
and you can't experience your own physical death
so I just thought
that might be helpful
because so many people are afraid of
physical death
and you can't experience it
nobody can experience physical death
because the you is no longer there
and if it's not there
how can they experience what's there
when it's here
how many people here have gone out of body
out of body
more out of bodies than near deathers
ok
well you know the instant you're out of body
the you is up here
and the body is down there
but that which is me
is up here
the me is up here
the sense of self
me, I
the focus of your existence
has nothing to do with the physicality
because the physicality is laying down there
alright so
this is the beginning of spiritual truth
calibrates at 200
the arm goes strong
one is empowered by truth
beyond that
you go to neutrality
courage is
you still can feel fear
in courage
you can still feel fear
but walk into the bullets anyway
and many a lifetime
is often gone through
before one is finally
for a higher principle, a higher cause
willing to face the bullets
and actually die for the cause
and then they have conquered all of this
beyond that
is a more comfortable level called neutral
neutral
it's ok if you get the job
it's ok if you don't
willingness is an even higher energy level
neutral she serves you your breakfast
she takes your order in the restaurant
but she doesn't really look you in the eye
willingness is how can I help you
so we're getting closer and closer to Walmart
as we get up there
laughter
we did all the corporations in America
you know
I know there's Walmart haters out there
and you'll have to forgive me
but anyway
whether people like it or not Walmart calibrates
higher than any corporation in the world
it is also the largest corporation in the world
it also has the biggest bottom line
so what's strange about Walmart
is that they
tend to be friendly
how can I help you
if you don't like the product bring it back
we give you your money
so he bought the product
on sale
you were thinking it'd I
the videos
you don't have to
and it was
good
some people
but
well
if you do
them
make money
there's no
Calvary's higher than any corporation in the world.
So that's interesting, that spiritual principles,
when they're applied to everyday life, are not airy-fairy.
Spiritual principles of integrity
are the most profoundly important thing in business.
It's integrity that shows up on the bottom line.
So you've got the example of Walmart.
Walmart's the biggest corporation in the world,
the whole world, not just the U.S.,
and the most profitable, biggest corporation in the world
based on spiritual principles.
Isn't that marvelous?
So it's not exactly airy-fairy, airy-fairy.
So when people try to establish spiritual principles in business,
don't call them spiritual.
Don't call them spiritual.
Just say integrity pays off, and Walmart is a prime example.
And we see Enron and those companies
where the opposite was applied.
All collapsed.
All right, so the validity, then, of integrity
as the basis of everyday practical life.
Then we move on up to acceptance,
which is a very comfortable thing,
and reason and the intellect.
So America calibrates around 425, 431, around there.
That's the world of reason and the intellect.
That's also the reason of logic.
The intellect.
The intellect will take you as far as Einstein.
Einstein calibrates at 499.
Sir Isaac Newton, who invented the differential calculus
and the Newtonian paradigm of reality,
which is the home of causality, 499.
Einstein, 499.
Sir Isaac Newton, 499.
Sigmund Freud, 499.
So that's pushing the intellect as far as you can go.
Pushing the intellect as far as you can go.
What happened with Einstein,
then, was at the Solvay Conference,
Copenhagen, on quantum mechanics.
The problem was facing the implication,
the metaphysical, philosophic implication
of the Heisenberg principle.
The discovery that on the microscopic,
submicroscopic level,
that merely observation already changes the result.
The introduction of human consciousness
already changes the result,
collapses the wave function,
and brings,
out a new reality.
So the potentiality becomes an actuality,
and the trigger is merely human observation.
At that time, there was all the big leading people,
I mean, theoretical physics, Bohm,
and all the people there.
And Einstein said,
you see, what we're talking about is a paradigm jump.
Einstein said, I prefer to think.
There's an observable, verifiable, objective world
that exists.
It exists independent of human observation.
Independent.
And at that point, he sealed himself off at 499.
Because the jump to 500 is a different paradigm.
They are jumping from the objective to the subjective.
See, love is subjective.
You can't prove love.
You can't measure love.
So the scientific dictum that if you can't measure it or weigh it,
it isn't real, you know, is idiotic, right, on the surface.
Because that's a subjective concept.
That's a subjective conclusion on the first place.
It's radical subjectivity to assume that some proposition is true.
So the beginning of spiritual reality, as we understand it,
it calibrates 500 and up.
The world of the kitty purr.
The domain of the wagging tail.
Rare is the individual in our world who calibrates at 500.
Hmm.
Four percent.
Four percent of humanity calibrates 500 or over.
Four percent of all the people on this earth ever get to consciousness level 500.
Love at 500 is still conditional.
So the dog will love just about everybody, but occasionally he won't.
So it's a little bit conditional.
Otherwise, he'd calibrate at 540.
540 is unconditional love.
That's interesting.
Unconditional love, then, is practically saintly.
It is, oddly enough, 540 is a calibrated level of AA and all the 12-step programs.
Unconditional love.
A guy in AA goes out and gets drunk.
He drives over four people, destroys his car, burns down the house.
He goes back to a meeting, and they say,
George, we're sure glad you're back.
Now, only one concern.
That's this man's spiritual recovery.
Period.
All the rest.
They leave for the world.
And A Course in Miracles, of course, calibrates at 600.
So 500 is extremely rare.
540, 0.4% of the world's population ever reaches 540.
By 570, we consider them saints.
Father Pio, all the great spiritual writers, Dalai Lama, the Pope, all those people are in 570, around in there.
We consider them saintly.
To transcend saintliness, then, is another dimension.
And it takes one to 600, in which the mind is transcended altogether.
Everything becomes silent, beatific.
One is outside time, space, dimension, position.
And the body is irrelevant.
And if the world and karmically...
Karmically is actually a karmic inheritance.
If the body is destined to continue, then friendly...
People and supportive beings will appear that encourage you to hang into the body, and feed it, and clothe it, and all kinds of things that they seem to be interested in.
All right.
Otherwise, 50% of the people, once they hit 600, will leave the body.
And if you've ever gone to a bliss state, you realize how easy that would be.
If you've been in a divine state, you know that whether it continues or not is irrelevant.
Because the experience...
The experience is beyond physicality, and one loses one's interest in the world of appearance, huh?
600 is extremely rare.
One in 10 million people, huh?
The other odd thing that happens at 600...
Well, not really quite at 600, but 600 or over, is the recall of past lives.
There's no longer identification with this physicality or the mind, because you think...
When you think my life, what you mean is...
The memory of this body, and this fixed quantum of mentation, when you stop identifying with the physicality and the mind, when you're beyond mind and body, then all the lifetimes are one lifetime.
And significant events happen in each one of profound spiritual implication, and those you remember, because they were powerful lessons.
That's why...
That life went that way, was to learn that lesson, to learn that you are a spirit, for instance.
So, at the oars of a slave ship, in a state of agony and semi-starvation and dehydration, in a stench that's unbelievable, under extreme cruelty, you suddenly get, you don't have to be trapped, you're not a prisoner, you can just leave the body and die.
Wham!
Out of body.
Ha ha ha.
You thought you were caught in an endless torture chamber.
How stupid.
So, you realize that you could just let the body die, and you're free of it.
Huh.
I tell old people that in the nursing homes all the time.
They call me in, tell them it's okay to die.
You know.
I was the psychiatrist for all the nursing homes in the county, because there wasn't any other psychiatrist who's willing to do it, to go and see all these old people.
And they'd be going back to the nursing home, and they'd be saying, here's the body.
people going back and forth in a wheelchair,
help, help, help, help.
And I look at her and I say,
Granny, what's the matter?
Help, help, and you know,
they won't let me die.
It's against Medicare regulations
to let a patient die.
She wants to please pull all these tubes out
and let me be in peace, you know?
Just as she goes off in peace,
they stick some more tubes
and pump some more things in her
and force her to keep breathing and yeah, so.
All right, so then the higher levels of consciousness,
of course, are traditional throughout history
and they're extremely rare.
Most of those people do not stay around.
Those who reach like 700 and on
seldom become teachers or anything.
They usually withdraw from the world
if they continue to exist.
And rarely do they come to the attention of the world
and the ability to speak, the ability to speak.
And when such a state comes on,
it's necessary
to really leave the world.
There's no way you can relate to the world.
There's nothing you can say about it.
There's no way to describe it.
There's nothing to describe.
The profound change cannot be communicated.
So usually nothing is said about it at all,
except through accidentally getting dragged back
into the world to speak of it.
So those are the ineffable states.
The transcending of the ego.
So today we want to really address that more intensely.
First, we have sort of a map of consciousness
to tell us where we're going.
And let's go on to the next one then.
We want to show the distribution of the levels
of consciousness in mankind.
So the population of the world,
this is the population of the world, you see.
To reach 1,000 is, one person to 1,000 is,
counterbalances the entire negativity over here.
200 or one or two at 700 counterbalances
the total negativity of all of mankind.
Two or three here counterbalances all of mankind.
Because you see, here's the world's population,
calibrates at 200, but less than 200.
So the great mass of mankind then,
the mass of mankind is here.
Here's where most Americans live,
where an audience like this lives right about in here.
And you see how few in number they are.
But collectively, the people in this realm
are also counterbalancing the negative.
So, if it weren't for those
of a higher level of consciousness,
you can see that the world's population would self-destruct.
Because the power of these people though,
see these calibrated levels are,
decimal, I mean are logarithm to base 10.
These are logarithmic.
Consequently, the increase of one point here,
is quite sizable because it's the logarithm
of going up to the base 10.
So, the power of these people is so enormous
that they can counterbalance the mass of these people.
These people are massive in number,
but they are deficient in power.
So, only a few individuals then,
who are spiritually evolved,
are already counterbalancing huge numbers of people
at the other end of the spectrum.
Where's the next one?
Ah, yes.
We were talking about duality,
transcending good and evil,
which is a very difficult one.
To understand how the ego works then,
it adopts a positionality.
It takes a position about something,
and once you take a position about something,
you've now divided the world into the opposites.
The polarities of good and evil,
hot and cold, et cetera.
As we tried to explain early this morning then,
by seeing it differently,
you can transcend the opposites
and see that there are no such things as opposites,
that there's actually only one variable.
As an example, let's take hot and cold.
People say, well, hot and cold are opposites.
Well, if we put them all on the same scale,
we'll see there are not two opposites of hot and cold.
There's only the presence of heat or not.
There's only one variable.
And that is the presence of heat.
Get lots of heat, we call it hot.
As the heat goes down, the temperature goes down,
but you're not into two opposites now.
Heat is not the opposite of cold.
So this is not its opposite.
This is merely a designation for convenience.
There's only one variable present.
In all dualistic seeming polarities,
there are not two opposites.
There's only one variable.
And when you see the one variable,
you realize you can dissolve the so-called polarity
of the opposites, which is the great blockade to enlightenment.
Classically, the great blockade to enlightenment is getting stuck
in the polarity of the opposites,
seeming polarity of the opposites.
We'll use another system.
You say things are good and things are worthless.
Things are good and bad and awful.
All right.
We skipped that one in a hurry.
On this one, we've got varying degrees of love.
No.
You want to do that one?
I don't care.
Here, you have desirability.
You see, there's only one variable.
And we value a thing.
There's only one variable, and that's our desire for that thing.
Things are not good and bad, desirable and repulsive.
You either desire them or you don't.
You may consider swallowing the entrails of a spiny creature
at the bottom of the sea, whether that's a delicacy
or repulsive.
Depends on your viewpoint.
What was that spiny black thing at the bottom of the sea?
The black, spiny thing?
Whatever it is, anyway, some parts of the world,
swallowing its intestines is a great delicacy,
and it makes other people nauseated to think of it.
So, is it precious, valuable, worthwhile?
Should we pay a lot of money for it on our sushi dinner
or whatever you call that?
Or is it repulsive?
Well, okay, let's go to the next one.
Yeah.
So, the next one, we have the presence of love or not, see?
It's either there's the presence of love
or there's not the presence of love.
There either is love or not love.
On the right-hand side, you see there are not opposites
of light and darkness.
Those are not opposites.
See, we're showing you how to transcend good and evil,
which is the tough one, but once you see the paradigm here,
you'll see light is present or not present to varying degrees,
but there isn't a thing called light.
There's no light against a thing called darkness, huh?
You can see there's only one variable, light.
There's lots of it or not so much of it,
and lots of it.
So, we turn the light down.
Eventually, so there are no real opposites.
You see, because we give language to a thing,
we think it must exist in reality.
That's the problem of the intellect.
That's why one can't become enlightened through the intellect,
but only by transcending the intellect,
because the intellect will always, you know,
propose something and then project it in the world
and think that it exists in the world.
It, you know, causality is an explanation.
It's a mentation.
It's an intellectualization.
It exists only as a mentalization.
Nobody can find any causality in the universe anywhere.
It doesn't exist out there.
It's a concept projected onto, okay?
That's an important jump in consciousness
because there you shift paradigm
from form and structure,
which is the limitation of the ego in the 400s,
and you begin to move into subjective reality
because the absolute reality that people are looking for
in all spiritual work is completely subjective.
That's why theology calibrates in the high 400s.
Theology will take you through the 400s,
philosophy and theology, and the answer is the conundrums.
I have all the great books
of the Western world at home.
They calibrate around 465.
The answer to the enigmas of existence
and divinity cannot be found through the intellect.
They can be talked about.
So theology calibrates around 465.
Let's see if that's so.
We have permission to ask that here.
Theology as a science calibrates over 460, 465, 470, 480.
Okay, epistemology calibrates over 475, 480.
Epistemology, hmm, well, the answer is that theology,
you know, philosophy takes you into theology,
and then theology, you hit dead ends,
and the answers then take you into epistemology.
Epistemology is how does man know in the first place?
How can we know?
Because the riddles that have baffled the world
are the ones that are the most important to us.
Okay?
They baffle the philosophers over the centuries, you know.
Eventually, you run up against,
well, how do we even know anything?
How do we know that anything?
How do we know that we know?
Then that is the question of epistemology.
We see it calibrates around 475.
Of course, the answer is really by revelation, subjectively.
That's how you transcend to the next paradigm.
You have to leave the intellect altogether.
You have to, you cannot prove the kiddies' fur.
You cannot prove the doggies' wagging tail.
You cannot prove love and compassion.
You cannot prove why you stop and turn a little beetle
over on his feet so he can get going again
before the sun comes out and shrivels him up.
Why do you suddenly care about that little black beetle?
Actually, you don't really care.
It isn't that you care about it,
because that's an attachment.
It's that that's the kind of being you have become.
So 500,
that's what love really means then.
Love is not an emotion.
It goes from here to there, from me to you,
and therefore it's vulnerable.
If love is just an emotion,
then you end up with homicide and suicide.
That's the setup, isn't it?
If it goes from here to there,
well, you don't own it, now it's vulnerable,
and the other person can say bye now,
then you have to kill them.
Or whoever persuaded them to leave you,
you have to kill them both, better, you know?
And at the end of that, you have to kill yourself.
So that, there's the whole human tragedy
without which we couldn't have any operas.
We go to all the operas and watch all the,
we love you, sweetheart, out there,
and then they go through the agony and the jealousy
and then they all stab themselves, you know?
And then the curtain comes down, dun, dun, dun, dun.
Encapsulates.
That's the whole human tragedy, yeah.
Now, what happens as a result of spiritual work,
you know, and dedication,
is that you become the love of lovingness.
So, love is a way of being.
It's what you have become.
It's not what you do, it's not what you feel,
it's what you are.
It's because of what you are,
you turn the little black beetle over, see?
It isn't that you love them, and if you get squashed,
you're not gonna grieve.
Oh, you might.
You might be a little black beetle,
but then you catch yourself emotionalizing about it,
and you disconnect from that, too.
So then, love is not an attachment,
it's a way of being in the world,
a way of being in the world.
It's a necessary part of the evolution of consciousness
to become enlightened,
because the ultimate realization is God is allness,
the allness of God.
It's important to see that at this point, because,
it's important to see that at this point, because,
there are certain branches of Buddhism,
which I am at liberty to speak of having been there,
they will teach that love is another attachment.
Now, emotional love as an attachment is a hindrance,
but love as a way of being, then,
love is one of the attributes of God,
and if you negate the divinity of love,
you end up in the void,
and I've been in the void, it's very, very impressive.
And if the void was real,
I wouldn't be here to tell you about it.
The void is not the ultimate,
the pathway of negation, negation then,
has a zinger in it, you gotta watch it.
God is the infinite allness of existence.
Out of the unmanifest arises the manifest,
arises consciousness, arises all of creation.
God is the allness out of which all arises
and has its existence.
You know, I understand the void,
the void calibrates about 900 and something or other,
and it is extremely impressive,
except you can't stay there.
And then you come back the next lifetime,
still in the void of nothingness, bang,
suddenly confronted with existence.
You still haven't handled it.
You're not beyond existence versus non-existence
is the ultimate reality.
And that's where this lifetime started at age three.
Out of oblivion, absolute oblivion,
void, nothingness, suddenly there was a shock.
Like out of the darkness,
all of a sudden all the light's going on,
and I'm shocked with existence.
A three-year-old doesn't know the word existence.
Didn't think existence.
But the knowingness of existence as existence
was like a shock, profound confrontation.
I was not happy with it either.
I was not happy with being confronted
with existence at all.
I voided it out, and here I am confronted with it again.
As soon as existence was faced as an experiential reality,
it was an experiential reality.
Instantly the fear of non-existence came up.
If you exist, it could have come about
that you would not have existed.
And so there was the duality of existence
versus non-existence as the ultimate reality.
Another conundrum, the Calvary said 850 to resolve,
and it took 50 years to do it, yeah.
So that's interesting how life starts right out
with the unfinished spiritual business that you're left with.
It's like it's the confrontation of the next life, huh?
All right, so we've handled now
the most difficult dualities to be faced,
and we handled them early in the game instead of late.
And the reason we did is we wanted to take their structure
out from underneath them.
The structure is the belief that things are the opposites
of each other, which is not a possibility.
That's a mental positionality, yeah.
There's only one variable.
All right, so now we've handled good versus evil and existence
versus non-existence, so as you get close to the door
of enlightenment, these will not come up and hit you.
Okay, we'll go to the next one.
Ah, yeah.
The mind.
We said it's based on positionalities,
and it tends to become enamored of itself.
The interesting thing about the mind, people say,
well, to become enlightened or to become very spiritually evolved,
it's necessary to transcend the mind,
first to educate the mind about spiritual matters,
but eventually you realize you're confronted
with having to transcend it all altogether.
And the mind is structured then on certain positionalities,
and we tried to talk about the dualistic,
polarities which are traditionally the blocks
to enlightenment, how to transcend the mind itself.
Well, we learned a lot of interesting things this morning.
The next most interesting thing, and all the things
that I tell you are gratifying and things to make you happy,
so you'll be real happy on the way home,
is that 99% of your mind is already silent.
You will think, how am I going to quiet this mind?
I meditate and it just chatters on and on.
Ninety-nine percent of your mind, or is it 98%?
Ninety-nine percent.
Uh-oh, is it 98% or 99%?
Oh, I wrote 98%.
Oh, well, 98% of your mind is silent.
Now, you think when you listen to your mind,
when you're meditating and it's thinking about this,
imaging that, remembering that, and anticipating that,
that you can't seem to get your mind to be silent,
and people become very frustrated and they give up meditation,
because it's very frustrating.
All I do is just sit there and think my thoughts,
which I do anyway when I'm driving,
so I'm wasting time and I'm not going to be a good Buddhist anyway.
I don't like fish, and I don't like hamburgers,
and I like killing bugs, so I'm a lousy Buddhist, give up.
So, you can become a Unitarian or join Unity, it's coming.
So, what is going on?
This seeming horror.
It's a horrible block to enlightenment.
What is going on with this?
And there are all kinds of tomes and great establishments
dedicated to meditation and meditation techniques
with fancy sounding names, et cetera.
The fact is, if you look at mind,
if you look at your mind right now,
I will tell you one fact about it.
Ninety-eight percent of your mind is already silent.
Only one or two percent of your mind is thinking at all.
What's happened is that you're focused on this one or two percent.
It's like you're in a giant empty auditorium,
a giant stadium.
Only one or two percent of your mind is thinking at all.
What's happened is that you're focused on this one or two percent.
It's like you're in a giant empty auditorium,
a giant stadium.
Everybody's gone home.
You're the only one there, and way over in the corner,
you've got a four-by-five-inch old black and white TV,
and you're glued to it.
It's the only action.
There's nothing going on around here.
So, you say, boy, this is a noisy stadium.
There's no noise in the stadium.
It's just that you're glued to this little four-by-five-inch
black and white TV set.
All right, so now I'll give you another secret truth,
and that is that you're hypnotized by the one percent.
Ninety-eight percent of your mind is silent,
and I'll demonstrate it to you this morning.
Only one or two percent is active,
and what's happened is that you're the hypnotic victim.
You have become hypnotized, and you're in a hypnotic state
of this one or two percent,
in a hypnotic, post-hypnotic state of suggestion
in which you think that you are the one percent that's going on
because it's the only program on the dial.
.
To merely know that, certain knowledge advances consciousness rapidly just by hearing it.
Just to know that you are not the victim of your mind, that 98% of your mind is silent.
Alright, so to know that you are merely in a hypnotic state.
This hypnotic state then is of the 1% that's going on in the corner,
which you then tend to identify with because it's the only program going on in this empty stadium.
We tried to take apart causality this morning because that's going to become critical to know when you want to transcend mind.
The mind thinks that one thought is causing another.
So, the mind thinks...
The mind thinks that...
The thought dog chases cat up and then the tree.
Now, because it believes in sequential causality, it thinks that each one of these things is causing the next thing.
There we go.
It thinks the mind...
Here's the way the linear person believes the mind works.
And we've already taken out its underpinnings this morning.
So that what I say next morning...
This will make sense to you.
It thinks this is how it's working.
Now, the Buddha said the ultimate reality is realizable between two thoughts.
That's not the best form of expression and I've told him so.
I said, Buddha buddy, here's the way I look at it.
And he agreed, it's better.
He said, you got 2,000 years to think about it, you know what I'm saying?
Naturally, 2,000 years is the only way you can think about it.
So, if you meditate like I did when I first read about Zen and started going to Zen Institute and all,
you start looking between these thoughts.
You're waiting for between dog and cat and run up tree there's going to be a little space that you can see God through there.
You're going to wait a long time, folks, because these flow so fast you can't get between them.
There is no space between the thoughts.
All right.
And they do not occur this way.
Because if they occur this way, you can't get between them, huh?
How does thought really arise?
Well, here's the deliverance from being dominated by the ego.
Each thought, like creation, arises individually as a separate and individual creation out of nothing.
Out of nothingness, out of the great void, which is not the ultimate reality,
which it was thought by some Hinyana Buddhist.
Out of the void arises dog, arises cat, arises up, arises tree.
Each one, each concept is an original creation out of nothing.
This is not created out of this.
This is not an endless string of billiard balls and you can't get between the two billiard balls.
Dog comes up, then cat comes up, then up comes up, and then tree comes up.
And this is silence.
Out of silence, each thought arises as an original creation.
If you watch your thinkingness, then, instead of watching for this linear sequence,
saying, oh, God, please help me forget about how I let old Rover get hit by the car,
that's this whole long sequence.
You'll see that the thought is coming up piecemeal.
First, this component, out of a silent nothingness void,
arises this as an original creation.
If the basis of existence was causality,
you would not be able to interrupt the train of thought
because the train of thought is continuous and goes on forever.
There is no break in a train of thought.
The reason you can break through it is because this thought is not caused by this thought at all.
Each one of these thoughts arises independently,
and from here down, the mind is silent.
Here, 99% of this mind is silent, empty,
and each thought now arises independently.
The fact that they take some kind of a meaningful form
is because within consciousness there are certain designs,
certain designs which have been made famous by an English scientist
whose name I can't think of at the moment.
The things before they exist within the physical domain
already exist within consciousness as a pattern waiting for expression.
You got it, Rupert Sheldrake's Morphic Fields.
All right, so the Morphic Fields then exist within consciousness.
So out of silence, within consciousness,
there's a million patterns created by mankind
so that the potentiality for form exists
and this already is like a blueprint of energy.
That's our karmic pattern.
And within consciousness, there is the potentiality of all these various forms.
All right, so if you think you are this,
then you are in for a tough life,
which is 99% of people on the planet.
If you realize that you are this,
then you realize your mind is silent
because to go from silence into form
requires intention, intention.
And here you can catch that all thinkingness
is coming out of your personal intention to think
because you become hypnotized and fascinated
with thinkingness itself.
All right, you can catch this in meditation.
You can catch this in meditation.
You look at a tone of music.
You see, as a tone of music, as the note is struck,
it rises to your attention.
But as the note of music rises to your attention,
it's already beginning to fall, is it not?
It only is at the peak for a split 10,000th of a second.
No sooner has a tone of music become apparent to the ear
than it's already falling away.
So every experience can be viewed as a wave.
People who live in fear
then are always trying to anticipate
the front of the wave.
The experience comes up and then it's gone.
Some people are always trying to get one up on the next instant.
Fearful, they're constantly on guard, paranoid, fearful,
trying to control everything.
So they don't live in the joy of the present.
They live in the fear of the future
and constantly trying to control.
What will I say when he says this?
What will I wear? What will people think?
Which way shall I turn?
What will happen if I run out of insurance?
What if they fire me?
They just live on the fear of the future.
So they're living in advance of the wave of reality.
How can you experience reality
which is only experiential on the crest of the wave
when you're focused on the front of the wave, you know?
People hang into the past.
There are other people who ruminate all the time.
They never live on the crest of now
because they're always reworking what happened.
I should have said this. I'll show that guy.
Next time he tries that with me,
you know what I mean?
You're trying to rewrite history.
All the people busy in the academic world now
are trying to rewrite history.
To live on the crest of the moment
means the willingness to relinquish
the willfulness of editorializing about experience.
The human's will is to editorialize,
constantly change shape and control the experience.
Either try to fool reality by anticipating it
or refuse to let go of it by clinging to it.
So the technique of meditation
that brings you into an awareness of the presence as silence
is the willingness to surrender each thing as it arises.
The surrenderingness is as each thing peaks into awareness.
As it arises, we surrender it to God.
The willingness to surrender
everything to God as it comes into awareness.
Then, if you keep doing that,
you get earlier and earlier in the pattern of thought.
You begin to catch it here at Sheldrakes.
Thank you very much.
I couldn't think of his name at this point.
You begin to catch it here as it begins to take form.
As it begins to take form.
Because thoughts are not unlike the rest of creation.
Each species, each genus comes off the evolutionary branch.
Separately.
You don't see links between the various branches.
It comes off as this and then it comes off as that.
But you don't see any evolutionary half-zebra, half-horse.
You know what I'm saying?
The zebra comes off, the horse comes off.
Neanderthal man comes off, magnetoman comes off.
But you don't see evolution as a slow progression
from one genus and species into another.
What you see is the advancement on the stem of life energy itself.
It emerges as this and then more advanced as this
and then more advanced as that.
So homo sapien is not an improvement on chromomagnon man.
He's something different.
He's not an improvement on Neanderthal man.
You don't see Neanderthal man slowly becoming homo sapien.
No.
Each one comes off separately.
Each one is a different expression of Sheldrake's morphogenetic field.
Evolution occurs on the level of consciousness.
Then it manifests out as an expression of the form
that is held within consciousness.
So the evolution of form then happens on the level of consciousness
and then expresses itself within the manifest, visible,
domain.
That brings up an interesting conundrum,
which I haven't figured out yet.
Who was the mother of the first human being,
the first homo sapien?
Because if each branch doesn't become the next branch,
suddenly there's a new branch called homo sapien.
Who was the mother of the first human being?
It wasn't an ape because evolution doesn't occur out there.
It occurs on the level of consciousness.
Why do we humans even get ourselves born?
Also, not only are we born, but we've got no fur.
Seventy man finds himself born with no fur.
What the hell do you do?
No clothes and no fur.
No hooves.
How do you walk across the desert with these kind of feet?
Tell me that.
You can't climb rocks.
What can he do?
He hasn't got wings to fly.
He's a pathetic creature, isn't he?
Stark naked, no fur, no wings, no claws.
No big teeth.
No hooves.
And you're supposed to survive.
Oh, boy.
We were the losers in some big crap game, weren't we?
You get no fur.
You get no clothes.
You get no money when you get there.
No hooves, no paws.
No friends, no mama, no daddy.
All right.
All right, we're trying to transcend the mind.
Things I'm saying are not irrelevant to the ultimate conclusion,
which is your enlightenment.
Because these are the blocks which prevent it.
The belief in duality.
Not realizing that just holding on to a positionality
is creating all the noise in your mind.
Thinking that your confrontation is that you have to transcend
this entire mind where you don't.
98% of your mind is gone already.
That's the good news.
Oh, yeah.
If you watch your mind, then you will see
that thoughts are originating out of silence.
All right.
If you look at your mind right now,
picture your mind as sort of a space here.
You'll see the thinkingness is going on at the very front.
Words, thinkingness, images, all that.
Right behind all that is really sort of a feelingness.
But then behind all that is really nothing at all.
There's really primarily silence.
Out of which a little wispy thought starts to come out.
If you encourage it, it'll gain some control.
If you don't encourage it, it'll back down again.
You can actually catch the mind.
You'll catch the source of thinkingness
coming out of an energy field.
There's an energy field within the void itself
whose narcissistic goal is its own continuation,
and it does so by energizing thinkingness.
And what you're hooked on and hypnotized by
is the thinkingness itself.
Now, hypnotic states can be undone.
Once you realize they are a hypnotic state,
they cannot be undone if you just think that's reality.
But once you realize, and the doctor tells you,
you've all been hypnotized without your conscious assent,
then you're in a position to begin to undo it.
Just to know that you are not your thoughts,
that you are hypnotized in a hypnotic state
in which you believe that your thinkingness and thoughts are you.
It's not possible for your thinkingness and your thoughts to be you,
or you'd be dead long ago.
Now that, if you weren't dead,
somebody would kill you for sure
for what goes on in your thinkingness and your thoughts,
wouldn't they?
No, your thinkingness and your thoughts are not you,
or you couldn't even be here.
All right, so you discover.
Now here's how the addiction to the thinkingness
propagates itself.
Polarity means, then,
that we create a set of,
a set of opposites so that that sets up tension,
contention,
and propagates the illusions of the ego.
The way we do this is we are addicted to politicizing things.
Politicizing.
You can't mention anything anymore
that doesn't get instantly politicized.
People want to either de-genderize everything
or genderize it, depending on their political position.
And I say, if you want to de-genderize everything,
you've got to get into a foreign language
where everything in the,
every single word in the language has a gender.
The table, the door.
Whether you use a feminine or masculine pronoun,
so how in the world are you going to de-genderize
the language in which it is intrinsic to the language?
Or it moralizes about things,
or it idealizes,
hypothesizes.
These are the bases of death and destruction throughout history.
We politicize things,
and then we get out the machine guns.
We moralize they deserve to die.
We don't even feel guilty about it.
We idealize what a nice world it would be if they were gone.
We hypothesize that they shouldn't be the way they are anyway.
We romanticize what a nice world it would be
if all the so-and-sos were off the planet.
And we'll help them get off the planet by one form or another.
The justification and the rationalization for this
is to criticize.
So we criticize.
We polarize.
We get ourselves in quite a state and emotionalize about it.
And then we dramatize it.
We have a drama.
We have a protest.
We parade with flags.
Down with the whatchamacallits.
Down with the professional protesters.
You know, the FBI takes pictures of all these protests.
And you see people there at every protest about everything.
They have the sign at home that says down with,
and they leave that blank.
Put in there down with Clinton,
down with Bush,
down with animal rights,
down with God knows what,
down with dogs.
And they tend to dramatize it
and that justifies catastrophizing it.
Catastrophizing it.
Our society is now in a catastrophe.
Our society has been in a continuous catastrophe
since man began.
Man's history is one continuous catastrophe
if you look at it in a certain way.
It started with a catastrophe.
No fur, no claws, no hoofs.
I mean, you know, no mother.
Who is the human being's first mother?
I wish that everybody would puzzle on that one.
Who could be the first mother?
Because each one comes off as a new one.
So who is the first mother then
if it didn't evolve from a prior biped?
I don't know.
So we theorize about it,
just as I'm doing right now.
So we theorize it.
Well, it could have been a...
Then we rationalize our behavior.
We fantasize.
We infantilize everything.
Our society is greatly damaged.
Nobody is infantilizing.
Nobody is responsible for anything anymore.
If you hit your head against the door,
you sue the doormaker.
If your building gets bombed,
you sue people that your building is bombable.
That's the latest kick.
That your building is bombable.
All right.
So you fantasize.
You infantilize people.
You intellectualize.
So you don't have to feel negative about things.
You intellectualize how right it is.
And you mentalize.
We idealize twice.
We idealize twice because it's so important.
Then we glamorize.
It must be weird when they show up twice.
And then we glamorize everything.
And this is the great world of the media.
The great media add to the hypnotic trance.
Everybody is in a hypnotic trance.
And the media know that.
So therefore, you don't have to have any...
The basic dictum now is no reality is necessary.
In fact, it's an impediment.
Knowing that it counts is the image.
The image that is the total message.
You don't need any reality at all.
And I can create...
Oh, I'll create a product right now.
Grabhams.
Big red box.
Hands coming out.
Children's hands.
Grabhams.
Now, it doesn't matter what you put in the box, does it?
Crunchies, creepies, pink and blue little crunchies.
Doesn't matter what you put in the box
because you already got a product.
Your product is the grabhams.
Grabhams make you happy.
Grabhams make you healthy.
Grabhams build better humans, Americans.
You can build up a whole product called grabhams.
And you don't even know what the product is yet.
That's the last part of the...
When you get the whole production put together,
you say, what are we going to put in the box?
I don't know.
Put the little crunchy things.
And that's the last minute.
Doesn't require...
So you can glamorize things.
Beautiful people eat grabhams.
Strong people eat grabhams.
People with great abs.
Great abs.
People with big biceps like mine.
People with a full head of hair.
Demonizing is the specialty of the current media
and it's the one you really got to watch.
It can't seem to like vanilla without hating chocolate.
The current political bent, editorial bent is
you can't just like something,
you have to hate the other one.
So we said last night,
the fact that you love vanilla
doesn't mean you have to hate chocolate.
The fact that you like chocolate
doesn't mean you have to hate vanilla.
You can tell me what's great about your candidate.
You don't have to demonize the other one.
You see?
If you don't have anything good to say about yourself,
then all you can do is demonize the opponent.
People spend all their time demonizing the opponent.
I say they must not have anything good to offer
because all they can do is knock the other guy.
But what have you got to offer?
You know?
What is your solution to man's problems?
And then they go silent.
They don't have any.
All right, so we demonize.
We prize things and we seek them out.
And of course, victimizing is of course
the great basis of current society.
Everything and everyone is the victim of something else.
And we have the world of perpetrator and victim
which is the ultimate expression
of the basic belief in causality.
As long as you believe in causality,
there will always be a perpetrator and a victim.
And you will never find the answer to anything
because neither one is so.
Those are both imaginations projected out there.
The closest thing to the truth I've seen in the media then
was the discovery of that headline
that said that the accident of that,
what do you call those spaceships?
Shuttle.
Shuttle, thanks.
Was the consequence of the culture,
now they're getting close.
That's the first thing I've heard that's close to reality
that's crossed the public view.
It's the culture.
It's the totality of the field that allows that to happen.
As long as you're looking for Mr. X
who forgot to screw in the jiggly thing so we can sue him,
you're never going to find it
because he's only the expression of the totality of the culture
which all of us grab a little from the till,
all of us scoop a little off the bottom,
all of us, you know what I mean?
It's the culture that allows that.
And we see whole societies and countries bogged down
because of the culture, the culture.
What went on in Chicago when I was a kid,
I don't know if it still goes on,
but the culture, the culture allowed for certain variances
with what we would call the perfect ideal.
And somebody I knew,
I used to come down and see him in Chicago,
and he'd park right in front of the hydrant.
I'd say, hey, you're going to get a ticket.
He says, no, the cop and I are friends,
you know what I mean?
In that culture, at that time, in that neighborhood,
that's the way things went, you know?
That's the way things went.
We see whole cultures in which that's how it goes.
The police pull you over not because you're violating the law,
but because they got you and it's going to cost you to get off.
And the judge knows that, so he gets a slice,
so God help you if you've been a defender in certain countries
because it's going to cost you plenty to get it back.
You're under arrest for so and so,
the hand's out there.
So that's endemic to the culture.
It's the culture.
It's the whole space that allows that.
It isn't him being a bad guy,
doing a bad thing against a bad guy,
because that's causality.
It's the totality of the field.
So we as spiritually evolving people then
are actually changing the field.
We're actually changing the field.
A field that went up from 190 to 207 is a different field.
In 207, you can't just comfortably pay off the local cops anymore.
You can't comfortable.
He isn't comfortable about it anymore.
There's a certain lap over between the old way and the new way.
There's a period of discomfort.
The guys who are used to it the old way
don't want to, you know, go against their old friends.
The new guys don't want to make it hard on the old guys.
So you get a sort of a painful adjustment
where you're lapping over from one culture
into a new culture.
And people, opportunists, try to seize the new culture
and retrograde, project it against the old culture
and do a make wrong on what would happen in history.
What happened in history?
The relationship of men and women
in our socioeconomic state is different in 2003
than it was in 1930.
You can't take the social structure of 2003
and go back to 1930 and say,
look how wrong it was.
That was an agrarian, rural culture.
We all had our family roles
based on the nature of society at that time.
To take some political agenda
projected backward in time and do a make wrong,
you see how you're no longer dealing in reality at all.