That's wonderful.
God appears and disappears on command.
Am I turned on?
Oh, good, okay.
Some days I fall over, this morning I'm falling over,
so we have the chair for assistance.
We always start the lectures
with a very significant piece of information,
which can save you many lifetimes.
Nothing is causing anything.
The primary illusion, the ignorance.
All the great avatars spoke of a basic ignorance.
They didn't really define what the ignorance was,
to my satisfaction.
The basic ignorance is, for the intelligent world,
of which we are a major component,
the basic belief in causality is the stumbling block.
Why?
Because people get beyond the 400s.
Even Einstein didn't make it, 499, Newton.
The great geniuses couldn't get beyond
the great barrier of the intellect.
The sense of a separate, independent person,
different and separate from God,
is based on the whole axiom of causality.
There is nothing causing anything.
Nothing is causing anything.
All comes into existence,
by virtue of divine ordination.
The unmanifest becoming manifest.
Everything is happening spontaneously,
effortlessly and perfectly,
as evolution is unfolding.
Creation and evolution are one and the same thing.
The great infinite energy field,
in which we all have our existence,
everything is happening spontaneously,
everything automatically fulfills its karmic potential.
It's all happening of its own, with absolute perfection.
It requires no outside agent.
That we say now is the advancing edge of evolution.
We are the product of all of evolution,
throughout all of time.
We inherit a potentiality.
The world is called that karma.
We can do without it.
We can do without karma.
You can just be what you are.
You relax into it.
There is nothing to be acquired.
There's nothing new.
There's only the relinquishment of that which you are not.
That requires no effort,
but it requires merely a laying back
and allowing things to be.
So where do you find the essence of divinity within you?
God is both transcendent,
from a descriptive viewpoint,
and imminent from an experiential.
God transcendent is the subject of theology.
God imminent is the subject of the mystic.
Just as the scientist is the authority of the linear domain,
the mystic is the authority of the nonlinear domain,
which is completely experiential.
And about which nothing can be said.
It will take us all morning to explain
how nothing need be said.
Where's the board?
Whiteboard.
Why did you cancel?
I mean, you'll have to have the whiteboard.
Do we have the whiteboard, Brock?
Yes, Brock, we have the whiteboard.
We can maybe get one from the hotel.
You can't find God without an explanation,
you understand that?
Without a diagram.
So.
So we are at the forefront.
We are at the forefront of the evolution of consciousness
as it has evolved through millennia.
We're the epitome of it in this domain at this moment.
We all have within us a potentiality.
Education is to inform us about the content
and has to do with the world of form.
The spiritual reality, which everyone seeks
when they reach a certain level of consciousness,
they begin to intuit it.
And then they get captivated,
and then they get captured by the gravity.
They get captured by the gravity of the potential
of their own future.
People think they're driven by the past.
You're not driven by the past.
You're attracted by the future.
And the future has been set by your own intention.
The intention to become enlightened, then,
is why everybody is here
and why they're all gonna be enlightened.
Once the desire to be enlightened,
you can't be enlightened.
Once the desire to be enlightened, you can't be enlightened.
Once you've heard of it, nothing else will suffice.
The Buddha said that and that is a fact.
Somebody asked already,
What's the difference between salvation and enlightenment?
As we said, much of what we say came about
not only through subjective realization,
but then a verification by advanced techniques
of consciousness research.
To an ignorant world, Christ came directly from Heaven,
with no prior human knowledge.
in lifetimes to teach salvation that there was an infinite domain of spiritual reality
and he taught how to avoid what we can only call bad karma to avoid the lower energy fields
because there is no death consequently when you leave the body you will really experience that
which you are that which you are is in a way self-created through one's own choice and
spiritual intention so he said do not create for yourself once you leave the body regions of
suffering and misery instead follow these teachings and you will experience the heavenly realms
therefore the knowingness of that is already within you he said heaven is already within
you
you and it is only necessary to discover it. So he led the way and showed the way
how to discover it. The energy field of that which we call Jesus the Christ
calibrates at 1,000 which is the highest dimension on our calibrated scale of
consciousness. It is very unlikely that the human nervous system can handle an
energy field over a thousand and even as it gets near there there's a tendency to
fall over and get weak and leave the world.
All right so we'll try to what we're actually going to be doing is trying to
clarify what Christ said and as you will discover he said avoid anything that
makes you go weak with kinesiology that's what he said because we discover
then it calibrates below 200 and makes you go weak with kinesiology
is precisely what has been what he defined as sin. So sin is not to be
feared not to be dreaded not to be a source of guilt it's to be transcended
and avoided because it's a road that leads you to unpleasant places. In this
experiential infinity which is talking to you today there was the profound
experience of the lower depths of hell and I agree with Jesus Christ.
They are to be avoided at all costs. Far more dreadful than can be imagined.
Why? Because they are outside of time. It's one thing to have a migraine it's
another have to have a migraine through all eternity. There's no imitrix in hell.
Though the spontaneous inner awareness that transformed this consciousness is
in total agreement with Christ.
However he's saying in a way that this is a very difficult level. This is a very
difficult planet for humans. Life is very difficult and the chance of
becoming completely enlightened are slim here because the gravity of our
civilization is so powerful. As we finish as we get into the lecture today which
is actually quite fascinating.
You know it's like you discovered EMC squared and you can't wait to show it to
everybody. The explanation of all of history you'll understand this morning.
So yes it's gonna be clear as a bell. So what Jesus said is the best thing to do
is to from a practical viewpoint don't forget at the time of the birth of Jesus
the calibrated level of consciousness of mankind was 100. At the time of the birth
of the Buddha was 90.
100 uneducated tribes is what he was talking to. Couldn't read, spell, had no
schooling, illiterate, printing press hadn't been invented yet. You're talking to a
relatively primitive society and he was also not appreciated for telling the
truth.
Let's have the calibrated level of consciousness. We ask was Jesus Christ put to death for
telling the truth?
The answer is no.
The answer is yes. We corroborate everything we say. That's a fact. He was put to
death for telling the truth. In contrast, so what Jesus Christ said, I always forget
my pointer. I've got a gorgeous little light at home but I can't figure out how to use it.
So Jesus Christ, we never attended one of my classes but if he had he would have mentioned.
No. We were focused and...
Thank you. Alright. He said, avoid anything that calibrates below 200, that which is fallacious,
that which is prideful, angered, guilt, desire. Avoid coming out, I mean there's another
terminology, avoid coming out of the lower chakras. Strive at least in America so the
solar plexus has gotten us where we are. Achievement, drive...
That's great.
That's a great quote.
Yeah.
Thank you.
That's great.
That's a good one.
Yeah.
Thank you.
I love that.
Yeah, thank you.
Thank you.
Thank you, thank you.
greed, but then once you've achieved that, you have the courage to start looking for
the truth.
So avoid anything that makes you go weak with kinesiology.
We have a culture, you know, which is devoted to promoting vulgarity, violence.
I heard, I saw a tape by Wayne Dyer the other day, he said that by the time the average
child is 12 or 15, something like that, he's already witnessed 58,000 murders, hour after
hour.
And then he turns off the killing on the television set and gets a video game which teaches him
how to kill with greater technical capacity.
The outpouring of the negativity then is immense.
So in a society which calibrated at 90.
He said, well, I'm going to kill you.
He said, to strive for love, and the highest love is unconditional love.
So what he was really saying, the perfect Christian then strives for unconditional love,
and that is the saint.
To strive for sainthood, and as we'll see when we finally get to some calibrations of
spiritual teachers and all, that Christian sainthood characteristically does occur in
the 500s.
The capacity to reach 500 itself is reached by only 4% of the population, and unconditional
love is reached by 0.4% of the population.
So what is practical and feasible in our world, he said, is if you avoid sin, and by meditation,
worship and forgiveness of others, strive to reach unconditional love.
Why?
Because from unconditional love, from love, from love, one goes to the higher celestial
realms, the heavens, when you leave the physical body.
You can turn that off.
The Buddha, however, had a different message.
The Buddha, although he was speaking in a society where the calibrated level of consciousness
of the world was only 90, he came from a pretty sophisticated background.
Enlightened.
Enlightenment was already ancient in the Vedas, and therefore his audience, which was
a more advanced spiritual audience, was capable of reaching for something higher.
So the Buddha taught the way to enlightenment.
So as love is 500 to 540, enlightenment, when it occurs, is calibrated at 600.
The Buddha himself went to advanced states of enlightenment, which practically never
occurred in history, to 1,000, its ultimate capability.
The presence of divinity within, as the self, is a realization that occurs about 700.
And that is a practical goal, to realize the self.
And in recent times, we use Ramana Maharshi and Nisargadatta Maharaj as examples, primarily
because they live sufficiently.
Recently, what they had to say has been taken down verbatim.
What Jesus said and what the Buddha said, thousands of years ago, some of it is verifiable
and some of it is not, which we'll get into today.
Enlightenment is therefore, you might say, a more ambitious undertaking, and it requires
a more intense commitment.
What we teach?
What it's given we have called, devotional non-duality.
Why?
Because, to reach enlightenment one has to transcend duality.
And to do that takes a great devotion, a great devotion to the truth.
Not devotion to some other being, but devotion to the essence of the truth itself, which
is already within you.
It means, under appropriate conditions with great intention, one can filamentate it and
reach a very advanced state of consciousness even within this world therefore both salvation and
enlightenment are possibilities practical possibilities doable except that you don't do it
so how to find the way all right the most direct way is to my studies understanding
and experiences devotional non-duality why because god cannot be experienced in as a past entity so
traditional religion will tell you what happened on the other side of the world with some other
ethnic group 2 000 years ago under peculiar conditions and how does that help you now
if you're waiting for the bus that's very interesting historically and that has been
sort of the way of religion is to
what should we say not academic but um to put in a rigid form historical events
what happened to who where and when backwards in time gets into sort of a deification of geography
and historic events most of which were more political than spiritual in the first place
however innate within religion is spiritual truth and some people are
capable of ignoring the trivialities and focusing on the central truth when people reach a certain
level of consciousness however they begin seeking the core of spiritual truth for its own sake
what is the ultimate reality that is realizable and they begin to seek what is traditionally
called self-realization the awareness that the source of your own existence is within
therefore if the discovery is something within there's no point of looking for it in history
or elsewhere there is nothing new to be acquired no new knowledge no new experience it's a matter of
surrendering to what already exists so what needs to be realized that which people are looking for
is already an existent reality and one's devotion to letting go of polygamy and the
spiritualaniy of the soul of god
all the obstacles, which is devotional,
is letting go all judgmentalism,
all considerations, all dualistic,
this versus that,
and allowing which already exists.
The most profound awareness as it unfolds
is that divinity is the very source of your existence.
So the fast track is to look back of the mind
and begin to try to sense and intuit
the source out of which your existence arises,
the source out of which all phenomena arise
is an infinite, is a potentiality becoming manifest.
And as you see, everything is happening spontaneously
and perfectly of its own.
Nothing is causing anything.
The belief in cause will fix you in an idea
that there's a subconsciousness,
a separate I, the ego self,
that is separate from the infinite I.
So the whole belief system of causality
is why most people never transcend the 400th.
Everything is happening spontaneously
by virtue of the fact that it is manifesting
its potential, its karmic inheritance,
fulfilling its potentiality.
This is all a concept.
This is all occurring in an infinite universe
of infinite power.
The universe which we call consciousness,
which is beyond form,
the non-linear domain beyond form,
is the source of infinite power.
Even within the physical domain,
one cubic centimeter of space
contains an infinite amount of power.
The potential power in one cubic centimeter,
of space, is infinite.
Therefore, the field, the field,
is the source of power within the universe.
And a field exerts its dominance, its power,
by merely being what it is,
to merely be that which it is.
Everything within it, like little iron filings,
automatically moves in a karmic dance
of its own potentiality.
There is no other to be feared.
There is no other to be dreaded.
The infinite field, then, dominates all within it.
It's the context, the infinite source of existence.
Within, then, the source of joy is not out there.
The source of joy, then, is the witnessing,
the realization, the experience, the knowingness.
The source of your existence is the source of joy.
And it is the same source,
as the devotion,
which drives you through the obstacles of the ego.
To transcend the ego, then,
one can save an infinite number of lifetimes
by letting go of the theory of causality.
Before we genuflect before the theory of causality,
let's see what it calibrates.
It calibrates.
Causality is over 460.
465.
470.
The principle of causality is 470.
That is wonderful for operating in the world.
It's science.
It's logic.
But 470 is a long, long way from enlightenment.
At 470, you read about it.
As we'll see, the great churches,
they started out at 1,000,
and then over time came down into the high 400s.
They did so because they were trying to explain
it, to explain it.
The experience is way beyond 400.
In fact, nothing is thinking.
As the realization of the source of your experience,
you realize it's the divinity that is the source
and the isness of all that exists.
And it just reveals itself in an enormous overwhelm,
which takes you out of the world for some time.
I don't know how you get back into it.
So let's say here's a person with a small essence,
a small self,
and here we're going to make the universe,
sort of a mini-universe,
which you can't see, which is good.
Where do I get hung up on form?
I think somebody washed this with a nice high-gloss polish.
Let's see.
Oh, there we have the ego, the world of form.
And here we have, with little dots,
an infinite universe.
So we can save huge amounts of time
by understanding what this is all about.
This is the world of form,
which we witness every day,
which we identify with as the ego.
And this is the self, with a small s.
This infinite potentiality is the self with a capital S.
The average person thinks,
I am this, and ignores this.
The average person thinks my survival is this.
When it's due to this,
when it's actually due to this.
Your existence is supported by the field,
despite the best efforts of your ego,
which it looks for praise.
I remembered the keys to the house today.
What a good boy am I.
Why did I remember the keys to the house?
Because the spirit, which sustains my life,
then, is a field,
which tends to bring that kind of self-preservation thinking
up out of the ego, see,
without
the infinite field,
the mind would have had no reason
to remember the keys to the house.
All right.
When one lets go thinking that I am this,
so you see how causality works.
Causality thinks there is a personal I
that is the cause of that.
Or there's something out there
that is the cause of this.
And therefore,
the average lifetime is spent
manipulating and struggling
in the world of duality,
which is the world of force,
based on the idea of causality.
With the transcendence of identification with this,
one begins to intuit
that there is a higher field,
and
the letting go of the identification with this itself
leads to the identification of this itself.
And that's why we tell people,
if you're serious about spiritual work,
make sure you have friends that know that.
Ha ha.
I said that in some lecture,
and I got a worried letter.
Why should we do that, you know?
Because intense meditation,
plus really merely hearing of higher truth,
can transport you rather rapidly past
the levels of the ego,
and you find yourself in a state
that can only be described as what?
Classically, it's called bliss.
In that state, one really,
from a physical viewpoint,
is relatively immobilized.
Why?
Because the volition has gone out of,
out of running it.
If it's not me,
it becomes like a piece of furniture
of no particular interest.
Other people may entreat you
to come back in the body and reactivate it,
and it's best to ignore them.
They think you've died, let them grieve it.
Because there is no death.
It is not possible for life
to cease to exist.
The law of the conservation of energy of matter
and energy applies to life.
That which is the source,
the very source and essence of existence,
can hardly have a beginning or an end.
That which is all-encompassing
can only transform from this into that,
but it cannot cease to exist.
It does not have the power within itself
to create its own existence,
nor does it have within itself
the option to cease its own existence,
because the source and the control of existence
does not belong to you.
It doesn't belong to you.
You're not going to have any say about it at all.
The upside of that is
you don't get to experience
even your own physical death.
As I said, the karmic destination
is already set at the time of birth.
The time of death is already set.
As people are born,
they already have a calibrated level of consciousness.
So if people don't believe in karma,
they will have to explain that.
However, then we know that the spirit
enters the embryo in the third month.
First, you're born with a calibrated level of consciousness
right from birth.
The spirit, the entity from our own consciousness research,
enters the embryo at age three months.
After that time, it waits to see
if it's going to make it.
This bus is going to get there
before it gets on the bus.
Then, the time of expiration of this physicality
is already set at the time of birth.
The time of birth is already set.
At that particular event,
it's not possible to experience one's physical death
because you're instantly out of the body.
You witnessed the physicality down there
and you didn't die at all.
That's disappointing for a lot of people.
Everything we said.
We verify anything that may be
somewhat in conflict with popular belief systems.
In fact, if what I'm saying isn't in conflict
with many belief systems,
you know I'm lying.
Because if the truth were prevalent,
everybody would be enlightened.
It's extremely rare, consequently.
What the world believes primarily
is primarily fallacious.
The consciousness level of the world
was 190 until the late 1980s
when it suddenly jumped to 207.
And so, it's a new level of consciousness
for all of mankind.
With profound implications for life,
you know, here on this planet.
Therefore, nothing that happens
has a cause.
Everything is coming about
as the advancing edge
of creation, evolution,
as the spontaneous interaction
of all that is,
both linear and non-linear,
back through infinite time.
That which is infinite
has no beginning nor end.
One time a student in the back of the classroom
said,
teacher, teacher,
when did you say the world was ending?
And the teacher said,
a hundred trillions.
He said, oh my god,
I thought you said a hundred billion.
That's what most people worry about.
The trivial idiocies and irrelevancies of life.
And many religions fall into that.
They're more worried about
what kind of shoelaces to wear,
and whether they wear a hat
or don't wear a hat.
And completely ignore
the crucial spiritual truth, you know.
All right.
So we'll look at the sad story
of the world's religions in a little while.
So let's just have
the Calvary level of consciousness.
And we want to just reaffirm,
with kinesiology,
anything from here down
makes you go weak.
Anything from here up
makes you go strong.
The response
is an impersonal response
of consciousness itself.
Consciousness itself
is an expression of life,
and life recognizes truth
and that which is.
And it fails to recognize
that which is adverse to life
and which has no intrinsic reality.
And therefore the arm goes weak.
The theory of evolution
also calibrates around 460.
So it's an explanation
which satisfies the intellect.
But a group like this,
your problem is not your intellect.
The problem is to transcend the intellect.
You've already arrived
at a very advanced level of consciousness,
which is the high,
most people are in the,
considerably into the 400s.
All right.
So we'll just continue that.
And then we'll go on
to some more interesting things.
Let's do that next one.
I'm just recapitulating
previous lectures here
for people who haven't been here before.
And because we all want to start out
in the same place.
We said that the basic principle
of the divisive factor
that keeps the ego going
is its capacity to think
in terms of duality.
The pathway of devotional non-duality
then is,
means how to transcend
dualistic thinking.
Either or,
good and bad,
war and peace.
As we demonstrated
in previous lectures,
war is not the opposite of peace.
In other words,
peace is the opposite of war.
The idea of creating
artificial dualities,
which exist only as mentations
within the mind.
These dualities are only a mentation.
And to demonstrate this,
we point that opposite,
that hot is not the opposite of cold.
There are varying degrees
of the presence of heat.
And it's arbitrary to say
this is hot and cold.
And it's quite obvious
they're not opposites.
There's only one variable.
And that's a fact
in all dualistic thinking.
There's actually only one variable.
In linguistic convenience,
we have divided it.
But in fact,
there is no such reality.
That which has absolute reality
can only be proven subjectively.
Therefore,
the newest book is called
I,
Reality and Subjectivity.
Because reality can only be known
as subjectively.
So dualistic is a way of talking about it,
but it's not a way of being it.
Let's use value.
You can see again,
this has to do with
how it looks to you.
This is not the opposite of this.
And what somebody thinks
is an ugly-looking alley
can look to somebody else
like an artistic presentation.
Okay, so we're done with all that.
And then we...
Oh, I wanted to show
the last one in this one.
This is a new one.
So what we've done now
is recapitulate how we got here.
This was a girl
at the girl's rehab place that I go.
And all she says is,
I want out of here.
All our girls say that.
So I made her draw this.
And she actually did this freehand.
I said,
This is what you want.
Here.
I want out of here.
Give me them bananas.
And I said,
Look how you're...
The harder you reach for the bananas,
the tighter you are against the bars.
The more you shout,
yell,
hit people,
cut yourself,
threaten people,
you can see you're tightening your imprisonment.
Eventually you're going to flatten yourself
up against the bars.
And they do.
Completely paralyzed by their own.
So here is the unsophisticated basis of the ego.
The I want,
the grabbing this,
which comes out of the animal evolution.
And I said,
So I said to the girl,
Do you realize
that the door to the cage is over here?
Here is freedom.
You have to turn your back
on the solar plexus demanding this,
of I wanting this,
and become what this place is for.
To learn how to behave,
learn how to control yourself,
learn how to be responsible,
learn something of the milk of human kindness.
And then the door is open to you.
I said,
The door is open all the time.
The door has never been closed.
And of course,
when they reach a certain level of improvement,
they're automatically discharged.
In fact,
they can't even stay there.
Their agency pulls them out.
So this is the way it is with enlightenment.
It is not something you can reach for
and strive to get,
but it is already a reality
and the door is already open.
Thank you.
So that was her contribution.
She did it freehand,
and I thank her for it.
I made many copies for it.
I knew I'd use it someday for something,
and this morning it came up.
All right.
So everybody knows the way to enlightenment now.
It's merely a surrendering
of all opinionation, positionalities.
And remember this, folks.
Judgmentalism is bad.
You see,
the circuitous way the ego can grab you, you know.
I got a letter from a lady.
She said,
Why do you use bad language?
No.
Did she say bad language?
Yes, bad language.
Well, I never heard myself use bad language.
First of all,
I don't know what's going to be said
until I hear it myself.
So she goes to a lecture on non-duality,
letting go of judgmentalism,
and tells me my speech.
I use bad language.
I've got to get a kick out of that.
What was the bad language about?
So,
we've got our perceptions.
At the time,
I'm certain I thought it was good.
Why?
Because there's men and women,
you understand?
And what sounds meaningful
and sinks home with a woman
to a guy who's going to say,
Man, that was really airy-fairy, wasn't it?
You know what I'm saying?
It's all peaches and cream and flowers,
and it sounds sweet.
But what about the real world?
So occasionally,
I use language that's masculine
because it pulls out of your gut
that that's crap.
You know what I mean?
That word gets,
Oh, I get what you mean, see?
I could say it's inadvisable.
It's not totally acceptable.
Last night,
they had the History Channel,
the story of Ivan the Terrible,
one of the worst stories in history.
I looked at Susie and I said,
His behavior was not really too desirable, Susie.
Now, occasionally,
you've got to speak to the masculine
because there's a gut way of being.
You know,
that the woman doesn't really understand.
It's a glance between two guys,
and in that,
there's a complete understanding,
a whole culture.
You get what it is.
This is your moment to climb the mast, Shorty.
The fact that you're terrified is your crap, boy.
Actually, Shorty didn't make it.
He got to the top and had to be rescued.
But the guy knows what that means, you know.
And it isn't a woman's language.
So when the guy goes like that with his foot,
it already has a meaning in his culture
and his background.
And when the woman goes like this,
that has a meaning in her culture and background.
And I spent a lot of time learning about those things.
I'll say,
that's insignificant tripe.
I mean,
but that's where they live.
Yeah.
She'll say,
but that kind of a remark is,
you know,
this and that.
And I say,
yeah,
but that's where men live.
So,
you will have to forgive me for using
the best bad language I can think of at the time.
My function is to communicate.
And,
you know,
it isn't a,
it's a doingness.
It's a,
anyway,
it happens of its own anyway.
So,
I can't be responsible for what's said anyway.
I don't know what's said until it's said.
I want to watch the time
because we've got a lot of tremendous stuff
to cover this morning.
Rather earth-shaking and,
well,
we better get to the earth-shaking world.
Let's start with the map.
Well,
I've been working for,
some months,
as soon as I've been working.
We calibrated the level of consciousness
of every country in the world.
We then proceeded to do every continent.
We then proceeded to do,
now,
so for simple explanation,
almost all of history and current events
suddenly becomes obvious to you.
And you realize that man has been trying to navigate
without a compass.
How diplomatic course,
how countries,
how statesmen can deal with each other
when they don't even know
what they're dealing with is beyond me.
It would lead to endless catastrophe,
war, revolution,
and of course it has.
So,
just like the invention of the telescope
allowed amazing discoveries,
or E equals MC squared,
allows amazing discoveries,
some discoveries are seminal
and open up whole dimensions.
Here we have the Western Hemisphere.
We calibrated the level of the consciousness
of these particular areas.
I hope it's big enough that you can all see it.
Anyway, we look up at Greenland and 345.
Iceland, I think, is somewhat less than that.
They have a lot of alcoholism there.
I think half the population is alcoholic in Iceland.
So that would be why it's somewhat lower.
You look at North America,
you see Canada's about five points,
10 points less than the United States.
But the general area you see is 410 to 421.
So that's education,
that's science,
that's reason,
rationality.
Those are the laws we live by
and we presume everybody else lives by that.
Now we get to the Central America,
the 300s.
That's enthusiasm,
building big cement plants.
It's impressive what they do.
That's industry and forthrightness.
Here you've got South America.
It runs generally 285 to 310.
What's important of all this is it's all over 200.
It's all over 200.
In other words, you're relatively safe.
People may screw up down here with the Falkland Islands.
I forgot to put them in.
Due to some mad person,
but that's just bad judgment.
It's not a violently explosive hemisphere.
You've only got one place here you've got to worry about
and they're too weak and at the bottom of the barrel
to worry about them yet.
But they're at 55 and that's Haiti.
Haiti can't do much about it.
So when you pour more money into Haiti,
the only thing that happens is the birth rate goes up
and poverty and starvation goes up.
So something other than cash,
which has been tried and everybody decided
it doesn't help any.
Those kind of people are also quite subject to
sadistic rule by a dictator.
A sadistic dictator.
So if I don't know anything about the history of Haiti,
I'll tell you this place is probably
currently or recently run
by a sadistic dictator
who exploits the people,
allows them to starve
and probably just kills them for amusement.
Which is probably pretty accurate.
Okay, where's the next one?
Now we'll get to more serious considerations.
We look at the other hemisphere.
We saw Australia 410, intelligent, rational, educated.
Now we start getting up higher.
You see Korea in the 400s,
Japan, they're all pretty good.
India, 355.
Now you see Madagascar, 125.
South Africa, 195.
And now you see the real trouble coming up.
Here is all of Africa, about 40 to 60.
And North Africa, 70 to 185.
And we will see the difficulty arises
between latitude 10 to 40 north
in North Africa
is where you're going to see all the problems.
You see Russia,
then you see Mongolia,
you see China at 305,
Japan at 355.
This is your...
I don't know what it is up there.
Something.
Anyway, we've got maps with greater detail.
I tried to simplify it so you can see
you're looking at North Africa about 175
and you're looking at the Near East.
So let's go on to the next one.
How much will democracy appeal
to people who calibrated 55?
They haven't even got water.
You don't have bathrooms.
You don't have food.
Your children are dying,
falling over with AIDS and starvation.
Who is interested in political systems?
They will naturally follow anybody
who gives them food and water.
It's easy to become a dictator.
You just steal from the weak
and use that to control them.
And you give it back to them for a trickle
and in turn for their worship and servitude.
All right, so here we have this again.
No, let's...
Is that the next one?
Oh, there we go.
This is too complicated, so...
The original of this took me a week.
It took us a week, right?
A whole weekend.
All right, so we calibrated every country in the world.
You see, I took the names of the countries out
because you wouldn't be able to read anything.
But now you can see what you're dealing with.
So if you're in the State Department
and you say we're going to deal with
such and such country in such and such region,
you better know what the hell you're talking about.
Calibrated level of consciousness 70
has nothing to do with 421.
It has nothing to do with it.
They slaughter each other here.
They just slaughter each other.
They're not even up to slavery yet.
Slavery, 70 you get,
the people just vanquished are worth money on the market.
These people aren't even there yet.
They just slaughter them.
They take over a village.
They kill everybody in the village.
Here's North Africa.
And you see,
Europe is in the 300s,
340s, 400.
And you see the big problem areas of the world.
So if you don't know anything about it,
don't read the newspaper at all,
and you look at this, you say,
uh-oh, I can see where the problems
are likely to be here.
I was embarrassed by
the way an American interviewer
interviewed the President of China.
President of China, by the way,
is much higher than 305,
way up there.
Insulting, saying to him,
look what's wrong with your culture,
civil rights and all that.
Idiotic.
Antagonizing the people
acting like we're better than they are.
See?
That isn't the way to make friends.
Let's have the next
sad story here.
Now
that you got the overall picture,
because people ask me,
what the names of the various countries are,
I don't know, so I put this up.
If you want the names of the countries, ask me now.
Sudan, 70.
Rwanda, 70.
Kenya, 70.
Tanzania, 80.
Zambia, 110.
Angola, 50.
Namibia, 100.
Zimbabwe, 80.
Botswana, 65.
Nigeria, 75.
Chad, 90.
Look at the size of this country.
Ethiopia,
one something or other.
Somalia, 100.
Okay.
That's North Africa.
Now let's look up to an even sadder story.
The Middle East.
Here you see,
these people are not a danger to the world.
At 50, you can't get your act together.
You don't have hardly clothes to wear.
You're not much of a danger to anybody.
But now,
when you start rising up a little bit
and getting a little bit of power,
you give people with a caveman mentality
a gun, now you've got problems.
Who are you giving a gun?
People with a mentality up in here.
180, 190.
So you'll find,
oh, look over on the right, I got it already.
What's the current calibration?
We change these calibrations
from time to time.
As of maybe a week ago,
this is where it all was a week ago.
Israel, 185.
Palestine, 165.
Saudi Arabia, 175.
Iraq, 160.
United Arab Emirates, 180.
Jordan, 185.
Iran, 190.
Iraq, 125.
Syria, 120.
And the only hope in the region, Turkey, 245.
Now you tell me
what good a peace parade will do.
Let's have the next one.
The next one was this week's Time Magazine.
While I was doing all this,
we just reached its completion
this week.
I opened Time Magazine,
they must have had spies.
From 10 to 40 degrees
north latitude.
10 to 40 degrees north latitude.
Which is what I said already, right?
Now the question is,
should the missionaries go in and,
you know, that was the topic.
Here are exactly the same countries,
exactly the same war area.
It's all
mind with potential
problems. The question was,
should the Christian missionaries go in there
and convert these people?
Which I thought was hysterically funny.
Because they'll get executed
for doing so, but aside from that,
it brings up
the corollary.
Shouldn't the Islamic people be over in America
trying to convert us to Islam?
So,
when we talk about spiritual
community, we want to know,
what is the world, the condition of the world?
We're in it, but not of it.
What can we do
directly? Well, if you
deal with,
if you deal with this invisible
diagram here,
if you come at it directly,
you can see the difficulty you're going to have.
To use force, then,
is going to have a limited response.
It's not going to transform
the people and turn them into
saintly peaceniks.
They make their living by war.
They get their status from war.
They get their sense of
masculinity, sufficiency.
And even now, their spiritual
belief system is just tied up
with violence.
Therefore, it does not seem to me
that addressing it directly is going to have
very salutary
results.
If you can't approach
a thing with force in the level
of form, then how
can you transform
it? Well,
by addressing the level
of power, not the level of force.
If I go in there and try to force
you to change your belief systems,
and force you to adopt mind,
and if I don't,
and if you don't,
I'll execute you,
that's going to have a very limited benefit.
Alright, so if I want to influence
something that is not touchable,
you can't really touch that
system, can you? You can't really touch it
without it blowing back at you.
Force creates counter-force.
So you're not going to
save the world. What can
we do then, as a spiritual community,
if we are all one as humans,
is by letting go
our own egoistic positionalities,
we reinforce
the field.
Alright, by quantum mechanics,
we don't have that formula with us today.
If you don't behave, I'll get it out and show it to them.
Quantum mechanics, we showed
that the collapse of the wave function,
by the collapse of the wave function,
by spiritual intention,
via the Heisenberg principle,
and Neumann manifestation of it,
as a collapse of the wave function,
we change the field.
We change the field.
So let's say
human-ness is highly
visible as structure,
this thing-ness here,
which is behaving very well today.
There is this thing-ness here,
and then around it we could say
there's mentalization as we advance.
The animal doesn't do much in the way of
mentalization, but as he gets
more advanced, he gets more mentalization.
And then he gets intuitive knowingness.
And some animals
get to be pretty advanced.
Some animals
get more advanced than humans.
Not intellectually,
but spiritually.
As I said in the book, you're safer with Coco,
the gorilla,
than you are with any of these people from the Near East.
Coco will not turn on you,
will not deceive you, will not lie to you,
will not kill you.
When you turn your back, you're safe.
You're capable of being honest.
There's that famous African
gray parrot
at the University in
Arizona, too.
Also very honest.
Can't get it to lie.
Blue ball, red sponge,
soap.
Incapable of deception.
Okay.
Then we get mentation.
We get up to the 400s, we get mentation.
So you can say there's an energy field,
not physical.
It registers in the physical and activates the brain.
The brain is a response
system to energy fields, and
it's a
receiver of
thought forms.
The thought forms are extremely high frequency,
not reduplicable
within the physical realm,
but sufficiently powerful
to activate neuronal
imprinting and
memorization, etc.
So,
intelligence then and mentation
creates like another field around this.
And then comes spiritual awareness.
And the first one
identifies here, then here, then
here, then identifies with this here.
When you stop identifying
with this and identify with
the field, you realize
the source of your own existence
because at 600, one goes
into a state of profound bliss.
Everything is silent.
There is no words.
There is no other.
There is only the allness
of an infinite, exquisite
presence as
the very essence of love itself.
And that is
the end of the road.
The best thing to do at that point,
seeing as you've lost interest in breathing,
is to forget about it.
The bliss state at 600.
So, we say to people
that are serious about spiritual work,
let people that are somewhat spiritually
sophisticated be aware, and
if you go into such a state,
they should just smile at you
and pray with you
and be happy for you.
Otherwise, they may call the police,
they may call the doctor,
they may call for a psychiatrist,
who won't know what the heck it's all about.
As it approaches,
it becomes like euphoria.
There's a gladness, a happiness, a joy.
And this can reach
states of high ecstasy.
So one can also go into states
of high ecstasy,
which can be confused with
mania, religious mania.
So I think in the last book,
I gave two columns,
how to differentiate a true spiritual state
from various psychiatric conditions.
And when I was a consultant
to many dioceses,
Catholic and Episcopal
and Zen monastery and all,
they would sometimes send a monk to me
and they didn't know, is this guy enlightened
or is he catatonic?
It can be hard to tell that for an unsophisticated layman,
they wouldn't know the difference.
And having gone into such states,
also I could see where the police
would come and get you
and you just sit on this rock
and there's no reason to move
and the state is complete.
It's because of the completeness of the state.
There is no desire or thought
to do or be anything else
than what is.
Everything is total and complete.
As a day or two went by,
the passers-by might notify the police
and you might get dragged off for observation.
So it's best to have somebody aware
that, hey, he meditates a lot.
Oh.
Yes, he meditates a lot.
And if he wishes to leave the body,
we will allow him to do so.
That's against Medicare rules, you know.
I really quit going to the
nursing homes.
I couldn't stand it.
All these people who want to leave the body so badly.
Everything is gone.
There's tubes into everything.
And it's on wheels.
It doesn't want to eat.
It's lost interest and all that.
It's please let me die is what it wants.
So they go, the little old lady
you can hear in any nursing home.
Help! Help! Help!
What is it you want to help us with,
sweetheart?
Help me out of here.
It's against the law
to allow them to expire.
Against their wishes.
You would think they would have the right of decision.
No, it's against their wishes.
They have to be hydrated.
There are tubes stuck in everywhere.
You won't swallow it, they'll put a tube down your...
It's because Medicare
believes that when you die, you die.
Therefore they get excited about all that.
So you go from identifying
with this to identifying with mind,
all this mental energy.
Then you begin to intuit
and feel the energy,
feel the spirit around you.
You let go of the identification with this
and it can happen in a sudden second.
In a sudden second.
One tenth of a second.
People say, how long does it take to get enlightened?
One tenth of a second, frankly.
The next instant,
everything has become technicolor,
3D and incredible.
Now, one stays in this state.
50% never come back
to the world.
50% never survive physically.
50% will not
breathe again
and realize that it's idiotic.
Or at that point, there is no choice.
So when it happens, it isn't like
you have a choice.
If enough energy gets put in from here,
you maybe get pulled back into identifying
with this thinkingness here
and fall for choice.
So it's best to avoid relatives.
One then spaces out and becomes
I am not this, I am this.
The realization of the self
is the infinite reality,
the very source of all of existence
out of which all of mankind arises.
The divinity is the core and the essence
of all that exists.
Pretty much takes you out of the world
for some years.
So it's best to have a fallback plan.
Traditionally,
people as they get into
really serious advanced spiritual work
have gathered together in ashrams,
spiritual communities.
Our spiritual community is the people
who show up here and we know each other.
So we all know that we're involved in this.
So the good doctor there passes over
into the state of bliss.
His wife calls me and I say,
yeah, he's fine, me and Bea,
I'll go over and enjoy with him.
We know each other to some degree.
So we don't have to congregate
geographically in a secluded area
which has been a traditional way of doing it.
The difficulty then,
it's actually not a difficulty,
it has to do with the karmic
I guess,
I don't know, contract.
Was it an option or a contract?
I have permission to ask this.
It was an option.
No, there was the option.
There was not the realization
that there was an option.
There was
the decision made
by the field itself
to continue to exist.
But this
resulted in removal from the world
for some years.
It took years to learn how to
refunction again.
And then, even more rarely,
is the capacity to realize
both realities
simultaneously
and begin to
be able to relearn how to function
in the world again
with some physical difficulty.
So that's the evolution
of consciousness as it evolves
on our planet.
Alright.
We'll stop for a break at 10.30
and then we'll resume.
What people would like to know,
they know we've calibrated
the fields of consciousness,
we've done it.
We started out to do 1,000
and
we're up to 3,000 already.
I'm not done with the list.
We started doing just
so far we've done
Americana, everything from
rock music to movie stars.
And the next section has to do
with spiritual reality.
The calibration of the various spiritual realities.
Then we do countries,
international, we go into
paleontology, archaeology,
and then we go
into the arts, music,
architecture, the great cathedrals,
places of great spiritual interest.
So in the lectures
I'm sort of sharing with you
as we get to a certain point
we can make a transparency
which is semi-legible.
So today we have a semi-legible transparency.
Has anybody got any questions
about the distribution of consciousness?
You get the implications
of the distribution of consciousness
when you see it country by country,
region by region,
continent by continent.
You get the implications
for how to be
in a world like that.
And you realize
why so much diplomacy
completely fails.
You just miscalculate
where the other person is at.
You see, because of egotism
everybody presumes that other people
think like you do.
They don't think like you do at all.
They think the way you speak is idiotic.
Freedom of speech is the most
idiotic thing in the world.
There's nothing dumber than freedom of speech.
Let's have the percentage
of people who think
that freedom of speech is
fallacious.
Fallacious is over 75%,
80%, 85%, 90%.
Free speech.
90% of free speech
is totally fallacious.
Are we supposed to give up our life
and genuflect
because occasionally
somebody tells the truth
15% of the time?
If you tell the truth
your butt is in hot water.
The editorials,
everything is attacking everything.
You calibrate the level of consciousness
of all that data
and now a new picture of man's consciousness
begins to evolve.
To another country,
to allow such disorder,
imagine how that's viewed
in Singapore.
Rioting teenagers.
Why should they allow
civil disruption
and threat to the peace of the community?
So you see how a different community
views that.
Dabbling idiots,
causing unrest,
throwing rocks,
starting fires,
calling forth the police,
getting arrested,
causing disruption
because they're
expounding some ideology
which if executed
would probably kill half the population
and usually does
after the French Revolution,
the Russian Revolution,
manage to slay most of the population.
Here's a country then
in which we worship free speech,
85% of which is fallacious.
Starting from a
primarily fallacious position,
we then seek to approach a country
whose calibrated level of consciousness
we haven't got the slight idea about
and even if they could understand us
they would consider it ridiculous
in the first place.
You want us to have riots in the streets,
drugs, crime and divorce rates
50% and a high abortion rate
for unwedded mothers?
What for?
What's the good of that?
Why should we strive and die for that?
So you begin to see what you're up against.
We're smugly politically superior.
Our system is good,
the best and better
and if other people don't like it
we'll shove it down their throat
or buy their way to it.
So the beginning of success
in international affairs then
is by attracting
the greatly successful
people in society
are based on attraction
and not promotion.
Nobody tries to sell you anything.
They tell you this is how it was with me,
this is what I learned
and this is how my life is now.
Profound transformation.
Probably the best example,
the most successful spiritual endeavor
in the world today
is probably 12 step groups
where you take a hopelessly pathologic
condition with a 100% death rate
nobody ever recovered from it
with a wet brain.
Nobody ever recovered from it.
Now millions not only recover
but become very famous people
governors and statesmen
and great leaders of the world
once had a drinking problem.
So the spiritual power then
of truth,
pure spiritual truth then
is enormously powerful.
So the way
we can influence other countries then
is through the field
through spiritual upliftment
I saw a girl Friday
at a staff meeting
really into apathy.
The world would call it depression
and it would look for psychological reasons
because the world thinks in terms of cause
what's causing it.
But to me I saw this girl
who had never had energy or love
poured into her.
Where is that map of South Africa or Africa?
You still got it there?
Alright.
You see,
I'll tell you,
you're not going to find logic or reason
to be of any help whatsoever
at Energy Fuel 50.
This girl at the staff meeting
doesn't have enough
energy
power of life
to even learn how to control
her bladder and her bowel.
It's like an infant.
And the problem is not depression
the problem is apathy.
You've got a poor energy.
The old lady rocking in her chair
and she did nothing but rock back and forth
and look out the window.
She hasn't got enough energy
to get up and move or eat
get dressed.
You have to pour energy into them.
So I had to control myself
because I could have really
opened up the dams
and just flooded her with
and I tried to give her a flash
as she went by
the joy of existence
comes out of
the awareness of the presence within.
To have joy
she needs the energy of joy
to come out of the bottom of the box.
So I'm done with that one.
Let's go back to the Calvary
level of consciousness.
So depression is not where she's at.
She's I'm sure here.
Apathy.
Hopelessness.
What's the point of going to school?
What's the point of keeping your room neat?
What's the point of going to the dentist?
What's the point?
Total apathy.
Here's where South Africa is.
Here's where that girl is.
Here's not South Africa
but many places in Africa.
Here's where the girl is.
Hopelessness.
She's given up.
God has no interest in her
naturally in despair.
And she's into despondency.
She tries to cover it up
with a certain social veneer
but I see through it.
She's going to hold the social veneer
as long as she's forced to do it.
She's going to pour energy into them.
What is the energy you pour into them?
Well you love them.
You take this girl and say
I demand that you get better.
And then she laughs.
She giggles.
Somebody cares enough about her
to be with her in a state of joyful ecstasy
and pour forth that life energy into her.
The pouring forth of life energy then
is the only way you can get things
out of the bottom of the barrel.
Okay so we're done with that.
So this sort of changes
the way we see international politics.
It means
our first
the first thing we have to do
is we have to understand
where are they spiritually?
What does that mean in terms of
the level of consciousness?
What are the values of people at that level?
And address those values.
That's why the crime bosses
are so successful in poverty areas.
It's the only source of food.
Jobs.
They deplore it and call them criminals.
But where else are they going to get a handout?
Even the United States
we compromised didn't we
in Afghanistan on the poppy fields.
Right?
We did a trade off.
It's cheaper to let them raise the poppy
and support themselves
than to destroy the poppy
and we've got to put them all on welfare.
It seemed to me like that kind of a trade off.
Afghanistan is the source
of the world's supply of heroin.
The suffering and death brought about
by heroin worldwide
is staggering.
That was the trade off.
Let them keep the opium fuels
in return for what we got for it.
It's a hard one.
It's like dropping an atomic bomb.
I'm glad I didn't have to make that decision.
The karma of all those dying heroin addicts
out of there because of you.
Your trade off.
Save the taxpayers of America the money
of supporting those people.
Let them support themselves with heroin and opium.
So you see how the thinking,
the determinants of judgment,
morality,
the weighing of things.
You see it's not a matter of opposites.
You can see that life is a matter of subtleties.
Slightly warmer to a little less warmer.
And a little bit more of this
and a little bit more of that.
But even when you suddenly take this direction
you only did it because
there was one more feather.
The feather tipped the balance this way
and now you decide to go that way.
So this isn't the opposite of that.
It's only one feather away.
One feather away.
One more feather on this side they live.
One more feather on this side they die.
One more feather.
So we hold the feathers.
We hold the feathers.
Virtually evolved people
are the only source of real hope
that people who live down here
have.
It's by our pouring forth
our concern for them.
Just our concern for them.
Our concern for their welfare.
Our concern for their survival.
Our hope for their betterment.
It's when we send an invisible
love that they feel a stirring.
You see it's not a direct
cause and effect.
You can change the rate at which
something rises in water
a cork rises in water
by changing the density of the water.
Every swimmer knows that.
You float higher in the ocean
than you do in the Great Lakes.
I grew up around the Great Lakes.
No salt in the water.
Different buoyancy.
So what we can do then
is by the emanation
of our own divinity forth
our knowingness of it
our awareness of it
to all of mankind
we change the specific gravity
and the density
of the field
and therefore those people
become uplifted.
You can't go there
and say here I want you
to stop being poverty
because this is food
and now that solves it.
No. Keeps them alive
so you can die even worse
at a later date doesn't it?
No. One has to change
the total overall context.
And as we demonstrated
in previous lectures
that is scientifically valid.
It's not hearts and flowers.
The quantum mechanics of it
is that decision then.
Once you make a decision
and collapse the wave function
you can change it.
The emanation of that
for those of you
who are interested
is in the computer.
What do you call that computer thing?
The e-mail world.
Internet world, yes.
Henry Stapp.
Professor of physics at Berkeley
gives a very neat explanation
comprehensible by the intellect
with the opening into spiritual realities
and how that could manifest
and that their research
can help us
to understand
that every time you make a decision
in this direction
you increase the potentiality
and the likelihood of its recurrence.
There's another principle
in quantum mechanics
that the more times you say yes
to a thing
you increase the probability
of it being yes.
It's not 50-50 anymore.
Now it becomes higher and higher
probability.
That works at a certain level.
But that's not going to really change things
because when they run out of food
they're right back to the same fact
that they've got nothing to raise food on.
When they run out of this bag of flour
they're right back to starvation again.
So we try to lift
the consciousness of all of mankind
by evolving our own.
The devotion
to the presence of God
then
is a very powerful tool.
It already exists.
You don't have to create it.
That which is willing to surrender
everything for God
even life itself
already exists within you.
And much to your surprise
it comes up in great power
when you didn't even know it was there.
At the last moment
you're faced with surrendering
life itself to God.
To thee, O God, do I surrender this life.
The devotion to do so
is already present.
And it's like a shock
when it comes up and you realize
that you have within you
the power to do that.
Not only to surrender the details of life
to dissolve the ego
transcend the ego
but eventually the very core
of that which you think is you
as you all sit there
that which you profoundly believe
is you
your reality
and who you are
experientially, not intellectually
that's the doorway
one surrenders completely.
And that is the doorway to enlightenment.
Because of the limitation
of the commitment
it doesn't happen all that often.
Devotional non-duality means
one is devoted to the truth
devoted to the truth
and we'll get to more of the truth
after we have a break.
That which is necessary
to reach enlightenment
already exists.
To reach a state of divine
unconditional lovingness
is quite sufficient.
And
the Lotusland Buddhism
which teaches pretty much the same
as Christianity then says
once you've reached the level of unconditional love
the way is certain
and you can relax.
And so we'll take a break.
Those of you who have read
the books and attended lectures
know that the pathway
the direct pathway to God is radical.
It's a radical devotion
to truth above all else.
Why is that so important?
Because untruth stands
in the way of love
and those who seek to reach God through love
constantly run into blocks.
So we try to resolve the blocks
so that when devotion
comes up there's nothing to obstruct it
and when it does it comes like
like a dam just broke
there is no stopping it.
So we'll get rid of duality
today and the next
less than a minute.
Just because
you like chocolate doesn't mean
you have to hate vanilla.
That resolves all your political problems
right there.
Some people like chocolate
some people like vanilla.
We don't have to kill them.
You don't have
to kill them.
The best way, the fastest way
to reach the presence within
is through joy.
Joy, happiness,
thankfulness, gratitude,
goodwill.
So you hear those are all positive things.
That's different than
sackcloth and ashes,
self-flagellation, agony, suffering,
sin. It's a different pathway.
You're welcome
to it if you wish.
It's certainly why I became
an atheist when I was a young age.
No, because it
conflicted with an inner knowingness
of the truth that the presence
has to do with that which is
ecstatic, exquisite,
joyful.
So we look at the
antecedent of it. We looked at the world
today and we see how it's laid out at this point
with the advancement of evolution.
We see the distribution of
consciousness. You understand
the profundity of the discovery
because we can take
the calibrated levels of consciousness of every
country and every region.
We can do that with every
antecedent of man, Neanderthal man,
Homo erectus.
This week's Time magazine
had a new one, 160,000 years old.
We didn't calibrate
his level of consciousness yet.
We will do so now.
He is an antecedent.
We have permission to ask this.
He is an antecedent of Homo sapiens.
And he is an early Homo sapiens.
And his consciousness
is over 100.
His consciousness is over 70.
His consciousness is over
65.
His consciousness is over 60.
His consciousness is over 55.
He better get up there.
Well,
but you see the beginning of the structure
of Homo sapiens.
And then consciousness catches up with it.
Okay.
Grandpa.
Oh yeah.
The difficulty with the calibrated levels
of consciousness is
it can get you into a polarized position
of that which makes you go weak,
that which makes you go strong,
that which is below 200,
and that which is over.
The truth versus falsehood.
And that's the downside of it.
So that's why I mentioned chocolate and vanilla.
Because you like chocolate.
It doesn't mean you have to make vanilla wrong.
Because vanilla had to first become vanilla
before it could become chocolate.
You had to have ice cream before you could flavor it.
You understand?
So vanilla is below 200.
It's early antecedent Homo sapiens.
And then he rises
in his level of consciousness
and it becomes chocolate.
Alright.
So we want to get out of polarization.
Remember chocolate and vanilla
because it will get you right out of it.
You'll see that your mind is automatically reverting back to
we're right therefore they're wrong.
No, they like chocolate, we like vanilla.
We as societies think that free speech is idiotic.
It leads to insurrection.
It leads to death.
It leads to revolt.
It leads to destruction of the economy.
So you see
they like chocolate and we like vanilla.
We want to feel that you can blabber anything you want.
Which is entertaining.
I mean our country is more entertaining.
If you can only say what's been approved
how tedious, huh?
Right now
the books I've written are being looked at
in China and they have a thought police there
they have to examine them and see
whether or not they're permissible
to publish in China.
So we're hoping that they won't notice
spiritual and religious and they just pay attention
to consciousness.
Consciousness may slip by the censors.
Alright so today I thought we would
share where we are.
You see you can go back now in the maps
that we have and check them out
century by century.
Take this whole map.
I want you to picture this.
This is a wonderment of movies
like a hologram.
Let's say each one of those calibrations
has a color.
It gets darker and lighter let's say.
Or more green and more yellow.
And you go back 500 years
and do these same areas.
You go back another 100 years and do the same areas.
You go back and back and back through time.
See what a fascinating map that would make?
First you see light begin to appear.
Then it comes out light yellow.
Then it starts to turn green.
And over here you see it turn red.
Then it turns black.
And here it shines forth
like a moving hologram over time.
See what you can do with that with graphics.
I'm sure the technology exists to do it.
So what were the levels of these countries
century by century?
And you can see the
men begin to appear.
Homo sapiens begin to evolve.
You see the consciousness level
appear and then you see it shine forth
most brilliantly in today's world
in North America
and in America in particular.
You might say
we're the advancing front
of the evolution of human consciousness.
Calibrates higher than any country.
Which means
that we don't like idiots.
It's just that
vanilla and chocolate is mixed together
so you get mocha.
Now the difference is that
the reason I said
the best thing we can do for the world
is to hold them in our thoughts and prayers
is because
the higher the calibrated level of consciousness
the greater its power.
So numerically
there may be many below 200
but their relative power
is weak because
one person at 600
counterbalances
most of humanity
and one at 1000
really counterbalances
all of mankind.
So consequently
the more advanced we become
and hold such people in mind
compassionate
for their suffering
then the power of that intention
is such that we actually
lift the life of people
at the bottom.
Let's see if that's true
or if that's airy-fairy.
Sedona doesn't like airy-fairy.
So we just said it's true.
The devotion of even a group like this
will have a measurable effect
on the consciousness level
of those at the bottom of the world.
The consciousness of this group
here
affects those at the bottom of the barrel.
One day
instead of not having the energy
to even feed yourself
suddenly you care enough to feed yourself.
Many at the bottom of the barrel
do not even have the energy
to feed themselves.
They will starve to death
laying right next to the food.
It's hard to believe but it's so.
So if we include them
in our intention
and spiritual intention is where your power is
that will save you flying over there
and marching in parades
because you affect the field
and because you affect the field
you affect that which is real.
That which is real. That which is permanent.
That which has great power.
Alright, so we just transcended
the ego and the intellect
and we did a lot already.
So let's see how this
evolved over time
because we also
calibrated, I don't know
like about 600
spiritual teachers, religions
things that
I get a constant mail
about these things
and therefore we thought we'd do some.
So let's start with one.
People ask, you know
endlessly. We've got stacks
of mail this high.
This teacher, that guru, that book
this spiritual discipline,
this religion. Now where do they
calibrate? Well
we've reached the
at least this group has reached the level
of dedication to truth.
So I'll give you a caveat.
Anybody who belongs to a
rigid religion, you better
leave now. Alright, so we
began calibrating
so that we all start out
in the same place as
to the nature of God.
In the book I, I think
we summarized what we did at Creative Life
I think chapter 10 calibrates it
a thousand. The exact nature
of God. I think we made 24
or 28 statements about the exact nature
of God. In the entire group
we all did kinesiology together
and there was 100%
agreement about the truth of every single
statement, which is videotaped
documented forever.
So you don't have to go back to scriptures that
are a thousand years old
all about dead people and geographic
places you're never going to visit and never have been.
The evidence for the existence
and the reality of God is right here
now. Right here now.
You don't have to rely on
history. Hmm.
So to make sure we're all in the same
place, we have to understand
what we mean by God and so we asked
what are the various names of God
and what do they calibrate?
The verification of spiritual realities.
Man has had no way to verify
spiritual reality. The only person who can
verify spiritual reality is a mystic.
Everybody else is just talking about it.
What they heard, what they read in
some old book. What good does that
do you? You don't get enlightened
2000 years back in retrospect.
It happens here now folks.
Therefore,
God has to be an
existent, verifiable,
experiential, subjective
reality which can
be experienced in the here and now.
Otherwise it's just talk.
The world is full of talking
about God. Alright.
So, we said what is
the energy field of
the concept of God transcendent?
What's
God infinity, the creator?
Almighty God.
Creator of heaven and earth
and of all things visible and invisible
through his son our Lord Jesus Christ
and the Holy Spirit.
We do bless this endeavor. Amen.
All those terms are infinity.
The supreme,
which you hear from Krishna.
The supreme, Allah, the God of
Muslims, Shiva,
Brahman, all the names for God,
Vishnu. You ask what do they
calibrate? God of Moses
and I wrote that in.
Don't want to forget
Abraham. All of them
infinity. Okay.
So that is God as transcendent.
The infinite creator
of all that exists.
The unmanifest becoming manifest
as creation.
The infinite energy field
to which all form
responds automatically
as a quality
of its own existence.
God is imminent then
is the God of the mystic.
The one that we strive
for in these classes.
It's referred to
in Sanskrit as God imminent
as the Purusa.
As a spiritual teacher is talking
once comes the wording,
understanding, the conceptualization,
etc. It happens
spontaneously of its own.
There is no decision or thought about it.
To use a bad word
is not a decision one makes
when hears it.
It was just
said. Oh, okay.
It's happening of its own spontaneously.
And when you reach a certain
level of realization
you realize that
that is the state of reality
that exists at all times.
There is no you
deciding to sit in the chair
or trying to understand this
or think your thoughts.
It's happening of its own.
You as this little iron filing
through your own spiritual intention
bring yourself into a certain field
in which all that phenomena
is happening autonomously,
automatically, and perfectly of its own.
It doesn't require you to even do that.
That gets rid of you.
To think that there is a person
speaking all these words
would be the height of success of the ego.
The ego would say,
I am the author of all that you do think
and experience.
The ego is not the author of experience.
It's something
that gets filtered through.
So, the self
we hear the realization of the self
many spiritual treatises
are called realization of the self.
The self with a capital S then
is God immanent, present
and it speaks as the
Purusha of the teacher.
It speaks as that.
So that's merely the voice.
Another term for it is Atman.
And this
is supposed to be down below here.
Anyway, I want to contrast
God immanent and transcendent
because there is great argumentation.
The Catholic Church is divided
East and West, the Greek Orthodox
and the Roman Church
over the understanding of
some of these things.
So they are very divisive
whether the ultimate reality is
God transcendent or
God immanent
can lead to huge schisms within the church.
And in reality
you can't experience God as transcendent.
You can only
experience God as immanent.
You can talk about God as transcendent
and therefore theology goes up to about
460 and then it stops there.
So theology
has perfected the talking-ness about it
and
one of the ways to God is through philosophy
and if you are serious about philosophy
it will take you to epistemology.
Epistemology will take you
to the transference
of the source of the reality
of the source of the realization
of reality from objective to subjective
and there you are.
So you can find God if you
follow philosophy to its bitter end
where you finally give up classical
philosophy and you realize
that only subjectivity
can be verified.
One cannot verify
any objectivity at all
anywhere.