The archangels, which we've mentioned before,
calibrate 50,000 up.
Now, these numbers, if you remember, are logarithmic.
50,000, 10 times 10 times 10, 50,000 times.
You have a comparable,
these are only ways of speaking,
of the power of an archangel.
A passing thought of an archangel
is enough to blow you out for 30 years.
It takes 30 years to figure out
how to describe what happened.
A passing thought.
Okay, so there are other descriptions
of the ultimate spiritual reality.
The Buddha nature, as allness, as void.
The Native American Great Spirit
calibrates over 850, which is way up there.
Yehwah, I'm not familiar with,
and Jehovah, I'm not too familiar with,
but they were there, so I did them.
Yehwah was 460, Jehovah was 205.
Then there are other ways of describing gods
that,
we just thought we would see what they are.
And I can't say that I understand all of these either.
There's a term there, Elohim,
which I don't know what it means.
God of the Old Testament is 100.
The Greek gods are 90,
Germanic gods, Scandinavian gods.
So what would you conclude from all of this?
That these were very primitive,
tribal cultures, very primitive.
Okay, let's go to the next one.
The other gods that have been worshipped over time,
the gods of war,
pagan gods of Rome,
the names for God,
the name of God as Om,
as Aum,
or Mother-Father God.
Mother-Father God makes your own go weak.
You can't project gender onto an infinite reality.
I mean, that's giving politics a little too far, right?
You can't project gender onto the infinite reality.
You like trying to project gender onto electricity
or the atmosphere.
It's beyond all gender.
Now, we go to the great spiritual teachers.
They, characteristically, have calibrated it at a thousand.
Jesus the Christ, a thousand.
The Buddha, a thousand.
Krishna, Zoroaster, the twelve Christian apostles.
These are the greats of history,
and there may be some I have forgotten.
And if so, you can put them on a three-by-five card
and leave them with me.
As it is, we spent months and years at this already,
so you can leave some, but you don't have to.
So I thought first we'll start with the verifiable reality.
Let's see if everything on the first slide was correct.
You have permission to ask in front of this audience, oh Lord.
Everything on the first slide was correct.
So we check ourself as we go, you understand?
We check ourself as we go,
because the best of intentions, through ignorance,
one can make a mistake.
And I don't want the karma of making a mistake
as a spiritual teacher with an audience.
Okay, the twelve Christian apostles then.
We see that in the first century,
first century Christianity is extremely high.
The twelve Christian apostles at 980,
you remember the Holy Spirit was transmitted to them.
In the form of the Holy Spirit,
the divinity of the Christ energy,
which is coming from God through that avatar,
was transmitted to the apostles.
And because you look at twelve people,
that's such a profound effect on the world.
They must have been carrying some energy.
And as it turned out, 980, John the Baptist,
St. Peter, Saul of Tarsus.
Yeah, he was Saul of Tarsus and he became St. Peter.
Isn't that correct?
We got Paul instead of Saul?
Well, I'm not much of a biblical scholar, as you can see.
Anyway, I meant to tell you,
these are not the corrected slides.
These are the first run.
And then we go back to them and we make the corrections.
So there are some things I had to write in and all.
And I missed that one.
But we'll get that one before it gets published in a book.
So we're running it through here.
And we'll pick up anything,
because it's really annoying.
Every time you write a book,
you've got to go back and correct this,
and then you reprint it, and then you correct that,
and then somebody writes you something missing on that page.
So this time, we're going to do it all in advance.
.
Abraham, Moses,
so the great avatars of history.
Muhammad is a peculiar case at the time.
He dictated in the Quran.
He was at 740.
Later in life, he took up the sword,
and the way of the sword,
and his calibrated energy dropped to 135.
So that's all phenomena,
not peculiar to him,
but demonstrated most vividly by him.
At that point, they took up the sword
and began killing infidels,
which has continued to this day.
That's how you get off the rail
without kinesiology, right?
That may have something to do
with the way we calibrated North Africa
between plus 10 and plus 40 latitude north,
because that's predominantly Islamic.
So,
we've seen this phenomena happen in many others.
That's a separate section of the book
of still honored gurus,
who at one time were quite high,
and now are considerably less than 200.
We've spoken of that before,
that as consciousness evolves,
there are certain challenges that come up.
And unless one has been adequately informed beforehand,
one is not prepared for that.
And therefore, I have tried to consistently mention
and describe the pitfalls,
how they came in,
and what the error is,
because the error sounds very convincing.
What the error was,
I never had the chance to research it out,
that came to Muhammad,
that he bought into.
He probably bought that he was saving them for God,
probably something like that.
Maybe he thought that by killing them,
he was honoring God, I don't know.
Anyway,
as we mentioned before,
the way to God is through joy.
It is not through death and destruction.
And because you're for chocolate,
you don't have to kill vanilla.
You probably thought you did.
Such fall in grace has happened
with a lot of well-known names in history.
And it's also happened in the secular domain,
not just spiritual teachers.
It happened,
Adolf Hitler,
I think calibrated around 450
when he wrote Mon Confidence.
Early political world,
he was about 450.
By the time he died,
he was like 90 or something.
Napoleon was very advanced consciousness.
He was a brilliant genius.
I think he calibrated around 455, 460.
And after he crowned himself emperor,
he crashed and before he died,
he was like 90.
At Waterloo,
the English,
Wellington, yes.
Wellington calibrated at 460
at the time of Waterloo.
And by that time,
he had fallen to I think about 90.
All right.
So,
it has happened to other people
who reach a certain level of,
I think, power over others.
And suddenly,
there comes a temptation
and the error of judgment is made
and because the person is not adequately prepared in advance,
they fall for the sophistry.
God created sex.
Sex is good,
so let's all have group sex and worship God.
You know what I mean?
There's groups like that.
They were recently famous.
That group crashed very amazingly not long ago too.
Sophistry.
So,
the unprepared mind then is susceptible to error.
And,
again,
what was the problem?
The problem was ignorance.
There's only one ignorance
and that is that the human mind cannot tell truth from falsehood.
The human mind cannot know truth from falsehood.
At a certain level of consciousness,
the spiritual truth is intuitive.
And when it comes to you,
you'll recognize its falsity.
But,
for other reasons I don't know,
a person can fall for it
and therefore we try to prepare everybody in advance for it.
We tell them,
then as you get into the 500s
where everybody is beautiful, holy, and innocent,
that you are wide open on the downside
to be taken in by
the con men of spirituality.
Okay,
so let's go on to the next.
All right.
So now,
we wanted to calibrate some of the world's religions.
This is stuff I've all gotten in the mail.
Everybody's asking all these questions endlessly
and asked when is this book going to come out.
Everything is subject to change and verification later.
Why?
Because
consciousness level of mankind is always shifting.
It's always changing.
A religious sect or something may calibrate here today
and make a big mistake.
A mistake can drop like that.
Or they may suddenly throw out some falsity
and suddenly rise like that.
So it should really have a date on it.
This is of recent times.
Sometime in the early part of the summer or over the winter.
Mahayana Buddhism seems to have survived the best
of any of the religions as far as
being desecrated by extraneous error.
Of which Zen Buddhism is a form of Mahayana Buddhism.
Hinayana Buddhism is
the way of the individual enlightenment.
Mahayana is the greater vehicle.
That one stays back as a bodhisattva because
of one's love and devotion
for the consciousness of all of mankind.
The purpose of Manahayana is
the enlightenment of all of mankind.
Just as our prayers
are for the enlightenment
for the emergence of life energy
and the downtrodden of the world.
So to do that, holding in mind
those who are at the very bottom
who have given up
almost depleted of the energy of life.
So we as a group do that.
That's characteristic of Mahayana.
Hinayana, you worry about your own enlightenment.
You just worry about him.
Mahayana, you hold all of mankind.
Lotus Land Buddhism we mentioned this morning
is somewhat like, in my understanding of it,
is somewhat like Christianity.
See, if the gravity, the spiritual gravity
of this world is so powerful
that it's unlikely you're going to really reach
a great height here because of the negativity,
profound negativity.
One should strive for something that's realizable
such as unconditional love
and at death one automatically goes into
a celestial realm.
The Buddha says somewhat, or some branch of Buddhism
said the same thing.
Instead of heaven is called Lotus Land.
So here one earns merit, perfects oneself
and then the Buddha acts as,
so Christ is your intercessor in heaven
and the Buddha of the Lotus Land
who has a Sanskrit name that I can remember.
Remember the name of the Buddha of the Lotus Land?
Whatever.
Anyhow, acts as your, speaks for you
from the Lotus Land.
Lotus Land is really heaven
and it's practical.
So it's saying most of humanity,
you can shoot for Lotus Land
and from there the presence of the Buddha
will carry you through to enlightenment.
So there is a great similarity then
in Lotus Land Buddhism and Christian heaven.
Tantric Buddhism calibrates considerably less
because it gets involved in occult
and esoteric form.
It gets involved in form
and manipulations of form and symbolism.
So it's considerably less powerful.
And then there are very interpretations
which are quite recent of one Buddhism
and we wondered how they calibrated.
They calibrated in the 400s
so that an intelligent person can read this
and get what it's at.
And a person who really gets what it's at
begins to transcend
and move beyond
that which they've just read.
Because the teaching says move this way.
And so they read and they read and they read
and then they get,
oh, how better is that moving this way?
I mean, you got to come off the page,
come out of the book
and experience the reality.
Christianity beginning in the first century
calibrates extremely high, 980.
I'm in your way.
I'm sorry.
Why is it right here?
Well, I don't know.
You can't see that way.
Get dehydrated.
In the beginning Christianity
was really called the way.
As we see, the apostles calibrated at 980.
And interestingly enough,
first century Christianity calibrates at 980,
exactly that of the apostles.
Christianity took a giant fall.
It crashed worse than any other religion.
At the Council of Nicaea,
it dropped from the 900s
down to 465, 485, somewhere in there.
That in itself is a whole research project.
Who was at this council?
What were the factions involved?
What was the energy that brought it down?
What was the spiritual error?
What was the sacrifice that was made?
My suspicion is that for political reasons,
some sacrifice in truth was made.
And we can't condemn it
because maybe in order to survive,
Christianity had to make that concession,
perhaps politically.
So that's sort of my intuition,
that there are certain points
at which certain religions
have had to make some kind of an accord
with the political powers that ruled at the time
in order to survive at all.
And so they said,
it's better to survive
and give up, let's say, the requirement
to not eat meat on Friday or something trivial
and survive rather than insist on it
and find ourselves outlawed and executed.
Okay.
So first century Christianity then reflects
the apostles at 980,
the dominance of spiritual truth,
and something happened to it
after the Council of Nicaea.
The College of Cardinals right now
calibrates at 490.
The papacy itself, as a position,
calibrates at 570,
which is the same as the Dalai Lama,
who, see, those two functions are similar,
to be head of a church.
A lot of these calibrations you have to,
you know, we're not talking about judgmentalism.
One is not better than another.
Because each calibrated level
is suitable for itself.
So perfect doesn't mean higher.
It means perfect for that.
At 570, you would make a very bad
president of the United States.
At 600, it'd be a joke.
The ideal president of the United States
would be around 460.
And all the presidents, frankly,
have been around that.
Higher than that,
you'd rather be a professor.
Lower than that, you haven't got the savvy.
So you have to ask yourself,
what's ideal?
To be ideal as the inspirational head
of a world church,
you should calibrate around 570.
And, peculiarly enough,
they do.
The current pope is at 570.
And the Dalai Lama,
about the same.
Coptic, I'm not that familiar.
Born again is more sort of
a radical positionality to it.
So it drops down to
sort of a us and them.
It's a very,
sort of an us and them about it all.
The agnostics
didn't calibrate as high as I thought
they would, and I would,
I may have to research it further.
Because I was,
a lot of times we just calibrated the term.
See, each one of these is a lifetime
project in itself, right?
You understand that.
To just pick one of these and explain
why is this what it is,
that would get you a PhD thesis
to study that, wouldn't it?
You'd have to study it through history,
how it was described from various viewpoints,
look at it from the inside,
the outside, its impact,
the culture it grew up in,
and then you would really begin to get what it means.
So I can't tell you that I know
what all of this signifies.
Not this morning.
Not until after lunch.
Why is Coptic 475?
Why is this 350
and this year 290
when these are much higher?
I don't know why.
Modern Protestantism is at 510.
I thought it was going to be at 410.
Modern Catholicism is at 440.
If you ask
what are some of the recent
decisions the Church has made,
you will find they are far less than 440.
But that the overall thrust of the
whole was not
because the decisions were made by
laymen
or by people, just by people
and perhaps for practical
reasons, who knows.
So anyway, modern Catholicism
is still at 440.
The Jesuit Order reflects it quite
accurately.
I went to a Jesuit university.
I had a good deal of respect for their
academic dedication
and especially their courses on ethics.
And
I thought it's too bad most of the
world hasn't taken a course
of ethics at a Jesuit university.
Too bad.
Ethics. So they did very good on logic
and ethics and all, and I
really appreciated their dedication.
The Amish, I'm not that familiar
with, except they have
sort of funny ways.
And the Quakers
at
505, and
I've always admired the Quakers, and I did
go to a couple of Quaker events,
and they were quite so different
than anything else. There was no liturgy.
People sat quietly
and started meditating, and when they felt the Spirit
lift them to speak, they stood up and spoke.
It was quite impressive. I really
liked it. It was very genuine
and very much this
instant and not based on
ancient history.
So
the Amish and then we have the Quakers
and Unity is
an interest of mine. I've always liked
Unity because
they seem to try to stick to the spiritual
core of
Christianity primarily
or any spiritual reality.
Pentecostal
I'm not that familiar with.
The Puritans are at 210.
The Puritans
at 210
sound like they could have been a little prissy.
No, they weren't
prissy. The Puritans left
out of protest against
the hedonistic
indulgence and decadence
of Europe of the day.
And therefore, they maybe went
the other way and became particularly
stringent. And in our culture
what we consider
morality is primarily
Puritanism.
You don't realize that until you travel to Europe.
You think that our morality
is, you know, morality.
And then you go to
Paris and you go to
the washroom and it says
they don't have a men here and a women
there, they have just one.
It's sort of shocking. You walk
in and well the men go to this side
and the women go to this side, but there's only one washroom
and then you all use the same washstand in the middle
and they have passoires where the conversation
and they're both, these guys urinating
in this little box and their
conversation goes right on. And you
say, my God, are we ever prissy back
in America?
We all thought this was immoral.
You realize it's got nothing to do with morality.
You don't want to interrupt the conversation just because
you got to take a leak, so they just stop by.
Conversation goes on
and the girlfriend's out there and they're arguing and then
he walks out and she's buttoning his pants and goes
and you say, my God, we're prissy
back home. We thought that
was ethics and morality. You see, it's not
got nothing to do with ethics and morality. It has to do with
Puritanism. Oh.
It isn't ethics and morality, it's
Puritanism, so you see. The source
of our own Puritanism.
So that's why it's 210. It's not exactly
devotional love.
Television evangelists,
so they're over
200. They're over 200.
Thank God.
205.
The new, what's that
little boy with the glasses book?
Harry Potter.
I was very relieved. We calibrated the Harry Potter
book and it's 208. And I said,
thank God.
A lot of the video games, you know, that capture
the youth calibrate like 60 or 70.
I mean, they're really, really
they're calibrated about the same as
Ivan the Terrible. I mean, they're just horrible.
So I was so relieved that Harry
Potter was over 207, I think. Thank God.
Thank you, Lord, for
Harry Potter being over 208.
All these kids being brainwashed
with something that's calibrated at 90. I mean,
you know what I'm saying? So, anyway.
Alright. The Church of
LDS is, I get a lot of
questions about them. They're 390 and
I think the Book of Mormon calibrates around
500. Ancient Hinduism,
the ancient Vedas,
calibrated extremely
high. And, of course, those are celebrated
in the Sanskrit literature.
The great
spiritual enlightened
teachers of ancient
time. Many of whom
are almost like
fables, you know. Modern
Hinduism is like
Christianity. It seems like
the great religions come into the high
400s because they
are being presented
as a teaching,
as an intellectual. So it's given a
scholastic
form, you understand?
So to explain anything comes out in,
tends to come out in the 400s, where people
of reason and logic
can study it at the university
and get a PhD in comparative
theology. Alright.
Hmm. Hinduism, Hare Krishna
order
460. Hinduism,
Subhadra is a current
relatively well known. And the Sikhs
are 420. So,
okay, let's do another one.
See, what we're trying to do is get a
panorama. We're trying to get a panorama
of what has spiritual truth been like
over the ages. How does it
express itself in the different cultures
and the different religions
and spiritual belief systems.
This is a current Hinduism that is
popular in South
India. Tamils sort of
tradition, 330.
Raja Yoga, 485.
Sahad Marj, 410.
Jainism, 495.
It's inconvenient, Jainism, in the United States
because you've got to step over every mosquito
and things like that.
You have to step over every, I always thought those
were people who disregarded life in the last
lifetime. And in this lifetime, by God, they
step over every ant until they get it, you know?
What do they do about the flies?
I don't know. After many years
I had an office in New York, you know, very
famous office. And behind the
drapes I had hidden a butterfly net.
And when the patients weren't there,
there was always some flies flying around.
And I hid this butterfly net behind the
drapes. And when the staff wasn't there
and no patients were there, I quickly ran out and
snared them and put them out the window.
Because I was a
strict Buddhist for a long time. I didn't eat
meat, I was a vegetarian.
No sugar, no, I didn't kill even a fly.
But I thought they would all think
that's a little weird, so I kept it hidden behind
the drapes.
The patient walks out and the doctor runs
around with a butterfly net.
He opens the window, puts them out,
blesses them, bless you.
Oh boy.
So I was a
secret Buddhist.
I went to the first Zen Institute
in New York City. I was a secret Buddhist.
Anyway, it was
sort of
pop culture for a while, too.
Anyway, I secretly saved
the life of the flies.
Where are we? Oh, Islam.
Oh yeah, we had Islam.
See, Islam, the Koran, is still at
700. The Koran, I mean
the truth of the Koran then, has been
savaged
by the political
people, which as
Christianity was at the time of the
Inquisition, etc.
So any political group can come in
and claim that it is part of a
religious thing.
And Ayatollah in Iran,
however, it's extremely low, as do all the
mullahs and the rest of the
Arabic world. But
the truth of the basic religion itself
is at 700.
Islam, 700.
Islam, as practiced, is 325.
Muslims,
205.
Modern Judaism, I'm not all that much
of an expert on Judaism
and its history.
I know there's several main schools,
conservatives and modern
and traditional, etc.
So that would require somebody who knows
something about it to set up what should be
calibrated. I don't myself know that much about it.
Shinto itself is
350. And of course
that played a big part in World War II.
And the way of the Dao
is 500.
And I say, relax into the flow,
the realization of that which you already
are. That's the
way of the Dao.
590? Okay.
That phrase, relax into the
reality of that which you already are.
Calibrates over 600.
It's over 590.
Relax into the reality of that which you already are.
Calibrates over 595.
600.
Right at 600.
That's right at 600. So that would be
an expression
of Daoism.
It's spelled T-A-O, but it's
pronounced Dao.
Comparative calibrations. We said
these are all things people have sent us.
We still have stacks
of them to go. We're going to be old and gray
by the time we finish.
And the book's going to be this thick.
People keep sending us more.
They keep sending us more books. Every day in the mail
there's more books. Please calibrate this, calibrate this teacher.
Alright, so we got some of
the evidence. What have they got? I don't know the
reason for all these things.
But these are the calibrations
which we got, and we've
of course
reverified these
before we made them into a slide.
Yesterday we went back
over each one of them, because I don't want
them to be there and be an error.
We said that these are
accurate as they stand.
We have permission to ask this
in front of this group over there.
This slide is accurate as it stands.
This slide is accurate
as it stands, as much as we know
as of today.
Any one of these can make a shift
in tomorrow, just like doing
the giant corporations. The minute they
fire that CEO, the calibration level
of that corporation jumps up.
We've also done
100 corporations.
We've been busy, right?
Did all the countries in the world,
did all the spiritual
teachers, all the books, and
we were working on the Fortune 500
list of the best, biggest
corporations in the world.
So, anyway,
this is part of the ongoing study.
It's called the Institute for Advanced
Theoretical Research, Consciousness Research.
So they say, what do you
do there? Well, this is what we do. We try to find
out what is the reality of everything.
Because it totally changes
your conception of it, your understanding
of it. It's like a
two-dimensional world now suddenly becoming
three-dimensional and technicolor. It takes on
a whole different significance and
impact.
Seventh-day Adventists, I don't know what their
problem is.
I know what it is.
A lot of these get caught up in
I know what it is. A lot of
these groups get caught up in the Book of
Revelations. And you remember
the Book of Revelations calibrates at 70.
Seventy, in contrast
to the New Testament.
So if you get caught up, and it's easy to get
caught up in the Book of Revelations because it's
so dramatic. I mean,
you know, drama tends to
suck people right in.
It sounds so dramatic that it
is, what?
What?
Huh?
She interrupted. How do you like that?
Are you asking something?
Oh, I don't know what time it is.
Is it three minutes to twelve?
Oh, it can't be three minutes to twelve.
We just started. It's only 830, isn't it?
Alright, we've got three minutes to finish
the rest of these religions, and then we'll break for lunch.
Oh, there's no clock in here.
It must be we're living in
timelessness.
We disappeared time this morning. I don't know where time went.
I didn't notice it. Did you notice that? I didn't either.
Alright, we'll quickly run through all these.
Some of them are sort of
fun to look at.
Jehovah's Witness 195, they have sort of
a strange
understanding of the Old Testament with sort of a
thing about
what's expected there. I forget what they call that.
Alright, so right-wing
fundamentalist Christian and right-wing all
that tends to come down quite a bit.
The Urantia book is 150.
Wicca, as you would expect, is 160.
Army of God is
the people that blow up
abortion
clinics and kill
gynecologists and stuff.
Imagine running around with a bomb
and you can't find an abortion clinic to blow
up with it.
I was going to say you're a
terrorist and you can't find a busload of
children to blow up. Imagine the frustration.
You've got these bombs and you can't find a busload of
kids. Okay, so
Army...
New Age gets sort of out there.
They recently
had a
fairy festival here and it
calibrated at 140.
Alright, so
these are sort of primitive.
New Ageism itself, which we
said is one of the things you can get
pulled into.
Practically all of us here at one time, I'm sure, have had a
psychic reading. We've done the
tarot cards. I mean, everybody's got to check
it out, do the I Ching, you know.
And you find out what that's all about.
That's part of curiosity. It's part of
spiritual adolescence.
What's out there? What are the alternatives?
What does it look like? A lot of it is
attractive. And I'll tell you
what tends to calibrate quite low,
disappointingly low. We notice
characteristically there'll be at least a quarter
page in the newspaper.
And it always has a Christ-like
figure there.
Who comes from a long
spiritual tradition of the sixth
reincarnation of the ancient something.
And he's going to give you a four or five day
workshop on how to breathe your way to God
and this is going to cost you 500 bucks.
So we've noticed that there's a
seduction to it. He said,
what's characteristic? Because there's a whole lot of
East Indian gurus that have come down a
long way. I mean a long way.
From mid to high 500s down
less than 200.
Characteristic of those groups is
the glamour
of spiritual seduction.
The mystical, magical,
and on the internet it tells you they are the
great savior, the new avatar.
And you calibrate them
and they're 290.
So mankind projects
onto them their own
fantasies and wishes.
That which is garbed and robed
in seductiveness
once you be
a watchful eye.
It's trying to pull you into the glamour.
So the glamourization of spiritual
reality with sandals,
incense, bald heads, flowing robes
and showing peculiar things
and sitting cross legged and smoking weird
things and being feeble at the same
time is not necessarily
the greatest
truth on earth.
But the oohs and the ahhs.
Look we've all been there.
So and so's ashram and walked through
the incense and all the praying
and the old headed people and
the weird crap you eat with two fingers.
Disgusting. I knew I wasn't
going to be a Hare Krishna right off the bat.
This is strained
peas and you eat it with two fingers.
No thank you.
The way to God is not
through colonic irrigations
and
strained peas.
We'll prove that later
on because I think we did strain peas
in colonic irrigations. I think it comes up.
Alright so
what's wrong with this is
it's adolescent fantasying.
It's the child, the spiritual child
who's enamored
of the flowers and
the fairy dances around the
maypole. Alright so now
we can see what these all are
and we notice that cults can
go anywhere from 50 to
160 and we've already
described cults.
A cult has
membership. You have to do
certain things. You have to pay certain things.
The teacher, the head
person has all kinds of privileges
and you don't.
They can have sex but you can't.
You should turn over your money to them.
Anyway, the whole charisma
of the cult is
so well known now. I think several
of them having fallen in the last 20 years
with a loud crash
many people are quite aware of what a
cult looks like and
sounds like. The accumulation
of wealth and the attraction seems
to be of those gurus who fall
into power over others.
We calibrated
the term guru itself
and the term baba.
We found that both of them make you go weak.
The term guru
started to make you go weak after 1960.
Before that
traditionally it was
a title of honor for a
spiritual teacher
who calibrated. We said we found out
it was 540 or 460.
True guru
was 540 or 560.
We got in these books
not to use the term
because I go over every page I've written
and I say there's something out.
We always get the word guru is not correct.
I tried to use it in its historic
classical meaning
and I was advised not to use it.
Also the word baba.
So
we asked what was it in 1960?
The word guru fell.
The word guru fell
in 1960.
The influence of the
glamorization through the media
and the exploitation
somehow brought down
the calibrated energy of that
title.
Then we have other things
that have fallen.
These seem to have to do with
control of people.
Those which
have fallen off and become cults
seem to have to do with controlling people,
having lots of followers
and interfering with their personal
life.
Can you imagine a real teacher
really caring whether you stay married
or don't get married?
What would he care about that?
Whether you sell your oxen
and you don't sell your oxen
or whether you eat soup for lunch
or you eat fish.
Why would a person want to control you?
A true teacher has no interest in controlling people
and having followers.
Who wants troops and zillions of people following you around
if you're a real nuisance?
Throwing melons at you
and whatever.
Dodging flowers.
It would be horrible.
I hope you like that.
Qigong, Shiite Muslim cults.
We'll stop at the end of this list
and break for lunch.
This is of course the cult that set off
the poison bomb
in the Tokyo subway.
All these things that are done
in the name of God.
I forget which one this one is.
This is the fellow
who recently was in the news.
Anyway,
he only calibrates to 130.
That's the one the salvation of mankind
is going to come by an extraterrestrial,
I think.
All right.
This is Dr. Moon.
We see what the Catholic
religion itself stands at.
It still stands solid and firm.
But its positionality
on pedophilia
is frankly at 90.
So,
even though one is a great world leader,
we know from past presidents and all,
you can still have errors
on the side.
Apparently it did not bring down the church itself
because the church as such,
as a body of traditional
et cetera,
stands firm.
But the decision itself
has not had a good effect.
All right.
So, we know that it's bad to be judgmental.
And you know
you can tell that...
All right.
So, we had one more to do?
Oh, okay.
Well, this one we've hit before.
Somehow the Old Testament,
the book of Revelations we know,
and we know that the calibration of,
which we'll get to in the next slide,
I think,
of Scriptures has to do with
whether or not you have
in the Old Testament certain books.
And the minute you take them out,
the calibrated level of the Bible jumps.
It's down three, four hundred points.
The minute you remove those books
that make you go weak,
especially the book of Revelations,
the calibrated level.
So, the Lamsa Bible minus the Old Testament
with the exception of Psalms,
Proverbs, and Genesis,
and the Lamsa version,
which is from the Aramaic
rather than the Greek,
calibrates at 880,
which is quite a bit different
than that translated from the Greek
kind of common English translation, which is only 480.
So, in other words,
to be able to calibrate the level of truth of things
is of great,
is a great advance.
Don't forget we're at the leading edge.
Man never had this tool before.
You can't fault people for going in the wrong direction
if they've got no compass.
Last night we watched two guys who get lost
up in the Rockies at the
Continental Divide,
and I said,
this guy's out there without even a compass.
And his buddy goes a mile ahead of him
in the strand zone. I said,
he goes a mile ahead
in the snowstorm,
and strains his buddy a mile behind him
who doesn't have a compass.
If you ever wandered around the Continental Divide,
you know what it's like in the middle of winter.
I remember the Continental Divide
on the 4th of July, it was snowing.
And I marked that in my mind,
I said, remember this, on the 4th of July,
the Continental Divide, it was snowing.
Alright, so it's time to take
a break for lunch. Has everybody been able
to handle this okay?
I mean, I don't want to upset anybody, understand?
I turned my co-dependency
over to God, and it's your problem.
Well, we're on the air, folks.
We have
21 pages of calibrations,
each of which has 30
calibrations on it.
Where's
Sonya? Sonya is the one responsible
for having it in the form
that we could actually project it
for the audience. She worked around the clock
for days.
21 pages with 30 calibrations
on each one was quite a bit
of effort to get it done for today.
So we want to thank you.
That's dedication.
Alright.
When we were doing
higher spiritual groups, I thought I'd mention
that the Bee Gees calibrated 510.
I just thought you'd like to know that.
I knew it, I knew it.
Well, you see, because I'm trying to
talk about what is a spiritual reality.
You see, a pious sounding
hymn, you might say, oh, that's so
pious and Lord Jesus this and all.
You'd say, whoa.
No, the Bee Gees are at 510.
Why is that? Well, when you hear the Bee
Gees, it's hard to sit still, isn't it?
I mean, it's almost impossible
not to dance at 510
because you're,
because it brings up the joy of your
own existence, you understand?
It's ecstatically joyful
and
so that's the reality we're looking
for. Not which is
pain and sin and suffering
and chains and all that.
But that which leads to
truth, you know,
because you start experiencing
moments of joy
and they're like
outside of time and you
know you're on the right way. And then
they disappear. In the beginning they appear
and then they disappear.
But don't feel bad about it.
Don't feel bad about it. I mean,
not feel bad about it.
You let go of that little
piece of karma and now you've got some more. Oh well.
But those
little glimpses that you begin to get
early in the, early
you know, tell you that
you're on the right road.
What we're talking
about of course are
first of all things that are outside of
time, things
of recent discovery
together with the subjective
experiential which is totally outside
of time. The field of consciousness,
the nature of the field of
consciousness is that it
registers everything and anything
that happened, every event,
every thought, every feeling, every incident.
Nothing escapes the
field of consciousness. Consequently,
that which has
preceded us in time is registered
forever. It says
in scripture, not one hair of your
head shall go uncounted and that is a
fact. It's registered
there forever. It's obvious
then that you can't
use kinesiology about the future
because it has no reality.
It's only a hypothetical possibility
and because it hasn't
been printed out yet, there's no way to
get that newspaper. You can't get it in
tomorrow's newspaper today because
it has not unfolded. So
in a way what consciousness
is, is a recording of the history
of evolution, of
creation. It's the history of
creation as it appears
as evolution
and the appearance in evolution
of course is to perception
and beyond perception there's nothing
evolving.
It doesn't
need explanation at all
because it's only a way of looking
at things. So let's
go on to the next exciting chapter.
I don't know how far we'll get through it today.
You can see that
any one of these calibrations
could, you could spend a whole
couple years studying it
to get the complete story. What happened
at the Council of Nicaea,
why various things calibrated what they do.
Each one is
a whole world of study in itself.
So we're sort of like Galileo
who discovered the telescope
and now he's going to give you the
rudiments of the heavens
but astronomy is
around the clock by thousands of people with
computers and they're still discovering
things. So that's where we're at in the
unfolding of this sort of field
of conscious awareness
that is of such recent
origin. However it was
predicted and it did
come into existence
subsequent to the
jump in consciousness
of mankind from 190 to 207
which happened in the late
1980s. So
all of it seems to
coincide and everything as you can
see happens in
absolute perfection.
So it doesn't really need you in a way
you say.
That which is evolutionary
unfoldment then
is what we witness.
So we tracked down
as I say we have
quite a few major subjects. Spirituality
is one of them. Americana is another.
History, archaeology, paleontology,
art, science,
philosophy. All
of them are things we are working on currently.
But this one is at least
type Delphic dissonia and
so we have spiritual
titles you see because
throughout the years various titles are
used by various spiritual
groups and organizations and just
what does that mean you know see.
A true master is 700
and over. A saint is 700 and over.
Lord is a thousand.
A sage is 700 and
over. Angels are
550 and over. So you don't have to
hit 50,000 to be an angel.
That's archangel.
You get to be a general.
And enlightenment we said is
600. The title
which I
cannot pronounce is 800.
The probe is 570. Now the
true guru was 540
and that was so until
1960. And now it says don't use it
because it has come to mean something else.
But a true guru,
a true spiritual teacher would
be ideally 540 and over.
And these are other terms from
Sanskrit and Swami and
oh yes I have guru prior to the
1960s was 540 and over.
Now for some reason the title of
Baba and Guru have
fallen down
and just as a curiosity
we noticed that over time three popes
despite the title of pope which calibrates
as 570 actually calibrated
below 200.
Alright so that's not surprising.
We're all familiar with history.
And you learn a lot of spiritual reality
watching the history channel. You really do. You see the
unfoldment and you say ah I see what that is.
And you say ah I see what that is.
Oh you get an understanding.
They're neat.
Scriptures and traditional spiritual writings.
People are always interested in these things.
As I say I get
box loads of letters asking
all these things.
Bhagavad Gita at 910.
The Vedas at 910.
So the ancient Hindu enlightened
masters, mystics
stand at very high.
Zohar which is more the
Hebraic and Judaic
tradition is also extremely
high at 720.
Ramayana 810.
Mahabharata 780.
Kabbalah 720.
Apocrypha.
It's still part of what?
The Roman Catholic Bible I believe.
The Torah 745.
The Koran is at 700.
The Heart, Lotus, and Diamond
Sutras are all in the high 700s.
So when
Niko chants, one reason we have the music
that we have when you come in is that
calibrates at 700.
And when Niko chants that mantra
is at 700.
It's non-intellectual.
So they're both non-intellectual.
Instead of just being at one with the field
which doesn't require any thought or
thinkingness so you don't get trapped in the 400s.
The Dead Sea Scrolls at 650.
The Gospel of St. Thomas
660.
The Book of Kells, that's my writing.
In Dublin.
The illuminated
manuscripts which are fascinating.
And sometimes one manuscript
took a monk one entire lifetime.
It's staggering.
So what you see is the devotion,
the tremendous devotion
to dedicate yourself
and dedicate this expertise and this beauty.
It's like the carver
who carved the pulpit in the cathedral
in
South America.
I was telling them about that
at lunch and I'm not too much
into the thinking mind
at the moment. Where was that?
That was in
Peru, yes, yes.
Anyway, and there was this magnificent pulpit
in Cusco.
Cusco, right, yes.
Yes, in Cusco, there's the cathedral.
Oh, magical, enchanting.
And there's this incredible
pulpit. A pulpit is really two stories
high. You think of a pulpit as this high.
No, no, it's a great big thing.
One entire lifetime.
And the carving is at great depth.
So there's figures here and figures behind them
and then animals behind that.
So this carving goes in at great depth.
One whole lifetime.
And there at the top sits, in a little
hall, things like this, the skull
of the sculptor.
You know, we think it's sort of
awkward coming from our culture,
but it's like reverence.
Here's the, like
the relics, the bones of the man who
spent an entire lifetime devoting
his whole lifetime
to celebrating
the magnificence of God by
giving what his gift was.
You know, it's quite heart touching.
We've added a 595.
Now, we've already covered the Bible
before, and I want to make sure
that everybody's got it down
where it is.
The Lamsa Bible,
which is translated from the Eastern
manuscripts from Aramaic,
calibrates roughly
20 points higher than
the King James
version, which is translated from the Greek.
20 points in serious
spiritual work is quite a bit different.
Some things that are stated
in a negative term
in the King James
version, as you read it,
it doesn't sit right. It just doesn't feel
like Jesus Christ would have said that, and you're
probably correct. And then when you
look at that from the Aramaic,
he didn't say that. He said more what you
thought he was going to say. So it's sort of interesting.
We know
that in the Old Testament,
three books of the Old Testament make you
go strong with kinesiology, and only
three. Psalms,
Genesis, and Proverbs.
If you take out the rest of the Old Testament,
then
the calibrated level of the Bible
jumps extremely high.
The New Testament,
King James, is at
790 if you delete the Book of
Revelations. If you want the highest
possible Christian reading, you have
the lumps of Bible, minus the Old Testament,
minus the Book of
Revelation, but including
Genesis, Psalms, and Proverbs,
and you come out at
880. So that would
seem to be the highest Christian
scripture is from
the Aramaic, minus that
which makes you go weak with
kinesiology. Alright, and that
brings it up to 880.
880 is certainly a lot higher
than the ordinary
King James version.
The Tibetan Book of the
Dead, of course, is historic,
575. It's not
the ultimate thing that a lot of people would like
to think it is. The Sanhedrin at the
time of Jesus, who after all voted
on his fate,
calibrated at 240.
Therefore,
doing what in their understanding was
integrous. 240 is above
integrity. So,
as mistaken as we might think
they were, they nevertheless
were coming from
truth as they saw it.
The Yoga Sutras of
Patanjali,
630.
The Course in Miracles,
600. The Book of Mormon,
510.
Wayne Dyer likes this
I made a note of this because
I know he likes...
I used to think it was Patanjali.
He said no, potentially.
So, I don't know if he's right or not.
Neither one of us knows, I mean,
I'm sure.
Wayne is extremely well read, you know,
Dyer's read everything.
That's what makes him a great teacher.
Alright, spiritual
concepts. The saying of
Jesus Christ, none get to heaven but by
me, calibrates at 940.
Meaning what?
Meaning that the average person
needs a savior.
The average person, because he's
not at 540, is going to need a savior.
And
that which stands at the hand of God,
you might say, and speaks in your behalf
then, is the savior.
The same as
the Buddha of the Lotus Sutra, yeah?
The statement,
I of the I,
I of the I, is itself
900. I as
divinity, 990 to
998.
I as the allness, the totality.
And I as the supreme.
And those, of course,
are aligned with the titles
of the books to signify
the content, or the intention
of the content. Justice
as a concept,
as a way of life, everybody's very
hung up on justice, is
380. Justice
is an I for an I,
is 375.
Alright, and theology itself,
as a study, as a way to understand
and get to God,
theology then takes the intellect
up to 460.
And then, as I said,
from theology, you really have to go to
epistemology, and from
epistemology
to gnosis, and
the innate knowingness of the divinity
within which shines forth
when you remove all that stands in its
way. Alright, and before
I fall over, we'll do the near death
experience.
Laughter
Which almost took me out a couple times.
It was 520.
There I was in the snow bank.
That was the snow bank, right?
That was the
paper boy that I wrote about in the book.
Yeah.
Never heard of such a thing.
So I never mentioned it to anybody.
I never mentioned it until 1995.
What are you going to tell?
In the subway, you can poke somebody and say, hey, guess what?
In the presence of divinity, they say,
wow, have you seen your doctor lately?
Better increase your
Prozac.
Satori,
these are the experiences that come on and then
you feel dismal that they don't persist.
They often come on
in the beginning with
formal meditation with your eyes closed.
Then if you open your eyes
and begin to move around, it disappears.
In a more advanced state, you can
open your eyes and it does not disappear.
In an even more advanced state,
you can get up sitting cross-legged
in a meditative position,
keep your eyes open, and walk around in the world.
And the presence maintains.
All those things
have names in Sanskrit, by the way,
which I don't understand
Sanskrit, so I'll skip them.
All right, so Satori, then,
these are the flashes of light
that you see, and they may stay
for varying periods of time.
They all have formal names.
I think in Ramana Maharshi's
book, it does give names. There's somebody
who wrote a book like that.
It gives the names for the different states
when Satori is eyes closed, eyes open,
eyes walking around,
and it becomes more and more permanent.
The Christian Communion,
the act of the Christian Communion,
is surprisingly high.
The first time I did it,
I got 700.
At the moment when
the blessed
wafer, etc.,
and the blessing occurs,
that energy is actually 700.
Anybody can calibrate it. You can watch
Midnight Mass at home,
and you'll get that at that moment,
as they present it,
that is 700.
So there is certainly
a good reason, then,
to honor
Communion.
There are various ceremonies
and festivals.
The sweat lies ceremony came out
higher than I thought it would, because of the intention
of purification.
It actually comes out at 560.
Smudging, which is a fun thing,
also turns out
to be 520.
Some of them turned out to be a little higher
than I thought they'd be.
Transcendental meditation,
as you see, is a technique.
As a technique,
it comes out at 220.
The sound of Tibetan Buddhist horns, 320.
This is a sacred dance,
320.
This is a holiday of Christmas itself,
the so-called Christmas spirit,
538.
Certainly, we recognize it
as love.
This is one of the states
we referred to,
one of the Satori states,
but this one is called Samadhi,
and that is extremely high.
The following spiritual experiences,
the reason I repeat these
is because on the audio
you won't be able to see the chart.
We ask about spiritual energy,
is that an absolute reality?
Because, you know, science books
and most of the things we're talking about today,
is chi energy
an actual reality?
We get yes.
Is the etheric body an actual reality?
The answer is yes.
Anybody who's gone out of body,
it will seem like a
comical question.
But the people who've never been out of the body,
they think it is a fantasy or an imagination.
And
there's certain
pseudo science programs
that come on
and their purpose is to
discredit all these things
and disprove them.
Anyway, so I thought we should just reaffirm them.
They're all experiential.
I know the reality
having experienced them.
But not everybody has.
Is reincarnation a reality?
Karma and reincarnation?
Yes.
The 33 miracles attributed to Jesus.
True.
He miraculously fed the thousands.
Says it's true.
The miracles performed by the Christian apostles.
Don't forget they calibrated
980 at the time.
Positive. Speaking in tongues.
Positive.
The Pentecostal flame by which the Holy Spirit
infused
and lifted the
level of consciousness of the apostles
is true.
John the Baptist was killed for revealing
the truth. True.
Jesus was killed for revealing the truth.
The truth has never always been,
as you can see, very popular.
In today's world,
when we get to some reality,
in today's world,
it is extremely unpopular.
The truth is not popular.
Pentecostal flame positive.
John the Baptist, Jesus.
Name and form are one. True.
This is something we've said before we discovered.
Wait three days before a burial or cremation
of the body after
physical death to allow the
spirit to get adjusted.
You always thought
you were this and then suddenly
the this is laying down there
and you're here.
It takes a little while to perhaps grieve.
The lower the level of consciousness,
the longer you should delay.
Because the lower
the level of consciousness, the more you think you are
that and therefore
there's considerable grief.
You're mourning the loss of the physicality
and the life that went with it.
As you're more advanced, you're very happy to be
rid of it and you could probably be
cremated in 10-20 minutes.
You go,
whew,
what a relief.
It's like taking off all this baggage and weight.
It's like all your clothes are so heavy.
You take them all off.
You take this helmet off.
You take all this crap off and now you feel light and free.
I don't see any point in
mourning it.
This is what it says
as a generality. Wait three days.
We asked, can a human actually live
on prana energy and we got true.
That is so.
There is a fabled saint who lived her life
in Germany
solely on prana.
That's a fact.
I'm so doubtful about that one.
She's of course fabled
as a great saint.
The consciousness level is already set at birth.
We've already mentioned that is true.
The exact time of death
leaving the physical body is karmically
set at birth. That is true.
Comparative calibrations.
Ghosts are real.
No.
Haunting. No.
The prophecy at end times upon which
a lot of people make a lot of
gain of
pulling off the fear.
Prophecy at end times are nonsense.
Including Saint Matthew's
prophecy at end times. His is nonsense too.
One can experience
one's own physical death.
It's not possible.
The experiencer
which is the spirit
has already left it.
How can you experience what's over there
when you're here?
I can't experience what goes on with the carpet
because I'm not a carpet.
When I thought I was a carpet
I thought you were walking on me all the time.
We'll go on to the next
exciting chapter.
I can't tell you how much time
went into all this.
The correcting of it.
The inquisition of
the great fable of the inquisition
of the Middle Ages and medieval times
frankly calibrated at 30.
How mankind survived is really unbelievable.
Channeling itself.
190 and transmediumship
and tarot readings
and the occult
are all things that I've said in previous lectures to avoid.
Scripture doesn't say
that it's not true.
It says don't go there.
It says don't go there
because you're not as clever
as that which has existed as cleverness
for millennia.
It knows just what would attract you
and says,
Hi, sweetie.
Give me a kiss for Jesus.
Gotcha.
It's because
it's uncanny.
Until the third eye opens
until you have spiritual discernment
you can spot what it is.
You spot
the seduction of the glamour
you can spot the seduction
of the glamourization
of spiritual truth
which is put out by some organizations
which I already mentioned this morning.
You just get the sense
that there's a glamourization
and a seduction
to try and pull you in.
There's going to be shared secrets
reviewed by ancient masters.
The minute you hear that, forget it.
Because they want a piece of you
in return, control it's called.
So you don't want to do
a deal with that which you cannot see.
Alright.
The tarot readings, etc. 190.
The occult, 150. Voodoo, 45.
Satanism, 45.
Fortune telling, 60. Devil worship.
Black magic. Black witchcraft.
And all these
negative things.
You begin to sense as you evolve
that that is not the pathway
of love and purity.
It's the pathway of hidden
secrets and surreptitious
ceremonies.
It's the accumulation of energies.
And unless you're in a very advanced
shaman, in which case you wouldn't
even be here, I wouldn't mess with them.
Because they're
smarter than you are.
Alright, so on the positive side,
the Lord's Prayer itself,
650.
Om, pronounced as om,
740.
Aum, 210.
Om namah shivaya, 630.
Chani, chani,
that's not spelled right.
Whatever it is, it's 650.
Sounds good.
Om mana padme hum,
700.
The Gregorian Chants, somebody asked me about.
595.
Japa, the repetition, etc.
of Japa, 515.
The Jesus Prayer itself, 525.
Sing the Rosary,
515.
Prayer of Shabez, which has gotten a lot of
publicity, 310.
Alright, comparative calibrations.
Using the Lord's name in vain,
not as an expletive,
but as a curse,
45.
One thing you really don't want to do,
if you've got a choice,
I don't want to even
say what it is.
The Ankh is a peculiar thing.
The Ankh, which you see many hanging around the necks
of all kinds of spiritually oriented people,
actually
is only 160.
It's been taken over by the occult.
It actually
generates an occult energy
of 160.
This terminology we ran,
used by a supposed
guru of
some regional
group,
that she gave you that.
Shakti energy is one thing.
Shaktipat is apparently a different term.
So sometimes what we're really getting
is the energy of the term.
When you've had enough, you raise your hands, okay?
Having just
lined up with them last week, what?
Turned over all my worldly
goods to them?
Okay, we've
gone to something else?
Okay, I know you're kidding me.
Anyway, the Druids come out at 450.
Theosophy,
365.
Freemasonry, 510.
Metaphysics, 420.
Intellectualism, 405.
Science of Mind, 405.
I Ching, 430.
Keys of Enoch, 265.
Fundamentalism,
200. Astrology,
210. Crystals. These came out a little higher
than I thought they would. Astrology, Crystals,
and Numerology all came out over 200.
Tai Chi, as the exercise,
is 310. Hatha Yoga,
260. Kung Fu,
410. Rebirthing,
250. Yakal
is Kamsi Kamsa.
It's above and below
200, depending. Biofeedback
is 202. Holographic
Breathing, 202.
Ear heart seminars training was
400. Anybody
here do Est? How many did Est? Yeah, a lot of
Esti people. Oh, that was a
fun deal, wasn't it? You can go all day
without going to the bathroom. What a great discovery.
Oh, you
can go all day without going to the
bathroom and you don't die and you don't lose control
and you say, oh my god, that's wonderful.
And you don't need your watch.
I mean, all kinds of liberations.
Alright. Shamanism, 210
to 230. Carlos Castaneda,
220.
Hatha Yoga, 330. Universalist
Church, 320. Ethical Culture,
350. Qigong is sort of
a question in my market. It says
240. Uden,
275. Sedona Releasing Method,
490. Soul Midwifery,
Huna and Falun Gong.
Alright, so we're trying
to cover, you know, a diverse,
diverse
subjects, diverse.
The
Japanese code of
Shinto at 200.
It means it could go above
or below. It's very
iffy. The White Brotherhood,
channeled through
Alice Bailey, right?
560.
Publisher of the Trumpet. I got them for free, so I
had to calibrate what they are.
Philadelphia
Church of God, publisher of the Trumpet,
415. The Zeth
Books by Jane Roberts, 470.
Rosicrucians, 405. Knights
Templar, 435.
Reiki, 285. Avatar
Workshops. Oh, that's
funny. There hasn't been any avatars in thousands of
years, but they got a workshop going, and a
bus that says Avatar Workshop.
So if you want to become an avatar, you do their
workshop. It's 245.
Bodywork, 205, and rolfing.
So, maintaining the body,
also sex. I think sexuality
calibrates at 200 or 205.
So physicality
itself is like
integrus, and
it's like 205. Sexuality
so you don't have to kill yourself
for having sex, because it is over 200,
thank goodness.
Scientology,
195. Atheism,
195. Branch Davidians.
Then there's all kinds of world mothers.
World Church
of the Creator. That's a white supremacist
church. They call it a church. See, that's why
I did it. Imagine calling yourself
something like the World Church
of the Creator,
and you come out at 85.
Should be
the World Church of the
opposite of the Creator. I don't know why.
Order of the Golden Dawn, of course, is
whose tarot cards did he do?
Alastair Crowley,
60.
The occult, the downside of the occult.
Alright. Now we'll get
to people that everyone is
interested in, and as I say, over the years
we've gotten a zillion questions
like this, and books.
Oh my God,
we spent weekends doing this,
and she'd say, I can't do any more
I can't do any more.
I'd say, just ten
more. And then
we'd stop for dinner, and in the middle of dinner I'd say,
but what about just
the one? I can't finish
my dinner until I know this one.
Alright.
Plotinus, one of the
greats of history, Plotinus.
730.
We said the White Brotherhood,
those ascended
spiritual masters,
whose names I have forgotten.
Yeah, right, and I remember
one of the books I really thought was very good
was Glamour. Anyway,
the White Brotherhood, who
are, to my understanding, within
the celestial realm.
They leave the body, and they are
already quite advanced.
We have permission to ask this.
The White Brotherhood is within
the celestial realm.
The higher heavens are the celestial.
Alright.
Then we got into
mystics and mysticism.
Sort of historically,
it was well known back in the 13th
century, Matilda
von Magdeburg, 13th century
mystic, 640.
Another German mystic, again, this one from
the 14th century, Johann Tauler,
640.
Huang Po was one of
my favorites, The Transmission of No Mind,
which is called The Transmission
of Mind, meaning The Transmission of No Mind.
Plus it's idiotic because there's nothing
you can transmit anyway, but anyway.
I know what he means.
960. Zen Master
is 700 and over.
Mahatma Gandhi stood off the British Empire,
as you remember I wrote in Power vs. Force.
The British Empire at the
time calibrated at 190,
arrogance.
They were notoriously arrogant,
and that's really why everybody got to hate them,
was their arrogance.
It wasn't the expertise of their rule
or anything else, it was just their attitude.
So this being
disrespectful of other cultural
cultures and other regimes, you can see
what a terrible consequence it has.
So Mahatma Gandhi,
who was well over 700,
then did nothing but stand there
up against the British Empire.
And weighing
less than 100 pounds, Mahatma Gandhi
defeated the entire British Empire
without firing a shot.
That's what you call power.
Power just stands there,
like this. It just stands there.
It changes everything
by virtue of that which it is.
So Gandhi stands there
on the high 700s,
and the British Empire
was brought to its knees.
So that demonstrates an interesting power
and force, because at the time
that that happened, the British Empire
was the most powerful empire the world
had ever seen. It ruled one quarter
of the world.
Okay, so that's
power. Mother Teresa also
had a transforming effect on the
consciousness of all of mankind.
And one of the
great masters of power
was the Nobel Prize for Peace
at 710.
Meister Eckhart had difficulty
with the Catholic Church,
and he did because he was a mystic.
Well, mystics throughout history
have had a bad time with
established religion,
and have been thought to be possessed
by demons and things,
and burned at the stake.
And there are still certain
denominations currently present
in our society who think that
it's really taken over by a demon.
All right, so
Meister Eckhart was a mystic,
and I think he got
either excommunicated or threatened
to be excommunicated.
Anyway, he was put on the
com-si-com-sa list,
and
they didn't know whether to hang him
or sanctify him, so
of course he was a teacher,
a doctor of divinity of the church,
and so therefore they treated him
with some deference.
Chief Detroit was quite advanced.
When you read Chief Detroit's
expositions, they are very advanced
spiritual comprehension,
and of course that has to do with
the formation of the Constitution
of the United States.
The energy of Chief Detroit
is very, very discernible
in the Constitution of the United States,
and the political structure
of the Native Americans there,
where they had a Congress,
and et cetera.
So the Constitution of the United States
is partly the result
of the Native Americans,
and that's why I honor them.
Karmapa, 630.
Makananda, who I got to meet,
he was great fun,
and he used to take these orange
knit caps off and throw them
into the audience,
and people wanted his energy
to run and get these orange
knit caps and pull them on.
Makananda was self,
the realization of the self.
Vivekananda, 610.
620.
One of the great mystics
in Hebrew tradition,
Rabbi Moses de Leon of Granada,
who was 14th century,
was at 720.
Nisargadatta and Ramana Maharshi
were at 720.
Ramesh Bolsikar,
who I spent seven days with,
came out, yes, he was at 760.
He was a translator
for Nisargadatta
for some 20 years,
and he himself became enlightened.
I got to spend some time with him
in 20 palms, or whatever it's called
in California.
Confucius at 590.
St. Patrick, 590.
Wallace Black Elk of Lakota, 499.
John Calvin, 580.
John Wesley, 360.
Martin Luther, 580.
The current Dalai Lama, 570.
Maharishi, Transcendental Meditation, 410.
Swami Ram Dass,
who died in 63, 570.
Robert Powell,
more a contemporary,
whose books are available
via Dove Press, 525.
Joel Golson at 455.
Poonjanand, HWL,
which I think is a cool name,
370.
And there's a lot of Rinpoches,
a lot of Rinpoches,
and this one's 499,
and Tibetan Buddhist.
Any questions about what we've covered so far?
These are the answers
we've gotten when we asked the question,
and the way we ask the question
is just the way we do
in the audience this morning.
You sort of intuit,
and the more you do this, the closer you get.
So when we were doing countries, for instance,
we began to suspect that there was
something wrong with our technique.
Because I'd say,
Banja Waja, and I'd say
it's over 460, 465.
We hit it within five points every time.
I'd say, how can that be?
Let's try Gunga Bongo,
and I'd say let's start at 210, 215.
We would almost know where to start,
because otherwise you're going to spend half an hour
summing up the whole scale of consciousness.
But you can intuit pretty much
almost where to start.
And the more you do it,
you get very, very close.
And if one of you doesn't get the question,
the other one will intuit it.
So it can become extremely fast
and extremely accurate once you get used to it.
Okay, now we have other
Tibetan Buddhists,
and
I think that was the next one,
the second one was the first guy
to scale Mount Everest.
Yes.
Wu, Wu Wei, 475.
Dayananda Swami, 460.
Charles Fillmore, 45.
The founder,
supposed founder of
Tibetan Buddhism,
which I don't actually believe the collaboration,
but because the history of
ancient teachings is muddled,
Padmasambhava,
founder,
and the term Babaji,
I know this is also bandied around.
There's all kinds of entities called Babaji.
So,
to find out what that really is,
you'd have to spend some time and some research.
Which Babaji are you talking about?
Currently alive,
of legend,
or what?
Ramchandra.
Swami Satchinananda,
who we all liked,
was 605.
He had such a great beard, you know.
Meher Baba, 240.
Sorry, Karuna Maya, 220.
Garchin Rinpoche, 385.
460.
The Old Testament prophets were not
what I would expect they would be.
202.
Tenzin Gyaltsen,
isn't that the guy that climbed the Himalayas?
That's the one.
I had the wrong Tenzin.
Tenzin Gyaltsen, correct,
is 599.
He was a very advanced entity, wasn't he?
And he climbed, he was the first.
All right.
Alice Bailey, 445.
She wasn't really a channel.
She's more,
channeling is one thing.
She's more an intermediary,
much like Helen
who did the Course in Miracles.
Helen didn't hear anybody
speaking to her.
It's not like she heard an entity there
She called it inner dictation.
It was like an inner knowingness
unfolded itself from within her mind,
sentence by sentence,
and she just typed it up as it came through.
Different than another entity,
you know,
like Master So-and-so on the other side
telling you to sell your sheep
and buy goats or something.
Peter Ouspensky, Robert Schuller,
the founder of
Buddhism, 510,
Mother Mira, 240.
There's another one of the Miras,
mothers, I mean.
Tibetan masters can
calibrate from over 200
to the 500s.
We wondered where in the middle of all this
and we got 220.
In other words,
nothing of superhuman evolution,
but more a talent.
He had a talent.
Martin Buber, 405.
St. Thomas Aquinas, 435.
Tertullian,
one of the greats of history,
385.
St. Bonaventure, 385.
Then we get to some current people.
Fitchinat Han, 460.
Tsongkhapa, 445.
This gives us a panorama
of what exists on the planet.
What kind of teachers are they?
How are they spread out
amongst the different religions?
What's their exposure to the populace?
What is their impact?
Because that somewhat defines
or limits their impact on society.
Now these are the ones
that people really pester me with.
The only reason I'm doing it
is so they stop pestering me.
Can you see?
Want to move over?
Can you see from here?
No, I'm fine.
Okay, we all knew that Yogananda
was in the 500s.
He was a saint, self-realized yoga,
and his famous book
is an autobiography
of a yoga.
Very famous and established
in California
and to this day has many followers
and supporters.
Lao Tzu, 520.
Alan Watts, who popularized
Zen
himself was 485.
John Blofield wrote
on Taoism, 465.
Silent Mind,
465.
Poonja Ajit
wrote a book called
Nothing Happened, 520.
We're just trying to get a feel
for the kind of writings
and what kind of an energy field
they're coming out of
which is always cultured by
ethnic, cultural, historic
and other factors
Bernadette Roberts,
445.
Buddha Nanda, Swami Buddha Nanda
who wrote the book
Mind and its Control, 485.
Gene Klein
is the more current Gene Klein.
Ease of Being, 510.
Chogyam Trungpa,
495. Ram Dass, 425.
And
Leadbeater, 485.
Brad Shaw, who wrote, of course,
all the famous books on recovery.
M. Scott Peck
both way up in the 400s.
Gangaji, I don't know who that is,
475. Joseph Smith,
510. He's certainly well known.
Emmet Fox, who is
extremely popular,
especially with people who've been through
12-step groups, I think he was one of
Bill Wilson's favorites.
Sermon on the Mount, 470.
Thomas Merton,
we used his book, New Seeds of
Contemplation,
to calibrate from.
We get 510.
Pat Kahn, who is going to be speaking,
I think, either here or,
we're going to be speaking, I'm going to be speaking with him
on the same platform, someplace.
Here, Europe, someplace.
It's 499.
The next author I'm not familiar with,
Arjuna Ardha.
That was one that was sent to me.
Amachiyama, there's another mother, 300.
Rudolf Steiner
is interesting because
it depends how you ask it
and at what age you ask it.
It could be 365, it could also be
475, and I think you remember
Theosophy was 475.
So, at his highest,
that would be his highest.
Robert Monroe, who wrote
that fascinating book, Journeys Out of the Body,
I found him
very interesting.
He had a voice that had a
peacefulness to it that was
amazing.
And, of course, he was
naive. Everybody knows
the story of Monroe. How many
don't know it? Oh, okay.
So, Monroe was an engineer
and suddenly at night he started
astral
projecting. He started going out of body
and having these
adventures, exploring these astral domains.
He'd never heard of it.
He didn't know how to explain it.
And he would wake up in his body
again. Sometimes he would have
amorous adventures, which he hoped his wife
did not notice.
Meet amorous entities
in other domains.
So, Monroe, and he also went to some lower
astral domains, where
he had some unpleasant experiences.
And Monroe, being a scientist
and an engineer by training,
kept a careful notebook.
So, he would come back in the body, he would
turn on his overhead light, and he
would make careful notes of what his
experience was, and the atmospheric conditions,
the barometric pressure, the time
of the month, etc.
Because he didn't know what it was.
So, he kept a careful study of the
phenomena, and he was quite an
astrojector. I mean, he did a lot of it.
And got to explore a lot of astral realms.
And Monroe
wrote this book.
What's charming about it
is it's his complete naivete
as this all begins to happen to him.
He wrote Journeys
Out of the Body. Monroe then
devised the system of an altered
state of consciousness.
He put on earphones, and there was a slight
difference in the frequency between the two
earphones. And the difference
in the frequency would send you
to different, older states of consciousness.
Which, that plus intentionality
and some self-hypnotic
techniques you could take off
out of the body at will.
And so that was exciting. It was like a ten day
training they did in Virginia.
You spend ten days laying on your back on a
mattress with earphones on it.
And those that were
trained in it could agree on where they
were going to meet. And they would all leave the body
at the same time and meet out there, and then come back
in the body. And
I said, this is all ridiculous, you know.
Until I went out of body, and then
I remember when I
tried to come back in the body, I was upside down.
I'm in the body, and I'm
looking out the back of my head at the floor.
And I realized I had to back out,
turn around 180, and go back in again.
Is that too strong?
No, I got turned back in correctly.
Yes, that was it.
There you are, you're out of the body. Of course,
it had happened to me spontaneously.
Also,
years before that, and so
I had some familiarity with it
spontaneously, but I thought
that would be interesting to study
how you could do it at will.
And it's true, you can explore many
domains.
And then Monroe had
in these earphones, he had
a little signal that you had to come back to the
body, because you could get lost in
adventures, and of course you're outside of time.
So, you know,
you get lost in various astral realms and all
kinds of adventures with other entities.
And so he had this whistle,
and he would blow that, and bang, you had to come back in the body.
It was like, you're trained to
like Bonzo returned to the dog
trainer, so you don't get lost
in the woods chasing rabbits.
So that was Monroe, who is now
deceased, but that's a great classic.
Just like
Kundalini energy is a great classic.
Each of those were sort of a classic.
Then we
have other people
of
Eastern origin,
and then we come back to
Father Pio, very well known,
and
who also has difficulties, I think,
with the church for some time.
And he also experienced
some very interesting
things, such as by
location, in which his spirit
could split and be in two places
at the same time.
Richard Buck was one of the most famous
authors of people who are studying
consciousness and enlightenment.
He was a physician who
became enlightened and went into
a state of cosmic consciousness
and wrote the classic.
It's a classic book called
Cosmic Consciousness.
Physicians were not exactly
the kind of people who
championed such concepts,
so he was rather courageous in that
as a practicing physician,
he explained his own
subjective experiences.
And Raymond Moody, who has written
much about near-death experiences
and death and dying.
Anthroposophy is 405.
Nathaniel Brandon is Psychology
and Self-Esteem.
That's really Ayn Rand's Objectivism,
isn't it? Objectivism by Ayn Rand
is in the
400s.
Alright, now we've got some
crooked people here.
We have the pathway
of inner light and sound.
315.
C.S. Lewis, 390.
Lightworkers. Ron Sedona,
a lot of people that are lightworkers.
As a group,
there are 215.
Sri Siva,
Sri Guruji, 220.
Sri Swami Master Ram.
So you see there's many
teachers with these exotic names.
And
the thing is not to be
misled by the ethnic novelty
and
the novelty of the name
or the title.
What's important is what they calibrate at.
It's better to have a
neighbor down the street teaching you
who's at 480
than a Swami something-rather who's at 220.
You understand? It just lacks
the glamour, but it's
fact.
Then there are various other things of great interest.
Siddha Yoga,
395. Joseph
Campbell, who's a well-known writer, of course.
410. And we've got Nostradamus
again. Then there's various things like
websites. People send me these things.
Because they're, again,
quite impressive looking.
You know, this fancy readout.
220.
And Ashram of Enlightenment.
Advaita,
Modism, Vedanta.
So a lot of these teachers, I just put them here
because people sent them to me.
The Mountain Order of Sri Shankar
something-rather, 305.
So people send me all these
things and therefore you'll have to punish
them. Don't punish me.
Hakuya,
Taizan, Maizumi for
a 505. These are some Zen teachers.
Zen teachers
and masters who write books about
Zen are very often
in 500s.
Bernie Glassman Roshi was
455 on Zen practice.
465. This is
White Plum Asanga is
a group, Zen
Kabbalah