Praise
and
his
his song.
Give
Give me
to
to meet
to meet everybody
to meet everybody this
to meet everybody this morning.
to meet everybody this morning. Hi.
>> Hello.
>> Hi
>> Hi again.
>> Everybody
>> Everybody in
>> Hi again.
>> Everybody in the
>> Everybody in the middle.
>> Good
>> Good morning.
Hey,
>> look
>> look at
>> look at the
>> look at the big
>> look at the big guy
>> look at the big guy back
>> look at the big guy back here.
>> The
>> The big
>> look at the big guy back here.
>> The big guy
>> The big guy is
>> look at the big guy back here.
>> The big guy is hiding
>> The big guy is hiding in
>> look at the big guy back here.
>> The big guy is hiding in the
>> The big guy is hiding in the back.
>> look at the big guy back here.
>> The big guy is hiding in the back. He
didn't
didn't want
didn't want to
didn't want to scare
didn't want to scare me
didn't want to scare me up
didn't want to scare me up front.
>> Big
>> Big people
didn't want to scare me up front.
>> Big people like
>> Big people like that
didn't want to scare me up front.
>> Big people like that scare
>> Big people like that scare me.
>> Hello
Hi.
>> Morning.
>> Morning. How
>> Morning. How are
>> Morning. How are you?
>> Oh,
hello.
hello. Hi.
Hi,
Hi, sweetheart.
>> Well,
I
I got
>> Well,
I got to
I got to keep
>> Well,
I got to keep moving.
I got to keep moving. It's
>> Well,
I got to keep moving. It's hard
I got to keep moving. It's hard to
>> Well,
I got to keep moving. It's hard to meet
everybody,
everybody, but
everybody, but we'll
everybody, but we'll meet
everybody, but we'll meet other
everybody, but we'll meet other people
afterwards.
Yeah.
Good
Good morning.
>> Good
>> Good morning.
>> Yes,
>> Yes, it
>> Good morning.
>> Yes, it is
>> Yes, it is indeed.
>> Good morning.
>> Yes, it is indeed. And
>> Yes, it is indeed. And uh
>> Good morning.
>> Yes, it is indeed. And uh I
>> Yes, it is indeed. And uh I know
>> Good morning.
>> Yes, it is indeed. And uh I know we're
in
in for
in for a
in for a good
in for a good time
in for a good time today.
in for a good time today. I
in for a good time today. I know
in for a good time today. I know it's
going
going to
in for a good time today. I know it's
going to be
going to be really
in for a good time today. I know it's
going to be really good
going to be really good cuz
in for a good time today. I know it's
going to be really good cuz I
going to be really good cuz I was
in for a good time today. I know it's
going to be really good cuz I was about
to
to greet
to greet doctor
to greet doctor and
to greet doctor and he
to greet doctor and he got
to greet doctor and he got out
to greet doctor and he got out of
to greet doctor and he got out of the
car
car saying
to greet doctor and he got out of the
car saying I'm
car saying I'm back
to greet doctor and he got out of the
car saying I'm back in
car saying I'm back in the
to greet doctor and he got out of the
car saying I'm back in the body.
>> So,
>> So, I
>> So, I don't
>> So, I don't know
>> So, I don't know what's
>> So, I don't know what's coming,
>> So, I don't know what's coming, but
>> we're
>> we're back
>> So, I don't know what's coming, but
>> we're back on
>> we're back on the
>> So, I don't know what's coming, but
>> we're back on the home
>> we're back on the home court.
I
I always
I always tell
I always tell the
I always tell the homep
I always tell the homep cuz
I always tell the homep cuz you
I always tell the homep cuz you all
I always tell the homep cuz you all keep
showing
showing up.
So,
So, it
So, it is
So, it is my
So, it is my pleasure
So, it is my pleasure this
So, it is my pleasure this morning
So, it is my pleasure this morning to
So, it is my pleasure this morning to uh
introduce
introduce again
So, it is my pleasure this morning to uh
introduce again my
introduce again my friend,
So, it is my pleasure this morning to uh
introduce again my friend, mentor
introduce again my friend, mentor and
gift
gift to
gift to the
gift to the world
gift to the world and
gift to the world and his
gift to the world and his right
gift to the world and his right arm
Susan,
Susan, Dr.
gift to the world and his right arm
Susan, Dr. David
Susan, Dr. David Hman.
Oh,
Oh, wow.
Okay.
Where
Where were
Where were we?
We
We have
Where were we?
We have to
we
we have
we have to
we have to provide
we have to provide a
we have to provide a contextualization
for
for the
we have to provide a contextualization
for the lectures.
Devotional
Devotional non-duality
Devotional non-duality means
Devotional non-duality means the
straight
straight way
Devotional non-duality means the
straight way to
straight way to God
Devotional non-duality means the
straight way to God bypassing
straight way to God bypassing the
Devotional non-duality means the
straight way to God bypassing the mind,
the
the intellect,
the intellect, the
the intellect, the ego.
>> We're
>> We're either
the intellect, the ego.
>> We're either not
>> We're either not on
the intellect, the ego.
>> We're either not on or
>> We're either not on or not
the intellect, the ego.
>> We're either not on or not on
>> We're either not on or not on go.
I've
I've got
I've got so
I've got so many
I've got so many wires
I've got so many wires on.
I've got so many wires on. I
I've got so many wires on. I don't
I've got so many wires on. I don't know
whether
whether I'm
going
going to
going to get
going to get electrocuted
going to get electrocuted or
going to get electrocuted or what
going to get electrocuted or what here.
>> Are
>> Are we
going to get electrocuted or what here.
>> Are we on?
>> Okay.
>> There
>> There we
>> Okay.
>> There we go.
>> First
>> First crisis
>> First crisis of
>> First crisis of the
>> First crisis of the day
>> First crisis of the day successfully
transcended.
transcended. Thank
>> First crisis of the day successfully
transcended. Thank the
transcended. Thank the Lord.
The
The only
The only way
The only way you
The only way you get
The only way you get by
The only way you get by in
The only way you get by in today's
electronic
electronic world,
The only way you get by in today's
electronic world, the
electronic world, the way
The only way you get by in today's
electronic world, the way I
electronic world, the way I get
The only way you get by in today's
electronic world, the way I get by
electronic world, the way I get by is
with
with the
with the help
with the help of
with the help of God.
with the help of God. I
with the help of God. I look
with the help of God. I look at
with the help of God. I look at all
with the help of God. I look at all this
equipment.
Well,
Well, we
Well, we recontextualize
Well, we recontextualize the
Well, we recontextualize the purpose
Well, we recontextualize the purpose of
all
all the
Well, we recontextualize the purpose of
all the lectures
all the lectures and
Well, we recontextualize the purpose of
all the lectures and the
all the lectures and the books
Well, we recontextualize the purpose of
all the lectures and the books and
um
what
what we're
um
what we're really
what we're really talking
um
what we're really talking about
what we're really talking about is
um
what we're really talking about is the
direct
direct way
direct way to
direct way to God
by
by bypassing
direct way to God
by bypassing the
by bypassing the mind,
direct way to God
by bypassing the mind, the
by bypassing the mind, the intellect,
all
all positionalities,
all of
all of our
all positionalities,
all of our dedications
all of our dedications to
all positionalities,
all of our dedications to the
all of our dedications to the ego
all positionalities,
all of our dedications to the ego and
all
all its
all its rewards.
You
You either
all its rewards.
You either serve
You either serve God
all its rewards.
You either serve God or
You either serve God or you
all its rewards.
You either serve God or you serve
You either serve God or you serve the
ego.
The
The way
ego.
The way to
The way to the
ego.
The way to the way
The way to the way to
ego.
The way to the way to God
The way to the way to God is
obscure.
People
People worship
obscure.
People worship all
People worship all kinds
obscure.
People worship all kinds of
People worship all kinds of things.
If
If the
If the way
If the way to
If the way to God
If the way to God were
If the way to God were easy,
If the way to God were easy, everybody
would
would be
If the way to God were easy, everybody
would be enlightened.
would be enlightened. So
If the way to God were easy, everybody
would be enlightened. So this
would be enlightened. So this is
If the way to God were easy, everybody
would be enlightened. So this is a
would be enlightened. So this is a world
dominated
dominated by
dominated by the
dominated by the ego.
dominated by the ego. To
dominated by the ego. To transcend
dominated by the ego. To transcend the
gravity
gravity of
dominated by the ego. To transcend the
gravity of the
gravity of the ego
dominated by the ego. To transcend the
gravity of the ego is
gravity of the ego is extraordinarily
difficult.
difficult. In
difficult. In fact,
difficult. In fact, without
difficult. In fact, without higher
truth,
truth, it's
difficult. In fact, without higher
truth, it's not
truth, it's not possible.
So,
So, one
So, one is
So, one is dedicated
So, one is dedicated to
So, one is dedicated to reaching
So, one is dedicated to reaching the
highest
highest truth
So, one is dedicated to reaching the
highest truth or
highest truth or one
So, one is dedicated to reaching the
highest truth or one genulelex
highest truth or one genulelex to
So, one is dedicated to reaching the
highest truth or one genulelex to the
ego
ego and
ego and that
ego and that decision
ego and that decision is
ego and that decision is what
makes
makes the
ego and that decision is what
makes the difference
in
in calibrated
in calibrated levels
in calibrated levels of
in calibrated levels of truth.
in calibrated levels of truth. So,
On
On the
in calibrated levels of truth. So,
On the calibrated
On the calibrated levels
in calibrated levels of truth. So,
On the calibrated levels of
consciousness,
consciousness, truth
consciousness, truth and
consciousness, truth and God
consciousness, truth and God and
divinity
divinity are
consciousness, truth and God and
divinity are at
divinity are at the
consciousness, truth and God and
divinity are at the top
divinity are at the top of
consciousness, truth and God and
divinity are at the top of the
divinity are at the top of the chart
consciousness, truth and God and
divinity are at the top of the chart and
the
the ego
the ego is
the ego is at
the ego is at the
the ego is at the bottom
the ego is at the bottom of
the ego is at the bottom of the
the ego is at the bottom of the chart.
The
The world
the
the world
the world has
the world has had
the world has had it
the world has had it backwards
the world has had it backwards for
the world has had it backwards for a
long
long time.
the world has had it backwards for a
long time. Still
long time. Still does.
So
So there's
So there's a
So there's a caveat
So there's a caveat before
So there's a caveat before we
So there's a caveat before we start.
So there's a caveat before we start. If
you're
you're not
So there's a caveat before we start. If
you're not dedicated
you're not dedicated to
So there's a caveat before we start. If
you're not dedicated to the
you're not dedicated to the truth,
you're
you're in
you're in the
you're in the wrong
you're in the wrong lecture.
If
If you
you're in the wrong lecture.
If you expect
If you expect me
you're in the wrong lecture.
If you expect me to
If you expect me to back
you're in the wrong lecture.
If you expect me to back up
If you expect me to back up your
favorite
favorite twisted
favorite twisted positionalities,
favorite twisted positionalities, you're
going
going to
favorite twisted positionalities, you're
going to be
going to be disappointed.
The
The way
The way to
The way to the
The way to the way
The way to the way to
The way to the way to the
The way to the way to the highest
The way to the way to the highest levels
of
of truth
The way to the way to the highest levels
of truth is
of truth is often
The way to the way to the highest levels
of truth is often painful,
of truth is often painful, in
The way to the way to the highest levels
of truth is often painful, in fact,
anguishing.
anguishing. I
anguishing. I went
anguishing. I went through
anguishing. I went through it.
anguishing. I went through it. So
there's
there's no
anguishing. I went through it. So
there's no point
there's no point in
anguishing. I went through it. So
there's no point in whimpering.
If
If I
If I did
If I did it,
If I did it, you
If I did it, you can
If I did it, you can do
If I did it, you can do it.
Nobody
Nobody was
If I did it, you can do it.
Nobody was more
Nobody was more dedicated
If I did it, you can do it.
Nobody was more dedicated to
Nobody was more dedicated to the
If I did it, you can do it.
Nobody was more dedicated to the ego
than
than I
than I was.
I
I was
than I was.
I was one
I was one of
than I was.
I was one of the
I was one of the world's
than I was.
I was one of the world's most
I was one of the world's most devout
than I was.
I was one of the world's most devout and
devout
devout atheists
devout atheists for
devout atheists for many
devout atheists for many years.
And
And uh
all
all right.
all right. So
all right. So sometimes
all right. So sometimes the
all right. So sometimes the way
all right. So sometimes the way the
truth
truth means
all right. So sometimes the way the
truth means going
truth means going through
disillusionment
disillusionment of
disillusionment of vested
disillusionment of vested interests
disillusionment of vested interests and
belief
belief systems
and
and one
and one has
and one has to
and one has to be
and one has to be willing
and one has to be willing to
and one has to be willing to sacrifice
everything
everything for
and one has to be willing to sacrifice
everything for the
everything for the truth.
and one has to be willing to sacrifice
everything for the truth. Parts
everything for the truth. Parts of
and one has to be willing to sacrifice
everything for the truth. Parts of your
body
body may
body may even
body may even disappear.
Strange
Strange things
body may even disappear.
Strange things may
Strange things may happen.
There's
There's another
There's another person
There's another person who
There's another person who sacrificed
the
the feast
There's another person who sacrificed
the feast of
the feast of his
There's another person who sacrificed
the feast of his body
the feast of his body and
There's another person who sacrificed
the feast of his body and we
the feast of his body and we four
There's another person who sacrificed
the feast of his body and we four of
the feast of his body and we four of us
got
got together
got together one
got together one time.
got together one time. Uh
got together one time. Uh some
got together one time. Uh some kind
got together one time. Uh some kind of
oath
oath we
got together one time. Uh some kind of
oath we took
oath we took in
got together one time. Uh some kind of
oath we took in some
oath we took in some lifetime.
got together one time. Uh some kind of
oath we took in some lifetime. Therefore
I
I recommend
I recommend people
I recommend people don't
I recommend people don't take
I recommend people don't take oaths
I recommend people don't take oaths you
know
or
or at least
or at least calibrate
or at least calibrate them
or at least calibrate them before
or at least calibrate them before you
take
take them.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So what
All right. So what we
All right. So what we stumbled
All right. So what we stumbled upon
All right. So what we stumbled upon the
condition
condition which
All right. So what we stumbled upon the
condition which prevailed
condition which prevailed which
All right. So what we stumbled upon the
condition which prevailed which came
upon
upon this
upon this entity
upon this entity standing
upon this entity standing before
upon this entity standing before you
was
catastrophic.
The
The degree
The degree of
The degree of catastrophe
The degree of catastrophe was
The degree of catastrophe was sort
The degree of catastrophe was sort of
like
like falling
The degree of catastrophe was sort of
like falling out
like falling out of
The degree of catastrophe was sort of
like falling out of a
like falling out of a 10-ft
The degree of catastrophe was sort of
like falling out of a 10-ft building.
And
And the
And the when
And the when you
And the when you hit
And the when you hit the
And the when you hit the ground,
And the when you hit the ground, it
And the when you hit the ground, it was
something
something of
And the when you hit the ground, it was
something of that
something of that equivalence.
That
That which
That which is
That which is the
That which is the absolute,
That which is the absolute, the
That which is the absolute, the certain,
the
the profound,
That which is the absolute, the certain,
the profound, the
the profound, the supreme
reveals
reveals itself
reveals itself in
reveals itself in a
reveals itself in a stunning
overwhelming
overwhelming shock
reveals itself in a stunning
overwhelming shock that
overwhelming shock that leaves
reveals itself in a stunning
overwhelming shock that leaves you
silent
silent for
silent for many
silent for many years.
The
The way
silent for many years.
The way to
The way to that
silent for many years.
The way to that state
The way to that state then
silent for many years.
The way to that state then is
The way to that state then is what
silent for many years.
The way to that state then is what we
have
have on
have on the
have on the board.
We
We had
have on the board.
We had on
We had on the
have on the board.
We had on the board.
It
It takes
It takes you
It takes you through
It takes you through the
It takes you through the various
It takes you through the various states
which
which we
It takes you through the various states
which we recapitulate.
How
How many
How many people
How many people here
How many people here have
How many people here have never
How many people here have never been
How many people here have never been to
a
a lecture
How many people here have never been to
a lecture here
a lecture here or
How many people here have never been to
a lecture here or a
a lecture here or a lecture
How many people here have never been to
a lecture here or a lecture any
a lecture here or a lecture any of
How many people here have never been to
a lecture here or a lecture any of my
lectures?
lectures? How
lectures? How many
lectures? How many people
lectures? How many people have
lectures? How many people have never
read
read power
lectures? How many people have never
read power versus
read power versus force?
lectures? How many people have never
read power versus force? Get
read power versus force? Get their
lectures? How many people have never
read power versus force? Get their names
and
and addresses
and addresses and
get
get their
and addresses and
get their fingerprints.
All right.
All right. So,
All right. So, we
All right.
All right. So, we won't
All right. So, we won't spend
All right.
All right. So, we won't spend too
All right. So, we won't spend too much
time
time recapitulating,
time recapitulating, but
time recapitulating, but every
time recapitulating, but every time
time recapitulating, but every time we
go
go over
time recapitulating, but every time we
go over it,
go over it, we
time recapitulating, but every time we
go over it, we see
go over it, we see something
time recapitulating, but every time we
go over it, we see something new.
The
The gravity
The gravity of
The gravity of the
The gravity of the ego
The gravity of the ego is
The gravity of the ego is severe
and
and we
The gravity of the ego is severe
and we see
and we see the
The gravity of the ego is severe
and we see the reason
and we see the reason for
The gravity of the ego is severe
and we see the reason for it.
and we see the reason for it. We
The gravity of the ego is severe
and we see the reason for it. We can
lessen
lessen its
lessen its hold
lessen its hold on
lessen its hold on us
lessen its hold on us by
lessen its hold on us by merely
understanding
understanding the
lessen its hold on us by merely
understanding the evolution
understanding the evolution of
lessen its hold on us by merely
understanding the evolution of the
understanding the evolution of the ego
and
and how
and how it
and how it arose.
And
And so
and how it arose.
And so we
And so we recapitulate
and how it arose.
And so we recapitulate now
And so we recapitulate now each
and how it arose.
And so we recapitulate now each lecture.
I
I found
I found it's
I found it's very
I found it's very useful
how
how to
I found it's very useful
how to contextualize
how to contextualize the
I found it's very useful
how to contextualize the ego
how to contextualize the ego so
I found it's very useful
how to contextualize the ego so as
how to contextualize the ego so as to
avoid
avoid getting
avoid getting polarized
avoid getting polarized about
avoid getting polarized about it.
avoid getting polarized about it. So
avoid getting polarized about it. So as
to
to avoid
avoid getting polarized about it. So as
to avoid get
to avoid get seeing
avoid getting polarized about it. So as
to avoid get seeing as
to avoid get seeing as good
avoid getting polarized about it. So as
to avoid get seeing as good good
to avoid get seeing as good good versus
evil,
evil, the
evil, the good
evil, the good versus
evil, the good versus the
evil, the good versus the bad.
evil, the good versus the bad. So
to
to transcend
evil, the good versus the bad. So
to transcend that's
to transcend that's a
evil, the good versus the bad. So
to transcend that's a very
to transcend that's a very difficult
duality
duality to
duality to transcend.
duality to transcend. See
duality to transcend. See because
duality to transcend. See because the
the
the mind
duality to transcend. See because the
the mind creates
the mind creates positionalities
duality to transcend. See because the
the mind creates positionalities and
the mind creates positionalities and now
you
you have
you have a
you have a duality
you have a duality to
you have a duality to transcend.
you have a duality to transcend. And
those
those traditionally
you have a duality to transcend. And
those traditionally are
those traditionally are the
you have a duality to transcend. And
those traditionally are the dragons
those traditionally are the dragons that
stand
stand in
stand in and
stand in and guard
stand in and guard the
stand in and guard the the
stand in and guard the the gates
stand in and guard the the gates of
truth.
truth. each
stand in and guard the the gates of
truth. each one
truth. each one of
stand in and guard the the gates of
truth. each one of them
truth. each one of them represents.
stand in and guard the the gates of
truth. each one of them represents. So
truth. each one of them represents. So I
tend
tend to
tend to teach
tend to teach things
tend to teach things backwards.
tend to teach things backwards. Now
tend to teach things backwards. Now I
start
start with
tend to teach things backwards. Now I
start with the
start with the end
tend to teach things backwards. Now I
start with the end and
start with the end and go
tend to teach things backwards. Now I
start with the end and go to
start with the end and go to the
tend to teach things backwards. Now I
start with the end and go to the front
and
and that
and that saves
and that saves a
and that saves a lot
and that saves a lot of
and that saves a lot of time.
So
So if
and that saves a lot of time.
So if we
So if we look
and that saves a lot of time.
So if we look at
So if we look at how
and that saves a lot of time.
So if we look at how the
So if we look at how the ego
and that saves a lot of time.
So if we look at how the ego trans
So if we look at how the ego trans began
then
then when
then when we
then when we get
then when we get to
then when we get to that
then when we get to that place
then when we get to that place of
surrendering
surrendering it
then when we get to that place of
surrendering it the
surrendering it the ego
then when we get to that place of
surrendering it the ego already
surrendering it the ego already has
then when we get to that place of
surrendering it the ego already has has
diminished
diminished in
diminished in stature.
diminished in stature. And
diminished in stature. And so
we
we see
diminished in stature. And so
we see that
all
all things
all things come
all things come into
all things come into manifestation
as
as a
all things come into manifestation
as a consequence
as a consequence of
potentiality
potentiality becoming
potentiality becoming actuality.
That
That action
potentiality becoming actuality.
That action then
That action then by
potentiality becoming actuality.
That action then by intention
That action then by intention the
potentiality
potentiality becomes
potentiality becomes an
potentiality becomes an actuality
because
because of
potentiality becomes an actuality
because of the
because of the power
potentiality becomes an actuality
because of the power of
because of the power of the
potentiality becomes an actuality
because of the power of the infinite
field.
field. The
field. The field
field. The field is
field. The field is so
field. The field is so powerful
field. The field is so powerful that
that
that which
field. The field is so powerful that
that which has
that which has potentiality
as
as life
as life then
as life then comes
as life then comes into
as life then comes into actuality.
Therefore,
Therefore, creation
as life then comes into actuality.
Therefore, creation and
Therefore, creation and evolution
as life then comes into actuality.
Therefore, creation and evolution are
one
one and
one and the
one and the same
one and the same thing.
Evolution
Evolution is
one and the same thing.
Evolution is nothing
Evolution is nothing but
one and the same thing.
Evolution is nothing but the
Evolution is nothing but the witnessing
of
of potentiality
of potentiality coming
of potentiality coming into
of potentiality coming into actuality.
And
And we
of potentiality coming into actuality.
And we call
And we call that
of potentiality coming into actuality.
And we call that creation
And we call that creation which
of potentiality coming into actuality.
And we call that creation which seems
And we call that creation which seems to
the
the mind
the mind to
the mind to the
the mind to the ego
the mind to the ego as
the mind to the ego as sequential.
The
The only
the mind to the ego as sequential.
The only sequence
The only sequence is
the mind to the ego as sequential.
The only sequence is one
The only sequence is one of
the mind to the ego as sequential.
The only sequence is one of observation.
There's
There's no
There's no sequence
There's no sequence in
There's no sequence in the
There's no sequence in the world
There's no sequence in the world as
There's no sequence in the world as it
is.
So
So out
So out of
So out of a
So out of a huge
So out of a huge galaxy,
So out of a huge galaxy, I
So out of a huge galaxy, I hope
So out of a huge galaxy, I hope this
So out of a huge galaxy, I hope this is
the
the right
So out of a huge galaxy, I hope this is
the right ear
the right ear I'm
So out of a huge galaxy, I hope this is
the right ear I'm poking
the right ear I'm poking in.
So out of a huge galaxy, I hope this is
the right ear I'm poking in. Yes,
the right ear I'm poking in. Yes, this
one
one has
one has a
one has a thing
one has a thing in
one has a thing in it.
Have
Have to
one has a thing in it.
Have to get
Have to get used
one has a thing in it.
Have to get used to
Have to get used to all
one has a thing in it.
Have to get used to all this
Have to get used to all this astronaut
equipment.
equipment. So
equipment. So the
equipment. So the um
equipment. So the um here's
equipment. So the um here's this
equipment. So the um here's this molten
ball.
ball. Energy
equipment. So the um here's this molten
ball. Energy E=
ball. Energy E= MC².
equipment. So the um here's this molten
ball. Energy E= MC². What
ball. Energy E= MC². What does
equipment. So the um here's this molten
ball. Energy E= MC². What does that
mean?
mean? In
mean? In just
mean? In just kindergarten
mean? In just kindergarten language,
energy
energy can
mean? In just kindergarten language,
energy can be
energy can be converted
mean? In just kindergarten language,
energy can be converted to
energy can be converted to mass.
mean? In just kindergarten language,
energy can be converted to mass. They
can
can energy
can energy and
can energy and mass
can energy and mass can
can energy and mass can convert
can energy and mass can convert back
can energy and mass can convert back and
forth
forth from
can energy and mass can convert back and
forth from one
forth from one to
can energy and mass can convert back and
forth from one to the
forth from one to the other.
can energy and mass can convert back and
forth from one to the other. That
forth from one to the other. That will
blow
blow the
blow the mind
blow the mind of
blow the mind of every
blow the mind of every physicist
blow the mind of every physicist in
blow the mind of every physicist in the
audience.
audience. But
blow the mind of every physicist in the
audience. But roughly
audience. But roughly that's
blow the mind of every physicist in the
audience. But roughly that's what
audience. But roughly that's what it
means.
You
You need
means.
You need time
You need time and
means.
You need time and various
You need time and various other
means.
You need time and various other things
in
in the
in the equation.
in the equation. But
in the equation. But as
in the equation. But as a
in the equation. But as a matter
in the equation. But as a matter of
experience,
experience, then
in the equation. But as a matter of
experience, then this
experience, then this molten
in the equation. But as a matter of
experience, then this molten glob
experience, then this molten glob of
lava
lava spins
lava spins off
lava spins off from
lava spins off from some
lava spins off from some galaxy,
spins
spins around
lava spins off from some galaxy,
spins around out
spins around out there
lava spins off from some galaxy,
spins around out there in
spins around out there in space
lava spins off from some galaxy,
spins around out there in space for
eons,
eons, billions
eons, billions and
eons, billions and billions,
eons, billions and billions, maybe
eons, billions and billions, maybe even
trillions
trillions of
eons, billions and billions, maybe even
trillions of years
trillions of years and
eons, billions and billions, maybe even
trillions of years and slowly
trillions of years and slowly cools
down.
down. And
down. And as
down. And as it
down. And as it cools
down. And as it cools down,
down. And as it cools down, its
down. And as it cools down, its surface
now
now becomes
down. And as it cools down, its surface
now becomes solidified.
The
The center
The center of
The center of this
The center of this world
The center of this world is
The center of this world is still
The center of this world is still molten
lava.
lava. Center
The center of this world is still molten
lava. Center of
lava. Center of this
The center of this world is still molten
lava. Center of this world
lava. Center of this world is
The center of this world is still molten
lava. Center of this world is still
molten
molten lava.
molten lava. So
molten lava. So we
molten lava. So we we
molten lava. So we we live
molten lava. So we we live on
molten lava. So we we live on this
cooled
cooled off
molten lava. So we we live on this
cooled off crust
cooled off crust then.
molten lava. So we we live on this
cooled off crust then. So
cooled off crust then. So as
molten lava. So we we live on this
cooled off crust then. So as this
cooled off crust then. So as this lava
cools
cools off
cools off it
cools off it forms
cools off it forms a
cools off it forms a crust
cools off it forms a crust that
cools off it forms a crust that you
cools off it forms a crust that you can
stand
stand on
that
that you
that you can
that you can walk
that you can walk on.
that you can walk on. And
that you can walk on. And in
that you can walk on. And in the
beginning
beginning then
that you can walk on. And in the
beginning then the
beginning then the radiance
that you can walk on. And in the
beginning then the radiance of
beginning then the radiance of the
that you can walk on. And in the
beginning then the radiance of the power
of
of the
of the infinite
of the infinite field
of the infinite field of
of the infinite field of consciousness
cell
cell itself
of the infinite field of consciousness
cell itself a
cell itself a quality
of the infinite field of consciousness
cell itself a quality of
cell itself a quality of divinity
of the infinite field of consciousness
cell itself a quality of divinity as
cell itself a quality of divinity as it
interacts
interacts with
interacts with matter
interacts with matter potentiates
interacts with matter potentiates the
emergence
emergence of
interacts with matter potentiates the
emergence of life.
emergence of life. So
interacts with matter potentiates the
emergence of life. So the
emergence of life. So the potentiality
for
for life
for life is
for life is universal
for life is universal throughout
all
all of
for life is universal throughout
all of creation
only
only awaiting
only awaiting proper
only awaiting proper conditions.
only awaiting proper conditions. H
only awaiting proper conditions. H I
never
never said
only awaiting proper conditions. H I
never said that
never said that before.
Um
Um that
Um that was
Um that was correct.
Um that was correct. Okay.
Um that was correct. Okay. So
Um that was correct. Okay. So does
Um that was correct. Okay. So does life
exist
exist on
Um that was correct. Okay. So does life
exist on other
exist on other planets?
Um that was correct. Okay. So does life
exist on other planets? Well,
exist on other planets? Well, if
Um that was correct. Okay. So does life
exist on other planets? Well, if the
potentiality
potentiality for
potentiality for life
potentiality for life is
potentiality for life is universal,
then
then it
potentiality for life is universal,
then it emerges
then it emerges as
potentiality for life is universal,
then it emerges as life
then it emerges as life wherever
conditions
conditions are
conditions are appropriate.
Hm.
Hm. So
conditions are appropriate.
Hm. So then
Hm. So then life
conditions are appropriate.
Hm. So then life emerged
Hm. So then life emerged first
conditions are appropriate.
Hm. So then life emerged first on
Hm. So then life emerged first on this
planet
in
in the
planet
in the most
in the most primitive
planet
in the most primitive form
and
and it
and it began
and it began as
the
the first
and it began as
the first conscious
the first conscious entity
and it began as
the first conscious entity was
the first conscious entity was a
bacteria
before
before we
bacteria
before we have
before we have a
bacteria
before we have a slide
before we have a slide on
bacteria
before we have a slide on that
before we have a slide on that later
bacteria
before we have a slide on that later but
we
we won't
we won't go
we won't go there
we won't go there yet.
The
The first
we won't go there yet.
The first matter,
The first matter, living
we won't go there yet.
The first matter, living matter
The first matter, living matter was
lychans
and
and uh
lychans
and uh viruses.
Viruses
Viruses reproduce
Viruses reproduce their
Viruses reproduce their DNA,
Viruses reproduce their DNA, but
Viruses reproduce their DNA, but they're
not
not conscious.
Don't
Don't ask
Don't ask me
Don't ask me why
Don't ask me why they're
Don't ask me why they're not
Don't ask me why they're not conscious.
I
I don't
Don't ask me why they're not conscious.
I don't know
I don't know why
Don't ask me why they're not conscious.
I don't know why they're
I don't know why they're not
Don't ask me why they're not conscious.
I don't know why they're not conscious.
A
A virus
A virus just
A virus just doesn't
A virus just doesn't know
A virus just doesn't know anything.
Bacteria
Bacteria somehow
A virus just doesn't know anything.
Bacteria somehow has
Bacteria somehow has the
A virus just doesn't know anything.
Bacteria somehow has the capacity
Bacteria somehow has the capacity to
experience.
Yeah.
Yeah. Is
experience.
Yeah. Is that
Yeah. Is that the
experience.
Yeah. Is that the differential?
Yeah. Is that the differential? Oh,
experience.
Yeah. Is that the differential? Oh, so
the
the virus
the virus does
the virus does not
the virus does not have
the virus does not have the
the virus does not have the capacity
the virus does not have the capacity for
experience.
experience. the
the virus does not have the capacity for
experience. the bacteria
experience. the bacteria literally
experiences.
Wow.
Wow. So,
experiences.
Wow. So, we
Wow. So, we discover
experiences.
Wow. So, we discover new
Wow. So, we discover new things
experiences.
Wow. So, we discover new things all
Wow. So, we discover new things all the
time.
I
I wondered
time.
I wondered why
I wondered why that
time.
I wondered why that was.
I wondered why that was. So,
time.
I wondered why that was. So, I
I wondered why that was. So, I guess
time.
I wondered why that was. So, I guess you
got
got to
got to be
got to be a
got to be a virus
got to be a virus for
got to be a virus for a
got to be a virus for a while.
got to be a virus for a while. You
got to be a virus for a while. You move
up
up to
got to be a virus for a while. You move
up to being
up to being a
got to be a virus for a while. You move
up to being a bacteria.
Anyway,
Anyway, when
Anyway, when you
Anyway, when you get
Anyway, when you get to
Anyway, when you get to be
Anyway, when you get to be a
Anyway, when you get to be a bacteria,
you
you get
Anyway, when you get to be a bacteria,
you get to
you get to be
Anyway, when you get to be a bacteria,
you get to be experiential.
you get to be experiential. Ah,
subjectivity
subjectivity emerges
subjectivity emerges along
subjectivity emerges along with
subjectivity emerges along with life.
Wow.
Concomatant.
Concomatant. With
Concomatant. With the
Concomatant. With the emergency
Concomatant. With the emergency of
Concomatant. With the emergency of life
emerges
emerges the
Concomatant. With the emergency of life
emerges the capacity
emerges the capacity for
Concomatant. With the emergency of life
emerges the capacity for subjectivity.
Wow.
For
For life
Wow.
For life to
For life to survive,
Wow.
For life to survive, it
For life to survive, it has
Wow.
For life to survive, it has to
For life to survive, it has to be
Wow.
For life to survive, it has to be able
to
to get
it
it doesn't
to get
it doesn't have
it doesn't have innate
to get
it doesn't have innate within
it doesn't have innate within itself
to get
it doesn't have innate within itself a
source
source of
source of energy.
It
It has
source of energy.
It has to
It has to get
source of energy.
It has to get it
It has to get it out
source of energy.
It has to get it out there
It has to get it out there somewhere.
The
The amoeba
The amoeba doesn't
The amoeba doesn't have
The amoeba doesn't have sufficient
energy
energy to
The amoeba doesn't have sufficient
energy to survive.
energy to survive. The
The amoeba doesn't have sufficient
energy to survive. The ambia
energy to survive. The ambia amieba
The amoeba doesn't have sufficient
energy to survive. The ambia amieba has
to
to go
to go out
to go out and
to go out and eat
to go out and eat a
to go out and eat a crumb
to go out and eat a crumb or
to go out and eat a crumb or whatever
amieba
amieba eat.
Graham
Graham cracker
Graham cracker crumb
Graham cracker crumb if
Graham cracker crumb if I
Graham cracker crumb if I was
Graham cracker crumb if I was an amoeba.
So
So you
Graham cracker crumb if I was an amoeba.
So you see
So you see that
Graham cracker crumb if I was an amoeba.
So you see that innate
So you see that innate quality
Graham cracker crumb if I was an amoeba.
So you see that innate quality to
So you see that innate quality to life.
First
First of
First of all
First of all it
First of all it has
First of all it has to
First of all it has to have
First of all it has to have appropriate
conditions.
That's
That's important
That's important to
That's important to understand
That's important to understand too
because
because everything
manifests
manifests as
manifests as a
manifests as a result
manifests as a result of
manifests as a result of of
manifests as a result of of conditions.
Propensity
Propensity becomes
manifests as a result of of conditions.
Propensity becomes actuality
Propensity becomes actuality but
manifests as a result of of conditions.
Propensity becomes actuality but only
when
when conditions
when conditions are
when conditions are appropriate.
Therefore
Therefore the
when conditions are appropriate.
Therefore the intrinsic
Therefore the intrinsic quality
when conditions are appropriate.
Therefore the intrinsic quality of
Therefore the intrinsic quality of life
then
then in
then in the
then in the first
then in the first beginning
then in the first beginning of
subjectivity
is
is getting
is getting gettingness.
Nothing
Nothing has
is getting gettingness.
Nothing has within
Nothing has within it
is getting gettingness.
Nothing has within it sufficient.
Nothing
Nothing is
Nothing is self-powered.
It's
It's got
Nothing is self-powered.
It's got to
It's got to get
Nothing is self-powered.
It's got to get it
It's got to get it from
Nothing is self-powered.
It's got to get it from somewhere.
So
So right
So right from
So right from the
So right from the beginning,
So right from the beginning, life
So right from the beginning, life at
least
least from
So right from the beginning, life at
least from a
least from a human
So right from the beginning, life at
least from a human viewpoint
is
is a
is a gettingness,
is a gettingness, a
is a gettingness, a wantingness,
is a gettingness, a wantingness, a
having
having to
is a gettingness, a wantingness, a
having to have
having to have this
is a gettingness, a wantingness, a
having to have this in
having to have this in order
is a gettingness, a wantingness, a
having to have this in order to
having to have this in order to survive.
And
And as
And as we
And as we come
And as we come on
And as we come on up
And as we come on up through
And as we come on up through evolution
then
then to
And as we come on up through evolution
then to the
then to the evolutionary
And as we come on up through evolution
then to the evolutionary series
then to the evolutionary series you
And as we come on up through evolution
then to the evolutionary series you see
increasing
increasing complexity
increasing complexity and
increasing complexity and expertise
increasing complexity and expertise in
getting
getting this
h
h to
h to survive.
h to survive. You
h to survive. You have
h to survive. You have to
h to survive. You have to be
h to survive. You have to be able
h to survive. You have to be able to
acquire
to
to get
and
and if
to get
and if you
and if you got
to get
and if you got to
and if you got to have
to get
and if you got to have the
and if you got to have the capacity
to get
and if you got to have the capacity to
get
get then
get then gettingness
get then gettingness becomes
get then gettingness becomes intrinsic
to
to the
get then gettingness becomes intrinsic
to the ego.
Plus,
Plus, you
Plus, you begin
Plus, you begin to
Plus, you begin to worry
Plus, you begin to worry that
Plus, you begin to worry that you
Plus, you begin to worry that you might
not
not have
Plus, you begin to worry that you might
not have enough.
not have enough. That's
Plus, you begin to worry that you might
not have enough. That's what
not have enough. That's what this
Plus, you begin to worry that you might
not have enough. That's what this when
you
you get
you get to
you get to the
you get to the level
you get to the level of
you get to the level of squirrel,
you get to the level of squirrel, the
squirrel
squirrel starts
you get to the level of squirrel, the
squirrel starts worrying
squirrel starts worrying there
you get to the level of squirrel, the
squirrel starts worrying there won't
squirrel starts worrying there won't be
enough
enough this
enough this winter.
enough this winter. So,
enough this winter. So, he
enough this winter. So, he starts
creating
creating wealth.
Wealth.
Wealth. The
Wealth. The squirrel
Wealth. The squirrel is
Wealth. The squirrel is the
Wealth. The squirrel is the first
capitalist.
capitalist. See,
the
the animal
the animal kingdom
the animal kingdom is
the animal kingdom is full
the animal kingdom is full of
capitalists
capitalists who
the animal kingdom is full of
capitalists who fill
capitalists who fill their
the animal kingdom is full of
capitalists who fill their burrows
capitalists who fill their burrows with
food
food for
food for the
food for the winter.
I
I once
food for the winter.
I once watched
I once watched a
food for the winter.
I once watched a squirrel
I once watched a squirrel do
food for the winter.
I once watched a squirrel do that.
I once watched a squirrel do that. In
fact,
fact, what
fact, what I'm
fact, what I'm talking
fact, what I'm talking about
fact, what I'm talking about this
morning
morning really
fact, what I'm talking about this
morning really came
morning really came from
fact, what I'm talking about this
morning really came from observing
animals.
animals. Uh,
animals. Uh, I
animals. Uh, I once
animals. Uh, I once had
animals. Uh, I once had a
animals. Uh, I once had a a
animals. Uh, I once had a a bunch
animals. Uh, I once had a a bunch of
nuts
nuts left
animals. Uh, I once had a a bunch of
nuts left over
nuts left over from
animals. Uh, I once had a a bunch of
nuts left over from Christmas.
nuts left over from Christmas. You
animals. Uh, I once had a a bunch of
nuts left over from Christmas. You know,
the
the kind
the kind that
the kind that you're
the kind that you're supposed
the kind that you're supposed to
the kind that you're supposed to crack,
but
but you
the kind that you're supposed to crack,
but you never
but you never do
by
by June
by June or
by June or July,
by June or July, the
by June or July, the dust
by June or July, the dust on
by June or July, the dust on them.
So,
So, I
by June or July, the dust on them.
So, I take
So, I take take
by June or July, the dust on them.
So, I take take the
So, I take take the bowl
by June or July, the dust on them.
So, I take take the bowl of
So, I take take the bowl of nuts
by June or July, the dust on them.
So, I take take the bowl of nuts and
So, I take take the bowl of nuts and I
put
put it
put it out
put it out on
put it out on in
put it out on in the
put it out on in the grass.
put it out on in the grass. And
put it out on in the grass. And I
put it out on in the grass. And I looked
out
out later
put it out on in the grass. And I looked
out later and
out later and a
put it out on in the grass. And I looked
out later and a squirrel
out later and a squirrel went
put it out on in the grass. And I looked
out later and a squirrel went cuckoo.
You
You never
You never saw
You never saw a
You never saw a squirrel
You never saw a squirrel just
You never saw a squirrel just freak
You never saw a squirrel just freak out.
ran
ran excitedly
You never saw a squirrel just freak out.
ran excitedly here,
ran excitedly here, there,
You never saw a squirrel just freak out.
ran excitedly here, there, the
ran excitedly here, there, the other
place.
place. His
place. His mouth
place. His mouth full
place. His mouth full of
place. His mouth full of nuts
place. His mouth full of nuts and
carrying
carrying more
place. His mouth full of nuts and
carrying more nuts
carrying more nuts and
place. His mouth full of nuts and
carrying more nuts and he's
carrying more nuts and he's digging
place. His mouth full of nuts and
carrying more nuts and he's digging and
he
he doesn't
he doesn't know.
he doesn't know. He
he doesn't know. He doesn't
he doesn't know. He doesn't know
he doesn't know. He doesn't know what
he doesn't know. He doesn't know what to
do
do with
he doesn't know. He doesn't know what to
do with all
do with all this.
It's
It's like
It's like people
It's like people win
It's like people win the
It's like people win the lottery.
They
They go
It's like people win the lottery.
They go from
They go from poverty
It's like people win the lottery.
They go from poverty to
They go from poverty to 50
It's like people win the lottery.
They go from poverty to 50 million.
They go from poverty to 50 million. What
do
do you
do you do
do you do with
do you do with it?
Well,
Well, we
do you do with it?
Well, we know
Well, we know what
do you do with it?
Well, we know what the
Well, we know what the statistics
do you do with it?
Well, we know what the statistics are
not
not too
not too good
not too good about
not too good about that.
not too good about that. Uh
not too good about that. Uh so
not too good about that. Uh so pray
not too good about that. Uh so pray that
nobody
nobody leaves
not too good about that. Uh so pray that
nobody leaves you
nobody leaves you any
not too good about that. Uh so pray that
nobody leaves you any 50
nobody leaves you any 50 million
unexpectedly
unexpectedly because
unexpectedly because most
unexpectedly because most of
unexpectedly because most of those
people
people go
unexpectedly because most of those
people go down
people go down quick
unexpectedly because most of those
people go down quick not
people go down quick not prepared
unexpectedly because most of those
people go down quick not prepared for
that
that takes
that takes lifetimes
that takes lifetimes of
that takes lifetimes of training
that takes lifetimes of training to
handle
handle it.
that takes lifetimes of training to
handle it. So
to
to handle
to handle all
to handle all those
to handle all those nuts
to handle all those nuts so
we
we see
to handle all those nuts so
we see the
we see the evolution
to handle all those nuts so
we see the evolution of
we see the evolution of consciousness
then
then its
then its innate
then its innate core
then its innate core is
then its innate core is wantingness
based
based on
then its innate core is wantingness
based on insufficiency.
It
It does
It does not
It does not have
It does not have within
It does not have within itself
uh
uh the
It does not have within itself
uh the capacity
uh the capacity to
It does not have within itself
uh the capacity to feed
uh the capacity to feed itself.
It does not have within itself
uh the capacity to feed itself. It
uh the capacity to feed itself. It has
to
to get
to get food
to get food out
to get food out there.
to get food out there. So
to get food out there. So that's
to get food out there. So that's what
to get food out there. So that's what we
see
see in
to get food out there. So that's what we
see in the
see in the evolution
to get food out there. So that's what we
see in the evolution of
see in the evolution of consciousness
then
then is
then is the
then is the innate
then is the innate core
then is the innate core of
then is the innate core of the
then is the innate core of the ego
then is the innate core of the ego is
that
that the
then is the innate core of the ego is
that the first
that the first quality
then is the innate core of the ego is
that the first quality of
that the first quality of life
then is the innate core of the ego is
that the first quality of life we
that the first quality of life we can
get
get is
get is that
get is that it
get is that it needs
it
it needs.
Today
Today we're
Today we're going
Today we're going to
Today we're going to talk
Today we're going to talk about
Today we're going to talk about how
Today we're going to talk about how to
transcend
transcend feelings
Today we're going to talk about how to
transcend feelings and
transcend feelings and emotions.
All
All the
All the feelings
All the feelings and
All the feelings and emotions,
All the feelings and emotions, they
All the feelings and emotions, they keep
disappearing
disappearing magically.
All the feelings and emotions, they keep
disappearing magically. I
disappearing magically. I don't
All the feelings and emotions, they keep
disappearing magically. I don't know.
We're
We're can
We're can leave
We're can leave that
We're can leave that on
We're can leave that on there.
We're can leave that on there. It's
okay.
okay. They're
We're can leave that on there. It's
okay. They're not
okay. They're not charging
We're can leave that on there. It's
okay. They're not charging us
okay. They're not charging us by
We're can leave that on there. It's
okay. They're not charging us by the
Oreo.
Oreo. Okay.
Oreo. Okay. So,
feeling
feeling list
Oreo. Okay. So,
feeling list and
feeling list and emotions.
All
All all
All all of
All all of all
All all of all of
All all of all of what
All all of all of what you
All all of all of what you see
All all of all of what you see here
All all of all of what you see here is
based
based on
All all of all of what you see here is
based on this
based on this basic
All all of all of what you see here is
based on this basic premise
based on this basic premise that
All all of all of what you see here is
based on this basic premise that I
based on this basic premise that I must
have
have in
have in order
have in order to
have in order to survive.
Then
Then when
have in order to survive.
Then when you
Then when you add
have in order to survive.
Then when you add the
Then when you add the prefrontal
have in order to survive.
Then when you add the prefrontal cortex
to
to the
to the animal
to the animal to
to the animal to the
to the animal to the animal
to the animal to the animal now
to the animal to the animal now he
elaborates
elaborates what
to the animal to the animal now he
elaborates what I
elaborates what I must
to the animal to the animal now he
elaborates what I must have
elaborates what I must have not
to the animal to the animal now he
elaborates what I must have not just
nuts
nuts and
uh
uh refrigerator
nuts and
uh refrigerator full
uh refrigerator full uh
nuts and
uh refrigerator full uh now
uh refrigerator full uh now he
elaborates
elaborates intellectually
elaborates intellectually I
elaborates intellectually I must
elaborates intellectually I must have
approval
approval I
elaborates intellectually I must have
approval I must
approval I must have
elaborates intellectually I must have
approval I must have status
approval I must have status I
elaborates intellectually I must have
approval I must have status I must
approval I must have status I must have
the
the right
the right labels
the right labels I
the right labels I must
the right labels I must be
the right labels I must be correct
I
I must
the right labels I must be correct
I must be
I must be a
the right labels I must be correct
I must be a member
I must be a member of
the right labels I must be correct
I must be a member of some
I must be a member of some exclusive
body
body I
body I must
body I must have
body I must have a
body I must have a title
All
All right.
body I must have a title
All right. So
All right. So the
body I must have a title
All right. So the the
All right. So the the wanting
body I must have a title
All right. So the the wanting of
All right. So the the wanting of appro
then
then we
then we get
then we get into
then we get into wantingness
then we get into wantingness from
then we get into wantingness from other
human
human beings.
You
You see
You see the
You see the infant
You see the infant squalling
You see the infant squalling there
You see the infant squalling there is
squalling
squalling with
You see the infant squalling there is
squalling with wantingness.
squalling with wantingness. It
You see the infant squalling there is
squalling with wantingness. It wants
squalling with wantingness. It wants to
be
be cuddled
be cuddled held
be cuddled held coo
be cuddled held coo to
be cuddled held coo to fed
be cuddled held coo to fed water
diaper
diaper rediapered
be cuddled held coo to fed water
diaper rediapered whatever
the
the crybaby
the crybaby never
the crybaby never goes
the crybaby never goes away
the crybaby never goes away in
the crybaby never goes away in most
people.
It
It gets
It gets elaborated.
It gets elaborated. The
It gets elaborated. The evening
It gets elaborated. The evening news
It gets elaborated. The evening news is
full
full of
It gets elaborated. The evening news is
full of cryb
full of cryb babies.
It gets elaborated. The evening news is
full of cryb babies. You
full of cryb babies. You know,
It gets elaborated. The evening news is
full of cryb babies. You know, who
should
should we
should we blame
should we blame for
should we blame for this
should we blame for this and
should we blame for this and who
should we blame for this and who should
we
we blame
should we blame for this and who should
we blame for
we blame for that?
should we blame for this and who should
we blame for that? Yeah.
we blame for that? Yeah. Blame
should we blame for this and who should
we blame for that? Yeah. Blame life.
Blame
Blame your
Blame your mom
Blame your mom and
Blame your mom and dad.
That's
That's why
Blame your mom and dad.
That's why you're
That's why you're here
Blame your mom and dad.
That's why you're here to
That's why you're here to complain.
Yeah.
Yeah. So,
Yeah. So, everybody
feel
feel the
Yeah. So, everybody
feel the same.
The
The first
The first thing
The first thing you
The first thing you must
The first thing you must do
The first thing you must do is
The first thing you must do is complain
and
and demand.
The first thing you must do is complain
and demand. And
and demand. And uh
so
so you
so you see
so you see a
so you see a projection
so you see a projection of
so you see a projection of the
so you see a projection of the infantile
ego
ego then
so you see a projection of the infantile
ego then onto
ego then onto the
so you see a projection of the infantile
ego then onto the world
ego then onto the world and
so you see a projection of the infantile
ego then onto the world and almost
ego then onto the world and almost all
the
the viferous
talkingness
talkingness that
the viferous
talkingness that goes
talkingness that goes on
the viferous
talkingness that goes on on
talkingness that goes on on television
every
every night.
every night. If
every night. If you
every night. If you see
every night. If you see it
every night. If you see it that
every night. If you see it that way,
you'll
you'll realize
every night. If you see it that way,
you'll realize that
you'll realize that those
every night. If you see it that way,
you'll realize that those are
you'll realize that those are all
infants
infants crying
infants crying and
infants crying and talking.
infants crying and talking. It's
amazing.
They
They were
They were angry
They were angry about
They were angry about this
They were angry about this and
They were angry about this and they
protest
protest about
They were angry about this and they
protest about that
protest about that and
They were angry about this and they
protest about that and they're
protest about that and they're critical
of
of this
of this and
anyway
anyway if
of this and
anyway if you
anyway if you calibrate
of this and
anyway if you calibrate it
anyway if you calibrate it all
of this and
anyway if you calibrate it all it's
anyway if you calibrate it all it's a
joke
joke you
joke you know
joke you know see
turn
turn down
joke you know see
turn down the
turn down the TV
joke you know see
turn down the TV and
turn down the TV and say
joke you know see
turn down the TV and say this
turn down the TV and say this speaker
calibrates
calibrates it.
calibrates it. Uh
calibrates it. Uh oh.
calibrates it. Uh oh. Yeah.
calibrates it. Uh oh. Yeah. Okay.
calibrates it. Uh oh. Yeah. Okay. Senior
senator
senator from
calibrates it. Uh oh. Yeah. Okay. Senior
senator from some
senator from some place.
calibrates it. Uh oh. Yeah. Okay. Senior
senator from some place. All
senator from some place. All right.
calibrates it. Uh oh. Yeah. Okay. Senior
senator from some place. All right. So
if
if we
if we can't
if we can't get
if we can't get what
if we can't get what we
if we can't get what we want
if we can't get what we want then
if we can't get what we want then all
these
these negative
if we can't get what we want then all
these negative feelings
these negative feelings come
if we can't get what we want then all
these negative feelings come up.
We're
We're miserable.
We're miserable. We're
We're miserable. We're desparing.
We're miserable. We're desparing. We're
going
going to
We're miserable. We're desparing. We're
going to commit
going to commit suicide.
When
When that's
When that's given
When that's given up,
When that's given up, on
When that's given up, on the
When that's given up, on the other
When that's given up, on the other hand,
we
we reach
When that's given up, on the other hand,
we reach hopeless
we reach hopeless hopelessness.
And
And when
And when we
And when we reach
And when we reach absolute
And when we reach absolute hopelessness,
then
then we're
And when we reach absolute hopelessness,
then we're at
then we're at the
And when we reach absolute hopelessness,
then we're at the bottom
then we're at the bottom of
And when we reach absolute hopelessness,
then we're at the bottom of the
then we're at the bottom of the bo
barrel.
barrel. We're
barrel. We're at
barrel. We're at apathy
barrel. We're at apathy and
barrel. We're at apathy and we
barrel. We're at apathy and we expire.
All
All right?
barrel. We're at apathy and we expire.
All right? So
All right? So for
barrel. We're at apathy and we expire.
All right? So for physical
All right? So for physical survival
barrel. We're at apathy and we expire.
All right? So for physical survival then
the
the ego
the ego serves
the ego serves a
the ego serves a useful
the ego serves a useful function.
Yeah.
Yeah. If
the ego serves a useful function.
Yeah. If we
Yeah. If we don't
the ego serves a useful function.
Yeah. If we don't get
Yeah. If we don't get the
the ego serves a useful function.
Yeah. If we don't get the approval
Yeah. If we don't get the approval we
want
want from
want from people
want from people then
want from people then we
want from people then we have
want from people then we have shame.
Where's
Where's my
want from people then we have shame.
Where's my spotter
Where's my spotter thing?
>> Oh
>> Oh wow.
I
I don't know.
>> Oh wow.
I don't know. It
I don't know. It works
>> Oh wow.
I don't know. It works somehow.
I
I don't
I don't tr
I don't tr I
I don't tr I don't
I don't tr I don't trust
I don't tr I don't trust this
I don't tr I don't trust this thing.
I don't tr I don't trust this thing. I
don't
don't know.
I don't tr I don't trust this thing. I
don't know. It
don't know. It just
I don't tr I don't trust this thing. I
don't know. It just doesn't
don't know. It just doesn't work.
Is
Is it
Is it working?
>> Turn
>> Turn it
Is it working?
>> Turn it around.
>> Well,
>> Well, it's
>> Well, it's too
>> Well, it's too it's
>> Well, it's too it's too
>> Well, it's too it's too something
>> Well, it's too it's too something or
other.
other. Well,
>> Well, it's too it's too something or
other. Well, we'll
other. Well, we'll just
>> Well, it's too it's too something or
other. Well, we'll just use
other. Well, we'll just use our
>> Well, it's too it's too something or
other. Well, we'll just use our fingers.
Our
Our fingers
Our fingers are
Our fingers are good
Our fingers are good enough.
If
If you
Our fingers are good enough.
If you don't
If you don't get
Our fingers are good enough.
If you don't get the
If you don't get the approval
Our fingers are good enough.
If you don't get the approval you
If you don't get the approval you want,
you
you don't
you don't get
you don't get society's
you don't get society's approval,
you don't get society's approval, you
end
end up
you don't get society's approval, you
end up here
end up here with
you don't get society's approval, you
end up here with shame.
Below
Below that,
Below that, you
Below that, you have
Below that, you have apathy
Below that, you have apathy and
hopelessness.
hopelessness. No
Below that, you have apathy and
hopelessness. No hope
hopelessness. No hope now
Below that, you have apathy and
hopelessness. No hope now and
hopelessness. No hope now and no
Below that, you have apathy and
hopelessness. No hope now and no hope
ever
in
in the
ever
in the depths
in the depths of
ever
in the depths of hell.
in the depths of hell. That
ever
in the depths of hell. That is
in the depths of hell. That is the
message.
Not
Not upper
message.
Not upper hell,
Not upper hell, which
message.
Not upper hell, which is
Not upper hell, which is torture
message.
Not upper hell, which is torture and
being
being chopped
being chopped up
being chopped up in
being chopped up in screams
being chopped up in screams of
being chopped up in screams of agony.
That's
That's that's
being chopped up in screams of agony.
That's that's just
That's that's just Jack's
being chopped up in screams of agony.
That's that's just Jack's ropers.
But
But the
But the bottom
But the bottom of
But the bottom of hell
is
is hopelessness
forever.
Hopelessness
Hopelessness forever.
It
It is
It is so
It is so ghastly
It is so ghastly that
It is so ghastly that I
It is so ghastly that I cannot
It is so ghastly that I cannot describe
it
it to
It is so ghastly that I cannot describe
it to you.
Ever
Ever since
Ever since then,
Ever since then, I've
Ever since then, I've recommended
Ever since then, I've recommended you
don't
don't go
Ever since then, I've recommended you
don't go in
don't go in that
Ever since then, I've recommended you
don't go in that direction.
It
It is
It is far
It is far worse
It is far worse than
It is far worse than any
It is far worse than any description
I've
I've ever
It is far worse than any description
I've ever read
I've ever read of
It is far worse than any description
I've ever read of it.
Anyway,
Anyway, hopelessness.
Anyway, hopelessness. So,
Anyway, hopelessness. So, that
Anyway, hopelessness. So, that was
Anyway, hopelessness. So, that was the
fixity
fixity of
Anyway, hopelessness. So, that was the
fixity of finding
fixity of finding truth
Anyway, hopelessness. So, that was the
fixity of finding truth no matter
fixity of finding truth no matter where
it
it took
it took me.
it took me. And
it took me. And it
it took me. And it took
it took me. And it took me
it took me. And it took me there.
Hopeless.
And
And it
And it was
And it was a
And it was a forever
And it was a forever condition.
And it was a forever condition. the
spiritual
spiritual agony
And it was a forever condition. the
spiritual agony was
spiritual agony was forever
and
and that
and that it
and that it was
and that it was hell.
and that it was hell. So
as
as at
and that it was hell. So
as at about
as at about 20
and that it was hell. So
as at about 20 we
as at about 20 we merely
and that it was hell. So
as at about 20 we merely have
as at about 20 we merely have shame
and that it was hell. So
as at about 20 we merely have shame and
people
people become
people become ejected
people become ejected from
people become ejected from their
society,
society, banished
people become ejected from their
society, banished out
society, banished out of
people become ejected from their
society, banished out of humiliation
and
and you're
and you're really
and you're really being
and you're really being the
and you're really being the process
and you're really being the process is
you're
you're really
and you're really being the process is
you're really being
you're really being eliminated.
Now
Now we
Now we come
Now we come to
Now we come to the
Now we come to the next
guilt.
What
What is
What is guilt?
What is guilt? It's
What is guilt? It's a
What is guilt? It's a denial
What is guilt? It's a denial of
What is guilt? It's a denial of what
What is guilt? It's a denial of what the
ego
ego is
What is guilt? It's a denial of what the
ego is craving.
ego is craving. So
What is guilt? It's a denial of what the
ego is craving. So you
ego is craving. So you see
What is guilt? It's a denial of what the
ego is craving. So you see all
ego is craving. So you see all these
responses
responses are
responses are responses
responses are responses of
responses are responses of the
responses are responses of the ego
of
of its
responses are responses of the ego
of its wantingness.
It
It wants
It wants prestige.
It wants prestige. You
It wants prestige. You want
It wants prestige. You want status.
It wants prestige. You want status. So
these
these are
It wants prestige. You want status. So
these are all
these are all reactions.
It wants prestige. You want status. So
these are all reactions. The
these are all reactions. The fear
It wants prestige. You want status. So
these are all reactions. The fear is
fear
fear that
fear that I
fear that I won't
fear that I won't physically
fear that I won't physically survive.
Fear
Fear that
fear that I won't physically survive.
Fear that I
Fear that I won't
fear that I won't physically survive.
Fear that I won't reach
Fear that I won't reach my
fear that I won't physically survive.
Fear that I won't reach my goal.
Fear that I won't reach my goal. Fear.
So
So it's
So it's a
So it's a fear
So it's a fear of
So it's a fear of what?
So it's a fear of what? It's
So it's a fear of what? It's a
So it's a fear of what? It's a fear
So it's a fear of what? It's a fear of
not
not achieving
So it's a fear of what? It's a fear of
not achieving a
not achieving a wantingness.
So
So right
So right back
So right back to
So right back to the
So right back to the bacteria
So right back to the bacteria who
So right back to the bacteria who So
So right back to the bacteria who So all
of
of us
So right back to the bacteria who So all
of us in
of us in inside
So right back to the bacteria who So all
of us in inside are
of us in inside are just
So right back to the bacteria who So all
of us in inside are just bacteria
wanting.
wanting. We're
wanting. We're just
wanting. We're just amiebas
wanting. We're just amiebas wanting
something.
something. We're
wanting. We're just amiebas wanting
something. We're terrified
something. We're terrified we
wanting. We're just amiebas wanting
something. We're terrified we won't
something. We're terrified we won't get
it.
it. You
it. You know,
it. You know, we
it. You know, we won't
it. You know, we won't have
it. You know, we won't have enough.
it. You know, we won't have enough. So
you
you get
it. You know, we won't have enough. So
you get greed.
The
The greedy
The greedy person
The greedy person is
The greedy person is never
The greedy person is never has
The greedy person is never has enough.
Never
Never has
The greedy person is never has enough.
Never has enough.
Never has enough. You
The greedy person is never has enough.
Never has enough. You know,
Never has enough. You know, sometimes
you
you marvel
you marvel how
you marvel how how
you marvel how how some
you marvel how how some tycoon
you marvel how how some tycoon who's
worth
worth 200
you marvel how how some tycoon who's
worth 200 billion,
worth 200 billion, you
you marvel how how some tycoon who's
worth 200 billion, you know,
worth 200 billion, you know, risks
you marvel how how some tycoon who's
worth 200 billion, you know, risks it
all
all out
all out of
all out of greed
all out of greed for
all out of greed for another
all out of greed for another 20
all out of greed for another 20 billion.
You
You see,
there's
there's nuts
there's nuts buried
there's nuts buried everywhere,
but
but they
there's nuts buried everywhere,
but they want
but they want more
there's nuts buried everywhere,
but they want more nuts.
but they want more nuts. You
there's nuts buried everywhere,
but they want more nuts. You know
but they want more nuts. You know what
there's nuts buried everywhere,
but they want more nuts. You know what I
mean?
Oh,
Oh, God.
mean?
Oh, God. So
you
you see
you see what
you see what happens
you see what happens is
you see what happens is then
you see what happens is then is
you see what happens is then is the
human
human becomes
you see what happens is then is the
human becomes the
human becomes the victim
you see what happens is then is the
human becomes the victim of
human becomes the victim of the
you see what happens is then is the
human becomes the victim of the ego.
human becomes the victim of the ego. The
human
human population
human population represents
a
a population
human population represents
a population is
a population is victimized
human population represents
a population is victimized by
a population is victimized by the
human population represents
a population is victimized by the ego
and
and we
and we came
and we came on
and we came on earth
and we came on earth to
and we came on earth to transcend
and we came on earth to transcend that
to
to transcend.
and we came on earth to transcend that
to transcend. The
to transcend. The purpose
and we came on earth to transcend that
to transcend. The purpose of
to transcend. The purpose of human
and we came on earth to transcend that
to transcend. The purpose of human life
is
is to
is to transcend
is to transcend the
is to transcend the ego
is to transcend the ego under
is to transcend the ego under the
is to transcend the ego under the best
appropriate
appropriate conditions.
To
To be
To be born
To be born in
To be born in this
To be born in this world
To be born in this world is
To be born in this world is a
To be born in this world is a great
To be born in this world is a great gift
because
because here
we
we have
we have the
we have the maximal
we have the maximal opportunity
we have the maximal opportunity to
transcend
transcend the
we have the maximal opportunity to
transcend the ego.
We
We see
We see in
We see in this
We see in this world
We see in this world the
We see in this world the thing
We see in this world the thing humans
that
that calibrate
We see in this world the thing humans
that calibrate at
that calibrate at 30.
We see in this world the thing humans
that calibrate at 30. Yeah.
that calibrate at 30. Yeah. See
We see in this world the thing humans
that calibrate at 30. Yeah. See lots
that calibrate at 30. Yeah. See lots of
humans
humans here
humans here who
humans here who calibrate
humans here who calibrate at
humans here who calibrate at 30.
humans here who calibrate at 30. They
establish
establish religions.
humans here who calibrate at 30. They
establish religions. Even
the
the religion
the religion of
the religion of the
the religion of the 30s
the religion of the 30s had
the religion of the 30s had uh
the religion of the 30s had uh based
the religion of the 30s had uh based on
hate
hate and
the religion of the 30s had uh based on
hate and killing.
hate and killing. Hate
the religion of the 30s had uh based on
hate and killing. Hate and
hate and killing. Hate and killing.
the religion of the 30s had uh based on
hate and killing. Hate and killing. So
uh
uh there
uh there are
uh there are religions
uh there are religions of
uh there are religions of hate
uh there are religions of hate and
killing
killing and
uh there are religions of hate and
killing and they
killing and they are
uh there are religions of hate and
killing and they are world
killing and they are world famous.
uh there are religions of hate and
killing and they are world famous. Mhm.
Along
Along with
Along with that
Along with that goes
Along with that goes blame.
Along with that goes blame. You
Along with that goes blame. You see
Along with that goes blame. You see so
you
you can
Along with that goes blame. You see so
you can see
you can see that
Along with that goes blame. You see so
you can see that blame
you can see that blame is
Along with that goes blame. You see so
you can see that blame is really
you can see that blame is really not
Along with that goes blame. You see so
you can see that blame is really not a
praiseworthy
uh
uh goal.
to
to try
to try to
to try to ascertain
to try to ascertain who's
to try to ascertain who's to
to try to ascertain who's to blame
takes
takes you
to try to ascertain who's to blame
takes you right
takes you right down
to try to ascertain who's to blame
takes you right down to
takes you right down to the
to try to ascertain who's to blame
takes you right down to the bottom
takes you right down to the bottom of
the
the pit.
the pit. Why?
the pit. Why? Because
the pit. Why? Because it's
the pit. Why? Because it's going
the pit. Why? Because it's going to
bring
bring up
the pit. Why? Because it's going to
bring up hatred.
Vindictiveness.
Vindictiveness. So
Vindictiveness. So you
Vindictiveness. So you see
Vindictiveness. So you see the
politicians
politicians who
Vindictiveness. So you see the
politicians who get
politicians who get out
Vindictiveness. So you see the
politicians who get out there
politicians who get out there and
Vindictiveness. So you see the
politicians who get out there and shake
their
their fist
their fist with
their fist with hatred
their fist with hatred and
their fist with hatred and denounce
somebody.
somebody. That's
their fist with hatred and denounce
somebody. That's called
somebody. That's called being
vindictive.
vindictive. Vindictive.
So
the
the lessons
the lessons on
the lessons on the
the lessons on the ego
the lessons on the ego are
the lessons on the ego are every
the lessons on the ego are every night
on
on television.
the lessons on the ego are every night
on television. You
on television. You watch
the lessons on the ego are every night
on television. You watch it,
on television. You watch it, you
calibrate
calibrate what
calibrate what it
calibrate what it is,
calibrate what it is, you
calibrate what it is, you look
calibrate what it is, you look at
calibrate what it is, you look at the
chart
chart and
calibrate what it is, you look at the
chart and you
chart and you say,
calibrate what it is, you look at the
chart and you say, "Where
chart and you say, "Where are
calibrate what it is, you look at the
chart and you say, "Where are these
people
people coming
people coming from?"
All right.
All right. So
people coming from?"
All right. So the
All right. So the ego
people coming from?"
All right. So the ego then
All right. So the ego then is
people coming from?"
All right. So the ego then is an
All right. So the ego then is an endless
wantingness,
cravingness,
cravingness, desiringness.
And
And because
And because that's
And because that's its
And because that's its nature,
And because that's its nature, it
And because that's its nature, it can't
be
be satisfied.
You
You can't
You can't satisfy
You can't satisfy the
You can't satisfy the ego
You can't satisfy the ego because
You can't satisfy the ego because you
would
would have
You can't satisfy the ego because you
would have to
would have to change
You can't satisfy the ego because you
would have to change its
would have to change its nature.
You can't satisfy the ego because you
would have to change its nature. You
can't
can't change
can't change the
can't change the squirrel's
can't change the squirrel's nature
can't change the squirrel's nature by
giving
giving it
can't change the squirrel's nature by
giving it a
giving it a few
can't change the squirrel's nature by
giving it a few more
giving it a few more nuts
can't change the squirrel's nature by
giving it a few more nuts because
giving it a few more nuts because it
can't change the squirrel's nature by
giving it a few more nuts because it is
still
still a
still a squirrel.
Oh,
Oh, it's
still a squirrel.
Oh, it's still
Oh, it's still a
still a squirrel.
Oh, it's still a squirrel.
Oh, it's still a squirrel. So,
still a squirrel.
Oh, it's still a squirrel. So, the
Oh, it's still a squirrel. So, the ego
is
is still
is still the
is still the ego
is still the ego even
is still the ego even though
is still the ego even though you
is still the ego even though you satisfy
it.
it. There
is still the ego even though you satisfy
it. There is
it. There is not
is still the ego even though you satisfy
it. There is not there's
you
you can't
you can't get
you can't get all
you can't get all the
you can't get all the approval
you can't get all the approval that
you can't get all the approval that the
ego
ego wants.
It
It wants
It wants everybody
It wants everybody on
It wants everybody on the
It wants everybody on the planet
It wants everybody on the planet to
It wants everybody on the planet to bow
down
down and
It wants everybody on the planet to bow
down and worship
down and worship you.
It wants everybody on the planet to bow
down and worship you. That's
down and worship you. That's what
It wants everybody on the planet to bow
down and worship you. That's what it
wants.
wants. It
wants. It wants
wants. It wants to
wants. It wants to be
wants. It wants to be God.
And
And Nate
wants. It wants to be God.
And Nate is
And Nate is this
wants. It wants to be God.
And Nate is this wantingness.
Wantingness.
And
And to
Wantingness.
And to cap
And to cap it
Wantingness.
And to cap it off,
And to cap it off, what
Wantingness.
And to cap it off, what the
And to cap it off, what the ego
Wantingness.
And to cap it off, what the ego really
wants
wants to
wants to be
wants to be is
wants to be is the
wants to be is the world
wants to be is the world to
wants to be is the world to recognize
its
its divinity.
Narcissistic
megalamomaniac
egotism
is
is wanting
egotism
is wanting the
is wanting the world
egotism
is wanting the world to
is wanting the world to see
egotism
is wanting the world to see you
is wanting the world to see you as
egotism
is wanting the world to see you as God.
Right?
Those
Those are
Right?
Those are the
Those are the ones
Right?
Those are the ones who
Those are the ones who cause
Right?
Those are the ones who cause the
Those are the ones who cause the death
of
of deaths
of deaths of
of deaths of millions.
30 million
30 million people
of deaths of millions.
30 million people in
30 million people in my
of deaths of millions.
30 million people in my lifetime.
over
over 100
over 100 million
over 100 million people
over 100 million people killed
over 100 million people killed by
over 100 million people killed by the
narcissistic
narcissistic megalomania
over 100 million people killed by the
narcissistic megalomania of
narcissistic megalomania of the
over 100 million people killed by the
narcissistic megalomania of the ego.
So
So it's
So it's probably
So it's probably a
So it's probably a good
So it's probably a good thing
So it's probably a good thing that
So it's probably a good thing that it
does
does get
So it's probably a good thing that it
does get frustrated
in
in the
in the average
in the average person.
in the average person. Remember,
in the average person. Remember, you
know,
know, if
in the average person. Remember, you
know, if everybody
know, if everybody had
in the average person. Remember, you
know, if everybody had that
know, if everybody had that bad
in the average person. Remember, you
know, if everybody had that bad severe
an
an ego,
an ego, life
an ego, life is
an ego, life is difficult
an ego, life is difficult as
an ego, life is difficult as it
an ego, life is difficult as it is.
When
When the
an ego, life is difficult as it is.
When the ego
When the ego doesn't
an ego, life is difficult as it is.
When the ego doesn't get
When the ego doesn't get what
an ego, life is difficult as it is.
When the ego doesn't get what it
When the ego doesn't get what it wants,
it
it goes
it goes into
it goes into grief.
It
It wants
it goes into grief.
It wants all
It wants all those
it goes into grief.
It wants all those nuts.
It wants all those nuts. Just
it goes into grief.
It wants all those nuts. Just as
It wants all those nuts. Just as it
it goes into grief.
It wants all those nuts. Just as it goes
there,
there, they
there, they disappear.
there, they disappear. It
there, they disappear. It mourns
there, they disappear. It mourns the
loss.
It
It wouldn't
It wouldn't see
It wouldn't see it
It wouldn't see it as
It wouldn't see it as a
It wouldn't see it as a loss
It wouldn't see it as a loss if
It wouldn't see it as a loss if it
didn't
didn't want
It wouldn't see it as a loss if it
didn't want it
didn't want it in
It wouldn't see it as a loss if it
didn't want it in the
didn't want it in the first
It wouldn't see it as a loss if it
didn't want it in the first place.
didn't want it in the first place. So
all
all grieving
all grieving then
all grieving then is
all grieving then is the
all grieving then is the loss
all grieving then is the loss of
all grieving then is the loss of a
wantingness.
Yeah.
Yeah. If
Yeah. If you
Yeah. If you give
Yeah. If you give up
Yeah. If you give up wanting,
Yeah. If you give up wanting, how
Yeah. If you give up wanting, how would
you
you suffer
Yeah. If you give up wanting, how would
you suffer from
you suffer from anything?
If
If you're
If you're not
If you're not wanting
If you're not wanting and
If you're not wanting and you
If you're not wanting and you don't
If you're not wanting and you don't need
anything
anything from
If you're not wanting and you don't need
anything from the
anything from the world,
If you're not wanting and you don't need
anything from the world, you
anything from the world, you don't
If you're not wanting and you don't need
anything from the world, you don't have
to
to live
to live in
to live in fear
to live in fear because
to live in fear because if
to live in fear because if they
to live in fear because if they don't
give
give it
to live in fear because if they don't
give it to
give it to you,
to live in fear because if they don't
give it to you, so
said
said this
said this morning,
said this morning, Susie
said this morning, Susie said
said this morning, Susie said she
said this morning, Susie said she read
some
some negative
said this morning, Susie said she read
some negative review
some negative review or
said this morning, Susie said she read
some negative review or something.
some negative review or something. she
said.
said. And
said. And I
said. And I said,
said. And I said, "So
if
if what
said. And I said, "So
if what I've
if what I've written
said. And I said, "So
if what I've written would
if what I've written would make
everybody
everybody in
everybody in the
everybody in the world
everybody in the world happy,
everybody in the world happy, I
everybody in the world happy, I would
everybody in the world happy, I would be
really
really frightened.
I
I would
I would have
I would have completely
I would have completely failed.
Lord
Lord God,
I would have completely failed.
Lord God, I
Lord God, I have
I would have completely failed.
Lord God, I have failed
Lord God, I have failed me
I would have completely failed.
Lord God, I have failed me completely
because
because you
because you cannot
because you cannot state
because you cannot state the
because you cannot state the truth
without
without ruffling
because you cannot state the truth
without ruffling some
without ruffling some feathers.
because you cannot state the truth
without ruffling some feathers. Anybody
who's
who's had
who's had any
who's had any spiritual
who's had any spiritual evolution
who's had any spiritual evolution that
up
up to
who's had any spiritual evolution that
up to this
up to this point
who's had any spiritual evolution that
up to this point knows
up to this point knows that
who's had any spiritual evolution that
up to this point knows that you
up to this point knows that you can't
face
face a
face a truth
face a truth about
face a truth about yourself
face a truth about yourself without
face a truth about yourself without a
few
few ruffle
face a truth about yourself without a
few ruffle feathers.
few ruffle feathers. You
face a truth about yourself without a
few ruffle feathers. You come
few ruffle feathers. You come out
face a truth about yourself without a
few ruffle feathers. You come out of
denial
denial about
denial about something,
denial about something, you
denial about something, you own
denial about something, you own it.
denial about something, you own it. You
stop
stop being
denial about something, you own it. You
stop being an
stop being an enabler.
denial about something, you own it. You
stop being an enabler. Whatever
stop being an enabler. Whatever step
denial about something, you own it. You
stop being an enabler. Whatever step it
is
is you're
is you're taking
is you're taking spiritually,
is you're taking spiritually, it
is you're taking spiritually, it ruffles
some
some feathers
is you're taking spiritually, it ruffles
some feathers within
some feathers within yourself
is you're taking spiritually, it ruffles
some feathers within yourself and
some feathers within yourself and it
is you're taking spiritually, it ruffles
some feathers within yourself and it may
ruffle
ruffle some
ruffle some feathers
ruffle some feathers out
ruffle some feathers out there.
ruffle some feathers out there. So
ruffle some feathers out there. So that
a
a spiritually
ruffle some feathers out there. So that
a spiritually committed
a spiritually committed life
ruffle some feathers out there. So that
a spiritually committed life is
a spiritually committed life is not
necessarily
necessarily peaceful
necessarily peaceful and
necessarily peaceful and beatotific.
Everybody
Everybody thinks,
necessarily peaceful and beatotific.
Everybody thinks, well,
Everybody thinks, well, I'm
necessarily peaceful and beatotific.
Everybody thinks, well, I'm going
Everybody thinks, well, I'm going to
become
become spiritual
become spiritual now.
become spiritual now. You
become spiritual now. You go
become spiritual now. You go in
become spiritual now. You go in the
nearest
nearest New
become spiritual now. You go in the
nearest New Age
nearest New Age bookstore,
become spiritual now. You go in the
nearest New Age bookstore, there's
incense
incense and
incense and flowers
incense and flowers and
incense and flowers and fairies.
Fairies.
Fairies. There's
incense and flowers and fairies.
Fairies. There's always
Fairies. There's always fairies
incense and flowers and fairies.
Fairies. There's always fairies and
butterflies
butterflies and
butterflies and birds.
It's
It's so
butterflies and birds.
It's so dreamy,
It's so dreamy, airy
butterflies and birds.
It's so dreamy, airy fairy.
So
So smooth.
Run,
run,
run.
That's
That's going
That's going to
That's going to the
That's going to the movies.
It's
It's more
That's going to the movies.
It's more likely
It's more likely spiritual
That's going to the movies.
It's more likely spiritual evolution
It's more likely spiritual evolution is
more
more likely
more likely you
more likely you can't
more likely you can't eat
more likely you can't eat your
more likely you can't eat your dinner
because
because you're
more likely you can't eat your dinner
because you're up
because you're up so
more likely you can't eat your dinner
because you're up so upset
because you're up so upset about
more likely you can't eat your dinner
because you're up so upset about what
you
you just
you just discovered
you just discovered about
you just discovered about yourself.
You
You walk
you just discovered about yourself.
You walk away
You walk away from
you just discovered about yourself.
You walk away from the
You walk away from the business.
you just discovered about yourself.
You walk away from the business. You
walk
walk away
walk away from
walk away from relationships.
walk away from relationships. I
walk away from relationships. I mean,
it's
it's catastrophic.
walk away from relationships. I mean,
it's catastrophic. You
it's catastrophic. You know,
uh
uh where's
uh where's the
uh where's the hearts
uh where's the hearts and
uh where's the hearts and the
uh where's the hearts and the flowers
and
and the
uh where's the hearts and the flowers
and the music
and the music and
uh where's the hearts and the flowers
and the music and and
and the music and and the
uh where's the hearts and the flowers
and the music and and the then
and the music and and the then the
pedals?
You're
You're not
pedals?
You're not allowed
You're not allowed to
pedals?
You're not allowed to bring
You're not allowed to bring petals
pedals?
You're not allowed to bring petals and
incense
incense in
incense in this
incense in this meeting
incense in this meeting hall.
They
They must
incense in this meeting hall.
They must not
They must not be
incense in this meeting hall.
They must not be spiritual,
They must not be spiritual, right?
That's
That's what
That's what they
That's what they say.
That's what they say. No
That's what they say. No pedals,
smellers,
incenses,
incenses, etc.
All
All right.
incenses, etc.
All right. So,
All right. So, we
incenses, etc.
All right. So, we like
All right. So, we like we
incenses, etc.
All right. So, we like we say
All right. So, we like we say in
incenses, etc.
All right. So, we like we say in the
shakra
shakra system
shakra system that
shakra system that this
shakra system that this is
shakra system that this is a
characteristic
characteristic of
shakra system that this is a
characteristic of the
characteristic of the solar
shakra system that this is a
characteristic of the solar plexus.
This
This wantingness,
This wantingness, this
This wantingness, this wantingness,
This wantingness, this wantingness, this
desiringness,
desiring
desiring then
desiring then begins
desiring then begins to
desiring then begins to run
desiring then begins to run run
desiring then begins to run run us.
desiring then begins to run run us. Then
we
we if
desiring then begins to run run us. Then
we if we
we if we desire,
desiring then begins to run run us. Then
we if we desire, we
we if we desire, we see
desiring then begins to run run us. Then
we if we desire, we see the
we if we desire, we see the world
desiring then begins to run run us. Then
we if we desire, we see the world as
denying.
denying. We
denying. We see
denying. We see the
denying. We see the world
denying. We see the world as
denying. We see the world as cruel.
denying. We see the world as cruel. We
see
see it
denying. We see the world as cruel. We
see it as
see it as disappointing.
We're
We're stuck
We're stuck with
We're stuck with an
We're stuck with an endless
We're stuck with an endless cravingness
to
to which
We're stuck with an endless cravingness
to which we
to which we are
We're stuck with an endless cravingness
to which we are enslaved.
We
We can't
We can't transcend
We can't transcend something
We can't transcend something unless
We can't transcend something unless we
get
get acquainted
We can't transcend something unless we
get acquainted with
get acquainted with what
We can't transcend something unless we
get acquainted with what it
get acquainted with what it is.
We
We come
We come into
We come into this
We come into this world
We come into this world as
We come into this world as a
We come into this world as a consequence
of
of the
We come into this world as a consequence
of the evolution
of the evolution of
We come into this world as a consequence
of the evolution of consciousness
of the evolution of consciousness with
We come into this world as a consequence
of the evolution of consciousness with a
cravingness
cravingness and
cravingness and a
cravingness and a wantingness
cravingness and a wantingness which
cravingness and a wantingness which sets
us
us up.
We've
We've all
We've all been
We've all been set
We've all been set up.
That's
That's enough
We've all been set up.
That's enough to
That's enough to make
We've all been set up.
That's enough to make you
That's enough to make you get
We've all been set up.
That's enough to make you get paranoid
right
right after
right after the
right after the beginning.
right after the beginning. In
right after the beginning. In the
right after the beginning. In the moment
of
of birth,
right after the beginning. In the moment
of birth, you've
of birth, you've been
right after the beginning. In the moment
of birth, you've been set
of birth, you've been set up
right after the beginning. In the moment
of birth, you've been set up to
of birth, you've been set up to suffer.
Why?
Why? because
Why? because of
Why? because of the
Why? because of the nature
Why? because of the nature of
Why? because of the nature of the
cravingness,
cravingness, the
Why? because of the nature of the
cravingness, the wantingness,
cravingness, the wantingness, the
desiringness
which
which is
desiringness
which is a
which is a quality
desiringness
which is a quality of
which is a quality of life
desiringness
which is a quality of life as
which is a quality of life as it
desiringness
which is a quality of life as it has
evolved
evolved on
evolved on this
evolved on this planet.
Seldom
Seldom to
evolved on this planet.
Seldom to people
Seldom to people transcend
evolved on this planet.
Seldom to people transcend that
completely.
completely. However,
here
here we
completely. However,
here we see
here we see the
completely. However,
here we see the person
here we see the person is
completely. However,
here we see the person is you
here we see the person is you you
completely. However,
here we see the person is you you see
aggressiveness
aggressiveness and
aggressiveness and anger
aggressiveness and anger and
aggressiveness and anger and vengeful
war,
war, hatred.
aggressiveness and anger and vengeful
war, hatred. Today's
war, hatred. Today's headlines
aggressiveness and anger and vengeful
war, hatred. Today's headlines are
war, hatred. Today's headlines are all
the
the consequence
the consequence of
the consequence of somebody's
the consequence of somebody's ego
the consequence of somebody's ego uh
wanting
wanting to
the consequence of somebody's ego uh
wanting to control
wanting to control the
the consequence of somebody's ego uh
wanting to control the world.
Now
Now if
Now if a
Now if a person
Now if a person wants
Now if a person wants to
Now if a person wants to think
Now if a person wants to think what
Now if a person wants to think what they
want
want to
Now if a person wants to think what they
want to think,
want to think, why
Now if a person wants to think what they
want to think, why does
want to think, why does the
Now if a person wants to think what they
want to think, why does the whole
want to think, why does the whole world
have
have to
have to agree
have to agree with
have to agree with you?
have to agree with you? You
have to agree with you? You know what
have to agree with you? You know what I
mean?
mean? You
have to agree with you? You know what I
mean? You can
mean? You can see
have to agree with you? You know what I
mean? You can see that's
mean? You can see that's megalomaniac
just
just to
just to begin
just to begin with.
just to begin with. Take
just to begin with. Take a
just to begin with. Take a religious
position
position that
just to begin with. Take a religious
position that either
position that either the
just to begin with. Take a religious
position that either the whole
position that either the whole world
agrees
agrees with
agrees with you
agrees with you or
agrees with you or you
agrees with you or you kill
agrees with you or you kill them
agrees with you or you kill them all.
Wahabism
is
is a
is a variant
of
of Islamic
is a variant
of Islamic culture.
of Islamic culture. You
is a variant
of Islamic culture. You know
of Islamic culture. You know he
is a variant
of Islamic culture. You know he the
of Islamic culture. You know he the the
birther
birther of
birther of that
birther of that was
birther of that was born
birther of that was born about
birther of that was born about 300
birther of that was born about 300 years
ago.
ago. He
birther of that was born about 300 years
ago. He calibrates
ago. He calibrates 30.
birther of that was born about 300 years
ago. He calibrates 30. No
ago. He calibrates 30. No he
birther of that was born about 300 years
ago. He calibrates 30. No he calibrates
20.
20. Wahabism
20. Wahabism calibrates
20. Wahabism calibrates about
20. Wahabism calibrates about 30.
20. Wahabism calibrates about 30. And
that
that position
20. Wahabism calibrates about 30. And
that position is
that position is the
20. Wahabism calibrates about 30. And
that position is the only
that position is the only ones
20. Wahabism calibrates about 30. And
that position is the only ones that
that position is the only ones that are
right
right are
right are them
right are them which
right are them which condemns
right are them which condemns all
right are them which condemns all of
mankind
mankind except
right are them which condemns all of
mankind except their
mankind except their cult.
All
All of
All of mankind.
all
all of
All of mankind.
all of mankind
all of mankind declares
All of mankind.
all of mankind declares other
all of mankind declares other Islamics
to
to be.
So
So that's
to be.
So that's egomania
that
that only
that only us
that only us are
that only us are right
that only us are right and
that only us are right and everybody
else.
You
You could
You could say,
You could say, well,
You could say, well, what
You could say, well, what about
You could say, well, what about just
You could say, well, what about just if
everybody
everybody else
You could say, well, what about just if
everybody else just
everybody else just didn't
You could say, well, what about just if
everybody else just didn't agree
everybody else just didn't agree with
you?
you? No.
you? No. If
you? No. If they
you? No. If they don't
you? No. If they don't agree
you? No. If they don't agree with
you? No. If they don't agree with you,
they
they must
you? No. If they don't agree with you,
they must die.
It's
It's the
It's the obligation
It's the obligation to
It's the obligation to kill
It's the obligation to kill infidants.
That's
That's what
It's the obligation to kill infidants.
That's what the
That's what the war
It's the obligation to kill infidants.
That's what the war is
That's what the war is about.
It's the obligation to kill infidants.
That's what the war is about. People
say,
say, "What's
say, "What's the
say, "What's the war
say, "What's the war about?"
say, "What's the war about?" It's
say, "What's the war about?" It's about
being
being seen
say, "What's the war about?" It's about
being seen as
being seen as unworthy
say, "What's the war about?" It's about
being seen as unworthy of
being seen as unworthy of life
say, "What's the war about?" It's about
being seen as unworthy of life because
you
you don't
you don't agree
you don't agree with
you don't agree with a
you don't agree with a specific
you don't agree with a specific cult.
That's
That's the
you don't agree with a specific cult.
That's the whole
That's the whole story.
you don't agree with a specific cult.
That's the whole story. The
That's the whole story. The rest
you don't agree with a specific cult.
That's the whole story. The rest of
That's the whole story. The rest of it
is
is just
is just the
is just the consequences
is just the consequences of
is just the consequences of that.
So,
So, we
is just the consequences of that.
So, we see
So, we see what
is just the consequences of that.
So, we see what power
So, we see what power the
is just the consequences of that.
So, we see what power the ego
So, we see what power the ego has
is just the consequences of that.
So, we see what power the ego has in
So, we see what power the ego has in the
really
really non-spiritual
really non-spiritual world.
Finally,
Finally, a
really non-spiritual world.
Finally, a person
Finally, a person gets
really non-spiritual world.
Finally, a person gets off
Finally, a person gets off of
really non-spiritual world.
Finally, a person gets off of pride.
Gets
Gets off
Gets off of
Gets off of pride.
Gets off of pride. gets
Gets off of pride. gets off
Gets off of pride. gets off of
Gets off of pride. gets off of pride
Gets off of pride. gets off of pride and
begins
begins to
Gets off of pride. gets off of pride and
begins to listen
begins to listen to
Gets off of pride. gets off of pride and
begins to listen to a
begins to listen to a different
intuitive
knowingness
and
and crosses
and crosses over
and crosses over the
and crosses over the level
and crosses over the level of
and crosses over the level of 200.
and crosses over the level of 200. They
stop
stop looking
and crosses over the level of 200. They
stop looking for
stop looking for blame.
What
What happens
What happens is
What happens is a
What happens is a consequence
What happens is a consequence of
What happens is a consequence of that
which
which I
What happens is a consequence of that
which I am
which I am is
What happens is a consequence of that
which I am is a
which I am is a profound
What happens is a consequence of that
which I am is a profound truth.
which I am is a profound truth. When
What happens is a consequence of that
which I am is a profound truth. When you
get
get away
get away from
when
when you
get away from
when you get
when you get away
get away from
when you get away from
when you get away from causality,
get away from
when you get away from causality, when
you
you get
you get away
you get away from
you get away from perpetrator
you get away from perpetrator and
victim,
victim, when
you get away from perpetrator and
victim, when you
victim, when you get
you get away from perpetrator and
victim, when you get away
victim, when you get away from
you get away from perpetrator and
victim, when you get away from blame,
then
then you
then you start
then you start owning
then you start owning your
then you start owning your own
responsibility.
You
You give
You give up
You give up on
You give up on the
You give up on the excuses.
You
You whimper
You give up on the excuses.
You whimper a
You whimper a little
You give up on the excuses.
You whimper a little bit,
You whimper a little bit, but
You give up on the excuses.
You whimper a little bit, but you
You whimper a little bit, but you don't
really
really believe
really believe it.
Just
Just for
really believe it.
Just for appearance
Just for appearance sake,
really believe it.
Just for appearance sake, you
Just for appearance sake, you whimper,
but
but actually
but actually within
but actually within yourself,
but actually within yourself, you
but actually within yourself, you have
the
the courage
but actually within yourself, you have
the courage to
the courage to face
but actually within yourself, you have
the courage to face the
the courage to face the truth.
That's
That's a
That's a difficult
That's a difficult step.
That's a difficult step. That's
That's a difficult step. That's a
difficult
difficult step.
85%
85% of
85% of the
85% of the world
85% of the world totally
85% of the world totally is
85% of the world totally is unable
85% of the world totally is unable to
make
make that
85% of the world totally is unable to
make that step
make that step as
85% of the world totally is unable to
make that step as yet.
In
In America,
In America, 51%
In America, 51% now
In America, 51% now have
In America, 51% now have cali
In America, 51% now have cali now
calibrate
calibrate over
In America, 51% now have cali now
calibrate over 200.
calibrate over 200. It
In America, 51% now have cali now
calibrate over 200. It was
calibrate over 200. It was 5050.
51%
of
of Americans
calibrate
calibrate over
calibrate over 200.
calibrate over 200. That's
calibrate over 200. That's the
calibrate over 200. That's the first
time
time in
calibrate over 200. That's the first
time in human
time in human history.
calibrate over 200. That's the first
time in human history. First
time in human history. First time
calibrate over 200. That's the first
time in human history. First time in
human
human history
human history such
human history such a
human history such a phenomena
human history such a phenomena has
human history such a phenomena has ever
occurred.
That
That there's
That there's a
That there's a predominance
That there's a predominance of
That there's a predominance of people
who
who calibrate
That there's a predominance of people
who calibrate at
who calibrate at the
That there's a predominance of people
who calibrate at the level
who calibrate at the level of
That there's a predominance of people
who calibrate at the level of truth
who calibrate at the level of truth or
over.
over. It's
over. It's never
over. It's never happened
over. It's never happened before.
That
That should
over. It's never happened before.
That should create
That should create a
over. It's never happened before.
That should create a good
That should create a good deal
over. It's never happened before.
That should create a good deal of
That should create a good deal of upset
everywhere.
The
The truth
everywhere.
The truth is
The truth is not
everywhere.
The truth is not popular.
The truth is not popular. The
everywhere.
The truth is not popular. The truth
The truth is not popular. The truth is
not
not popular.
Popularity
Popularity is
not popular.
Popularity is one
Popularity is one thing.
not popular.
Popularity is one thing. Truth
Popularity is one thing. Truth is
another.
Yeah.
This
This level
This level of
This level of truth
This level of truth then
This level of truth then shows
This level of truth then shows a
This level of truth then shows a shift
in
in the
This level of truth then shows a shift
in the basic
in the basic energy
This level of truth then shows a shift
in the basic energy of
in the basic energy of life.
This level of truth then shows a shift
in the basic energy of life. It's
in the basic energy of life. It's taking
on
on a
on a different
on a different dimension.
on a different dimension. It's
on a different dimension. It's going
outside
outside of
on a different dimension. It's going
outside of itself.
It's
It's going
It's going out
It's going out of
It's going out of outside
It's going out of outside of
It's going out of outside of itself
It's going out of outside of itself to
another
another kind
It's going out of outside of itself to
another kind of
another kind of knowingness.
The
The bacteria
The bacteria doesn't
The bacteria doesn't know
The bacteria doesn't know anything
The bacteria doesn't know anything about
truth.
truth. Neither
The bacteria doesn't know anything about
truth. Neither does
truth. Neither does a
The bacteria doesn't know anything about
truth. Neither does a squirrel.
It
It just
It just is
It just is what
It just is what it
It just is what it is.
It just is what it is. Therefore,
It just is what it is. Therefore, it's
neither
neither good
It just is what it is. Therefore, it's
neither good nor
neither good nor evil.
It just is what it is. Therefore, it's
neither good nor evil. It
neither good nor evil. It just
It just is what it is. Therefore, it's
neither good nor evil. It just is
neither good nor evil. It just is what
it
it is.
it is. The
it is. The nature
it is. The nature of
it is. The nature of life
it is. The nature of life as
it is. The nature of life as it
it is. The nature of life as it emerges
throughout
evolution
evolution is
evolution is intrinsically
self-directed.
self-directed. Uh
evolution is intrinsically
self-directed. Uh all
self-directed. Uh all right.
evolution is intrinsically
self-directed. Uh all right. So
self-directed. Uh all right. So the
evolution is intrinsically
self-directed. Uh all right. So the ego
can
can now
can now be
can now be turned
can now be turned around
can now be turned around against
can now be turned around against itself
because
because the
can now be turned around against itself
because the ego
because the ego now
can now be turned around against itself
because the ego now can
because the ego now can begin
can now be turned around against itself
because the ego now can begin to
because the ego now can begin to desire
spiritual
spiritual awareness,
self-improvement
self-improvement classes,
spiritual awareness,
self-improvement classes, the
self-improvement classes, the great
cultural
cultural creatives
cultural creatives which
cultural creatives which are
cultural creatives which are now
cultural creatives which are now 25%
cultural creatives which are now 25% of
the
the population.
Self-improvement
Self-improvement classes
Self-improvement classes are
Self-improvement classes are well
attended.
attended. So
Self-improvement classes are well
attended. So s
attended. So s now
Self-improvement classes are well
attended. So s now suddenly
attended. So s now suddenly a
Self-improvement classes are well
attended. So s now suddenly a a
attended. So s now suddenly a a new
emergence.
emergence. At
emergence. At first
emergence. At first the
emergence. At first the ego
emergence. At first the ego grabs
emergence. At first the ego grabs on
emergence. At first the ego grabs on to
this.
In
In history,
In history, of
In history, of course,
In history, of course, religion
In history, of course, religion has
In history, of course, religion has been
the
the source
In history, of course, religion has been
the source of
the source of the
In history, of course, religion has been
the source of the greatest
the source of the greatest truth
available
available to
available to mankind.
The
The only
available to mankind.
The only difficulty
The only difficulty with
sharing
sharing religious
sharing religious truths
sharing religious truths with
sharing religious truths with the
sharing religious truths with the ego
sharing religious truths with the ego is
is
is that
sharing religious truths with the ego is
is that you
is that you end
sharing religious truths with the ego is
is that you end up
is that you end up with
sharing religious truths with the ego is
is that you end up with a
is that you end up with a spiritualized
ego.
ego. Yeah.
Then
Then you
ego. Yeah.
Then you end
Then you end up
ego. Yeah.
Then you end up with
Then you end up with the
ego. Yeah.
Then you end up with the downside
Then you end up with the downside of
Christianity
Christianity in
Christianity in the
Christianity in the middle
Christianity in the middle ages
Christianity in the middle ages and
Christianity in the middle ages and etc.
That
That is
Christianity in the middle ages and etc.
That is the
That is the consequence
Christianity in the middle ages and etc.
That is the consequence of
That is the consequence of the
spiritualized
spiritualized ego
which
which can
spiritualized ego
which can be
which can be brutally
spiritualized ego
which can be brutally dangerous.
which can be brutally dangerous. In
fact,
fact, the
fact, the most
fact, the most dangerous
fact, the most dangerous thing
fact, the most dangerous thing on
fact, the most dangerous thing on the
planet
planet is
fact, the most dangerous thing on the
planet is the
planet is the spiritualized
fact, the most dangerous thing on the
planet is the spiritualized ego.
planet is the spiritualized ego. That
fact, the most dangerous thing on the
planet is the spiritualized ego. That is
the
the most
the most dangerous
the most dangerous thing
the most dangerous thing on
the most dangerous thing on the
the most dangerous thing on the planet.
That's
That's what
the most dangerous thing on the planet.
That's what the
That's what the current
the most dangerous thing on the planet.
That's what the current world
That's what the current world conflict
is
is about.
If
If you
is about.
If you don't
If you don't agree
is about.
If you don't agree with
If you don't agree with us,
is about.
If you don't agree with us, you
If you don't agree with us, you must
is about.
If you don't agree with us, you must all
die.
That's
That's a
die.
That's a little
That's a little selfish
die.
That's a little selfish when
That's a little selfish when you
die.
That's a little selfish when you think
to
to it.
to it. A
to it. A little
to it. A little bit
to it. A little bit selfish.
to it. A little bit selfish. Anyway,
yeah.
yeah. All right.
to it. A little bit selfish. Anyway,
yeah. All right. So,
yeah. All right. So, one
to it. A little bit selfish. Anyway,
yeah. All right. So, one thing
yeah. All right. So, one thing that
happens
happens when
happens when you
happens when you have
happens when you have the
happens when you have the capacity
happens when you have the capacity to
tell
tell the
happens when you have the capacity to
tell the truth
tell the truth is
happens when you have the capacity to
tell the truth is the
tell the truth is the beginning.
Maybe
Maybe I
Maybe I could
Maybe I could be
Maybe I could be wrong.
Maybe
Maybe I
Maybe I could be wrong.
Maybe I could
Maybe I could be
Maybe I could be wrong.
Maybe I could be wrong. That
Maybe I could be wrong. That never
occurs
occurs below
occurs below 200.
below
below 200,
occurs below 200.
below 200, it's
below 200, it's somebody
occurs below 200.
below 200, it's somebody else's
below 200, it's somebody else's fault,
but
but not
but not my
but not my fault.
Therefore,
Therefore, I
but not my fault.
Therefore, I respect
Therefore, I respect any
but not my fault.
Therefore, I respect any politician
Therefore, I respect any politician who
says,
says, you
says, you know,
says, you know, I
says, you know, I screwed
says, you know, I screwed up.
So,
So, you
says, you know, I screwed up.
So, you wonder
So, you wonder why
says, you know, I screwed up.
So, you wonder why people
So, you wonder why people stonewall
when
when admitting
when admitting the
when admitting the truth
when admitting the truth would
when admitting the truth would be
when admitting the truth would be so
easy,
you
you know?
you know? So,
you know? So, you
you know? So, you forgot
you know? So, you forgot to
you know? So, you forgot to to
you know? So, you forgot to to get
you know? So, you forgot to to get bread
on
on the
you know? So, you forgot to to get bread
on the way
on the way home.
you know? So, you forgot to to get bread
on the way home. So,
And
And that's
And that's the
And that's the beginning
And that's the beginning of
And that's the beginning of the
bloodshed.
Most
Most domestic
Most domestic battles,
Most domestic battles, you
Most domestic battles, you see
Most domestic battles, you see the
pictures
pictures of
Most domestic battles, you see the
pictures of the
pictures of the people
Most domestic battles, you see the
pictures of the people with
pictures of the people with with
Most domestic battles, you see the
pictures of the people with with the
black
black eye,
etc.
etc. That's
black eye,
etc. That's the
etc. That's the way
black eye,
etc. That's the way it
etc. That's the way it started.
black eye,
etc. That's the way it started. It
started,
started, you
started, you forgot
started, you forgot to
started, you forgot to fill
started, you forgot to fill the
started, you forgot to fill the gas
tank.
tank. You
started, you forgot to fill the gas
tank. You forgot
tank. You forgot to
started, you forgot to fill the gas
tank. You forgot to get
tank. You forgot to get the
started, you forgot to fill the gas
tank. You forgot to get the bread.
tank. You forgot to get the bread. You
forgot
forgot to
forgot to mill
forgot to mill the
forgot to mill the letter.
And
And then
forgot to mill the letter.
And then it
And then it escalates
forgot to mill the letter.
And then it escalates from
And then it escalates from there.
forgot to mill the letter.
And then it escalates from there. Why
would
would it
would it escalate
would it escalate over
would it escalate over something
would it escalate over something so
trivial?
trivial? Because
would it escalate over something so
trivial? Because the
trivial? Because the ego,
would it escalate over something so
trivial? Because the ego, in
trivial? Because the ego, in order
would it escalate over something so
trivial? Because the ego, in order to
survive,
survive, has
survive, has to
survive, has to feel
survive, has to feel that
survive, has to feel that it's
survive, has to feel that it's right.
Therefore,
for
for somebody
for somebody to
for somebody to admit
for somebody to admit that
for somebody to admit that they
for somebody to admit that they were
wrong
wrong is
for somebody to admit that they were
wrong is impossible
wrong is impossible below
for somebody to admit that they were
wrong is impossible below 200.
The
The way
The way to
The way to not
The way to not get
The way to not get your
The way to not get your feelings
The way to not get your feelings hurt,
The way to not get your feelings hurt, I
guarantee
guarantee I'll
The way to not get your feelings hurt, I
guarantee I'll give
guarantee I'll give you
The way to not get your feelings hurt, I
guarantee I'll give you a
guarantee I'll give you a perfect
The way to not get your feelings hurt, I
guarantee I'll give you a perfect list
to
to make
to make sure
to make sure your
to make sure your feelings
to make sure your feelings never
to make sure your feelings never get
hurt
hurt again.
Take
Take a
Take a legalized
Take a legalized pad.
Write
Write down
Take a legalized pad.
Write down all
Write down all your
Take a legalized pad.
Write down all your faults.
Write
Write down
Write down your
Write down your faults
Write down your faults that
Write down your faults that other
Write down your faults that other people
think
think you
Write down your faults that other people
think you have,
think you have, even
Write down your faults that other people
think you have, even though
think you have, even though you
Write down your faults that other people
think you have, even though you think
they're
they're liars.
And
And now
they're liars.
And now own
And now own them
they're liars.
And now own them all.
Even
Even if
Even if they
Even if they see
Even if they see you
Even if they see you that
Even if they see you that way
Even if they see you that way and
Even if they see you that way and you're
not
not that
Even if they see you that way and you're
not that way,
not that way, you
Even if they see you that way and you're
not that way, you take
not that way, you take responsibility
that
that because
that because of
that because of you,
that because of you, you
that because of you, you they
that because of you, you they see
that because of you, you they see you
that
that way.
that because of you, you they see you
that way. What
that way. What about
that because of you, you they see you
that way. What about you
that way. What about you is
that because of you, you they see you
that way. What about you is allowing
them
them to
them to see
them to see you
them to see you that
them to see you that way.
them to see you that way. See,
them to see you that way. See, you
them to see you that way. See, you just
presume
presume that
them to see you that way. See, you just
presume that there's
presume that there's some
them to see you that way. See, you just
presume that there's some degree
presume that there's some degree of
truth
truth in
truth in all
truth in all of
truth in all of it.
truth in all of it. If
truth in all of it. If you're
truth in all of it. If you're a
truth in all of it. If you're a liar,
you
you tell
truth in all of it. If you're a liar,
you tell them,
you tell them, "I'm
truth in all of it. If you're a liar,
you tell them, "I'm the
you tell them, "I'm the best
truth in all of it. If you're a liar,
you tell them, "I'm the best liar
you tell them, "I'm the best liar on
truth in all of it. If you're a liar,
you tell them, "I'm the best liar on the
planet.
planet. You
planet. You want
planet. You want to
planet. You want to hire
planet. You want to hire me?
planet. You want to hire me? I'm
planet. You want to hire me? I'm worth
planet. You want to hire me? I'm worth a
fortune.
Am
Am I
Am I forgetful?
If
If this
Am I forgetful?
If this wasn't
If this wasn't connected
Am I forgetful?
If this wasn't connected to
If this wasn't connected to this,
Am I forgetful?
If this wasn't connected to this, I
would
would have
would have lost
would have lost it
would have lost it a
would have lost it a long
would have lost it a long time
would have lost it a long time ago."
If
If you
would have lost it a long time ago."
If you own
If you own your
would have lost it a long time ago."
If you own your possible
If you own your possible downside,
would have lost it a long time ago."
If you own your possible downside, don't
you
you see?
you see? Nobody
you see? Nobody has
you see? Nobody has any
you see? Nobody has any place
you see? Nobody has any place to
you see? Nobody has any place to attack
you.
And
And people
And people intuit
And people intuit it
And people intuit it where
And people intuit it where you've
And people intuit it where you've got
And people intuit it where you've got a
and
and that's
And people intuit it where you've got a
and that's what
and that's what they
And people intuit it where you've got a
and that's what they go
and that's what they go for.
And people intuit it where you've got a
and that's what they go for. So
and that's what they go for. So if
you're
you're being
you're being abused
you're being abused by
you're being abused by people
you're being abused by people in
you're being abused by people in various
ways,
ways, it's
you're being abused by people in various
ways, it's because
ways, it's because you're
you're being abused by people in various
ways, it's because you're attracting
ways, it's because you're attracting it
by
by something
by something you're
by something you're not
by something you're not owning
by something you're not owning about
yourself.
Besides,
Besides, there's
Besides, there's nothing
Besides, there's nothing wrong
Besides, there's nothing wrong with
being
being stupid
Besides, there's nothing wrong with
being stupid and
being stupid and ugly.
So
So I'm
So I'm stupid
So I'm stupid and
So I'm stupid and ugly,
So I'm stupid and ugly, right?
I
I was
So I'm stupid and ugly, right?
I was on
I was on a
So I'm stupid and ugly, right?
I was on a radio
I was on a radio show
So I'm stupid and ugly, right?
I was on a radio show in
I was on a radio show in Chicago
So I'm stupid and ugly, right?
I was on a radio show in Chicago with
I was on a radio show in Chicago with a
well-known
well-known jock
well-known jock there
well-known jock there and
well-known jock there and one
well-known jock there and one of
well-known jock there and one of his
team
team admits
well-known jock there and one of his
team admits he's
team admits he's stupid
well-known jock there and one of his
team admits he's stupid and
team admits he's stupid and ugly.
well-known jock there and one of his
team admits he's stupid and ugly. In
fact,
fact, the
fact, the part
fact, the part he
fact, the part he plays
fact, the part he plays on
fact, the part he plays on the
fact, the part he plays on the program
is
is when
fact, the part he plays on the program
is when you
is when you need
fact, the part he plays on the program
is when you need somebody
is when you need somebody stupid
fact, the part he plays on the program
is when you need somebody stupid and
ugly,
ugly, he
ugly, he comes
ugly, he comes in
ugly, he comes in and
ugly, he comes in and makes
ugly, he comes in and makes a
ugly, he comes in and makes a stupid
ugly, he comes in and makes a stupid and
ugly
ugly comment
ugly, he comes in and makes a stupid and
ugly comment and
ugly comment and they
ugly, he comes in and makes a stupid and
ugly comment and they all
ugly comment and they all cheer.
ugly, he comes in and makes a stupid and
ugly comment and they all cheer. Thank
you.
you. He
you. He says,
he
he makes
you. He says,
he makes a
he makes a very
you. He says,
he makes a very good
he makes a very good living
you. He says,
he makes a very good living being
he makes a very good living being stupid
and
and ugly.
So
So we
and ugly.
So we admit
So we admit our
and ugly.
So we admit our faults
So we admit our faults and
and ugly.
So we admit our faults and we
So we admit our faults and we stop
labeling
labeling them
labeling them faults.
I
I mean
labeling them faults.
I mean they
I mean they used
labeling them faults.
I mean they used to
I mean they used to call
labeling them faults.
I mean they used to call me
I mean they used to call me shorty.
Should
Should I
Should I get
Should I get indignant
Should I get indignant and
Should I get indignant and be
Should I get indignant and be sensitive?
Protest
shorty.
shorty. H.
So
So we
shorty. H.
So we have
So we have to
shorty. H.
So we have to get
So we have to get over
shorty. H.
So we have to get over narcissistic
sensitivity.
sensitivity. People
sensitivity. People who
sensitivity. People who are
sensitivity. People who are made
uncomfortable
uncomfortable by
sensitivity. People who are made
uncomfortable by things
uncomfortable by things need
sensitivity. People who are made
uncomfortable by things need a
psychiatrist.
And
And the
psychiatrist.
And the best
And the best advice
psychiatrist.
And the best advice is
And the best advice is to
psychiatrist.
And the best advice is to get
And the best advice is to get over
psychiatrist.
And the best advice is to get over it.
If
If the
If the word
If the word God
If the word God over
If the word God over the
If the word God over the courthouse
makes
makes you
If the word God over the courthouse
makes you nervous,
makes you nervous, you
If the word God over the courthouse
makes you nervous, you better
makes you nervous, you better see
If the word God over the courthouse
makes you nervous, you better see your
analyst
analyst about
analyst about it.
analyst about it. You
analyst about it. You know
analyst about it. You know what
analyst about it. You know what I
analyst about it. You know what I mean?
I
I mean,
analyst about it. You know what I mean?
I mean, those
I mean, those three
analyst about it. You know what I mean?
I mean, those three words
I mean, those three words are
analyst about it. You know what I mean?
I mean, those three words are not
I mean, those three words are not coming
down
down off
down off the
down off the cement
down off the cement and
down off the cement and hitting
down off the cement and hitting you
down off the cement and hitting you in
the
the head
down off the cement and hitting you in
the head or
the head or something.
down off the cement and hitting you in
the head or something. What
the head or something. What what
down off the cement and hitting you in
the head or something. What what is
the head or something. What what is it
doing
doing to
doing to you?
All
All negative
doing to you?
All negative reactions
All negative reactions are
doing to you?
All negative reactions are then
All negative reactions are then not
caused
caused from
caused from outside.
caused from outside. It's
caused from outside. It's how
caused from outside. It's how you
choose.
choose. Everybody
caused from outside. It's how you
choose. Everybody who's
choose. Everybody who's uncomfortable
caused from outside. It's how you
choose. Everybody who's uncomfortable in
various
various situations
various situations is
various situations is completely
various situations is completely legally
free
free to
various situations is completely legally
free to not
free to not feel
various situations is completely legally
free to not feel uncomfortable.
And
And I'm
And I'm trying
And I'm trying to
And I'm trying to explain
And I'm trying to explain to
And I'm trying to explain to them
And I'm trying to explain to them how
And I'm trying to explain to them how to
do
do it.
And I'm trying to explain to them how to
do it. The
do it. The world
And I'm trying to explain to them how to
do it. The world is
do it. The world is not
And I'm trying to explain to them how to
do it. The world is not going
do it. The world is not going to
And I'm trying to explain to them how to
do it. The world is not going to agree
with
with your
with your political
with your political views.
with your political views. So
the
the world
with your political views. So
the world is
the world is not
with your political views. So
the world is not going
the world is not going to
with your political views. So
the world is not going to agree
the world is not going to agree with
many
many things
many things you
many things you hold
many things you hold about
many things you hold about yourself.
The
The way
many things you hold about yourself.
The way to
The way to become
many things you hold about yourself.
The way to become bulletproof
is
is to
is to own
is to own any
is to own any negativity
is to own any negativity that
is to own any negativity that you
is to own any negativity that you can
even
even imagine
is to own any negativity that you can
even imagine might
even imagine might apply
is to own any negativity that you can
even imagine might apply to
even imagine might apply to yourself.
Now,
Now, when
Now, when you
Now, when you go
Now, when you go to
Now, when you go to accept
Now, when you go to accept that,
Now, when you go to accept that, you'll
run
run into
Now, when you go to accept that, you'll
run into the
run into the ego
that
that you
that you are
that you are dumb
that you are dumb and
that you are dumb and ugly.
that you are dumb and ugly. Well,
that you are dumb and ugly. Well, that's
true.
But
But God
But God loves
But God loves me.
God
God loves
But God loves me.
God loves me
God loves me anyway.
But God loves me.
God loves me anyway. Okay.
God loves me anyway. Okay. You're
But God loves me.
God loves me anyway. Okay. You're short
and
and stubby
and stubby and
and stubby and you
and stubby and you wear
and stubby and you wear thick
and stubby and you wear thick glasses,
right?
The
The coach
The coach wouldn't
The coach wouldn't approve
The coach wouldn't approve me
The coach wouldn't approve me for
The coach wouldn't approve me for the
team.
team. Any
The coach wouldn't approve me for the
team. Any team.
The
The the
The the chess.
The the chess. He
The the chess. He suggested
The the chess. He suggested chess.
I
I remember
The the chess. He suggested chess.
I remember he
I remember he squeezed
The the chess. He suggested chess.
I remember he squeezed my
I remember he squeezed my bones
The the chess. He suggested chess.
I remember he squeezed my bones and
I remember he squeezed my bones and he
says
one
one quarterback
says
one quarterback hits
one quarterback hits you
says
one quarterback hits you with
one quarterback hits you with that
says
one quarterback hits you with that and
it's
it's busted.
it's busted. So
it's busted. So even
it's busted. So even with
it's busted. So even with all
it's busted. So even with all these
things
things my
it's busted. So even with all these
things my mom
things my mom bought
it's busted. So even with all these
things my mom bought me
things my mom bought me or
it's busted. So even with all these
things my mom bought me or I
things my mom bought me or I bought
myself
myself helmets
myself helmets and
myself helmets and all
myself helmets and all this
myself helmets and all this crap,
myself helmets and all this crap, you
know,
know, and
myself helmets and all this crap, you
know, and all
know, and all these
myself helmets and all this crap, you
know, and all these pads
know, and all these pads and
myself helmets and all this crap, you
know, and all these pads and all
know, and all these pads and all they
wouldn't
wouldn't let
wouldn't let me
wouldn't let me out
wouldn't let me out on
wouldn't let me out on the
wouldn't let me out on the field.
Yeah.
Yeah. I
wouldn't let me out on the field.
Yeah. I went
Yeah. I went back
wouldn't let me out on the field.
Yeah. I went back to
Yeah. I went back to trying
wouldn't let me out on the field.
Yeah. I went back to trying to
Yeah. I went back to trying to climb
wouldn't let me out on the field.
Yeah. I went back to trying to climb a
rope
rope loses
rope loses all
rope loses all the
rope loses all the way
rope loses all the way to
rope loses all the way to the
rope loses all the way to the ceiling.
rope loses all the way to the ceiling. I
would
would get
rope loses all the way to the ceiling. I
would get about
would get about this
rope loses all the way to the ceiling. I
would get about this far
would get about this far and
rope loses all the way to the ceiling. I
would get about this far and I
would get about this far and I go
rope loses all the way to the ceiling. I
would get about this far and I go with
it.
That
That just
it.
That just wasn't
That just wasn't my
it.
That just wasn't my world.
That just wasn't my world. All right.
So,
So, you
So, you see
So, you see how
So, you see how you
So, you see how you accept
So, you see how you accept your
limitation?
limitation? What
So, you see how you accept your
limitation? What is
limitation? What is your
So, you see how you accept your
limitation? What is your world?
limitation? What is your world? Well,
So, you see how you accept your
limitation? What is your world? Well, if
you
you got
you got four
you got four eyes
you got four eyes and
you got four eyes and you're
you got four eyes and you're skinny
you got four eyes and you're skinny and
and
and look
you got four eyes and you're skinny and
and look like
and look like some
you got four eyes and you're skinny and
and look like some kind
and look like some kind of
you got four eyes and you're skinny and
and look like some kind of comical
character,
character, you
character, you can
character, you can sit
character, you can sit in
character, you can sit in a
character, you can sit in a big
character, you can sit in a big book
character, you can sit in a big book and
read
read Plato's
character, you can sit in a big book and
read Plato's Republic,
read Plato's Republic, which
character, you can sit in a big book and
read Plato's Republic, which is
read Plato's Republic, which is what
character, you can sit in a big book and
read Plato's Republic, which is what I
did.
Socrates.
Socrates. So,
did.
Socrates. So, my
Socrates. So, my hero
did.
Socrates. So, my hero was
Socrates. So, my hero was Socrates.
Socrates,
Socrates, right?
>> What?
>> Oh,
>> Oh, this
>> Oh, this is
>> Oh, this is a
>> Oh, this is a pointer.
Well,
Well, okay.
>> Oh, this is a pointer.
Well, okay. There's
Well, okay. There's the
>> Oh, this is a pointer.
Well, okay. There's the pointer.
Well, okay. There's the pointer. A
pointer
pointer is
pointer is whatever
pointer is whatever you
pointer is whatever you call
pointer is whatever you call a
pointer is whatever you call a pointer.
So
the
the nature,
the nature, the
the nature, the quality
the nature, the quality of
the nature, the quality of the
the nature, the quality of the ego
the nature, the quality of the ego then
is
is for
the nature, the quality of the ego then
is for survival.
is for survival. It
the nature, the quality of the ego then
is for survival. It believes
is for survival. It believes it
the nature, the quality of the ego then
is for survival. It believes it has
is for survival. It believes it has to
constantly
constantly get
constantly get because
constantly get because it
constantly get because it thinks
constantly get because it thinks that
the
the source
constantly get because it thinks that
the source of
the source of his
constantly get because it thinks that
the source of his life
the source of his life of
constantly get because it thinks that
the source of his life of its
its
its life
its life is
its life is out
its life is out there
its life is out there and
its life is out there and has
its life is out there and has to
its life is out there and has to be
gotten.
This
This delusion,
This delusion, this
This delusion, this illusion
This delusion, this illusion persists
all
all the
This delusion, this illusion persists
all the way
all the way up
This delusion, this illusion persists
all the way up the
all the way up the scale.
This delusion, this illusion persists
all the way up the scale. All
all the way up the scale. All the
This delusion, this illusion persists
all the way up the scale. All the way
all the way up the scale. All the way up
the
the scale
the scale until
the scale until you
the scale until you begin
the scale until you begin to
the scale until you begin to experience
a
a different
the scale until you begin to experience
a different energy.
Now,
Now, what
Now, what brings
Now, what brings in
Now, what brings in what
Now, what brings in what you
Now, what brings in what you need
Now, what brings in what you need is
Now, what brings in what you need is who
you
you are.
Now, what brings in what you need is who
you are. As
you are. As you're
Now, what brings in what you need is who
you are. As you're a
you are. As you're a friendly
Now, what brings in what you need is who
you are. As you're a friendly person,
you
you begin
you begin to
you begin to notice
you begin to notice everybody
you begin to notice everybody smiles
you begin to notice everybody smiles at
you.
you. Everybody
you begin to notice everybody smiles at
you. Everybody smiles
you. Everybody smiles at
you begin to notice everybody smiles at
you. Everybody smiles at you.
Almost
Almost everybody
Almost everybody smiled
Almost everybody smiled at
Almost everybody smiled at me
Almost everybody smiled at me this
morning
morning when
Almost everybody smiled at me this
morning when I
morning when I was
Almost everybody smiled at me this
morning when I was greeting
morning when I was greeting everybody.
Couple
Couple of
Couple of people
Couple of people looked
Couple of people looked at
Couple of people looked at me
Couple of people looked at me a
Couple of people looked at me a little
like
like we'll
Couple of people looked at me a little
like we'll wait
like we'll wait and
Couple of people looked at me a little
like we'll wait and see,
like we'll wait and see, you
Couple of people looked at me a little
like we'll wait and see, you know.
Anyway,
Anyway, okay.
All right.
All right. So,
Anyway, okay.
All right. So, who
All right. So, who you
Anyway, okay.
All right. So, who you become
All right. So, who you become then
begins
begins to
begins to have
begins to have an
begins to have an effect
begins to have an effect beyond
causality.
Uh
Uh because
Uh because now
Uh because now you're
Uh because now you're beginning
Uh because now you're beginning to
Uh because now you're beginning to live
in
in a
Uh because now you're beginning to live
in a different
in a different field.
Uh because now you're beginning to live
in a different field. So,
in a different field. So, we're
Uh because now you're beginning to live
in a different field. So, we're getting
out
out of
out of cause
out of cause and
out of cause and effect.
out of cause and effect. We're
out of cause and effect. We're getting
out
out of
out of cause and effect. We're getting
out of the
out of the ego
out of cause and effect. We're getting
out of the ego and
out of the ego and we're
out of cause and effect. We're getting
out of the ego and we're seeing
out of the ego and we're seeing that
out of cause and effect. We're getting
out of the ego and we're seeing that who
we
we are
we are is
we are is now
we are is now determining
we are is now determining a
we are is now determining a field.
we are is now determining a field. And
the
the experiences
we are is now determining a field. And
the experiences of
the experiences of the
we are is now determining a field. And
the experiences of the field
the experiences of the field are
different
different than
different than what
different than what they
different than what they were.
different than what they were. So
different than what they were. So the
field
field that
different than what they were. So the
field that calibrates
field that calibrates at
different than what they were. So the
field that calibrates at 200
field that calibrates at 200 is
different
different than
different than the
different than the field
different than the field and
different than the field and different
than
than the
different than the field and different
than the field
than the field at
different than the field and different
than the field at 350.
350.
Whether
Whether people
350.
Whether people like
Whether people like it
350.
Whether people like it or
Whether people like it or not.
350.
Whether people like it or not. I
Whether people like it or not. I always
say,
say, you
say, you know,
say, you know, Walmart
say, you know, Walmart calibrates
say, you know, Walmart calibrates at
350,
350, 365.
If
If that
If that makes
If that makes you
If that makes you mad,
If that makes you mad, see
If that makes you mad, see your
If that makes you mad, see your doctor.
It
It makes
If that makes you mad, see your doctor.
It makes you
It makes you mad.
That's
That's a
That's a fact.
That's a fact. It
That's a fact. It does
That's a fact. It does calibrate
That's a fact. It does calibrate that.
All
All right.
That's a fact. It does calibrate that.
All right. So,
All right. So, what
That's a fact. It does calibrate that.
All right. So, what we
All right. So, what we discovered
That's a fact. It does calibrate that.
All right. So, what we discovered then
was
was a
was a way
was a way of
was a way of um
calibrating
calibrating the
was a way of um
calibrating the level
calibrating the level of
was a way of um
calibrating the level of truth.
calibrating the level of truth. We
discovered
discovered that
discovered that everything
discovered that everything below
discovered that everything below 200
makes
makes you
discovered that everything below 200
makes you weak.
makes you weak. Everything
discovered that everything below 200
makes you weak. Everything over
makes you weak. Everything over 200
makes
makes you
makes you go
makes you go strong.
makes you go strong. We
makes you go strong. We now
makes you go strong. We now had
makes you go strong. We now had for
makes you go strong. We now had for the
first
first time
makes you go strong. We now had for the
first time in
first time in human
makes you go strong. We now had for the
first time in human history
first time in human history a
makes you go strong. We now had for the
first time in human history a means
first time in human history a means of
discerning
discerning truth
discerning truth from
discerning truth from falsehood.
discerning truth from falsehood. plus
discerning truth from falsehood. plus a
means
means of
discerning truth from falsehood. plus a
means of discerning
means of discerning what
discerning truth from falsehood. plus a
means of discerning what is
means of discerning what is truth
discerning truth from falsehood. plus a
means of discerning what is truth which
we
we found
we found out
we found out you
we found out you cannot
we found out you cannot define
we found out you cannot define what
truth
truth is
we found out you cannot define what
truth is without
truth is without stating
we found out you cannot define what
truth is without stating the
truth is without stating the context.
Everything
Everything is
Everything is only
Everything is only true
Everything is only true within
Everything is only true within a
Everything is only true within a certain
context.
context. And
Everything is only true within a certain
context. And we
context. And we saw
Everything is only true within a certain
context. And we saw why
context. And we saw why the
Everything is only true within a certain
context. And we saw why the world
context. And we saw why the world was
unable
unable to
unable to reach
unable to reach any
unable to reach any agreement
unable to reach any agreement on
unable to reach any agreement on what
unable to reach any agreement on what is
truth
truth since
unable to reach any agreement on what is
truth since the
truth since the beginning
unable to reach any agreement on what is
truth since the beginning of
truth since the beginning of time.
There's
There's been
There's been no
There's been no common
There's been no common agreement
There's been no common agreement on
There's been no common agreement on what
is
is truth.
There's been no common agreement on what
is truth. As
is truth. As we'll
There's been no common agreement on what
is truth. As we'll see
is truth. As we'll see later,
you
you can
you can see
you can see now
you can see now down
you can see now down here.
you can see now down here. If
you can see now down here. If you
you can see now down here. If you don't
get,
get, you're
you can see now down here. If you don't
get, you're going
get, you're going to
you can see now down here. If you don't
get, you're going to die.
get, you're going to die. up
you can see now down here. If you don't
get, you're going to die. up here.
get, you're going to die. up here. What
you
you need
you need begins
you need begins to
you need begins to appear
you need begins to appear of
you need begins to appear of its
you need begins to appear of its own.
And
And I
you need begins to appear of its own.
And I experimented
And I experimented with
you need begins to appear of its own.
And I experimented with that
And I experimented with that when
you need begins to appear of its own.
And I experimented with that when I
And I experimented with that when I did
first
first did
first did the
first did the course
first did the course of
first did the course of miracles.
first did the course of miracles. It
says
says you
first did the course of miracles. It
says you don't
says you don't need
first did the course of miracles. It
says you don't need anything
says you don't need anything out
first did the course of miracles. It
says you don't need anything out there
at
at all.
at all. So
at all. So I
at all. So I walked
at all. So I walked out
at all. So I walked out of
at all. So I walked out of the
at all. So I walked out of the house
with
with no
at all. So I walked out of the house
with no money,
with no money, no
at all. So I walked out of the house
with no money, no food
with no money, no food or
at all. So I walked out of the house
with no money, no food or nothing.
Sure
Sure enough,
Sure enough, around
Sure enough, around lunch
Sure enough, around lunch time,
Sure enough, around lunch time, somebody
I
I was
Sure enough, around lunch time, somebody
I was passing
I was passing by
Sure enough, around lunch time, somebody
I was passing by said,
I was passing by said, "Do
Sure enough, around lunch time, somebody
I was passing by said, "Do you
I was passing by said, "Do you have
lunch
lunch yet?"
lunch yet?" I
lunch yet?" I said,
lunch yet?" I said, "No."
lunch yet?" I said, "No." He
lunch yet?" I said, "No." He says,
lunch yet?" I said, "No." He says, "I
got
got an
lunch yet?" I said, "No." He says, "I
got an extra
got an extra sandwich."
lunch yet?" I said, "No." He says, "I
got an extra sandwich." Everything
got an extra sandwich." Everything began
to
to appear
to appear of
to appear of its
to appear of its own
to appear of its own out
to appear of its own out of
to appear of its own out of nothingness,
out
out of
to appear of its own out of nothingness,
out of nowhere,
out of nowhere, just
to appear of its own out of nothingness,
out of nowhere, just like
out of nowhere, just like chocolate
appears
appears now,
appears now, you
appears now, you know,
appears now, you know, by
appears now, you know, by the
appears now, you know, by the box.
I
I don't
appears now, you know, by the box.
I don't ask
I don't ask any
appears now, you know, by the box.
I don't ask any chocolate.
I don't ask any chocolate. It
appears now, you know, by the box.
I don't ask any chocolate. It just
appears,
appears, you
appears, you know,
appears, you know, have
appears, you know, have a
appears, you know, have a closet
appears, you know, have a closet full
appears, you know, have a closet full of
chocolate.
chocolate. So
what
what you
what you become
what you become then
what you become then begins
what you become then begins to
what you become then begins to influence
the
the field.
what you become then begins to influence
the field. And
the field. And what
what you become then begins to influence
the field. And what you
the field. And what you need,
what you become then begins to influence
the field. And what you need, what
the field. And what you need, what you
need,
need, what
need, what you
need, what you really
need, what you really need
need, what you really need then
need, what you really need then becomes
a
a present
need, what you really need then becomes
a present by
a present by virtue
need, what you really need then becomes
a present by virtue of
a present by virtue of the
need, what you really need then becomes
a present by virtue of the quality
a present by virtue of the quality of
the
the field
the field itself.
This
This is
the field itself.
This is beyond
This is beyond the
the field itself.
This is beyond the ego's
This is beyond the ego's understanding.
The
The ego
The ego cannot
The ego cannot understand
The ego cannot understand why
The ego cannot understand why morality,
fairness,
fairness, ethics,
The ego cannot understand why morality,
fairness, ethics, integrity
fairness, ethics, integrity etc.
The ego cannot understand why morality,
fairness, ethics, integrity etc. is
fairness, ethics, integrity etc. is not
a
a sacrifice.
People
People below
a sacrifice.
People below 200
People below 200 think
a sacrifice.
People below 200 think those
People below 200 think those are
a sacrifice.
People below 200 think those are sacri
that
that is
that is a
that is a sacrifice
that is a sacrifice and
that is a sacrifice and there
that is a sacrifice and there is
that is a sacrifice and there is a
that is a sacrifice and there is a very
verbal
verbal viciferous
group
group out
group out there
group out there that
group out there that wants
group out there that wants to
group out there that wants to vilify
morality
morality and
group out there that wants to vilify
morality and ethics
morality and ethics and
group out there that wants to vilify
morality and ethics and all
morality and ethics and all because
group out there that wants to vilify
morality and ethics and all because it
doesn't
doesn't see
doesn't see any
doesn't see any gain
doesn't see any gain in
doesn't see any gain in it.
doesn't see any gain in it. Doesn't
doesn't see any gain in it. Doesn't see
any
any gain.
doesn't see any gain in it. Doesn't see
any gain. Doesn't
any gain. Doesn't see
doesn't see any gain in it. Doesn't see
any gain. Doesn't see any
any gain. Doesn't see any gain.
doesn't see any gain in it. Doesn't see
any gain. Doesn't see any gain. No,
there
there is
there is no
there is no immediate
there is no immediate gain
there is no immediate gain of
there is no immediate gain of visible
there is no immediate gain of visible to
the
the ego.
there is no immediate gain of visible to
the ego. And
the ego. And it's
there is no immediate gain of visible to
the ego. And it's only
the ego. And it's only by
there is no immediate gain of visible to
the ego. And it's only by being
the ego. And it's only by being that
being
being that
being that that
being that that you
being that that you discover
what
what it
being that that you discover
what it means
without
without looking
without looking for
without looking for anything.
without looking for anything. You're
sitting
sitting in
without looking for anything. You're
sitting in a
sitting in a chair
without looking for anything. You're
sitting in a chair and
sitting in a chair and your
without looking for anything. You're
sitting in a chair and your spouse
sitting in a chair and your spouse puts
their
their hands
their hands on
their hands on your
their hands on your shoulders
their hands on your shoulders and
their hands on your shoulders and you
feel
feel the
their hands on your shoulders and you
feel the world
feel the world is
their hands on your shoulders and you
feel the world is great.
The
The kitty
The kitty sits
The kitty sits on
The kitty sits on your
The kitty sits on your lap
The kitty sits on your lap and
The kitty sits on your lap and purr.
What
What more
The kitty sits on your lap and purr.
What more do
What more do you
The kitty sits on your lap and purr.
What more do you need?
What more do you need? You're
The kitty sits on your lap and purr.
What more do you need? You're complete
and
and total
and total from
and total from instant
and total from instant to
and total from instant to instant.
and total from instant to instant. Then
it
it dawns
and total from instant to instant. Then
it dawns on
it dawns on you
and total from instant to instant. Then
it dawns on you one
it dawns on you one time.
H
H then
H then when
H then when you
H then when you stop
H then when you stop coming
H then when you stop coming from
H then when you stop coming from lack,
you
you see
H then when you stop coming from lack,
you see when
you see when you
H then when you stop coming from lack,
you see when you come
you see when you come from
H then when you stop coming from lack,
you see when you come from lack,
you see when you come from lack, when
you
you look
you look at
you look at the
you look at the Newtonian
you look at the Newtonian paradigm,
you look at the Newtonian paradigm, it
looks
looks like
you look at the Newtonian paradigm, it
looks like uh
looks like uh you
you look at the Newtonian paradigm, it
looks like uh you go
looks like uh you go from
you look at the Newtonian paradigm, it
looks like uh you go from incomplete
looks like uh you go from incomplete to
complete
complete to
complete to incomplete
complete to incomplete to
complete to incomplete to complete
complete to incomplete to complete and
you
you begin
complete to incomplete to complete and
you begin to
you begin to realize
complete to incomplete to complete and
you begin to realize that
you begin to realize that you
complete to incomplete to complete and
you begin to realize that you really
you begin to realize that you really go
from
from complete
from complete to
from complete to complete.
This
This instant
from complete to complete.
This instant is
This instant is complete.
This
This instant
This instant is
This instant is complete.
This instant is complete. Is
This instant is complete. Is there
anything
anything I
This instant is complete. Is there
anything I need
anything I need at
This instant is complete. Is there
anything I need at this
anything I need at this instant?
This instant is complete. Is there
anything I need at this instant? No,
anything I need at this instant? No, I'm
complete.
You
You go
complete.
You go from
You go from complete
complete.
You go from complete from
You go from complete from incomp
complete.
You go from complete from incomp instead
of
of from
of from incomplete
of from incomplete which
of from incomplete which is
of from incomplete which is the
of from incomplete which is the world
of from incomplete which is the world of
the
the ego
of from incomplete which is the world of
the ego which
the ego which is
of from incomplete which is the world of
the ego which is a
the ego which is a wantingness.
of from incomplete which is the world of
the ego which is a wantingness. You
always
always feel
always feel incomplete
always feel incomplete to
always feel incomplete to complete
always feel incomplete to complete to
complete.
complete. Doesn't
always feel incomplete to complete to
complete. Doesn't mean
complete. Doesn't mean you
always feel incomplete to complete to
complete. Doesn't mean you can't
complete. Doesn't mean you can't have
more
but
but you
more
but you don't
but you don't feel
more
but you don't feel any
but you don't feel any suffering
more
but you don't feel any suffering that
but you don't feel any suffering that it
isn't
isn't yet.
isn't yet. Huh?
isn't yet. Huh? Because
isn't yet. Huh? Because what
isn't yet. Huh? Because what you
isn't yet. Huh? Because what you want
people
people want
isn't yet. Huh? Because what you want
people want to
people want to know
isn't yet. Huh? Because what you want
people want to know what
people want to know what is
isn't yet. Huh? Because what you want
people want to know what is the
people want to know what is the clue
isn't yet. Huh? Because what you want
people want to know what is the clue to
success?
success? The
success? The clue
success? The clue to
success? The clue to success
success? The clue to success is
success? The clue to success is to
success? The clue to success is to just
be
be exactly
success? The clue to success is to just
be exactly what
be exactly what you
success? The clue to success is to just
be exactly what you are.
be exactly what you are. Be
success? The clue to success is to just
be exactly what you are. Be a
be exactly what you are. Be a class
success? The clue to success is to just
be exactly what you are. Be a class act.
Be
Be completely
Be completely and
Be completely and totally
100%
100% what
Be completely and totally
100% what you
100% what you are
Be completely and totally
100% what you are and
100% what you are and the
Be completely and totally
100% what you are and the world
100% what you are and the world will
provide
provide all
provide all that
provide all that you
provide all that you need.
Who's
Who's my
provide all that you need.
Who's my favorite?
Satcho,
Satcho, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Satcho.
>> Yeah. Louis
>> Yeah. Louis Armstrong.
>> Yeah. Louis Armstrong. Well,
>> Yeah. Louis Armstrong. Well, we
calibrated
calibrated Lemstrong.
>> Yeah. Louis Armstrong. Well, we
calibrated Lemstrong. I
calibrated Lemstrong. I mean,
just
just wonderfully
just wonderfully being
just wonderfully being precisely
just wonderfully being precisely who
just wonderfully being precisely who you
are.
are. Absolutely.
just wonderfully being precisely who you
are. Absolutely. you
are. Absolutely. you know,
just wonderfully being precisely who you
are. Absolutely. you know, sends
are. Absolutely. you know, sends people
into
into joy.
Sends
Sends people
into joy.
Sends people into
Sends people into joy.
into joy.
Sends people into joy. He
Sends people into joy. He just
into joy.
Sends people into joy. He just he
calibrates
calibrates over
calibrates over 500.
calibrates over 500. You
calibrates over 500. You know,
calibrates over 500. You know, sort
calibrates over 500. You know, sort of
calibrates over 500. You know, sort of a
universal
universal lovingness,
calibrates over 500. You know, sort of a
universal lovingness, but
universal lovingness, but it
calibrates over 500. You know, sort of a
universal lovingness, but it comes
universal lovingness, but it comes from
not
not wanting
not wanting anything
not wanting anything but
not wanting anything but sharing
not wanting anything but sharing who
not wanting anything but sharing who one
is
is with
not wanting anything but sharing who one
is with the
is with the world.
not wanting anything but sharing who one
is with the world. To
is with the world. To share
not wanting anything but sharing who one
is with the world. To share who
is with the world. To share who you
not wanting anything but sharing who one
is with the world. To share who you are
completely
completely with
completely with the
completely with the world,
completely with the world, then
completely with the world, then you're
complete
complete and
completely with the world, then you're
complete and total.
complete and total. Need
completely with the world, then you're
complete and total. Need nothing.
complete and total. Need nothing. Need
nothing
nothing from
nothing from the
nothing from the world.
nothing from the world. So
nothing from the world. So these
feelings
feelings down
nothing from the world. So these
feelings down here
feelings down here don't
nothing from the world. So these
feelings down here don't keep
feelings down here don't keep recurring.
If
If you
If you don't
If you don't want
If you don't want anything,
If you don't want anything, you
If you don't want anything, you can't
If you don't want anything, you can't be
disappointed.
disappointed. Because
If you don't want anything, you can't be
disappointed. Because you're
disappointed. Because you're complete
If you don't want anything, you can't be
disappointed. Because you're complete in
total
total from
total from moment
total from moment to
total from moment to moment.
total from moment to moment. Huh?
total from moment to moment. Huh? So
life
life becomes
total from moment to moment. Huh? So
life becomes perfect
life becomes perfect from
total from moment to moment. Huh? So
life becomes perfect from moment
life becomes perfect from moment to
moment.
Therefore
Therefore we
moment.
Therefore we can
Therefore we can stop
moment.
Therefore we can stop vilifying
Therefore we can stop vilifying the
moment.
Therefore we can stop vilifying the ego
and
and see
and see it
and see it as
and see it as an
and see it as an evol
and see it as an evol evolutionary
arrest.
arrest. So
and see it as an evol evolutionary
arrest. So below
arrest. So below 200
and see it as an evol evolutionary
arrest. So below 200 what
arrest. So below 200 what you
and see it as an evol evolutionary
arrest. So below 200 what you see
arrest. So below 200 what you see is
and see it as an evol evolutionary
arrest. So below 200 what you see is an
evolutionary
evolutionary arrest
evolutionary arrest in
evolutionary arrest in which
evolutionary arrest in which the
evolutionary arrest in which the animal
emotions
emotions the
evolutionary arrest in which the animal
emotions the animal
emotions the animal state
evolutionary arrest in which the animal
emotions the animal state tends
emotions the animal state tends to
predominate.
Then
Then you
predominate.
Then you get
Then you get the
predominate.
Then you get the emergence
Then you get the emergence of
predominate.
Then you get the emergence of the
spiritual
spiritual and
spiritual and then
spiritual and then you
spiritual and then you have
spiritual and then you have that
difficult
difficult period
spiritual and then you have that
difficult period in
difficult period in spiritual
spiritual and then you have that
difficult period in spiritual evolution
where
where you're
where you're looking
where you're looking at
where you're looking at the
where you're looking at the downside.
You're
You're looking
where you're looking at the downside.
You're looking at
You're looking at angriness.
where you're looking at the downside.
You're looking at angriness. You're
looking
looking at
looking at selfishness
looking at selfishness and
looking at selfishness and you're
looking at selfishness and you're being
pulled
pulled up
looking at selfishness and you're being
pulled up towards
pulled up towards the
looking at selfishness and you're being
pulled up towards the top
pulled up towards the top and
looking at selfishness and you're being
pulled up towards the top and all
pulled up towards the top and all this
stuff
stuff is
stuff is now
stuff is now being
stuff is now being pulled
stuff is now being pulled up
stuff is now being pulled up in
stuff is now being pulled up in the
unconscious.
unconscious. You
stuff is now being pulled up in the
unconscious. You know,
unconscious. You know, there's
stuff is now being pulled up in the
unconscious. You know, there's various
archetypes.
archetypes. So
archetypes. So you
archetypes. So you can
archetypes. So you can clear
archetypes. So you can clear out
archetypes. So you can clear out one
archetype
archetype and
archetypes. So you can clear out one
archetype and then
archetype and then another
archetypes. So you can clear out one
archetype and then another one
archetype and then another one comes
archetypes. So you can clear out one
archetype and then another one comes up
all
all the,
all the, you
all the, you know,
all the, you know, comes
all the, you know, comes up.
Yeah.
Yeah. The
all the, you know, comes up.
Yeah. The one
Yeah. The one I
all the, you know, comes up.
Yeah. The one I had
Yeah. The one I had the
all the, you know, comes up.
Yeah. The one I had the most
Yeah. The one I had the most problem
all the, you know, comes up.
Yeah. The one I had the most problem was
the
the spiritual
the spiritual knight
the spiritual knight who
the spiritual knight who was
the spiritual knight who was always
getting
getting indignant
at
non-integrity.
non-integrity. You
at
non-integrity. You know,
if
if you're
if you're going
if you're going to
if you're going to get
if you're going to get indignant
if you're going to get indignant and
non-
non- integrity,
if you're going to get indignant and
non- integrity, you're
non- integrity, you're going
if you're going to get indignant and
non- integrity, you're going to
non- integrity, you're going to spend
if you're going to get indignant and
non- integrity, you're going to spend a
lot
lot of
lot of time
lot of time being
lot of time being indignant.
You
You know,
lot of time being indignant.
You know, shock
You know, shock how
lot of time being indignant.
You know, shock how a
You know, shock how a person
lot of time being indignant.
You know, shock how a person could
You know, shock how a person could say
that
that under
that under these
that under these circumstances.
that under these circumstances. You
that under these circumstances. You say
it's
it's not
that under these circumstances. You say
it's not possible.
it's not possible. It's
that under these circumstances. You say
it's not possible. It's not
it's not possible. It's not possible.
All
All right.
All right. To
All right. To get
All right. To get over
All right. To get over judgmentalism
then
then is
All right. To get over judgmentalism
then is to
then is to accept
All right. To get over judgmentalism
then is to accept that
then is to accept that the
All right. To get over judgmentalism
then is to accept that the world
then is to accept that the world is
All right. To get over judgmentalism
then is to accept that the world is the
way
way it
way it is
way it is because
way it is because it
way it is because it serves
way it is because it serves a
way it is because it serves a tremendous
purpose
purpose being
way it is because it serves a tremendous
purpose being that
purpose being that way.
way it is because it serves a tremendous
purpose being that way. It's
purpose being that way. It's a
way it is because it serves a tremendous
purpose being that way. It's a great
karmic
karmic opportunity
karmic opportunity to
karmic opportunity to be
karmic opportunity to be born
karmic opportunity to be born in
karmic opportunity to be born in this
world
world which
karmic opportunity to be born in this
world which is
world which is in
karmic opportunity to be born in this
world which is in my
world which is in my view
karmic opportunity to be born in this
world which is in my view of
world which is in my view of it
purgatorial
purgatorial in
purgatorial in that
purgatorial in that it
purgatorial in that it goes
purgatorial in that it goes from
purgatorial in that it goes from the
very
very bottom
purgatorial in that it goes from the
very bottom to
very bottom to the
purgatorial in that it goes from the
very bottom to the very
very bottom to the very highest.
purgatorial in that it goes from the
very bottom to the very highest. And
very bottom to the very highest. And the
Buddhist
Buddhist said
Buddhist said fortunate
Buddhist said fortunate one
Buddhist said fortunate one is
to
to have
Buddhist said fortunate one is
to have been
to have been born
Buddhist said fortunate one is
to have been born a
to have been born a human
Buddhist said fortunate one is
to have been born a human being.
to have been born a human being. even
more
more fortunate
uh
uh to
more fortunate
uh to have
uh to have heard
more fortunate
uh to have heard of
uh to have heard of enlightenment
more fortunate
uh to have heard of enlightenment and
even
even rarer
even rarer still
even rarer still to
even rarer still to seek
even rarer still to seek enlightenment
and
and most
even rarer still to seek enlightenment
and most rare
and most rare of
even rarer still to seek enlightenment
and most rare of all
and most rare of all to
even rarer still to seek enlightenment
and most rare of all to have
and most rare of all to have achieved
it.
it. So
it. So we
it. So we become
it. So we become grateful
it. So we become grateful for
it. So we become grateful for our
it. So we become grateful for our human
existence
existence instead
it. So we become grateful for our human
existence instead of
existence instead of be
it. So we become grateful for our human
existence instead of be bewailing
existence instead of be bewailing it.
it. So we become grateful for our human
existence instead of be bewailing it. So
gratitude
gratitude takes
gratitude takes us
gratitude takes us right
gratitude takes us right over
gratitude takes us right over 200
gratitude takes us right over 200 to
begin
begin with.
gratitude takes us right over 200 to
begin with. If
begin with. If this
gratitude takes us right over 200 to
begin with. If this is
begin with. If this is a
gratitude takes us right over 200 to
begin with. If this is a world
begin with. If this is a world of
maximum
maximum opportunity
maximum opportunity for
maximum opportunity for spiritual
maximum opportunity for spiritual growth
and
and development,
maximum opportunity for spiritual growth
and development, then
and development, then there's
maximum opportunity for spiritual growth
and development, then there's some
and development, then there's some part
of
of us
of us should
of us should be
of us should be saying,
of us should be saying, well,
of us should be saying, well, God,
of us should be saying, well, God, I
of us should be saying, well, God, I got
my
my doubts,
of us should be saying, well, God, I got
my doubts, but
my doubts, but I
of us should be saying, well, God, I got
my doubts, but I give
my doubts, but I give thanks
of us should be saying, well, God, I got
my doubts, but I give thanks that
my doubts, but I give thanks that this
is
is a
is a world
is a world in
is a world in which
is a world in which I
is a world in which I can
is a world in which I can experience
is a world in which I can experience and
grow,
grow, where
is a world in which I can experience and
grow, where I
grow, where I have
is a world in which I can experience and
grow, where I have freedom
grow, where I have freedom of
is a world in which I can experience and
grow, where I have freedom of the
grow, where I have freedom of the will.
So,
So, one's
So, one's consciousness
So, one's consciousness level
So, one's consciousness level is
So, one's consciousness level is set
So, one's consciousness level is set by
the
the spiritual
So, one's consciousness level is set by
the spiritual will.
We're
We're constantly
We're constantly presented
We're constantly presented with
We're constantly presented with yes,
We're constantly presented with yes, no,
yes,
yes, no.
We're constantly presented with yes, no,
yes, no. If
yes, no. If you
We're constantly presented with yes, no,
yes, no. If you watch
yes, no. If you watch the
We're constantly presented with yes, no,
yes, no. If you watch the intricacy
yes, no. If you watch the intricacy of
the
the mind's
the mind's operations,
the mind's operations, which
the mind's operations, which I
the mind's operations, which I don't
advise,
advise, but
the mind's operations, which I don't
advise, but if
advise, but if you
the mind's operations, which I don't
advise, but if you do,
you
you see
you see that
you see that it's
you see that it's saying
you see that it's saying yes,
you see that it's saying yes, no
you see that it's saying yes, no every
instant.
instant. Every
you see that it's saying yes, no every
instant. Every instant,
instant. Every instant, it's
you see that it's saying yes, no every
instant. Every instant, it's really
making
making a
making a decision.
making a decision. It's
making a decision. It's really
overwhelming
overwhelming that
making a decision. It's really
overwhelming that it's
overwhelming that it's able
making a decision. It's really
overwhelming that it's able to
overwhelming that it's able to do
making a decision. It's really
overwhelming that it's able to do that.
And
And it
And it does
And it does it
And it does it nonverbally
And it does it nonverbally and
non-linguistically.
But
But you
But you see,
But you see, the
But you see, the arm
But you see, the arm moves
But you see, the arm moves out
But you see, the arm moves out of
But you see, the arm moves out of its
own.
own. Something
But you see, the arm moves out of its
own. Something decided
own. Something decided to
But you see, the arm moves out of its
own. Something decided to move
own. Something decided to move the
But you see, the arm moves out of its
own. Something decided to move the arm
out
out of
out of its
out of its own.
you
you weren't
out of its own.
you weren't even
you weren't even thinking
out of its own.
you weren't even thinking about
you weren't even thinking about it.
out of its own.
you weren't even thinking about it. All
right?
right? So
right? So then
right? So then you
right? So then you run
right? So then you run eventually
right? So then you run eventually into
spontaneity
and
and you
and you begin
and you begin to
and you begin to realize
and you begin to realize everything
and you begin to realize everything is
happening
happening of
and you begin to realize everything is
happening of its
happening of its own.
So
So let's
So let's go
So let's go to
So let's go to the
So let's go to the slide.
So let's go to the slide. Has
So let's go to the slide. Has anybody
got
got any
So let's go to the slide. Has anybody
got any questions
got any questions about
So let's go to the slide. Has anybody
got any questions about this?
got any questions about this? Uh
So let's go to the slide. Has anybody
got any questions about this? Uh the
next
next book
next book I'm
next book I'm going to
next book I'm going to do
next book I'm going to do will
next book I'm going to do will go
next book I'm going to do will go into
each
each one
next book I'm going to do will go into
each one of
each one of these
next book I'm going to do will go into
each one of these more
each one of these more specifically
next book I'm going to do will go into
each one of these more specifically how
to
to transcend
to transcend each
to transcend each level.
to transcend each level. Uh
to transcend each level. Uh the
to transcend each level. Uh the next
book
book is
to transcend each level. Uh the next
book is going
book is going to
to transcend each level. Uh the next
book is going to be
book is going to be written,
to transcend each level. Uh the next
book is going to be written, you
book is going to be written, you know,
almost
almost completely
almost completely for
almost completely for the
almost completely for the spiritual
aspirant.
aspirant. The
almost completely for the spiritual
aspirant. The one
aspirant. The one I'm
almost completely for the spiritual
aspirant. The one I'm finishing
aspirant. The one I'm finishing now
almost completely for the spiritual
aspirant. The one I'm finishing now is
using
using the
using the calibrated
using the calibrated levels
using the calibrated levels of
using the calibrated levels of truth.
You
You know,
using the calibrated levels of truth.
You know, using
You know, using the
using the calibrated levels of truth.
You know, using the calibration
technique,
technique, what
technique, what what
technique, what what do
technique, what what do you
technique, what what do you find
technique, what what do you find if
technique, what what do you find if you
if
if you
technique, what what do you find if you
if you examine
if you examine the
technique, what what do you find if you
if you examine the whole
if you examine the whole world
throughout
throughout all
throughout all of
throughout all of history
throughout all of history and
throughout all of history and all
throughout all of history and all of
human
human conduct,
throughout all of history and all of
human conduct, political
positionalities,
uh
uh possessions,
positionalities,
uh possessions, uh
uh possessions, uh movies.
positionalities,
uh possessions, uh movies. So,
uh possessions, uh movies. So, we'll
positionalities,
uh possessions, uh movies. So, we'll do
movies
movies later
movies later today.
movies later today. Uh
movies later today. Uh we
movies later today. Uh we did
movies later today. Uh we did 200
movies later today. Uh we did 200 movies
and
and uh
movies later today. Uh we did 200 movies
and uh anyway,
and uh anyway, you
movies later today. Uh we did 200 movies
and uh anyway, you don't
and uh anyway, you don't have
movies later today. Uh we did 200 movies
and uh anyway, you don't have to
and uh anyway, you don't have to copy
them
them down
them down because
them down because they'll
them down because they'll be
them down because they'll be on
them down because they'll be on the
book.
book. All
them down because they'll be on the
book. All right.
book. All right. So,
them down because they'll be on the
book. All right. So, I'll
book. All right. So, I'll move
them down because they'll be on the
book. All right. So, I'll move up.
book. All right. So, I'll move up. Move
up.
up. I
up. I thought
up. I thought it
up. I thought it was
up. I thought it was interesting
up. I thought it was interesting because
movies
movies are
up. I thought it was interesting because
movies are very
movies are very big
up. I thought it was interesting because
movies are very big in
movies are very big in our
up. I thought it was interesting because
movies are very big in our in
movies are very big in our in our
up. I thought it was interesting because
movies are very big in our in our world.
These
These are
These are calibrated
These are calibrated levels
These are calibrated levels of
consciousness
consciousness which
These are calibrated levels of
consciousness which George
consciousness which George Serinsky
These are calibrated levels of
consciousness which George Serinsky sent
us.
us. Uh
us. Uh he
us. Uh he recalculated
us. Uh he recalculated the
us. Uh he recalculated the figures
us. Uh he recalculated the figures we
had
had in
us. Uh he recalculated the figures we
had in the
had in the book.
us. Uh he recalculated the figures we
had in the book. The
had in the book. The figures
us. Uh he recalculated the figures we
had in the book. The figures I
had in the book. The figures I had
us. Uh he recalculated the figures we
had in the book. The figures I had in
the
the book
the book about
the book about the
the book about the power
the book about the power of
the book about the power of a
the book about the power of a loving
thought
thought compared
the book about the power of a loving
thought compared to
thought compared to a
the book about the power of a loving
thought compared to a an
thought compared to a an unloving
thought
thought is
thought is something
thought is something like
thought is something like minus
thought is something like minus to
thought is something like minus to the
400 million
versus
versus minus
versus minus something
versus minus something or
versus minus something or other.
versus minus something or other. I'm
versus minus something or other. I'm not
very
very good
versus minus something or other. I'm not
very good at
very good at math.
versus minus something or other. I'm not
very good at math. So
very good at math. So I
versus minus something or other. I'm not
very good at math. So I just
very good at math. So I just did
versus minus something or other. I'm not
very good at math. So I just did it
very good at math. So I just did it with
kinesiology.
That's
That's the
kinesiology.
That's the way
That's the way I
kinesiology.
That's the way I figure
That's the way I figure out
kinesiology.
That's the way I figure out how
That's the way I figure out how much
kinesiology.
That's the way I figure out how much I
owe
owe my
owe my secretary.
We
We say
owe my secretary.
We say I
We say I owe
owe my secretary.
We say I owe you
We say I owe you so
owe my secretary.
We say I owe you so much
We say I owe you so much so
owe my secretary.
We say I owe you so much so much.
We say I owe you so much so much. That's
how
how much
how much I
how much I make
how much I make the
how much I make the check
how much I make the check for.
how much I make the check for. Neither
one
one of
how much I make the check for. Neither
one of us
one of us can
how much I make the check for. Neither
one of us can figure
one of us can figure it
how much I make the check for. Neither
one of us can figure it out.
one of us can figure it out. I
how much I make the check for. Neither
one of us can figure it out. I know.
one of us can figure it out. I know. All
right.
right. So
right. So anyway,
right. So anyway, what
right. So anyway, what George
right. So anyway, what George did
right. So anyway, what George did was
right. So anyway, what George did was he
knows
knows more
right. So anyway, what George did was he
knows more about
knows more about mathematics
right. So anyway, what George did was he
knows more about mathematics and
knows more about mathematics and he
calibrated
calibrated the
calibrated the levels
calibrated the levels of
calibrated the levels of consciousness
uh
uh in
calibrated the levels of consciousness
uh in microwatts
uh in microwatts with
calibrated the levels of consciousness
uh in microwatts with more
uh in microwatts with more advanced
mathematics.
And
And you
mathematics.
And you see
And you see the
mathematics.
And you see the how
And you see the how how
mathematics.
And you see the how how it
And you see the how how it progresses
here
here up
here up to
here up to the
here up to the level
here up to the level of
here up to the level of 100
here up to the level of 100 then
here up to the level of 100 then 200
suddenly
suddenly you
here up to the level of 100 then 200
suddenly you see
suddenly you see a
here up to the level of 100 then 200
suddenly you see a major
suddenly you see a major incline
here up to the level of 100 then 200
suddenly you see a major incline and
suddenly you see a major incline and at
500 you
500 you see
500 you see a
500 you see a very
500 you see a very major
500 you see a very major jump
500 you see a very major jump and
500 you see a very major jump and at
500 you see a very major jump and at 600
of
of course
500 you see a very major jump and at 600
of course you
of course you start
500 you see a very major jump and at 600
of course you start going
of course you start going out
500 you see a very major jump and at 600
of course you start going out to
infinity.
All
All right
infinity.
All right so
All right so we'll
infinity.
All right so we'll go
All right so we'll go to
infinity.
All right so we'll go to the
All right so we'll go to the next
infinity.
All right so we'll go to the next 600
All right so we'll go to the next 600 we
don't
don't say
don't say too
don't say too much
don't say too much about
don't say too much about let's
don't say too much about let's because
it's
it's very
don't say too much about let's because
it's very rare.
it's very rare. All
don't say too much about let's because
it's very rare. All right
it's very rare. All right 250
don't say too much about let's because
it's very rare. All right 250 here
it's very rare. All right 250 here you
here's
here's 78%
here's 78% of
here's 78% of the
here's 78% of the world's
here's 78% of the world's population.
Let's
Let's see
here's 78% of the world's population.
Let's see if
Let's see if that's
here's 78% of the world's population.
Let's see if that's still
Let's see if that's still a
here's 78% of the world's population.
Let's see if that's still a fact
Let's see if that's still a fact because
these
these figures
these figures shift.
these figures shift. We
these figures shift. We have
these figures shift. We have permission
to
to ask
these figures shift. We have permission
to ask that.
to ask that. Of
these figures shift. We have permission
to ask that. Of the
to ask that. Of the world's
these figures shift. We have permission
to ask that. Of the world's population,
totally
78%
78% are
totally
78% are below
78% are below 200.
totally
78% are below 200. Is
78% are below 200. Is this
totally
78% are below 200. Is this 79%.
78%.
All
All right.
78%.
All right. So,
All right. So, it's
78%.
All right. So, it's like
All right. So, it's like the
78%.
All right. So, it's like the temperature
of
of the
of the ocean
of the ocean doesn't
of the ocean doesn't change
of the ocean doesn't change much
of the ocean doesn't change much over
the
the eons.
of the ocean doesn't change much over
the eons. I
the eons. I don't
of the ocean doesn't change much over
the eons. I don't suppose
the eons. I don't suppose the
temperature
temperature of
temperature of today's
temperature of today's ocean
temperature of today's ocean is
temperature of today's ocean is much
different
different than
temperature of today's ocean is much
different than a thousand
different than a thousand years
temperature of today's ocean is much
different than a thousand years ago
different than a thousand years ago or
thousand
thousand years
thousand years before.
So
So 78%
thousand years before.
So 78% of
So 78% of the
thousand years before.
So 78% of the world's
So 78% of the world's population.
thousand years before.
So 78% of the world's population. See,
it's
it's easy
it's easy to
it's easy to do
it's easy to do spiritual
it's easy to do spiritual work
it's easy to do spiritual work if
it's easy to do spiritual work if you
begin
begin to
it's easy to do spiritual work if you
begin to realize
begin to realize who
it's easy to do spiritual work if you
begin to realize who you
begin to realize who you are,
it's easy to do spiritual work if you
begin to realize who you are, how
begin to realize who you are, how you
got
got to
got to be
got to be that
got to be that way,
got to be that way, and
got to be that way, and what
got to be that way, and what is
got to be that way, and what is the
context
context in
got to be that way, and what is the
context in which
context in which you're
got to be that way, and what is the
context in which you're trying
context in which you're trying to
accomplish
accomplish what
accomplish what you're
accomplish what you're trying
accomplish what you're trying to
accomplish.
accomplish. You
accomplish what you're trying to
accomplish. You see,
accomplish. You see, other
accomplish what you're trying to
accomplish. You see, other than
accomplish. You see, other than just
pick picking
pick picking a
pick picking a a
pick picking a a cute
pick picking a a cute book
pick picking a a cute book off
pick picking a a cute book off the
bookshelf
bookshelf and
pick picking a a cute book off the
bookshelf and jumping
bookshelf and jumping into
pick picking a a cute book off the
bookshelf and jumping into it,
bookshelf and jumping into it, uh
pick picking a a cute book off the
bookshelf and jumping into it, uh I
think
think it's
think it's useful
think it's useful to
think it's useful to have
think it's useful to have a
think it's useful to have a total
contextualization
contextualization of
think it's useful to have a total
contextualization of who
contextualization of who you
think it's useful to have a total
contextualization of who you are
contextualization of who you are under
what
what circumstances,
what circumstances, how
what circumstances, how the
what circumstances, how the human
condition
condition got
what circumstances, how the human
condition got to
condition got to be
what circumstances, how the human
condition got to be that
condition got to be that way,
what circumstances, how the human
condition got to be that way, you
condition got to be that way, you know,
because
because if
because if you're
because if you're going
because if you're going to
because if you're going to go
because if you're going to go someplace,
you
you should
because if you're going to go someplace,
you should know
you should know where
because if you're going to go someplace,
you should know where you
you should know where you are
because if you're going to go someplace,
you should know where you are on
you should know where you are on the
map,
map, you
map, you know,
map, you know, to
map, you know, to start
map, you know, to start from.
map, you know, to start from. So,
map, you know, to start from. So, all
right.
right. So,
map, you know, to start from. So, all
right. So, here's
right. So, here's how
map, you know, to start from. So, all
right. So, here's how it
right. So, here's how it balances
map, you know, to start from. So, all
right. So, here's how it balances out.
If
If that
If that is
If that is so,
If that is so, why
If that is so, why doesn't
If that is so, why doesn't the
If that is so, why doesn't the world
blow
blow apart?
If that is so, why doesn't the world
blow apart? It's
blow apart? It's because
If that is so, why doesn't the world
blow apart? It's because the
blow apart? It's because the 15%
If that is so, why doesn't the world
blow apart? It's because the 15% over
200 have
200 have so
200 have so much
200 have so much power.
200 have so much power. This
200 have so much power. This 15%
200 have so much power. This 15% has
enormous
enormous power
200 have so much power. This 15% has
enormous power because
enormous power because those
200 have so much power. This 15% has
enormous power because those are
logarithmic.
logarithmic. The
logarithmic. The power
logarithmic. The power of
logarithmic. The power of the
logarithmic. The power of the 15%
totally
totally counterbalances
logarithmic. The power of the 15%
totally counterbalances the
totally counterbalances the negativity
of
of the
of the 85%.
Yeah.
Otherwise,
that
that which
Otherwise,
that which hates
that which hates all
Otherwise,
that which hates all of
that which hates all of human
Otherwise,
that which hates all of human life,
that which hates all of human life, you
know,
know, that
know, that which
know, that which wants
know, that which wants to
know, that which wants to destroy
know, that which wants to destroy all
know, that which wants to destroy all of
human
human life
know, that which wants to destroy all of
human life except
human life except its
know, that which wants to destroy all of
human life except its own
human life except its own little
know, that which wants to destroy all of
human life except its own little band
human life except its own little band of
people,
if
if you
people,
if you state
if you state the
people,
if you state the truth
if you state the truth about
people,
if you state the truth about it,
if you state the truth about it, it
hates
hates human
hates human life.
H
H never
hates human life.
H never thought
H never thought of
hates human life.
H never thought of that.
H never thought of that. The
hates human life.
H never thought of that. The energy
H never thought of that. The energy of
which
which I'm
which I'm thinking
which I'm thinking that's
which I'm thinking that's coming
which I'm thinking that's coming out
politically
politically hates
which I'm thinking that's coming out
politically hates human
politically hates human life.
which I'm thinking that's coming out
politically hates human life. Resist.
Hates
Hates human
Hates human life.
Hates human life. Not
Hates human life. Not just
Hates human life. Not just infidels.
Hates
Hates human
Hates human life. Not just infidels.
Hates human life.
You
You want
You want to
You want to know
You want to know what
You want to know what it's
You want to know what it's up
You want to know what it's up to?
You want to know what it's up to? It
hates
hates you
You want to know what it's up to? It
hates you in
hates you in life.
You want to know what it's up to? It
hates you in life. And
hates you in life. And all
You want to know what it's up to? It
hates you in life. And all it
hates you in life. And all it does
You want to know what it's up to? It
hates you in life. And all it does is
find
find some
find some rationale
find some rationale to
find some rationale to work
find some rationale to work to
find some rationale to work to express
it.
But
But the
But the hatred
But the hatred there
But the hatred there is
But the hatred there is primary,
But the hatred there is primary, not
secondary.
The
The hatred
The hatred there
The hatred there is
The hatred there is primary.
It's
It's primary,
The hatred there is primary.
It's primary, folks.
It's primary, folks. Not
The hatred there is primary.
It's primary, folks. Not something
It's primary, folks. Not something you
did,
did, not
did, not something
did, not something America
did, not something America did,
did, not something America did, not
something
something George
did, not something America did, not
something George Bush
something George Bush did,
did, not something America did, not
something George Bush did, not
something George Bush did, not something
the
the Iranians
the Iranians did,
not
not something
the Iranians did,
not something that
not something that the
the Iranians did,
not something that the oil
not something that the oil cartel
the Iranians did,
not something that the oil cartel did.
They
They are
They are that
They are that way
They are that way and
They are that way and then
They are that way and then they
They are that way and then they find
They are that way and then they find a
rationale
rationale to
They are that way and then they find a
rationale to make
rationale to make it
They are that way and then they find a
rationale to make it seem
rationale to make it seem plausible
They are that way and then they find a
rationale to make it seem plausible and
get
get followers.
It's
It's like
get followers.
It's like you
It's like you start
get followers.
It's like you start out
It's like you start out hating
get followers.
It's like you start out hating somebody
and
and now
and now you
and now you find
and now you find reasons
and now you find reasons and
and now you find reasons and excuses
and now you find reasons and excuses to
justify
justify it.
and now you find reasons and excuses to
justify it. Well,
justify it. Well, her
and now you find reasons and excuses to
justify it. Well, her hair
justify it. Well, her hair looks
and now you find reasons and excuses to
justify it. Well, her hair looks funny
and
and her
and her nose
and her nose is
and her nose is wide
and her nose is wide and
and her nose is wide and her
and her nose is wide and her feet
and her nose is wide and her feet are
too
too fat.
and her nose is wide and her feet are
too fat. I
too fat. I mean,
and her nose is wide and her feet are
too fat. I mean, now
too fat. I mean, now you
and her nose is wide and her feet are
too fat. I mean, now you start
No,
No, the
No, the truth
No, the truth is
No, the truth is you
No, the truth is you started
No, the truth is you started out
No, the truth is you started out with
hate.
hate. So,
to
to cross
to cross over
to cross over 200,
to cross over 200, you
to cross over 200, you would
to cross over 200, you would have
to cross over 200, you would have to
to cross over 200, you would have to own
that
that you
to cross over 200, you would have to own
that you started
that you started with
to cross over 200, you would have to own
that you started with hate
that you started with hate and
to cross over 200, you would have to own
that you started with hate and now
you're
you're just
you're just trying
you're just trying to
you're just trying to justify
you're just trying to justify it,
you're just trying to justify it, find
reasons
reasons for
you're just trying to justify it, find
reasons for expression,
reasons for expression, etc.
But
But the
But the hatred
But the hatred was
But the hatred was there
But the hatred was there primary.
But the hatred was there primary. Let's
do
do that
But the hatred was there primary. Let's
do that again.
The
The hatred
The hatred we're
The hatred we're experiencing
The hatred we're experiencing in
The hatred we're experiencing in the
world
world today
The hatred we're experiencing in the
world today preexisted.
Pre-existed
Pre-existed all
Pre-existed all the
Pre-existed all the phenomena
Pre-existed all the phenomena exist.
It
It preexisted
Pre-existed all the phenomena exist.
It preexisted all
It preexisted all the
Pre-existed all the phenomena exist.
It preexisted all the phenomena.
That's
That's that
That's that solves
That's that solves a
That's that solves a lot
That's that solves a lot of
That's that solves a lot of things,
doesn't
doesn't it?
That's that solves a lot of things,
doesn't it? It
doesn't it? It pre-existed.
That's that solves a lot of things,
doesn't it? It pre-existed. Pre-existed.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So we
All right. So we have
All right. So we have a
All right. So we have a dualistic
All right. So we have a dualistic ego
which
which we've
All right. So we have a dualistic ego
which we've just
which we've just talked
All right. So we have a dualistic ego
which we've just talked about
which we've just talked about before
that
that tends
that tends to
that tends to separate
that tends to separate things
that tends to separate things into
that tends to separate things into good
and
and evil.
that tends to separate things into good
and evil. That's
and evil. That's the
that tends to separate things into good
and evil. That's the other
and evil. That's the other trouble
that tends to separate things into good
and evil. That's the other trouble with
the
the calibrated
the calibrated levels
the calibrated levels of
the calibrated levels of consciousness
is
is the
the calibrated levels of consciousness
is the mind
is the mind tends
the calibrated levels of consciousness
is the mind tends to
is the mind tends to think
the calibrated levels of consciousness
is the mind tends to think about
is the mind tends to think about the
good
good is
good is 200
good is 200 and
good is 200 and over
good is 200 and over and
good is 200 and over and the
good is 200 and over and the bad
good is 200 and over and the bad is
good is 200 and over and the bad is 200
below.
below. And
good is 200 and over and the bad is 200
below. And that
below. And that is
good is 200 and over and the bad is 200
below. And that is a
below. And that is a problem
good is 200 and over and the bad is 200
below. And that is a problem you
below. And that is a problem you do
good is 200 and over and the bad is 200
below. And that is a problem you do have
to
to transcend.
to transcend. Yes,
it
it isn't
to transcend. Yes,
it isn't that
it isn't that it's
to transcend. Yes,
it isn't that it's good
it isn't that it's good versus
to transcend. Yes,
it isn't that it's good versus evil.
It's
It's that
It's that which
It's that which is
It's that which is more
It's that which is more evolved
It's that which is more evolved in
contrast
contrast to
It's that which is more evolved in
contrast to that
contrast to that which
It's that which is more evolved in
contrast to that which is
contrast to that which is less
It's that which is more evolved in
contrast to that which is less evolved.
that
that which
that which calibrates
that which calibrates at
that which calibrates at 35
which
which was
that which calibrates at 35
which was present
which was present as
that which calibrates at 35
which was present as life
which was present as life on
that which calibrates at 35
which was present as life on this
planet.
planet. The
the
the age
planet. The
the age of
the age of the
planet. The
the age of the reptiles,
the
the Komodo
the Komodo dragon
historically
historically still
the Komodo dragon
historically still exists.
historically still exists. It
the Komodo dragon
historically still exists. It didn't
disappear
disappear and
disappear and get
disappear and get replaced
disappear and get replaced by
disappear and get replaced by something
better.
better. It's
disappear and get replaced by something
better. It's still
better. It's still here.
disappear and get replaced by something
better. It's still here. Still
better. It's still here. Still here.
Okay.
All right.
All right. So
Okay.
All right. So we
All right. So we don't
Okay.
All right. So we don't want
All right. So we don't want to
Okay.
All right. So we don't want to say
All right. So we don't want to say this
is
is good
is good this
is good this is
is good this is bad.
is good this is bad. So
is good this is bad. So how
is good this is bad. So how should
is good this is bad. So how should we
see
see it?
is good this is bad. So how should we
see it? We'll
see it? We'll see
is good this is bad. So how should we
see it? We'll see things
see it? We'll see things are
is good this is bad. So how should we
see it? We'll see things are more
evolved
evolved or
evolved or less
evolved or less evolved.
evolved or less evolved. The
evolved or less evolved. The only
evolved or less evolved. The only one
thing
thing that
evolved or less evolved. The only one
thing that is
thing that is on
evolved or less evolved. The only one
thing that is on the
thing that is on the calibrated
evolved or less evolved. The only one
thing that is on the calibrated level
thing that is on the calibrated level of
consciousness
consciousness is
consciousness is degree
consciousness is degree of
consciousness is degree of evolution.
The
The degree
consciousness is degree of evolution.
The degree of
The degree of evolution
consciousness is degree of evolution.
The degree of evolution up
The degree of evolution up goes
consciousness is degree of evolution.
The degree of evolution up goes up
The degree of evolution up goes up this
way
way or
way or down
way or down this
way or down this way.
way or down this way. So
way or down this way. So we
way or down this way. So we see
way or down this way. So we see that
way or down this way. So we see that 85%
of
of the
way or down this way. So we see that 85%
of the people
of the people on
way or down this way. So we see that 85%
of the people on the
of the people on the planet
way or down this way. So we see that 85%
of the people on the planet have
of the people on the planet have not
evolved
evolved to
evolved to the
evolved to the point
evolved to the point of
evolved to the point of the
evolved to the point of the willingness
to
to own
evolved to the point of the willingness
to own the
to own the truth.
evolved to the point of the willingness
to own the truth. Huh?
to own the truth. Huh? Honesty,
integrity,
integrity, huh?
integrity, huh? The
integrity, huh? The courage
integrity, huh? The courage to
integrity, huh? The courage to face
integrity, huh? The courage to face the
truth.
H
we'll
we'll use
H
we'll use other
we'll use other examples
H
we'll use other examples that
we'll use other examples that are
common.
common. We
common. We should
common. We should get
common. We should get some
common. We should get some new
common. We should get some new slides
because
because you've
common. We should get some new slides
because you've seen
because you've seen some
common. We should get some new slides
because you've seen some of
because you've seen some of these
before.
before. And
before. And that
before. And that is
before. And that is the
before. And that is the presence
before. And that is the presence or
before. And that is the presence or the
absence
absence of
before. And that is the presence or the
absence of heat.
absence of heat. There's
before. And that is the presence or the
absence of heat. There's not
absence of heat. There's not heat
before. And that is the presence or the
absence of heat. There's not heat versus
cold.
cold. There's
cold. There's either
cold. There's either heat
cold. There's either heat and
cold. There's either heat and there's
varying
varying degrees
cold. There's either heat and there's
varying degrees of
varying degrees of heat.
cold. There's either heat and there's
varying degrees of heat. This
varying degrees of heat. This is
cold. There's either heat and there's
varying degrees of heat. This is lots
varying degrees of heat. This is lots of
heat
heat and
heat and this
heat and this is
heat and this is less
heat and this is less heat.
heat and this is less heat. But
heat and this is less heat. But they're
not
not opposites.
heat and this is less heat. But they're
not opposites. This
not opposites. This is
heat and this is less heat. But they're
not opposites. This is desiraability.
This
This you
This you really
This you really want
This you really want it
This you really want it a
This you really want it a lot.
This you really want it a lot. You
This you really want it a lot. You say
it's
it's precious.
This you really want it a lot. You say
it's precious. And
it's precious. And if
This you really want it a lot. You say
it's precious. And if you
it's precious. And if you think
This you really want it a lot. You say
it's precious. And if you think it's
ugly,
ugly, you
ugly, you call
ugly, you call it
ugly, you call it call
ugly, you call it call it
ugly, you call it call it awful.
ugly, you call it call it awful. Huh?
Then
Then the
ugly, you call it call it awful. Huh?
Then the mind
Then the mind makes
ugly, you call it call it awful. Huh?
Then the mind makes the
Then the mind makes the mistake
ugly, you call it call it awful. Huh?
Then the mind makes the mistake of
rejecting
rejecting it
rejecting it into
rejecting it into the
rejecting it into the world
rejecting it into the world and
rejecting it into the world and saying
it
it is
rejecting it into the world and saying
it is awful.
it is awful. No,
rejecting it into the world and saying
it is awful. No, you
it is awful. No, you see
rejecting it into the world and saying
it is awful. No, you see it
it is awful. No, you see it as
rejecting it into the world and saying
it is awful. No, you see it as awful.
it is awful. No, you see it as awful. It
is
is neither
is neither awful
is neither awful nor
is neither awful nor not
is neither awful nor not awful.
is neither awful nor not awful. So
is neither awful nor not awful. So the
big
big mistake
is neither awful nor not awful. So the
big mistake the
big mistake the ego
is neither awful nor not awful. So the
big mistake the ego makes
big mistake the ego makes is
to
to confuse
to confuse rest
to confuse rest interna
to confuse rest interna with
to confuse rest interna with rest
externa.
externa. the
to confuse rest interna with rest
externa. the Latin
externa. the Latin for
that
that which
that which is
that which is within
that which is within the
that which is within the mind
that which is within the mind and
that which is within the mind and that
which
which is
that which is within the mind and that
which is in
which is in nature
that which is within the mind and that
which is in nature in
which is in nature in the
that which is within the mind and that
which is in nature in the world
which is in nature in the world and
that which is within the mind and that
which is in nature in the world and to
confuse
confuse that
confuse that how
confuse that how I
confuse that how I see
confuse that how I see it
confuse that how I see it is
confuse that how I see it is how
confuse that how I see it is how the
world
world is
confuse that how I see it is how the
world is how
world is how you
confuse that how I see it is how the
world is how you see
world is how you see it
confuse that how I see it is how the
world is how you see it is
world is how you see it is how
confuse that how I see it is how the
world is how you see it is how you
world is how you see it is how you see
it
it you
it you should
it you should stop
it you should stop there
the
the false
it you should stop there
the false is
the false is to
it you should stop there
the false is to say
the false is to say therefore
it you should stop there
the false is to say therefore that's
the false is to say therefore that's the
way
way the
way the world
way the world is
way the world is no
way the world is no okay
way the world is no okay I
way the world is no okay I see
way the world is no okay I see something
as
as such
way the world is no okay I see something
as such so
as such so if
way the world is no okay I see something
as such so if you
as such so if you own
way the world is no okay I see something
as such so if you own that
as such so if you own that then
way the world is no okay I see something
as such so if you own that then you're
integrous
integrous is
integrous is if
integrous is if you
integrous is if you jump
integrous is if you jump and
integrous is if you jump and say
integrous is if you jump and say because
I
I see
integrous is if you jump and say because
I see it
I see it that
integrous is if you jump and say because
I see it that way
I see it that way that's
integrous is if you jump and say because
I see it that way that's the
I see it that way that's the way
integrous is if you jump and say because
I see it that way that's the way the
world
world is
world is that
world is that is
world is that is not
world is that is not onism.
world is that is not onism. All right.
So
So that
world is that is not onism. All right.
So that distinction
So that distinction of
world is that is not onism. All right.
So that distinction of course
So that distinction of course is
world is that is not onism. All right.
So that distinction of course is very
famous
famous in
famous in philosophic
famous in philosophic history.
famous in philosophic history. All
right.
right. So
famous in philosophic history. All
right. So the
right. So the next
famous in philosophic history. All
right. So the next one
right. So the next one we
famous in philosophic history. All
right. So the next one we got
right. So the next one we got is
desiraability.
desiraability. Again
desiraability. Again we
desiraability. Again we say
desiraability. Again we say it's
heavenly.
heavenly. It's
desiraability. Again we say it's
heavenly. It's wonderful.
heavenly. It's wonderful. So,
desiraability. Again we say it's
heavenly. It's wonderful. So, we
heavenly. It's wonderful. So, we look
desiraability. Again we say it's
heavenly. It's wonderful. So, we look at
the
the calibrated
the calibrated scale
the calibrated scale of
the calibrated scale of consciousness
just
just like
the calibrated scale of consciousness
just like we
just like we do
the calibrated scale of consciousness
just like we do every
just like we do every night's
the calibrated scale of consciousness
just like we do every night's TV
just like we do every night's TV news
and
and we
and we say,
and we say, "Isn't
and we say, "Isn't that
and we say, "Isn't that horrible?
and we say, "Isn't that horrible? Isn't
that
that ghastly?
and we say, "Isn't that horrible? Isn't
that ghastly? Isn't
that ghastly? Isn't that
and we say, "Isn't that horrible? Isn't
that ghastly? Isn't that wicked?
that ghastly? Isn't that wicked? Isn't
that
that bad?
that bad? And
that bad? And isn't
that bad? And isn't this
that bad? And isn't this person
wonderful?
wonderful? And
that bad? And isn't this person
wonderful? And this
wonderful? And this is
that bad? And isn't this person
wonderful? And this is good.
wonderful? And this is good. This
that bad? And isn't this person
wonderful? And this is good. This is
very
very good."
So,
So, that
very good."
So, that judgmentalism
So, that judgmentalism then
very good."
So, that judgmentalism then is
So, that judgmentalism then is a
projection
projection is
projection is a
projection is a projection.
projection is a projection. Oh,
projection is a projection. Oh, you
projection is a projection. Oh, you got
it
it to
projection is a projection. Oh, you got
it to work.
>> Is
>> Is a
>> Is a projection
>> Is a projection of
>> Is a projection of the
>> Is a projection of the ego.
All
All right.
Psychoanalysis,
Psychoanalysis, you
Psychoanalysis, you know,
is
is one
Psychoanalysis, you know,
is one place
is one place you
Psychoanalysis, you know,
is one place you learn
is one place you learn that
Psychoanalysis, you know,
is one place you learn that quickly.
is one place you learn that quickly. You
know,
know, the
know, the theorists
know, the theorists who
know, the theorists who reject
psychoanalysis,
I
I tell
I tell them,
I tell them, "Yeah,
I tell them, "Yeah, right.
I tell them, "Yeah, right. You
I tell them, "Yeah, right. You go
I tell them, "Yeah, right. You go lay
down
down an
I tell them, "Yeah, right. You go lay
down an analyst
down an analyst couch
I tell them, "Yeah, right. You go lay
down an analyst couch an
down an analyst couch an hour
I tell them, "Yeah, right. You go lay
down an analyst couch an hour hour
down an analyst couch an hour hour a
day,
day, five
day, five days
day, five days a
day, five days a week
day, five days a week for
day, five days a week for a
day, five days a week for a couple
day, five days a week for a couple years
and
and see
day, five days a week for a couple years
and see what
and see what comes
day, five days a week for a couple years
and see what comes up."
If
If you
If you don't
If you don't think
If you don't think you
If you don't think you got
If you don't think you got an
unconscious,
unconscious, so
things
things are
things are seen
things are seen as
things are seen as heavenly,
things are seen as heavenly, very
things are seen as heavenly, very good.
These
These are
things are seen as heavenly, very good.
These are all
These are all projections.
The
The first
The first thing
The first thing that
The first thing that happens
when
when you
The first thing that happens
when you go
when you go to
The first thing that happens
when you go to lay
when you go to lay down
The first thing that happens
when you go to lay down on
when you go to lay down on the
The first thing that happens
when you go to lay down on the analyst
couch
couch is
couch is instantly
couch is instantly because
couch is instantly because he
couch is instantly because he just
couch is instantly because he just sits
there
there and
couch is instantly because he just sits
there and says
there and says nothing.
couch is instantly because he just sits
there and says nothing. He's
there and says nothing. He's not
couch is instantly because he just sits
there and says nothing. He's not saying
anything.
anything. Got
anything. Got a
anything. Got a pad
anything. Got a pad of
anything. Got a pad of paper
anything. Got a pad of paper just
anything. Got a pad of paper just like
in
in the
anything. Got a pad of paper just like
in the cartoon.
in the cartoon. How
anything. Got a pad of paper just like
in the cartoon. How many
in the cartoon. How many people
anything. Got a pad of paper just like
in the cartoon. How many people have
been
been in
been in psychoanalysis?
Yeah.
Yeah. Okay.
been in psychoanalysis?
Yeah. Okay. You
Yeah. Okay. You know,
been in psychoanalysis?
Yeah. Okay. You know, he
Yeah. Okay. You know, he just
been in psychoanalysis?
Yeah. Okay. You know, he just lays
there.
there. You
there. You just
there. You just leave
there. You just leave there
there. You just leave there and
there. You just leave there and uh
instantly
instantly you
there. You just leave there and uh
instantly you find
instantly you find it's
there. You just leave there and uh
instantly you find it's difficult
instantly you find it's difficult to
talk.
talk. You're
talk. You're wondering
talk. You're wondering what
talk. You're wondering what he
talk. You're wondering what he thinks
about
about you.
talk. You're wondering what he thinks
about you. You
about you. You presume
talk. You're wondering what he thinks
about you. You presume he's
about you. You presume he's thinking
this.
this. He
this. He thinks
this. He thinks you're
this. He thinks you're stupid.
this. He thinks you're stupid. If
this. He thinks you're stupid. If I
this. He thinks you're stupid. If I say
this,
this, he's
this. He thinks you're stupid. If I say
this, he's going
this, he's going to
this. He thinks you're stupid. If I say
this, he's going to think
this, he's going to think I'm
this. He thinks you're stupid. If I say
this, he's going to think I'm six
pervert.
pervert. I
pervert. I mean,
pervert. I mean, you
pervert. I mean, you know,
pervert. I mean, you know, all
pervert. I mean, you know, all the
pervert. I mean, you know, all the crap
comes
comes up
pervert. I mean, you know, all the crap
comes up like
comes up like this.
pervert. I mean, you know, all the crap
comes up like this. People
comes up like this. People say
pervert. I mean, you know, all the crap
comes up like this. People say they
don't
don't believe
don't believe in
don't believe in psychoanalysis.
don't believe in psychoanalysis. I
don't believe in psychoanalysis. I say,
"Yeah,
"Yeah, right.
don't believe in psychoanalysis. I say,
"Yeah, right. You
"Yeah, right. You need
don't believe in psychoanalysis. I say,
"Yeah, right. You need a
"Yeah, right. You need a doctor."
Anyway,
Anyway, one
Anyway, one one
Anyway, one one value
Anyway, one one value is
Anyway, one one value is you're
Anyway, one one value is you're getting
over
over you
Anyway, one one value is you're getting
over you get
over you get over
Anyway, one one value is you're getting
over you get over being
over you get over being judgmental
because
because you
because you see
because you see it
because you see it comes
because you see it comes out
because you see it comes out of
because you see it comes out of like
nowhere.
nowhere. It's
because you see it comes out of like
nowhere. It's like
nowhere. It's like instinctual.
because you see it comes out of like
nowhere. It's like instinctual. You
don't
don't even
don't even know
don't even know this
don't even know this guy
don't even know this guy and
don't even know this guy and already
don't even know this guy and already you
got
got a
don't even know this guy and already you
got a whole
got a whole program
don't even know this guy and already you
got a whole program you're
got a whole program you're projecting
don't even know this guy and already you
got a whole program you're projecting on
to
to him.
to him. He
to him. He won't
to him. He won't like
to him. He won't like me
to him. He won't like me because
to him. He won't like me because of
to him. He won't like me because of so
and
and so,
to him. He won't like me because of so
and so, uh,
and so, uh, etc.
The
The other
The other duality
The other duality is
The other duality is light
The other duality is light versus
The other duality is light versus dark.
So
So once
The other duality is light versus dark.
So once once
So once once we
The other duality is light versus dark.
So once once we get
So once once we get this
The other duality is light versus dark.
So once once we get this principle
So once once we get this principle down,
we're
we're going
we're going to
we're going to replace
we're going to replace these
we're going to replace these slides,
we're going to replace these slides, but
I
I use
we're going to replace these slides, but
I use these
I use these out
we're going to replace these slides, but
I use these out of
I use these out of town.
we're going to replace these slides, but
I use these out of town. So
either
either light
either light is
either light is very
either light is very There's
either light is very There's a
either light is very There's a lot
either light is very There's a lot of
light
light up
either light is very There's a lot of
light up at
light up at the
either light is very There's a lot of
light up at the top
light up at the top or
either light is very There's a lot of
light up at the top or light
light up at the top or light is
either light is very There's a lot of
light up at the top or light is absent.
But
But there
But there is
But there is no
But there is no such
But there is no such thing
But there is no such thing as
But there is no such thing as light
But there is no such thing as light and
darkness
darkness being
But there is no such thing as light and
darkness being opposites.
Just
Just like
Just like nonspace
Just like nonspace has
Just like nonspace has no
Just like nonspace has no existence.
It's
It's important
Just like nonspace has no existence.
It's important to
It's important to the
Just like nonspace has no existence.
It's important to the kinesiologic
It's important to the kinesiologic test
because
because what
because what the
because what the test
because what the test merely
because what the test merely tests
because what the test merely tests is
whether
whether a
because what the test merely tests is
whether a thing
whether a thing is
because what the test merely tests is
whether a thing is true.
whether a thing is true. That's
because what the test merely tests is
whether a thing is true. That's all.
whether a thing is true. That's all. It
doesn't
doesn't test
doesn't test true
doesn't test true versus
doesn't test true versus false.
doesn't test true versus false. It
doesn't test true versus false. It only
tests
tests true.
the
the light
the light either
the light either goes
the light either goes on
the light either goes on or
the light either goes on or the
the light either goes on or the light
does
does not
the light either goes on or the light
does not go
does not go on.
the light either goes on or the light
does not go on. So
does not go on. So if
the light either goes on or the light
does not go on. So if what
does not go on. So if what I'm
the light either goes on or the light
does not go on. So if what I'm holding
in
in mind
in mind and
in mind and I
in mind and I don't
in mind and I don't have
in mind and I don't have to
in mind and I don't have to tell
in mind and I don't have to tell it
in mind and I don't have to tell it to
her
her verbally,
in mind and I don't have to tell it to
her verbally, I
her verbally, I don't
in mind and I don't have to tell it to
her verbally, I don't have
her verbally, I don't have to
in mind and I don't have to tell it to
her verbally, I don't have to tell
her verbally, I don't have to tell her
verbally
verbally what
verbally what I'm
verbally what I'm holding
verbally what I'm holding in
verbally what I'm holding in mind.
verbally what I'm holding in mind. I
verbally what I'm holding in mind. I can
just
just say
verbally what I'm holding in mind. I can
just say what
just say what I'm
verbally what I'm holding in mind. I can
just say what I'm holding
just say what I'm holding in
verbally what I'm holding in mind. I can
just say what I'm holding in mind
just say what I'm holding in mind is
true
true or
true or calibrates
true or calibrates over
true or calibrates over 200.
true or calibrates over 200. That's
true or calibrates over 200. That's how
the
the test
true or calibrates over 200. That's how
the test is
the test is done.
However,
However, the
However, the people
However, the people who
However, the people who do
However, the people who do the
However, the people who do the tests
have
have themselves
However, the people who do the tests
have themselves have
have themselves have to
However, the people who do the tests
have themselves have to calibrate
have themselves have to calibrate 200
However, the people who do the tests
have themselves have to calibrate 200 or
over
over and
over and the
over and the intention
over and the intention intention
over and the intention intention of
over and the intention intention of the
question
question has
over and the intention intention of the
question has to
question has to be
over and the intention intention of the
question has to be integrous.
question has to be integrous. So
over and the intention intention of the
question has to be integrous. So you
can't
can't use
can't use it
can't use it for,
can't use it for, you
can't use it for, you know,
can't use it for, you know, self-s
serving
serving needs.
can't use it for, you know, self-s
serving needs. When
serving needs. When I
can't use it for, you know, self-s
serving needs. When I wrote
serving needs. When I wrote par's
can't use it for, you know, self-s
serving needs. When I wrote par's first,
I
I thought
I thought everybody
I thought everybody could
I thought everybody could use
I thought everybody could use it.
I thought everybody could use it. I
I thought everybody could use it. I was
very
very naive
I thought everybody could use it. I was
very naive at
very naive at the
I thought everybody could use it. I was
very naive at the time.
very naive at the time. I
I thought everybody could use it. I was
very naive at the time. I thought,
very naive at the time. I thought, oh
I thought everybody could use it. I was
very naive at the time. I thought, oh my
god,
god, everybody,
god, everybody, everybody
god, everybody, everybody can
god, everybody, everybody can use
god, everybody, everybody can use it.
And
And then
god, everybody, everybody can use it.
And then I
And then I discovered,
god, everybody, everybody can use it.
And then I discovered, no,
And then I discovered, no, that
god, everybody, everybody can use it.
And then I discovered, no, that is
And then I discovered, no, that is not
so.
so. It's
so. It's only
so. It's only the
so. It's only the people
so. It's only the people who
so. It's only the people who have
already
already committed
so. It's only the people who have
already committed themselves
already committed themselves to
so. It's only the people who have
already committed themselves to wanting
to
to know
to know the
to know the truth
to know the truth for
to know the truth for its
to know the truth for its own
to know the truth for its own sake.
to know the truth for its own sake. So
the
the willingness
to know the truth for its own sake. So
the willingness to
the willingness to let
to know the truth for its own sake. So
the willingness to let go
the willingness to let go of
positionality
and
and instead
positionality
and instead align
and instead align oneself
positionality
and instead align oneself with
and instead align oneself with truth
takes
takes one
takes one rapidly
takes one rapidly to
takes one rapidly to God
takes one rapidly to God rapidly.
All right.
All right. So
takes one rapidly to God rapidly.
All right. So we
All right. So we said
takes one rapidly to God rapidly.
All right. So we said that
All right. So we said that the
takes one rapidly to God rapidly.
All right. So we said that the mind
All right. So we said that the mind all
right
right we
right we did
right we did the
right we did the mind
right we did the mind before.
right we did the mind before. The
right we did the mind before. The mind
then
then is
right we did the mind before. The mind
then is the
then is the field
right we did the mind before. The mind
then is the field in
then is the field in which
right we did the mind before. The mind
then is the field in which all
then is the field in which all this
right we did the mind before. The mind
then is the field in which all this uh
hypothesis
hypothesis goes
hypothesis goes on.
hypothesis goes on. So
hypothesis goes on. So the
hypothesis goes on. So the ego
hypothesis goes on. So the ego then
begins
begins to
hypothesis goes on. So the ego then
begins to dominate
begins to dominate not
hypothesis goes on. So the ego then
begins to dominate not just
begins to dominate not just feelings
hypothesis goes on. So the ego then
begins to dominate not just feelings but
our
our thoughts
our thoughts about
our thoughts about things.
The
The way
our thoughts about things.
The way to
The way to overcome
our thoughts about things.
The way to overcome and
The way to overcome and transcend
feelings
feelings then
feelings then is
feelings then is to
feelings then is to let
feelings then is to let go
feelings then is to let go the
positionality
positionality which
feelings then is to let go the
positionality which underlies
positionality which underlies a
particular
particular feeling.
particular feeling. And
particular feeling. And we
particular feeling. And we find
particular feeling. And we find that
feelings
feelings are
particular feeling. And we find that
feelings are linked
feelings are linked together.
particular feeling. And we find that
feelings are linked together. You're
angry
angry when
angry when you
angry when you say
angry when you say well
angry when you say well why
angry when you say well why am
angry when you say well why am I
angry when you say well why am I angry?
I'm
I'm angry
angry when you say well why am I angry?
I'm angry because
I'm angry because I
angry when you say well why am I angry?
I'm angry because I was
I'm angry because I was insulted.
angry when you say well why am I angry?
I'm angry because I was insulted. Well
that's
that's pride
that's pride right?
And
And why
that's pride right?
And why was
And why was I
that's pride right?
And why was I was
And why was I was insulted?
that's pride right?
And why was I was insulted? Because
And why was I was insulted? Because I
expected
expected to
expected to be
expected to be applauded
expected to be applauded or
expected to be applauded or agreed
expected to be applauded or agreed with
and
and I
expected to be applauded or agreed with
and I wasn't.
and I wasn't. So
expected to be applauded or agreed with
and I wasn't. So that
and I wasn't. So that was
expected to be applauded or agreed with
and I wasn't. So that was looking
and I wasn't. So that was looking for
gain,
gain, wanting
gain, wanting everybody
gain, wanting everybody to
gain, wanting everybody to agree
gain, wanting everybody to agree with
you.
you. And
gain, wanting everybody to agree with
you. And that
you. And that is
gain, wanting everybody to agree with
you. And that is coming
you. And that is coming from
gain, wanting everybody to agree with
you. And that is coming from control.
you. And that is coming from control. So
you
you see
you see how
you see how they're
you see how they're all
you see how they're all linked
you see how they're all linked together.
Therefore,
Therefore, you
you see how they're all linked together.
Therefore, you can
Therefore, you can unravel
you see how they're all linked together.
Therefore, you can unravel the
Therefore, you can unravel the ego
you see how they're all linked together.
Therefore, you can unravel the ego like
a
a sweater
a sweater with
a sweater with a
a sweater with a yarn.
a sweater with a yarn. You
a sweater with a yarn. You just
a sweater with a yarn. You just start
pulling
pulling the
a sweater with a yarn. You just start
pulling the yarn
pulling the yarn here
a sweater with a yarn. You just start
pulling the yarn here and
pulling the yarn here and the
a sweater with a yarn. You just start
pulling the yarn here and the whole
pulling the yarn here and the whole ego
will
will disintegrate.
will disintegrate. The
will disintegrate. The whole
will disintegrate. The whole ego
will disintegrate. The whole ego will
disintegrate.
Its
Its structure
Its structure is
Its structure is not
Its structure is not based
Its structure is not based on
Its structure is not based on truth.
But
But on
Its structure is not based on truth.
But on a
But on a fallacy
Its structure is not based on truth.
But on a fallacy that
the
the laws
the laws of
the laws of life
the laws of life which
the laws of life which dominated
the laws of life which dominated early
primitive
primitive life
the laws of life which dominated early
primitive life in
primitive life in its
the laws of life which dominated early
primitive life in its earliest
primitive life in its earliest forms
is
is the
is the same
is the same law
is the same law that
is the same law that humans
is the same law that humans have
is the same law that humans have to
is the same law that humans have to live
by.
by. They
is the same law that humans have to live
by. They do
by. They do up
is the same law that humans have to live
by. They do up to
by. They do up to 200
is the same law that humans have to live
by. They do up to 200 but
by. They do up to 200 but beyond
is the same law that humans have to live
by. They do up to 200 but beyond 200
then
then they
then they begin
then they begin to
then they begin to transcend
then they begin to transcend that.
then they begin to transcend that. So
we're
we're here
then they begin to transcend that. So
we're here to
we're here to escape
then they begin to transcend that. So
we're here to escape the
we're here to escape the dominance
then they begin to transcend that. So
we're here to escape the dominance of
the
the ego
the ego which
the ego which is
the ego which is a
the ego which is a characteristic
the ego which is a characteristic of
the ego which is a characteristic of the
animal
animal kingdom.
And
And I
And I brought
And I brought my
And I brought my animal
And I brought my animal with
And I brought my animal with me
And I brought my animal with me again.
And I brought my animal with me again. I
almost
almost forgot
And I brought my animal with me again. I
almost forgot my
almost forgot my animal.
And
And I
And I advise
And I advise everybody
And I advise everybody to
And I advise everybody to have
And I advise everybody to have an
And I advise everybody to have an animal
that
that represents
And I advise everybody to have an animal
that represents their
that represents their ego,
And I advise everybody to have an animal
that represents their ego, which
that represents their ego, which is
greedy.
greedy. Yes.
greedy. Yes. Selfish,
wants
wants more,
greedy. Yes. Selfish,
wants more, hates
wants more, hates people,
wants
wants to
wants to get
wants to get even.
Your
Your ego
wants to get even.
Your ego is
Your ego is doing
wants to get even.
Your ego is doing what
Your ego is doing what it's
wants to get even.
Your ego is doing what it's supposed
Your ego is doing what it's supposed to
do.
do. Folks,
do. Folks, there's
do. Folks, there's no
do. Folks, there's no point
do. Folks, there's no point to
do. Folks, there's no point to feel
guilt
guilt about
do. Folks, there's no point to feel
guilt about greed.
guilt about greed. It's
do. Folks, there's no point to feel
guilt about greed. It's doing
guilt about greed. It's doing what
do. Folks, there's no point to feel
guilt about greed. It's doing what it
thinks
thinks it's
thinks it's supposed
thinks it's supposed to
thinks it's supposed to do.
The
The squirrel's
thinks it's supposed to do.
The squirrel's ego
The squirrel's ego wants
thinks it's supposed to do.
The squirrel's ego wants more
The squirrel's ego wants more and
thinks it's supposed to do.
The squirrel's ego wants more and more
nuts.
Tons
Tons of
nuts.
Tons of them.
If
If I
If I brought
If I brought in
If I brought in a
If I brought in a truck
If I brought in a truck and
If I brought in a truck and unloaded
If I brought in a truck and unloaded a
bunch
bunch of
If I brought in a truck and unloaded a
bunch of nuts,
bunch of nuts, you
If I brought in a truck and unloaded a
bunch of nuts, you know
bunch of nuts, you know what
If I brought in a truck and unloaded a
bunch of nuts, you know what the
squirrel
squirrel would
squirrel would do?
squirrel would do? He'd
squirrel would do? He'd run
squirrel would do? He'd run all
squirrel would do? He'd run all around
the
the edge
squirrel would do? He'd run all around
the edge getting
the edge getting more
squirrel would do? He'd run all around
the edge getting more nuts.
the edge getting more nuts. He's
squirrel would do? He'd run all around
the edge getting more nuts. He's got
the edge getting more nuts. He's got a
mountain
mountain of
mountain of them.
All right,
All right, what's
mountain of them.
All right, what's our
All right, what's our next
mountain of them.
All right, what's our next surprise?
Uh
Uh yeah.
Uh yeah. So
Uh yeah. So now
Uh yeah. So now the
Uh yeah. So now the mind
Uh yeah. So now the mind gets
Uh yeah. So now the mind gets taken
Uh yeah. So now the mind gets taken over
because
because when
Uh yeah. So now the mind gets taken over
because when the
because when the prefrontal
Uh yeah. So now the mind gets taken over
because when the prefrontal cortex
because when the prefrontal cortex was
added,
added, the
added, the animal
added, the animal brain
added, the animal brain was
added, the animal brain was not
added, the animal brain was not removed.
Folks,
Folks, there
added, the animal brain was not removed.
Folks, there you
Folks, there you got
added, the animal brain was not removed.
Folks, there you got the
Folks, there you got the whole
added, the animal brain was not removed.
Folks, there you got the whole human
experience
experience explained
experience explained to
experience explained to you.
experience explained to you. The
experience explained to you. The source
of
of all
experience explained to you. The source
of all suffering.
The
The old
The old animal
The old animal brain
The old animal brain was
The old animal brain was not
The old animal brain was not replaced
The old animal brain was not replaced by
a
a prefrontal
The old animal brain was not replaced by
a prefrontal cortex.
a prefrontal cortex. It
The old animal brain was not replaced by
a prefrontal cortex. It was
a prefrontal cortex. It was added
The old animal brain was not replaced by
a prefrontal cortex. It was added on.
Now
Now you're
Now you're in
Now you're in a
Now you're in a worse
Now you're in a worse fix
Now you're in a worse fix than
Now you're in a worse fix than you
Now you're in a worse fix than you were
before.
You
You were
You were just
You were just a
You were just a happy
You were just a happy lion
You were just a happy lion eating
rabbits
rabbits cuz
You were just a happy lion eating
rabbits cuz he's
rabbits cuz he's hungry.
Now
Now you
Now you got
Now you got a
Now you got a problem.
Now you got a problem. You're
Now you got a problem. You're killing
the
the rabbits.
Now you got a problem. You're killing
the rabbits. Oh
the rabbits. Oh my
Now you got a problem. You're killing
the rabbits. Oh my god.
Shouldn't
Shouldn't I
Shouldn't I be
Shouldn't I be a
Shouldn't I be a vegetarian?
Poor
Poor Eeyore.
Anyhow,
our
our affliction
Anyhow,
our affliction then
our affliction then the
Anyhow,
our affliction then the price
our affliction then the price of
Anyhow,
our affliction then the price of being
our affliction then the price of being a
human
human being,
human being, the
human being, the price
human being, the price of
human being, the price of the
human being, the price of the evolution
of
of consciousness
human being, the price of the evolution
of consciousness is
of consciousness is we
human being, the price of the evolution
of consciousness is we go
of consciousness is we go through
human being, the price of the evolution
of consciousness is we go through a
period
period of
period of tremendous
period of tremendous conflict.
period of tremendous conflict. To
period of tremendous conflict. To be
period of tremendous conflict. To be a
human
human being
period of tremendous conflict. To be a
human being is
human being is agonizing.
Anybody
Anybody disagree?
I
I was
Anybody disagree?
I was going
I was going to
Anybody disagree?
I was going to say
I was going to say I'll
Anybody disagree?
I was going to say I'll refer
I was going to say I'll refer you
Anybody disagree?
I was going to say I'll refer you to
I was going to say I'll refer you to my
analyst.
It's
It's agonizing.
analyst.
It's agonizing. Why?
It's agonizing. Why? Because
analyst.
It's agonizing. Why? Because you've
It's agonizing. Why? Because you've got
a
a prefrontal
a prefrontal cortex
a prefrontal cortex plastered
a prefrontal cortex plastered onto
a prefrontal cortex plastered onto an
old
old animal
a prefrontal cortex plastered onto an
old animal brain.
You
You got
You got a
You got a conscience
You got a conscience plastered
You got a conscience plastered onto
You got a conscience plastered onto a
brain
brain that
You got a conscience plastered onto a
brain that wants
brain that wants to
You got a conscience plastered onto a
brain that wants to kill
brain that wants to kill people.
Wow.
Don't
Don't you
Wow.
Don't you feel
Don't you feel guilty?
No.
He
He doesn't
No.
He doesn't feel
He doesn't feel guilty.
All right.
All right. So
All right. So see
All right. So see that
All right. So see that the
All right. So see that the source
All right. So see that the source of
your
your guilt
All right. So see that the source of
your guilt is
your guilt is a
All right. So see that the source of
your guilt is a byproduct
your guilt is a byproduct and
All right. So see that the source of
your guilt is a byproduct and a
consequence
consequence of
consequence of your
consequence of your own
consequence of your own spiritual
aspiration.
It's
It's not
It's not intrinsic
It's not intrinsic and
It's not intrinsic and innate
It's not intrinsic and innate to
It's not intrinsic and innate to the
It's not intrinsic and innate to the act
or
or anything.
It's not intrinsic and innate to the act
or anything. Guilt
or anything. Guilt is
It's not intrinsic and innate to the act
or anything. Guilt is a
or anything. Guilt is a super
superimposition
superimposition that
superimposition that you
superimposition that you project
superimposition that you project onto
superimposition that you project onto it
or
or you
superimposition that you project onto it
or you buy
or you buy from
superimposition that you project onto it
or you buy from society.
You
You made
You made that
You made that up.
The
The tiger
You made that up.
The tiger eats
The tiger eats the
You made that up.
The tiger eats the rabbit
The tiger eats the rabbit because
You made that up.
The tiger eats the rabbit because it's
hungry.
That's
That's all.
hungry.
That's all. That's
That's all. That's the
hungry.
That's all. That's the world
That's all. That's the world the
hungry.
That's all. That's the world the way
That's all. That's the world the way it
is.
is. Rest
is. Rest external,
is. Rest external, rest
is. Rest external, rest internal.
is. Rest external, rest internal. Now
you've
you've got
is. Rest external, rest internal. Now
you've got a
you've got a prefrontal
is. Rest external, rest internal. Now
you've got a prefrontal cortex
you've got a prefrontal cortex that
throws
throws you
throws you into
throws you into guilt.
throws you into guilt. You
throws you into guilt. You just
throws you into guilt. You just murdered
the
the rabbit.
Wow.
That
That keeps
Wow.
That keeps the
That keeps the mind
Wow.
That keeps the mind very
That keeps the mind very busy.
It
It keeps
It keeps it
It keeps it going.
It keeps it going. So
It keeps it going. So what
It keeps it going. So what happens
It keeps it going. So what happens is
the
the ego's
It keeps it going. So what happens is
the ego's energy
the ego's energy now
It keeps it going. So what happens is
the ego's energy now gets
the ego's energy now gets invested
It keeps it going. So what happens is
the ego's energy now gets invested in
the
the mind.
the mind. So
the mind. So when
the mind. So when you
the mind. So when you look
the mind. So when you look at
the mind. So when you look at your
the mind. So when you look at your mind
now
now what
the mind. So when you look at your mind
now what you're
now what you're seeing
the mind. So when you look at your mind
now what you're seeing is
now what you're seeing is the
the mind. So when you look at your mind
now what you're seeing is the energy
now what you're seeing is the energy of
the
the primitive
the primitive ego
which
which for
the primitive ego
which for survival
which for survival is
the primitive ego
which for survival is now
which for survival is now become
the primitive ego
which for survival is now become a
which for survival is now become a tool
of
of the
of the animal.
Your
Your mind
of the animal.
Your mind is
Your mind is the
of the animal.
Your mind is the tool
Your mind is the tool of
of the animal.
Your mind is the tool of the
Your mind is the tool of the animal.
Therefore
Therefore it's
Therefore it's interested
Therefore it's interested in
Therefore it's interested in what?
Survival.
So
So the
So the mind
So the mind is
So the mind is up
So the mind is up to
So the mind is up to the
So the mind is up to the same
So the mind is up to the same thing
So the mind is up to the same thing as
any
any animal
So the mind is up to the same thing as
any animal is
any animal is up
So the mind is up to the same thing as
any animal is up to.
And
And here's
And here's how
And here's how it
And here's how it keeps
And here's how it keeps going.
And here's how it keeps going. It
politicizes
politicizes everything.
And here's how it keeps going. It
politicizes everything. That'll
politicizes everything. That'll do
And here's how it keeps going. It
politicizes everything. That'll do you
politicizes everything. That'll do you a
lot
lot of
lot of lifetimes.
lot of lifetimes. It
lot of lifetimes. It moralizes
lot of lifetimes. It moralizes about
everything.
everything. That'll
lot of lifetimes. It moralizes about
everything. That'll get
everything. That'll get you
lot of lifetimes. It moralizes about
everything. That'll get you a
everything. That'll get you a lot
lot of lifetimes. It moralizes about
everything. That'll get you a lot of
lifetimes.
lifetimes. It
lifetimes. It idealizes
lifetimes. It idealizes everything.
Hypothesizes
the
the world
the world of
the world of hyp
the world of hyp the
the world of hyp the hypothetical.
It
It romanticises,
the world of hyp the hypothetical.
It romanticises, ranticize.
It romanticises, ranticize. It
criticizes.
Emotionalizes,
Emotionalizes, dramatizes,
catastrophizes,
catastrophizes, victimizes.
catastrophizes, victimizes. It
rationalizes.
rationalizes. It
catastrophizes, victimizes. It
rationalizes. It makes
rationalizes. It makes endless
catastrophizes, victimizes. It
rationalizes. It makes endless excuses.
It
It lives
It lives in
It lives in a
It lives in a fantasy
It lives in a fantasy world
It lives in a fantasy world of
infantilism.
And
And it
And it likes
And it likes to
And it likes to intellectualize,
it
it likes
And it likes to intellectualize,
it likes to
it likes to mentalize,
And it likes to intellectualize,
it likes to mentalize, it
it likes to mentalize, it glamorizes
things,
demonizes
demonizes them,
things,
demonizes them, it
demonizes them, it prizes
things,
demonizes them, it prizes them
demonizes them, it prizes them as
things,
demonizes them, it prizes them as goals,
and
and it
and it endlessly
and it endlessly theorizes
and it endlessly theorizes about
and it endlessly theorizes about things.
The
The hypothetical
and it endlessly theorizes about things.
The hypothetical is
The hypothetical is the
and it endlessly theorizes about things.
The hypothetical is the ego's
grandstanding
grandstanding through
grandstanding through the
grandstanding through the intellect.
grandstanding through the intellect. So,
next
next slide.
grandstanding through the intellect. So,
next slide. We're
next slide. We're going
grandstanding through the intellect. So,
next slide. We're going to
next slide. We're going to go
grandstanding through the intellect. So,
next slide. We're going to go through
the
the slides
the slides a
the slides a little
the slides a little faster.
the slides a little faster. We
the slides a little faster. We got
the slides a little faster. We got to
watch
watch it
the slides a little faster. We got to
watch it because
watch it because we
the slides a little faster. We got to
watch it because we got
watch it because we got 200
the slides a little faster. We got to
watch it because we got 200 movies
watch it because we got 200 movies to
go.
go. You
go. You know,
I've
I've lost
go. You know,
I've lost track
I've lost track of
go. You know,
I've lost track of time.
I've lost track of time. What
go. You know,
I've lost track of time. What time
I've lost track of time. What time do
go. You know,
I've lost track of time. What time do we
take
take a
take a break?
>> Okay.
>> Huh?
>> About
>> About 10:30.
>> What
>> What time
>> What time is
>> What time is it
>> What time is it now?
>> 10
>> 10 after
>> What time is it now?
>> 10 after 10.
>> My
>> My good
>> My good watch.
>> My good watch. I
>> My good watch. I broke
>> My good watch. I broke the
>> My good watch. I broke the crystal.
>> My good watch. I broke the crystal. Or
God
God broke
>> My good watch. I broke the crystal. Or
God broke the
God broke the crystal.
>> My good watch. I broke the crystal. Or
God broke the crystal. Somebody
God broke the crystal. Somebody did.
Somebody
Somebody is
Somebody is to
Somebody is to blame.
Here
Here we
Somebody is to blame.
Here we talk
Here we talk about
Somebody is to blame.
Here we talk about the
Here we talk about the paradigms
Somebody is to blame.
Here we talk about the paradigms of
Here we talk about the paradigms of the
Newtonian
Newtonian and
Newtonian and quantum
Newtonian and quantum mechanics.
Newtonian and quantum mechanics. We
Newtonian and quantum mechanics. We said
that
that the
Newtonian and quantum mechanics. We said
that the ego
that the ego then
Newtonian and quantum mechanics. We said
that the ego then works
that the ego then works on
Newtonian and quantum mechanics. We said
that the ego then works on the
that the ego then works on the basis
Newtonian and quantum mechanics. We said
that the ego then works on the basis of
the
the Newtonian
the Newtonian paradigm
the Newtonian paradigm of
the Newtonian paradigm of causality.
The
The way
the Newtonian paradigm of causality.
The way to
The way to jump
the Newtonian paradigm of causality.
The way to jump the
The way to jump the calibrate
the Newtonian paradigm of causality.
The way to jump the calibrate the
The way to jump the calibrate the the
world
world of
world of the
world of the 400s,
world of the 400s, the
world of the 400s, the world
world of the 400s, the world of
world of the 400s, the world of the
400s,
400s, the
world of the 400s, the world of the
400s, the Newtonian
400s, the Newtonian paradigm
world of the 400s, the world of the
400s, the Newtonian paradigm is
400s, the Newtonian paradigm is the
intellect,
intellect, which
intellect, which becomes
intellect, which becomes taken
intellect, which becomes taken over
intellect, which becomes taken over by
the
the ego.
Well,
Well, quick
Well, quick way
Well, quick way to
Well, quick way to transcend
Well, quick way to transcend the
Well, quick way to transcend the 400s
and
and not
Well, quick way to transcend the 400s
and not spend
and not spend 20
Well, quick way to transcend the 400s
and not spend 20 lifetimes
and not spend 20 lifetimes at
Well, quick way to transcend the 400s
and not spend 20 lifetimes at it
is
is to
is to see,
is to see, merely
is to see, merely see.
is to see, merely see. And
is to see, merely see. And if
is to see, merely see. And if you
is to see, merely see. And if you don't
see
see it,
is to see, merely see. And if you don't
see it, take
see it, take my
is to see, merely see. And if you don't
see it, take my word
see it, take my word for
is to see, merely see. And if you don't
see it, take my word for it.
Nothing
Nothing comes
Nothing comes into
Nothing comes into to
Nothing comes into to being
Nothing comes into to being as
Nothing comes into to being as a
Nothing comes into to being as a result
of
of causality.
Everything
Everything comes
Everything comes into
Everything comes into existence
Everything comes into existence out
Everything comes into existence out of
nothingness.
All
All arises
All arises out
All arises out of
All arises out of nothing
All arises out of nothing as
All arises out of nothing as a
potentiality.
A
A potentiality
A potentiality within
A potentiality within an
A potentiality within an infinite
A potentiality within an infinite p
power
power field
A potentiality within an infinite p
power field becomes
power field becomes an
A potentiality within an infinite p
power field becomes an actuality
power field becomes an actuality by
virtue
virtue of
virtue of the
virtue of the power
virtue of the power of
virtue of the power of the
virtue of the power of the field.
Not
Not by
virtue of the power of the field.
Not by virtue
Not by virtue of
virtue of the power of the field.
Not by virtue of that
Not by virtue of that out
virtue of the power of the field.
Not by virtue of that out there.
Not by virtue of that out there. Not
virtue of the power of the field.
Not by virtue of that out there. Not by
virtue
virtue of
virtue of that
virtue of that out
virtue of that out there
virtue of that out there potentiality
now
now becomes
virtue of that out there potentiality
now becomes an
now becomes an actuality
virtue of that out there potentiality
now becomes an actuality and
now becomes an actuality and this
virtue of that out there potentiality
now becomes an actuality and this is
now becomes an actuality and this is the
what
what we
what we call
what we call creation.
The
The unmanifest
what we call creation.
The unmanifest becomes
The unmanifest becomes manifest
what we call creation.
The unmanifest becomes manifest by
virtue
virtue of
virtue of the
virtue of the divinity
virtue of the divinity of
virtue of the divinity of the
virtue of the divinity of the infinite
field
which
which we
which we call
which we call God.
That
That is
which we call God.
That is an
That is an absolute
which we call God.
That is an absolute fact.
That is an absolute fact. Is
which we call God.
That is an absolute fact. Is that
That is an absolute fact. Is that is
which we call God.
That is an absolute fact. Is that is an
absolute
absolute fact.
absolute fact. Therefore,
absolute fact. Therefore, you
absolute fact. Therefore, you really
don't
don't have
absolute fact. Therefore, you really
don't have to
don't have to think
absolute fact. Therefore, you really
don't have to think anymore
don't have to think anymore because
absolute fact. Therefore, you really
don't have to think anymore because now
you
you got
you got it.
Everything
Everything is
you got it.
Everything is attracting
Everything is attracting to
you got it.
Everything is attracting to it
Everything is attracting to it what
you got it.
Everything is attracting to it what it
attracts
attracts to
attracts to it
attracts to it by
attracts to it by virtue
attracts to it by virtue of
attracts to it by virtue of what
attracts to it by virtue of what it
attracts to it by virtue of what it is.
Wow.
Wow. That
attracts to it by virtue of what it is.
Wow. That totally
Wow. That totally changes
attracts to it by virtue of what it is.
Wow. That totally changes how
Wow. That totally changes how the
attracts to it by virtue of what it is.
Wow. That totally changes how the you
see
see the
see the world
see the world operating
blows
blows a
see the world operating
blows a lot
blows a lot of
see the world operating
blows a lot of sociological
blows a lot of sociological theories.
It's
It's sort
It's sort of
It's sort of that
It's sort of that which
It's sort of that which you
It's sort of that which you are
karmically
karmically what
It's sort of that which you are
karmically what you've
karmically what you've inherited
It's sort of that which you are
karmically what you've inherited when
you
you get
you get born.
you get born. Every
you get born. Every being
you get born. Every being already
you get born. Every being already has
you get born. Every being already has a
calibrated
calibrated level
you get born. Every being already has a
calibrated level of
calibrated level of energy
you get born. Every being already has a
calibrated level of energy at
calibrated level of energy at the
you get born. Every being already has a
calibrated level of energy at the time
of
of birth
of birth over
of birth over these
of birth over these things
of birth over these things that
of birth over these things that could
of birth over these things that could be
iffy.
iffy. We
of birth over these things that could be
iffy. We that's
iffy. We that's a
of birth over these things that could be
iffy. We that's a fact.
Every
Every being
Every being at
Every being at the
Every being at the moment
Every being at the moment of
Every being at the moment of birth
already
already has
Every being at the moment of birth
already has a
already has a calibrated
Every being at the moment of birth
already has a calibrated level
already has a calibrated level of
energy.
It's
It's also
energy.
It's also born
It's also born in
energy.
It's also born in the
It's also born in the most
energy.
It's also born in the most optimal
circumstances
circumstances propitious
circumstances propitious for
circumstances propitious for karmic
evolution
evolution for
circumstances propitious for karmic
evolution for the
evolution for the evolution
circumstances propitious for karmic
evolution for the evolution of
consciousness.
consciousness. So
consciousness. So we
consciousness. So we start
consciousness. So we start from
consciousness. So we start from where
consciousness. So we start from where we
left
left off
consciousness. So we start from where we
left off with
left off with the
consciousness. So we start from where we
left off with the evolution
left off with the evolution of
consciousness.
consciousness. We
consciousness. We start
consciousness. We start in
consciousness. We start in this
physicality.
We
We then
We then attract
We then attract to
We then attract to us
that
that which
We then attract to us
that which we
that which we attract
We then attract to us
that which we attract is
that which we attract is because
We then attract to us
that which we attract is because of
that which we attract is because of our
own
own magnetism.
own magnetism. Ah
own magnetism. Ah there
own magnetism. Ah there you
own magnetism. Ah there you got
own magnetism. Ah there you got it.
So
So the
own magnetism. Ah there you got it.
So the calibrated
So the calibrated level
own magnetism. Ah there you got it.
So the calibrated level of
So the calibrated level of consciousness
then
then could
then could be
then could be compared
then could be compared to
then could be compared to magnetic
power.
power. Huh?
then could be compared to magnetic
power. Huh? Those
power. Huh? Those with
then could be compared to magnetic
power. Huh? Those with weak
power. Huh? Those with weak power
attract
attract nothing
attract nothing to
attract nothing to them.
attract nothing to them. They
attract nothing to them. They lay
attract nothing to them. They lay there
apathetically.
apathetically. There's
attract nothing to them. They lay there
apathetically. There's no
apathetically. There's no vaccine
available.
There's
There's no
available.
There's no food.
There's no food. There's
available.
There's no food. There's no
There's no food. There's no ambulance.
There's
There's no
There's no hospital
There's no hospital services.
There's
There's no
There's no hospital services.
There's no judiciary.
There's no judiciary. There
There's no hospital services.
There's no judiciary. There are
There's no judiciary. There are no
courts.
courts. There's
courts. There's no
courts. There's no organization
courts. There's no organization to
courts. There's no organization to the
government.
The
The next
The next thing
The next thing that
The next thing that wants
The next thing that wants to
The next thing that wants to chop
The next thing that wants to chop you
The next thing that wants to chop you up
comes
comes over
The next thing that wants to chop you up
comes over and
comes over and chops
The next thing that wants to chop you up
comes over and chops you
comes over and chops you up
because
because you're
because you're What
because you're What do
because you're What do they
because you're What do they do
because you're What do they do in
Rwanda?
Rwanda? Places
because you're What do they do in
Rwanda? Places like
Rwanda? Places like that.
because you're What do they do in
Rwanda? Places like that. They
Rwanda? Places like that. They just
because you're What do they do in
Rwanda? Places like that. They just chop
you
you up
you up cuz
you up cuz you're
you up cuz you're there.
Turn
Turn the
you up cuz you're there.
Turn the corner
Turn the corner and
you up cuz you're there.
Turn the corner and there
Turn the corner and there were
you up cuz you're there.
Turn the corner and there were these
four
four people.
four people. So
four people. So I
four people. So I chop
four people. So I chop them
four people. So I chop them up.
Now
Now you
four people. So I chop them up.
Now you go
Now you go back
four people. So I chop them up.
Now you go back and
Now you go back and to
four people. So I chop them up.
Now you go back and to your
Now you go back and to your team
four people. So I chop them up.
Now you go back and to your team and
your
your hero.
Chopped
Chopped up
your hero.
Chopped up four.
Chopped up four. Chopped
your hero.
Chopped up four. Chopped up
Chopped up four. Chopped up four
your hero.
Chopped up four. Chopped up four what?
Chopped
Chopped up
Chopped up four
Chopped up four infants.
Chopped up four infants. That
Chopped up four infants. That won't
Chopped up four infants. That won't get
you
you into
Chopped up four infants. That won't get
you into the
you into the big
Chopped up four infants. That won't get
you into the big league,
you into the big league, boy.
It
It will
It will not
It will not get
It will not get you
It will not get you into
It will not get you into the
It will not get you into the big
It will not get you into the big league.
But
But that
It will not get you into the big league.
But that is
But that is the
It will not get you into the big league.
But that is the nature
But that is the nature of
It will not get you into the big league.
But that is the nature of life
But that is the nature of life at
It will not get you into the big league.
But that is the nature of life at the
bottom.
bottom. It
bottom. It pulls
bottom. It pulls to
bottom. It pulls to it
bottom. It pulls to it by
bottom. It pulls to it by virtue
bottom. It pulls to it by virtue of
bottom. It pulls to it by virtue of that
which
which it
bottom. It pulls to it by virtue of that
which it is.
Takes
Takes a
Takes a lot
Takes a lot of
Takes a lot of moral
Takes a lot of moral courage
Takes a lot of moral courage and
integrity
integrity to
Takes a lot of moral courage and
integrity to own
integrity to own that.
Takes a lot of moral courage and
integrity to own that. that
integrity to own that. that all
Takes a lot of moral courage and
integrity to own that. that all what
integrity to own that. that all what has
consequenced
consequenced in
consequenced in our
consequenced in our life
consequenced in our life experientially
has
has been
consequenced in our life experientially
has been a
has been a conse
consequenced in our life experientially
has been a conse has
has been a conse has been
consequenced in our life experientially
has been a conse has been the
has been a conse has been the automatic
consequence
consequence of
consequence of that
consequence of that which
consequence of that which we
consequence of that which we are.
Nothing
Nothing and
consequence of that which we are.
Nothing and no
Nothing and no one
consequence of that which we are.
Nothing and no one is
Nothing and no one is out
consequence of that which we are.
Nothing and no one is out there
Nothing and no one is out there to
blame.
blame. Huh?
Let's
Let's take
blame. Huh?
Let's take a
Let's take a guy
blame. Huh?
Let's take a guy standing
Let's take a guy standing on
blame. Huh?
Let's take a guy standing on the
sidewalk.
A
A car
sidewalk.
A car goes
A car goes by
sidewalk.
A car goes by and
A car goes by and it
sidewalk.
A car goes by and it backfires
and
and he
and he goes
falls
falls over
and he goes
falls over with
falls over with a
and he goes
falls over with a heart
falls over with a heart attack.
It's
It's because
It's because of
It's because of what
It's because of what he
It's because of what he is
It's because of what he is that
It's because of what he is that the
backfire
backfire blew
It's because of what he is that the
backfire blew his
backfire blew his coronary
It's because of what he is that the
backfire blew his coronary artery.
The
The automobile
The automobile didn't
The automobile didn't have
The automobile didn't have anything
The automobile didn't have anything to
do
do with
The automobile didn't have anything to
do with his
do with his cor
The automobile didn't have anything to
do with his cor coronary
do with his cor coronary artery.
The automobile didn't have anything to
do with his cor coronary artery. The
automobile's
automobile's in
automobile's in the
automobile's in the street.
automobile's in the street. His
automobile's in the street. His coronary
artery
artery is
automobile's in the street. His coronary
artery is in
artery is in his
automobile's in the street. His coronary
artery is in his chest.
In
In court,
In court, in
In court, in court,
In court, in court, however,
In court, in court, however, which
In court, in court, however, which pays
no
no attention
In court, in court, however, which pays
no attention to
no attention to reality,
the
the backfire
the backfire of
the backfire of the
the backfire of the taxi
the backfire of the taxi caused
the backfire of the taxi caused my
clients
clients h
the backfire of the taxi caused my
clients h to
clients h to have
the backfire of the taxi caused my
clients h to have a
clients h to have a heart
the backfire of the taxi caused my
clients h to have a heart attack.
clients h to have a heart attack. Huh.
How
How about
How about 30
How about 30 years
How about 30 years of
How about 30 years of double
cheeseburgers,
cheeseburgers, folks?
Well,
Well, we
Well, we know
Well, we know whose
Well, we know whose fault
Well, we know whose fault that
Well, we know whose fault that is.
Well, we know whose fault that is. The
Big
Big M.
The
The big
The big M
The big M made
The big M made him
The big M made him eat
The big M made him eat all
The big M made him eat all them.
No,
No, his
The big M made him eat all them.
No, his animal
No, his animal made
The big M made him eat all them.
No, his animal made him
No, his animal made him eat
The big M made him eat all them.
No, his animal made him eat it.
No, his animal made him eat it. So
The big M made him eat all them.
No, his animal made him eat it. So when
you
you own
you own your
you own your own
you own your own animal,
you own your own animal, you'll
you own your own animal, you'll be
you own your own animal, you'll be a
you own your own animal, you'll be a lot
happier.
Yeah.
Yeah. Won't
Yeah. Won't you?
Yeah. Won't you? You
Yeah. Won't you? You don't
Yeah. Won't you? You don't have
Yeah. Won't you? You don't have to
Yeah. Won't you? You don't have to feel
guilt.
guilt. Don't
Yeah. Won't you? You don't have to feel
guilt. Don't have
guilt. Don't have to
Yeah. Won't you? You don't have to feel
guilt. Don't have to blame
guilt. Don't have to blame anybody.
Yeah. Won't you? You don't have to feel
guilt. Don't have to blame anybody. See,
because
because the
because the downside
because the downside of
because the downside of blame
because the downside of blame is
because the downside of blame is guilt.
Why?
Why? Because
because the downside of blame is guilt.
Why? Because every
Why? Because every time
because the downside of blame is guilt.
Why? Because every time you
Why? Because every time you lie,
because the downside of blame is guilt.
Why? Because every time you lie, even
though
though you
though you intellectually
though you intellectually believe
though you intellectually believe it,
though you intellectually believe it, on
the
the unconscious
though you intellectually believe it, on
the unconscious level,
the unconscious level, you
though you intellectually believe it, on
the unconscious level, you realize
you've
you've lied.
So
So when
you've lied.
So when we
So when we own
you've lied.
So when we own that
So when we own that we
you've lied.
So when we own that we are
So when we own that we are the
you've lied.
So when we own that we are the source
So when we own that we are the source of
all
all the
all the phenomena
all the phenomena that
all the phenomena that happens
all the phenomena that happens in
all the phenomena that happens in our
life
life we
all the phenomena that happens in our
life we already
life we already I
all the phenomena that happens in our
life we already I can
life we already I can guarantee
all the phenomena that happens in our
life we already I can guarantee you
life we already I can guarantee you over
200 guarantee
200 guarantee that's
200 guarantee that's over
200 guarantee that's over 200
that
that which
200 guarantee that's over 200
that which you
that which you are
200 guarantee that's over 200
that which you are then
that which you are then brings
200 guarantee that's over 200
that which you are then brings to
that which you are then brings to it
200 guarantee that's over 200
that which you are then brings to it as
a
a consequent
a consequent of
a consequent of that
a consequent of that which
a consequent of that which it
a consequent of that which it is.
a consequent of that which it is. See
you
you might
a consequent of that which it is. See
you might say
you might say the
a consequent of that which it is. See
you might say the car
you might say the car the
a consequent of that which it is. See
you might say the car the karmic
you might say the car the karmic body
you
you might
you might say
you might say has
you might say has a
you might say has a certain
you might say has a certain way
you might say has a certain way of
you might say has a certain way of being
and
and the
you might say has a certain way of being
and the way
and the way it's
you might say has a certain way of being
and the way it's it
and the way it's it is
you might say has a certain way of being
and the way it's it is pulls
and the way it's it is pulls to
you might say has a certain way of being
and the way it's it is pulls to it
and the way it's it is pulls to it that
which
which is
which is appropriate
which is appropriate like
which is appropriate like a
which is appropriate like a molecule
does.
does. So
which is appropriate like a molecule
does. So it's
does. So it's like
which is appropriate like a molecule
does. So it's like the
does. So it's like the soul
which is appropriate like a molecule
does. So it's like the soul I
does. So it's like the soul I look
which is appropriate like a molecule
does. So it's like the soul I look like
a
a big
a big giant
a big giant molecule
a big giant molecule see
a big giant molecule see and
a big giant molecule see and it
interacts
interacts with
a big giant molecule see and it
interacts with that
interacts with that with
a big giant molecule see and it
interacts with that with which
interacts with that with which it
a big giant molecule see and it
interacts with that with which it is
concordant
concordant by
concordant by virtue
concordant by virtue of
concordant by virtue of what
concordant by virtue of what it
concordant by virtue of what it is
concordant by virtue of what it is its
own
own structure
concordant by virtue of what it is its
own structure that
own structure that which
concordant by virtue of what it is its
own structure that which it
own structure that which it has
concordant by virtue of what it is its
own structure that which it has become.
Therefore,
Therefore, the
Therefore, the universe
Therefore, the universe is
Therefore, the universe is absolutely
just.
The
The universe
The universe in
The universe in all
The universe in all of
The universe in all of its
The universe in all of its expression
The universe in all of its expression is
absolutely
absolutely just
resist.
That's
That's a
resist.
That's a fact.
And
And they
And they better
And they better buy
And they better buy it,
And they better buy it, too.
Susan
Susan puts
And they better buy it, too.
Susan puts up
Susan puts up with
And they better buy it, too.
Susan puts up with all
Susan puts up with all this
And they better buy it, too.
Susan puts up with all this all
Susan puts up with all this all the
time.
She's
She's in
time.
She's in the
She's in the middle
time.
She's in the middle of
She's in the middle of making
time.
She's in the middle of making a
sandwich.
sandwich. I
sandwich. I say
sandwich. I say I
sandwich. I say I got
sandwich. I say I got to
sandwich. I say I got to have
sandwich. I say I got to have a
sandwich. I say I got to have a number,
but
but it's
sandwich. I say I got to have a number,
but it's burning.
but it's burning. I'll
sandwich. I say I got to have a number,
but it's burning. I'll just
but it's burning. I'll just one
sandwich. I say I got to have a number,
but it's burning. I'll just one number.
Okay,
Okay, just
say
say you
Okay, just
say you promise
say you promise just
Okay, just
say you promise just one
say you promise just one number
because
because one
because one number
because one number always
because one number always brings
because one number always brings up
because one number always brings up the
next
next number
because one number always brings up the
next number to
next number to confirm
because one number always brings up the
next number to confirm it
next number to confirm it and
because one number always brings up the
next number to confirm it and enlarge
next number to confirm it and enlarge on
it
it and
it and amplify
it and amplify it.
it and amplify it. You
it and amplify it. You know,
it and amplify it. You know, especially
when
when you're
it and amplify it. You know, especially
when you're writing
when you're writing a
it and amplify it. You know, especially
when you're writing a book
when you're writing a book in
it and amplify it. You know, especially
when you're writing a book in which,
when you're writing a book in which, you
know,
know, so
know, so far
know, so far we've
know, so far we've done
know, so far we've done 250,000
know, so far we've done 250,000 numbers.
Wow.
250,000.
Come
Come up
250,000.
Come up here.
Come up here. Get
250,000.
Come up here. Get up.
She
She does
She does it
She does it out
She does it out of
She does it out of love.
She
She say,
She does it out of love.
She say, "All
She say, "All right,
She does it out of love.
She say, "All right, I
She say, "All right, I love
She does it out of love.
She say, "All right, I love you."
She say, "All right, I love you." Okay.
Especially
Especially watch
Especially watch looking
Especially watch looking through
cataloges.
cataloges. She
Especially watch looking through
cataloges. She loves
cataloges. She loves cataloges.
Especially watch looking through
cataloges. She loves cataloges. And
cataloges. She loves cataloges. And I
hate
hate to
hate to interrupt
hate to interrupt her
hate to interrupt her with
hate to interrupt her with a
hate to interrupt her with a catalog.
hate to interrupt her with a catalog. A
new
new catalog.
It's
It's like
It's like a
It's like a new
It's like a new tool
It's like a new tool to
It's like a new tool to a
It's like a new tool to a guy,
It's like a new tool to a guy, you
It's like a new tool to a guy, you know.
She's
She's got
It's like a new tool to a guy, you know.
She's got to
She's got to get
It's like a new tool to a guy, you know.
She's got to get to
She's got to get to it.
It's like a new tool to a guy, you know.
She's got to get to it. All right.
She's got to get to it. All right. So,
let's
let's skip
let's skip the
let's skip the Newtonian
let's skip the Newtonian paradigm.
let's skip the Newtonian paradigm. I
don't
don't feel
let's skip the Newtonian paradigm. I
don't feel up
don't feel up to
let's skip the Newtonian paradigm. I
don't feel up to the
don't feel up to the Newtonian
let's skip the Newtonian paradigm. I
don't feel up to the Newtonian paradigm
today.
Uh
Uh these
today.
Uh these are
Uh these are the
today.
Uh these are the the
Uh these are the the scale
today.
Uh these are the the scale 600
Uh these are the the scale 600 and
today.
Uh these are the the scale 600 and over.
600 and
600 and over.
Those
Those are
600 and over.
Those are unusual.
Quite
Quite unusual.
Quite unusual. And
Quite unusual. And in
Quite unusual. And in fact,
Quite unusual. And in fact, they
practically
practically never
Quite unusual. And in fact, they
practically never happen.
practically never happen. And
Quite unusual. And in fact, they
practically never happen. And I
practically never happen. And I think
it's
it's because
it's because that
it's because that level
it's because that level you
it's because that level you really
belong
belong in
it's because that level you really
belong in a
belong in a different
it's because that level you really
belong in a different realm,
belong in a different realm, you
it's because that level you really
belong in a different realm, you know.
All right.
All right. But
All right. But anyway,
All right. But anyway, people
All right. But anyway, people are
curious
curious about
All right. But anyway, people are
curious about them.
curious about them. So,
All right. But anyway, people are
curious about them. So, we
curious about them. So, we have
All right. But anyway, people are
curious about them. So, we have them
here.
here. As
here. As I
here. As I say,
here. As I say, they're
here. As I say, they're extremely
here. As I say, they're extremely rare.
And
And when
here. As I say, they're extremely rare.
And when they
And when they do
here. As I say, they're extremely rare.
And when they do occur,
And when they do occur, uh,
here. As I say, they're extremely rare.
And when they do occur, uh, usually
And when they do occur, uh, usually the
world
world doesn't
world doesn't know
world doesn't know about
world doesn't know about it.
world doesn't know about it. Most
world doesn't know about it. Most people
just
just stay
world doesn't know about it. Most people
just stay there
just stay there and
world doesn't know about it. Most people
just stay there and leave.
just stay there and leave. Uh,
world doesn't know about it. Most people
just stay there and leave. Uh, 50%
just stay there and leave. Uh, 50% will
leave
leave the
leave the body
leave the body as
leave the body as soon
leave the body as soon as
leave the body as soon as they
leave the body as soon as they hit
leave the body as soon as they hit that
low.
low. And
leave the body as soon as they hit that
low. And if
low. And if they
leave the body as soon as they hit that
low. And if they don't
low. And if they don't hit
leave the body as soon as they hit that
low. And if they don't hit there,
low. And if they don't hit there, uh,
they'll
they'll leave
they'll leave the
they'll leave the body
they'll leave the body here.
they'll leave the body here. So
they'll leave the body here. So all
along
along here
they'll leave the body here. So all
along here the
along here the few
they'll leave the body here. So all
along here the few that
along here the few that do
they'll leave the body here. So all
along here the few that do arrive
usually
usually leave.
usually leave. Yeah.
usually leave. Yeah. And
usually leave. Yeah. And uh
usually leave. Yeah. And uh some
usually leave. Yeah. And uh some hang
usually leave. Yeah. And uh some hang in
by
by virtue
usually leave. Yeah. And uh some hang in
by virtue of
by virtue of uh
usually leave. Yeah. And uh some hang in
by virtue of uh I
by virtue of uh I think
usually leave. Yeah. And uh some hang in
by virtue of uh I think suspect
by virtue of uh I think suspect some
kind
kind of
kind of primary
kind of primary some
kind of primary some prior
kind of primary some prior agreement.
Yeah.
Yeah. Anyway,
kind of primary some prior agreement.
Yeah. Anyway, these
Yeah. Anyway, these states
kind of primary some prior agreement.
Yeah. Anyway, these states have
Yeah. Anyway, these states have been
described
described throughout
described throughout the
described throughout the ages.
described throughout the ages. And
described throughout the ages. And then
we
we asked
described throughout the ages. And then
we asked about
we asked about archangels
described throughout the ages. And then
we asked about archangels because
we asked about archangels because when
in
in the
in the pits
in the pits of
in the pits of hell
in the pits of hell I
in the pits of hell I asked
in the pits of hell I asked if
in the pits of hell I asked if there
in the pits of hell I asked if there was
I
I I
in the pits of hell I asked if there was
I I said
I I said if
in the pits of hell I asked if there was
I I said if there
I I said if there is
in the pits of hell I asked if there was
I I said if there is a
I I said if there is a god
in the pits of hell I asked if there was
I I said if there is a god I
I I said if there is a god I asked
in the pits of hell I asked if there was
I I said if there is a god I asked him
for
for help.
for help. Uh
for help. Uh it
for help. Uh it was
for help. Uh it was in
for help. Uh it was in the
for help. Uh it was in the very
for help. Uh it was in the very pits
for help. Uh it was in the very pits of
hell
hell which
for help. Uh it was in the very pits of
hell which is
hell which is timeless
eternal
eternal and
didn't
didn't hold
eternal and
didn't hold my
didn't hold my breath
eternal and
didn't hold my breath as
didn't hold my breath as a
eternal and
didn't hold my breath as a sincere
atheist
and
and suddenly
atheist
and suddenly oblivion
and
and then
and then emergence
that
that which
and then emergence
that which was
that which was replaced
and then emergence
that which was replaced by
that which was replaced by a
and then emergence
that which was replaced by a state
that which was replaced by a state a
condition.
condition. It
condition. It can
condition. It can only
condition. It can only be
condition. It can only be called
condition. It can only be called a
condition. It can only be called a state
or
or a
condition. It can only be called a state
or a condition.
or a condition. It's
condition. It can only be called a state
or a condition. It's a
or a condition. It's a state.
condition. It can only be called a state
or a condition. It's a state. It's
or a condition. It's a state. It's a
condition.
condition. It's
condition. It's a
condition. It's a state
condition. It's a state or
condition. It's a state or condition
condition. It's a state or condition of
what
what can
condition. It's a state or condition of
what can I
what can I say
condition. It's a state or condition of
what can I say this
what can I say this the
condition. It's a state or condition of
what can I say this the ab
what can I say this the ab the
condition. It's a state or condition of
what can I say this the ab the absolute
it's
it's a
it's a state
it's a state or
it's a state or condition
it's a state or condition of
it's a state or condition of the
absolute
absolute resist
it's a state or condition of the
absolute resist yeah
absolute resist yeah that's
it's a state or condition of the
absolute resist yeah that's what
absolute resist yeah that's what gives
us
us it
us it its
us it its strength
us it its strength and
us it its strength and conviction
us it its strength and conviction and
power
all
all right
so
so we'll
all right
so we'll move
so we'll move on
all right
so we'll move on to
so we'll move on to the
all right
so we'll move on to the next
so we'll move on to the next things
these
these are
these are the
these are the fields
these are the fields of
these are the fields of realization
these are the fields of realization when
you're
you're transcending
these are the fields of realization when
you're transcending the
you're transcending the ego
um
um these
um these are
um these are the
um these are the levels
um these are the levels which
um these are the levels which I'll
um these are the levels which I'll go
um these are the levels which I'll go to
into
into more
um these are the levels which I'll go to
into more in
into more in the
um these are the levels which I'll go to
into more in the next
into more in the next book,
um these are the levels which I'll go to
into more in the next book, but
into more in the next book, but I
um these are the levels which I'll go to
into more in the next book, but I did
cover
cover it
cover it in
cover it in some
cover it in some of
cover it in some of the
cover it in some of the previous
cover it in some of the previous ones.
In
In the
cover it in some of the previous ones.
In the beginning,
In the beginning, you're
cover it in some of the previous ones.
In the beginning, you're dominated
In the beginning, you're dominated by
form.
form. Then
form. Then you're
form. Then you're trying
form. Then you're trying to
form. Then you're trying to transcend
the
the ego.
form. Then you're trying to transcend
the ego. You
the ego. You can
form. Then you're trying to transcend
the ego. You can begin
the ego. You can begin to
form. Then you're trying to transcend
the ego. You can begin to see
the ego. You can begin to see you're
form. Then you're trying to transcend
the ego. You can begin to see you're not
form.
form. You're
form. You're not
form. You're not the
form. You're not the content
form. You're not the content of
form. You're not the content of the
mind.
mind. You're
form. You're not the content of the
mind. You're that
mind. You're that which
form. You're not the content of the
mind. You're that which is
mind. You're that which is registering
what's
what's in
what's in mind.
what's in mind. Then
what's in mind. Then you
what's in mind. Then you begin
what's in mind. Then you begin to
what's in mind. Then you begin to see
that
that you're
what's in mind. Then you begin to see
that you're recogniz
that you're recogniz you're
what's in mind. Then you begin to see
that you're recogniz you're the
that you're recogniz you're the really
the
the watcher.
the watcher. And
the watcher. And Mr.
the watcher. And Mr. Gdata
the watcher. And Mr. Gdata Maharaj
recommends
that
that you
that you just
that you just do
that you just do that
that you just do that continuously.
that you just do that continuously. Just
watch
watch the
that you just do that continuously. Just
watch the mind.
watch the mind. He
that you just do that continuously. Just
watch the mind. He says
watch the mind. He says the
that you just do that continuously. Just
watch the mind. He says the way
watch the mind. He says the way to
transcend
transcend the
transcend the mind
transcend the mind is
transcend the mind is to
transcend the mind is to just
transcend the mind is to just watch
transcend the mind is to just watch it
be
be because
transcend the mind is to just watch it
be because it
be because it dawns
transcend the mind is to just watch it
be because it dawns on
be because it dawns on you
transcend the mind is to just watch it
be because it dawns on you after
be because it dawns on you after doing
this
this for
this for a
this for a while.
this for a while. All
this for a while. All of a
this for a while. All of a sudden
this for a while. All of a sudden you
become
become the
this for a while. All of a sudden you
become the watcher
become the watcher and
this for a while. All of a sudden you
become the watcher and not
become the watcher and not the
this for a while. All of a sudden you
become the watcher and not the not
become the watcher and not the not the
thoughts.
thoughts. You
thoughts. You realize
thoughts. You realize I'm
thoughts. You realize I'm the
thoughts. You realize I'm the I'm
thoughts. You realize I'm the I'm the
witness
witness of
thoughts. You realize I'm the I'm the
witness of the
witness of the mind.
thoughts. You realize I'm the I'm the
witness of the mind. I'm
witness of the mind. I'm the
thoughts. You realize I'm the I'm the
witness of the mind. I'm the witness.
The
The watcher.
The watcher. I'm
The watcher. I'm not
The watcher. I'm not the
The watcher. I'm not the content.
The watcher. I'm not the content. The
content
content changes
The watcher. I'm not the content. The
content changes all
content changes all the
The watcher. I'm not the content. The
content changes all the time.
content changes all the time. But
The watcher. I'm not the content. The
content changes all the time. But the
witness
witness the
witness the watcher
witness the watcher doesn't
witness the watcher doesn't change
witness the watcher doesn't change at
all.
all. And
witness the watcher doesn't change at
all. And then
all. And then you
witness the watcher doesn't change at
all. And then you begin
all. And then you begin to
witness the watcher doesn't change at
all. And then you begin to realize
all. And then you begin to realize that
that
that is
that is the
that is the light
that is the light of
that is the light of consciousness.
That's
That's a
that is the light of consciousness.
That's a meditative
That's a meditative state.
that is the light of consciousness.
That's a meditative state. It's
That's a meditative state. It's also
that is the light of consciousness.
That's a meditative state. It's also a
the
the result
the result of
the result of a
the result of a contemplative
the result of a contemplative state.
the result of a contemplative state. And
I
I recommend
the result of a contemplative state. And
I recommend walking
I recommend walking around
the result of a contemplative state. And
I recommend walking around the
I recommend walking around the world
the result of a contemplative state. And
I recommend walking around the world in
a
a contemplative
a contemplative state.
a contemplative state. You
a contemplative state. You can
a contemplative state. You can have
somebody
somebody else
a contemplative state. You can have
somebody else drive
somebody else drive till
a contemplative state. You can have
somebody else drive till you
somebody else drive till you get
a contemplative state. You can have
somebody else drive till you get used
somebody else drive till you get used to
it.
Next
Next one.
All right.
All right. The
All right. The we
All right. The we we
All right. The we we use
All right. The we we use the
All right. The we we use the calibrated
levels
levels of
All right. The we we use the calibrated
levels of consciousness
levels of consciousness which
All right. The we we use the calibrated
levels of consciousness which we're
going
going to
going to publish
going to publish in
going to publish in the
going to publish in the next
going to publish in the next book
going to publish in the next book to
going to publish in the next book to u
get
get the
going to publish in the next book to u
get the levels
get the levels of
going to publish in the next book to u
get the levels of consciousness
get the levels of consciousness of
going to publish in the next book to u
get the levels of consciousness of the
various
various areas
various areas of
various areas of the
various areas of the world.
various areas of the world. People
various areas of the world. People come
in
in here
various areas of the world. People come
in here then
in here then uh
various areas of the world. People come
in here then uh collectively
in here then uh collectively uh
karmically
karmically they're
karmically they're great
karmically they're great groups
karmically they're great groups and
karmically they're great groups and they
settle
settle just
karmically they're great groups and they
settle just like
settle just like you
karmically they're great groups and they
settle just like you watch
settle just like you watch swans
karmically they're great groups and they
settle just like you watch swans or
various
various birds.
various birds. They
various birds. They come
various birds. They come in
various birds. They come in a
various birds. They come in a flock
various birds. They come in a flock and
they
they tend
various birds. They come in a flock and
they tend to
they tend to settle
various birds. They come in a flock and
they tend to settle in
they tend to settle in various
various birds. They come in a flock and
they tend to settle in various parts
they tend to settle in various parts of
the
the world.
the world. They
the world. They don't
the world. They don't just
the world. They don't just all
the world. They don't just all of
the world. They don't just all of them
settle
settle everywhere
the world. They don't just all of them
settle everywhere whistling
settle everywhere whistling swans
the world. They don't just all of them
settle everywhere whistling swans or
whatever.
They
first
first of
first of all
first of all have
first of all have a
first of all have a cyclic
first of all have a cyclic nature.
first of all have a cyclic nature. They
come
come in
first of all have a cyclic nature. They
come in together
come in together karmically
first of all have a cyclic nature. They
come in together karmically unified
come in together karmically unified as
first of all have a cyclic nature. They
come in together karmically unified as a
field.
field. And
field. And as
field. And as you
field. And as you watch
field. And as you watch them
field. And as you watch them fly,
they're
they're entrancing.
field. And as you watch them fly,
they're entrancing. When
they're entrancing. When you
field. And as you watch them fly,
they're entrancing. When you watch
they're entrancing. When you watch a
flock
flock of
flock of birds,
flock of birds, what
flock of birds, what you're
flock of birds, what you're watching
flock of birds, what you're watching is
an
an attractor
flock of birds, what you're watching is
an attractor field.
an attractor field. Last
flock of birds, what you're watching is
an attractor field. Last night
an attractor field. Last night they
flock of birds, what you're watching is
an attractor field. Last night they did
one
one on
one on schools
one on schools of
one on schools of fish.
one on schools of fish. It
one on schools of fish. It looked
one on schools of fish. It looked like
one on schools of fish. It looked like a
giant
giant rubber
one on schools of fish. It looked like a
giant rubber donut.
giant rubber donut. It
one on schools of fish. It looked like a
giant rubber donut. It had
giant rubber donut. It had the
one on schools of fish. It looked like a
giant rubber donut. It had the shape
giant rubber donut. It had the shape of
a
a donut
a donut made
a donut made up
a donut made up of
a donut made up of millions
a donut made up of millions of
a donut made up of millions of fish.
a donut made up of millions of fish. And
you
you see
a donut made up of millions of fish. And
you see the
you see the donut
a donut made up of millions of fish. And
you see the donut rotating.
Remember
Remember that?
Remember that? It
Remember that? It was
Remember that? It was amazing.
Remember that? It was amazing. Have
Remember that? It was amazing. Have you
ever
ever seen
Remember that? It was amazing. Have you
ever seen that?
>> Yeah.
All
All the
>> Yeah.
All the schools
All the schools of
>> Yeah.
All the schools of fish
All the schools of fish rotate
>> Yeah.
All the schools of fish rotate like
All the schools of fish rotate like a
unity.
unity. See,
unity. See, they're
unity. See, they're not
unity. See, they're not just
unity. See, they're not just everywhere
scattered
scattered about.
unity. See, they're not just everywhere
scattered about. You
scattered about. You watch
unity. See, they're not just everywhere
scattered about. You watch a
scattered about. You watch a flock
unity. See, they're not just everywhere
scattered about. You watch a flock of
birds.
birds. It
birds. It sweeps
birds. It sweeps up
birds. It sweeps up like
birds. It sweeps up like this.
You
You think
birds. It sweeps up like this.
You think each
You think each bird
birds. It sweeps up like this.
You think each bird is
You think each bird is following
birds. It sweeps up like this.
You think each bird is following another
bird
in
in a
bird
in a school
in a school of
bird
in a school of fish,
in a school of fish, the
bird
in a school of fish, the ego
in a school of fish, the ego thinks
Newtonianly
Newtonianly that
Newtonianly that they're
Newtonianly that they're following
Newtonianly that they're following the
other
other fish,
Newtonianly that they're following the
other fish, they're
other fish, they're following
Newtonianly that they're following the
other fish, they're following the
other fish, they're following the other
bird.
bird. They're
bird. They're not.
Each
Each bird
bird. They're not.
Each bird is
Each bird is independently
bird. They're not.
Each bird is independently being
Each bird is independently being guided
by
by the
by the attractor
by the attractor field.
Yeah,
that's
that's a
that's a fact.
that's a fact. Is
that's a fact. Is it?
That's
That's a
that's a fact. Is it?
That's a fact.
That's a fact. It's
that's a fact. Is it?
That's a fact. It's a
That's a fact. It's a knowingness
that's a fact. Is it?
That's a fact. It's a knowingness that
becomes
becomes obvious
becomes obvious because
becomes obvious because you
becomes obvious because you see
becomes obvious because you see it
sweeps
sweeps as
becomes obvious because you see it
sweeps as though
sweeps as though it's
becomes obvious because you see it
sweeps as though it's one
sweeps as though it's one entity.
becomes obvious because you see it
sweeps as though it's one entity. Yeah.
Each
Each bird,
Each bird, each
Each bird, each fish
Each bird, each fish is
Each bird, each fish is being
individually
individually directed.
Each bird, each fish is being
individually directed. Each
individually directed. Each one
Each bird, each fish is being
individually directed. Each one is
tracking
tracking the
tracking the field
tracking the field and
tracking the field and it's
tracking the field and it's following
the
the field.
tracking the field and it's following
the field. what
the field. what the
tracking the field and it's following
the field. what the other
the field. what the other people
tracking the field and it's following
the field. what the other people are
doing,
doing, they're
doing, they're doing.
doing, they're doing. But
doing, they're doing. But that
doing, they're doing. But that bird
doing, they're doing. But that bird is
tracking
tracking the
doing, they're doing. But that bird is
tracking the field
tracking the field coming
doing, they're doing. But that bird is
tracking the field coming from
tracking the field coming from within.
Ah,
Ah, isn't
Ah, isn't that
Ah, isn't that interesting?
Ah, isn't that interesting? So,
Ah, isn't that interesting? So, you
Ah, isn't that interesting? So, you see
the
the swooping
Ah, isn't that interesting? So, you see
the swooping then
the swooping then of
Ah, isn't that interesting? So, you see
the swooping then of the
the swooping then of the birds
Ah, isn't that interesting? So, you see
the swooping then of the birds and
the swooping then of the birds and the
fish
fish here
fish here and
fish here and how
fish here and how they
fish here and how they settle
fish here and how they settle out.
fish here and how they settle out. These
are
are the
fish here and how they settle out. These
are the marsh
are the marsh birds
fish here and how they settle out. These
are the marsh birds and
are the marsh birds and these
fish here and how they settle out. These
are the marsh birds and these are
are the marsh birds and these are the
wingy
wingy birds
wingy birds and
wingy birds and all.
Let's
Let's go
wingy birds and all.
Let's go on
Let's go on to
wingy birds and all.
Let's go on to the
Let's go on to the next.
wingy birds and all.
Let's go on to the next. We
Let's go on to the next. We predicted
from
from this
from this map
from this map where
from this map where the
from this map where the trouble
from this map where the trouble would
from this map where the trouble would be
in
in the
from this map where the trouble would be
in the world.
in the world. If
from this map where the trouble would be
in the world. If you
in the world. If you come
from this map where the trouble would be
in the world. If you come from
in the world. If you come from some
other
other universe
other universe and
other universe and all
other universe and all you
other universe and all you do
other universe and all you do is
calibrate
calibrate levels
other universe and all you do is
calibrate levels of
calibrate levels of consciousness,
other universe and all you do is
calibrate levels of consciousness, you
can
can pretty
can pretty much
can pretty much lay
can pretty much lay out
can pretty much lay out what
can pretty much lay out what would
happen
happen in
can pretty much lay out what would
happen in this
happen in this world.
can pretty much lay out what would
happen in this world. So,
happen in this world. So, this
can pretty much lay out what would
happen in this world. So, this is
happen in this world. So, this is where
the
the birds
the birds settle
the birds settle out.
the birds settle out. So,
the birds settle out. So, we'll
the birds settle out. So, we'll go
the birds settle out. So, we'll go on
the birds settle out. So, we'll go on to
the
the next
the birds settle out. So, we'll go on to
the next because
the next because we've
the birds settle out. So, we'll go on to
the next because we've shown
the next because we've shown that
the birds settle out. So, we'll go on to
the next because we've shown that one
before.
Uh
this
this is
this is uh
this is uh interesting.
this is uh interesting. I
this is uh interesting. I think
this is uh interesting. I think we've
got
got one.
this is uh interesting. I think we've
got one. As
got one. As we
this is uh interesting. I think we've
got one. As we said,
got one. As we said, the
this is uh interesting. I think we've
got one. As we said, the problem
got one. As we said, the problem when
this is uh interesting. I think we've
got one. As we said, the problem when we
first
first did
first did the
first did the map,
first did the map, there
first did the map, there wasn't
first did the map, there wasn't any
overt
overt problem
first did the map, there wasn't any
overt problem in
overt problem in Haiti,
first did the map, there wasn't any
overt problem in Haiti, but
overt problem in Haiti, but when
first did the map, there wasn't any
overt problem in Haiti, but when we
overt problem in Haiti, but when we did
the
the map,
the map, we
the map, we said
the map, we said 55,
the map, we said 55, that's
the map, we said 55, that's going
the map, we said 55, that's going to
the map, we said 55, that's going to be
a
a problem.
the map, we said 55, that's going to be
a problem. But
a problem. But it's
the map, we said 55, that's going to be
a problem. But it's only
a problem. But it's only going
the map, we said 55, that's going to be
a problem. But it's only going to
a problem. But it's only going to be
the map, we said 55, that's going to be
a problem. But it's only going to be a
problem
problem to
problem to itself.
problem to itself. It
problem to itself. It doesn't
problem to itself. It doesn't have
enough
enough power
problem to itself. It doesn't have
enough power to
enough power to be
problem to itself. It doesn't have
enough power to be a
enough power to be a problem
problem to itself. It doesn't have
enough power to be a problem to
enough power to be a problem to the
world.
world. Like
world. Like 180
world. Like 180 or
world. Like 180 or 190
world. Like 180 or 190 can
world. Like 180 or 190 can be
world. Like 180 or 190 can be a
world. Like 180 or 190 can be a big
problem
problem to
world. Like 180 or 190 can be a big
problem to the
problem to the world.
world. Like 180 or 190 can be a big
problem to the world. 55
problem to the world. 55 barely
world. Like 180 or 190 can be a big
problem to the world. 55 barely exists.
So
So we
So we said
So we said the
So we said the problem
So we said the problem was
So we said the problem was going
So we said the problem was going to
So we said the problem was going to come
from
from North
So we said the problem was going to come
from North Africa
from North Africa and
So we said the problem was going to come
from North Africa and that's
from North Africa and that's where
So we said the problem was going to come
from North Africa and that's where it
came
came from.
came from. Time
came from. Time magazine
came from. Time magazine came
came from. Time magazine came out
came from. Time magazine came out about
a
a year
came from. Time magazine came out about
a year or
a year or two
came from. Time magazine came out about
a year or two ago
a year or two ago with
came from. Time magazine came out about
a year or two ago with practically
a year or two ago with practically the
same
same map
same map except
same map except it
same map except it didn't
same map except it didn't have
calibrations.
calibrations. And
same map except it didn't have
calibrations. And this
calibrations. And this is
same map except it didn't have
calibrations. And this is where
calibrations. And this is where apathy
settles.
settles. So
settles. So this
settles. So this is
settles. So this is where
if
if karmically
that's
that's where
that's where you
that's where you ended
that's where you ended up
that's where you ended up then
that's where you ended up then that's
where
where you
that's where you ended up then that's
where you start.
where you start. And
that's where you ended up then that's
where you start. And of
where you start. And of course
that's where you ended up then that's
where you start. And of course if
where you start. And of course if you
want
want to
want to really
want to really do
want to really do karmic
want to really do karmic research
want to really do karmic research you
can
can ask
want to really do karmic research you
can ask why
can ask why does
want to really do karmic research you
can ask why does this
can ask why does this group
want to really do karmic research you
can ask why does this group come
can ask why does this group come in
want to really do karmic research you
can ask why does this group come in here
with
with that
with that kind
with that kind of
with that kind of a
with that kind of a level
with that kind of a level of
consciousness.
Just
Just as
Just as we
Just as we have
Just as we have individual
Just as we have individual karma
Just as we have individual karma we
Just as we have individual karma we have
group
group karma.
Just as we have individual karma we have
group karma. So
group karma. So a
Just as we have individual karma we have
group karma. So a group
that
that goes
that goes out
that goes out and
that goes out and creates
that goes out and creates enormously
negative
negative karma
that goes out and creates enormously
negative karma for
negative karma for itself
still
still has
still has a
still has a chance
still has a chance for
still has a chance for evolution.
And
And where
still has a chance for evolution.
And where will
And where will it
still has a chance for evolution.
And where will it do
And where will it do that
still has a chance for evolution.
And where will it do that if
And where will it do that if it
still has a chance for evolution.
And where will it do that if it does?
And where will it do that if it does? So
this
this planet
this planet seems
this planet seems to
this planet seems to be
this planet seems to be where
this planet seems to be where you
this planet seems to be where you do
that.
that. This
this planet seems to be where you do
that. This planet
that. This planet goes
this planet seems to be where you do
that. This planet goes from
that. This planet goes from the
this planet seems to be where you do
that. This planet goes from the very
bottom
bottom to
bottom to the
bottom to the very
bottom to the very top.
How
How are
bottom to the very top.
How are you
How are you going
bottom to the very top.
How are you going to
How are you going to undo
bottom to the very top.
How are you going to undo that
How are you going to undo that kind
bottom to the very top.
How are you going to undo that kind of
negative
negative karma?
negative karma? The
negative karma? The green
negative karma? The green river
negative karma? The green river killer
something.
something. I
negative karma? The green river killer
something. I mean,
something. I mean, where
negative karma? The green river killer
something. I mean, where is
something. I mean, where is he
negative karma? The green river killer
something. I mean, where is he going
something. I mean, where is he going to
start?
start? I
start? I don't
start? I don't know.
start? I don't know. Start
start? I don't know. Start at
start? I don't know. Start at the
bottom,
bottom, huh?
start? I don't know. Start at the
bottom, huh? Maybe
bottom, huh? Maybe in
start? I don't know. Start at the
bottom, huh? Maybe in Rwanda.
bottom, huh? Maybe in Rwanda. I
start? I don't know. Start at the
bottom, huh? Maybe in Rwanda. I don't
know.
know. All
know. All right.
know. All right. So,
know. All right. So, this
know. All right. So, this is
know. All right. So, this is the
know. All right. So, this is the end
know. All right. So, this is the end of
the
the map.
know. All right. So, this is the end of
the map. And
the map. And we'll
know. All right. So, this is the end of
the map. And we'll just
the map. And we'll just go
know. All right. So, this is the end of
the map. And we'll just go to
the map. And we'll just go to one
know. All right. So, this is the end of
the map. And we'll just go to one more
thing
thing and
thing and we'll
thing and we'll go
thing and we'll go to
thing and we'll go to take
thing and we'll go to take a
thing and we'll go to take a break.
My
My brains
thing and we'll go to take a break.
My brains wore
My brains wore out
thing and we'll go to take a break.
My brains wore out already.
Oh,
Oh, I
Oh, I thought
Oh, I thought this
Oh, I thought this is
Oh, I thought this is fun.
We
We did
Oh, I thought this is fun.
We did the
We did the United
Oh, I thought this is fun.
We did the United States
We did the United States at
Oh, I thought this is fun.
We did the United States at 421,
you
you know,
you know, and
you know, and I
you know, and I was
you know, and I was at
you know, and I was at Chicago.
you know, and I was at Chicago. I
haven't
haven't been
you know, and I was at Chicago. I
haven't been there
haven't been there many
you know, and I was at Chicago. I
haven't been there many a
haven't been there many a year.
you know, and I was at Chicago. I
haven't been there many a year. And
haven't been there many a year. And I
looked
looked there
looked there and
looked there and I
looked there and I said,
looked there and I said, "My
looked there and I said, "My god,
looked there and I said, "My god, this
is
is stunningly
looked there and I said, "My god, this
is stunningly beautiful."
is stunningly beautiful." We
looked there and I said, "My god, this
is stunningly beautiful." We looked
is stunningly beautiful." We looked down
this
this river,
this river, incredible
this river, incredible buildings,
this river, incredible buildings, the
merchandise
merchandise mart.
this river, incredible buildings, the
merchandise mart. And
merchandise mart. And I
this river, incredible buildings, the
merchandise mart. And I said,
merchandise mart. And I said, "This
place
place is
place is like
place is like Carl
place is like Carl Samberg
place is like Carl Samberg described
place is like Carl Samberg described it,
a
a real
place is like Carl Samberg described it,
a real dynamo
a real dynamo of
place is like Carl Samberg described it,
a real dynamo of power,
a real dynamo of power, you
place is like Carl Samberg described it,
a real dynamo of power, you know."
a real dynamo of power, you know." So
place is like Carl Samberg described it,
a real dynamo of power, you know." So we
calibrated,
calibrated, we
calibrated, we started
calibrated, we started with
calibrated, we started with Chicago.
Where
Where is
calibrated, we started with Chicago.
Where is Chicago?
>> Right
>> Right there
>> Right there on
>> Right there on the
>> Right there on the right.
>> Yeah,
>> Yeah, we
>> Right there on the right.
>> Yeah, we did
>> Yeah, we did Chicago.
>> Right there on the right.
>> Yeah, we did Chicago. Yeah.
>> Yeah, we did Chicago. Yeah. So
>> Right there on the right.
>> Yeah, we did Chicago. Yeah. So there
>> Yeah, we did Chicago. Yeah. So there we
were
were in
were in the
were in the middle
were in the middle of
were in the middle of Chicago,
were in the middle of Chicago, but
were in the middle of Chicago, but we
said
said America's
were in the middle of Chicago, but we
said America's 421.
said America's 421. We
were in the middle of Chicago, but we
said America's 421. We were
said America's 421. We were surprised
were in the middle of Chicago, but we
said America's 421. We were surprised as
all
all get
all get out.
all get out. I
all get out. I said,
all get out. I said, 'Wow,
all get out. I said, 'Wow, Chicago
all get out. I said, 'Wow, Chicago is
445.
445. I
all get out. I said, 'Wow, Chicago is
445. I wonder
445. I wonder where
all get out. I said, 'Wow, Chicago is
445. I wonder where some
445. I wonder where some other
all get out. I said, 'Wow, Chicago is
445. I wonder where some other cities
are.
are. Then
are. Then I
are. Then I wonder
are. Then I wonder if
are. Then I wonder if where
are. Then I wonder if where you
are. Then I wonder if where you are
are. Then I wonder if where you are in
Chicago
Chicago makes
are. Then I wonder if where you are in
Chicago makes a
Chicago makes a difference.
are. Then I wonder if where you are in
Chicago makes a difference. Well,
Chicago makes a difference. Well, we
were
were at
were at a
were at a posh
were at a posh hotel
and
and it
were at a posh hotel
and it calibrated
and it calibrated about
were at a posh hotel
and it calibrated about 450.
and it calibrated about 450. Other
were at a posh hotel
and it calibrated about 450. Other areas
of
of the
of the city
of the city could
of the city could go
of the city could go down
of the city could go down to
of the city could go down to 200,
of the city could go down to 200, but
you
you see
of the city could go down to 200, but
you see it
you see it wasn't
of the city could go down to 200, but
you see it wasn't below
you see it wasn't below 200.
of the city could go down to 200, but
you see it wasn't below 200. Wow.
you see it wasn't below 200. Wow. Thank
God
God it's
God it's not
God it's not below
God it's not below 200.
God it's not below 200. So
God it's not below 200. So what
God it's not below 200. So what was
below
below 200
God it's not below 200. So what was
below 200 is
below 200 is now
God it's not below 200. So what was
below 200 is now come
below 200 is now come up
God it's not below 200. So what was
below 200 is now come up to
below 200 is now come up to 200.
God it's not below 200. So what was
below 200 is now come up to 200. Boy,
that
that in
that in itself
that in itself is
that in itself is really
that in itself is really great.
So
So we
that in itself is really great.
So we do
So we do the
that in itself is really great.
So we do the United
So we do the United States
that in itself is really great.
So we do the United States uh
So we do the United States uh here
that in itself is really great.
So we do the United States uh here and
we
we do
we do you
we do you see
we do you see you
we do you see you can
we do you see you can calibrate
we do you see you can calibrate the
people
people the
we do you see you can calibrate the
people the leader
people the leader and
we do you see you can calibrate the
people the leader and the
people the leader and the government
here's
here's the
here's the president
here's the president present
here's the president present time
here's the president present time anyway
last
last public
here's the president present time anyway
last public origin
last public origin you
here's the president present time anyway
last public origin you see
last public origin you see where
here's the president present time anyway
last public origin you see where the
government
government at
government at is
government at is at
government at is at you
government at is at you see
government at is at you see where
government at is at you see where the
people
people is
government at is at you see where the
people is at
people is at you
government at is at you see where the
people is at you can
people is at you can do
government at is at you see where the
people is at you can do the
people is at you can do the United
States
States of
States of America
States of America the
States of America the east
States of America the east coast
States of America the east coast is
States of America the east coast is 360
west
west coast
States of America the east coast is 360
west coast is
west coast is 290
States of America the east coast is 360
west coast is 290 and
west coast is 290 and the
States of America the east coast is 360
west coast is 290 and the Midwest
west coast is 290 and the Midwest is
States of America the east coast is 360
west coast is 290 and the Midwest is 440
and
and you
and you know
and you know most
and you know most people
and you know most people say
and you know most people say the
and you know most people say the only
same
same people
and you know most people say the only
same people left
same people left on
and you know most people say the only
same people left on the
same people left on the planet
and you know most people say the only
same people left on the planet came
same people left on the planet came from
the
the Midwest
the Midwest quest
the Midwest quest and
the Midwest quest and we
the Midwest quest and we saying,
the Midwest quest and we saying, "See,
there's
there's some
the Midwest quest and we saying, "See,
there's some degree
there's some degree of
the Midwest quest and we saying, "See,
there's some degree of truth
there's some degree of truth in
the Midwest quest and we saying, "See,
there's some degree of truth in that.
The
The farther
The farther you
The farther you get
The farther you get to
The farther you get to the
The farther you get to the coast,
The farther you get to the coast, the
cookier
cookier it
The farther you get to the coast, the
cookier it gets,
cookier it gets, right?"
The farther you get to the coast, the
cookier it gets, right?" So,
cookier it gets, right?" So, we
The farther you get to the coast, the
cookier it gets, right?" So, we said,
"Well,
"Well, the
"Well, the cookies,
"Well, the cookies, alleged
"Well, the cookies, alleged cooks,
"Well, the cookies, alleged cooks, live
in
in California.
"Well, the cookies, alleged cooks, live
in California. What
in California. What is
"Well, the cookies, alleged cooks, live
in California. What is California
calibrate?"
calibrate?" 280.
calibrate?" 280. 280.
calibrate?" 280. 280. Massachusetts
calibrate?" 280. 280. Massachusetts 305.
I'm
I'm sure.
calibrate?" 280. 280. Massachusetts 305.
I'm sure. Anyway,
I'm sure. Anyway, it's
calibrate?" 280. 280. Massachusetts 305.
I'm sure. Anyway, it's just
I'm sure. Anyway, it's just very
interesting.
interesting. So,
interesting. So, we
interesting. So, we asked,
interesting. So, we asked, "What
interesting. So, we asked, "What is
Phoenix?"
Phoenix?" Phoenix
interesting. So, we asked, "What is
Phoenix?" Phoenix is
Phoenix?" Phoenix is 425.
Washington
Washington DC
Washington DC where
Washington DC where we
Washington DC where we were
Washington DC where we were recently
too.
too. I
Washington DC where we were recently
too. I said
too. I said there's
Washington DC where we were recently
too. I said there's pristine
too. I said there's pristine efficiency
here.
here. It
here. It looks
here. It looks like
here. It looks like government.
here. It looks like government. Yep.
450.
I
I mean
I mean it's,
I mean it's, you
I mean it's, you know,
I mean it's, you know, efficient
I mean it's, you know, efficient and
stunningly
stunningly beautiful.
I mean it's, you know, efficient and
stunningly beautiful. The
stunningly beautiful. The Lincoln
Memorial
Memorial is
Memorial is really
Memorial is really very
Memorial is really very impressive.
Memorial is really very impressive. Uh,
and
and what
Memorial is really very impressive. Uh,
and what about
and what about Hollywood?
Memorial is really very impressive. Uh,
and what about Hollywood? Well,
Hollywood
Hollywood calibrates
Hollywood calibrates at
Hollywood calibrates at 190.
Hollywood calibrates at 190. Yeah.
New
New York
Hollywood calibrates at 190. Yeah.
New York City,
New York City, the
Hollywood calibrates at 190. Yeah.
New York City, the Upper
New York City, the Upper East
Hollywood calibrates at 190. Yeah.
New York City, the Upper East Side,
New York City, the Upper East Side, 430.
New
New York
New York City
New York City 385.
New York City 385. Upper
New York City 385. Upper East
New York City 385. Upper East Side
New York City 385. Upper East Side 430,
west
west side
New York City 385. Upper East Side 430,
west side 245,
west side 245, the
New York City 385. Upper East Side 430,
west side 245, the inner
west side 245, the inner city
New York City 385. Upper East Side 430,
west side 245, the inner city 135.
west side 245, the inner city 135. So
the
the inner
the inner city
the inner city in
the inner city in New
the inner city in New York
the inner city in New York City,
the inner city in New York City, you
know,
know, is
the inner city in New York City, you
know, is not
know, is not up
the inner city in New York City, you
know, is not up to
know, is not up to uh
the inner city in New York City, you
know, is not up to uh so
know, is not up to uh so Chicago
the inner city in New York City, you
know, is not up to uh so Chicago is
making
making progress
making progress and
making progress and pulling
making progress and pulling it
making progress and pulling it up
making progress and pulling it up and
New
New York
making progress and pulling it up and
New York City,
New York City, of
making progress and pulling it up and
New York City, of course,
New York City, of course, is
making progress and pulling it up and
New York City, of course, is just
overwhelmed
overwhelmed by
overwhelmed by the
overwhelmed by the influx
overwhelmed by the influx of
overwhelmed by the influx of people
overwhelmed by the influx of people and
probably
probably just
overwhelmed by the influx of people and
probably just can't
probably just can't do
overwhelmed by the influx of people and
probably just can't do more
probably just can't do more they
overwhelmed by the influx of people and
probably just can't do more they can
probably just can't do more they can do.
So,
So, okay,
So, okay, we
So, okay, we we'll
So, okay, we we'll stop
So, okay, we we'll stop there
So, okay, we we'll stop there for
So, okay, we we'll stop there for now.
We're
We're going
So, okay, we we'll stop there for now.
We're going to
We're going to take
So, okay, we we'll stop there for now.
We're going to take a
We're going to take a break.
So, okay, we we'll stop there for now.
We're going to take a break. I
We're going to take a break. I just
thought
thought it's
thought it's interesting
thought it's interesting to
thought it's interesting to apply
thought it's interesting to apply it
thought it's interesting to apply it to
some
some different
thought it's interesting to apply it to
some different things
some different things that
thought it's interesting to apply it to
some different things that we
some different things that we haven't
done
done before.
done before. As
done before. As I
done before. As I say,
done before. As I say, later
done before. As I say, later on
done before. As I say, later on we'll
done before. As I say, later on we'll do
200 movies.
>> Well,
>> Well, we
>> Well, we don't
>> Well, we don't need
>> Well, we don't need an
>> Well, we don't need an audience
>> Well, we don't need an audience to
speak,
speak, so
we'll
we'll speak
we'll speak without
we'll speak without the
we'll speak without the audience
we'll speak without the audience anyway.
And
And of
we'll speak without the audience anyway.
And of course,
And of course, this
we'll speak without the audience anyway.
And of course, this is
And of course, this is funny,
we'll speak without the audience anyway.
And of course, this is funny, isn't
And of course, this is funny, isn't it?
I
I think
I think we'll
I think we'll go
I think we'll go to
I think we'll go to the
I think we'll go to the next
I think we'll go to the next slide.
Quantum
Quantum mechanics
I think we'll go to the next slide.
Quantum mechanics is
Quantum mechanics is a
I think we'll go to the next slide.
Quantum mechanics is a little
Quantum mechanics is a little heavy.
I think we'll go to the next slide.
Quantum mechanics is a little heavy. No,
we
we leave
we leave quantum
we leave quantum mechanics
we leave quantum mechanics on
we leave quantum mechanics on for
we leave quantum mechanics on for a
second.
I
I just
I just got
I just got through
I just got through explaining
I just got through explaining quantum
mechanics
mechanics and
I just got through explaining quantum
mechanics and how
mechanics and how you
I just got through explaining quantum
mechanics and how you arrive
mechanics and how you arrive at
I just got through explaining quantum
mechanics and how you arrive at E=
mechanics and how you arrive at E= MC².
Okay,
Okay, now
Okay, now we'll
Okay, now we'll go
Okay, now we'll go to
Okay, now we'll go to the
Okay, now we'll go to the next
Okay, now we'll go to the next slide.
Now
Now we'll
Okay, now we'll go to the next slide.
Now we'll say
Now we'll say something
Okay, now we'll go to the next slide.
Now we'll say something that
Now we'll say something that sounds
astonishing
astonishing but
astonishing but by
astonishing but by the
astonishing but by the end
astonishing but by the end of the
astonishing but by the end of the day
it'll
it'll be
astonishing but by the end of the day
it'll be clear.
it'll be clear. Feelings
astonishing but by the end of the day
it'll be clear. Feelings are
it'll be clear. Feelings are impersonal.
Well
Well you
Well you see
Well you see the
Well you see the ego
Well you see the ego is
Well you see the ego is narcissistic.
Thinks
Thinks me
Well you see the ego is narcissistic.
Thinks me me
me me me me me me me me me me me
me me me me me
me me me me me all all
me me me me me all all the
me me me me me all all the time.
me me me me me all all the time. It
thinks
thinks a
me me me me me all all the time. It
thinks a feeling
thinks a feeling comes
me me me me me all all the time. It
thinks a feeling comes up.
thinks a feeling comes up. It's
me me me me me all all the time. It
thinks a feeling comes up. It's my
feelings.
feelings. It's
feelings. It's me.
feelings. It's me. No,
feelings. It's me. No, it's
feelings. It's me. No, it's feelings
feelings. It's me. No, it's feelings but
it
it ain't
feelings. It's me. No, it's feelings but
it ain't you.
Did
Did you
Did you ask
Did you ask for
Did you ask for them?
Did you ask for them? No.
Are
Are you
Did you ask for them? No.
Are you karmically
Are you karmically responsible
Did you ask for them? No.
Are you karmically responsible for
having
having feelings?
having feelings? Well,
having feelings? Well, you're
having feelings? Well, you're an
having feelings? Well, you're an animal.
Animal
Animal has
having feelings? Well, you're an animal.
Animal has feelings.
If
If you
If you examine
If you examine the
If you examine the state
If you examine the state of
If you examine the state of a
If you examine the state of a feeling,
you'll
you'll see
If you examine the state of a feeling,
you'll see it's
you'll see it's impersonal.
And
And then
And then because
And then because of
And then because of the
And then because of the narcissism
And then because of the narcissism of
the
the ego,
And then because of the narcissism of
the ego, you
the ego, you say
And then because of the narcissism of
the ego, you say it's
the ego, you say it's my
And then because of the narcissism of
the ego, you say it's my feeling.
the ego, you say it's my feeling. It's
And then because of the narcissism of
the ego, you say it's my feeling. It's a
feeling.
feeling. It's
feeling. It's the
feeling. It's the feeling
feeling. It's the feeling and
feeling. It's the feeling and it's
feeling. It's the feeling and it's not
you.
you. Otherwise,
feeling. It's the feeling and it's not
you. Otherwise, every
you. Otherwise, every time
feeling. It's the feeling and it's not
you. Otherwise, every time you
you. Otherwise, every time you had
feeling. It's the feeling and it's not
you. Otherwise, every time you had a
feeling,
feeling, your
feeling, your calibrated
feeling, your calibrated level
feeling, your calibrated level of
consciousness
consciousness would
feeling, your calibrated level of
consciousness would jump
consciousness would jump all
feeling, your calibrated level of
consciousness would jump all over
consciousness would jump all over the
map.
map. See?
All
All right.
map. See?
All right. So,
All right. So, the
map. See?
All right. So, the calibrated
All right. So, the calibrated level
map. See?
All right. So, the calibrated level of
consciousness,
consciousness, which
consciousness, which you
consciousness, which you start
consciousness, which you start with
consciousness, which you start with your
karmic
karmic inheritance,
is
is is
is is set
is is set by
is is set by the
is is set by the spiritual
is is set by the spiritual will
comparable
comparable to
is is set by the spiritual will
comparable to a
comparable to a ship.
When
When you
When you set
When you set the
When you set the compass,
When you set the compass, he
When you set the compass, he says,
When you set the compass, he says, set
it
it 8°
When you set the compass, he says, set
it 8° north
it 8° north by
When you set the compass, he says, set
it 8° north by northwest.
it 8° north by northwest. Now
When you set the compass, he says, set
it 8° north by northwest. Now you
it 8° north by northwest. Now you set
the
the compass
the compass 8
the compass 8 degrees
the compass 8 degrees north
the compass 8 degrees north by
the compass 8 degrees north by northwest
and
and we'll
the compass 8 degrees north by northwest
and we'll stay
and we'll stay on
the compass 8 degrees north by northwest
and we'll stay on that
and we'll stay on that for
the compass 8 degrees north by northwest
and we'll stay on that for the
and we'll stay on that for the next
the compass 8 degrees north by northwest
and we'll stay on that for the next 500
miles.
Anyway,
Anyway, the
miles.
Anyway, the ship
Anyway, the ship goes
miles.
Anyway, the ship goes this
Anyway, the ship goes this way
miles.
Anyway, the ship goes this way and
Anyway, the ship goes this way and the
ship
ship goes
ship goes this
ship goes this way.
ship goes this way. The
ship goes this way. The wind
ship goes this way. The wind blows
ship goes this way. The wind blows it,
the
the waves
ship goes this way. The wind blows it,
the waves come
the waves come and
ship goes this way. The wind blows it,
the waves come and go.
the waves come and go. But
ship goes this way. The wind blows it,
the waves come and go. But you
the waves come and go. But you set
ship goes this way. The wind blows it,
the waves come and go. But you set the
you
you don't
you don't change
you don't change the
you don't change the course.
you don't change the course. So
you don't change the course. So when
you don't change the course. So when I
was
was in
you don't change the course. So when I
was in the
was in the Navy
you don't change the course. So when I
was in the Navy at
was in the Navy at we
you don't change the course. So when I
was in the Navy at we were
was in the Navy at we were in
you don't change the course. So when I
was in the Navy at we were in a
was in the Navy at we were in a typhoon,
famous
famous famous
famous famous typhoon,
famous famous typhoon, uh
famous famous typhoon, uh ships
famous famous typhoon, uh ships turned
over.
over. So
famous famous typhoon, uh ships turned
over. So anyway,
I
I was
I was at
I was at the
I was at the wheel.
I was at the wheel. Two
I was at the wheel. Two of
I was at the wheel. Two of us
I was at the wheel. Two of us didn't
I was at the wheel. Two of us didn't get
seasick,
seasick, so
I was at the wheel. Two of us didn't get
seasick, so we
seasick, so we took
I was at the wheel. Two of us didn't get
seasick, so we took turns.
seasick, so we took turns. Everybody
else
else turned
else turned green.
Anyway,
Anyway, two
else turned green.
Anyway, two of
Anyway, two of us
else turned green.
Anyway, two of us didn't
Anyway, two of us didn't didn't
else turned green.
Anyway, two of us didn't didn't get
seasick,
seasick, so
seasick, so we
seasick, so we took
seasick, so we took turns
seasick, so we took turns at
seasick, so we took turns at the
seasick, so we took turns at the wheel,
you
you know.
seasick, so we took turns at the wheel,
you know. But
you know. But you
seasick, so we took turns at the wheel,
you know. But you had
you know. But you had to
seasick, so we took turns at the wheel,
you know. But you had to constantly
correct
correct the
correct the wheel.
correct the wheel. Constantly
correct the wheel. Constantly correct
the
the wheel.
correct the wheel. Constantly correct
the wheel. Constantly
the wheel. Constantly correct
correct the wheel. Constantly correct
the wheel. Constantly correct the
the wheel. Constantly correct the wheel.
So
So that's
So that's what
So that's what we
So that's what we do.
So that's what we do. Like
we
we constantly
So that's what we do. Like
we constantly correct
we constantly correct the
So that's what we do. Like
we constantly correct the wheel
we constantly correct the wheel because
a
a wave
a wave of
a wave of anger
a wave of anger comes
a wave of anger comes up,
a wave of anger comes up, but
a wave of anger comes up, but the
a wave of anger comes up, but the anger
wasn't
wasn't you.
a wave of anger comes up, but the anger
wasn't you. Nor
wasn't you. Nor did
a wave of anger comes up, but the anger
wasn't you. Nor did it
wasn't you. Nor did it change
a wave of anger comes up, but the anger
wasn't you. Nor did it change your
course.
So
So your
course.
So your calibrated
So your calibrated level
course.
So your calibrated level of
consciousness
is
is set
consciousness
is set by
is set by your
consciousness
is set by your commitment.
If
If you
If you say
If you say I'm
If you say I'm committed
If you say I'm committed to
If you say I'm committed to to
If you say I'm committed to to the
If you say I'm committed to to the truth
no
no matter
If you say I'm committed to to the truth
no matter what
no matter what that
If you say I'm committed to to the truth
no matter what that powerfully
no matter what that powerfully sets
If you say I'm committed to to the truth
no matter what that powerfully sets your
compass
compass here.
compass here. See
compass here. See now
compass here. See now here
compass here. See now here you're
persuaded
persuaded to
compass here. See now here you're
persuaded to get
persuaded to get angry
compass here. See now here you're
persuaded to get angry there
persuaded to get angry there and
compass here. See now here you're
persuaded to get angry there and all
that
that but
that but that
that but that doesn't
that but that doesn't change
that but that doesn't change your
course.
course. That
that but that doesn't change your
course. That doesn't
course. That doesn't change
that but that doesn't change your
course. That doesn't change your
course. That doesn't change your course.
The
The current
The current the
The current the big
The current the big decisions
The current the big decisions that
change
change our
The current the big decisions that
change our course.
change our course. We
The current the big decisions that
change our course. We can
change our course. We can go
The current the big decisions that
change our course. We can go up
change our course. We can go up or
The current the big decisions that
change our course. We can go up or down.
Famous
Famous people,
Famous people, in
Famous people, in fact,
Famous people, in fact, it
Famous people, in fact, it seems
Famous people, in fact, it seems to
Famous people, in fact, it seems to hit
famous
famous people
Famous people, in fact, it seems to hit
famous people and
famous people and celebrities
Famous people, in fact, it seems to hit
famous people and celebrities more
famous people and celebrities more than
anybody.
anybody. Uh,
anybody. Uh, you
anybody. Uh, you know,
anybody. Uh, you know, they
anybody. Uh, you know, they calibrated
extremely
extremely high
anybody. Uh, you know, they calibrated
extremely high at
extremely high at a
anybody. Uh, you know, they calibrated
extremely high at a certain
extremely high at a certain point.
anybody. Uh, you know, they calibrated
extremely high at a certain point. Then
they
they got
they got all
they got all kinds
they got all kinds of
they got all kinds of worldly
they got all kinds of worldly power
they got all kinds of worldly power and
all
all the
they got all kinds of worldly power and
all the pump
all the pump and
they got all kinds of worldly power and
all the pump and circumstance
all the pump and circumstance and
suddenly
suddenly you
suddenly you see
suddenly you see they
suddenly you see they go
suddenly you see they go from
suddenly you see they go from even
suddenly you see they go from even over
crash
crash down
crash down to
crash down to like
crash down to like 130
every
every day.
crash down to like 130
every day. Every
every day. Every day.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So it's
All right. So it's like
All right. So it's like as
All right. So it's like as you
All right. So it's like as you move
along,
along, you
All right. So it's like as you move
along, you get
along, you get tested.
All right. So it's like as you move
along, you get tested. You
along, you get tested. You get
All right. So it's like as you move
along, you get tested. You get tested.
And
And the
And the value
And the value of
And the value of a
And the value of a spiritual
And the value of a spiritual teacher
And the value of a spiritual teacher is
to
to warn
And the value of a spiritual teacher is
to warn you
to warn you of
And the value of a spiritual teacher is
to warn you of what
to warn you of what the
And the value of a spiritual teacher is
to warn you of what the tests
to warn you of what the tests are,
And the value of a spiritual teacher is
to warn you of what the tests are, how
they
they come
they come up,
they come up, where
they come up, where they
they come up, where they come
they come up, where they come up,
they come up, where they come up, what
disguises
disguises they
they come up, where they come up, what
disguises they come
disguises they come in.
Uh
Uh and
Uh and so
Uh and so I
Uh and so I feel
Uh and so I feel sorry
Uh and so I feel sorry for
Uh and so I feel sorry for those
Uh and so I feel sorry for those who
crash
crash because
Uh and so I feel sorry for those who
crash because they
crash because they didn't
Uh and so I feel sorry for those who
crash because they didn't have
crash because they didn't have a
Uh and so I feel sorry for those who
crash because they didn't have a teacher
that
that warned
that warned them
that warned them about
that warned them about that.
So
So one
that warned them about that.
So one of
So one of my
that warned them about that.
So one of my functions
So one of my functions is
that warned them about that.
So one of my functions is to
So one of my functions is to warn
that warned them about that.
So one of my functions is to warn people
of
of what
of what the
of what the downside
of what the downside is
of what the downside is each
of what the downside is each of
of what the downside is each of these
levels.
levels. And
of what the downside is each of these
levels. And the
levels. And the higher
of what the downside is each of these
levels. And the higher you
levels. And the higher you get,
of what the downside is each of these
levels. And the higher you get, the
levels. And the higher you get, the more
they
they come
they come after
they come after you.
they come after you. When
they come after you. When you're
they come after you. When you're small
fish,
fish, they
they come after you. When you're small
fish, they don't
fish, they don't go
they come after you. When you're small
fish, they don't go after
fish, they don't go after you.
they come after you. When you're small
fish, they don't go after you. But
fish, they don't go after you. But when
as
as you
as you get
as you get up
as you get up close
as you get up close to
as you get up close to 500,
as you get up close to 500, you
as you get up close to 500, you become
dangerous.
You
You see
You see how
You see how dangerous
You see how dangerous you
You see how dangerous you are
You see how dangerous you are at
You see how dangerous you are at 480
You see how dangerous you are at 480 or
490.
490. You
You see how dangerous you are at 480 or
490. You threaten
490. You threaten the
You see how dangerous you are at 480 or
490. You threaten the whole
490. You threaten the whole world
You see how dangerous you are at 480 or
490. You threaten the whole world of
fallacy.
51%
51% of
fallacy.
51% of the
51% of the world's
fallacy.
51% of the world's going
51% of the world's going to
fallacy.
51% of the world's going to hate
51% of the world's going to hate you
already.
The
The higher
already.
The higher you
The higher you get
because
because you
because you become
because you become a
because you become a danger
because you become a danger to
falsehood.
falsehood. Well,
because you become a danger to
falsehood. Well, that
falsehood. Well, that which
because you become a danger to
falsehood. Well, that which is
fellacious
fellacious has
fellacious has run
fellacious has run this
fellacious has run this world
until
until last
fellacious has run this world
until last October.
until last October. No,
fellacious has run this world
until last October. No, till
until last October. No, till the
fellacious has run this world
until last October. No, till the late
late
late 1980s.
late 1980s. Yeah.
late 1980s. Yeah. The
late 1980s. Yeah. The consciousness
level
level of
late 1980s. Yeah. The consciousness
level of mankind
level of mankind went
late 1980s. Yeah. The consciousness
level of mankind went over
level of mankind went over 200.
But
But fallacy
But fallacy rules
But fallacy rules large
But fallacy rules large masses
But fallacy rules large masses of
But fallacy rules large masses of the
population
population and
But fallacy rules large masses of the
population and therefore
population and therefore being
But fallacy rules large masses of the
population and therefore being a
proponent
proponent of
proponent of truth
proponent of truth will
proponent of truth will not
proponent of truth will not always
proponent of truth will not always make
you
you popular.
proponent of truth will not always make
you popular. So
you popular. So therefore,
proponent of truth will not always make
you popular. So therefore, it's
you popular. So therefore, it's best
proponent of truth will not always make
you popular. So therefore, it's best to
keep
keep your
keep your own
keep your own counsel.
in
in certain
keep your own counsel.
in certain circumstances.
All right.
All right. Next.
All right. Next. You
All right. Next. You know,
All right. Next. You know, I
All right. Next. You know, I get
All right. Next. You know, I get static
all
all the
All right. Next. You know, I get static
all the time.
all the time. You
All right. Next. You know, I get static
all the time. You know,
all the time. You know, because
All right. Next. You know, I get static
all the time. You know, because a
all the time. You know, because a person
wants
wants to
wants to know
wants to know what
wants to know what a
wants to know what a thing
wants to know what a thing calibrates
and
and they
wants to know what a thing calibrates
and they feel
and they feel insulted
wants to know what a thing calibrates
and they feel insulted that
and they feel insulted that I'm
wants to know what a thing calibrates
and they feel insulted that I'm not
going
going to
going to support
going to support their
going to support their positionality.
You
You see,
going to support their positionality.
You see, I
You see, I hate
going to support their positionality.
You see, I hate so-
You see, I hate so- and
going to support their positionality.
You see, I hate so- and so
You see, I hate so- and so because
going to support their positionality.
You see, I hate so- and so because he's
this
this and
this and then
this and then I
this and then I say,
this and then I say, "Yeah,
this and then I say, "Yeah, but
this and then I say, "Yeah, but he's
over
over two
this and then I say, "Yeah, but he's
over two 200."
over two 200." Oh,
this and then I say, "Yeah, but he's
over two 200." Oh, they
over two 200." Oh, they get
this and then I say, "Yeah, but he's
over two 200." Oh, they get so
over two 200." Oh, they get so mad.
So
So you
So you have
So you have to
So you have to be
So you have to be sure
So you have to be sure that
So you have to be sure that you're
willing
willing to
So you have to be sure that you're
willing to surrender
willing to surrender anything
So you have to be sure that you're
willing to surrender anything to
willing to surrender anything to God.
You
You know
You know what
You know what you're
You know what you're looking
You know what you're looking for
You know what you're looking for is
You know what you're looking for is God.
And
And God
You know what you're looking for is God.
And God is
And God is at
You know what you're looking for is God.
And God is at the
And God is at the top
You know what you're looking for is God.
And God is at the top of
And God is at the top of the
You know what you're looking for is God.
And God is at the top of the chart.
And God is at the top of the chart. See,
God
God is
God is at
God is at I
God is at I have
God is at I have to
God is at I have to remind
God is at I have to remind people,
God is at I have to remind people, God
is
is at
God is at I have to remind people, God
is at the
is at the top
God is at I have to remind people, God
is at the top of
is at the top of the
God is at I have to remind people, God
is at the top of the chart.
is at the top of the chart. He
God is at I have to remind people, God
is at the top of the chart. He is
is at the top of the chart. He is not
God is at I have to remind people, God
is at the top of the chart. He is not on
the
the level
the level of
the level of vindictiveness,
the level of vindictiveness, hate,
the level of vindictiveness, hate, you
know,
know, not
the level of vindictiveness, hate, you
know, not on
know, not on the
the level of vindictiveness, hate, you
know, not on the level
know, not on the level of
the level of vindictiveness, hate, you
know, not on the level of hate.
know, not on the level of hate. You
won't
won't find
won't find God
won't find God there.
won't find God there. So
won't find God there. So if
won't find God there. So if you're
willing
willing to
won't find God there. So if you're
willing to surrender
willing to surrender hatred
uh
uh for
uh for peace,
uh for peace, then
uh for peace, then you're
uh for peace, then you're in
uh for peace, then you're in the
uh for peace, then you're in the right
class.
class. Otherwise,
uh for peace, then you're in the right
class. Otherwise, the
class. Otherwise, the exit's
uh for peace, then you're in the right
class. Otherwise, the exit's there.
class. Otherwise, the exit's there. All
right.
right. Now,
right. Now, where
right. Now, where were
right. Now, where were we?
right. Now, where were we? We're
right. Now, where were we? We're doing
uh
uh I
right. Now, where were we? We're doing
uh I was
uh I was explaining
right. Now, where were we? We're doing
uh I was explaining E=
uh I was explaining E= MC²
and
and all
and all right.
and all right. Now,
and all right. Now, this
and all right. Now, this is
and all right. Now, this is just
and all right. Now, this is just quantum
mechanics.
This
This is
This is just
This is just quantum
This is just quantum mechanics.
This is just quantum mechanics. Uh
This is just quantum mechanics. Uh which
we've
we've gone
This is just quantum mechanics. Uh which
we've gone over
we've gone over before
This is just quantum mechanics. Uh which
we've gone over before and
we've gone over before and either
This is just quantum mechanics. Uh which
we've gone over before and either you
know
know it's
know it's it's
know it's it's fun
know it's it's fun or
know it's it's fun or it's
know it's it's fun or it's not
know it's it's fun or it's not fun.
know it's it's fun or it's not fun. It
makes
makes you
know it's it's fun or it's not fun. It
makes you sound
makes you sound very
know it's it's fun or it's not fun. It
makes you sound very arerodiodite.
Now
Now these
Now these are
Now these are the
Now these are the trading
Now these are the trading ring
Now these are the trading ring equations
as
as you
Now these are the trading ring equations
as you see
as you see which
Now these are the trading ring equations
as you see which are
as you see which are both
Now these are the trading ring equations
as you see which are both dependent
as you see which are both dependent and
time
time time
time time independent
and
and the
time time independent
and the by
and the by virtue
time time independent
and the by virtue of
and the by virtue of the
time time independent
and the by virtue of the Heisenberg
process.
process. So
process. So the
process. So the only
process. So the only thing
process. So the only thing of
process. So the only thing of interest
to
to us
process. So the only thing of interest
to us really
is
is the
is the value
is the value of
is the value of the
is the value of the Heisenberg
is the value of the Heisenberg process
because
because we
is the value of the Heisenberg process
because we know
because we know that
is the value of the Heisenberg process
because we know that intention,
intention
intention then
intention then is
intention then is what
intention then is what sets
intention then is what sets your
intention then is what sets your dial,
sets
sets your
intention then is what sets your dial,
sets your compass.
sets your compass. Intention,
intention then is what sets your dial,
sets your compass. Intention, the
sets your compass. Intention, the power
of
of intention.
of intention. That's
of intention. That's a
of intention. That's a new
of intention. That's a new book
of intention. That's a new book by
of intention. That's a new book by Wayne
Dyer
Dyer and
of intention. That's a new book by Wayne
Dyer and I
Dyer and I read
of intention. That's a new book by Wayne
Dyer and I read the
Dyer and I read the last
of intention. That's a new book by Wayne
Dyer and I read the last chapter,
Dyer and I read the last chapter, the
power
power of
power of intention.
And
And you
power of intention.
And you get
And you get the
power of intention.
And you get the last
And you get the last chapter
power of intention.
And you get the last chapter for
And you get the last chapter for free
off
off the
off the internet.
And
And when
off the internet.
And when I
And when I when
off the internet.
And when I when I
And when I when I get
off the internet.
And when I when I get when
And when I when I get when I
off the internet.
And when I when I get when I when
And when I when I get when I when I
off the internet.
And when I when I get when I when I get
off
off being
off being cheap,
off being cheap, I'll
off being cheap, I'll buy
off being cheap, I'll buy the
off being cheap, I'll buy the book.
off being cheap, I'll buy the book. I'm
waiting
waiting for
off being cheap, I'll buy the book. I'm
waiting for her
waiting for her to
off being cheap, I'll buy the book. I'm
waiting for her to come
waiting for her to come out
off being cheap, I'll buy the book. I'm
waiting for her to come out and
waiting for her to come out and figure
it
it back,
it back, you
it back, you know.
it back, you know. So
it back, you know. So anyway,
it back, you know. So anyway, the
Heisenberg
Heisenberg principle
it back, you know. So anyway, the
Heisenberg principle then
Heisenberg principle then is
it back, you know. So anyway, the
Heisenberg principle then is intention.
Okay,
Okay, why
Okay, why is
Okay, why is intention
Okay, why is intention important?
Because
Because it's
Okay, why is intention important?
Because it's what
Because it's what sets
Okay, why is intention important?
Because it's what sets your
Because it's what sets your compass.
It's
It's what
It's what sets
It's what sets your
It's what sets your compass.
It's what sets your compass. If
It's what sets your compass. If a
It's what sets your compass. If a person
comes
comes up
It's what sets your compass. If a person
comes up to
comes up to ask
It's what sets your compass. If a person
comes up to ask me
comes up to ask me a
It's what sets your compass. If a person
comes up to ask me a question
comes up to ask me a question and
It's what sets your compass. If a person
comes up to ask me a question and her
intention
intention is
intention is she
intention is she wants
intention is she wants to
intention is she wants to use
intention is she wants to use me
intention is she wants to use me to
intention is she wants to use me to sell
her
her product
intention is she wants to use me to sell
her product or
her product or to
intention is she wants to use me to sell
her product or to verify
her product or to verify her
intention is she wants to use me to sell
her product or to verify her political
candidate
candidate or
candidate or whatever.
See
See that
candidate or whatever.
See that that's
See that that's her
candidate or whatever.
See that that's her intention.
See that that's her intention. So
candidate or whatever.
See that that's her intention. So she's
looking
looking for
looking for confirmation
looking for confirmation of
looking for confirmation of falsehood
which
which I
looking for confirmation of falsehood
which I can't
which I can't give
looking for confirmation of falsehood
which I can't give her
uh
uh because
uh because of
uh because of my
uh because of my own
uh because of my own karma.
The
The downside
uh because of my own karma.
The downside of
The downside of being
uh because of my own karma.
The downside of being a
The downside of being a spiritual
teacher
teacher is
teacher is you've
teacher is you've got
teacher is you've got karmic
responsibility
responsibility for
teacher is you've got karmic
responsibility for the
responsibility for the truth
teacher is you've got karmic
responsibility for the truth of
responsibility for the truth of what
teacher is you've got karmic
responsibility for the truth of what you
say
and
and I
say
and I know
and I know that.
say
and I know that. Therefore,
and I know that. Therefore, what
say
and I know that. Therefore, what I
and I know that. Therefore, what I say
say
and I know that. Therefore, what I say I
say with
say with caution
say with caution and
say with caution and we
say with caution and we check
say with caution and we check it
say with caution and we check it out
with
with the
say with caution and we check it out
with the arm
with the arm to
say with caution and we check it out
with the arm to make
with the arm to make sure.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So the
All right. So the Heisenberg
All right. So the Heisenberg principle
is
is set
All right. So the Heisenberg principle
is set by
is set by intention.
All right. So the Heisenberg principle
is set by intention. So
is set by intention. So my
All right. So the Heisenberg principle
is set by intention. So my intention
is set by intention. So my intention is
to
to teach
to teach the
to teach the truth
to teach the truth as
to teach the truth as I
to teach the truth as I have
to teach the truth as I have realized
to teach the truth as I have realized it
as
as as
to teach the truth as I have realized it
as as the
as as the state
to teach the truth as I have realized it
as as the state realizes
as as the state realizes it.
to teach the truth as I have realized it
as as the state realizes it. the
condition
condition because
condition because what
condition because what overcame
condition because what overcame me
condition because what overcame me years
ago
ago was
condition because what overcame me years
ago was a
ago was a state
condition because what overcame me years
ago was a state a
ago was a state a condition.
condition because what overcame me years
ago was a state a condition. It's
ago was a state a condition. It's it's
condition because what overcame me years
ago was a state a condition. It's it's a
state.
state. It's
state. It's a
state. It's a condition.
It's
It's an
state. It's a condition.
It's an energy
that
that is
that is like
that is like absolute.
It
It is
that is like absolute.
It is infinitely
It is infinitely powerful.
It
It is
It is also
It is also infinitely
It is also infinitely exquisitly
It is also infinitely exquisitly gentle.
How
How can
It is also infinitely exquisitly gentle.
How can it
How can it be
It is also infinitely exquisitly gentle.
How can it be all
How can it be all powerful
It is also infinitely exquisitly gentle.
How can it be all powerful and
How can it be all powerful and yet
gentle?
Can't
Can't explain
gentle?
Can't explain it.
It's
It's absolute
and
and yet
It's absolute
and yet it's
and yet it's like
It's absolute
and yet it's like a
and yet it's like a kitten's
It's absolute
and yet it's like a kitten's paw.
It
It melts
It melts you
It melts you by
It melts you by it
It melts you by it melts
It melts you by it melts what
It melts you by it melts what was
It melts you by it melts what was left
of
of thinkingness
It melts you by it melts what was left
of thinkingness and
of thinkingness and mind
It melts you by it melts what was left
of thinkingness and mind and
of thinkingness and mind and any
illusion
illusion that
illusion that that's
illusion that that's who
illusion that that's who you
illusion that that's who you are.
illusion that that's who you are. The
Heisenberg
Heisenberg process
illusion that that's who you are. The
Heisenberg process then
Heisenberg process then so
illusion that that's who you are. The
Heisenberg process then so spiritual
work
work is
work is set
work is set by
work is set by intention.
work is set by intention. Intention.
And
And that's
work is set by intention. Intention.
And that's why
And that's why I
work is set by intention. Intention.
And that's why I thought
And that's why I thought it
work is set by intention. Intention.
And that's why I thought it was
And that's why I thought it was an
important
important book
important book Wayne
important book Wayne Dyer
important book Wayne Dyer wrote
important book Wayne Dyer wrote because
he
he devoted
important book Wayne Dyer wrote because
he devoted a
he devoted a whole
important book Wayne Dyer wrote because
he devoted a whole book
he devoted a whole book to
important book Wayne Dyer wrote because
he devoted a whole book to the
he devoted a whole book to the power
important book Wayne Dyer wrote because
he devoted a whole book to the power of
intention.
Then
Then because
intention.
Then because of
Then because of your
intention.
Then because of your intention
Then because of your intention then
intention.
Then because of your intention then the
potentiality
potentiality becomes
potentiality becomes an
potentiality becomes an actuality
potentiality becomes an actuality either
in
in thought
potentiality becomes an actuality either
in thought or
in thought or in
potentiality becomes an actuality either
in thought or in higher
in thought or in higher frequencies
potentiality becomes an actuality either
in thought or in higher frequencies not
necessarily
necessarily physical.
When
When you
necessarily physical.
When you say
When you say yes,
necessarily physical.
When you say yes, when
When you say yes, when you
necessarily physical.
When you say yes, when you say
When you say yes, when you say yes,
necessarily physical.
When you say yes, when you say yes, then
you've
you've just
you've just collapsed
you've just collapsed the
you've just collapsed the wave
you've just collapsed the wave function,
meaning
meaning from
you've just collapsed the wave function,
meaning from potential
meaning from potential to
you've just collapsed the wave function,
meaning from potential to actual.
The
The power
The power of
The power of prayer.
The power of prayer. As
The power of prayer. As we
The power of prayer. As we said,
The power of prayer. As we said, the
Ganges
Ganges River
The power of prayer. As we said, the
Ganges River calibrates
Ganges River calibrates over
The power of prayer. As we said, the
Ganges River calibrates over 500.
Everybody
Everybody says,
Everybody says, "Let's
Everybody says, "Let's clean
Everybody says, "Let's clean it
Everybody says, "Let's clean it up.
Everybody says, "Let's clean it up. It's
the
the filthiest
Everybody says, "Let's clean it up. It's
the filthiest river
the filthiest river on
Everybody says, "Let's clean it up. It's
the filthiest river on the
the filthiest river on the planet."
Everybody says, "Let's clean it up. It's
the filthiest river on the planet." It
is.
is. It's
is. It's disgusting.
I
I died
is. It's disgusting.
I died a
I died a number
is. It's disgusting.
I died a number of
I died a number of lifetimes
is. It's disgusting.
I died a number of lifetimes on
I died a number of lifetimes on the
banks
banks of
banks of the
banks of the Ganges
banks of the Ganges on
banks of the Ganges on the
banks of the Ganges on the Gats
banks of the Ganges on the Gats burning
gats.
gats. It's
banks of the Ganges on the Gats burning
gats. It's disgustingly
gats. It's disgustingly filthy,
banks of the Ganges on the Gats burning
gats. It's disgustingly filthy, full
gats. It's disgustingly filthy, full of
excrement
excrement and
excrement and dead
excrement and dead bodies
excrement and dead bodies and
excrement and dead bodies and garbage.
It's
It's the
excrement and dead bodies and garbage.
It's the dumping
It's the dumping ground
excrement and dead bodies and garbage.
It's the dumping ground for
It's the dumping ground for 100
excrement and dead bodies and garbage.
It's the dumping ground for 100 cities
along
along the
along the Ganges
along the Ganges River.
Yeah.
Yeah. And
along the Ganges River.
Yeah. And some
Yeah. And some environmental
along the Ganges River.
Yeah. And some environmental group
Yeah. And some environmental group wants
to
to clean
to clean it
to clean it up.
God
God bless
to clean it up.
God bless them.
It
It calibrates
It calibrates over
It calibrates over 500.
It calibrates over 500. The
It calibrates over 500. The power
It calibrates over 500. The power of
intention
intention of
It calibrates over 500. The power of
intention of millions
intention of millions of
It calibrates over 500. The power of
intention of millions of Hindus
intention of millions of Hindus bathing
and
and purifying
and purifying themselves
and purifying themselves in
and purifying themselves in the
and purifying themselves in the Ganges
River.
River. The
and purifying themselves in the Ganges
River. The Ganges
River. The Ganges River
and purifying themselves in the Ganges
River. The Ganges River calibrates
River. The Ganges River calibrates over
500.
500. Huh?
Higher
Higher than
500. Huh?
Higher than the
Higher than the water
500. Huh?
Higher than the water in
Higher than the water in your
500. Huh?
Higher than the water in your faucet.
The
The Ganges
The Ganges River
The Ganges River calibrates
The Ganges River calibrates higher
The Ganges River calibrates higher than
the
the water
The Ganges River calibrates higher than
the water in
the water in your
The Ganges River calibrates higher than
the water in your faucet
the water in your faucet at
The Ganges River calibrates higher than
the water in your faucet at home.
Resist.
Calibrates
Calibrates higher
Resist.
Calibrates higher than
Calibrates higher than your
Resist.
Calibrates higher than your water
Calibrates higher than your water in
your
your faucet.
your faucet. So
your faucet. So you
your faucet. So you ought
your faucet. So you ought to
your faucet. So you ought to be
your faucet. So you ought to be scared
of
of drinking
your faucet. So you ought to be scared
of drinking the
of drinking the water
your faucet. So you ought to be scared
of drinking the water out
of drinking the water out of
your faucet. So you ought to be scared
of drinking the water out of your
faucet.
faucet. Not
faucet. Not the
faucet. Not the Genji's
faucet. Not the Genji's River.
All
All right.
faucet. Not the Genji's River.
All right. So
All right. So the
faucet. Not the Genji's River.
All right. So the direct
All right. So the direct process
faucet. Not the Genji's River.
All right. So the direct process then
All right. So the direct process then is
a
a mathematical
a mathematical calculation.
The
The universe
a mathematical calculation.
The universe went
The universe went from
a mathematical calculation.
The universe went from this
The universe went from this potentiality
by
by intention.
by intention. You
by intention. You collapsed
by intention. You collapsed the
by intention. You collapsed the wave
function.
function. It
by intention. You collapsed the wave
function. It now
function. It now has
by intention. You collapsed the wave
function. It now has now
function. It now has now it's
by intention. You collapsed the wave
function. It now has now it's at
function. It now has now it's at this
actuality.
actuality. You
actuality. You can
actuality. You can calculate
actuality. You can calculate it
mathematically
mathematically by
actuality. You can calculate it
mathematically by the
mathematically by the durac
actuality. You can calculate it
mathematically by the durac equation.
And
And this
And this is
And this is an
And this is an explanation
And this is an explanation of
And this is an explanation of the
Heisenberg
Heisenberg process.
And this is an explanation of the
Heisenberg process. And
Heisenberg process. And I
And this is an explanation of the
Heisenberg process. And I tell
Heisenberg process. And I tell people
And this is an explanation of the
Heisenberg process. And I tell people if
you're
you're interested
you're interested in
you're interested in this
you're interested in this you
you're interested in this you see
you're interested in this you see Henry
Stap
Stap on
you're interested in this you see Henry
Stap on the
Stap on the internet
you're interested in this you see Henry
Stap on the internet www.
That
That stands
That stands for
That stands for world
That stands for world worldwide
That stands for world worldwide web.
The
The worldwide
That stands for world worldwide web.
The worldwide web.
The worldwide web. You
That stands for world worldwide web.
The worldwide web. You look
The worldwide web. You look up
That stands for world worldwide web.
The worldwide web. You look up Henry
Stappa.
Stappa. That's
Stappa. That's with
Stappa. That's with two
Stappa. That's with two P's.
Stappa. That's with two P's. And
Stappa. That's with two P's. And he
explains
explains the
Stappa. That's with two P's. And he
explains the whole
explains the whole thing.
Stappa. That's with two P's. And he
explains the whole thing. You
explains the whole thing. You won't
understand
understand it
understand it then
understand it then either,
understand it then either, but
understand it then either, but at
understand it then either, but at least
you
you got
understand it then either, but at least
you got it
you got it on
understand it then either, but at least
you got it on your
you got it on your You
understand it then either, but at least
you got it on your You got
you got it on your You got it
understand it then either, but at least
you got it on your You got it on
you got it on your You got it on your
computer.
Intention
Intention then
computer.
Intention then is
Intention then is an
computer.
Intention then is an emanation
Intention then is an emanation of
consciousness
consciousness itself.
consciousness itself. a
consciousness itself. a radiance
consciousness itself. a radiance from
consciousness
consciousness and
consciousness itself. a radiance from
consciousness and the
consciousness and the intention
consciousness itself. a radiance from
consciousness and the intention will
what
what you
what you intend
what you intend then
what you intend then will
what you intend then will determine
what you intend then will determine what
you
you find.
what you intend then will determine what
you find. That's
you find. That's the
what you intend then will determine what
you find. That's the value
you find. That's the value of
what you intend then will determine what
you find. That's the value of the
you find. That's the value of the search
engine
engine on
engine on the
engine on the www.
set
set the
engine on the www.
set the search
set the search engine
engine on the www.
set the search engine and
set the search engine and it
engine on the www.
set the search engine and it finds
set the search engine and it finds what
your
your intention
your intention is
your intention is to
your intention is to find.
Right.
Right. Yes.
www
www search
www search engine.
www search engine. Uh
www search engine. Uh so
www search engine. Uh so your
www search engine. Uh so your intention
determines
determines what
www search engine. Uh so your intention
determines what you
determines what you will
www search engine. Uh so your intention
determines what you will discover.
Now
Now if
Now if your
Now if your intention
Now if your intention is
Now if your intention is to
Now if your intention is to prove
Now if your intention is to prove that
somebody
somebody is
Now if your intention is to prove that
somebody is evil,
somebody is evil, you
Now if your intention is to prove that
somebody is evil, you will
somebody is evil, you will discover
Now if your intention is to prove that
somebody is evil, you will discover that
they're
they're evil.
they're evil. If
they're evil. If your
they're evil. If your intention
they're evil. If your intention is
they're evil. If your intention is to
discover
discover that
they're evil. If your intention is to
discover that somebody
discover that somebody is
they're evil. If your intention is to
discover that somebody is integrous,
discover that somebody is integrous, you
will
will see
will see the
will see the integrity
will see the integrity in
will see the integrity in them.
will see the integrity in them. See?
will see the integrity in them. See? So
intention
intention then
will see the integrity in them. See? So
intention then decides
intention then decides what
will see the integrity in them. See? So
intention then decides what you
intention then decides what you will
discover.
So
So those
discover.
So those who
So those who set
discover.
So those who set your
So those who set your intention
discover.
So those who set your intention on
So those who set your intention on truth
is
is a
is a pathway
is a pathway to
is a pathway to God.
is a pathway to God. What
is a pathway to God. What about
is a pathway to God. What about the
heart?
It
It says
It says devotion.
It says devotion. Devotion.
It says devotion. Devotion. So
It says devotion. Devotion. So the
heart,
heart, the
It says devotion. Devotion. So the
heart, the devotion
heart, the devotion is
It says devotion. Devotion. So the
heart, the devotion is to
heart, the devotion is to truth
It says devotion. Devotion. So the
heart, the devotion is to truth because
truth
truth is
a
a the
truth is
a the radiation
a the radiation of
truth is
a the radiation of divinity
a the radiation of divinity as
truth is
a the radiation of divinity as it
a the radiation of divinity as it is
knowable
knowable in
knowable in this
knowable in this domain.
The
The way
knowable in this domain.
The way to
The way to God
knowable in this domain.
The way to God then
The way to God then is
knowable in this domain.
The way to God then is through
The way to God then is through truth
knowable in this domain.
The way to God then is through truth and
that
that which
that which is
that which is verifiable
that which is verifiable truth,
verifiable
verifiable truth.
that which is verifiable truth,
verifiable truth. If
verifiable truth. If it's
that which is verifiable truth,
verifiable truth. If it's truth,
verifiable truth. If it's truth, it
should
should be
should be verifiable.
So
So people
should be verifiable.
So people can
So people can come
should be verifiable.
So people can come on
So people can come on voseiferous
should be verifiable.
So people can come on voseiferous with
So people can come on voseiferous with a
certain
certain positionality.
But
But if
certain positionality.
But if it
But if it was
certain positionality.
But if it was so,
But if it was so, it
certain positionality.
But if it was so, it would
But if it was so, it would calibrate
over
over 200
over 200 and
over 200 and it
over 200 and it doesn't.
over 200 and it doesn't. So
over 200 and it doesn't. So I
over 200 and it doesn't. So I follow
over 200 and it doesn't. So I follow the
highest
highest numbers.
I
I don't
I don't follow
I don't follow anything
I don't follow anything except
I don't follow anything except just
I don't follow anything except just the
highest
highest numbers,
I don't follow anything except just the
highest numbers, folks,
highest numbers, folks, you
I don't follow anything except just the
highest numbers, folks, you know.
Read
Read the
Read the label.
Read the label. The
Read the label. The label
Read the label. The label on
Read the label. The label on this
Read the label. The label on this new
editorial.
We
We did
We did the
We did the editorial
We did the editorial section
We did the editorial section of
We did the editorial section of the
Chicago
Chicago Tribune
We did the editorial section of the
Chicago Tribune when
Chicago Tribune when we
We did the editorial section of the
Chicago Tribune when we were
Chicago Tribune when we were there
We did the editorial section of the
Chicago Tribune when we were there last
week.
week. It
week. It was
week. It was 195.
week. It was 195. Yeah.
week. It was 195. Yeah. 195.
week. It was 195. Yeah. 195. Chicago
Tribune.
Uh
Uh actually
Uh actually the
Uh actually the paper
Uh actually the paper newspaper
Uh actually the paper newspaper that
calibrates
calibrates the
Uh actually the paper newspaper that
calibrates the highest
calibrates the highest is
Uh actually the paper newspaper that
calibrates the highest is the
calibrates the highest is the Wall
Street
Street Journal
Street Journal and
Street Journal and the
Street Journal and the Christian
Street Journal and the Christian Science
Monitor.
Monitor. So
Street Journal and the Christian Science
Monitor. So if
Monitor. So if you're
Street Journal and the Christian Science
Monitor. So if you're interested
Monitor. So if you're interested in
truth,
they
they seem
truth,
they seem to
they seem to be
truth,
they seem to be more
they seem to be more aligned
truth,
they seem to be more aligned with
they seem to be more aligned with it.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So that's
All right. So that's the
All right. So that's the new
All right. So that's the new now
Einstein
Einstein didn't
All right. So that's the new now
Einstein didn't like
Einstein didn't like this
All right. So that's the new now
Einstein didn't like this idea
Einstein didn't like this idea because
it
it challenged
you
you see
it challenged
you see we
you see we go
it challenged
you see we go back
you see we go back to
it challenged
you see we go back to the
you see we go back to the old
it challenged
you see we go back to the old principle
of
of rest
of rest internal
of rest internal and
of rest internal and rest
of rest internal and rest external
uh
uh so
of rest internal and rest external
uh so Einstein
uh
uh bucked
uh bucked at
uh bucked at the
uh bucked at the subjectivity
uh bucked at the subjectivity the
concept
concept of
uh bucked at the subjectivity the
concept of subjectivity
concept of subjectivity and
uh bucked at the subjectivity the
concept of subjectivity and all
concept of subjectivity and all of
science
science still
science still does
science still does that
science still does that all
science still does that all of
science still does that all of science
we
we just
science still does that all of science
we just did
we just did um
science still does that all of science
we just did um one
we just did um one of
science still does that all of science
we just did um one of the
we just did um one of the most
science still does that all of science
we just did um one of the most famous
scientists
scientists on
scientists on the
scientists on the planet
uh
whose
whose current
whose current research
whose current research despite
whose current research despite his
whose current research despite his age
is
is devoted
whose current research despite his age
is devoted to
is devoted to proving
whose current research despite his age
is devoted to proving that
is devoted to proving that there
whose current research despite his age
is devoted to proving that there is
nothing
nothing beyond
nothing beyond death.
Yeah.
Yeah. Let's
nothing beyond death.
Yeah. Let's see.
Yeah. Let's see. Well,
nothing beyond death.
Yeah. Let's see. Well, that
Yeah. Let's see. Well, that proposition
calibrates
calibrates over
calibrates over 200.
He's
He's Oh,
calibrates over 200.
He's Oh, I
He's Oh, I see.
calibrates over 200.
He's Oh, I see. He's
He's Oh, I see. He's integrous
calibrates over 200.
He's Oh, I see. He's integrous in
proving
proving it.
proving it. Okay.
proving it. Okay. He's
proving it. Okay. He's integrous
proving it. Okay. He's integrous in
proving
proving it.
proving it. Okay. He's integrous in
proving it. He's
proving it. He's like
proving it. Okay. He's integrous in
proving it. He's like I
proving it. He's like I was
proving it. Okay. He's integrous in
proving it. He's like I was when
proving it. He's like I was when I
proving it. Okay. He's integrous in
proving it. He's like I was when I was
an
an atheist.
an atheist. I
an atheist. I was
an atheist. I was an
an atheist. I was an integrous
an atheist. I was an integrous atheist.
I
I wasn't
an atheist. I was an integrous atheist.
I wasn't ducking
I wasn't ducking doing
an atheist. I was an integrous atheist.
I wasn't ducking doing it
I wasn't ducking doing it to
an atheist. I was an integrous atheist.
I wasn't ducking doing it to duck
responsibility
responsibility or
responsibility or duck
responsibility or duck guilt
responsibility or duck guilt or
something.
But
But frankly,
But frankly, I
But frankly, I believe
But frankly, I believe that
But frankly, I believe that was
But frankly, I believe that was the
truth.
truth. I
But frankly, I believe that was the
truth. I was
truth. I was a
But frankly, I believe that was the
truth. I was a very
truth. I was a very serious
But frankly, I believe that was the
truth. I was a very serious atheist,
truth. I was a very serious atheist, you
know.
know. Okay,
know. Okay, we'll
know. Okay, we'll go
know. Okay, we'll go on
know. Okay, we'll go on to
know. Okay, we'll go on to the
know. Okay, we'll go on to the next.
Uh
Uh this
know. Okay, we'll go on to the next.
Uh this is
Uh this is just
know. Okay, we'll go on to the next.
Uh this is just a
Uh this is just a recap
know. Okay, we'll go on to the next.
Uh this is just a recap of
Uh this is just a recap of what
know. Okay, we'll go on to the next.
Uh this is just a recap of what we
Uh this is just a recap of what we were
talking
talking about
talking about this
talking about this morning.
talking about this morning. By
understanding
understanding the
talking about this morning. By
understanding the evolution
understanding the evolution of
consciousness,
consciousness, then
consciousness, then you
consciousness, then you get
consciousness, then you get off
consciousness, then you get off your
guilt
guilt about
consciousness, then you get off your
guilt about it.
guilt about it. You
consciousness, then you get off your
guilt about it. You get
guilt about it. You get off
guilt.
guilt. You
guilt. You get
guilt. You get off
guilt. You get off hating
guilt. You get off hating others.
Because
Because if
guilt. You get off hating others.
Because if your
Because if your consciousness
guilt. You get off hating others.
Because if your consciousness represents
the
the evolution
the evolution of
the evolution of consciousness
the evolution of consciousness via
the evolution of consciousness via this
pathway,
pathway, where
the evolution of consciousness via this
pathway, where somebody
pathway, where somebody else
the evolution of consciousness via this
pathway, where somebody else is
pathway, where somebody else is is
the evolution of consciousness via this
pathway, where somebody else is is where
theirs
theirs has
theirs has taken
theirs has taken them.
So
So a
theirs has taken them.
So a politician
So a politician who
theirs has taken them.
So a politician who comes
So a politician who comes off
theirs has taken them.
So a politician who comes off of
So a politician who comes off of service
at
at 190,
at 190, that's
at 190, that's as
at 190, that's as far
at 190, that's as far as
at 190, that's as far as he
at 190, that's as far as he I
at 190, that's as far as he I mean
that's
that's where
at 190, that's as far as he I mean
that's where he's
that's where he's gone
at 190, that's as far as he I mean
that's where he's gone to,
that's where he's gone to, but
at 190, that's as far as he I mean
that's where he's gone to, but he's
that's where he's gone to, but he's not
at
at 20
at 20 anymore.
at 20 anymore. He's
at 20 anymore. He's not
at 20 anymore. He's not at
at 20 anymore. He's not at 40.
at 20 anymore. He's not at 40. So
at 20 anymore. He's not at 40. So each
calibrated
calibrated level
at 20 anymore. He's not at 40. So each
calibrated level of
calibrated level of consciousness
at 20 anymore. He's not at 40. So each
calibrated level of consciousness is
calibrated level of consciousness is an
advance
advance above
advance above that
advance above that below
advance above that below it.
Everything
Everything serves
advance above that below it.
Everything serves that
Everything serves that which
advance above that below it.
Everything serves that which is
Everything serves that which is below
it.
A
A basic
it.
A basic principle
A basic principle of
it.
A basic principle of the
A basic principle of the rig
it.
A basic principle of the rig vida
A basic principle of the rig vida is
it.
A basic principle of the rig vida is one
there's
there's been
there's been one
there's been one big
there's been one big section
there's been one big section on
sacrifice
that
that each
that each level
that each level of
that each level of consciousness
that each level of consciousness each
level
level of
that each level of consciousness each
level of life
level of life is
that each level of consciousness each
level of life is sacrificial
level of life is sacrificial to
that each level of consciousness each
level of life is sacrificial to the
level of life is sacrificial to the one
above
above it.
above it. And
above it. And by
above it. And by sacrificing
above it. And by sacrificing itself
above it. And by sacrificing itself to
that
that which
above it. And by sacrificing itself to
that which is
that which is higher,
above it. And by sacrificing itself to
that which is higher, it
that which is higher, it karmically
earns
earns the
earns the karmic
earns the karmic credit
earns the karmic credit to
earns the karmic credit to become
earns the karmic credit to become the
higher.
As
As I
As I say,
As I say, I
As I say, I I
As I say, I I am
As I say, I I am a
As I say, I I am a representative
As I say, I I am a representative of
As I say, I I am a representative of the
vegetable
vegetable kingdom.
I've
I've been
I've been here
I've been here to
I've been here to protest
people
people eating
I've been here to protest
people eating them.
They
They kill
They kill them.
They kill them. Besides,
They kill them. Besides, you
They kill them. Besides, you know,
They kill them. Besides, you know, kill
them
them and
They kill them. Besides, you know, kill
them and eat
them and eat them.
They kill them. Besides, you know, kill
them and eat them. And
them and eat them. And I'm
They kill them. Besides, you know, kill
them and eat them. And I'm here
them and eat them. And I'm here to
pronounce
pronounce their
pronounce their official
pronounce their official protest.
Except
Except by
pronounce their official protest.
Except by so
Except by so doing,
pronounce their official protest.
Except by so doing, they
Except by so doing, they become
pronounce their official protest.
Except by so doing, they become part
Except by so doing, they become part of
us,
us, do
us, do they
us, do they not?
us, do they not? They
us, do they not? They evolve.
us, do they not? They evolve. Their
consciousness
consciousness now
us, do they not? They evolve. Their
consciousness now becomes
consciousness now becomes incorporated
with
with within
with within us.
with within us. And
with within us. And the
with within us. And the way
with within us. And the way the
dandelion
dandelion returns
with within us. And the way the
dandelion returns to
dandelion returns to God
with within us. And the way the
dandelion returns to God is
dandelion returns to God is through
with within us. And the way the
dandelion returns to God is through us.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu