you see Hobbes, you see all the great names of history, and then you see
Immanuel Kant who set up the categories, the categories of abstraction, and all
the time on television you hear people violate the various levels, they violate
the various levels. Here's the great names, Sir Isaac Newton, so there's three
interesting geniuses, Sigmund Freud calibrates at 499, Sir Isaac Newton
calibrates at 499, who is Z equals something, C squared? Einstein at 499, all
of them. See because at 500 there's a new paradigm. You move from that which is
supposedly objective logical sequential to the subjective, which is not provable.
Advanced spiritual truth then is not provable because it's a
different paradigm. That which is provable is not spiritual truth,
because you are always in competition.
Because you would be stating something within the limitation of the dualistic Newtonian paradigm, which is linear.
Spiritual reality is non-linear, not provable, not demonstrable, subjectively experiential, and hugely transformative.
Even one or two mild spiritual experiences, whoa, not to mention a near-death experience or something transformative like that.
Which totally changes you forever.
Near-death experience.
This is as far as the human psyche goes.
Sophocles, the great names of history.
The great names of history.
And when I was a kid, Socrates was my hero.
Socrates, of course, didn't write anything.
But, of course, his teachings are well described in Plato, etc.
Socrates calibrates at 512.
He was, to me, a great spiritual teacher, one of my heroes.
Socrates, actually, was willing to die for truth.
Now, in the days of Socrates, there wasn't the Catholic Church.
Buddhism was on the other side of the world.
Hindu sages were on the other side of the world.
And, therefore, in a really, in a way, non-religious society, Socrates intuited truth at the level of 540, unconditional love.
And Socrates, when he was accused of perverting the minds of youth by teaching them the kind of things I'm teaching today.
Where's my hemlock, by the way?
Either had to change what he was teaching or drink the hemlock.
Socrates chose hemlock rather than violate the truth.
Socrates chose death rather than physical life because of his alignment with truth.
One of Socrates' best sayings is a very useful one.
And, pragmatically, for all of us on an almost daily basis.
In fact, even now, with the coming elections, it's very good to know.
Socrates said something that really resolves just about everything.
Man only chooses the good.
Man always chooses the good.
In fact, he can only choose that which he envisions as good.
The only trouble is he doesn't know which is the good.
And he chooses the temporary and illusory rather than the infinite and perpetual.
On the other hand, his intention is always to choose what he feels to be the good.
What he thinks to be the good.
Unfortunately, it might be killing you.
Blowing up a busload of children.
But, he believes that it is for the good.
So that sort of seconds man's intrinsic innocence because the Buddha, Krishna, and Christ,
every great being that ever lived, said man only has one defect.
And that's ignorance.
He doesn't know the good from the bad.
He doesn't know.
He thinks that it's good.
So he votes for illusion.
He sacrifices his life for illusion because he cannot tell truth from falsehood.
You see the incredible gift that we have right now?
For the first time in the evolution of all of time, we can tell truth from falsehood.
Not only that, but within an instant.
Wow. Think of the positive karma of a group like this.
People on the earth today now, for the first time, can tell truth from falsehood.
Man only chooses the good.
So those of us who look favorably on the Course in Miracles,
you know, the Course in Miracles is based on forgiveness.
Well, how can you forgive people if they're wrong?
That's the question that always arises.
And if they're bad and evil, how can you forgive people if they're wrong, bad, and evil?
It's because...
They saw that, was that killing you was to their highest good.
The fact that they get to go to heaven, and 3,000 kids get to be blown up in a bus is the price of it,
would seem to us an illusion.
But perhaps to their extreme viewpoint, that is truth.
So therefore, we can see the innate innocence.
Because each of us, then, is born with hardware, the hardware,
and then superimposed...
Superimposed on that is software.
Well, the hardware cannot protect itself against the software.
The human mind is like the hardware.
And now it gets programmed with software.
It doesn't have any switch.
That when you try to put falsity into it, it goes...
Doesn't do that.
That's the tragedy.
So we can see that instead of evil and hatred,
perhaps compassion for the tragedy of ignorance,
the tragedy of ignorance costs the lives of 10 million, 10 million.
Now, the calibrated levels of the great books of the Western world calibrate around 450 or something.
But if you remove this guy here, Karl Marx, the whole collective total comes out at 460.
So the difficulty with the recent world and today's social world is the perpetrator-victim model,
the dualistic creation.
Marx had an unresolved...
method of a complex.
And he revolted against the leading philosopher of his day, Hegel.
When Hegel's basic teachings was that of the absolute,
what you saw that he demonstrated is the influence of the absolute.
The infinite field of consciousness, which is what we consult with kinesiology all the time,
is the absolute field.
Hegel said,
all are accountable because of the principle of the absolute.
Well, if there's anything that Eagleton...
ego hates is to hear that it's not God. The ego secretly thinks it is God, and it hates God and
disguises that hatred in many forms. At least the secularists are honest. They hate God, and the word
makes them very nervous and upset, so they want to remove it. At least they're honest about it, you
see. The ego is more clever than that. It gets rid of God by getting rid of the sovereignty of the
absolute, the sovereignty of the absolute. It's the sovereignty of the absolute that the core of the
narcissistic ego hates, and the ego hates God. So, Marx had an unresolved, edible complex. I speak as a,
you know, I did 50 years of psychoanalysis and psychiatry, was psychoanalyzed by myself, one of the
world's most famous and best. Deep within the unconscious, there is a hatred of that which
represents authority, the father figure.
If your experience with your father was benign, you see authority as friendly and protective. If your
experience or your image, not necessarily your reality experience, at least your image of your father, was
threatening, then you confuse authority with authoritarianism, and you hate all authority because you think
it's authoritarian, and you fail to see the legitimacy of true authority. For one thing, information, fact, and
knowledge is itself an authority.
So, the current relativistic philosophers even hate science and logic, you know, the problematic hermeneutics of relativistic epistemology.
You first heard it here.
The probabilistic hermeneutics of relativistic epistemology is why the classroom of America, which used to calibrate in the
1800s, it now calibrates to about 190.
The denigration of logic, reason, the discipline that goes with that.
Yeah, so, anyway, because of Marx's unresolved Oedipal Complex, he, which I say is a fact, resist, he was his Oedipal Complex,
resist. Okay, just check my psychoanalysts, see if he's right. I sweated it out on couch, so I mean I'm screaming.
Okay, just check my psychoanalysts, see if he's right. I sweated it out on couch, so I mean I'm screaming.
experientially. You know, 50 years of psychiatry, nobody ever came in
that didn't have an Oedipal complex or so on. He would be from a different planet
because you grow up with parents, so you're going to see one view as the maternal
permissive, all-inclusive, non-judgmental, and then you're going to
see the father figure that says, yes, that's nice, but
if you've got a job, you've got to go to work every day. You just can't call in and say, I don't feel like
going to work today. You won't have a job on Monday. The maternal
is permissive and inclusive, and the paternal stands
more for the survival in the external world.
Anyway, Hegel was the authority father figure,
and its impact, this unresolved Oedipal complex here
has impacted all of life in our current society.
That error, that error of failure
of truth, that fallacy, has cost tens of millions
of lives.
Millions of lives have been slaughtered by the error of
projecting, rest in turn, seeing perpetrator and victim
out there in the world. There is no perpetrator and victim out there in the world.
Everything comes about as a consequence of the field,
plus your karma and your calibrated level of consciousness.
How can you turn everything into perpetrator and victim? You'll see that's today's
social contention, the whole litiginous, sociologic
disaster.
A disaster sees everything as innocent victim and
wicked perpetrator.
No such thing exists in the world.
That is a perception projected onto society.
A company moves into town, theology of Wisconsin, and their
county company at heine's ball or other poor little farmer
neighborhood.
Now people, they're crops are bought instantly, whole crop.
The company makes money because they're maping their future to a new type of farming.
they've got inexpensive labor and they're right there in the middle of
where the growing fields are the town prospers people now can buy cars they
can afford telephones and they put down electricity electricity down one side of
the highway and company makes money and people invest in the company and the
consumer gets products on the field you don't have to can all your own peas so I
worked there and you got paid a nickel an hour for everything extra over 12
hours 30 cents an hour and if you work more than 12 hours you got 35 cents
everybody was happy I was happy I had an income the town was happy the company
was happy then how do you find a perpetrator and victim in there you have
that as a belief system now you walk into the town you say well look the
company's exploiting the workers then you can walk the other way around say
the workers are milking the company no no now the townspeople are willed
milking the employees oh no the employees are milking the townspeople no
the shopkeepers are but this is all happening in your head I lived there I
experienced it I got the 30 to 35 cents I used to hope that it would last over
12 hours guys because I got 35 cents you can call that oppressive if you want but
I'll tell you when you need money I was happy to have there's your five cents an
hour and as you can make $40 a month I mean you know riches Rockefeller yeah
therefore the error so to be able to use calibration techniques how can you
tell if a statement is truthful or not truthful yeah unless you can depend on a
reliable source of discerning truth and falsehood the kinesiologic method is the
first way 135 is way down from truth isn't it what truth is at 200 135 is
way down now you've got huge countries
China Russia giant countries being run by a consciousness level belief system at
135 135 brings death destruction paranoia the KGB the secret police
secret killings brings pull pot or pot pull whatever that is name is pull pot
pull went to pot potty pull I don't know what it is
I mean yet you know we're not just speaking academically today talking
about the lives of tens of millions of people in my lifetime died for
falsehood tens of millions tens of millions died for falsehood the
inability to discern truth from falsehood hmm
all right so here's the content here's the proximate field years the internet
field so here's the Internet field of consciousness
infinitely power. This is powerful. This is what we consult with kinesiology. This is the absolute
as compared to the absolute, which is infinite. This statement calibrates so far. So this is the
absolute spoken of by Hegel and which would give Karl Marx nightmares if he was reborn today,
because I'd say this is the criteria of truth and not your narcissistic ego. This is the proximate
field. The second naivete is any statement is only true within a stated context. The naivete of the
human mind, it thinks only in terms of limitation. This is not a great diagram, but we're going to
make a better one. We were going to make a better diagram. Anyway, this is the linear definable
world of Newtonian.
In science, you can measure it. This is the field of the scientific reductionist, the materialistic
reductionist. Unless you can measure it, weigh it, score it, it's not real. This is the linear
statement that so-and-so is true, that so-and-so lied, so-and-so didn't lie, et cetera, that a
certain law violates human rights or something.
The statement is only true within a certain context. That's true under this context. It is not true
on another context. The rules that apply to the population in times of war are quite different than
the ones that apply in times of peace. It's confused. So truth is only true if you state in what
context, in what context. So the context then is the proximate field. The proximate field is the
conditions, climate, population, wealth, a thousand things. A thing is only true under certain
conditions. The conditions which the naive mind thinks are causal, they're not causal. They're just
conditions. Rain and humidity and barometric pressure and altitude. If you try to find the
cause of anything within the Newtonian paradigm of cause and effect, you will find that every single
event, supposed event, has an infinite number of causes, that the world of causality is an illusion.
If you say, what is the cause of this little speck of dust being here right now? Well, it depends on
the barometric pressure, the ozone, depends on the altitude, depends on the wind speed, it depends on
what time of the year, it depends on temperature, barometric pressure. It would have to occur in a
building, so somebody would have to create this building for this little piece of dust to be here,
and this building requires a state to be in.
Which requires a globe, which requires a universe. So you can see a complete explanation of why this
little piece of dust is right here. The number of factors is infinite, infinite, infinite. And then
you will realize that you're dealing in an illusion. There is no cause for it to be, because phenomena
are like clouds appearing in the sky. The cloud appears as a consequence of the totality of the
environment, condensing and presenting itself thusly.
There's no cause for a cloud. No cause. No cause. It's not caused. It's the consequence of the field.
When all factors are favorable, then it emerges spontaneously of its own. And when they're not, it fades away
of its own. You say, well, the wind is causing it. The wind's not causing it, there's wind there all the time.
All right, so this is the infinite contact which we can solve, the absolute, when we consult with kinesiologists.
We say, as compared to the absolute, this calibrates as so much. Okay, we'll move on.
The content field and context, this is just in words. The content in the center is limited.
That's the ego, the linear, definable, measurable, and it deals in force.
The infinite field deals in power. Force moves from here to there. Consequently, force always creates
counter-force.
As Napoleon and everybody else has found out through history, forcing people to do things results in counter-force.
If it evolves as a consequence of the field, then it has no enemies, because now it's coming out of power.
And power is aligned with truth. Therefore, that which is truthful, then, and integrous, eventually influences
what is witnessed within the world, but not in a cause and effect way. It may be delayed over time.
Why? Because truth then begins to set a context by which everything is measured. Everything is measured by.
And its effect may be slow. So, force is quick and temporary. Power is slow.
So, force is like hitting something, and power is like gravity. Gravity just stands there.
Now, force, you have to constantly feed it energy. It's always wearing out. You have to feed it.
Military supplies, battle, money, tax money, etc.
Force then exhausts itself and creates counter-force.
Power then just merely stands there, controls everything within it.
Every iron filing within the gravitational field is at the effect of the field.
It has no opposition. It has no opposite. So, truth has no opposite.
There is no opposite to truth. There is only its absence.
Truth is either present or not present.
With the kinesiologic response, what you see is in the presence of truth,
the energy flows down the acupuncture system. The body goes instantly strong in the presence of truth.
It's almost like protoplasm recognizes that which is supportive of life.
And in the presence of falsehood, the arm goes weak because protoplasm, on an even physical level,
protoplasm knows what is inimicable to life.
The amoeba goes towards that which supports its survival. It withdraws.
Even protoplasm, which is an impersonal response.
So, the kinesiologic response is impersonal.
The proximate field is the spiritual ego. It's semi-linear.
It seems to be random.
It's definable not within the Newtonian, but more by non-linear dynamics.
The field tends to quickly do a thing like, see what it did again?
If you don't watch it, it'll just fly out by itself.
You have to tuck it in someplace, make it stop.
It's unpredictable.
Extreme sports. I always say something about extreme sports.
Not trying to keep them alive past their time to leave this world.
Never.
But so you understand non-linear dynamics,
that after 32 jumps from the plane,
number 33 is coming up.
And that's the non-linear dynamics.
Out of regularity, unpredictably comes non-regularity.
Remember that computer chip had an error in the 26th decimal point?
Somebody in the audience always remembers the name of that chip.
Remember that? It was about 25 years ago?
Huh? Intel?
Okay. There was an error in the 26th decimal point.
And people said,
how often is the 26th decimal point going to come up?
Forget it.
Except that by iteration, meaning repetition,
millions and millions of times,
26th decimal point can only change the whole course of civilization.
Whoa.
So, all right.
So non-linear dynamics.
I always bring that up.
And the infinite context we call spirit.
Now, linear, unlimited.
It's purely experiential.
You cannot prove it.
It's self-existent.
It's subjective.
It's knowable.
It's experiential.
It's non-local.
Okay, we'll go to the next.
So just so we define the different context.
The spiritual foundation is a novelty in today's world.
But in the world I grew up, it's the way the world was.
In Wisconsin, this is the way everybody was.
Chicago, by the way, calibrates at 440.
So if you have an adolescent child who's lost himself,
and has to go someplace on the planet to find himself,
I'd suggest he go to Chicago.
Rather than Afghanistan or some place.
These are the virtues.
We're going to see how important they are.
They sound like, so what homilies, homilies.
No, in the world I grew up, everybody was this way.
Everybody went to Boy Scouts.
Everybody went to church.
Everybody was the Girl Scout.
Everybody belonged to the 4-H club.
Everybody was honest, reliable, and integrity, and polite.
Everybody was cordial.
Everybody did their homework.
Fairness was okay.
So we take these for granted.
You think everybody in the world is considerate, responsible, moral, warm, kind, easygoing, tolerant.
You try to control your temper.
You just don't ramble off all over the place.
You're friendly.
You meet somebody, you say, how do you do?
People are orderly.
They don't either slobby mess every place they go.
Pick up after yourself, young men.
We take these for granted.
Whole segments of society do not.
They do not pick up after themself.
One glimpse of a sidewalk anywhere in any big city, I can tell you what the caliber, level, consciousness of that city is.
Just one glance.
Everybody I grew up with was sane, fair, ethical.
People tried to stay healthy.
They were faithful.
Everybody had a sense of humor.
They were rational.
It was reasonable or not reasonable.
Everybody's intention was benign.
People were honorable.
People were automatically protective.
If you had a little kid with you, you protected it.
If it was somebody else's little kid, everybody was protective of life.
You tried to steer around the cat in the road and not run over it.
Everybody was humane.
If the animal was sick and aged and in suffering and pain, you tried to put it to sleep.
You had to do it, but you did it because you loved the animal, see?
Everybody's interested in being pleasing and happy and glad and positive.
People were generally the salt of the earth.
They tend to be modest, diplomatic, polite.
People are just sort of automatically nice to each other.
That's the world of the 200s and the 300s.
The 200s and the 300s.
It's positive emotion.
These are all emotion, but these are not positive.
From this, you can create a whole different life.
When you think of the large segments of the world's populations that do not express these,
they do not express these attitudes at all.
Our failure of diplomatic relations with such countries is that we assume they're this way.
They are not.
They think being honest is stupid, honorable is dumb, completely the opposite of what we believe.
We'll get to that later.
These are the virtues and their effect on brain physiology is what we have to get to.
We're going to move into that.
This is about the mind.
We said the mind is silent.
This mind, this thing is magnetic.
Isn't that something?
People say I try to meditate, I try to contemplate, but my mind is busy.
No, your mind is not busy.
Your mind, this is where your mind is, is silent.
This is 1% of your mind.
That which you think is your mind is 1%.
1%.
I try to meditate, but my mind just won't stop.
What won't stop is 1% of your mind is speaking.
How do you know it's speaking?
Because of the silence of the 99%.
You realize if it wasn't for the silence of the woods, you couldn't hear the birds song, could you?
It's because of the fact that your mind is blank.
It's blank.
That's why you can see the A.
The only reason you can see this A
is because of the whiteness of the blackboard.
Isn't that so?
If this was all jammed up with stuff, you couldn't read A.
Alright, so you're already quite well advanced.
99% of your mind is already silent.
And the 1% is speaking.
If it wasn't for the 99% being silent, you wouldn't know what the 1% was saying.
And the difficulty is not that you have a busy mind,
but you are hypnotized by the 1%.
Having heard that, you're already somewhat liberated from its dominance.
You think this is a huge mind full of all kinds of stuff.
How would you ever clear it out in a hundred lifetimes?
You don't have to.
The mind is 99% silent.
1% is speaking or imaging.
And what you've done is fallen into a hypnotic trance at the 1%.
You are hypnotized and in a trance by the 1%.
If it's a silent population, one person talks,
you're going to be dominated by that one person who talks.
Correct?
You're not going to listen to the fact that 999 of the people in this population are silent.
There's only one idiot chair-ringing away.
No, you're going to say, he is the genius and they're the dumb ones.
I will listen to him.
He knows how to talk.
He's linear.
You folks are non-linear.
I will listen to the linear and ignore the non-linear.
I will pay attention to the one frog in the ocean and ignore the entire ocean.
Now I think the whole ocean is full of frogs.
It's just this little frog here, folks.
This little frog.
The ocean is not full of frogs.
It's full of not-frogs.
Now how does this 1% keep you in its grip?
In its thrall, you know, in its thralldom?
How does it gain its power and dominance over you?
It's because it politicizes everything.
What would we watch at 5 o'clock or 6 o'clock on TV?
It politicizes, moralizes, idealizes, hypothesizes, romanticizes.
Wouldn't that be wonderful?
Criticizes, emotionalizes, dramatizes, fantasizes, prizes, theorizes.
What happens is the silence gets eyes to death.
It's always izing something.
Hypnotizing, victimizing, theorizing.
Perfecture to victimizing.
Let's move on to the next.
Uh-huh.
Well, this is held within consciousness and then it seems to be experiential.
It thinks the cause is here.
Actually, the concept is being held in consciousness and demonstrates out in the world.
The mind is then the effect, the final result.
Then the mind itself tends to have lower mind and higher mind.
Below 200 people mentate.
They mentate.
They don't think.
But they think they think.
And so there's a calibrated lower mind in esoteric psychology.
It calibrates at about 155.
And it's the one that the politician aims for.
This is the one...
The politician politician is trying to stir up your feelings and avoid reason, logic, and proof.
It can just accuse something of something and stir up the people.
It tries to avoid higher mind, which values truth, logic, and proof.
You see?
Say if somebody's a crook, you've got to have evidence that he's a crook and that he stole it, etc.
So this side is higher.
It's more...
It's more diffuse.
It's appreciative of the beauties of life.
It has power rather than...
He relies on the power of truth rather than force.
It's more open.
And we say that those people are more evolved.
That's the purpose of education is to move people out of just emotionalizing about everything.
You don't have to be a human to emotionalize about everything.
Just emotionalizing.
Just thinking about them, reflecting on them, beginning to get what the inference and the meaning is.
Okay.
So we move on.
The Power of Intention.
What's the name's new book called, The Power of Intention?
Wayne Dyer.
Yeah.
As I say, I read the last chapter because you could get it free off the internet.
The Power of Intention.
Yes.
Well, we said that this is how things come about.
As a consequence of intention, the field manifests as a consequence of intention of the infinite potentiality becoming an actuality.
So the need for a pointer actualizes a pointer.
It was the need.
The need of the pointer.
And then the person who had the pointer also had an intentionality to be useful of service or whatever.
So the intentionalities came together.
And then it manifested as such.
Quantum mechanics demonstrates.
The reason I put it in because there's a certain kind of a scientific, intellectualized, educated mind that objects to spirituality, you know, that it's not logical, etc.
So we show how to go from the most primitive up through the evolution of mankind and consciousness up to thinkingness up through the mind.
And from the Newtonian paradigm.
You then have to move into 500.
But to get there, you have to move out of the lock-in of the Newtonian paradigm, dualistic, definable over this causing of that on a one-to-one basis.
One-to-one basis.
And the way out, the way you can still be logical and be spiritual is to move into what happened to it.
Uh-oh.
What happened to our last line?
Oh, there it is.
Okay.
Is to move into nonlinear dynamics and quantum mechanics.
You know, the reason that it's important for us is because we talk about the power of intention.
And therefore, we're talking about the Heisenberg principle.
The state of the world is definable right at this instant via the Schrodinger equations, which are quite complicated.
No, actually, they're not complicated.
If you understand them, they're simple.
But they are both time-dependent and time-independent.
That's the state, the potentiality of the universe.
You see, what a thing could be in the next instant depends on what it is right now.
So what is the state of this world right now?
Then by intention, which you hold in consciousness, what happens is you cannot do the same experiment twice because having done it once, you've already changed the conditions.
And the consequence is the Dirac equation.
So the Heisenberg principle then is the introduction of the power of intention.
Many things can come out of a situation.
But because of your intention and the collective intention of other people, you collapse the potentiality, so-called you collapse the wave function, and the potential now becomes the actual.
Therefore, the collective intention of wide numbers of people has a determining effect on what actually precipitates in the world.
Our combined intention is influencing the world.
The combined intention of this group here, which is a very powerful group, is within the 15%, which is influencing what is happening within the world and is supporting the evolution of consciousness, which is now over 207.
Potential.
So the potential of consciousness to move ahead is moved ahead by spiritually oriented people.
And people who are not.
Don't call themselves spiritual.
They just call themselves honest, hardworking, and pay their taxes, and take care of their family and kids, etc.
They don't call that spiritual.
But those are, as you can see, those are the very basics of spirituality, is responsibility, accountability, commitment to others.
All right, we'll finish with this, certainly.
Now, once you, because of intention now, the world has changed.
And therefore, you move from.
The world is defined, calculable by the Schrodinger equations to the Dirac equations.
The Dirac equations.
So here's a potential.
Now you, through intention, you change it into an actual.
This comes from the Schrodinger equations.
This is now the Dirac equations.
The Dirac equations now define what are the new Schrodinger equations, the new condition of the universe, from which intention will again move it into another potential.
Another potentiality.
So here you see, you might say, scientifically stated, spiritual intention, its power, is via the Heisenberg principle.
And the von Neumann process is a way of describing it, process one and process two.
Now, its significance is that Einstein is at 499.
We said Freud was also at 499, and so was Sir Isaac Newton.
Einstein.
He was confronted with this back in the 20s.
This Heisenberg process.
Refused it.
He did not move, jump the paradigm jump at level 500 to the subjective.
He said, I prefer to believe that there's an independent objective universe out there, independent of human consciousness.
And so Einstein calibrated at 499.
David Bohm calibrates at 510.
Because Bohm saw the unmanifest.
Infinite potential becoming manifest.
He talked about the enfolded and unfolded universe.
Potential, enfolded, becoming outfolded as a consequence of intention.
So Bohm's work calibrates about 400.
Freud, of course, made the same error when he, Freud, who is a great genius.
All these people at 499 are great geniuses.
They're all great geniuses.
Freud discovered the unconscious.
The powerful effect of the unconscious and the fact that you don't know what's in the unconscious, etc.
But Newton and Freud, like Einstein, just did not make the paradigm jump.
So you see on the calibrated level of consciousness, 500 is where you jump from a supposedly external objective logical world.
And you begin to live in the subjective.
If you look at the...
Mechanistic reductionist who says nothing is real unless I can measure it and describe it scientifically.
If you look at the mechanistic reductionist, he says that's true.
Why does he say that's true?
Because subjectively it's true.
So the mechanistic reductionist lives in the world of subjectivity the same as the rest of us do.
He talks about it in class and sounds very learned.
But on the way home...
I feel like this.
I feel like that.
He's glad to see the wife.
He's not glad to see the wife.
He's glad to see the dog.
He lives in the subjective reality the same as everybody else.
He's just being pompous in class.
He wants to sound like a professor.
Oh, God.
I had to give my pomposity a little shot there.
You know what I'm saying?
I mean, my old professor was saying, how about me?
Okay, professor.
All right.
Now we're called upon by reality, 12 o'clock.
What time do we resume?
1.30.
Oh, boy.
20 times.
Anyway, in the meantime, Susan has taught our new African gray.
What did you teach, Rockley?
I said, let's do kinesiology.
I can't get away from it.
The parrot wants me to do it.
All right.
That's enough of the Newtonian and the quantum mechanics and all that.
The mind thinks dualistically.
It thinks in terms of an either or.
How can you be nonlinear?
I mean, how do you think if you're nonlinear?
If you can't think dualistically anymore, it's against the rules.
You begin to see that there are no opposites, that the opposite ism is a product of mentation.
In the world, there is no opposite ism.
Just as we said, it's important to know because there is no opposite to truth.
There's either its presence or its absence.
Electricity is either running down the wire or it is not.
There is no alternate thing called offness.
There's no opposite to electricity called offness.
It's either present or not present.
We can demonstrate this with goodness.
And see, there's desirability.
And then here, desirability gets less and less.
One variable, desirability.
Let's take light.
Certainly, people say light and darkness are opposites.
There's light.
Light is either present or it is not present.
There's lots of light and then it gets dimmer and dimmer and dimmer.
And now it's absent.
So, darkness is the absence of light.
Just as.
So, that's applicable, as you see, to spiritual understanding.
The same goes, people say, well, what about hot and cold?
Heat is either present or not present.
It's extremely present, which we call that very hot.
Or it's not present.
So, there is no opposite of heat in this coldness.
Because it's not present.
It's a goodness called badness.
Value, again, you see, is just desirability.
It's either precious.
It's precious if you want it.
If you don't want it, it's worthless.
So, it does not exist out there.
You project that onto it and you say, oh, how beautiful.
As you transcend all these illusions and the duality of the opposites,
then you begin to see with increasing beauty.
If you live within the field instead of the content of the field,
one day as you're walking along, suddenly you're struck by the incredible beauty
of something you catch out of the corner of your eye.
It's incredible perfection.
It's divinity radiates out to you.
It's a gift from God.
You then notice that every weed is incredibly beautiful.
You look at a weed and its sculpture is absolutely, incredibly beautiful.
And it waves in the wind and expresses its beauty.
The beauty of a weed is the same as the beauty of a flower,
just of a different nature.
We're talking about the observer, the witness.
We said the observer witness is faster than ten thousandths of a second.
So, if you live in the field rather than the content of the field,
what we're talking about becomes obvious because it becomes experiential.
You begin to experience that everything is just the outflowing.
This cannot be picked up by the mind.
The mind picks up form.
How do you know you have a mind?
Because it registers, you recognize it through the watcher-experiencer.
But it is back here that you transcend the limitation of one-tenth thousandths of a second.
And it becomes apparent that everything is just happening of its own.
Everything is happening of its own.
Well, what is that crazy sound?
It's happening of its own.
Thank you.
We'll go on to the next exciting slide.
Yes, we said the power of intention.
The power of intention.
And we'll see how important that is when we get to brain physiology,
which will be coming up shortly.
The power of intention.
We noticed an interesting thing when we calibrated the level of the Ganges River.
The Ganges River is about as disgusting as you can get.
The sewage of one hundred large cities dumped into the Ganges River
dead bodies, feces, all the garbage of the world floats down the Ganges.
And the Ganges calibrates over five hundred.
How can that be?
The Ganges River calibrates over five hundred.
Because it has been sanctified by the collective intention of Hindus for millennia.
So I just thought these are very interesting.
And to pronounce it OM, not AUM, which is an error in translation,
which is an error in Satchitananda.
I don't know if it's Satchitananda's error.
Satchitananda's, I forget what it is, but anyway.
AUM is not correct.
Oh, Patanjali's, aphorisms of Patanjali, by Satchitananda.
Anyway.
It's pronounced AUM, and if you calibrate the difference,
there's quite a bit of difference.
The sound AUM calibrates extremely high.
AUM is a limitation at 210.
Om Namah Shivaya.
Chandi Chani Om Mani Padme Hum.
Gregorian Chants.
Japa, the Jesus Prayer.
Saying the Rosary.
All these things.
Twelve-step groups calibrated 540.
The Golden Rule.
See how high all these things are.
Now, the very interesting thing,
you notice a whole bunch of them calibrated 540,
and that's because of the power of intention.
To the Western Newtonian mind, scientific mind,
it seems like rotating a prayer wheel
would be an idiotic bit of ignorance, huh?
Except that the intention, the intention,
the intention of turning the prayer wheel is 540.
So whether prayer is wafted up to heaven or not
is all in your head.
The intention is what gives it its power.
The wailing wall, bathing in the Ganges,
prayer of Saint Francis of Assisi is at 580.
So devotional acts, devotional acts then.
So we sanctify things.
When we say grace in prayer, when we go thusly,
our devotion to God at 540
is what the power of the intention is.
Power of the intention.
Okay, what's the next one?
Well, this morning it looked a little pessimistic.
It looks like we're really screwed up forever.
We've inherited an animal mind,
which is all sinful from the human spiritual viewpoint,
and we've got a prefrontal cortex
that can't tell truth from falsehood.
What a pickle.
The human pickle
can't tell truth from falsehood,
but is spiritually responsible for knowing the difference,
which it can't know by its own design.
Oh, my God.
We are screwed up.
Okay.
How do we transcend that apparent disparity,
that duality between the animal mind
and spiritual awareness and intelligence?
Well, we said the prefrontal cortex
produces the calibrated fields in the 400s.
The animal produces consciousness up to 200.
Now, how do we ever become evolved?
Well, it's because we would be sort of in a pickle forever
if we were limited to the Newtonian paradigm
of protoplasm and causality
and the science, the dimensions of science.
The way out of this dilemma is non-protoplasmic.
You're not stuck just with your physical brain and your neurons.
The neurons, of course, do evolve
as you become more,
more conscious and aware.
The neuronal configuration tends to be influenced.
The most fortuitous thing, fortunate thing for children
is to grow up with classical music.
Classical music, exposure to some religion,
doesn't make much difference which religion,
but some kind of a spiritual integrity,
exposure to classical music.
And on top of that, you can add another 1% by playing chess.
The chances of criminality,
if you grew up under those conditions,
is practically zilch.
The minimal...
Those things then bring about a neuronal patterning.
The exposure of classical music,
the classics such as the great books of the Western world,
the exposure to beauty then, the reverence for beauty.
So religion of whatever sort gives you a reverence for beauty
and a reverence for truth.
This reverence then influences the neuronal patterning.
As you know, neurons
continue to grow.
And as you energize them with certain vibrational frequencies,
they tend to grow into those.
As you know, when you grow up,
you produce 10 times more neurons than you need.
So they weed out.
They weed out the ones that are not needed and unused.
What can we do for our children then?
What can we do for our children?
Our research indicates the greatest things you can do for your children
is classical music.
Chess, spiritual integrity,
and we'll see even Boy Scouts, Girl Scouts, 4-H,
all those things,
which teach you the difference between right and wrong.
Spiritual integrity.
Now, what happens, you see,
below level 200,
you're stuck with a strictly animal brain.
Below 200, the animal brain,
the input, what you see, the sensory input,
is fast relayed through a thing called the thalamus.
It's fast tracked to the amygdala,
which is somewhere south of Cincinnati.
You have an input quickly relayed to the emotional center.
Screw you.
And now your memory of the event
is stored in your hippocampus,
which is north of Detroit.
So this is the animal.
It sees.
You see, it's got to be fast tracked,
fast tracked,
because his survival is dependent on it.
You've got to quickly identify friend or foe and react.
You don't have time to think about it.
So the left brain human being,
below consciousness level 200,
reacts primarily emotionally,
and the input of the cortex,
you see that it's slow.
Slow.
We say they're a little slow.
And they are slow. So,
what's slow is,
is the, what we show in the great books of the Western world.
What's slow is the cerebral cortex.
Well, what about facts, reason, logic, proof, etc.
And this person just wants to react out of emotion, you see.
Alright, so what happens at consciousness level 200?
Then you would be at the effect
and the limitation of your animal.
Now, if I teach you spiritual religion,
what are you going to do with it?
What's an animal going to do with it?
He's going to use it to kill you with.
For Jesus,
for God, for Allah.
The animal is going to take religion
and use it as a new weapon with which to kill you.
I've done it, I know, I know, I've done it.
I told you about that a lifetime.
I killed him for Jesus and he killed me for Allah.
I mean...
With the evolution of consciousness,
then,
so below 200,
we have a left brain dominance.
It deals in a world that is linear.
It constantly releases stress hormones,
adrenaline,
depletes your norepinephrine.
You end up on Prozac.
It's set for fight or flight.
It's the alarm reaction, you see,
and it leads to exhaustion.
Selye made it very famous, you know,
as did Canon.
The suppression of the thymus gland,
the thymus gland regulates the immune system
and balances the acupuncture system.
So with this constant stress, then,
you have less immunity
and decreased circulating killer cells.
Killer cells are the good guys,
despite their name, Killer.
They kill the bad guys.
So you have stress of the thymus gland.
It disrupts...
Every time you go below that,
you disrupt the acupuncture system.
As you see with kinesiology,
the arm goes weak.
In the presence of falsehood,
It quickly recovers,
but it repeatedly does that.
As it repeatedly does that,
it keeps interrupting the same acupuncture points,
the same transmission of physiologic energy.
It gives you a negative kinesiologic response.
It decreases the neurotransmitters,
such as norepinephrine and serotonin in the brain.
And the track to the emotion is twice as fast
as through the mind.
All right.
Above consciousness level 200.
It's not difficult to get above 200.
You can get above 200 in one second.
In one second, you make a decision.
And suddenly, you're above 200.
Above 200, then, is intention.
Now, the input is fast.
It's fast.
Through the cerebral cortex,
through the etheric brain,
very fast.
So what happens at consciousness level 200
is you develop for the first time in evolution
an etheric brain.
The etheric brain is energy only,
not protoplasmic.
Why?
Because you're dealing with frequencies and energies
very high frequency.
The old vacuum tube will only serve you up to a certain point.
Beyond that, you need a silicone chip.
You can't handle that many frequencies
and that high energy with a vacuum tube.
So now you're dealing over 200.
You see, it's a logarithmic.
So above 200, you're dealing with extremely high frequencies.
And now you need a non-protoplasmic.
Protoplasm cannot respond at that frequency.
You need something non-protoplasmic,
which is composed of pure energy.
You now develop an etheric brain,
which is a purely energy body,
not subject to life or death of the physical body.
So the etheric brain,
when you go out of your physical body,
you don't come to an end.
So what is it that survives?
What is it that carries the karma?
So you develop the etheric brain.
The etheric brain now transforms you
from just an animal
to a spiritually aware, evolved being.
Above level 200, you have right brain dominance.
You're dealing in the non-linear.
Instead of releasing a drug,
you're releasing adrenaline all the time.
You're releasing endorphins.
You feel good and happy.
Positive emotions.
And that supports the thymus gland,
which is right behind the breastbone.
Because of that, your immunity is high.
Circulating killer cells,
you can count them, are increased.
Increased healing.
You balance the acupuncture system
and the kinesiologic response is strong.
So in the presence of truth then,
you have the etheric brain.
And of course, this is very rapid.
So now, this was fast to give you an emotion,
such as fear or hatred or anger or greed or something.
But now, what's very fast
is through the etheric brain to the amygdala.
The emotion now is a consequence
of seeing things spiritually.
And your memory in the hippocampus
is a different memory.
So below 200, you experience
a certain thing in a certain way.
And above 200, people experience it a different way.
And they both remember it differently.
You know how people's memory of certain events
can be so different.
You say, we both saw the same thing, right?
Yeah.
Okay, so that explains then
the difference in people's opinion of many things
because they interpret it differently.
And they interpret it differently
because their brain often
operates differently, that's why.
The spiritualized person sees things more benign,
sees the world in a more benign way.
Again, we're trying to get out of the box of causality.
There is no this causing a that.
Because as long as you believe that,
you're always going to demonize
the this that's causing the that.
There's always the evil perpetrator
and then the innocent victim
who now is in competition,
in the world of victimhood,
where competition is stiff.
Yeah, victims.
All right, so then how do things come about?
Well, here we have a correlation now.
Societal problems.
We were talking about, this morning,
about the problematic hermeneutics
of relativistic epistemology.
And now we'll demonstrate it.
There isn't a wicked society
causing the victims within it.
Consciousness is stratified, see?
It's stratified wherever it goes.
There are people that think
the Taj Mahal is ugly
and the bathrooms don't work well.
That's how they experience it.
It's drafty and the bathrooms don't work well.
And I wouldn't live there if you paid me.
Well, I wouldn't live there either.
Too many visitors.
All right.
Things are the consequence of the field.
If they're the consequence of the field,
then we should see a correlation
between the field
and what is witnessed in society.
Consciousness level is 600 and over.
Rate of unemployment, zero.
Poverty, zero.
Happiness, 100%.
Criminality, zero.
Between consciousness level 500
and 600.
Unemployment, zero.
Poverty, zero.
Happiness, 98%.
They just broke their ankle or what,
I don't know.
Criminality, 0.5%.
Those are fallen gurus, probably.
Sell tickets to heaven or something.
Sell salvation.
All right.
Between 400 and 500.
This is the world, the Newtonian paradigm
of intellect, the great works of the worst,
the rest of the world.
People of that level, unemployment, 2%.
Poverty, 0.5%.
Happiness, 70%.
They haven't attended these lectures.
Criminality, 2%.
All right.
Consciousness level, 300 to 400.
That's good intentioned, positive emotions.
Unemployment, 7%.
They're probably on unemployment insurance.
When it runs out, that'll drop to zero.
Poverty, 1%, because they just happen to be lazy.
Happiness is only 50%.
Criminality, 5%.
People still, usually that's greed.
Greed.
At this level, it's usually, you know,
Enron and those kind of people.
WorldCom, all those kind of people.
All right.
Now we go 200 to 300.
Unemployment is still only 8%.
Poverty, 1.5%.
Happiness seems to be falling down here.
We're down to 40.
Criminality, 9%.
And now let's see what happens at consciousness level 200.
At consciousness level 200,
unemployment goes from 8% to 50%.
One drop in consciousness level, low 200,
you go from 8 to 50.
Poverty goes from 1.5% to 22%.
Happiness drops from 40% to 15%.
And this was the one we had to recheck over.
Criminality is actually 50%.
People take a bribe.
People bribe off people.
People cheat on their income tax.
All right.
Because they don't feel guilt yet.
When you drop from 100 to 200,
the unemployment is 50%.
Poverty, 22%.
Happiness is down to 15%.
Now what happens if you drop below 100?
And a good-sized portion of society
does go from 50 to 100.
Unemployment is 75%.
Poverty, 40%.
Happiness, 2%.
Criminality, 91%.
91%.
When you get to the lower levels, below 50,
the prison populations in the United States
calibrate on an average from 30 to 60, around in there.
You're talking about
the criminal population below 50.
Unemployment is 97%.
Poverty, 65%.
Should be higher, but they steal a lot of cars.
I used to treat them so I know.
I treated all these people.
I know what they're up to.
I used to check to see if I had my fountain pen
when they left the office.
They just have sticky fingers.
I don't know.
They're living.
But their happiness rate is zero.
And the rate of criminality
is all the way up to 98%.
98%.
It's a consequence, then, of a level of consciousness.
It's not the fault of some segment of society
which is causing people to do these things.
You understand?
It's that field.
So in that field, this is what surfaces.
And in this field, this is what surfaces.
Yeah?
Mm-hmm.
What brings the figures up, of course,
is education, intention, the things we mentioned,
the emphasis on that which is of beauty,
the beauty of life.
There's a lot of graffiti in the New York subway.
There's no graffiti in the Moscow subway
and none at all in the great cathedrals of Europe.
See?
The power of the beauty is such
you just don't think of graffiti.
The Moscow subways are a beautiful, magnificent system.
Each subway station is like a little cathedral.
You just don't think of graffiti.
New York subway, graffiti.
Mexico City, graffiti.
Mexico City, sorry, subway calibrates.
I forget the calibrations are in the book.
The subway in Mexico City calibrates the same as New York City,
about 180 or something.
And so Mexico City got, caught the idea of it.
Now in the waiting stations and the subway stations,
they put free books.
Why?
Because if people are reading,
they're not doing graffiti.
So they've caught on.
The way to bring these bottom levels up then
is through education,
not by vilifying some evil doer out there,
capitalism or the government
or your parents or somebody.
No.
Okay, so that's just a very interesting correlation.
So that sort of takes care of causality.
Yeah?
We thought, you know, it's fun, the book I'm doing now.
If you can tell there's any truth in falsehood,
what happens if you take that and look at the world?
Let's say we're coming from a different universe.
The only thing we know how to do is calibrate levels of consciousness.
We began to look over the world and see
if we look at levels of truth in various aspects of life,
from the subway system to books to the literature
to the great battles, et cetera.
And so we did for fun.
Or she did for fun.
No, I did it for fun.
She did it, but not for fun.
I said, honey, we only got 200 movies to go.
Get away from me.
We didn't know we were going to end up doing 200,
but we do a bunch of them, and then we think of a bunch more.
And then we got the most famous 100 movies ever produced.
We ended up doing 200 movies, right?
Show them what happened to you as a result, honey.
No good anymore.
So we had to stop at 200.
Anyway, it's interesting.
See, all these numerical designations can be confrontive.
If you have a very fixed belief system
and you get a calibration that doesn't coincide,
then the thing is to look into it to understand how is it.
Because what you're talking about is perception,
and we're just calibrating things
as to what is their intrinsic reality.
So move to the next, huh?
Some of them you would just guess by looking at them.
Some of them are so ghastly, I would never even see them.
I'll say, what's that about?
Good God, I don't even hear what it's about.
Let's just go see it.
I don't want to subject myself to that energy field, you know?
OK.
All right, so what if we calibrate the world?
How long have we got today?
I forgot this.
There's 40 to this, and we're at 120.
133.
Break.
Is that three?
Another hour.
Oh, OK.
All right.
What happens then if we're from another planet,
and we want to know what, before we land on this planet,
what are we going to encounter?
So one thing you can do from a different culture
is calibrate the level of consciousness
of the people on this planet.
So we see, we said America runs about 421,
but the northern, north, this continent,
this continent,
this whole hemisphere is a very lucky hemisphere.
This is the right side of the world to get born on.
I'd advise it.
If you come back to this world, pick this hemisphere.
America's 421.
But generally it runs 415, 410,
various like that.
South America, Caribbean islands.
You see South America's in good shape.
It's close up around 300s,
which is a very good place to live.
And then right in the middle of this,
you have the anachronism of Haiti at 55.
We were talking this morning about group karma,
you know, group karma.
So these people must have a group karma
coming in at 55.
And of course they celebrate,
you know, they do voodoo and blood sacrifice
and worship demons and things.
So that may be a concomitant
of being at level 55.
55 is not a threat to the world.
55 is too incapacitated by its own internal problems.
They're lucky if they have enough to eat.
So I think there's been 20 different attempts
to raise the level of consciousness in Haiti,
and none of them has succeeded.
So it seems like a karmic propensity, doesn't it?
Right in the middle of a hemisphere like this,
you suddenly have a pocket
that all calibrates at a certain level.
Strange and peculiar.
Let's go to the next one.
This is just a different way of deepening.
We're depicting this hemisphere.
You see Greenland, Canada, Alaska.
Is that Alaska up there?
What is that over there?
Alaska, okay.
Mexico, the Caribbean.
Pretty much the same thing we saw before.
This is just delineated Brazil.
Those are good countries.
They're in the positive emotions, above 200.
Now we go to the other hemisphere.
They say, I would pick the first hemisphere
rather than the second one to get reborn.
This hemisphere is Australia at 410.
You see China.
China has come up a long way.
You see Manchuria.
You see India.
You see vast Russia.
And then you look over here.
Here's India.
And you see Africa and Europe.
And North Africa.
So now you can expect
all these.
Here in the middle of Africa,
you got a calibrated level of life at 40.
40, wow.
40.
What does 40 come forth as?
Rwanda, Civil War, Sudan, starvation, AIDS,
massacres, tribal warfare between chieftains, etc.
However, they're overwhelmed with their own internal problems.
There's no threat to the world.
They can barely get by till tomorrow.
Then as you get north,
to North Africa,
now you begin to see
their rising of difficulty.
You see Europe in the 300s to 400s,
Scandinavia,
all doing quite well.
I don't expect any trouble from Japan either.
So if you're looking for where you're going to find trouble,
you're going to find it here in Africa,
and especially you're going to find it in North Africa.
If I don't know anything about the news,
never read it,
I can look at this map
and tell you where there's going to be a problem.
Because 170, 180, 190 now has enough energy to it
that it can do a lot of harm.
And therefore, both sides,
in endless conflicts,
tend to calibrate about 190.
Pride, pride, arrogance,
eye for an eye, etc.
Forgiveness is not in the,
forgiveness is not part of
energy fuels 180 or 190.
So you can forecast then
the likelihood of what goes on.
This would be where
Rwanda and Sudan, etc.
This is a more detailed map.
It's so detailed you can't read it.
So let's go to the next one.
I thought we took this one out.
It escaped.
You saw the distribution of the levels of consciousness.
In the prior map we correlated them
with crime, poverty, income, education, etc.
This is just the distribution
of AIDS in the world.
And you see the distribution of AIDS
is almost identical to the map we just looked at.
The distribution of AIDS then
correlates with level of consciousness.
Not caused by anything.
The calibration level of 70 to 90
gives you no karmic immunity
to a negativity, whatever it might be.
If this was closer to the middle ages,
you'd be looking at the distribution
of the Black Death and the Plague.
This would be the distribution map
of the Black Plague instead of AIDS.
But AIDS is today's Black Plague.
Okay, so, move on.
It's like the broken window principle.
The energy attracts to it
that which is concordant with that energy.
That's why it's important to raise
the level of consciousness of people.
To pick up the trash on the streets.
You cannot.
Eliminate crime so long as there's trash
on the streets. Not possible.
Because they come from the same energy field.
That which doesn't care enough
about its own environment,
that which doesn't care about its fellow human being,
that which doesn't care about
neatness, orderliness, beauty,
then desecrates beauty
and it throws its trash on the street.
Not my problem.
They get paid to clean it up.
The minute you see trash on the streets,
I can tell you what the crime rate is.
Tell you what the crime rate is.
We can go blindfolded.
Any street, any city in the United States,
any world, look at the street
and tell you what the crime rate is there.
Okay.
We're looking at war and peace.
We're looking at history.
Trying to discern what is the truth
of what value might this be
in establishing peace as a reality
other than just a political slogan.
Generally, peace is a political slogan.
And people who really want it
wouldn't do it for a price.
It's a wonderful political slogan.
So most people who talk about peace
are talking about it as a political do-gooderism
to win something or other.
They don't really mean it.
Let's take a war,
well documented in history,
about which there is no currently unfolding mysteries.
Yeah, pretty much settled
and pretty much
concordance of opinion about this war.
What can we discover about a war
that's applicable to today's world
and to the peace in the future?
We see that one of the greatest powers
in the World War II
was the heart of Winston Churchill,
the heart of the lion.
It was the heart of the lion at 510
that held together the British people,
held them together, the heart of the lion.
Roosevelt at 499,
later Truman, General Eisenhower, MacArthur.
The U.S. government at 395,
in the norm of the invasion.
Here's Heisenberg,
out of which came the Heisenberg principle.
Wernher von Braun,
the U.S. military.
And here's something we were talking about
at lunch, triage.
Triage in the essence of,
in the context of the Second World War,
calibrated at 205.
The dropping of the atomic bomb
was triage.
Not understood by.
The mind doesn't understand triage
until you get to consciousness level 360.
It's understandable in the military.
It's not understandable.
The sacrifice of the few for the many.
The...
Having to pick the lesser of two evils.
So we look at the dropping of the atomic bomb.
President Truman had to decide
to sacrifice 7 million,
the estimated death rate if we invaded Japan,
was 7 million.
6 million Japanese and 1 million Americans
against killing 180,000 innocent civilians.
Triage, then,
is to try to save life.
Politically it's demonized as killing life.
You got your choice.
7 million or 180,000?
So Truman,
we can get what Truman's intention was
and what his level of...
intention was at 495.
He was pushing the intellect
to do what he thought was best for the world.
You can disagree with him,
but that's what it calibrates at.
Then we have the German military,
the military command.
You see, the military are usually quite integrous.
In fact, very often the military
calibrate higher than the generals.
The generals were willing to sacrifice...
Hitler was willing to sacrifice the whole German army
and, in fact, all the German people, you know.
So U.S. military at Pearl Harbor.
Kamikaze pilots calibrate quite high
and so does the Luftwaffe.
Then we saw Emperor Hirohito at 200
and Admiral Yamamoto.
So you get a chance to look over
what are the facts involved.
Adolf Hitler at 45.
So if we're going to prevent war in the future,
then we better use consciousness
calibration techniques
to diagnose the situation
before we decide on a course of action.
So at least you know what you're dealing with.
Adolf Hitler by that time was down to 45.
Stalin was down to 90.
All these dictators are all the way down.
And faithfully and unfortunately for the world,
Nobel Chamberlain calibrated at 185.
When he negotiated a peace treaty with Hitler,
and came home with a news piece on our time,
Hitler thought he was a stupid idiot.
Stupid idiot.
Sucker, how dumb can you get?
Like signing a contract with the mafia.
I'll pay you back a quarter of a million Tuesday.
Right.
Okay.
You see the Third Reich.
Neville Chamberlain said in denial
he was suffering from the
impairment of crippled hermeneutics
of relativistic epistemology.
Deadly.
It's deadly, folks.
Okay.
Japanese embassy.
Japanese government.
Robin Rappenheimer early was an integrist.
Late he sold out, apparently.
League of Nations didn't do too good at 185.
Pacifists attack up Pearl Harbor.
So you can analyze everything.
Here's the Cambridge Five.
And this is why we actually ended up with the Iraqi War.
The Iraqi War was a fear of atomic power.
Atomic power.
Yeah.
In the hands of the wrong people.
And how did the world,
how did the secret of the atomic bomb get out?
The secret of the atomic bomb was sold out
by these people here.
These people sold us out.
Americans who turned against their own country
with pseudo-philosophic,
pseudo-spiritual argumentation,
which is nothing but intellectual egotism.
So we were sold out then.
And because of that,
the world is in current danger.
And now the minute we suspect a rogue nation
has atomic power,
all hell breaks loose.
All hell breaks loose.
Not because of the reality,
but because of the potentiality
that they have access to atomic secrets.
And where did they get them?
And I'm showing you where they came from.
They came from this guy who turned against.
It came from the intellectuals
out of the Cambridge Five.
That's how it got to Russia.
And Russia was a serious threat.
Why?
Because its intention was less than 200,
but its capability was over 200.
Its capability was over 200.
And its intention was below 200.
And that is the danger sign.
And unless society learns that,
war will be with us forever.
So what's the practical application?
Is spirituality just airy-fairy?
Spiritual truth, then,
in daily life,
is manifest as integrity.
People don't talk about Jesus and Buddha
and holiness and all that in the secular world.
But the beginning of spiritual responsibility
is truth and integrity.
So the alignment with truth, then,
is not called, labeled spirituality
in the ordinary world.
But it is the beginning of real power.
The beginning of real power.
And looking at the history of the world,
in completing this book,
several years in which we did 7,000 calibrations,
everything in history and current and past life,
one thing became apparent.
The biggest enemy to peace in the world
is political naivete
and the clumsiness, awkwardness, and fallacy
of international diplomacy.
Absolutely no sense to it,
no reason to it, no logic to it,
much less a science to it.
There could be no hope of peace
so long as people are dealing with falsehood and illusion.
So the dictum of which we speak
is that truth brings peace
and falsehood brings war.
You cannot have war without falsehood
because it's built upon falsehood.
Nor can you have peace without truth.
So to establish that, then,
you would have to know what is the difference
between truth and falsehood.
And inasmuch as the human mind innately
is incapable of that,
you can see why the history of mankind
has been what it is.
Only 7% of the time
in all of human history
has there been peace.
7%.
93% of human history
has always been a war.
In my lifetime,
there's already five or six of them.
I don't know how many wars
I've lost track of them.
World War I had just stopped.
We're into World War II.
Then the Korean War, Vietnam War,
and go for it.
There's half a dozen wars
just in one lifetime, folks.
So peace is something
other than a placard
and a protest march.
Peace is based on radical science.
Radical science of truth.
So I put together this
for the sake of internet
and international diplomacy.
I've heard interviews on television
that to me were shocking
where an interviewer
mockingly suggests
to the president
of the largest country in the world,
one of the oldest countries in the world,
6,000 years of civilization
before America was even thought of,
and he's telling him
that he ought to really correct
his internal affairs in his country.
I thought it was so shockingly rude.
It was embarrassing.
All right.
The president of China is already,
now there's a different one,
but the president of China at that time
calibrated around 455.
All right.
So we put together then
some kind of a science
of international diplomacy.
There's never been such a thing,
you know,
never been a science
of international diplomacy.
And you can't just do international diplomacy
by votes, tarot cards,
you know,
channeled information.
All right.
So this chart is called Us and Them.
It's useful in many applications.
Today we're just talking about it
because it was the implication
for world peace.
It's called the Us and Them chart.
It can be your company
and other companies.
and your target market.
It can be your government association.
It can be your part
in civil organizations.
It can be the local towns,
it can be your own meeting.
It can be any place in our world
where you have two different segments
of society dealing with each other.
And this chart is called Us and Them.
Us and Them.
It gives you some kind of a scientific
rational basis upon which
to approach other people.
First you have to know who you are,
then you have to know who them is.
Nobody in this world knows who they are,
much less who them is.
How can you have success?
You don't know who you are,
and you don't know who they are.
Good God.
After many years of psychoanalysis,
I knew who I was.
It was now my job,
when a patient walked in,
to get to know who they are.
It wasn't their job
to come to where I was.
It was my job to go where they were
and build a walkway between us.
All right, so this is Us.
In international politics,
which is a profound application
of really new science,
this is Us.
And this is Them.
This is the calibrated levels
of consciousness
and sort of the predominant
emotional field.
You can hear me talking to myself.
Oh my gosh, I can hear myself
talking to myself.
Wow.
My voice goes out the front of my head
and comes in the back of my head.
Good God.
That was wonderful, sweetheart.
Thank you.
I can even hear what I'm saying.
All right, so here we have
America at 421.
Now here's who we're dealing with.
Sort of dumbly,
walk through the world
telling everybody
they ought to be democratic.
You should have a democracy.
Why should they have a democracy?
Just because you think
it's a good idea, huh?
So here we are at 421,
and here is where
the other country is.
Now what is their language?
Our job is to know
what their language is,
not vice versa.
They aren't evolved enough
to even be interested
in this chart.
Even the people of America
are probably not interested in it,
but you're going to get it anyway.
Here we are at 421.
Now you look at
who you're dealing with.
You're pretty safe dealing
with Canadians
despite their politics.
They believe in what they believe,
but they don't know they're stupid.
That's all.
Okay, so anyway,
now you see
where is the other country
you're dealing with, huh?
Here's Central Africa
at 40 to 80.
You're lucky to get through
a single day alive.
If you're awake at 8 in the morning,
you're lucky to be alive
at 4 in the afternoon.
If starvation,
lack of water,
deprivation,
disease,
marauding tribal chieftains
from neighboring tribes
haven't chopped you up yet,
you're lucky to still be breathing.
All right.
Now,
you look at the Middle East.
You see it runs around 180 to 190,
and those are the levels of pride,
militant pride and getting even.
A tit for a tat,
an eye for an eye,
and forgiveness is not something
you can expect of them.
Forgiveness is up around 500.
Yeah.
You look at China in the 300s.
South America.
All right.
So what is the context?
What is reality
to the people we're talking to?
Reason appeals to Canadians, huh?
It appeals to Canadians.
It does not appeal to the Middle East.
Arrogance and pride.
We kill a busload of children,
they kill a busload of children.
We blow up a busload
of their diplomats,
they blow up a busload.
An eye for an eye
and a tit for a tat.
So you know what to expect.
What to expect of who you're dealing with
and therefore you know how to appeal to them.
Cultures that are coming from lack
would only be interested in what we offer
if there is a gain to them.
They're coming from the solar plexus.
You hear about democracy.
What's in it for me?
You understand?
Solar plexus is me.
What's in it for me?
Democracy is great.
Why should I vote for it?
Because it's equality?
Equality.
Countries like that think that's such a stupid idea.
Stupid idea.
Equality, giving votes, equality to women,
the lower classes, never mind.
They're called dogs.
In their own society,
their own citizens are called dogs
by their rulers.
Dogs.
Hitler was willing to kill them all
because they lost the war.
There is dogs.
Saddam Hussein called them dogs.
These people here see women, children, and dogs.
Down here.
Should you give these women a vote?
What, dogs?
Women and children and dogs
are down at the bottom in such a society.
So you have to know who you're talking to now.
You see that these people here are ruled by reason.
These are into willingness.
This is all of South America.
You've got very willing people.
They're willing to go along with whatever they think is good.
Here you've got neutral.
Here you've got courage.
But from here on down, you're dealing in pride.
And this is North Africa,
and this is South, Central Africa.
So this is true now of any political situation in the world,
economic situation,
whether you're a giant business,
a giant corporation,
and you're dealing with a new market.
How do you appeal to that market?
That they should buy your product
because your product is so wonderful?
No, not wonderful.
How would it appeal to them?
Depends completely on your level of consciousness
and their level of consciousness.
And therefore, out of facing the facts,
facing the facts.
See, we fantasize about this country.
We fantasize about these cultures.
It's got nothing to do with who they are.
All right, so if you want to calibrate a culture,
a country,
what do you need to know?
You need to know three calibrations.
We only showed one today.
You need to know the calibration of the ruler.
You have to know that Saddam Hussein calibrates at 75.
At 75, we'll kill you for a buck.
Then you have to know the calibration of the government.
The government.
We know countries where the people are fantastic,
the leaders fantastic,
and the government is so rotten,
you take your life in your hands if you drive across the border.
You have to know the consciousness level of the people.
The people, the government, and the ruler.
Now you've got guaranteed success.
Guaranteed.
We never ask this.
We have permission to ask this only.
Guaranteed. Resist.
Wow.
Same as a scientific experiment.
If you know all the factors involved,
your success rate is extremely high.
So what mankind has been doing over the centuries
is trying to maneuver in the dark.
They don't know who they are.
They don't know who those people are.
They can't tell the ruler from the people.
You get a country that the people are wonderful
and the leaders are crook.
So we look at them benignly
because we know the people are lovely.
I know countries where the ruler
caliber is extremely high.
In fact, higher than any other leader in the world.
And the people are adorable.
And we love to visit there.
And the government is rotten through and through.
Let me just hold that government in mind.
That government, which you'll go on named,
calibrates over 60, 65, 70, 70.
70.
Are you safe in that country?
Not really.
Leaders are okay.
People are okay.
But if you've got a taillight out,
you may find yourself in jail.
$10,000 bail.
You ain't got it?
Get your mother to sell her house.
Now you get bailed out.
Routine in that country.
You have countries with very integrous populations
and very horrible rulers.
How does that come about?
Through the naivete of the people.
You know, Germany was a very,
very good country.
We had a very good country.
You know what I'm saying?
So you think,
if you're a Catholic,
you're a Protestant,
how can they elect somebody like Hitler
who calibrates to 70 or 80?
How can they do that?
All right.
So the calibration,
the,
the ruler,
the leader,
the government,
and the people.
Now your success rate should be close to 100%.
You'd never make a mistake.
You shouldn't try to sell people something
that they're not in the market for,
and it's meaningless to them.
democracy to these countries here, I'm going to show them how that's going to help them
win. It's going to make them more wealthy, more envied. It has to appeal to their solar
plexus. What do I get out of it? They don't respect integrity because of integrity. A
spiritually evolved person respects truth for its own sake. Non-integrist people respect
truth only because what they can get by it. The only use for science is what they can
win with science. They don't respect the Newtonian paradigm for its own intrinsic truth
and beauty. Okay, next thing. Oh, yes, well, this is the Louvre in Paris. The Louvre calibrates
at 500, and in the middle of it is this, that was Pi, the architect Pi, modernistic. So
this is a modernistic structure. So here you see
traditional beauty, which the relativistic epistemology disparages, by the way, and would
like to substitute this. Yeah, this belongs somewhere, but not in the middle of the Louvre,
in my view of it. Let's see, where are we on that list of slides? I want to see how
fast I have to talk. We did the Louvre, huh? Oh, yeah, okay. Okay, so I don't have to hurry
around. I'm going to go to the next slide, and then I'm going to go to the next slide.
How many people have never been to one of these lectures before? Oh, dear, oh, dear.
Well, I'm glad we did go over the basics then. I thought, because many of the people have
been here before, we might spend more time than usual on questions and answers and explanations,
people like that. And when we do questions and answers and explanations, we leave the
microphone on, so we can share the discussion with the whole audience.
Let's move to the next one. Oh, this is the new book. As far as it is there, and there's
Gigi. I was saying, oh, my God. Okay. Oh, my God. This is the book a couple of months
later, you know. And where's the book now? Oh, he said, oh, I can't go any further. I
got to rest up. So he took off a couple of months, all right, to go traveling. Let me
see what else we got here now. Let's see. Yeah?
Well, we'll end up with, well, we pretty much covered this subject, 39. We don't need
the slides. So what we've defined now is a way of discerning truth from falsehood for
the first time in human history. We have differentiated between the content of the field, the proximate
context, that is, the conditions, the time, prevailing elements and influences, and
contrasted that with the absolute. We saw the consciousness calibration gives us, for
the first time, a new tool for survival, for understanding, for spiritual growth and development.
Consequently, we are really a very fortunate generation. Mankind has never had the capacity
to tell truth from falsehood. Therefore, he was fated to endless misery, war, all the
catastrophes that we looked at this morning. And we're going to talk about that in a little
bit.
All came out of not knowing truth from falsehood. Not knowing truth from falsehood.
Truth arises then at, or our awareness of truth arises as a consequence of intention.
If our intention is aligned with integrity, we tend to manifest that. We tend to manifest
it in our world and in our understanding of the world. To see the world in extremely negative
ways comes out of a lack of integrity.
You can't use consciousness calibration to try to prove a positionality. It will constantly
upset you, so I would advise you not to do that. If you're using it to try and prove
a point. So, it means you cannot have anything riding on a perception. Because perception
and essence are two different things. The difficulty in finishing this sentence is that
you often feel that you've broken into the problem. You have to share it with the community.
And that's what it means. It means you can't solve problems, but at least one problem.
And that's why it's important to understand it.
This is the confusion and uncertainty. This is the feeling that you're having. This is the
question that I'm having. The obligation of truth to give us. For a trained architect, as well as the
procedure to provide a proper12 hour or one hour of reflection, we can't be more than able to do this.
The difficulty in finishing this book is the anticipation of what will be experienced by the reader,
because I'm quite aware of how large groups and various groups in society and the world view certain things.
And this is very often quite some disparity with the essential truth.
The book and the contents are not one and the same thing.
The media, of course, exploit that.
So one of the biggest sources of disinformation and lack of integrity is the media, the media.
Its impact on children, especially, the impact on children.
So it's blamed on the parents, but you'll see that the children are,
the children's consciousness is dominated by the media and by their friends,
the social milieu in which they live, and not by their parents.
By the time...
So we...
We inculcate this, we try to fortify them against what they're going to experience in the world
by the display, by the demonstration of our own integrity,
by giving them every advantage that we can,
education, classical music, beauty, ballet, dance,
the appreciation for the great beauty of the world.
You can tell that which calibrates below 100 because it hates and desecrates beauty.
It blows up the great Buddha in Afghanistan.
It desecrates the walls of the cathedrals.
That which desecrates beauty, then, tells you that is not the way you want to go.
Because beauty is one aspect of the sacred.
The attributes of God are truth, love.
The nonlinear dimension, then, is what we merge into with spiritual evolution.
As we let go, hanging on to and clutching at opinions and positionalities,
it's more that we open ourselves so that our life then becomes a prayer.
People say, what can I do to advance myself spiritually?
You know, it shocks me that when they ask me at the end of a lecture.
Well, I suggest you just do this and they own this.
It isn't what you do, it's what you have become.
So you become that which is integrous.
You become that which is reliable.
You become that which is loving.
You become that which respects beauty.
It sanctifies that which is integrous.
By being the field instead of the content of the field, then,
instead of talking about it, instead of preaching it,
you become it.
If you become it, you need say anything about it.
Because that which you are radiates its energy to the field.
Your energy becomes the power of intention which elevates the field.
As the level of the sea rises, it lifts all the ships at sea.
It's a sad you would just like to select.
We'll just lift this ship and we'll just lift this ship.
And we'll lift this ship.
Imagine how much energy and power it takes to lift a battleship.
Just one battleship.
There are thousands on the sea.
But if we raise the level of consciousness of mankind only a couple of degrees,
every ship on all the oceans in the world are lifted thereby.
So it's our collective intention.
You say, what can I do for God?
What can I do for my fellow human being?
What can I do for peace?
For me, you can leave your peace science home.
Why?
Because it creates antagonism and conflict.
Dogs, face shields, clubs, bloody bodies.
That's a political slogan, politicizing peace.
You become that.
You become the field.
You see from our diagram up there.
You become the field and by virtue of that which you are,
you are lifting the field.
That's what you need to do for the world.
It's that being what the world does not need.
It doesn't need another political slogan.
It doesn't need another set of dogs and face shields
and clubs and police barricades.
It needs those who uplift society by virtue of that which you have become.
Therefore, your life becomes, as I've said before,
your life becomes a mudra.
You know, in spiritual language, a mudra is a sacred position.
Spiritual work is attacked by many people in sort of a yang kind of a fashion.
They're going to go after enlightenment and battle their way to it
through fasts and shaving your head in sandals and walking about in the desert,
pilgrimages to various places.
Etc.
That's the yang way of approaching it.
If you embrace that which is integrous and become it,
then your life becomes like a prayer.
And the spiritual revelation is very yin.
One steps back from positionality
and allows the reality to reveal itself,
which it does unbidden.
Of its own, it reveals itself.
As you're walking down the street,
you notice the incredible beauty of the weed.
All of a sudden, one day you see its sculpture is absolutely perfect.
One person could create such a sculpture.
It would be coming out of the divinity within them
because beauty is the essence of spiritual reality.
Just as love and forgiveness
and kindness, sharing, tenderness.
So when we understand sort of a science of consciousness,
now we can see where everyone is in the world.
We can see the innate innocence
of those who are born for whatever karmic propensities
to fulfill whatever karmic destinies
via the Rig Veda, let us say,
which teaches that
that which gives up its life for a higher life
earns the karmic right to become that higher life.
When you sacrifice yourself to thee,
then you become entitled to become that.
So what seems to us as needless sacrifice
is from a very limited egoistic perception.
What you see are people proceeding
to the realization of their own divinity.
What you see is the unfolding of the opportunity
to undo the bad karma of that lifetime.
And in the undoing of it,
you see the essence of it
and out of that comes the forgiveness.
Out of that comes the forgiveness
and out of that one's energy field advances.
Therefore, it is not necessary to demonize
any aspect of life
because all of life subserves
the whole, all of life subserves the whole.
Some of us serve life
by appearing to be sacrificed in the process.
We were talking at lunch about the Rig Veda,
which points out that through sacrifice,
through surrender,
that which is lower life
earns its life to become higher life,
which the Native American realized
when he sacrifices the life of the animal.
The Native American,
whose spirituality he calibrates
extremely high from, by the way,
intuited the attractor field
and could even visualize it.
The attractor field,
which is the core of a certain animal kingdom.
See, each animal kingdom,
the animals all have the same attractor field,
this powerful attractor field then.
So all mules, all horses, all cats, all dogs
have the same
central organizing energy field
because they don't have individual karma yet.
So the Native American intuited
and even saw in their visions
the energy field, the attractor field.
So the Natives who worship the,
or pray to the spirit of the tiger,
the spirit of the tiger does rule the forest.
The spirit of the tiger rules the forest.
It's a fact.
The tiger is the king of the forest.
So when the Native American then
kills in order for a higher life to evolve,
what it does is it sanctifies
the sacrifice of the animal,
which by its being sanctified,
it gives up its life for thee, O human,
and by virtue of my sacrifice
do I earn becoming one of you.
That's the former tiger in me speaking.