the first science of truth then. We also have the first science of international diplomacy.
This has been corrected since Canada. Canada is about 415, right about here. So, here's
America at 421. Here is another citizenry, another country. As I say, you have to understand
the people, the government, and the ruler. It will first give you the first science of
diplomatic relationships. I see nothing but really profound ignorance in international
relationships in which the people are addressing each other completely incorrectly, no appeal,
turning each other off, trying to sell them a program that to them is horrific. You have
to know who you're talking to, who you're talking to. When a patient goes into my office,
I can't expect them to come from where I'm in after 50 years of psychiatry and psychoanalysis.
I have to go to where they are. He doesn't even know he's addicted yet. Five DWIs, the
wife has left him, he's lost his job, three times in jail. What do you mean I got an alcohol
problem, doc? So, help me God, they say that. Five times in jail, wife's lost, he's bankrupt,
he's unemployable, they've taken the keys to his car away, he was just in six months
for driving without a license.
He sits there and tells me he don't have an alcohol problem. Okay, so, let's talk about
international diplomacy because world peace is very profoundly important. In history,
peace has prevailed only seven percent of civilized time. Seven percent. So, stop lamenting
war, get real. War is the reality, peace is the unreality. War has prevailed ninety-three
percent.
Three percent of the time. Only seven percent. Everybody was broke and tired or what. Liquor
was free for a few years. I don't know, they all got smashed into the hell with fighting.
So you might say peace is the anomaly, isn't it? It's an unnatural condition, statistically
unlikely condition. Occurs only seven percent of the history of civilization. Here's America
at 421.
Why do you want to speak with another country? You've got to know where they're at. You've
got to know where they're at. Here's what America does. It talks across this way. There's
nobody there at 421 except you folks. You're talking in a mirror. Democracy is the wonder
of the world, yeah, right. And what does the mirror say back to you?
That's egoistic self, that's ego cynicism. Aren't we wonderful? Well, then my second question
and aren't we wonderful, just has not sold, folks, hasn't sold. Even where it prevailed,
it's disappeared, replaced by secular socialism. Even where it did work, it's disappearing.
All right, so at 421, you've got to know who you're talking about. Canada at 415, Canada has
also gone secular socialist. You've got to wait three months to get an appointment with a doctor
if you don't want to vote for it. South America, you see in the high 300s. I've been in Argentina
and Brazil, very energetic people, I'll tell you. Like in China or Korea, you're dealing with people
that are very energetic, very on the go, very upbeat. Here you got China at 310. Here you got
Cuba, the government of Cuba, and then you've got the people of Cuba. The leader of Cuba is about
here. The people of Cuba,
are still up in the 300s. Something else we saw in China. So the leader of a country may be very
integrous. I'm thinking of one who calibrated so high, I said, man, this is going to be great for
the future of the world. And the people calibrated in the 300s. They're swell people. It's great to
go on a vacation there. The government is totally rotten. You don't dare drive your car there.
Leave your car at the border. Let's see, the government,
The bureaucracy of the government I'm holding in mind calibrates over 160, 165, about 160.
Here you've got a great president, you've got great people, and the government calibrates it at 160.
Violated, you get held for ransom.
Trumped up charges, they find out you got money, you stay in the jail until you get your money up.
So there you've got great disparity between the people, the leader, and the government.
See the same thing in China.
China once calibrated about 140, it's up to 190.
You can own property there now.
President Zhang, J-H-A-N-G, what was his name, calibrated about 450.
Very smart guy, wonderful people.
What's wrong with the country then?
The government.
Same thing in post-communist Russia.
You didn't see people exuberant freedom, you saw the white, what do they call it, mafia.
You saw the Russians.
You saw the Russian mafia take over, because the government was rotting through and through, huh?
Alright, here you see Central Africa, the calibrations in Jordan and various places are as low as 40.
Life expectancy is about 4 1⁄2 years, more than half the people are born with AIDS.
If you don't die of starvation and AIDS, then a warring chieftain of a neighboring tribe will chop you up into small pieces.
They literally chop each other up.
Chop each other up.
Come here.
Chop up.
Here you die by chop up, AIDS and starvation.
Chop them up is getting to be stylish, it's on TV lately, heh.
You see how primitive and barbaric it is.
Alright.
So you see the implications for the whole world.
We have to know where we are.
Is this our president?
Is this our government?
Is this our people?
And look who we're talking to.
Here's a country with a booming economy, you know.
Good for Nixon.
One thing Nixon did is China could have been a real foe.
That's a dynamo.
If you put Chinamen, what is it, a thousand abreast and start them walking around the world,
they will never end.
Never.
Never end.
As the leading Chinese get to this side, the population has already increased.
You can encircle this people with the population forever.
Heh heh.
Okay.
That's a giant problem they could have been if that antagonism had remained.
So what we did was we cracked that egg and we became trading partners.
Now a trading partnership is meaningful, you understand?
Democracy is not meaningful up here to these people here.
You talk about trade.
Now China is not going to make war with us ever.
Why?
We're their biggest customer.
We're dealing with reality.
Got it?
Reality succeeds.
Okay.
Down here, people want to know, what do we get from dealing with you, paying attention
to your diplomats and your high-sounding, highfalutin philosophy?
You get a huge economy.
So China makes so much money dealing with us, they will never be, you realize how close
China came to really being the ultimate, forget about Russia, put China together, they could
have defeated the United States, frankly.
One against one.
And here we're dealing with countries that are in need.
So if you want to sell democracy, tell people what it can do for your people.
What it can do for you.
Not how wonderful it is, how superior it is, but how does it serve your needs?
My understanding of addiction is fine.
It doesn't help him get sober.
I have to somehow meet him.
Meet him where he's living, to provide him with something that appeals to him, that now
he would listen to what I have to say.
So when I say, go to AA or something like that, everything else is hopeless, I will
have prepared the way.
So we're just talking about using calibrated levels of consciousness to make it a more
effective world, a more peaceful world, a more gratifying world for everyone.
Not just for us.
I don't get anything out of the fact that some country became, what do you call it, a
world that's not just for us.
What do you call it in America?
Democracy.
Yeah, okay.
Does it do anything for me that these people here bought democracy?
Why do I care if they bought democracy?
What do I care?
Why should these people even care about these people here?
Because they have a commonality.
So we've got to find where is the commonality that we can talk in a meaningful way to them.
And hopefully, that would make sense.
That would make diplomatic relationships beneficial and increase the likelihood of
peace except war.
So we tend to increase the power of the field through truth and diminish its destruction
by falsehood.
So we'll take a break.
How long?
Fifteen minutes?
Fifteen.
And then after that, we'll conclude quickly.
And then after that, we'll do questions and answers.
Yeah?
Okay, folks.
We're going to resume.
We're going to move through our questions.
Okay.
We're going to go through a lot of questions and answers, sign books, and we have to be
out of here at 5 o'clock.
And there is a crocodile under your chair.
I don't think they're hearing me.
There is a crocodile slowly coming down the aisle.
Oh, you hear me now.
Okay.
We'll have plenty of time for questions and answers and signing books, and we're going
to be out of here by 5.
They have a wedding right after us.
And so we'll be responsible and considerate.
And only hedge on their time.
Only hedge on their time a little bit.
Okay.
So let us proceed.
I think we tried to cover the important things during the lecture and bring it into today's
world because people tend to compartmentalize spirituality.
That's the old style, Sunday morning, and then the rest of the week, you do what you
want to do.
So I've tried to bring spiritual reality into today's headlines, today's news, its reality
as it impacts our life.
Our life here in this world, and how to see things beyond just perception, how to understand
the core, the energy out of which they are coming, and instead of being manipulated by
rhetoric.
Okay.
So are we ready?
We've got somebody, people with questions.
We're right on schedule.
Resume break at 3.15.
I'll limit your question to one, please, because you see how many other people are here.
We're on a limited time schedule.
So if you have any questions, we'll be happy to answer them.
Thank you.
So if you could please limit your question to one, we would appreciate it.
So while you're standing in line, think about what you want to ask, but we cannot answer
two questions today.
Okay.
Go ahead.
Dr. Hawkins, could you speak to the usefulness of landmark education, such as the forum?
What does that mean?
The forum, the advanced course.
Never heard of it.
I guess you can't talk about it.
I was told that he had, okay.
I've never heard of it.
Forum.
I have never heard of it, no.
Warner Earhart asked.
Oh, Warner Earhart.
Warner Earhart.
What about Est?
Est was back in the 70s.
What about it?
Right.
Just wondered if it's valid and useful.
Calibrates at 400.
We all did Est, it was terrific.
Thank you.
Remember what I liked about it is, the basic thing was taking responsibility and disqualifying
excuses and blame.
So if you got there late, you said, I was late because the traffic held me up.
You know, and then they say, and what is the truth of it?
The truth of it.
you're late because you're late if you're responsible you would have left early so in
case you ran into a traffic jam you would have been here on time so the s would make you wait
outside the door until you got honest and admitted the only one that decided to be here late is you
you couldn't weasel out of it so s was designed to take you over calibration level 200
and uh i think it did a great job of that thank you yeah these are my books took people into
integrity beyond 200 stop blaming others you see blame blame projecting responsibility
instantly throws you below 200 and all the weak losers in the world uh feel sorry for
themselves and blame everything around them and by doing that they can lower their calibration
their power so they don't attract to them that which is successful so the way to success is to
be honest and integrity and accept the responsibility for everything
in your environment if a coffee pot falls off the shelf i look within myself to see what is careless
i don't blame the coffee pot i always assume responsibility for everything that happens in
my life or in my environment and you know i've calibrated the energy field just about everything
in the universe and picked up some discordant energies and had to cure them in myself you know
you tried to clear something there and it was a energy of discord and the way i picked it up is
i got a new fax machine and it was screwing up all the time so instead of saying well it's the
manufacturer of the fax machine there must be something in me that's pulling that into my field
then i went back i saw where i picked it up cleared it in myself that my reality is the harmony
the oneness cohesiveness of god and i'm not subject to discord see that's so that really
comes s was the first promoter of that degree of integrity
yeah so we're all grateful to warner for that thank you yep my coach prods me when i get out
of line she's good isn't she and i take responsibility for that i'm sorry
i try to over explain things because i want to make sure people get it so it comes out of years
of being a therapist or a psychoanalyst to explain it to make sure that they are getting it to me
and i still tend to do it yeah boy am i
in the right seat yeah will you help contextualize for me subjectivity objectivity and where is the
experiential in that the experiential is the basic how do you know you're asking me a question
how do you know you're asking me a question yeah
but within the class that's the subject of reality okay which is independent of content
whatever question you ask me you're still going to get the feeling of of me being the source and
the experiencer of it you know that's the radically subjective yeah is the absolute
the radically subjective is the field of the absolute the presence within yourself the self
with the capital s is the radical source of one's own existence beyond all content
people take existence for granted
to look to where the knowingness of existence is arising, that leads you to the very base
of consciousness itself, takes you out of content, takes you to context, and that's
the way to the realization of reality, non-duality.
And then objectivity would be duality?
No, objectivity.
Can be meant in several ways.
The way I was using it in the lecture today was res cogitans, that's your experience
of your mentalization, and then there's the world the way it is, totally independent
of your existence or your opinion of it.
That's what in scientific thinking the Newtonian paradigm is called objectivity, the world
the way it is, not what you think about it.
How is that a problem?
Then you would have to have a position.
To be objective, to be in objectivity.
No, because it doesn't need anybody to comment about it.
The world is without you here.
But that's absolute.
What makes you say it's absolute, that's your thinkingness, no you just thought that.
Aha, aha, yeah, I need some more work on that.
It's a little abstract when you talk about it theoretically, but you know the subjective
world in which you live, and the world the way it is, sometimes is in accord and quite
often is not.
Help.
I don't have a very rich background in spiritual matters, but I've had a lot of experiences
and a lot of them have to do with chakras opening and convincing me the reality of chakras
and stuff like that.
For instance, I just had a haircut a little while ago and it was about the worst experience
I've had.
It just felt like someone was cutting through a field over and over and over again.
And it was really uncomfortable.
Is there something I should be doing?
I never get them, that's for the reason.
A home haircut's good enough for me.
Even that's dangerous.
Sometimes you get your ear poked.
Ow!
And now I have, like, some pressure here.
Yeah?
And it's all kind of overwhelming because it's been pretty quick.
Well, I would do the Thymic Thump right now.
Please do the Thymic Thump.
Ha, ha, ha, ha, ha.
Okay, now your acupuncture is better balanced, yeah.
You're going to be all right.
Is there, will it pass?
Yeah.
Is it, will this feel like this?
This just feels like there's a cord or something.
It's, I don't like talking about it.
When did this happen?
Middle of March, I was meditating and had an experience, sort of,
where the top of my head no longer felt like the top of my head.
Disorder.
Beard?
Well.
You're a topless fella?
See, this is why I don't like talking about it, Dr. Hawkins.
Okay, you're laughing near me.
I get it.
Yeah, no, it felt like instead of what it had been,
it kind of folded in on itself and there was something.
Your body image.
I don't know what it was, but it.
Your experience of your body image, yeah.
Yes.
Yeah.
In fact, just walking around.
What I find is like, I don't know, I feel, sometimes I feel clumsy because I'm not exactly
sure where I am.
Sometimes I feel like.
Have you done any energy chakra balancing or acupuncture?
No, see, I don't know anything about that because I'm just really naive.
Well, I thought you said you had a number of experiences.
Well, yeah, I have had the experiences, but I don't know what to do with them.
That's why I'm talking to you.
Well, you need a spiritual teacher, obviously.
Amen.
And I can't find anybody because I've gone around to people in Boston and they don't,
they kind of look at me like, what?
Well, what kind of teachers are you looking at?
Well, I went to a Zen.
I went to a Shambhala center.
I went to more traditional Christian.
That was not the place to go, actually.
No, I think it's more energy balancing kind of thing.
I would look at your chakra system and polarity therapy.
It's like a more of an energy problem, huh?
So, you would go to like a Reiki person or something like that?
Well, Reiki, what do the people do with your feet kind of thing?
Reflexology.
I would look into energy medicine, energy medicine, okay?
And then see if that.
If that doesn't work, it should, yes.
Is this, will this persist, the feeling of being in the body?
I don't know.
I can't foretell the future.
If I were you, I would just do what the doctor says.
Go for energy medicine.
Stop talking.
Check it out first there, okay?
Thank you.
Yes.
Good, you got it.
It's a complicated problem.
It would take some study.
It would take some diagnostic energy.
It would take some energy work to see what chakras and what energy is out.
What's the nature of that energy?
You may have picked it up from the barber.
I don't know.
Yeah.
I wanted to say thank you to you.
And I also wanted a hug.
That's pretty much all I can do.
I did have a question about prayer, but you answered it earlier about raising the.
Yeah, yeah.
Okay.
Thank you.
You bet, sweetheart.
That's my name I wrote in there.
Not too legible, I know.
It's my scrawl.
Yeah.
Well, I sort of am in the same boat.
My question was about cause, and you also totally and completely answered that.
And I feel real comfortable with that.
And so I just also want to thank you for the blessing that you are.
Thank you so much.
And I also want a hug.
Oh, you also want a hug.
That's going to be a dollar now.
All right.
Thank you so much, honey, for what you said.
Very nice.
Oh, no.
Yeah.
Hi.
I just want to thank you so much for teaching and writing.
Yes.
You're such a blessing to me and so many people.
Thank you for thanking me.
All of them here and elsewhere.
I'd like to ask you about a spiritual experience I have.
And for you to comment on it, kind of tell me where I was.
I woke up one morning, and I was wide awake, and I rolled over and hugged my husband.
And I felt love for him.
And all of a sudden, I was somewhere else.
And I can't really describe it.
It was experiential.
If somebody told me what did it look like, I'd have to say light.
But I was just in a place where I felt great power, and it was very peaceful.
You're complaining?
No.
Did I look like I was complaining?
You went into a great space.
I went into this great space.
Yeah.
And the other thing I noticed about it was that even though it was totally alien to my experience here.
Not alien.
That's the wrong word.
Well, totally different from anything that we could experience here.
More advanced than what you're used to, yeah.
Yeah, I don't know whether it was advanced or not, but it was totally different.
It was light and love?
No, that's why I...
What was it?
It felt very familiar.
Yeah?
It felt extremely familiar.
Right.
I kind of recognized it.
Like at home?
Recognition, yeah, okay.
Yeah, and it was very comfortable and familiar, and it wasn't bad at all.
And I felt great power.
All around me.
Yeah.
And it was peaceful.
Mm-hmm.
But I didn't feel this enormous love that I hear some people talk about.
Well, that's just slightly different.
Yeah.
So, where did I go, and what was that?
Oh, well, you just went into a more advanced state of consciousness.
The characteristics of near-death experience, out-of-body experiences, that are varied from individual to individual.
You may experience just the presence of love with no light, or you may experience just light and clarity.
Because divinity has various characteristics of light, love, oneness, balance, yeah?
Mm-hmm.
Beauty.
You may experience the presence of God as suddenly overwhelmed by the stunning beauty of your surroundings.
You can walk through the woods and suddenly almost pass out.
You see the incredible beauty, like, shines forth.
And it's divinity expressing itself through your awareness as beauty.
So, you may get it as infinite silence, infinite love, infinite light.
Or infinite power.
It was a very good experience.
Yeah.
I guess I could say I experienced it as infinite power and silence and peace.
Yes, that's correct.
And a feeling of home.
Yes, familiarity is part of it.
What you was at was, you knew that you was over 500, 540, 540, 35, 540.
You was about 540.
Yeah, you start having those experiences, you get more advanced.
Feelings of oneness.
Feeling as though suddenly everything is silent, and you're living in a mystical world of the endlessly miraculous.
It felt very miraculous, and it was short, but I was definitely there.
And then I just sort of, I was overwhelmed with the wonder of it, and I gasped, and that closed the door for me.
That's right.
It's transitory in the beginning.
Yeah.
Okay.
It's transitory because you're above your karma, and then the karma catches up with you again, and they disappear.
And then you keep going, doing spiritual work, and you rise above your karma, and you have wonderful experiences, and then the karma sort of catches up with you again.
Yeah.
So in the beginning, they tend to be evanescent.
You know, the spiritual Christian saints.
Oh, Lord, why hast thou forsaken me?
Oh, lover, why hast thou left me?
Beware that wailing.
That's characteristic of these early experiences.
It disappears, and you feel like you've done something wrong.
You feel like you're forsaken.
You know it's idiotic, but you go back to the spirit.
You're in the same park, in the same corner where it happened, and of course, it doesn't happen again.
You know it's ridiculous even when you do it, but still, somehow, it's like trying to recapture that experience, because they're transformative.
Don't worry about it.
The thing about spiritual work that people don't quite get, and it has to be emphasized, is perseverance.
In other words, I think in the Course in Miracles it's called faithfulness.
Perseverance.
It means you don't do it for five minutes here.
And then go to the ball game, and then tomorrow at noon you suddenly remember to do it for five minutes.
And then Saturday you think, oh, I'll meditate.
I've got time today.
You know, that's sort of sporadic, interrupted.
What you do is you get a fixity of intention, a continuousness.
If you're going to let go of things as they arise, and you're serious about it, you do it continuously, continuously.
You're going to be aware of the field instead of the content of the field.
You do it continuously.
If you see life as a presence, and everything happening as a consequence of the presence, you do that continuously.
So that was one thing I was going to talk about today, and I'm glad you mentioned it.
It says here, persistence.
I gave myself a note about something.
The persistence of the determination of the process, whatever it is.
If you're forgiving, then you forgive.
You can't just forgive for an hour today, ten minutes tomorrow.
And when you go into a really advanced state, it's with one pointedness of mind.
Therefore, certain pathways, what they first do is train you how to attain one pointedness of mind before you even try it.
Because that's the tool you're going to need.
You cannot deviate one iota.
If you're going through surgery without anesthesia, you better walk the edge of the razor.
You have to resist it.
And then if you try to hang on to the pain you just experienced, it's agonizing.
The experience has to be non-resistive, let go of it at the very moment of its crest.
So you move along the crest of the moment of now, with the roll call of now, experiential immediacy.
Okay?
Okay.
And it'll come back then.
Don't worry about it.
Thank you so much.
Yeah.
I'm over explaining.
I just got pushed and nudged.
Is this your book?
No.
Okay.
We have someone peeing off the board.
Thank you so much.
So much.
All right.
Good.
Well, a lot of people have those early transitory experiences, and it worries them that they've disappeared or something.
Yeah.
Hi.
I would gladly pay you Tuesday if I could only have a hug today.
Gives me a dollar.
Okay.
I told you where I got that in the mountains of Peru, you know.
Good.
And actually, I'll add 10 to my credit if I can get a jig.
A what?
A jig.
The dance.
Oh, I haven't got the energy for a dance.
For $10.
I might.
.
it's more important for me whether one should really choose one path
or whether they can use both avatars.
There are two different things. No, not two different things.
There's the same thing, but in a different context.
Christ was born, and he never had a previous human lifetime.
His purpose is salvation, somewhat like the representation of Buddha
as Avalokiteshvara, the Buddha of infinite mercy, of lowest land Buddhism.
What Christ says is, strive for unconditional love.
And if you do so in my name, I will be your spokesman in the celestial realm,
which in this world is called heaven.
The Buddha never had any previous lifetimes.
No, I'm sorry. The Buddha had many previous lifetimes.
Represents enlightenment.
Enlightenment is a different ultimate objective from salvation.
Buddha's enlightenment.
Enlightenment is also realistic, that the likelihood of reaching enlightenment
in this lifetime is extremely small.
So you live as good a life as you can, and by karmic merit,
you will land in the lotus land, which is a celestial realm,
in which the Buddha of the celestial realm will be your advocate,
as Christ is in Christian heaven.
Therefore, the rest of the thing to do is be a Buddhist Christian or a Christian Buddhist.
I can do that.
The only difference is ecclesiastic doctrine.
There's the teaching of Jesus Christ,
and then there's the ecclesiastic doctrine of some church.
The teacher is the teacher.
The church is the church.
Very often, people don't get into spirituality.
They get into religionism.
So watch out.
The trap of religionism.
What you wear, whether you shave or don't shave,
what you eat, sex, no, sex is all irrelevant.
And they get caught up in all that.
At least you call me here on the left side.
The right side is all irrelevant.
Okay?
Okay. Thank you.
You've already got the core of it, or you wouldn't be asking me.
Look at that.
Yeah. Greed for money.
More.
Thank you, honey. I'll keep that.
I'll put it in my memory book.
Thanks.
Yeah.
If you would give me a die, I'd put them away for my old age.
I'm going to save them for my old age.
And I'm going to eat them then.
Yeah.
Doctor, does some food calibrate below 200?
And does it really matter what you eat?
Food in general, generically, calibrates around 200 or 205.
Yeah, you've got to move over here.
Calibrate 200, 204.
Food calibrates at 200, 202.
200.
All right.
The food in general, generically, calibrates around 200 or 205.
Yeah, you've got to move over here.
Calibrate 200, 204.
Food calibrates at 200, 202.
200.
All right.
When you bless food, it jumps to 207, 208.
When you bless food, it automatically energizes, raises the energy of the food.
Whether it is food that calibrates below 200, I don't know.
I've never eaten at a restaurant.
Maybe I should.
I'm going to be honest.
I don't know.
I don't understand.
eating at a restaurant. There is? Yeah, remember, it's that dead food. Oh yeah, dead food, yes. Oh yes, you're correct.
Machine-made food calibrates below 200. You can tell it. It's like it's dead when you put it in
your mouth. Food that's manufactured with human intervention, even if it's somebody overseeing
the pot where it's cooking, it raises the energy level above 200. Okay, so don't eat dad's food?
Oh, I didn't say don't eat it. Bless it. Okay. I can do that.
You know, there's cat food that calibrates below 200. My cat won't eat it.
So I bless it for her. Okay, thank you. No, there's really brands of cat food that calibrate
over 200, and there's one brand, Big Cellar, calibrates below 200. You know, my cat will not
eat it. She just sits there and looks at it. Well, looks at it, no.
So you better calibrate your kitty's food, you know.
I don't have any questions, because you've answered at least them for today. So I just
wanted to say thank you for your materials and your presence. Yes. This has really added to
my evolution. Good, thank you so much. Thank you. What color eyes are those? What color are you
calling them? Huh? You've got pretty eyes. That's a sort of a greenish-brownish, mysterious look.
Hazel. Hazel. I think they call them hazel eyes. Hazel. Yeah. Okay.
Yeah.
If the idea of enlightenment is a goal for this lifetime, what is a very effective practice?
You were listening during the lecture today? Yes. I know, but we have different guides teach
different ideas. I don't know if you've heard of it. I don't know if you've heard of it. I don't know.
What are the different forms of meditation and different topics of meditation?
Well, the only formal meditation I've ever done is Zen style, Zen. You go to a Zen monastery,
you go to a Zen monk, go to a Zen organization, and that's what I would do. Do the world's best.
And you said that the time of death is predestined for this lifetime. Is the ability
to attain enlightenment also? No. No. Okay. Thank you. No.
The law of the universe is freedom. Every instant you're free to choose a this or a that,
a this or a that, until you see there's no more of this or that, and then it stops.
Thank you. Yeah. I would look up a Zen. It's facilitated by will, yeah, but it comes on
on its own, yeah. One once said that the final doorway isn't far away for anybody here.
Who said that? You, actually. No, I didn't say that.
You know? It depends on what you mean by far away. Well, you know, a hundred lifetimes
is short, close by, yes. Right, right. Yeah, just, I guess I'm speaking from a dualistic,
unenlightened point of view. So, like, even the depths of despair, something could happen
where, boom, you know. Oh, yes. Or, but in a progression where somebody is dedicated
to devotional non-dwelling. You don't know when and how it's going to happen. Right.
Because there's not a linear phenomenon. Right. At the most unexpected moment, there's not
a linear phenomenon. Right. There's not a linear phenomenon. There's not a linear phenomenon.
Suddenly, there you have it. Yeah. That's why I like people to have the information
in advance, because you come into a sudden realization. At that point, there's no memory
of anything. You say, well, I'll remember what I learned. No, you won't. At that point,
the frequency and the vibration of your aura radiates a knowingness, non-verbally. You
just know to go this way. And the last fear comes up. And the knowingness. And the knowingness
said, all fear is illusion. Surrender it to God. So, even in the grip of terror, you walk
through the door, and it is the ultimate truth. Okay. So, there wouldn't be, if somebody stays
on a path of devotional non-duality and, say, goes through levels of consciousness, would
they experience certain things prior, possibly? Are there certain experiences that seem common
as somebody who progresses consciously, as opposed to, like, a sudden? No, it's not a
linear progression like that. Right. Okay. It may be. Yeah, I see. It may be period,
in which you feel like you're making great progress for a whole year, let's say. Then
suddenly you feel like you're bogged down. Like, God, I'm meditating, nothing's happening,
I'm getting nowhere. Well, you're undoing stacks of karma, see? And as that karmic obligation
gets dispelled, then you move ahead again, yeah? Okay, cool. Yeah. So, never worry about
it. Alrighty. Thanks so much. Never look at the mileage meter. Okay. Alrighty. Thanks
a lot.
I feel very blessed. Yeah. Yeah, it's not a linear logical progression. In fact, when
you think you're doing the worst, you can suddenly make a leap, and when you think you're
doing great, you can suddenly crash. So, yeah. Okay. Yeah, go ahead. One question. Okay.
The mother watch is over, so don't worry about it. Okay. Bottom of the context is I'm a third
grade teacher, okay? Okay. So, can I...
I'm a third grade teacher. Okay. So, can I become better at... So, can I recontextualize
the learning of my students who are eight and nine-year-olds to move them to a level
of consciousness such that I can teach them how to do kinesiology so that they can walk
out the door... At age nine? At age eight and nine. I don't know that you can actually
teach it. I've demonstrated it on videotape, you know, using kids. Kids are very easy.
Yeah, you can teach them how to do that. And...
They don't even have to know anything. They just hold this picture over your tummy, now
resist. Hitler makes them go weak, Lincoln makes them go strong. We've done that a hundred
times. So, as long as you don't have objection from the community or the parents that you're
teaching something esoteric, you know?
It ain't enough like Socrates.
Yeah, I don't want you to have to drink hemlock.
Hemlock and soda, huh?
If I was Socrates, I'd say, how about Virginia Jarrell, okay?
It's only death anyway.
That's the only one.
But, you know, we have a demonstration video we did back in 95. Early videos, you know,
I did them off in the ranch there. And they were very informal, but honest, you know?
But not a Hollywood production. But, you know, we demonstrated many things with innocent
people, you know? An innocent child doesn't know what that is. And we were showing the
disparity between perception and belief and reality.
And, you know, things that the world thinks will make you go weak didn't make her go weak.
Things they thought, the world thought would make her go strong, she went weak. So, we
just used her as an indicator of, uh, pretty reliable. Kids make very good test subjects.
Thank you.
You gotta pay them a dollar every time, though.
I had one question that I was going to ask you, which I think you've already answered.
I have a young friend, Sage, who...
who was with Eckhart Tolle, uh, up in Canada. And, uh, she had this enlightening experience
and was out teaching, and then has lost it.
Yes.
But I think you answered that, that that's not that unusual.
No, it's common.
And, and I think...
In fact, it's almost, yeah.
Almost guaranteed.
Oh, I remember, this got out of Maharaj, says the thing, I think, or Ramana Maharshi,
I forget. A couple of those teachers in the 700s said the same thing.
Yeah.
That it comes and goes, and, uh, then you, it's like you rise above your karma, and then
you go back and, and undo some more karma, and then you seem, you think you've lost it.
Mm-hmm.
It's the illumination, it's a revelation of what's to come. So, one should be encouraged
by the fact they had it all, instead of discouraged that it's not continuous.
And then just persevere through that.
That's right.
Uh, I had a good opportunity, I saw Nisargadatta in 1976.
Uh-huh.
And, uh, spent about two and a half years there.
Which was a real privilege, right?
Yeah.
Out of the blue.
So to speak.
Uh, when I was reading your introduction last week, someone gave me a book up in Calgary,
and, uh, how I discovered you were around.
Yeah.
And very much appreciate it.
Thank you so much.
Are you, when are you going?
I'll be in Toronto next weekend.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, you're going to Toronto.
Yeah.
I'm on the, sort of, the west, west side.
But we haven't gone to the other side.
Yeah.
Maybe you'll get up to Calgary if we, uh, invite you up.
Calgary's right north of us.
Yeah.
Not a bad trip up there.
I haven't been to Calgary in a lot of years, you know.
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
It's a very nice, uh, high energy place.
That I was once there.
Yeah.
I've been there.
I had a question for myself, if I may.
How, how do I.
Yeah.
Oh.
And to everybody else.
How do we establish the, um, conscious, uh, uh, level that we're at?
To, if we're going to go and do, uh, some, uh, uh, muscle testing and question with somebody
else.
Yeah.
Does that mean we're above 200?
Oh.
People below 200 are not interested in it.
Ah.
Oh.
They wouldn't be at this lecture.
I.
They wouldn't have sat through it.
Oh.
I.
Now we've had.
We've had people below 200 wander into the lecture.
And they usually will get up indignantly and stomp out somewhere in the lecture.
Yeah.
So you can.
Then how do you.
If nobody got outraged.
No.
And didn't stomp out.
Then they weren't below 200.
Oh.
Okay.
Yeah.
So how do we.
Um.
Sort of establish ourselves in.
Pardon me.
How do.
How do we what?
Yeah.
How do we.
Sort of chart our progress.
In fact we're.
You don't have to chart it.
Oh.
You don't have to.
Yeah.
Give it to God.
Let God worry about it.
Okay.
You got nothing else to do.
God's retired.
He just sits up there and gets advice from all those people.
And direction.
Mm-hmm.
Listens to complaints.
Guys they answer the email.
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you.
Can I get a hug too?
You're going to have a hug.
Okay.
You knocked my microphone right off my ear.
Oh sorry.
I stuck it in my eye one time on the stage.
I don't know how you get this freaking thing back on.
Here let me get it.
Oh.
Okay.
Since I knocked it off.
Oh.
Yeah.
There we go.
Okay.
I feel like a bird man from some planet.
Distant planet or something.
So we'll look forward.
Maybe.
It's a great microphone.
It seemed so strange when we first got it but person who sold me on it was the Unity
Minister.
She says, once you get used to it, you'll see.
Beats anything going.
And it's true.
After you've worn it for a while, you don't know it's there anymore.
Yes.
Dr. Hawkins, thank you first of all for today and for your books that I've read.
My husband and I feel we're on a spiritual path.
We moved from Atlanta, Georgia, to a small town in Georgia.
And now we're moving to Sedona.
We felt compelled to be here.
And does place matter?
Does place matter?
I don't think so, no.
That's what I thought.
It's what's within that matters.
Well, it's more as you move ahead, you look for what would,
that was just more concordant with where you are within yourself.
Yes.
When I moved out here, as I say, I didn't have a refrigerator.
I couldn't take the noise of it, you know what I'm saying?
Yes.
I wanted stillness, peace, and there was nobody in Sedona.
They closed it up all winter.
There was one restaurant open, and it closed at 8 o'clock.
It's much smaller than it used to be.
And that was just fine with me.
Now it seems like a thriving metropolis,
and I avoid Sedona and get out of town as quick as I can.
On downsizing, we're having to decide what to bring,
because the place here is small.
Yeah.
Can I, how does one have the confidence in kinesiology
when you're going through your big book collection
to know which ones to come with you?
Boy, I don't know.
There are people that are good at it.
If you don't have confidence in yourself,
if you don't have confidence in your own capacity,
there's people who are good at it.
And you ask them to help.
Yeah.
Boy, thank you.
May I also have a hug?
As far as spiritual libraries,
I've thrown them out two or three times.
Yes, that's right.
That's right.
To answer that question.
I left the East.
I left 6,000 volumes.
Then I, in Sedona, began stacking them up again.
Then I left all of them again.
And now to write this book, I've got to collect them again.
I mean, how many copies of the Rig Vita do you have to buy in a lifetime?
I'm Gary.
I have mixed emotions of being up here.
The last two people that came up did not have to give you a dollar for a hug.
The first one was a male.
All the rest of the women you asked, so what does that mean?
No, hugs are for free.
Hugs are for free?
Hugs are for free.
Okay.
Friendly hugs cost a dollar.
Bill, look at you.
No, he's a mesomorph.
Well, I was...
I was a mesomorph.
I was prepared to pay two, so...
No, no, one dollar is fine.
I'll put it in my piggy bank for when I get old.
We are a group of 22 men here on a spiritual path.
And one of the things that we do is we hug.
Oh.
And that's one of the reasons that...
Yes.
To get in touch with both our feminine and masculine...
Well, I'll give you a dollar.
I'll give you a dollar.
Now I'll get to my...
I'll get to my question.
Yeah.
Here again, as everybody else has said, thank you.
I believe I've had some insight, and this has to do with a relationship,
in a personal relationship with an immediate family.
One of the things that I've struggled with for quite some time is
when you see somebody that you love in the family,
but there are some demonstrations of things that...
behaviors that you do not go along with,
but you're afraid to confront them with it because of your relationship,
what is my responsibility?
What is my responsibility in that?
And how do...
If there is a thing of overcoming, how do I overcome that?
Oh, that's touchy very often.
The 12-step groups work on that, you know,
Al-Anon and all the time.
Whether to say nothing, you're being an enabler,
or whether to say something, you're trying to control.
So you screw it either way, see?
Do I go now?
No.
Peace be with me.
You try to be that which would make a mirror back to them.
You try to be that.
And at the same time, use spiritual techniques such as prayer.
You pray for them.
And you do the course of miracles and ask for a miracle.
And then you've done all you can.
The rest is up to God.
Thank you.
And if that don't work, you tell him he either straightens up
or he gets his ass the hell out.
Now I know I'm touching it.
Oh, yeah.
First, I want to say thank you very much.
Your books have had such a positive impact on my life
that it's just been incredible.
And I'm just grateful for your presence.
Thank you.
And the chance that I got to come and see you.
And second of all, my question is,
and I've wondered this in childhood,
how many licks does it take to get to the center
of a tattoo roll lollipop?
Why is it a whirly mouse?
Because the more it spins and then some.
Oh, my God.
And it's written all over the place.
Isn't that disrespectful?
Yeah, go ahead.
My name's Gary.
I'm from Canada and just came to say hi.
Yeah.
We've got so many Canadians lately.
I don't know what it is.
We're trying to get above 415.
Yeah, we're going to be in Toronto next weekend, you know.
And we're going to do what we can.
Help our brothers, our brothers.
My name is Dennis.
I'd just like to thank you.
Yeah.
Thank you for your teaching.
It's wonderful.
No, I haven't been in Canada in a long time.
Canada.
I used to fly there once a month from New York.
Oh, come on back.
I was on the board of directors of Weber Pharmaceuticals.
Weber, W-B-E-R.
They manufactured vitamin E,
and we were interested in researching the effect of vitamin E,
which is an antioxidant, on longevity, cardiac disease,
and improving mental disorders.
By improving the environment of the mind, you know.
And so I used to go there once a month, fly up there.
Yeah.
You know you're in Canada because everything's suddenly sane and neat.
On this side, everything looks chaotic and rubbishy.
And you get on the Canadian side, and here's this stunning apartment building.
Here's a whole city block, all lawn.
In the middle is this apartment building.
And you park underneath the apartment building,
so the streets are not all littered with cars.
So,
that, to me, is Canada.
Yeah.
And this side, it was cars parked this way, and this way, and this way, and chaotic.
So, my idea, memory of Canada is pristine and can be in the beauty of pristine clarity.
And, of course, it had a beautiful green lawn, and the cars are parked under the building,
so you don't see them all around, you know.
That's my memory of Canada.
Okay. Well, thank you very much.
Is that the way it is, or is that my dream state?
No, no.
That is.
That is the way it is.
Well, as an old-time obsessive-compulsive, it makes me real happy.
Aloha.
Yeah.
Which island?
Kauai.
Aloha and mahalo.
I have a quick question on walk-ins, question mark?
On what?
Walk-ins.
Is there such a truth as walk-ins?
That's a reality result.
It's a spiritual belief system, it's an actual reality result.
Ah, it's a belief system, that clears that up.
We've been asked that.
I don't remember that we ever did it, frankly.
Yeah, it was way back in the beginning, Dave.
Oh, years ago.
Well, we did it at home, I think, one time, but I forgot.
Well, that's good to know, thank you.
Yeah.
I think we got the same one.
I can't remember.
Yes, that's correct, we did.
We got about 180.
We should have come to Kauai.
Well, we've been asked to come to Kauai.
We've been asked to come to Kauai about three times.
Yeah.
But we haven't confirmed anything yet.
But we will be there.
Thank you.
Oh, and I need a hug.
Oh.
I can't go back to Kauai without one.
Thank you.
Ah, yes.
Last time I was in Hawaii was 1945.
The war was over, and we came back through Pearl Harbor, through, what the hell was
it there?
Hello?
Diamond Point or something.
Diamond Head.
Diamond Head, yeah.
We went out through Diamond Head, and those of us that made it back came back through
Diamond Head.
Yeah.
I have a question.
We come to the classes and it feels like we get a real lift, and then we get home Monday
morning and it seems to collapse.
You go back to work and you get buried back in work.
You talk about recontact.
Yeah.
textualizing in the eye.
Would you speak to that,
how one can retextualize and not fall into that?
All right, you sacrifice,
you give everything you do your maximum,
and you surrender it to God as you do it.
That way you bring up the joy of your own existence.
At this moment, I'm answering you to the best I can,
and I'm very conscious and aware of your presence
and the presence of the books and the presence of the audience.
I'm being maximally what I can be at this moment.
I have no regret that I'm not being more than what I'm being
because I'm being all that I can be right now.
When I dig a ditch, I dig it with absolute ferocity.
I mean, that ditch really gets it, you know?
So I give maximum what I am to everything I do,
whether it's more...
mowing the lawn, petting the kitty,
no matter what you do.
If you're writing a book,
you knock your brains out to do the maximum
to actualize your potential.
And that brings you joy,
so that every moment is equally joyful
because every moment is equally your maximum
being the potential of that which you can be every moment.
If I'm a protester, I'm going to protest to the maximum.
If I'm going to be content,
I'm going to sit there and eat donuts to the maximum.
You know what I mean?
I'm going to do whatever I do.
What are those donuts?
You eat one and you can't have another?
You can't stop?
Yeah.
I stay out of them.
Krusty something, rather?
I stay out of those places.
They bring them into my office.
Oh, man, I'd say take them away.
Please, please.
Either bring me six or don't bring me any.
I purposely never eat in the Krusty
because I know what would happen.
You get buried.
Anyway, you do everything you can do to the maximum.
To the maximum.
And the source of joy is within you
when you fulfill your potential every minute.
When you are what you can possibly be
from second to second,
there's no regrets.
When I think of the ditch I dug by hand,
I mean, you know, a long one, big one.
And when I think of it now,
I did the best I could on that ditch.
I really did.
My damn brain valve.
Or an ectomorph.
It was tough work.
You know?
Yeah, it is.
I've done that.
So, anyway,
that's what you want to do
is be the best you can be.
Be the best parent you can.
Be the best spouse you can.
Be the best citizen you can.
Be the best spiritual example you can be.
And you're doing all that simultaneously.
Yeah.
If that doesn't bring you joy,
I'll send you a script.
All right.
I want a hug.
Yeah.
So, that's really all there is to it.
Well, I'm making a mint today.
I don't want you to go hungry tonight.
No, no.
I want you to just be the absolute,
all that you can be.
Every moment.
Yeah, every moment.
Without relapse.
Thank you so much.
When you sleep,
you pass out as unconscious as you can be.
We still have someone who hasn't picked up the car keys.
Oh.
Yeah?
I think we have four.
We have a truck key up here.
Someone's lost one.
Hi.
I have schizophrenia.
And when I was first going nuts,
I had some spiritual experiences.
And I was wondering how much of that was like,
I mean, I believe some of the experiences were real,
but it's sort of,
some people with schizophrenia believe that everything they experience was wrong,
which is a great deal of it is pretty messed up.
So, I'm just,
I'm just wondering if the experiences I had were real, or?
Were they joyful?
Made you happy?
Connected with infinite oneness?
Love?
Well, then they're real.
There were little blue demons dancing around.
They're probably not real.
Okay.
Love is always love.
And therefore, the presence of love would tell you the difference.
Because you can't imitate the presence of love.
It either is or it is not.
It's, and such experiences are also described,
described in the kundalini literature.
Like?
Yeah, the kundalini knocking people into temporary psychosis,
and Gopi Krishna, I think, mentions it.
But there's others in the kundalini energy,
in which the energy impacts the brain,
and a person may become sort of out of it for a while.
With prayer and alignment with the truth of God, it cures itself.
So, if I pray, I'll be more likely to get better?
Oh, yeah.
Of course, of course.
And if you completely and totally surrender to God,
it doesn't make any difference whether you recover or not.
It's just a problem.
Well, he created you, didn't he?
Don't let him worry about it.
You do the best you can to straighten your head out, and the rest is up to him.
Am I right?
Thank you.
Yeah.
You surrender your coverage to God, you know.
Also, these things are cyclic.
You may cycle into it and then cycle out of it, karmic cycles.
I just wanted to say, last night I was so excited about coming here today
that I had a dream you were teaching me how to swim.
You know, and you would, like, go under the water,
and you were teaching me how to, like, hold my breath,
and it was just a great dream.
So, I just wanted to tell you.
That's very good.
I was a coach, huh?
That's right.
Like a swimming coach.
And I brought a dollar.
Thank God I'm making a mint today.
All right.
Thank you.
That's neat, a swimming coach.
That's fantastic.
Thank you.
Oh, boy.
Huh?
You used to love swimming.
Yeah.
Swimming was the only thing they would approve me to do.
But I wasn't allowed on the team.
But you can swim.
Hi, doctor.
My name is Richard.
I'm from New Orleans.
I've been working a 12-step program,
and you've got a lot of material and background in the 12-step program.
And I had a question.
Once a person's began to control the alcohol or the addiction.
Control what?
Well, they're no longer doing it for 20 years or so,
yet the character defects continue to surface.
Any suggestions?
Well, you keep doing the steps.
Fourth step, third step, eleventh step.
Join other spiritual groups.
Do the Course in Miracles.
A lot of people on the 12-step do.
Do the Course in Miracles, too.
And what do you mean by character defect?
Well, promiscuity, things of this nature that...
Oh, loss of impulse control?
Yes.
Oh, you're an impulse freak.
Yeah.
Oh, yeah.
Addicted to impulsivity and instant gratification.
Yeah.
Right.
Oh, it takes a lot of purr.
Oh, okay.
Yeah.
You can try it.
You can try fasting.
You can join a monastery.
Okay.
Thank you so much.
Yeah, it's a form of addiction, yeah.
You're addicted to sensation, pleasurable sensation.
Yeah.
And there is hope, huh?
Gee, I don't know.
Yeah, there's lots of people that have grown beyond it.
Okay.
Yeah.
Lots of people have grown beyond it.
You just keep surrendering to God, praying,
and doing the best you can with it.
Thank you.
Yeah.
I came mostly for the hug.
But my question is,
you mentioned to the young gentleman earlier
that the use of a spiritual teacher can be very beneficial.
Yes.
My question would be,
at what level should that teacher be at,
whether in person or through a book?
Anybody you relate to makes sense to you.
If they're too far beyond you,
it sounds too esoteric and unreal.
And if they're behind you,
it sounds too simplistic, you know.
Well, you know, you feel attracted to it, it's meaningful.
That's Vibrate.
It'd be meaningful to you.
Informative and meaningful.
So you sort of automatically gravitate to that, you know.
Or their style is meaningful to you, you know.
And one teacher will appeal to a certain group
and not appeal to another, you know.
Okay.
My style tends to be a little direct.
You know, and not everybody goes through that.
Right.
They're in enough time for their hearts and flowers.
So I'd sometimes just go for the reality of it, you know.
Okay.
You save 10, 20 lifetimes that way.
Sounds good. Thank you.
Oh, a hug.
Okay, yeah.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Yeah.
I must be the hug man on the planet.
I was once a touch-me-not.
You wouldn't believe it.
I said, I hated being physically near anybody.
I would never have been on a good submarine.
You know, some guy going by me, I'd go, Jesus Christ.
As a kid, I couldn't stand the other kids.
I was putting their grammy fingers in your eyes and stuff.
And rustling.
And now I'm a hug-a-bug.
I can't believe it.
No, I was a touch-me-not, you know.
Yeah.
Thank you for your books.
They've been very helpful.
One of the ways they've been helpful for me is to help me more consistently get past that
idea of an anthropomorphic God, which was really drummed into my head as a child.
Oh, yeah.
Well, we all did.
Through traditional Christianity.
Yeah.
God of the Old Testament.
But then that raises a question.
Because you also, in your work, you emphasize praying and just letting go, submitting.
Yeah.
But if there's not an anthropomorphic God to answer those prayers.
Then there could be a real God.
Then, well, what's the mechanism?
What's the mechanism?
And how would prayer work?
Because we know it works.
Is it maybe through the attractor fields that you talk about?
Something along those lines?
You want to know about the mechanisms of prayer?
Yes.
Well, the prayer itself, if you calibrate its energy, has an intention at a certain
level.
And when you surrender a thing to God, you don't look for a response, because you just
surrendered it to God.
So the prayer itself, if you calibrate its energy, has an intention at a certain level.
And when you surrender a thing to God, you don't look for a response, because you just
surrendered it to God.
so there's no anthropomorphic expectation.
Okay.
You're looking at a two-way communication.
You are to God that which surrenders itself to God,
and by so doing, you pull in the energy field of the infinite.
That's why I recommend the 91st Psalm.
It isn't that you hear a conversational answer.
It's that you come into the presence of a certain aha, knowingness.
I think, God, what is this all about anyway?
I can't make head or tail out of this.
No answer.
Ah, to heck with you.
So you get the paper, and you open it, and there it is.
Got it?
It comes from the field.
There is an answer within the field, see?
Okay.
And you come to it because of the attraction of the field.
Okay, so it is the attraction of the field.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
So the answer unfolds of its own.
In the course of miracles, the way it's phrased is
you ask the Holy Spirit,
and you ask the Holy Spirit for a miracle.
A miracle means the recontextualization to your knowingness
so that you automatically see the answer
because that which is false is removed.
That's why we're talking about the importance of contextualization,
that what looks wrong in this particular context,
in a different context, just lost its wrongness or its rightness.
Mm-hmm.
So the answer to that is,
I always look at step-down levels of divinity, see?
We said archangels are at 50,000 and up.
This planet, you can get about as far as 1,000.
At that point, your nervous system burns out, and you croak.
We leave here at 1,000.
We seem very advanced.
We're in kindergarten in a level at archangel at 50,000
because we're talking about logarithmic.
So I always see God's power as being infinite,
which you cannot handle.
You can't touch an infinite power.
Instant fry.
So it's almost like step-down transformers, see?
And in this dimension and other dimensions,
you see levels of energy, levels of energy.
When you get to 1,000, you don't see it on this planet anymore.
It doesn't mean it's disappeared.
You went into the celestial dimensions
where they start at 600 and up, let's say.
And then it advances to a nonverbal knowingness.
In the depths of hell, one eye said,
well, not eye, but some voice,
and it said, in the depths of hell,
which is far worse than anybody's description of it I've ever read,
beyond all hope forever, eternally beyond all hope,
the voice said, if there is a God, I ask him to help me.
Then oblivion.
Then, from the depths of hell,
suddenly there was the realization of the allness of divinity
that shone forth like, shh.
Huh.
I always thought, in the depths of hell,
this prayer arose from some part of the consciousness,
and a passing archangel was cruising by,
noticed it, hmm, and left.
Just a hmm from an archangel.
I never spoke of it for 30 years.
Silenced the mind for 30 years.
Power beyond imagination.
Even when the presence is in the form of,
uh,
a love that just melts you with its exquisiteness.
That love has a peculiarity.
You can tell people who've been there.
Because the meltingness is exquisite.
Also infinitely powerful and peculiarly like rock.
Rock-like.
Infinite power.
Exquisitely gentle.
Like the most powerful machine on earth.
Unstoppable.
In all dimensions.
Touches you, and it's like, whew.
Difficult to describe.
Softer than silk.
Thank you.
Yeah.
So.
How do you do, sir?
Thank you.
My wife, the Canadian, wanted you to sign.
Yes.
My wife, the Canadian.
If you can get her over 415, I'll be happy.
I still got some Canadian money I've saved from my last trip there,
which was 35 years ago.
I wonder if I can still use it.
Buy it in my jewelry box.
What?
Did you know, Marta and Walter,
in Tucson?
I don't know anybody in Tucson.
Oh, okay.
They had a balancing program that had a lot of these same numbers.
Yeah.
Yeah, it's common in the Hoonah, too.
In the Hoonah?
Yeah.
I hope it's good there.
Anyway, I love your common practicality in a field that's full of other things.
Okay.
All right.
I think spiritually it has to be real.
And not just airy-fairy out there someplace.
Yeah.
And you do it when we all sit and meditate and play musical music
and burn incense and flowers and do rose petals.
Because that's not part of where you live.
Every day you're on the subway, you're dealing in business,
you're dealing with children, wives, flat tires.
You got to have a spirituality that's real from moment to moment in everyday life.
Yeah.
You spoke about experiences in war being very transformational at times.
Yeah, they are.
I was in Vietnam, and I came back after a year in the jungle, and I saw two people
fighting for a parking place in New York.
And I swore I would never again get that upset over that thing.
Happily, I never had to go to Vietnam.
I volunteered, but they said over 70, they won't take you.
You could have gladly had my place.
No, that was a bloody war.
Yeah.
Thank you, sir.
Mm-hmm.
Hello.
Yes.
Good to see you live.
Usually I see you on my TV in France.
Yes.
Yeah.
I mean, are books being translated into French?
No.
Are they translated?
Yes, they are.
Wow.
Yes.
So the question is about water and its properties related to consciousness.
Because these last years in the scientific community, people are demonstrating the ability
of water to store information and to give it back.
And there's a work of a Japanese person, Masaru Emoto, on the frozen water crystal
that really brought love in me.
And that was right at the moment when you answered my question on Beyond the Ordinary.
net radio.
And your answer was basically that I should not be passionate about thought systems and
theories.
And so the water crystal was kind of an answer to that, because it was just the overwhelming
beauty of it.
And I didn't need to put a word on it, you know.
It was just beautiful.
And yet, I want to ask if it's beneficial for me to know something about it.
I'm thinking about water and consciousness.
About water?
Water and consciousness.
Is water a...
Oh, the effect of consciousness on crystals, water crystals.
Oh, water crystals.
Yeah, yeah.
Is water a condition for consciousness?
Yeah.
Those experiments have been done for many years, not necessarily on the crystalline
structure of water, but on the surface tension, you know.
You can measure the surface tension, pray over it, and you change the surface tension
of the water, yeah.
Okay.
Yeah.
But it's anecdotal.
How does it get you enlightened?
Yeah.
Yes.
Yeah, that was one question that I wanted to gather so save your...
It's just diversion.
Okay.
Yeah.
I wanted to know if it's...
Is water a condition for the expression of consciousness on earth?
I don't get the question.
He wanted to know...
Like everything you calibrated, they contain water.
Okay.
He wants to say, since we're...
You're trying to give some kind of a magical condition to water.
No, no.
W...
What?
It came out in that.
Yes...
Yes, because your water and consciousness can affect the crystalline structure in the water, then so what?
So?
Your physical body is going to stay here when you leave.
You're going to take your spirit.
These things demonstrating the effect of consciousness and its impact on the physical domain, you know,
are curiosities, but they are useless.
Now, for instance, I can tell you, the Ganges River, which is one of the filthiest in the world,
is the dumping ground of 100 cities, full of feces, dead bodies.
The Ganges River calibrates over 500, 510, 515, 510.
The Ganges River calibrates at 510, which is higher than the water in your faucet at home.
How can that be?
Hmm?
Millions of faithful people praying, and what they did is they made the Ganges River sacred by intention.
Millions of Hindus over centuries and centuries have cleansed themselves in the Ganges and blessed it.
And in my lifetimes, as a worshiper of Shiva, I myself was incinerated on the ghats on the side of the Ganges River.
And the Ganges River...
The Ganges River becomes its energy at 500.
So...
But the water itself, I don't know anything about it, but I know of spiritual intention.
So when you bless food, you can calibrate food before you bless it, calibrate after you bless it.
You can calibrate food that's been made by hand with love at home, as compared to machine-made in the supermarket.
Yeah?
So, you see the impact of spiritual spirituality, isn't it?
That's okay.
Wonderful.
Great.
You bring upologizing.
I wish you any while.
That would be wonderful.
OK.
Casual.
Where to go after this.
He's hopefully at an outreach topic.
So it would be useful, I think that's interesting, that the crystalline effect, crystalline expressions of water molecules are affected by consciousness.
Thank you very much.
Yeah, sort of the Heisenberg principle, yeah, quantum mechanics of it all.
Hi there.
Yeah.
My body has been kind of puny this year, so I've had plenty of time to listen to your videos, and I've taken pieces and gotten them kind of mixed up, I think.
And basically about prayer, if you pray for a specific result, you said at one point that's like telling God what to do.
It's called outlining.
And then?
Dear God, I want $32 on Monday at 15, yeah.
And if you have something specific that you want to have happen, it's like not surrendering.
And then another time you said God doesn't interfere with Earth on any regard or on creation.
That he lets creation happen as the situation is.
So I'm kind of wondering, is prayer, besides communion, for any purpose?
You're talking about prayer being used now as a blessing for food, for water, for rivers.
It's a declaration of intention.
It has a certain energy of its own.
We demonstrated today that it collapses the wave function from the viewpoint of quantum mechanics.
There is even a mathematics to it.
It's a statement of intention.
If you pray for God's will in a matter and surrender it to God, then you're not looking for an answer,
so you wouldn't know if you got one because you surrendered it already.
But the likelihood, the potentiality of that which is prayed for becomes higher.
So you know that that which you hold in mind tends to manifest.
I've never looked.
Never looked where to live the last three or four, five places I've lived.
I held in mind what I wanted.
I lived way out in the country.
Went to many lectures, so many things in the city I thought if I just had an apartment in the city,
a little pita terre, you know, it'd be perfect.
So I got in the car, drove into town, parked at a real estate agency,
went in, said what I want on Fifth Avenue.
I got the only apartment available in all of New York City.
Rent controlled, right on Fifth Avenue.
That happened over and over.
It was just holding in mind the most, what you would be the most desire thing, but without adding desire to it.
And then you surrender.
You see, you're not trying to force God to give you this.
That's a whole different kind of thing.
That's not really prayer.
Prayer is really surrendering your vision to divinity.
And if it's karmically appropriate,
and divinity's in a good mood, it happens.
Otherwise, it's that nutty guy there with the same freaking prayer.
How do you shut him up, you know?
They send you an email that says, Igne, no.
No, because so many things depend on karmic propensity.
See, and you don't know what the karmic evolution of that is.
So people say, I did this and this and this and this and nothing happened,
and then I quit doing anything and all of a sudden it happened.
You got yourself out of the way.
So surrendering is a continuous process.
It's a way of being in the world.
As I say, it's like a mudra where you consistently surrender as it appears to be happening.
And whatever is, is whatever is.
What difference does it make?
You die today, you die ten years from now.
It's all the same.
At the end, it's all the same.
Thank you.
Yeah, we'll finish them all today.
Good.
Yes, ma'am.
I just have a, my question is always about daily life,
because it's hard to take this back.
Non-duality, trying to live your life in a state of non-duality
or not having positions about things, are we still supposed to vote?
You vote for the right one.
I mean, I can calibrate and vote for the person who calibrates higher,
but that's not necessarily...
Oh, you could do that if you wish.
But they both calibrate around the same, so...
Well, I'm ultra-liberal.
That means they're all fine with me.
The collective karma of mankind is what it is,
and its expression as America is what it is.
And what America needs to learn or go through or profit by will surface.
The people collectively will go in this way or that way.
So if I choose to vote, am I still participating in duality?
No, duality is how you see it.
Duality is, you see, you would see it as a choice.
Duality you'd see it as right and wrong and all kinds of judgmentalism and all.
You know what I'm saying?
You know, different drivers are going to have a different kind of ride, that's all.
With one, it seems a little prosaic, and the other could be quite exciting, you know.
I'm going to go this way today, that way tomorrow,
so I'm all for the excitement in whichever way it goes, you know.
Every president's been great.
Each one is great in its own way.
I don't know, I would have been bored with Hoover, however, I think.
I grew up in the time of Hoover, and he was sort of a boring kind of a guy.
I really don't have any questions.
You've answered a lot of them for me,
but I wanted to thank you so much for being who you are and sharing it.
Thank you.
And I want to acknowledge your presence, too. Thank you.
I want a hug.
You can have a hug.
I shouldn't say that about Hoover.
I was too young to appreciate his positive attributes.
Yeah.
That was the era of prohibition, wasn't it?
Yes, it was prohibition when I grew up.
Everybody made bathtub gin.
I have a question.
I've been studying your books and listening to your tapes,
and I understand that surrender and treating all actions as spiritual is critical,
but is that potentially incompatible or difficult with a career in business?
Because I spend 10, 12 hours a day, you know.
Is that compatible?
Is that compatible with what?
With a career in business, with, you know, focusing on, you know,
what you're enjoying, making money and doing deals and things like that.
I find it very difficult to reconcile the two.
Oh, it's because of the way you're contextualizing it.
See, you're contextualizing yourself as a profit maker which brings up guilt
or seeking profit or greed or, you know, you're contextualizing as guilty, greedy,
solar plexus kind of a phenomenon.
I would look at your business more from the viewpoint of stewardship.
Your responsibility is you have certain business gifts.
You know, a lot of people in this world do not have the gifts to be a businessman.
So you have to picture yourself as the steward of these gifts
from which everyone will benefit, employee, customer, co-worker,
and that you benefit the world by being the example of what that is
and how that looks in the world.
So there's lots of people that are interested
in bringing spirituality into business.
They do so by integrity.
Integrity is very powerful.
Integrity shows up on the bottom line.
You know, the most integrous corporation in the world.
Walmart?
Number uno.
All right.
So I view business as, or anything that you might say,
well, I can't do kinesiology on that because that's selfish.
No, because you have a responsibility to your assets.
To your family.
To the stewardship of your assets.
Whether they're, let's say you're born physically beautiful.
All right?
All right.
The best stewardship of that beauty might be to become a movie star
or a singer or something where that asset brings joy and happiness to people.
So look at it more like the stewardship of your skills
that you take responsibility that these skills are used
to the best advantage of as many people as possible.
Then, because of your integrity,
the field will feed back to you whatever is the consequence.
You don't have to worry about profit.
But do you, while you're doing things,
are you thinking about each action being spiritual or whatever else?
Or do you just have integrity and just do the best that you can?
You align yourself with integrity and make that your way of business.
Where everything is win-win.
Where you're willing to karmically face the consequences.
Face God for the responsibility of your behaviors.
I know, you see.
And if you're aware at all times that you're karmically responsible
for the consequences of your choices and decisions and actions and words,
that acts as a constraint anyway.
When I teach, I'm very aware of the conscious,
the karmic responsibility of everything I say.
Everything I write.
We calibrate every word, every sentence, every chapter,
every paragraph, every book.
Because I don't want to be the author of that which is false.
You understand?
So the commitment is integrity to the work itself.
Being the best that you can be.
And being, let's say, a salesman,
then be the best salesman you can be.
The best inventor, whatever it happens to be.
Can I get a hug too?
Yeah.
Everyone should pick your gifts, whatever they are.
And you're the steward of those gifts.
Maybe it's a mesomorphic body.
Maybe it's a high IQ.
Maybe it's being good looking.
Like me.
Thanks again also to Ed,
everybody's accolades about all the work you've done.
Regarding kinesiology, I saw a video
where you had Susan repeat the mantra OM
and it changed the outcome of the answer.
Is it possible that a person, personal agenda,
can affect the work of kinesiology?
Does the positionality affect the result?
The integrity of the question,
the integrity of the two people involved,
will determine the likelihood of validity.
A lot of people ask me a question.
What they want me to do is to reinforce some positionality.
They're not really asking me a question.
They're asking me to validate
some positionality.
Well, the question itself is not integrous.
Okay, but can a person...
Do you know what integrity is?
Yes.
It means surrounding the truth
without having a positionality
about how that should look or how it should come out.
But then if someone does...
Then they won't get correct answers.
Okay.
How can one discern that that might be taking place?
Maybe you can't.
If it's still a question,
do you doubt your own sincerity and integrity?
No.
Well, then why would there be a question that means you do?
I don't have any doubt about the integrity of my question.
It's an absoluteness.
So long as there's a doubt,
then there's some conflictual program,
unless you mean it about other people.
Other people.
Other people have their own programs,
and you can only calibrate their level of integrity
and see that they get the same answer as you do.
I mean, who should you put faith in?
What is your question?
Can a person's agenda...
Yes, it would decrease the likelihood
of their getting a correct response.
I already said that.
Okay.
Can that be discerned through kinesiology?
You mean this team doing it about this team?
Yes.
If this team is integrous,
and their question would be,
this team is reliable,
they should get a correct answer, yeah.
Everybody should get the same answer,
as long as integrity is intact.
About whether this team is integrous.
Yes.
Yes, everybody should get it.
If they're over 200,
then everybody should get,
yes, they're over 200, yeah.
Otherwise, they should give up kinesiology
and do something else.
Okay.
Are you accepting IOUs for hugs?
For what?
For hugs.
Yeah.
Thanks a lot.
Thank you.
Appreciate it.
I didn't quite understand the question
the way you were phrasing it,
but now I get what you're saying.
How reliable is reliable?
Well, pretty much sometimes,
but not always when it isn't.
First thing I'd like to say is thanks.
Yeah.
That's a lot of work for a lot of years.
I know I'm very appreciative of it.
And for those that don't know,
he recently had a birthday.
Happy birthday.
Yeah.
Is the only birth the birth of consciousness,
and the only death is the death of consciousness?
Well,
what we call birth, then,
is the emergence into the physicality,
and what we call death is leaving this physicality.
So people identify it with physicality.
In this lifetime experience at age three,
the physicality, as I told you,
was a grave disappointment.
I personally had a lot of anger about it.
You said you were disappointed.
I was really pissed, but anyway.
And that would be the only thing
that would be the death of consciousness.
And that would be the only death
would be the death of consciousness.
You can only experience one death.
Physical death you can't experience
because the capacity to experience
belongs to consciousness,
and the minute it leaves the physicality,
that which has the capacity to experience
is no longer part of the physicality,
so you can't experience your own physical death.
You can only witness it.
Is love really the only reality in this dimension?
Depends on who you ask.
I'm gonna ask you.
You know.
The awareness of,
no, the absolute reality is
the awareness of the oneness with
consciousness itself
as the absolute subjectivity
of the knowingness of your own existence.
Love is
expressible
as a quality of divinity.
It can be the primary presenting quality
when you're coming from ordinariness,
then to go out into the presence,
it's the love that just blows you over.
But as you progress in consciousness,
that condition of love begins to prevail,
so it doesn't knock you out.
But you may next be aware
of the incredible beauty of things,
and that beauty knocks you out.
So it's the not being used to it.
It's not the quality itself.
Once you,
once you become aware of the presence of God
as all existence,
and see the beauty of all that exists,
then you don't get knocked out by it, see?
Because everything you see,
when you first go into that state,
these flowers would incapacitate me.
I wouldn't be able to talk to you right now.
But I've gotten used to it.
So the vibrant beauty of it,
the expression of divinity
as the exquisite beauty of their presence,
I would learn how to live in that world.
But that took many years.
That's why I left the city
and said nothing really for 30 years.
Well, I'd give you a dollar,
but I'd rather give you two dollars
and let me hug Sue.
Where's my sword?
Okay, here's the buck I owe you for kissing her.
Oh, God, yeah.
All right, we're going to have to wrap it up, they say.
They're looking at us with cold stares and threats.
So have we completed our answering everyone's questions?
We'll do some words of wisdom.
Okay, all right.
So, well, today has been a wonderful day.
And it's been my divine,
it's been my pleasure.
It's been my pleasure to remain in this world.
So as to be that which I am,
to the fullest extent that I can be that.
And that is my joy.
And that is my reward for being here, you know.
And that is being steward of one's gifts.
So instead of looking for gain and gettingness,
which brings the energy down,
brings guilt and limitation,
if we are completely, totally
what we can be every moment,
we're fulfilling God's will for us,
we can live a guilt-free, joyful life.
And the rest is God's problem, isn't it?
If you're being the best tadpole you can be in the pond,
I mean, that's what's more,
who can fault you?
Being the best tadpole you can be from moment to moment.
That's what I try to do.
And I try to do it with this group.
As I said, I'm always aware of the karmic responsibility
and the consequences because my vision goes back,
you know, beyond, well, through eternal,
what the world calls eternity.
And one sees that every nuance,
every movement has had,
has a karmic consequence, you see.
Everything that enhances the appreciation of beauty
radiates forth that beauty down the corridors of time.
And then one comes into the karmic inheritance of that,
reverence for beauty,
and in this lifetime it comes back to you,
and as I was saying to him,
when it first hits you, it sort of takes you out of it.
And then you get used to living in the Taj Mahal.
You get used to living in the Alhambra.
And you learn how to function within the world again.
But it took many years,
and that's why I came out here from New York City.
Where I had an apartment at Fifth Avenue.
We recently visited New York City.
And I had a chance to see Central Park
and all the places,
the Plaza Hotel for lunch and all the way.
But that was the lifestyle there,
which couldn't be handled.
And so I left it for many years.
And now re-experienced it,
but from a whole different dimension.
And I must say that people in New York City
are very loving.
Very loving.
It's a very beautiful city.
And of course that's the way we experience all of life.
What we can do for God
is simultaneously what we can do for ourself.
To be all that we can be,
to the fullest extent we can be that.
And so,
oh, that was the message we got
from God
at the beginning of the lecture.
In a Chinese fortune cookie.
To be all that you can be.
From every moment,
you will never have any regret.
So I thank you all for being here.
It's been my pleasure.
Look at all the dollars I made.
I must have made five, six of them.