is
here.
here. be.
All
All right.
All right. So,
All right. So, the
All right. So, the evolution
All right. So, the evolution of
consciousness,
consciousness, as
All right. So, the evolution of
consciousness, as we
consciousness, as we said,
All right. So, the evolution of
consciousness, as we said, it
consciousness, as we said, it began
first
first as
first as bacteria.
I've
I've got
first as bacteria.
I've got a
I've got a pointer.
first as bacteria.
I've got a pointer. I
I've got a pointer. I got
first as bacteria.
I've got a pointer. I got a
I've got a pointer. I got a bigger
first as bacteria.
I've got a pointer. I got a bigger point
at
at home,
at home, but
at home, but I
at home, but I forgot
at home, but I forgot it.
at home, but I forgot it. This
at home, but I forgot it. This little
spotty
spotty thing
at home, but I forgot it. This little
spotty thing here.
Uh,
Uh, all
Uh, all right.
Uh, all right. So,
Uh, all right. So, bacteria,
Uh, all right. So, bacteria, we
Uh, all right. So, bacteria, we see
algae
algae don't
Uh, all right. So, bacteria, we see
algae don't have
algae don't have consciousness.
Why
Why am
Why am I
Why am I holding
Why am I holding these
Why am I holding these things?
Why am I holding these things? Anybody
know?
know? I
Why am I holding these things? Anybody
know? I don't
know? I don't know
Why am I holding these things? Anybody
know? I don't know why
know? I don't know why I'm
Why am I holding these things? Anybody
know? I don't know why I'm holding
know? I don't know why I'm holding those
things,
things, but
things, but they
things, but they were
things, but they were there.
You
You have
things, but they were there.
You have to
You have to do
things, but they were there.
You have to do what's
You have to do what's there,
which
which you
which you get
which you get used
which you get used to.
Takes
Takes a
which you get used to.
Takes a long
Takes a long time.
Takes
Takes a
Takes a long
Takes a long time
Takes a long time actually
Takes a long time actually to
Takes a long time actually to adjust
where
where the
Takes a long time actually to adjust
where the body
where the body is.
You
You have
You have to
You have to really
You have to really focus
You have to really focus on
You have to really focus on where
You have to really focus on where the
body
body is.
You have to really focus on where the
body is. And
body is. And anyway,
You have to really focus on where the
body is. And anyway, bacteria
body is. And anyway, bacteria start
You have to really focus on where the
body is. And anyway, bacteria start at
one.
one. And
one. And so
one. And so you
one. And so you go
one. And so you go up
one. And so you go up the
one. And so you go up the evolution,
one. And so you go up the evolution, you
see,
see, because
one. And so you go up the evolution, you
see, because it
see, because it it
one. And so you go up the evolution, you
see, because it it it
see, because it it it makes
one. And so you go up the evolution, you
see, because it it it makes it
see, because it it it makes it so
obvious
obvious what
obvious what the
obvious what the ego
obvious what the ego is,
obvious what the ego is, how
obvious what the ego is, how it
obvious what the ego is, how it got
obvious what the ego is, how it got to
be
be where
obvious what the ego is, how it got to
be where it
be where it is.
Why
Why mankind
Why mankind didn't
Why mankind didn't understand
Why mankind didn't understand the
Why mankind didn't understand the ego
and
and therefore
Why mankind didn't understand the ego
and therefore vilified
and therefore vilified it
Why mankind didn't understand the ego
and therefore vilified it in
and therefore vilified it in terms
Why mankind didn't understand the ego
and therefore vilified it in terms of
reveal
reveal religion.
It
It vilified
reveal religion.
It vilified it
It vilified it and
reveal religion.
It vilified it and therefore
It vilified it and therefore sin
reveal religion.
It vilified it and therefore sin came
It vilified it and therefore sin came to
grab
uh
uh human
grab
uh human consciousness.
uh human consciousness. It
grab
uh human consciousness. It reached
uh human consciousness. It reached its
height
height in
height in the
height in the middle
height in the middle ages,
height in the middle ages, the
height in the middle ages, the dark
ages.
Um
sin
sin was
Um
sin was seen
sin was seen everywhere
and
and you
and you either
and you either confessed
and you either confessed to
and you either confessed to something
and you either confessed to something or
other
other or
and you either confessed to something or
other or you
other or you got
and you either confessed to something or
other or you got tortured
other or you got tortured to
and you either confessed to something or
other or you got tortured to death.
other or you got tortured to death. So
that
that was
that was the
that was the dark
that was the dark ages.
that was the dark ages. the
that was the dark ages. the dark
that was the dark ages. the dark ages.
You
You see
that was the dark ages. the dark ages.
You see the
You see the evolution
that was the dark ages. the dark ages.
You see the evolution of
You see the evolution of consciousness
over
over huge
over huge lapses
over huge lapses of
over huge lapses of time.
over huge lapses of time. I
over huge lapses of time. I don't
over huge lapses of time. I don't even
understand
understand what
over huge lapses of time. I don't even
understand what these
understand what these terms
over huge lapses of time. I don't even
understand what these terms mean,
understand what these terms mean, but
probably
probably somebody
probably somebody out
probably somebody out there
probably somebody out there does.
probably somebody out there does. These
are
are the
probably somebody out there does. These
are the archaeologic
are the archaeologic ages.
And
And their
And their duration
And their duration in
And their duration in millions
And their duration in millions of
And their duration in millions of years,
millions
millions of
And their duration in millions of years,
millions of years.
millions of years. And
And their duration in millions of years,
millions of years. And what
millions of years. And what percentage
of
of time?
of time? You
of time? You see
of time? You see 70%
of time? You see 70% of
of time? You see 70% of time
of time? You see 70% of time of
of time? You see 70% of time of all
of time? You see 70% of time of all of
elapsed
elapsed time
of time? You see 70% of time of all of
elapsed time by
elapsed time by measured
of time? You see 70% of time of all of
elapsed time by measured time
elapsed time by measured time which
of time? You see 70% of time of all of
elapsed time by measured time which is
illusurary
illusurary but
illusurary but I
illusurary but I mean
illusurary but I mean it's
illusurary but I mean it's services
measured
measured time
illusurary but I mean it's services
measured time in
measured time in terms
illusurary but I mean it's services
measured time in terms of
measured time in terms of archaeologic
age
age 70%
age 70% of
age 70% of all
age 70% of all of
age 70% of all of time
age 70% of all of time was
age 70% of all of time was spent
age 70% of all of time was spent here
age 70% of all of time was spent here at
calibration
calibration level
age 70% of all of time was spent here at
calibration level one
calibration level one or
age 70% of all of time was spent here at
calibration level one or two
then
then only
then only 20%
was
was spent
then only 20%
was spent then
was spent then only
then only 20%
was spent then only 20%
was spent then only 20% was
then only 20%
was spent then only 20% was moving
was spent then only 20% was moving from
consciousness
consciousness level
consciousness level two
uh
uh up
consciousness level two
uh up to
uh up to 45
consciousness level two
uh up to 45 the
uh up to 45 the level
consciousness level two
uh up to 45 the level of
uh up to 45 the level of the
consciousness level two
uh up to 45 the level of the reptiles,
modern
modern insects.
H
then
then only
then only 8%
then only 8% of
then only 8% of time
then only 8% of time the
then only 8% of time the consciousness
level
level of
then only 8% of time the consciousness
level of life
level of life on
then only 8% of time the consciousness
level of life on this
level of life on this planet
then only 8% of time the consciousness
level of life on this planet moved
level of life on this planet moved from
45 to
45 to 68.
Now
Now you
45 to 68.
Now you see
Now you see how
45 to 68.
Now you see how evolution
Now you see how evolution is
45 to 68.
Now you see how evolution is speeding
Now you see how evolution is speeding up
in
in only
in only 2%
in only 2% of
in only 2% of all
in only 2% of all elapsed
in only 2% of all elapsed archaeologic
time.
time. you
in only 2% of all elapsed archaeologic
time. you see
time. you see consciousness
in only 2% of all elapsed archaeologic
time. you see consciousness level
time. you see consciousness level going
up
up to
up to really
up to really critical
up to really critical levels
up to really critical levels from
up to really critical levels from 84
up to really critical levels from 84 up
to
to 112
then
then into
then into the
then into the 200s
and
and then
then into the 200s
and then on
and then on up
then into the 200s
and then on up to
and then on up to modern
then into the 200s
and then on up to modern times.
and then on up to modern times. So
then into the 200s
and then on up to modern times. So you
see
the
the speed
see
the speed of
the speed of the
see
the speed of the evolution
the speed of the evolution of
consciousness
consciousness which
consciousness which is
consciousness which is a
consciousness which is a graph
consciousness which is a graph I
consciousness which is a graph I should
do.
I'll
I'll have
I'll have to
I'll have to remember
I'll have to remember to
I'll have to remember to do
I'll have to remember to do that.
Somebody
Somebody will
I'll have to remember to do that.
Somebody will remember
Somebody will remember how
I'll have to remember to do that.
Somebody will remember how to
Somebody will remember how to do
I'll have to remember to do that.
Somebody will remember how to do that.
It
It seems
It seems to
It seems to be
It seems to be going
It seems to be going like
It seems to be going like this,
It seems to be going like this, doesn't
it?
it? I
It seems to be going like this, doesn't
it? I mean,
it? I mean, very,
It seems to be going like this, doesn't
it? I mean, very, very
it? I mean, very, very slow.
It seems to be going like this, doesn't
it? I mean, very, very slow. And
it? I mean, very, very slow. And now
suddenly
suddenly it's
suddenly it's crescendo.
The
The crescendo.
suddenly it's crescendo.
The crescendo. When
The crescendo. When you
suddenly it's crescendo.
The crescendo. When you see
The crescendo. When you see a
suddenly it's crescendo.
The crescendo. When you see a crescendo
of
of truth
of truth on
of truth on the
of truth on the overall
of truth on the overall consciousness
of truth on the overall consciousness of
mankind,
be
be prepared
be prepared for
be prepared for cataclysms.
Cataclysms.
Cataclysms. Everybody
be prepared for cataclysms.
Cataclysms. Everybody thinks,
Cataclysms. Everybody thinks, oh,
be prepared for cataclysms.
Cataclysms. Everybody thinks, oh, as
consciousness
consciousness moves
consciousness moves along,
consciousness moves along, you
consciousness moves along, you know,
they're
they're back
consciousness moves along, you know,
they're back in
they're back in the
consciousness moves along, you know,
they're back in the bookstore.
they're back in the bookstore. Every
fairy
fairy and
fairy and music
fairy and music and
fairy and music and incense
fairy and music and incense and
God
God bless
fairy and music and incense and
God bless innocent
God bless innocent sweetness
fairy and music and incense and
God bless innocent sweetness and
God bless innocent sweetness and light.
That's
except
except the
That's
except the downside
except the downside is
That's
except the downside is they
except the downside is they get
That's
except the downside is they get rolled
right
right over.
right over. So
right over. So the
right over. So the naivity
right over. So the naivity is
right over. So the naivity is the
downside
downside of
right over. So the naivity is the
downside of the
downside of the spiritual
right over. So the naivity is the
downside of the spiritual aspirant.
the
the downside
to
to think
the downside
to think that
to think that everything
the downside
to think that everything is
to think that everything is how
the downside
to think that everything is how you
fantasize
fantasize it.
fantasize it. So
fantasize it. So to
fantasize it. So to know
fantasize it. So to know the
fantasize it. So to know the difference
between
between how
fantasize it. So to know the difference
between how you
between how you actually
fantasize it. So to know the difference
between how you actually perceive
between how you actually perceive it
fantasize it. So to know the difference
between how you actually perceive it and
what
what you're
what you're fantasizing
what you're fantasizing about
what you're fantasizing about it
what you're fantasizing about it because
there's
there's a
what you're fantasizing about it because
there's a great
there's a great deal
what you're fantasizing about it because
there's a great deal of
there's a great deal of literature
what you're fantasizing about it because
there's a great deal of literature out
there
there that
there that is
there that is pure
there that is pure fantasy.
there that is pure fantasy. I'd
there that is pure fantasy. I'd hate
there that is pure fantasy. I'd hate to
tell
tell you
there that is pure fantasy. I'd hate to
tell you what
tell you what percentage
is
is pure
is pure fantasy,
is pure fantasy, imaginative.
All right,
All right, so
is pure fantasy, imaginative.
All right, so we
All right, so we went
is pure fantasy, imaginative.
All right, so we went up
All right, so we went up the
is pure fantasy, imaginative.
All right, so we went up the animal
kingdom.
kingdom. This
kingdom. This is
kingdom. This is a
kingdom. This is a recap
kingdom. This is a recap of
kingdom. This is a recap of some
kingdom. This is a recap of some of the
things
things we
kingdom. This is a recap of some of the
things we said
things we said before.
kingdom. This is a recap of some of the
things we said before. I'm
things we said before. I'm recapping
kingdom. This is a recap of some of the
things we said before. I'm recapping it
because
because I'm
because I'm like
because I'm like trying
because I'm like trying to
because I'm like trying to recreate
because I'm like trying to recreate it
and
um
we're
we're going
um
we're going to
we're going to spend
um
we're going to spend more
we're going to spend more time
um
we're going to spend more time in
questions
questions and
questions and answers
questions and answers today.
questions and answers today. We're
questions and answers today. We're going
to
to spend
questions and answers today. We're going
to spend more
to spend more time
questions and answers today. We're going
to spend more time talking
to spend more time talking with
discussing
discussing questions
discussing questions but
discussing questions but I
discussing questions but I just
discussing questions but I just want
discussing questions but I just want to
recapulate
and
and recontextualize
and recontextualize the
and recontextualize the whole
understanding.
understanding. Then
and recontextualize the whole
understanding. Then we
understanding. Then we see
and recontextualize the whole
understanding. Then we see the
understanding. Then we see the animal
kingdom.
kingdom. You
kingdom. You see
kingdom. You see how
kingdom. You see how life
kingdom. You see how life evolves
kingdom. You see how life evolves up
here
here this
kingdom. You see how life evolves up
here this scale
here this scale with
kingdom. You see how life evolves up
here this scale with this
here this scale with this spotter
kingdom. You see how life evolves up
here this scale with this spotter thing
here.
Yeah.
Yeah. From
here.
Yeah. From bacteria.
Yeah. From bacteria. Then
here.
Yeah. From bacteria. Then you
Yeah. From bacteria. Then you see
here.
Yeah. From bacteria. Then you see it
Yeah. From bacteria. Then you see it go
up
up through
up through crustaceians,
up through crustaceians, insects,
fish,
fish, sharks,
up through crustaceians, insects,
fish, sharks, Komodo
fish, sharks, Komodo dragon.
up through crustaceians, insects,
fish, sharks, Komodo dragon. That's
fish, sharks, Komodo dragon. That's my
pale
pale Komodo
pale Komodo dragon.
Why
Why do
pale Komodo dragon.
Why do I
Why do I like
pale Komodo dragon.
Why do I like Kimoto
Why do I like Kimoto dragon?
pale Komodo dragon.
Why do I like Kimoto dragon? Cuz
Why do I like Kimoto dragon? Cuz he
tells
tells me
tells me where
tells me where the
tells me where the various
tells me where the various reptilian
dictators
dictators are.
All
All the
All the narcissistic,
All the narcissistic, megalomaniac,
messianic
messianic dictators
All the narcissistic, megalomaniac,
messianic dictators that
messianic dictators that have
All the narcissistic, megalomaniac,
messianic dictators that have destroyed
all
all mankind.
all mankind. That's
all mankind. That's where
all mankind. That's where the
all mankind. That's where the energy
comes
comes from.
all mankind. That's where the energy
comes from. They're
comes from. They're like
all mankind. That's where the energy
comes from. They're like at
comes from. They're like at a
all mankind. That's where the energy
comes from. They're like at a vistic.
they
they reach
they reach a
they reach a high
they reach a high state
they reach a high state and
they reach a high state and then
they reach a high state and then the
temptation
temptation the
they reach a high state and then the
temptation the egotism
temptation the egotism crown
they reach a high state and then the
temptation the egotism crown yourself
emperor
or
or whatever
with
with Hitler
with Hitler is
with Hitler is when
with Hitler is when he
with Hitler is when he became
with Hitler is when he became the
with Hitler is when he became the head
of
of all
with Hitler is when he became the head
of all the
of all the departments
with Hitler is when he became the head
of all the departments of
of all the departments of state
with Hitler is when he became the head
of all the departments of state United
States
States we
States we have
States we have the
States we have the judiciary
States we have the judiciary we
States we have the judiciary we have
States we have the judiciary we have the
anyway
anyway it's
States we have the judiciary we have the
anyway it's three
anyway it's three departments
States we have the judiciary we have the
anyway it's three departments where
anyway it's three departments where we
he
he was
he was ahead
he was ahead of
he was ahead of all
he was ahead of all of
he was ahead of all of them
he was ahead of all of them and
he was ahead of all of them and we
he was ahead of all of them and we got
just
just like
he was ahead of all of them and we got
just like with
just like with Napoleon
he was ahead of all of them and we got
just like with Napoleon he
just like with Napoleon he crashed
he was ahead of all of them and we got
just like with Napoleon he crashed when
he
he crowned
he crowned himself
he crowned himself emperor.
he crowned himself emperor. See,
he crowned himself emperor. See, it
he crowned himself emperor. See, it was
only
only the
he crowned himself emperor. See, it was
only the pope
only the pope that
he crowned himself emperor. See, it was
only the pope that had
only the pope that had the
he crowned himself emperor. See, it was
only the pope that had the power
only the pope that had the power to
crown
crown you
crown you emperor.
crown you emperor. And
crown you emperor. And Napoleon
crown you emperor. And Napoleon crowned
himself.
himself. In
crown you emperor. And Napoleon crowned
himself. In that
himself. In that instant,
crown you emperor. And Napoleon crowned
himself. In that instant, he
himself. In that instant, he went
crown you emperor. And Napoleon crowned
himself. In that instant, he went from
440 or
440 or something
440 or something down
440 or something down to
440 or something down to like
440 or something down to like I
440 or something down to like I think
440 or something down to like I think 90
or
or something.
440 or something down to like I think 90
or something. Then
or something. Then the
440 or something down to like I think 90
or something. Then the Duke
or something. Then the Duke of
Wellington
Wellington met
Wellington met him.
Wellington met him. The
Wellington met him. The Duke
Wellington met him. The Duke of
Wellington
Wellington calibrated
Wellington met him. The Duke of
Wellington calibrated like
Wellington calibrated like 440
Wellington met him. The Duke of
Wellington calibrated like 440 or
something.
something. By
something. By that
something. By that time,
something. By that time, Napoleon
something. By that time, Napoleon was
down
down to
something. By that time, Napoleon was
down to like
down to like 80
something. By that time, Napoleon was
down to like 80 or
down to like 80 or 90.
If
If that
If that hadn't
If that hadn't happened,
If that hadn't happened, Napoleon
If that hadn't happened, Napoleon I
If that hadn't happened, Napoleon I mean
the
the Duke
If that hadn't happened, Napoleon I mean
the Duke of
the Duke of Wellington
If that hadn't happened, Napoleon I mean
the Duke of Wellington would
the Duke of Wellington would have
If that hadn't happened, Napoleon I mean
the Duke of Wellington would have had
the Duke of Wellington would have had a
hard
hard time.
hard time. But
hard time. But by
hard time. But by that
hard time. But by that time
hard time. But by that time Napoleon
like
like Hitler
hard time. But by that time Napoleon
like Hitler had
like Hitler had crashed.
hard time. But by that time Napoleon
like Hitler had crashed. Hitler
like Hitler had crashed. Hitler also
hard time. But by that time Napoleon
like Hitler had crashed. Hitler also was
in
in the
in the high
in the high 400
in the high 400 not
in the high 400 not high
in the high 400 not high five
in the high 400 not high five but
in the high 400 not high five but modest
400s
400s did
in the high 400 not high five but modest
400s did a
400s did a lot
in the high 400 not high five but modest
400s did a lot of
400s did a lot of good
in the high 400 not high five but modest
400s did a lot of good for
400s did a lot of good for the
in the high 400 not high five but modest
400s did a lot of good for the country
and
and then
and then he
and then he he
and then he he himself
and then he he himself and
and then he he himself and then
and then he he himself and then he
crashed
crashed too
and then he he himself and then he
crashed too when
crashed too when he
and then he he himself and then he
crashed too when he became
crashed too when he became the
and then he he himself and then he
crashed too when he became the head
crashed too when he became the head of
all
all the
all the departments
all the departments of
all the departments of the
all the departments of the government
all the departments of the government uh
and
and he
all the departments of the government uh
and he was
and he was head
all the departments of the government uh
and he was head of
and he was head of the
all the departments of the government uh
and he was head of the military
and he was head of the military head
all the departments of the government uh
and he was head of the military head of
the
the everything.
the everything. All
the everything. All right.
the everything. All right. So
that's
that's the
the everything. All right. So
that's the reptilian,
the
the predatory.
the predatory. And
the predatory. And you
the predatory. And you see
the predatory. And you see the
the predatory. And you see the it's
predatory.
predatory. Predatory
the predatory. And you see the it's
predatory. Predatory is
predatory. Predatory is 40
the predatory. And you see the it's
predatory. Predatory is 40 is
predatory. Predatory is 40 is predatory.
And
And it
And it it'll
And it it'll say
And it it'll say things
And it it'll say things that
And it it'll say things that are
outrageous
outrageous like
And it it'll say things that are
outrageous like kill
outrageous like kill the
And it it'll say things that are
outrageous like kill the whole
outrageous like kill the whole country.
They
They don't
They don't deserve
They don't deserve to
They don't deserve to live.
They
They don't
They don't deserve to live.
They don't even
They don't even feel
They don't deserve to live.
They don't even feel tweed
They don't even feel tweed about
They don't deserve to live.
They don't even feel tweed about that.
>> To
>> To us,
>> To us, that's
>> To us, that's unimaginable.
>> To us, that's unimaginable. Can
>> To us, that's unimaginable. Can you
imagine
imagine that?
>> To us, that's unimaginable. Can you
imagine that? No.
imagine that? No. kill
>> To us, that's unimaginable. Can you
imagine that? No. kill everybody
imagine that? No. kill everybody in
>> To us, that's unimaginable. Can you
imagine that? No. kill everybody in this
audience
audience except
audience except me
audience except me and
audience except me and my
audience except me and my brother
audience except me and my brother here.
It's
It's not
audience except me and my brother here.
It's not conceivable.
So
So that's
So that's the
So that's the downside
So that's the downside of
So that's the downside of the
spiritually
spiritually person.
So that's the downside of the
spiritually person. You
spiritually person. You can't
So that's the downside of the
spiritually person. You can't conceive
of
of what
of what it
of what it really
of what it really is.
of what it really is. So
of what it really is. So you
of what it really is. So you to
of what it really is. So you to try
of what it really is. So you to try to
make
make up
of what it really is. So you to try to
make up some
make up some imaginary
of what it really is. So you to try to
make up some imaginary uh
make up some imaginary uh reason
of what it really is. So you to try to
make up some imaginary uh reason to
explain
explain it.
explain it. You
explain it. You don't
explain it. You don't have
explain it. You don't have a
explain it. You don't have a reason.
It's
It's what
explain it. You don't have a reason.
It's what it
It's what it is.
explain it. You don't have a reason.
It's what it is. So
It's what it is. So each
explain it. You don't have a reason.
It's what it is. So each thing
It's what it is. So each thing then
explain it. You don't have a reason.
It's what it is. So each thing then is
what
what it
what it is
what it is by
what it is by virtue
what it is by virtue of
what it is by virtue of its
what it is by virtue of its karmic
inheritance
and
and not
and not by
and not by anything
and not by anything else.
Wow.
Wow. The
and not by anything else.
Wow. The implication
Wow. The implication of
and not by anything else.
Wow. The implication of that
Wow. The implication of that is
tremendous.
tremendous. You're
tremendous. You're not
tremendous. You're not at
tremendous. You're not at the
tremendous. You're not at the effect
tremendous. You're not at the effect of
anything
anything else
tremendous. You're not at the effect of
anything else then
anything else then except
tremendous. You're not at the effect of
anything else then except your
anything else then except your own
spiritual
spiritual intention.
There
There is
spiritual intention.
There is no
There is no cause
spiritual intention.
There is no cause out
There is no cause out there.
You
You are
You are it
by
by virtue
You are it
by virtue of
by virtue of what
You are it
by virtue of what you
by virtue of what you are.
You are it
by virtue of what you are. And
by virtue of what you are. And by
You are it
by virtue of what you are. And by virtue
of
of what
of what you
of what you are
of what you are is
of what you are is what
of what you are is what you
of what you are is what you have
of what you are is what you have said
yes
yes to.
I
I say
I say yes
I say yes to
I say yes to kindness.
I say yes to kindness. What
I say yes to kindness. What does
I say yes to kindness. What does it
I say yes to kindness. What does it take
to
to be
I say yes to kindness. What does it take
to be a
to be a spiritual
I say yes to kindness. What does it take
to be a spiritual person?
Just
Just be
Just be halfway
Just be halfway decent.
Just be halfway decent. I
Just be halfway decent. I mean,
Just be halfway decent. I mean, is
Just be halfway decent. I mean, is that
asking
asking a
Just be halfway decent. I mean, is that
asking a lot?
Halfway
Halfway polite,
Halfway polite, halfway
Halfway polite, halfway considerate.
Close
Close the
Halfway polite, halfway considerate.
Close the What
Close the What do
Halfway polite, halfway considerate.
Close the What do they
Close the What do they say?
Halfway polite, halfway considerate.
Close the What do they say? Put
Close the What do they say? Put the
Halfway polite, halfway considerate.
Close the What do they say? Put the seat
down
down when
down when you're
down when you're done,
down when you're done, baby.
Sign
Sign of
down when you're done, baby.
Sign of love.
Just
Just to
Just to put
Just to put the
Just to put the toilet
Just to put the toilet seat
Just to put the toilet seat down
Just to put the toilet seat down puts
you
you way
Just to put the toilet seat down puts
you way up
you way up here,
Just to put the toilet seat down puts
you way up here, folks.
Oh
Oh god.
All
All right.
Oh god.
All right. We
All right. We come
Oh god.
All right. We come up
All right. We come up through
Oh god.
All right. We come up through snakes.
Alligators.
Alligators. I
Alligators. I never
Alligators. I never liked
Alligators. I never liked alligators
much.
much. They
Alligators. I never liked alligators
much. They eat
much. They eat you,
Alligators. I never liked alligators
much. They eat you, you
much. They eat you, you know.
Alligators. I never liked alligators
much. They eat you, you know. And
dinosaurs
dinosaurs were
dinosaurs were never
dinosaurs were never my
dinosaurs were never my favorites
either.
either. I
dinosaurs were never my favorites
either. I do
either. I do like
dinosaurs were never my favorites
either. I do like whales
either. I do like whales and
dinosaurs were never my favorites
either. I do like whales and dolphins.
And
And as
And as we
And as we move
And as we move up,
And as we move up, you
And as we move up, you see
And as we move up, you see as
And as we move up, you see as we
And as we move up, you see as we get
away
away from
uh
uh the
uh the predatory,
uh the predatory, the
uh the predatory, the vicious
uh the predatory, the vicious predatory
uh
uh their
uh the predatory, the vicious predatory
uh their likability
uh their likability increases
uh the predatory, the vicious predatory
uh their likability increases not
because
because of
because of a
because of a duality,
because of a duality, but
because of a duality, but because
because of a duality, but because they
come
come more
because of a duality, but because they
come more to
come more to the
because of a duality, but because they
come more to the reality
come more to the reality they
because of a duality, but because they
come more to the reality they re
come more to the reality they re we
recognize
recognize as
recognize as reality.
recognize as reality. You
recognize as reality. You come
recognize as reality. You come to
recognize as reality. You come to the
migratory
migratory birds
recognize as reality. You come to the
migratory birds that
migratory birds that was
recognize as reality. You come to the
migratory birds that was a
migratory birds that was a great
recognize as reality. You come to the
migratory birds that was a great movie.
I
I practically
I practically never
I practically never go
I practically never go to
I practically never go to a
I practically never go to a movie
I practically never go to a movie once
every
every five
I practically never go to a movie once
every five or
every five or 10
I practically never go to a movie once
every five or 10 years.
every five or 10 years. And
I practically never go to a movie once
every five or 10 years. And I
every five or 10 years. And I went
I practically never go to a movie once
every five or 10 years. And I went to
see
see migratory
see migratory what
see migratory what was
see migratory what was it?
see migratory what was it? Migratory
birds.
>> Wing
>> Wing birds.
>> Wing birds. wing
>> Wing birds. wing migration
>> Wing birds. wing migration or
>> Wing birds. wing migration or something.
It
It was
>> Wing birds. wing migration or something.
It was startingly
It was startingly beautiful.
Birds
Birds of
Birds of prey,
Birds of prey, rodents,
Birds of prey, rodents, rhinoceros,
uh
uh song
Birds of prey, rodents, rhinoceros,
uh song birds,
uh song birds, doves,
Birds of prey, rodents, rhinoceros,
uh song birds, doves, polar
uh song birds, doves, polar bears.
Birds of prey, rodents, rhinoceros,
uh song birds, doves, polar bears. I
love
love all
love all these
love all these people.
love all these people. Grizzly
love all these people. Grizzly bears,
water
water buffalo.
love all these people. Grizzly bears,
water buffalo. They
water buffalo. They got
love all these people. Grizzly bears,
water buffalo. They got to
water buffalo. They got to be
love all these people. Grizzly bears,
water buffalo. They got to be you
water buffalo. They got to be you got
love all these people. Grizzly bears,
water buffalo. They got to be you got to
watch
watch them.
You
You can
watch them.
You can look
You can look like
watch them.
You can look like you
You can look like you can
watch them.
You can look like you can see
You can look like you can see a
watch them.
You can look like you can see a friendly
water
water buffalo
water buffalo and
water buffalo and it'll
water buffalo and it'll just
water buffalo and it'll just suddenly
suddenly
suddenly take
water buffalo and it'll just suddenly
suddenly take off
suddenly take off and
water buffalo and it'll just suddenly
suddenly take off and attack
suddenly take off and attack you.
water buffalo and it'll just suddenly
suddenly take off and attack you. So,
yeah,
yeah, black
yeah, black bears
yeah, black bears again.
yeah, black bears again. I
yeah, black bears again. I saw
yeah, black bears again. I saw one
yeah, black bears again. I saw one black
bear
bear over
yeah, black bears again. I saw one black
bear over Mingus
bear over Mingus Mountain.
yeah, black bears again. I saw one black
bear over Mingus Mountain. I've
bear over Mingus Mountain. I've seen
yeah, black bears again. I saw one black
bear over Mingus Mountain. I've seen one
bear
bear out
bear out out
bear out out here
bear out out here driving
bear out out here driving along
bear out out here driving along the
highway.
highway. And
bear out out here driving along the
highway. And here's
highway. And here's a
bear out out here driving along the
highway. And here's a big
highway. And here's a big black
bear out out here driving along the
highway. And here's a big black bear
walking
walking across
walking across the
walking across the road.
walking across the road. And
walking across the road. And the
walking across the road. And the jackals
and
and the
walking across the road. And the jackals
and the foxes,
and the foxes, the
walking across the road. And the jackals
and the foxes, the wolves,
and the foxes, the wolves, the
hippopotamus,
hippopotamus, the
hippopotamus, the havina.
hippopotamus, the havina. Hippopotamus
kills
kills more
hippopotamus, the havina. Hippopotamus
kills more humans
kills more humans than
hippopotamus, the havina. Hippopotamus
kills more humans than anybody.
kills more humans than anybody. Uh
hippopotamus, the havina. Hippopotamus
kills more humans than anybody. Uh just
because
because it's
because it's a
because it's a hippopotamus,
because it's a hippopotamus, not
because it's a hippopotamus, not because
it
it hates
because it's a hippopotamus, not because
it hates you,
it hates you, but
because it's a hippopotamus, not because
it hates you, but I
it hates you, but I just
because it's a hippopotamus, not because
it hates you, but I just wouldn't
it hates you, but I just wouldn't go
swimming
swimming with
swimming with a
swimming with a hippopotamus.
I
I don't
swimming with a hippopotamus.
I don't know
I don't know how
swimming with a hippopotamus.
I don't know how they
I don't know how they kill
swimming with a hippopotamus.
I don't know how they kill him.
I don't know how they kill him. I
swimming with a hippopotamus.
I don't know how they kill him. I just
squish
squish him,
squish him, I
squish him, I guess.
squish him, I guess. I
squish him, I guess. I don't
squish him, I guess. I don't know.
Havina
Havina of
squish him, I guess. I don't know.
Havina of the
Havina of the grace.
squish him, I guess. I don't know.
Havina of the grace. Now
Havina of the grace. Now you
squish him, I guess. I don't know.
Havina of the grace. Now you see
Havina of the grace. Now you see a
squish him, I guess. I don't know.
Havina of the grace. Now you see a 200
that
that gri
that gri big
that gri big jump
that gri big jump on
that gri big jump on the
that gri big jump on the caliber
that gri big jump on the caliber level
of
of consciousness.
that gri big jump on the caliber level
of consciousness. You
of consciousness. You see
that gri big jump on the caliber level
of consciousness. You see 200
of consciousness. You see 200 is
that gri big jump on the caliber level
of consciousness. You see 200 is a
of consciousness. You see 200 is a big
jump.
jump. You
jump. You go
jump. You go from
jump. You go from the
jump. You go from the you
jump. You go from the you might
jump. You go from the you might call
these
these extremely
jump. You go from the you might call
these extremely predatory
these extremely predatory predatory.
jump. You go from the you might call
these extremely predatory predatory. I
mean
mean nothing's
mean nothing's more
mean nothing's more predatory
mean nothing's more predatory than
mean nothing's more predatory than a
komodo
komodo dragon
mean nothing's more predatory than a
komodo dragon and
komodo dragon and suddenly
mean nothing's more predatory than a
komodo dragon and suddenly you
komodo dragon and suddenly you move
mean nothing's more predatory than a
komodo dragon and suddenly you move up
to
to zebra,
to zebra, gazels,
to zebra, gazels, giraffes,
to zebra, gazels, giraffes, deer,
bison,
bison, pigs,
to zebra, gazels, giraffes, deer,
bison, pigs, elk,
all
all the
all the animals
all the animals that
all the animals that we
all the animals that we tend
all the animals that we tend to
all the animals that we tend to love.
all the animals that we tend to love. So
their
their lovability
all the animals that we tend to love. So
their lovability to
their lovability to us
all the animals that we tend to love. So
their lovability to us as
their lovability to us as humans
increases
increases as
increases as you
increases as you go
increases as you go up
increases as you go up the
increases as you go up the scale
increases as you go up the scale of
consciousness.
consciousness. Uh
increases as you go up the scale of
consciousness. Uh sheep,
consciousness. Uh sheep, range
increases as you go up the scale of
consciousness. Uh sheep, range cattle,
you
you see
you see the
you see the effect
you see the effect of
you see the effect of um
you see the effect of um human
consciousness
consciousness on
you see the effect of um human
consciousness on animals,
consciousness on animals, a
you see the effect of um human
consciousness on animals, a pet,
consciousness on animals, a pet, there's
a
a lot
a lot of
a lot of research
a lot of research showing
a lot of research showing the
a lot of research showing the beneficial
effect
effect of
a lot of research showing the beneficial
effect of pets.
effect of pets. It
a lot of research showing the beneficial
effect of pets. It decreases
effect of pets. It decreases your
a lot of research showing the beneficial
effect of pets. It decreases your blood
pressure,
pressure, tends
pressure, tends to
pressure, tends to release
pressure, tends to release endorphins,
and
and the
pressure, tends to release endorphins,
and the family.
and the family. So
pressure, tends to release endorphins,
and the family. So here's
and the family. So here's the
pressure, tends to release endorphins,
and the family. So here's the cat
and the family. So here's the cat at
240.
240. And
240. And then
240. And then once
240. And then once you
240. And then once you adopt
240. And then once you adopt a
240. And then once you adopt a kitty,
240. And then once you adopt a kitty, it
goes
goes up
240. And then once you adopt a kitty, it
goes up to
goes up to 245.
240. And then once you adopt a kitty, it
goes up to 245. The
goes up to 245. The same
240. And then once you adopt a kitty, it
goes up to 245. The same as
goes up to 245. The same as a
240. And then once you adopt a kitty, it
goes up to 245. The same as a horse.
goes up to 245. The same as a horse. A
horse
horse uh
horse uh jumps
horse uh jumps about
horse uh jumps about five
horse uh jumps about five points.
horse uh jumps about five points. Once
you
you uh
horse uh jumps about five points. Once
you uh become
you uh become a
horse uh jumps about five points. Once
you uh become a friend
you uh become a friend of
horse uh jumps about five points. Once
you uh become a friend of a
you uh become a friend of a horse
horse uh jumps about five points. Once
you uh become a friend of a horse and
train
train it,
train it, the
train it, the dog
train it, the dog jumps
train it, the dog jumps five
train it, the dog jumps five points.
train it, the dog jumps five points. So
a
a dog
train it, the dog jumps five points. So
a dog is
a dog is 250
train it, the dog jumps five points. So
a dog is 250 or
a dog is 250 or 245.
train it, the dog jumps five points. So
a dog is 250 or 245. The
a dog is 250 or 245. The family
train it, the dog jumps five points. So
a dog is 250 or 245. The family dog
jumps
jumps to
jumps to 250
jumps to 250 like
jumps to 250 like the
jumps to 250 like the Ganges
jumps to 250 like the Ganges River.
jumps to 250 like the Ganges River. So
uh
uh pouring
jumps to 250 like the Ganges River. So
uh pouring love
uh pouring love into
jumps to 250 like the Ganges River. So
uh pouring love into this
uh pouring love into this dog,
jumps to 250 like the Ganges River. So
uh pouring love into this dog, he
uh pouring love into this dog, he jump
you
you jump
you jump his
you jump his level
you jump his level of
you jump his level of consciousness
you jump his level of consciousness five
points.
points. Is
you jump his level of consciousness five
points. Is five
points. Is five points
you jump his level of consciousness five
points. Is five points a
points. Is five points a lot?
you jump his level of consciousness five
points. Is five points a lot? Oh,
points. Is five points a lot? Oh, it's
you jump his level of consciousness five
points. Is five points a lot? Oh, it's a
lot.
stat
stat statistical,
lot.
stat statistical, if
stat statistical, if I
lot.
stat statistical, if I could
stat statistical, if I could say
lot.
stat statistical, if I could say the
word,
word, average
word, average human
word, average human being
word, average human being in
word, average human being in the
word, average human being in the course
of
of one
word, average human being in the course
of one lifetime
of one lifetime goes
word, average human being in the course
of one lifetime goes up
of one lifetime goes up five
word, average human being in the course
of one lifetime goes up five points.
The
The family
The family dog
The family dog does
The family dog does that
The family dog does that just
The family dog does that just by
The family dog does that just by your
loving
loving him.
The family dog does that just by your
loving him. Once
loving him. Once you
The family dog does that just by your
loving him. Once you give
loving him. Once you give him
The family dog does that just by your
loving him. Once you give him a
loving him. Once you give him a name,
spot
spot and
spot and cuddle
spot and cuddle him,
spot and cuddle him, he
spot and cuddle him, he jumps
spot and cuddle him, he jumps five
points
more
more than
more than a
more than a human
more than a human being.
more than a human being. Well,
we
we still
more than a human being. Well,
we still haven't
we still haven't had
more than a human being. Well,
we still haven't had a
we still haven't had a chance
more than a human being. Well,
we still haven't had a chance to
research
research what
research what is
research what is the
research what is the karma
research what is the karma of
research what is the karma of this
monkeys.
monkeys. Uh
research what is the karma of this
monkeys. Uh here
monkeys. Uh here we
research what is the karma of this
monkeys. Uh here we have
monkeys. Uh here we have gorilla
and
and chimpanzees
and chimpanzees who
and chimpanzees who share
and chimpanzees who share you
and chimpanzees who share you know
and chimpanzees who share you know 99.5%
of
of our
and chimpanzees who share you know 99.5%
of our DNA.
And
And then
And then we
And then we get
And then we get up
And then we get up to
And then we get up to our
And then we get up to our exceptions.
This
This one's
And then we get up to our exceptions.
This one's on
This one's on the
And then we get up to our exceptions.
This one's on the internet
This one's on the internet too
And then we get up to our exceptions.
This one's on the internet too by
This one's on the internet too by the
way.
way. It's
way. It's called
way. It's called the
way. It's called the www
bird
bird a
way. It's called the www
bird a parro
bird a parro something.
Dr.
Dr. Pepper
Dr. Pepper Peppers
Dr. Pepper Peppers Pepperdine
Dr. Pepper Peppers Pepperdine Dr.
Pepperdine,
Pepperdine, I
Dr. Pepper Peppers Pepperdine Dr.
Pepperdine, I think
Pepperdine, I think from
Dr. Pepper Peppers Pepperdine Dr.
Pepperdine, I think from the
Pepperdine, I think from the University
of
of Cal,
of Cal, Arizona
of Cal, Arizona down
of Cal, Arizona down in
of Cal, Arizona down in Tucson.
of Cal, Arizona down in Tucson. Very
famous
famous parrot.
of Cal, Arizona down in Tucson. Very
famous parrot. Of
famous parrot. Of course,
of Cal, Arizona down in Tucson. Very
famous parrot. Of course, everybody
knows
knows Alex
knows Alex can
knows Alex can count
knows Alex can count and
knows Alex can count and figure
knows Alex can count and figure things
out.
out. And
knows Alex can count and figure things
out. And uh
out. And uh so
knows Alex can count and figure things
out. And uh so people
out. And uh so people argue,
knows Alex can count and figure things
out. And uh so people argue, well,
out. And uh so people argue, well, he's
not
not really
not really thinking,
not really thinking, but
not really thinking, but when
not really thinking, but when you
calibrate
calibrate him
not really thinking, but when you
calibrate him at
calibrate him at 401,
not really thinking, but when you
calibrate him at 401, he
calibrate him at 401, he is
not really thinking, but when you
calibrate him at 401, he is thinking.
You
You may
You may not
You may not think
You may not think he's
You may not think he's thinking.
You may not think he's thinking. Some
people
people feel
You may not think he's thinking. Some
people feel challenged
people feel challenged by
You may not think he's thinking. Some
people feel challenged by that.
people feel challenged by that. I've
watched
watched scientists
watched scientists get
that's
that's on
watched scientists get
that's on the
that's on the History
watched scientists get
that's on the History Channel
periodically.
periodically. They
periodically. They rerun
periodically. They rerun that.
periodically. They rerun that. You
periodically. They rerun that. You see
this
this indignant
periodically. They rerun that. You see
this indignant scientist
this indignant scientist arguing
periodically. They rerun that. You see
this indignant scientist arguing very
intensely.
intensely. Alex
intensely. Alex is
intensely. Alex is not
intensely. Alex is not capable
intensely. Alex is not capable of
thinking.
thinking. I
intensely. Alex is not capable of
thinking. I mean,
thinking. I mean, he's
intensely. Alex is not capable of
thinking. I mean, he's like
thinking. I mean, he's like he's
challenged,
challenged, you
challenged, you know,
challenged, you know, like
he's
he's challenged
challenged, you know, like
he's challenged by
he's challenged by 400.
Oh,
Oh, I
Oh, I see
Oh, I see why.
Oh, I see why. He
Oh, I see why. He can't
Oh, I see why. He can't be
Oh, I see why. He can't be at
Oh, I see why. He can't be at 400
himself
himself or
Oh, I see why. He can't be at 400
himself or he
himself or he wouldn't
Oh, I see why. He can't be at 400
himself or he wouldn't feel
himself or he wouldn't feel challenged,
would
would he?
would he? Oh,
would he? Oh, yeah.
would he? Oh, yeah. He's
would he? Oh, yeah. He's threatened
would he? Oh, yeah. He's threatened by
Alex's
Alex's capacity
would he? Oh, yeah. He's threatened by
Alex's capacity to
Alex's capacity to think.
would he? Oh, yeah. He's threatened by
Alex's capacity to think. Cuz
Alex's capacity to think. Cuz he
would he? Oh, yeah. He's threatened by
Alex's capacity to think. Cuz he can't
think.
think. Because
think. Because if
think. Because if he
think. Because if he could
think. Because if he could think,
think. Because if he could think, he
would
would see
think. Because if he could think, he
would see that
would see that Alex
think. Because if he could think, he
would see that Alex could
would see that Alex could think.
Of
course,
course, Alex's
Of
course, Alex's going
course, Alex's going to
Of
course, Alex's going to think
course, Alex's going to think any
Of
course, Alex's going to think any idiot
knows
knows that.
knows that. And
knows that. And the
knows that. And the same
knows that. And the same with
knows that. And the same with Koko,
knows that. And the same with Koko, our
favorite
favorite gorilla.
knows that. And the same with Koko, our
favorite gorilla. You
favorite gorilla. You know,
knows that. And the same with Koko, our
favorite gorilla. You know, Koko
favorite gorilla. You know, Koko is
knows that. And the same with Koko, our
favorite gorilla. You know, Koko is very
endearing.
endearing. And
endearing. And when
endearing. And when you
endearing. And when you see
endearing. And when you see Koko
endearing. And when you see Koko with
endearing. And when you see Koko with it
with
with Koko's
endearing. And when you see Koko with it
with Koko's pet
with Koko's pet kitten,
endearing. And when you see Koko with it
with Koko's pet kitten, Koko
with Koko's pet kitten, Koko just
endearing. And when you see Koko with it
with Koko's pet kitten, Koko just loving
this
this kitten
this kitten and
this kitten and defending
this kitten and defending this
this kitten and defending this kitten
and
and mothering
this kitten and defending this kitten
and mothering this
and mothering this kitten
this kitten and defending this kitten
and mothering this kitten at
and mothering this kitten at 405.
this kitten and defending this kitten
and mothering this kitten at 405. The
song
song bird
song bird song
song bird song for
song bird song for reasons
song bird song for reasons I
song bird song for reasons I don't
song bird song for reasons I don't know.
500.
500. Beauty.
song bird song for reasons I don't know.
500. Beauty. That's
500. Beauty. That's the
song bird song for reasons I don't know.
500. Beauty. That's the calibrated
energy
energy of
energy of beauty.
energy of beauty. And
energy of beauty. And of
energy of beauty. And of course,
energy of beauty. And of course, the
kitty,
kitty, the
energy of beauty. And of course, the
kitty, the cat's
kitty, the cat's purr,
energy of beauty. And of course, the
kitty, the cat's purr, dogs
kitty, the cat's purr, dogs wagging
energy of beauty. And of course, the
kitty, the cat's purr, dogs wagging tail
at
at 500.
at 500. All
at 500. All right.
at 500. All right. So,
I
I can
at 500. All right. So,
I can see
I can see why.
Oh.
Anyway,
that
that was
that was an
that was an historic
that was an historic karmic
that was an historic karmic moment.
Let's
Let's see.
that was an historic karmic moment.
Let's see. That
Let's see. That was
that was an historic karmic moment.
Let's see. That was an
Let's see. That was an historic
that was an historic karmic moment.
Let's see. That was an historic karmic
moment.
moment. Resist.
That
That was
moment. Resist.
That was an
That was an historic
moment. Resist.
That was an historic karmic
That was an historic karmic moment
because
because I'd
because I'd never
because I'd never gotten
because I'd never gotten along
because I'd never gotten along with
horses.
horses. I
because I'd never gotten along with
horses. I don't
horses. I don't want
because I'd never gotten along with
horses. I don't want to
horses. I don't want to bore
because I'd never gotten along with
horses. I don't want to bore bore
horses. I don't want to bore bore you
with
with my
with my past
with my past lives,
with my past lives, but
horses
horses and
with my past lives, but
horses and I
horses and I never
with my past lives, but
horses and I never got
horses and I never got along.
with my past lives, but
horses and I never got along. And
horses and I never got along. And uh
with my past lives, but
horses and I never got along. And uh I
tried
tried for
tried for riding,
tried for riding, you
tried for riding, you know,
tried for riding, you know, all
tried for riding, you know, all kinds
tried for riding, you know, all kinds of
riding.
riding. I
tried for riding, you know, all kinds of
riding. I got
riding. I got thrown
tried for riding, you know, all kinds of
riding. I got thrown from
riding. I got thrown from every
tried for riding, you know, all kinds of
riding. I got thrown from every horse
riding. I got thrown from every horse I
ever
ever rode.
ever rode. I
ever rode. I guess
ever rode. I guess there
ever rode. I guess there was
ever rode. I guess there was something
about
about me
ever rode. I guess there was something
about me and
about me and horses
ever rode. I guess there was something
about me and horses that
about me and horses that just
ever rode. I guess there was something
about me and horses that just didn't
mix.
mix. And
mix. And uh
mix. And uh I
mix. And uh I couldn't
mix. And uh I couldn't resonate
mix. And uh I couldn't resonate to
mix. And uh I couldn't resonate to a
horse's
horse's consciousness.
mix. And uh I couldn't resonate to a
horse's consciousness. I
horse's consciousness. I forgot
mix. And uh I couldn't resonate to a
horse's consciousness. I forgot where
they're
they're at.
they're at. Other
they're at. Other animals
they're at. Other animals I
they're at. Other animals I get
they're at. Other animals I get where
they're
they're at
they're at. Other animals I get where
they're at right
they're at right away.
they're at. Other animals I get where
they're at right away. Even,
they're at right away. Even, you
they're at. Other animals I get where
they're at right away. Even, you know,
deer,
deer, zebras,
deer, zebras, I
deer, zebras, I don't
deer, zebras, I don't trouble
deer, zebras, I don't trouble I
deer, zebras, I don't trouble I get
instantly
instantly where
deer, zebras, I don't trouble I get
instantly where they're
instantly where they're at.
deer, zebras, I don't trouble I get
instantly where they're at. Horses,
instantly where they're at. Horses, I
could
could never
could never get
could never get where
could never get where are
could never get where are they
could never get where are they at?
could never get where are they at? They
seem
seem sort
could never get where are they at? They
seem sort of
seem sort of dumb.
I
I knew
I knew karmically
I knew karmically I
I knew karmically I had
I knew karmically I had something
I knew karmically I had something out
with
with horses.
And
And uh
And uh anyway,
And uh anyway, I
And uh anyway, I finally
And uh anyway, I finally got
And uh anyway, I finally got off
And uh anyway, I finally got off it,
forgave
forgave myself
And uh anyway, I finally got off it,
forgave myself for
forgave myself for I
And uh anyway, I finally got off it,
forgave myself for I thought
forgave myself for I thought of
And uh anyway, I finally got off it,
forgave myself for I thought of all
forgave myself for I thought of all the
negative
negative things
negative things I
negative things I could
negative things I could think
negative things I could think about
negative things I could think about that
I
I could
negative things I could think about that
I could have
I could have done
negative things I could think about that
I could have done with
I could have done with horses
negative things I could think about that
I could have done with horses and
I could have done with horses and prayed
for
for forgiveness
for forgiveness for
for forgiveness for all
for forgiveness for all of
for forgiveness for all of them.
for forgiveness for all of them. And
that
that reawakened
for forgiveness for all of them. And
that reawakened the
that reawakened the memory
for forgiveness for all of them. And
that reawakened the memory of
that reawakened the memory of lifetime,
a
a couple
a couple lifetimes.
And
And anyway,
a couple lifetimes.
And anyway, I
And anyway, I forgot
a couple lifetimes.
And anyway, I forgot all
And anyway, I forgot all about
a couple lifetimes.
And anyway, I forgot all about horses.
And
And then
And then at
And then at this
And then at this girl's
And then at this girl's ranch
And then at this girl's ranch where
And then at this girl's ranch where I
was
was uh
And then at this girl's ranch where I
was uh leaving
was uh leaving them
And then at this girl's ranch where I
was uh leaving them and
was uh leaving them and uh
And then at this girl's ranch where I
was uh leaving them and uh they
was uh leaving them and uh they had
And then at this girl's ranch where I
was uh leaving them and uh they had a
new
new horse
new horse and
new horse and suddenly
new horse and suddenly I
new horse and suddenly I saw
new horse and suddenly I saw this
adorable
adorable horse.
new horse and suddenly I saw this
adorable horse. Adorable
adorable horse. Adorable horse.
new horse and suddenly I saw this
adorable horse. Adorable horse. I
adorable horse. Adorable horse. I was
new horse and suddenly I saw this
adorable horse. Adorable horse. I was on
adorable
adorable horse
adorable horse as
adorable horse as loving
adorable horse as loving and
adorable horse as loving and sweet
adorable horse as loving and sweet came
over
over and
adorable horse as loving and sweet came
over and just
over and just kissed
adorable horse as loving and sweet came
over and just kissed me
over and just kissed me all
adorable horse as loving and sweet came
over and just kissed me all over
over and just kissed me all over the
place.
place. You
place. You think
place. You think a
place. You think a horse
place. You think a horse can't
place. You think a horse can't kiss
place. You think a horse can't kiss you?
There
There is
place. You think a horse can't kiss you?
There is a
There is a horse
place. You think a horse can't kiss you?
There is a horse kissing
There is a horse kissing me.
And
And at
And at that
And at that point
And at that point horses
And at that point horses and
And at that point horses and I
And at that point horses and I I
resolved
resolved that
And at that point horses and I I
resolved that negative
resolved that negative karma
And at that point horses and I I
resolved that negative karma with
horses.
horses. All
horses. All right.
horses. All right. Thank
horses. All right. Thank you.
horses. All right. Thank you. Next,
people
people say
horses. All right. Thank you. Next,
people say spiritual
people say spiritual work
horses. All right. Thank you. Next,
people say spiritual work is
people say spiritual work is hard
horses. All right. Thank you. Next,
people say spiritual work is hard and
people say spiritual work is hard and as
we
we said
we said before,
we said before, it
we said before, it doesn't
we said before, it doesn't really
require
require much.
we said before, it doesn't really
require much. Just
require much. Just the
we said before, it doesn't really
require much. Just the capacity,
require much. Just the capacity, the
willingness
willingness to
willingness to be
willingness to be fair,
willingness to be fair, even,
decent.
You
You don't
You don't see
You don't see the
You don't see the sacredness
You don't see the sacredness of
You don't see the sacredness of life
until
until you
You don't see the sacredness of life
until you get
until you get more
You don't see the sacredness of life
until you get more evolved.
At
At a
At a more
At a more evolved
At a more evolved level,
At a more evolved level, these
At a more evolved level, these things
are
are automatic
At a more evolved level, these things
are automatic because
are automatic because you
At a more evolved level, these things
are automatic because you acknow
are automatic because you acknow you're
merely
merely acknowledging
merely acknowledging the
merely acknowledging the sacredness
merely acknowledging the sacredness of
life
life itself
merely acknowledging the sacredness of
life itself in
life itself in whatever
merely acknowledging the sacredness of
life itself in whatever form
life itself in whatever form it
merely acknowledging the sacredness of
life itself in whatever form it may
life itself in whatever form it may be
taking,
whatever
whatever form
taking,
whatever form it
whatever form it may
taking,
whatever form it may be
whatever form it may be taking.
See,
See, so
See, so the
See, so the guilt
See, so the guilt about
See, so the guilt about my
See, so the guilt about my the
See, so the guilt about my the way
See, so the guilt about my the way I
felt
felt about
See, so the guilt about my the way I
felt about horses
felt about horses because
See, so the guilt about my the way I
felt about horses because I
felt about horses because I knew
See, so the guilt about my the way I
felt about horses because I knew it
felt about horses because I knew it was
a
a violation
a violation of
a violation of the
a violation of the truth.
a violation of the truth. I
a violation of the truth. I knew
a violation of the truth. I knew it
wasn't
wasn't true
if
if I
if I saw
if I saw horses
if I saw horses the
if I saw horses the way
if I saw horses the way they
if I saw horses the way they really
were.
were. And
if I saw horses the way they really
were. And so
were. And so I
if I saw horses the way they really
were. And so I was
were. And so I was delighted
if I saw horses the way they really
were. And so I was delighted when
were. And so I was delighted when horses
and
and I
and I kissed
and I kissed and
and I kissed and make
and I kissed and make it
and I kissed and make it made
and I kissed and make it made up.
All right.
All right. So
and I kissed and make it made up.
All right. So just
All right. So just the
and I kissed and make it made up.
All right. So just the willingness
All right. So just the willingness to
and I kissed and make it made up.
All right. So just the willingness to um
it
it seems
it seems to
it seems to people
it seems to people who
it seems to people who are
it seems to people who are spiritually
committed
committed these
it seems to people who are spiritually
committed these all
committed these all seem
it seems to people who are spiritually
committed these all seem so
committed these all seem so simple
but
but most
but most of
but most of the
but most of the people
but most of the people on
but most of the people on the
but most of the people on the world
refuse
refuse this
but most of the people on the world
refuse this to
refuse this to be
but most of the people on the world
refuse this to be fair,
refuse this to be fair, balanced,
decent,
decent, considerate.
pick
pick up
decent, considerate.
pick up your
pick up your trash
decent, considerate.
pick up your trash instead
pick up your trash instead of
decent, considerate.
pick up your trash instead of throwing
it
it on
it on the
it on the sidewalk.
You
You can
it on the sidewalk.
You can blindfold
You can blindfold somebody,
it on the sidewalk.
You can blindfold somebody, take
You can blindfold somebody, take off
it on the sidewalk.
You can blindfold somebody, take off the
blindfolds,
blindfolds, and
blindfolds, and by
blindfolds, and by looking
blindfolds, and by looking at
blindfolds, and by looking at the
sidewalk,
sidewalk, I'll
blindfolds, and by looking at the
sidewalk, I'll tell
sidewalk, I'll tell you
blindfolds, and by looking at the
sidewalk, I'll tell you what
sidewalk, I'll tell you what the
calibrated
calibrated level
calibrated level of
calibrated level of consciousness
calibrated level of consciousness is
calibrated level of consciousness is of
that
that neighborhood
calibrated level of consciousness is of
that neighborhood of
that neighborhood of that
calibrated level of consciousness is of
that neighborhood of that community.
Just
being
being responsible
Just
being responsible for
being responsible for your
Just
being responsible for your own
being responsible for your own trash,
you
you know,
you know, to
you know, to be
you know, to be responsible
you know, to be responsible for
you know, to be responsible for your
you know, to be responsible for your own
trash,
trash, you
you know, to be responsible for your own
trash, you know,
trash, you know, and
you know, to be responsible for your own
trash, you know, and not
trash, you know, and not blame
you know, to be responsible for your own
trash, you know, and not blame it
trash, you know, and not blame it on
somebody
somebody else.
All
All right?
somebody else.
All right? So,
All right? So, we
somebody else.
All right? So, we consider
All right? So, we consider these
somebody else.
All right? So, we consider these people
uh
uh this
uh this is
uh this is the
uh this is the way
uh this is the way I
uh this is the way I thought
uh this is the way I thought everybody
was
was when
uh this is the way I thought everybody
was when I
was when I grew
uh this is the way I thought everybody
was when I grew up
was when I grew up in
uh this is the way I thought everybody
was when I grew up in the
was when I grew up in the Midwest.
Well,
Well, Chicago
Well, Chicago at
Well, Chicago at 444.
Uh
Uh Milwaukee,
Well, Chicago at 444.
Uh Milwaukee, north
Uh Milwaukee, north of
Well, Chicago at 444.
Uh Milwaukee, north of suburbs
Uh Milwaukee, north of suburbs where
Well, Chicago at 444.
Uh Milwaukee, north of suburbs where I
grew
grew up
grew up was
grew up was probably
grew up was probably about
grew up was probably about the
grew up was probably about the same
level.
level. So,
grew up was probably about the same
level. So, we
level. So, we just
grew up was probably about the same
level. So, we just assumed
level. So, we just assumed everybody
grew up was probably about the same
level. So, we just assumed everybody was
this
this way.
this way. And
this way. And if
this way. And if you
this way. And if you weren't
this way. And if you weren't that
this way. And if you weren't that way,
you
you should
this way. And if you weren't that way,
you should see
you should see a
this way. And if you weren't that way,
you should see a doctor
you should see a doctor psychiatrist.
Everybody
Everybody has
Everybody has their
Everybody has their quirks.
Everybody has their quirks. So
easygoingness
easygoingness of
Everybody has their quirks. So
easygoingness of course
easygoingness of course is
Everybody has their quirks. So
easygoingness of course is an
easygoingness of course is an ideal
which
which most
which most of
which most of us
which most of us find
which most of us find difficult
which most of us find difficult to
which most of us find difficult to to
which most of us find difficult to to be
that
that way
which most of us find difficult to to be
that way all
that way all the
which most of us find difficult to to be
that way all the time.
that way all the time. So
which most of us find difficult to to be
that way all the time. So some
that way all the time. So some of
which most of us find difficult to to be
that way all the time. So some of these
qualities
qualities the
qualities the value
qualities the value they
qualities the value they have
qualities the value they have to
qualities the value they have to us
qualities the value they have to us is
they
they act
qualities the value they have to us is
they act like
they act like pointers.
When
When something
When something throws
When something throws you
When something throws you out
When something throws you out of
easygoingness
that's
that's something
that's something in
that's something in yourself.
that's something in yourself. So
that's something in yourself. So all
these
these things
that's something in yourself. So all
these things are
these things are valuable.
that's something in yourself. So all
these things are valuable. Therefore,
you
you take
you take what
you take what you
you take what you consider
from
from a
you take what you consider
from a spiritual
from a spiritual viewpoint
you take what you consider
from a spiritual viewpoint as
from a spiritual viewpoint as a
you take what you consider
from a spiritual viewpoint as a negative
and
and you
and you turn
and you turn it
and you turn it into
and you turn it into a
and you turn it into a positive.
and you turn it into a positive. It's
like
like a
and you turn it into a positive. It's
like a light
like a light going
and you turn it into a positive. It's
like a light going on.
like a light going on. Look
and you turn it into a positive. It's
like a light going on. Look here.
like a light going on. Look here. Look
here.
here. Look
here. Look here.
here. Look here. Look
here. Look here. Look here.
here. Look here. Look here. Look
here. Look here. Look here. Look here.
So,
So, when
here. Look here. Look here. Look here.
So, when you're
So, when you're not
here. Look here. Look here. Look here.
So, when you're not easygoing,
So, when you're not easygoing, when
you're
you're not
you're not thoughtful,
you're not thoughtful, when
you're not thoughtful, when you're
you're not thoughtful, when you're not
tolerant,
tolerant, when
you're not thoughtful, when you're not
tolerant, when you're
tolerant, when you're not
you're not thoughtful, when you're not
tolerant, when you're not calm,
etc.,
etc., then
etc., then that
etc., then that is
etc., then that is pulling
etc., then that is pulling up
etc., then that is pulling up something
that
that you
etc., then that is pulling up something
that you got
that you got to
etc., then that is pulling up something
that you got to clear.
that you got to clear. And
etc., then that is pulling up something
that you got to clear. And how
that you got to clear. And how do
etc., then that is pulling up something
that you got to clear. And how do you
clear
clear it?
clear it? You
clear it? You clear
clear it? You clear it
clear it? You clear it by
clear it? You clear it by looking
clear it? You clear it by looking within
yourself
yourself and
clear it? You clear it by looking within
yourself and finding
yourself and finding it
clear it? You clear it by looking within
yourself and finding it there,
yourself and finding it there, owning
it,
it, forgiving
it, forgiving yourself
it, forgiving yourself for
it, forgiving yourself for it
it, forgiving yourself for it because
what
what you
it, forgiving yourself for it because
what you want
what you want is
it, forgiving yourself for it because
what you want is a
what you want is a fallible
it, forgiving yourself for it because
what you want is a fallible human
what you want is a fallible human being.
So
So the
So the kindness
So the kindness that
So the kindness that you
So the kindness that you show
So the kindness that you show to
yourself,
yourself, the
So the kindness that you show to
yourself, the willingness
yourself, the willingness to
So the kindness that you show to
yourself, the willingness to forgive
yourself
yourself then
yourself then transfers
yourself then transfers in
yourself then transfers in the
willingness
willingness to
yourself then transfers in the
willingness to forgive
willingness to forgive other
yourself then transfers in the
willingness to forgive other others
willingness to forgive other others out
there.
there. So
there. So instead
there. So instead of
there. So instead of look
there. So instead of look feeling
there. So instead of look feeling guilt
about
about the
there. So instead of look feeling guilt
about the negative,
what
what you
what you do
what you do is
what you do is you
what you do is you turn
what you do is you turn it
what you do is you turn it lemons
what you do is you turn it lemons into
lemonade.
If
If I
If I felt
If I felt there
If I felt there was
If I felt there was something
If I felt there was something I
If I felt there was something I didn't
trust,
trust, I
If I felt there was something I didn't
trust, I was
trust, I was afraid
If I felt there was something I didn't
trust, I was afraid of
trust, I was afraid of horses,
If I felt there was something I didn't
trust, I was afraid of horses, that
signals
signals to
signals to me
signals to me there's
signals to me there's something
signals to me there's something out.
There's
There's something
signals to me there's something out.
There's something out.
There's something out. You
signals to me there's something out.
There's something out. You see,
There's something out. You see, if
you're
you're not
you're not spiritually
you're not spiritually committed,
you're not spiritually committed, you'd
say
say it's
you're not spiritually committed, you'd
say it's the
say it's the horses
you're not spiritually committed, you'd
say it's the horses fault.
say it's the horses fault. Horses
you're not spiritually committed, you'd
say it's the horses fault. Horses are
say it's the horses fault. Horses are so
and
and you
and you can't
and you can't trust
and you can't trust horses.
and you can't trust horses. They'll
throw
throw you
and you can't trust horses. They'll
throw you there.
throw you there. You
and you can't trust horses. They'll
throw you there. You blame
throw you there. You blame it
and you can't trust horses. They'll
throw you there. You blame it on
throw you there. You blame it on horses.
You
You see?
All
All right.
You see?
All right. So
All right. So therefore,
You see?
All right. So therefore, anything
All right. So therefore, anything that
is
is not
is not what
is not what you
is not what you would
is not what you would like
is not what you would like it
is not what you would like it to
is not what you would like it to be,
is not what you would like it to be, you
have
have to
is not what you would like it to be, you
have to look
have to look what
is not what you would like it to be, you
have to look what could
have to look what could be
is not what you would like it to be, you
have to look what could be under
have to look what could be under it.
What
What could
What could be
What could be under
What could be under it?
What could be under it? One
What could be under it? One negative
feeling
feeling on
What could be under it? One negative
feeling on top
feeling on top means
What could be under it? One negative
feeling on top means it's
feeling on top means it's coming
What could be under it? One negative
feeling on top means it's coming from
something
something below.
something below. It's
something below. It's coming
something below. It's coming from
something below. It's coming from some
below.
The
The angriness
The angriness that
The angriness that you
The angriness that you can't
The angriness that you can't ride
The angriness that you can't ride the
horse
horse is
The angriness that you can't ride the
horse is coming
horse is coming from
The angriness that you can't ride the
horse is coming from wanting
horse is coming from wanting to
The angriness that you can't ride the
horse is coming from wanting to be
horse is coming from wanting to be able
to
to control
frustration
frustration etc.
to control
frustration etc. So
frustration etc. So and
to control
frustration etc. So and the
frustration etc. So and the pride
to control
frustration etc. So and the pride that
one
one is
one is able
one is able to
one is able to ride
one is able to ride it's
one is able to ride it's coming
one is able to ride it's coming from
other
other stuff.
one is able to ride it's coming from
other stuff. Right?
So
So all
So all of
So all of these
So all of these things
So all of these things then
So all of these things then we're
So all of these things then we're all
temp
temp we're
So all of these things then we're all
temp we're all
temp we're all tempted.
So all of these things then we're all
temp we're all tempted. So
temp we're all tempted. So we
So all of these things then we're all
temp we're all tempted. So we say
temptation
temptation is
temptation is to
temptation is to get
temptation is to get off
temptation is to get off this
temptation is to get off this uh
integrous
integrous course.
temptation is to get off this uh
integrous course. We
integrous course. We call
temptation is to get off this uh
integrous course. We call this
integrous course. We call this simply
morality
morality and
morality and ethics.
morality and ethics. Morality
morality and ethics. Morality that's
morality and ethics. Morality that's all
we
we call
morality and ethics. Morality that's all
we call it.
we call it. This
morality and ethics. Morality that's all
we call it. This is
we call it. This is what
morality and ethics. Morality that's all
we call it. This is what we
we call it. This is what we s
morality and ethics. Morality that's all
we call it. This is what we s assume
everybody
everybody in
everybody in the
everybody in the world
everybody in the world is
everybody in the world is like.
We
We assume
everybody in the world is like.
We assume everybody
We assume everybody in
everybody in the world is like.
We assume everybody in the
We assume everybody in the world
everybody in the world is like.
We assume everybody in the world is
We assume everybody in the world is like
this.
this. Unless
this. Unless you
this. Unless you lend
this. Unless you lend them
this. Unless you lend them a
this. Unless you lend them a book,
you
you know
this. Unless you lend them a book,
you know that
you know that their
this. Unless you lend them a book,
you know that their promise
you know that their promise to
this. Unless you lend them a book,
you know that their promise to return
the
the book
the book is
the book is a
the book is a lie
the book is a lie right
the book is a lie right off
the book is a lie right off the
the book is a lie right off the bat.
Nobody
Nobody returns
the book is a lie right off the bat.
Nobody returns books.
Not
Not within
Not within the
Not within the human
Not within the human domain.
Orderliness
Orderliness normally.
Not within the human domain.
Orderliness normally. So
Orderliness normally. So these
Not within the human domain.
Orderliness normally. So these are
Orderliness normally. So these are the
basic
basic virtues.
basic virtues. People
basic virtues. People think
basic virtues. People think I'm
basic virtues. People think I'm going
basic virtues. People think I'm going to
get
get spiritually
basic virtues. People think I'm going to
get spiritually committed
get spiritually committed right
basic virtues. People think I'm going to
get spiritually committed right away.
They
They want
They want to
They want to do
They want to do the
They want to do the Bhagabad
They want to do the Bhagabad Gita,
They want to do the Bhagabad Gita, you
know,
they
they want
they want to
they want to do
they want to do the
they want to do the Regita
they want to do the Regita and
they want to do the Regita and they
they want to do the Regita and they want
to
to do
they want to do the Regita and they want
to do Krishna
to do Krishna Murdy
they want to do the Regita and they want
to do Krishna Murdy or
to do Krishna Murdy or Nisa
they want to do the Regita and they want
to do Krishna Murdy or Nisa Maharaj
to do Krishna Murdy or Nisa Maharaj at
for
for starters,
for starters, you
for starters, you know,
for starters, you know, say
for starters, you know, say first
for starters, you know, say first learn
how
how to
for starters, you know, say first learn
how to be
how to be polite
for starters, you know, say first learn
how to be polite and
how to be polite and all
Bhagavagita
Bhagavagita is
Bhagavagita is tremendous.
It's
It's tremendous
Bhagavagita is tremendous.
It's tremendous when
It's tremendous when you
Bhagavagita is tremendous.
It's tremendous when you reach
It's tremendous when you reach a
Bhagavagita is tremendous.
It's tremendous when you reach a certain
point.
point. When
point. When you
point. When you get
point. When you get reach
point. When you get reach a
point. When you get reach a certain
point
point in
point. When you get reach a certain
point in the
point in the evolution
point. When you get reach a certain
point in the evolution of
point in the evolution of your
consciousness,
consciousness, the
consciousness, the Bhagavita
consciousness, the Bhagavita will
consciousness, the Bhagavita will just
blow
blow you
consciousness, the Bhagavita will just
blow you away.
blow you away. you
consciousness, the Bhagavita will just
blow you away. you go
blow you away. you go pow
consciousness, the Bhagavita will just
blow you away. you go pow like
blow you away. you go pow like god
consciousness, the Bhagavita will just
blow you away. you go pow like god this
is
is incredible
is incredible if
is incredible if you
is incredible if you started
is incredible if you started it
is incredible if you started it too
early
early you'd
is incredible if you started it too
early you'd say
early you'd say I
is incredible if you started it too
early you'd say I don't
early you'd say I don't know
is incredible if you started it too
early you'd say I don't know what
early you'd say I don't know what the
is incredible if you started it too
early you'd say I don't know what the is
all
all about
all about and
all about and put
all about and put it
all about and put it in
all about and put it in the
all about and put it in the in
all about and put it in the in the
all about and put it in the in the shelf
so
so the
all about and put it in the in the shelf
so the timing
so the timing of
all about and put it in the in the shelf
so the timing of things
so the timing of things then
all about and put it in the in the shelf
so the timing of things then so
so the timing of things then so a
all about and put it in the in the shelf
so the timing of things then so a friend
of
of mine
of mine is
of mine is doing
of mine is doing the
of mine is doing the babagi
of mine is doing the babagi right
of mine is doing the babagi right now
he's
he's just
of mine is doing the babagi right now
he's just blown
he's just blown away
of mine is doing the babagi right now
he's just blown away with
he's just blown away with it
of mine is doing the babagi right now
he's just blown away with it well
he's just blown away with it well it
of mine is doing the babagi right now
he's just blown away with it well it bo
is
is about
is about 900
is about 900 so
is about 900 so when
is about 900 so when you're
is about 900 so when you're blown
is about 900 so when you're blown away
with
with it
is about 900 so when you're blown away
with it you
with it you know
is about 900 so when you're blown away
with it you know you're
with it you know you're making
is about 900 so when you're blown away
with it you know you're making progress
so
so we
so we consider
so we consider people
so we consider people normally
so we consider people normally so
so we consider people normally so this
is
is what
so we consider people normally so this
is what you
is what you know
so we consider people normally so this
is what you know in
is what you know in the
so we consider people normally so this
is what you know in the Midwest
is what you know in the Midwest us
so we consider people normally so this
is what you know in the Midwest us we
consider
consider normal.
consider normal. This
consider normal. This is
consider normal. This is called
traditional
traditional America.
Traditional
Traditional America.
Traditional America. Fair,
Traditional America. Fair, balanced,
even
even going,
Traditional America. Fair, balanced,
even going, honest.
even going, honest. You
if
if you
if you don't
if you don't return
if you don't return the
if you don't return the book,
if you don't return the book, you
if you don't return the book, you at
least
least feel
if you don't return the book, you at
least feel guilty
least feel guilty about
if you don't return the book, you at
least feel guilty about it,
ethical,
ethical, flexible,
ethical, flexible, balanced,
ethical, flexible, balanced, respectful,
respectful,
respectful, respectful
may
may maybe
may maybe not
may maybe not of
may maybe not of the
may maybe not of the person,
may maybe not of the person, but
may maybe not of the person, but at
least
least of
may maybe not of the person, but at
least of the
least of the office.
may maybe not of the person, but at
least of the office. When
least of the office. When I'm
may maybe not of the person, but at
least of the office. When I'm talking
least of the office. When I'm talking to
the
the president
the president of
the president of the
the president of the university,
the president of the university, I'm
aware
aware that
the president of the university, I'm
aware that he
aware that he is
the president of the university, I'm
aware that he is president
aware that he is president of
the president of the university, I'm
aware that he is president of the
university
university and
university and therefore
university and therefore I'm
university and therefore I'm not
disrespectful.
disrespectful. I'm
university and therefore I'm not
disrespectful. I'm respectful
disrespectful. I'm respectful of
university and therefore I'm not
disrespectful. I'm respectful of his
position,
position, etc.
position, etc. Uh,
position, etc. Uh, these
position, etc. Uh, these people
position, etc. Uh, these people tend
position, etc. Uh, these people tend to
be
be faithful.
position, etc. Uh, these people tend to
be faithful. They
be faithful. They have
position, etc. Uh, these people tend to
be faithful. They have a
be faithful. They have a sense
position, etc. Uh, these people tend to
be faithful. They have a sense of
be faithful. They have a sense of humor.
As
As I
As I say,
As I say, always
As I say, always beware
As I say, always beware of
As I say, always beware of people
As I say, always beware of people who
have
have no
As I say, always beware of people who
have no sense
have no sense of
As I say, always beware of people who
have no sense of humor.
have no sense of humor. They'll
As I say, always beware of people who
have no sense of humor. They'll kill
have no sense of humor. They'll kill you
at
at a
at a moment's
at a moment's notice.
Well,
Well, he
at a moment's notice.
Well, he broke
Well, he broke the
at a moment's notice.
Well, he broke the law.
Deserves
Deserves to
Deserves to die.
You
You say,
Deserves to die.
You say, "But
You say, "But didn't
Deserves to die.
You say, "But didn't you
You say, "But didn't you just
Deserves to die.
You say, "But didn't you just do
You say, "But didn't you just do the
same
same thing?"
same thing?" That's
same thing?" That's beside
same thing?" That's beside the
same thing?" That's beside the point.
The
The humor
same thing?" That's beside the point.
The humor of
The humor of life
same thing?" That's beside the point.
The humor of life is
The humor of life is the
same thing?" That's beside the point.
The humor of life is the contrast
between
between the
between the hypothetical
between the hypothetical and
between the hypothetical and the
between the hypothetical and the real.
Okay.
Okay. A
between the hypothetical and the real.
Okay. A sense
Okay. A sense of
between the hypothetical and the real.
Okay. A sense of humor.
Okay. A sense of humor. Then
between the hypothetical and the real.
Okay. A sense of humor. Then without
Okay. A sense of humor. Then without a
sense
sense of
sense of humor,
sense of humor, I
sense of humor, I would
sense of humor, I would not
sense of humor, I would not advise
people
people to
sense of humor, I would not advise
people to take
people to take spiritual
sense of humor, I would not advise
people to take spiritual work
people to take spiritual work seriously.
It
It it
It it is
It it is not
It it is not a
It it is not a time
It it is not a time in
It it is not a time in your
It it is not a time in your life.
It it is not a time in your life. come
back
back another
It it is not a time in your life. come
back another lifetime.
back another lifetime. I
It it is not a time in your life. come
back another lifetime. I spoke
back another lifetime. I spoke at
It it is not a time in your life. come
back another lifetime. I spoke at a
place
place where
place where man
place where man they
place where man they were
place where man they were so
place where man they were so serious.
place where man they were so serious. It
was
was unbelievable.
place where man they were so serious. It
was unbelievable. And
was unbelievable. And I
place where man they were so serious. It
was unbelievable. And I mean,
was unbelievable. And I mean, you
place where man they were so serious. It
was unbelievable. And I mean, you know,
a
a place
a place with
a place with all
a place with all kinds
a place with all kinds of
a place with all kinds of holy
a place with all kinds of holy names,
you
you know,
a place with all kinds of holy names,
you know, monk
you know, monk monks
a place with all kinds of holy names,
you know, monk monks and
you know, monk monks and people.
a place with all kinds of holy names,
you know, monk monks and people. And
anyway,
anyway, man,
anyway, man, talk
anyway, man, talk about
anyway, man, talk about dead
anyway, man, talk about dead serious.
Flat
flat
flat and
flat and dead
flat and dead serious.
Yeah.
Yeah. big
flat and dead serious.
Yeah. big trouble.
Okay.
We
We tend
Okay.
We tend to
We tend to be
Okay.
We tend to be loyal
We tend to be loyal to
Okay.
We tend to be loyal to our
We tend to be loyal to our friends
Okay.
We tend to be loyal to our friends and
our
our country,
our country, supportive,
our country, supportive, benign,
protective,
protective, humane.
Pleasing
Pleasing others,
Pleasing others, we're
Pleasing others, we're glad
Pleasing others, we're glad to
Pleasing others, we're glad to be
Pleasing others, we're glad to be happy.
Pleasing
Pleasing others
Pleasing others, we're glad to be happy.
Pleasing others and
Pleasing others and love
Pleasing others, we're glad to be happy.
Pleasing others and love are
Pleasing others and love are sometimes
misconstrued
misconstrued as
um
um neurotic.
Loving
Loving is
Loving is different
Loving is different than
Loving is different than uh
wanting
wanting approval
Loving is different than uh
wanting approval and
wanting approval and being
Loving is different than uh
wanting approval and being protective
wanting approval and being protective is
different
different than
different than codependency.
different than codependency. So
different than codependency. So there's
sometimes
sometimes misunderstandings.
Uh
Uh these
Uh these people
Uh these people are
Uh these people are reasonably
Uh these people are reasonably happy
most
most of
Uh these people are reasonably happy
most of the
most of the time
Uh these people are reasonably happy
most of the time because
most of the time because they're
Uh these people are reasonably happy
most of the time because they're over
200.
200. They
200. They call
200. They call them
200. They call them the
200. They call them the soul
200. They call them the soul of
200. They call them the soul of the
earth.
earth. They
200. They call them the soul of the
earth. They tend
earth. They tend to
200. They call them the soul of the
earth. They tend to be
earth. They tend to be diplomatic.
200. They call them the soul of the
earth. They tend to be diplomatic. They
try
try to
try to be
try to be considerate
try to be considerate of
try to be considerate of the
try to be considerate of the listener.
There's
There's three
try to be considerate of the listener.
There's three ways
There's three ways of
try to be considerate of the listener.
There's three ways of presenting
There's three ways of presenting truth.
Huh?
Huh? It
Huh? It was
Huh? It was already
Huh? It was already well
Huh? It was already well known
Huh? It was already well known at
Huh? It was already well known at the
time
time of
Huh? It was already well known at the
time of Socrates,
time of Socrates, Plato
Huh? It was already well known at the
time of Socrates, Plato and
time of Socrates, Plato and my
Huh? It was already well known at the
time of Socrates, Plato and my childhood
friends
um
in
in which
in which Aristotle
really
really said
in which Aristotle
really said it
really said it correctly
in which Aristotle
really said it correctly and
really said it correctly and you
in which Aristotle
really said it correctly and you see
really said it correctly and you see it
in
in today's
in today's world
in today's world there
in today's world there is
in today's world there is ethos
in today's world there is ethos that
in today's world there is ethos that is
the
the ethical
in today's world there is ethos that is
the ethical stature
the ethical stature of
in today's world there is ethos that is
the ethical stature of the
the ethical stature of the speaker
there
there is
there is logos
there is logos that
there is logos that is
there is logos that is the
there is logos that is the logic
there is logos that is the logic the
dialectic
dialectic the
there is logos that is the logic the
dialectic the reasoning
which
which is
which is presented.
Then
Then there
which is presented.
Then there is
Then there is pos
that
that is
that is the
that is the positionality
that is the positionality of
that is the positionality of the
listener.
The
The listener
how
how effective
The listener
how effective you
how effective you are
The listener
how effective you are at
how effective you are at communication.
So
So the
So the although
So the although rhetoric
So the although rhetoric is
So the although rhetoric is below
calibrates
calibrates below
So the although rhetoric is below
calibrates below 200
calibrates below 200 one
So the although rhetoric is below
calibrates below 200 one side
calibrates below 200 one side of
rhetoric
rhetoric which
rhetoric which is
rhetoric which is a
rhetoric which is a value
rhetoric which is a value which
Aristotle
Aristotle preserves
is
is that
is that you
is that you have
is that you have to
is that you have to take
is that you have to take in
is that you have to take in accord
is that you have to take in accord where
is
is the
is that you have to take in accord where
is the listener
is the listener at?
of
of our
of our current
of our current president
of our current president I
of our current president I say
of our current president I say he's
of our current president I say he's very
good
good at
of our current president I say he's very
good at ethos
good at ethos very
of our current president I say he's very
good at ethos very good
good at ethos very good at
of our current president I say he's very
good at ethos very good at logos
good at ethos very good at logos not
of our current president I say he's very
good at ethos very good at logos not so
good
good at
good at pos
because
you're
you're coming
you're coming from
you're coming from a
you're coming from a naive
you're coming from a naive that
you're coming from a naive that because
what
what I
you're coming from a naive that because
what I know
what I know is
you're coming from a naive that because
what I know is speaking
what I know is speaking the
you're coming from a naive that because
what I know is speaking the truth
what I know is speaking the truth as
you're coming from a naive that because
what I know is speaking the truth as I
know
know it
know it maybe
know it maybe mistaken
know it maybe mistaken but
know it maybe mistaken but at least
know it maybe mistaken but at least it's
listening
listening the
know it maybe mistaken but at least it's
listening the integrity
listening the integrity of
know it maybe mistaken but at least it's
listening the integrity of the
listening the integrity of the speaker
should
should be
should be sufficient
should be sufficient to
should be sufficient to be
should be sufficient to be accepted
should be sufficient to be accepted by
the
the listener
should be sufficient to be accepted by
the listener but
the listener but no
should be sufficient to be accepted by
the listener but no that
the listener but no that is
should be sufficient to be accepted by
the listener but no that is not
the listener but no that is not things
have
have to
have to be
have to be contextualized
therefore
therefore President
have to be contextualized
therefore President Roosevelt
who
who got
who got elected
who got elected three
who got elected three terms,
who got elected three terms, you
who got elected three terms, you know,
and
and got
who got elected three terms, you know,
and got us
and got us through
who got elected three terms, you know,
and got us through World
and got us through World War
who got elected three terms, you know,
and got us through World War II.
and got us through World War II. But
Roosevelt
Roosevelt got
Roosevelt got elected
Roosevelt got elected three
Roosevelt got elected three times
Roosevelt got elected three times and
Roosevelt got elected three times and he
calibrates
calibrates the
Roosevelt got elected three times and he
calibrates the highest
calibrates the highest of
Roosevelt got elected three times and he
calibrates the highest of any
calibrates the highest of any of
Roosevelt got elected three times and he
calibrates the highest of any of the
presidents
presidents at
presidents at 499.
What
What was
presidents at 499.
What was characteristic
What was characteristic about
presidents at 499.
What was characteristic about Roosevelt?
Even
Even though
Even though you
Even though you even
Even though you even if
Even though you even if you
Even though you even if you weren't
Even though you even if you weren't a
Democrat,
Democrat, you
Even though you even if you weren't a
Democrat, you loved
Democrat, you loved them.
Even though you even if you weren't a
Democrat, you loved them. All
Democrat, you loved them. All the
non-democrats
non-democrats still
non-democrats still loved
non-democrats still loved Roosevelt.
And
And that
non-democrats still loved Roosevelt.
And that was
And that was because
non-democrats still loved Roosevelt.
And that was because of
And that was because of the
non-democrats still loved Roosevelt.
And that was because of the fireside
chats.
See,
See, so
chats.
See, so Roosevelt
See, so Roosevelt was
chats.
See, so Roosevelt was a
See, so Roosevelt was a great
chats.
See, so Roosevelt was a great president.
No
No doubt
No doubt about
No doubt about it.
No doubt about it. He
No doubt about it. He was
No doubt about it. He was a
No doubt about it. He was a great
politician.
politician. He
No doubt about it. He was a great
politician. He spoke
politician. He spoke from
No doubt about it. He was a great
politician. He spoke from integrity
politician. He spoke from integrity as
he
he knew
he knew it.
he knew it. He
he knew it. He never
he knew it. He never he
he knew it. He never he didn't
consciously
consciously lie
he knew it. He never he didn't
consciously lie to
consciously lie to any
he knew it. He never he didn't
consciously lie to any degree
consciously lie to any degree that
he knew it. He never he didn't
consciously lie to any degree that I
could
could ever
could ever discern.
But
But he
could ever discern.
But he didn't
But he didn't just
could ever discern.
But he didn't just expect
But he didn't just expect because
could ever discern.
But he didn't just expect because he's
president
president and
president and he's
president and he's telling
president and he's telling you
president and he's telling you the
president and he's telling you the truth
that
that you
president and he's telling you the truth
that you should
that you should be,
president and he's telling you the truth
that you should be, you
that you should be, you know,
president and he's telling you the truth
that you should be, you know, get
that you should be, you know, get it.
No,
No, he
No, he had
No, he had the
No, he had the fireside
No, he had the fireside cha
No, he had the fireside cha chat
No, he had the fireside cha chat in
which
which he
No, he had the fireside cha chat in
which he explained
which he explained the
No, he had the fireside cha chat in
which he explained the truth
which he explained the truth to
No, he had the fireside cha chat in
which he explained the truth to you.
Well,
Well, now
Well, now he
Well, now he rec
Well, now he rec you
Well, now he rec you know
Well, now he rec you know what
Well, now he rec you know what he
Well, now he rec you know what he does?
He
He contextualize
Well, now he rec you know what he does?
He contextualize it.
He contextualize it. Now,
Well, now he rec you know what he does?
He contextualize it. Now, when
He contextualize it. Now, when it's
contextualized,
contextualized, you
contextualized, you say,
contextualized, you say, "Oh,
contextualized, you say, "Oh, I
contextualized, you say, "Oh, I see
contextualized, you say, "Oh, I see why
we
we have
contextualized, you say, "Oh, I see why
we have to
we have to do
contextualized, you say, "Oh, I see why
we have to do so
we have to do so and
contextualized, you say, "Oh, I see why
we have to do so and so
we have to do so and so even
contextualized, you say, "Oh, I see why
we have to do so and so even though
we have to do so and so even though I
don't
don't agree
don't agree with
don't agree with it."
don't agree with it." So,
don't agree with it." So, the
don't agree with it." So, the failure
don't agree with it." So, the failure of
taking
taking into
don't agree with it." So, the failure of
taking into consideration
taking into consideration where
don't agree with it." So, the failure of
taking into consideration where the
audience
audience is
audience is at
audience is at means
audience is at means your
audience is at means your communication
may
may fall
audience is at means your communication
may fall flat.
may fall flat. You're
audience is at means your communication
may fall flat. You're correct
may fall flat. You're correct and
audience is at means your communication
may fall flat. You're correct and you're
presenting
presenting it
presenting it correctly.
presenting it correctly. It's
presenting it correctly. It's logical
and
and truth.
presenting it correctly. It's logical
and truth. if
and truth. if you
presenting it correctly. It's logical
and truth. if you can
and truth. if you can calibrate
presenting it correctly. It's logical
and truth. if you can calibrate the
truth
truth of
truth of some
truth of some politicians
truth of some politicians out
truth of some politicians out there
truth of some politicians out there and
it's
it's like
truth of some politicians out there and
it's like 460
but
but it's
but it's not
but it's not getting
but it's not getting across
but it's not getting across because
posthos
posthos as
but it's not getting across because
posthos as Aristotle
posthos as Aristotle said
but it's not getting across because
posthos as Aristotle said you
posthos as Aristotle said you have
but it's not getting across because
posthos as Aristotle said you have to
posthos as Aristotle said you have to be
aware
aware so
aware so the
aware so the upside
aware so the upside of
aware so the upside of rhetoric
aware so the upside of rhetoric then
aware so the upside of rhetoric then is
how
how to
aware so the upside of rhetoric then is
how to contextualize
how to contextualize a
aware so the upside of rhetoric then is
how to contextualize a thing
how to contextualize a thing so
aware so the upside of rhetoric then is
how to contextualize a thing so that
how to contextualize a thing so that is
comprehensible
comprehensible understandable
comprehensible understandable and
acceptable
acceptable acceptable
comprehensible understandable and
acceptable acceptable acceptable
okay
okay and
okay and that
okay and that by
okay and that by doing
okay and that by doing that
okay and that by doing that you're
okay and that by doing that you're at
least
least being
okay and that by doing that you're at
least being Nice.
Okay,
Okay, let's
Okay, let's go
Okay, let's go to
Okay, let's go to the
Okay, let's go to the next
Okay, let's go to the next exciting.
Okay, let's go to the next exciting. Oh,
there
there we
Okay, let's go to the next exciting. Oh,
there we go.
there we go. To
Okay, let's go to the next exciting. Oh,
there we go. To the
there we go. To the brain
Okay, let's go to the next exciting. Oh,
there we go. To the brain again.
there we go. To the brain again. Oh,
let's
let's I
let's I can't
let's I can't stand
let's I can't stand the
let's I can't stand the brain
let's I can't stand the brain today.
Let's
Let's move
let's I can't stand the brain today.
Let's move on.
Let's move on. Okay,
we're
we're going
we're going to
we're going to recapitulate
we're going to recapitulate uh
we're going to recapitulate uh truth.
Um,
Um, this
we're going to recapitulate uh truth.
Um, this has
Um, this has to
we're going to recapitulate uh truth.
Um, this has to do
Um, this has to do with
we're going to recapitulate uh truth.
Um, this has to do with the
understanding
understanding of
understanding of the
understanding of the condundolini
energy.
energy. The
understanding of the condundolini
energy. The condundolini
energy. The condundolini energy
understanding of the condundolini
energy. The condundolini energy begins
to
to run
to run at
to run at consciousness
to run at consciousness level
to run at consciousness level 200.
Therefore
Therefore to
to run at consciousness level 200.
Therefore to merely
Therefore to merely commit
to run at consciousness level 200.
Therefore to merely commit yourself
Therefore to merely commit yourself to
following
following the
following the truth
following the truth as
following the truth as you
following the truth as you as
following the truth as you as you
following the truth as you as you can
able
able to
following the truth as you as you can
able to discover
able to discover it
following the truth as you as you can
able to discover it already
able to discover it already begins
following the truth as you as you can
able to discover it already begins to
change
change your
change your physiology
and
and the
change your physiology
and the condolini
and the condolini energy
change your physiology
and the condolini energy begins
and the condolini energy begins to
change your physiology
and the condolini energy begins to flow
and
and as
and as you
and as you get
and as you get up
and as you get up into
and as you get up into the
and as you get up into the high
and as you get up into the high into
and as you get up into the high into the
500s
500s especially
and as you get up into the high into the
500s especially the
500s especially the higher
and as you get up into the high into the
500s especially the higher 500s
500s especially the higher 500s it's
subjectively
subjectively a
subjectively a rather
subjectively a rather profound
subjectively a rather profound and
strong
strong experience
subjectively a rather profound and
strong experience and
strong experience and went
subjectively a rather profound and
strong experience and went on
strong experience and went on in
subjectively a rather profound and
strong experience and went on in this
case
case for
case for years
case for years went
case for years went on
case for years went on I
case for years went on I don't know
case for years went on I don't know at
least
least five
case for years went on I don't know at
least five years
least five years and
case for years went on I don't know at
least five years and it's
least five years and it's amazing
case for years went on I don't know at
least five years and it's amazing ing
and
and what
and what it
and what it does
and what it does the
and what it does the energy
and what it does the energy what
and what it does the energy what it
and what it does the energy what it does
it
it does
and what it does the energy what it does
it does it
it does it by
and what it does the energy what it does
it does it by itself
it does it by itself by
and what it does the energy what it does
it does it by itself by the
it does it by itself by the way
and what it does the energy what it does
it does it by itself by the way there
it does it by itself by the way there is
no
no you
no you curing
no you curing that
no you curing that out
no you curing that out there
no you curing that out there there's
no you curing that out there there's no
you
you performing
no you curing that out there there's no
you performing miracles
there
there is
there is no
there is no you
there is no you doing
there is no you doing that
there is no you doing that the
there is no you doing that the energy
there is no you doing that the energy is
doing
doing that
there is no you doing that the energy is
doing that and
doing that and it
there is no you doing that the energy is
doing that and it does
doing that and it does it
there is no you doing that the energy is
doing that and it does it of
doing that and it does it of its
there is no you doing that the energy is
doing that and it does it of its own
people
people will
people will sit
people will sit down
people will sit down crippled
people will sit down crippled and
people will sit down crippled and walk
away
away well
amazing
it
it isn't
amazing
it isn't you
it isn't you that
amazing
it isn't you that made
it isn't you that made the
amazing
it isn't you that made the decision
it isn't you that made the decision the
Holy
Holy Spirit
uh
uh so
Holy Spirit
uh so you
uh so you become
Holy Spirit
uh so you become become
uh so you become become more
Holy Spirit
uh so you become become more like
uh so you become become more like an
antenna
antenna and
antenna and the
antenna and the energy
antenna and the energy goes
antenna and the energy goes out
antenna and the energy goes out to
whatever
whatever is
antenna and the energy goes out to
whatever is karmically
needful
needful of
needful of it
needful of it apparently
needful of it apparently because
needful of it apparently because when
needful of it apparently because when I
would
would go
needful of it apparently because when I
would go by
accidents
accidents on
accidents on the
accidents on the highway
accidents on the highway uh
accidents on the highway uh this
accidents on the highway uh this energy
would
would go
accidents on the highway uh this energy
would go out
would go out miles
accidents on the highway uh this energy
would go out miles ahead
would go out miles ahead of
accidents on the highway uh this energy
would go out miles ahead of the
would go out miles ahead of the accident
and
and it
and it would
and it would flow
and it would flow it
and it would flow it goes
and it would flow it goes up
and it would flow it goes up your
and it would flow it goes up your back
and
and then
and it would flow it goes up your back
and then it
and then it came
and it would flow it goes up your back
and then it came out
and then it came out through
and it would flow it goes up your back
and then it came out through the
and then it came out through the chest
exquisite
exquisite I
exquisite I mean
exquisite I mean you
exquisite I mean you know
exquisite I mean you know the
exquisite I mean you know the most
wonderful
wonderful of
exquisite I mean you know the most
wonderful of all
wonderful of all sensations
and
and it's
and it's and
and it's and it's
and it's and it's on
and it's and it's on its
and it's and it's on its own
and it's and it's on its own you're
and it's and it's on its own you're just
a
a witness
and it's and it's on its own you're just
a witness of
a witness of it
and it's and it's on its own you're just
a witness of it experiencing
a witness of it experiencing and
and it's and it's on its own you're just
a witness of it experiencing and it
would
would go
would go down
would go down the
would go down the highway
would go down the highway and
would go down the highway and around
would go down the highway and around the
mountains
mountains down
would go down the highway and around the
mountains down below
mountains down below and
would go down the highway and around the
mountains down below and pour
mountains down below and pour into
would go down the highway and around the
mountains down below and pour into a
car.
car. The
car. The wheels
car. The wheels were
car. The wheels were still
car. The wheels were still turning
car. The wheels were still turning and
it
it just
car. The wheels were still turning and
it just turned
it just turned over
and
and then
and then it
and then it would
and then it would stop
and then it would stop of
and then it would stop of its
and then it would stop of its own
and then it would stop of its own and
and then it would stop of its own and I
would
would sort
and then it would stop of its own and I
would sort of
would sort of hold
and then it would stop of its own and I
would sort of hold a
would sort of hold a question
and then it would stop of its own and I
would sort of hold a question like
would sort of hold a question like a
mua.
mua. See
mua. See I
mua. See I told
mua. See I told you
mua. See I told you how
mua. See I told you how I
mua. See I told you how I speak
mua. See I told you how I speak to
mua. See I told you how I speak to God
like
like a
mua. See I told you how I speak to God
like a mua.
like a mua. I
mua. See I told you how I speak to God
like a mua. I sort
like a mua. I sort of
mua. See I told you how I speak to God
like a mua. I sort of with
like a mua. I sort of with with
mua. See I told you how I speak to God
like a mua. I sort of with with my
beingness
beingness went
and
and I
beingness went
and I got
and I got that's
beingness went
and I got that's sufficient.
and I got that's sufficient. I
beingness went
and I got that's sufficient. I don't
have
have to
have to stop.
have to stop. I
have to stop. I don't
have to stop. I don't have
have to stop. I don't have to
have to stop. I don't have to do
anything
anything like
have to stop. I don't have to do
anything like you
anything like you as
have to stop. I don't have to do
anything like you as a
anything like you as a you
have to stop. I don't have to do
anything like you as a you as
anything like you as a you as a
have to stop. I don't have to do
anything like you as a you as a person
are
are not
are not needed
are not needed in
are not needed in this
are not needed in this whole
are not needed in this whole deal
are not needed in this whole deal at
are not needed in this whole deal at all
impersonal
and
and then
and then down
and then down the
and then down the highway
and then down the highway the
and then down the highway the same
phenomena
phenomena resumed.
This
This condundolini
This condundolini energy
This condundolini energy then
This condundolini energy then is
This condundolini energy then is a
wonderment
uh
uh and
uh and it
uh and it accompanies
uh and it accompanies spiritual
intention.
intention. The
uh and it accompanies spiritual
intention. The minute
intention. The minute you
uh and it accompanies spiritual
intention. The minute you become
spiritually
spiritually committed
spiritually committed this
spiritually committed this condundolini
energy
energy starts.
spiritually committed this condundolini
energy starts. It
energy starts. It has
spiritually committed this condundolini
energy starts. It has a
energy starts. It has a profound
spiritually committed this condundolini
energy starts. It has a profound effect
on
on our
on our physiology
on our physiology and
on our physiology and the
on our physiology and the way
on our physiology and the way the
on our physiology and the way the brain
works.
This
This is
This is the
This is the edge
This is the edge at
This is the edge at which
This is the edge at which science
This is the edge at which science is
trying
trying to
This is the edge at which science is
trying to make
trying to make sense
This is the edge at which science is
trying to make sense and
trying to make sense and of
This is the edge at which science is
trying to make sense and of course
trying to make sense and of course it's
not
not going
not going to
not going to because
not going to because science
not going to because science calibrates
in
in the
not going to because science calibrates
in the 400s
in the 400s and
not going to because science calibrates
in the 400s and now
in the 400s and now to
not going to because science calibrates
in the 400s and now to understand
in the 400s and now to understand we're
talking
talking about
talking about you
talking about you got
talking about you got to
talking about you got to go
talking about you got to go into
talking about you got to go into a
different
different paradigm.
talking about you got to go into a
different paradigm. So
different paradigm. So the
talking about you got to go into a
different paradigm. So the limitation
different paradigm. So the limitation of
science
science is
science is a
science is a is
science is a is one
science is a is one of
science is a is one of paradigm
science is a is one of paradigm paradigm
blindness
blindness and
science is a is one of paradigm paradigm
blindness and I
blindness and I get
science is a is one of paradigm paradigm
blindness and I get all
blindness and I get all kinds
science is a is one of paradigm paradigm
blindness and I get all kinds of
blindness and I get all kinds of things
like
like you
like you know
like you know science
like you know science and
like you know science and consciousness
or
spirituality
spirituality and
spirituality and science
spirituality and science or
spirituality and science or science
spirituality and science or science and
religion.
religion. What's
spirituality and science or science and
religion. What's the
religion. What's the relationship
between
between science
between science and
between science and religion
between science and religion or
spirituality?
spirituality? I'll
between science and religion or
spirituality? I'll tell
spirituality? I'll tell you
between science and religion or
spirituality? I'll tell you there
spirituality? I'll tell you there aren't
any.
There
There aren't
any.
There aren't any.
They're
They're different
They're different paradigms.
This
This is
They're different paradigms.
This is the
This is the world
They're different paradigms.
This is the world of
This is the world of logos
and
and description
and description and
and description and the
and description and the Newtonian
paradigm.
paradigm. So
and description and the Newtonian
paradigm. So you
paradigm. So you can
and description and the Newtonian
paradigm. So you can talk
paradigm. So you can talk about
speculations
speculations in
speculations in this
speculations in this paradigm,
speculations in this paradigm, but
speculations in this paradigm, but you
can't
can't know
speculations in this paradigm, but you
can't know them.
can't know them. You
speculations in this paradigm, but you
can't know them. You can't
can't know them. You can't know
speculations in this paradigm, but you
can't know them. You can't know them.
can't know them. You can't know them. So
it's
it's a
it's a paradigm
it's a paradigm blindness.
it's a paradigm blindness. All right.
it's a paradigm blindness. All right. So
what
what happens
it's a paradigm blindness. All right. So
what happens then
what happens then with
it's a paradigm blindness. All right. So
what happens then with the
what happens then with the condundolini
energy?
energy? When
energy? When you
energy? When you move
energy? When you move beyond
energy? When you move beyond 200,
energy? When you move beyond 200, you
put
put yourself
energy? When you move beyond 200, you
put yourself in
put yourself in a
energy? When you move beyond 200, you
put yourself in a different
put yourself in a different energy
field.
field. And
field. And the
field. And the condundolini
field. And the condundolini energy
field. And the condundolini energy is
field. And the condundolini energy is an
effect
effect of
field. And the condundolini energy is an
effect of the
effect of the field.
field. And the condundolini energy is an
effect of the field. It's
effect of the field. It's not
field. And the condundolini energy is an
effect of the field. It's not you.
effect of the field. It's not you. It's
an
an effect
an effect of
an effect of the
an effect of the field
an effect of the field because
an effect of the field because as
an effect of the field because as it
comes
comes on,
an effect of the field because as it
comes on, you
comes on, you realize
an effect of the field because as it
comes on, you realize it's
comes on, you realize it's impersonal.
This
This exquisite
This exquisite sensation
This exquisite sensation is
This exquisite sensation is running
This exquisite sensation is running up
your
your back.
This exquisite sensation is running up
your back. It's
your back. It's got
This exquisite sensation is running up
your back. It's got nothing.
your back. It's got nothing. I
This exquisite sensation is running up
your back. It's got nothing. I mean,
it's
it's doing
it's doing it
it's doing it on
it's doing it on its
it's doing it on its own
it's doing it on its own and
it's doing it on its own and it
it's doing it on its own and it does
it's doing it on its own and it does it
for
for a
it's doing it on its own and it does it
for a long,
for a long, long
it's doing it on its own and it does it
for a long, long time.
What
What does
What does it
What does it do?
What does it do? Well,
What does it do? Well, in
What does it do? Well, in the
What does it do? Well, in the leftbrain
person,
person, the
What does it do? Well, in the leftbrain
person, the once
person, the once still
What does it do? Well, in the leftbrain
person, the once still run
person, the once still run by
What does it do? Well, in the leftbrain
person, the once still run by the
animal,
animal, consciousness
animal, consciousness level
animal, consciousness level 200
animal, consciousness level 200 or
below,
phenomena
phenomena come
phenomena come in,
phenomena come in, sensations
phenomena come in, sensations come
phenomena come in, sensations come in,
everything
everything comes
phenomena come in, sensations come in,
everything comes in
everything comes in and
phenomena come in, sensations come in,
everything comes in and it's
everything comes in and it's primarily
left
left brain.
left brain. Primarily
left brain. Primarily left
left brain. Primarily left brain.
left brain. Primarily left brain. These
phenomena
phenomena are
left brain. Primarily left brain. These
phenomena are primarily
phenomena are primarily left
left brain. Primarily left brain. These
phenomena are primarily left brain.
phenomena are primarily left brain. The
input
input is
input is very
input is very fast
input is very fast to
input is very fast to the
input is very fast to the relay
input is very fast to the relay station
and
and fast
input is very fast to the relay station
and fast to
and fast to the
input is very fast to the relay station
and fast to the emotional
and fast to the emotional center.
input is very fast to the relay station
and fast to the emotional center. It
bypasses
bypasses the
bypasses the cortex
bypasses the cortex and
bypasses the cortex and the
bypasses the cortex and the stimulus
gets
gets processed
bypasses the cortex and the stimulus
gets processed by
gets processed by the
bypasses the cortex and the stimulus
gets processed by the prefrontal
gets processed by the prefrontal cortex
slower.
slower. So
slower. So the
slower. So the emotionality
slower. So the emotionality has
slower. So the emotionality has already
hit
hit and
slower. So the emotionality has already
hit and the
hit and the person
slower. So the emotionality has already
hit and the person has
hit and the person has already
slower. So the emotionality has already
hit and the person has already exploded.
Kill
Kill them.
Kill them. Kill
Kill them. Kill them.
Kill them. Kill them. All
Kill them. Kill them. All right.
Kill them. Kill them. All right. Reason
hasn't
hasn't had
Kill them. Kill them. All right. Reason
hasn't had a
hasn't had a chance
Kill them. Kill them. All right. Reason
hasn't had a chance yet.
hasn't had a chance yet. The
Kill them. Kill them. All right. Reason
hasn't had a chance yet. The minute
hasn't had a chance yet. The minute you
decide
decide to
decide to kill
decide to kill them,
decide to kill them, then
decide to kill them, then reason
decide to kill them, then reason comes
in
in and
decide to kill them, then reason comes
in and says,
in and says, "But
decide to kill them, then reason comes
in and says, "But that's
in and says, "But that's wrong
decide to kill them, then reason comes
in and says, "But that's wrong or
something."
something." Huh?
But
But it's
something." Huh?
But it's too
But it's too late.
The
The phenomena
The phenomena is
The phenomena is recorded
The phenomena is recorded in
The phenomena is recorded in in
The phenomena is recorded in in the
memory.
memory. So
The phenomena is recorded in in the
memory. So below
memory. So below 200
The phenomena is recorded in in the
memory. So below 200 people's
memory. So below 200 people's memories
tend
tend to
tend to be
tend to be painful.
You
You know,
tend to be painful.
You know, they
You know, they resent
tend to be painful.
You know, they resent a
You know, they resent a thing
tend to be painful.
You know, they resent a thing for
You know, they resent a thing for a
lifetime.
lifetime. I
lifetime. I know
lifetime. I know people
lifetime. I know people hated
lifetime. I know people hated each
lifetime. I know people hated each other
for
for 30
lifetime. I know people hated each other
for 30 years.
for 30 years. 30
lifetime. I know people hated each other
for 30 years. 30 years.
for 30 years. 30 years. Can
lifetime. I know people hated each other
for 30 years. 30 years. Can you
for 30 years. 30 years. Can you imagine?
Keep
Keep rerunning
Keep rerunning because
Keep rerunning because they're
Keep rerunning because they're rerunning
the
the way
Keep rerunning because they're rerunning
the way they
the way they experienced
Keep rerunning because they're rerunning
the way they experienced it.
the way they experienced it. Now
Keep rerunning because they're rerunning
the way they experienced it. Now this
the way they experienced it. Now this to
them
them is
them is reality
them is reality because
them is reality because that's
them is reality because that's how
them is reality because that's how they
experienced
experienced it.
them is reality because that's how they
experienced it. He
experienced it. He was
them is reality because that's how they
experienced it. He was rude
experienced it. He was rude to
them is reality because that's how they
experienced it. He was rude to me.
experienced it. He was rude to me. He
was
was this.
was this. He
was this. He was
was this. He was that.
was this. He was that. That's
was this. He was that. That's how
was this. He was that. That's how they
experienced
experienced it.
was this. He was that. That's how they
experienced it. I
experienced it. I went
was this. He was that. That's how they
experienced it. I went to
experienced it. I went to New
was this. He was that. That's how they
experienced it. I went to New York
experienced it. I went to New York and
they're
they're all
they're all cold
they're all cold and
they're all cold and unfriendly
they're all cold and unfriendly and
greedy
greedy and
they're all cold and unfriendly and
greedy and they
greedy and they they
they're all cold and unfriendly and
greedy and they they pick
greedy and they they pick my
they're all cold and unfriendly and
greedy and they they pick my pocket.
You
You must
You must have
You must have a
You must have a pickable
You must have a pickable pocket
You must have a pickable pocket to
You must have a pickable pocket to get
your
your pocket
You must have a pickable pocket to get
your pocket picked.
I
I don't know.
I don't know. People
I don't know. People always
I don't know. People always give
I don't know. People always give me
money
money in
I don't know. People always give me
money in New
money in New York.
I don't know. People always give me
money in New York. I
money in New York. I don't
I don't know. People always give me
money in New York. I don't know.
money in New York. I don't know. Other
people
people they
people they pick
people they pick their
people they pick their pockets.
All
All right.
people they pick their pockets.
All right. above
All right. above 200
people they pick their pockets.
All right. above 200 then
All right. above 200 then this
people they pick their pockets.
All right. above 200 then this condundol
linear
linear energy
linear energy surges
linear energy surges in
linear energy surges in and
linear energy surges in and now
linear energy surges in and now it
shifts
shifts the
linear energy surges in and now it
shifts the energy
shifts the energy field
linear energy surges in and now it
shifts the energy field the
shifts the energy field the impression
comes
comes in
comes in it's
comes in it's processed
comes in it's processed through
comes in it's processed through the
right
right brain
comes in it's processed through the
right brain and
right brain and what's
comes in it's processed through the
right brain and what's different
right brain and what's different here
comes in it's processed through the
right brain and what's different here is
it
it hits
it hits the
it hits the frontal
it hits the frontal prefrontal
it hits the frontal prefrontal cortex
it hits the frontal prefrontal cortex as
fast
fast as
it hits the frontal prefrontal cortex as
fast as it
fast as it faster
it hits the frontal prefrontal cortex as
fast as it faster and
fast as it faster and it
it hits the frontal prefrontal cortex as
fast as it faster and it goes
fast as it faster and it goes through
something
something new
something new called
something new called the
something new called the atheric
something new called the atheric brain
which
which is
something new called the atheric brain
which is a
which is a discovery
something new called the atheric brain
which is a discovery of
which is a discovery of this
something new called the atheric brain
which is a discovery of this kind
which is a discovery of this kind of
research
research I
research I fell
research I fell over
research I fell over when
research I fell over when I
research I fell over when I discovered
it
it that
research I fell over when I discovered
it that people
it that people below
research I fell over when I discovered
it that people below 200
it that people below 200 frankly
research I fell over when I discovered
it that people below 200 frankly don't
have
have an
have an atheric
have an atheric brain
have an atheric brain not only
have an atheric brain not only that
have an atheric brain not only that but
they
they don't
have an atheric brain not only that but
they don't have
they don't have personal
have an atheric brain not only that but
they don't have personal karma
they don't have personal karma They
have an atheric brain not only that but
they don't have personal karma They have
group
group karma.
If
If you
group karma.
If you call
If you call if
group karma.
If you call if your
If you call if your consciousness
group karma.
If you call if your consciousness level
is
is 130,
is 130, you
is 130, you share
is 130, you share it
is 130, you share it like
is 130, you share it like the
is 130, you share it like the group,
like
like the
is 130, you share it like the group,
like the flock.
like the flock. You
is 130, you share it like the group,
like the flock. You come
like the flock. You come in
is 130, you share it like the group,
like the flock. You come in at
like the flock. You come in at 130,
is 130, you share it like the group,
like the flock. You come in at 130, you
share
share what
share what 130
share what 130 is.
share what 130 is. But
share what 130 is. But there's
share what 130 is. But there's nothing
unique
unique yet.
It's
It's only
It's only when
It's only when you
It's only when you commit
It's only when you commit spiritually.
Now
Now you
It's only when you commit spiritually.
Now you have
Now you have a
It's only when you commit spiritually.
Now you have a unique
Now you have a unique karma.
It's only when you commit spiritually.
Now you have a unique karma. And
although
although the
although the whole
although the whole group
although the whole group flies
although the whole group flies this
although the whole group flies this way,
you
you are
although the whole group flies this way,
you are now
you are now guided
although the whole group flies this way,
you are now guided by
you are now guided by a
although the whole group flies this way,
you are now guided by a different
principle
principle than
principle than they
principle than they are.
All
All right?
principle than they are.
All right? So
All right? So you
principle than they are.
All right? So you now
All right? So you now become
principle than they are.
All right? So you now become right
brain.
brain. So
brain. So the
brain. So the athetheric
brain. So the athetheric brain
brain. So the athetheric brain now
brain. So the athetheric brain now is
brain. So the athetheric brain now is a
purely
purely energy
brain. So the athetheric brain now is a
purely energy brain.
purely energy brain. It
brain. So the athetheric brain now is a
purely energy brain. It has
purely energy brain. It has no
protoplasm.
Why?
Why? Because
protoplasm.
Why? Because the
Why? Because the frequencies
protoplasm.
Why? Because the frequencies of
spiritual
spiritual understanding
spiritual understanding are
spiritual understanding are of
spiritual understanding are of such
spiritual understanding are of such a
high
high frequency.
spiritual understanding are of such a
high frequency. Protoplasm
high frequency. Protoplasm is
spiritual understanding are of such a
high frequency. Protoplasm is way
high frequency. Protoplasm is way too
slow.
slow. That's
slow. That's why
slow. That's why we
slow. That's why we have
computer
computer chips
slow. That's why we have
computer chips because
computer chips because the
slow. That's why we have
computer chips because the oldfashioned
vacuum
vacuum tube
vacuum tube is
vacuum tube is far
vacuum tube is far too
vacuum tube is far too slow
vacuum tube is far too slow to
vacuum tube is far too slow to take
digital
digital information
vacuum tube is far too slow to take
digital information and
digital information and process
vacuum tube is far too slow to take
digital information and process it.
digital information and process it. Am
vacuum tube is far too slow to take
digital information and process it. Am I
right?
right? What
right? What I
right? What I said?
Hey,
I'm
I'm getting
I'm getting there.
I'm getting there. Anyhow,
I'm getting there. Anyhow, yes,
I'm getting there. Anyhow, yes, that's
the
the way
I'm getting there. Anyhow, yes, that's
the way it
the way it works.
I'm getting there. Anyhow, yes, that's
the way it works. Anyway,
this
this etheric
this etheric brain
this etheric brain then
this etheric brain then is
this etheric brain then is required
because
because the
this etheric brain then is required
because the frequencies
because the frequencies are
this etheric brain then is required
because the frequencies are like
because the frequencies are like the
highest
highest harmonics
highest harmonics of
highest harmonics of anything
highest harmonics of anything on
highest harmonics of anything on our
chart.
chart. They're
highest harmonics of anything on our
chart. They're beyond
chart. They're beyond that
highest harmonics of anything on our
chart. They're beyond that already.
They're
They're in
They're in a
They're in a different
They're in a different realm.
They're in a different realm. So,
They're in a different realm. So, you
need
need an
They're in a different realm. So, you
need an energy
need an energy that
They're in a different realm. So, you
need an energy that exists
need an energy that exists within
They're in a different realm. So, you
need an energy that exists within a
different
different realm,
different realm, but
different realm, but is
different realm, but is knowable
different realm, but is knowable from
this
this one,
different realm, but is knowable from
this one, which
this one, which is
different realm, but is knowable from
this one, which is and
this one, which is and the
different realm, but is knowable from
this one, which is and the connection
this one, which is and the connection is
subjectivity.
All
All right.
subjectivity.
All right. So,
All right. So, we'll
subjectivity.
All right. So, we'll just
All right. So, we'll just recap
subjectivity.
All right. So, we'll just recap and
All right. So, we'll just recap and then
it's
it's going
it's going to
it's going to be
it's going to be almost
it's going to be almost time
it's going to be almost time for
it's going to be almost time for lunch.
So
So the
it's going to be almost time for lunch.
So the left
So the left brain
it's going to be almost time for lunch.
So the left brain dominance
So the left brain dominance is
it's going to be almost time for lunch.
So the left brain dominance is linear.
That's
That's the
That's the world
That's the world of
That's the world of the
That's the world of the ego.
That's the world of the ego. It's
stressful.
stressful. Releases
That's the world of the ego. It's
stressful. Releases adrenaline.
stressful. Releases adrenaline. It's
That's the world of the ego. It's
stressful. Releases adrenaline. It's uh
poised
poised for
poised for fight
poised for fight or
poised for fight or flight.
poised for fight or flight. It
poised for fight or flight. It stresses
your
your thymus
poised for fight or flight. It stresses
your thymus gland.
your thymus gland. That's
poised for fight or flight. It stresses
your thymus gland. That's why
your thymus gland. That's why we
poised for fight or flight. It stresses
your thymus gland. That's why we do
your thymus gland. That's why we do the
Dr.
Dr. Diamond
Dr. Diamond thymus
Dr. Diamond thymus thump.
Stimulate
Stimulate thymus
Dr. Diamond thymus thump.
Stimulate thymus that
Stimulate thymus that depresses
Dr. Diamond thymus thump.
Stimulate thymus that depresses the
protective
protective killer
protective killer cells
protective killer cells which
protective killer cells which kill
germs.
germs. So
protective killer cells which kill
germs. So you're
germs. So you're more
protective killer cells which kill
germs. So you're more prone
germs. So you're more prone to
protective killer cells which kill
germs. So you're more prone to getting
disease.
disease. Uh
disease. Uh it
disease. Uh it blows
disease. Uh it blows out
disease. Uh it blows out the
disease. Uh it blows out the acupuncture
meridian.
meridian. you
disease. Uh it blows out the acupuncture
meridian. you get
meridian. you get a
disease. Uh it blows out the acupuncture
meridian. you get a negative
kinesiologic
kinesiologic response.
kinesiologic response. The
kinesiologic response. The arm
kinesiologic response. The arm goes
weak.
weak. Calibration
kinesiologic response. The arm goes
weak. Calibration level
weak. Calibration level below
kinesiologic response. The arm goes
weak. Calibration level below 200.
weak. Calibration level below 200. Okay.
On
On over
On over 200,
On over 200, we
On over 200, we see
On over 200, we see a
On over 200, we see a whole
On over 200, we see a whole different
deal.
The
The memory
The memory of
The memory of having
The memory of having been
The memory of having been in
The memory of having been in New
The memory of having been in New York
City
City is
The memory of having been in New York
City is that
City is that people
The memory of having been in New York
City is that people were
City is that people were just
The memory of having been in New York
City is that people were just friendly
like
like at
like at home.
like at home. And
like at home. And I'll
like at home. And I'll tell
like at home. And I'll tell you,
like at home. And I'll tell you, it's
like at home. And I'll tell you, it's a
fact.
fact. You
like at home. And I'll tell you, it's a
fact. You can
fact. You can walk
like at home. And I'll tell you, it's a
fact. You can walk down
fact. You can walk down the
like at home. And I'll tell you, it's a
fact. You can walk down the street
fact. You can walk down the street in
New
New York
New York City
New York City and
New York City and stop
New York City and stop anybody
New York City and stop anybody and
New York City and stop anybody and say,
"What
"What do
New York City and stop anybody and say,
"What do you
"What do you think
New York City and stop anybody and say,
"What do you think of
"What do you think of them
New York City and stop anybody and say,
"What do you think of them paying
"What do you think of them paying this
building
building with
building with our
building with our taxpayers
building with our taxpayers money?"
building with our taxpayers money?" And
they'll,
they'll, "You're
building with our taxpayers money?" And
they'll, "You're right.
they'll, "You're right. By
building with our taxpayers money?" And
they'll, "You're right. By God,
they'll, "You're right. By God, I
building with our taxpayers money?" And
they'll, "You're right. By God, I mean,
it's
it's like
it's like you
it's like you knew
it's like you knew them
it's like you knew them for
it's like you knew them for 20
it's like you knew them for 20 years.
It's
It's real
it's like you knew them for 20 years.
It's real simple.
It's real simple. I
it's like you knew them for 20 years.
It's real simple. I can
It's real simple. I can start
it's like you knew them for 20 years.
It's real simple. I can start a
conversation
conversation with
conversation with anybody
conversation with anybody in
conversation with anybody in anywhere
conversation with anybody in anywhere in
New
New York
conversation with anybody in anywhere in
New York City.
New York City. All right.
conversation with anybody in anywhere in
New York City. All right. So,
New York City. All right. So, my
conversation with anybody in anywhere in
New York City. All right. So, my memory
of
of New
of New York
of New York City
of New York City is
of New York City is different.
of New York City is different. Why?
Because
Because my
of New York City is different. Why?
Because my right
Because my right brain
of New York City is different. Why?
Because my right brain dominates,
releases
releases endorphins.
releases endorphins. Endorphins
releases endorphins. Endorphins feel
good.
good. Positive
releases endorphins. Endorphins feel
good. Positive emotions,
good. Positive emotions, supports
releases endorphins. Endorphins feel
good. Positive emotions, supports the
thymus,
thymus, increases
thymus, increases immunity,
thymus, increases immunity, balances
thymus, increases immunity, balances the
acupuncture
acupuncture systems,
thymus, increases immunity, balances the
acupuncture systems, and
acupuncture systems, and you
thymus, increases immunity, balances the
acupuncture systems, and you get
acupuncture systems, and you get a
positive
positive kinesiologic
positive kinesiologic response.
Next,
Next, we
positive kinesiologic response.
Next, we got
Next, we got two
positive kinesiologic response.
Next, we got two minutes
Next, we got two minutes till
positive kinesiologic response.
Next, we got two minutes till dinner
till
till lunch.
till lunch. How
till lunch. How long
till lunch. How long do
till lunch. How long do we
till lunch. How long do we have
till lunch. How long do we have for
lunch?
lunch? An
till lunch. How long do we have for
lunch? An hour
lunch? An hour and
till lunch. How long do we have for
lunch? An hour and a
lunch? An hour and a half.
till lunch. How long do we have for
lunch? An hour and a half. So,
lunch? An hour and a half. So, you
till lunch. How long do we have for
lunch? An hour and a half. So, you got
time
time to
time to go
time to go out
time to go out and
time to go out and go
time to go out and go back?
>> An
>> An hour
time to go out and go back?
>> An hour and
>> An hour and a
time to go out and go back?
>> An hour and a half.
>> Hour
>> Hour and
>> Hour and a
>> Hour and a half.
>> Hour and a half. Yeah.
>> Hour and a half. Yeah. Okay.
>> Hour and a half. Yeah. Okay. Okay.
>> Hour and a half. Yeah. Okay. Okay. The
functions
functions of
>> Hour and a half. Yeah. Okay. Okay. The
functions of mind.
functions of mind. Well,
>> Hour and a half. Yeah. Okay. Okay. The
functions of mind. Well, we
functions of mind. Well, we got
>> Hour and a half. Yeah. Okay. Okay. The
functions of mind. Well, we got we
functions of mind. Well, we got we went
through
through evolution
through evolution up
through evolution up to
through evolution up to the
through evolution up to the point
through evolution up to the point of
mind.
mind. But
through evolution up to the point of
mind. But now
mind. But now mind
through evolution up to the point of
mind. But now mind has
mind. But now mind has two
through evolution up to the point of
mind. But now mind has two different
attractor
attractor fields.
attractor fields. There's
attractor fields. There's lower
attractor fields. There's lower mind.
The
The animal
attractor fields. There's lower mind.
The animal learns
The animal learns how
attractor fields. There's lower mind.
The animal learns how to
The animal learns how to think,
attractor fields. There's lower mind.
The animal learns how to think, but
The animal learns how to think, but it
thinks
thinks in
thinks in an
thinks in an animal
thinks in an animal kind
thinks in an animal kind of
thinks in an animal kind of a
thinks in an animal kind of a way.
That's
That's at
thinks in an animal kind of a way.
That's at 155.
Then
Then we
Then we go
Then we go to
Then we go to higher
Then we go to higher mind.
Then we go to higher mind. higher
Then we go to higher mind. higher mind.
So
So in
Then we go to higher mind. higher mind.
So in esoteric
So in esoteric like
Then we go to higher mind. higher mind.
So in esoteric like Alice
So in esoteric like Alice Bailey
Then we go to higher mind. higher mind.
So in esoteric like Alice Bailey kind
So in esoteric like Alice Bailey kind of
material
material there's
material there's lower
material there's lower mind
material there's lower mind which
material there's lower mind which is
material there's lower mind which is an
attractor
attractor field
material there's lower mind which is an
attractor field calibrates
attractor field calibrates about
material there's lower mind which is an
attractor field calibrates about 155
attractor field calibrates about 155 and
it's
it's all
it's all these
it's all these characteristics
it's all these characteristics on
it's all these characteristics on the
left
left hand
it's all these characteristics on the
left hand side
left hand side which
it's all these characteristics on the
left hand side which is
left hand side which is going
it's all these characteristics on the
left hand side which is going to
left hand side which is going to be
it's all these characteristics on the
left hand side which is going to be in
the
the book
the book coming
the book coming out
the book coming out pretty
the book coming out pretty soon.
the book coming out pretty soon. Higher
mind
mind is
the book coming out pretty soon. Higher
mind is a
mind is a different
the book coming out pretty soon. Higher
mind is a different energy
mind is a different energy field
the book coming out pretty soon. Higher
mind is a different energy field and
mind is a different energy field and has
an
an different
an different attractor
an different attractor energy
an different attractor energy field
an different attractor energy field and
it
it calibrates
an different attractor energy field and
it calibrates at
it calibrates at 275.
So
So lower
So lower mind
So lower mind is
So lower mind is very
So lower mind is very literal
So lower mind is very literal has
So lower mind is very literal has to
So lower mind is very literal has to do
with
with content
So lower mind is very literal has to do
with content and
with content and form
So lower mind is very literal has to do
with content and form and
with content and form and higher
So lower mind is very literal has to do
with content and form and higher mind
begins
begins to
begins to now
begins to now go
begins to now go into
begins to now go into the
begins to now go into the abstract.
begins to now go into the abstract. This
person
person is
begins to now go into the abstract. This
person is concrete
person is concrete and
begins to now go into the abstract. This
person is concrete and literal.
person is concrete and literal. This
person
person says
person says yeah
person says yeah but
person says yeah but what
person says yeah but what does
person says yeah but what does it
person says yeah but what does it mean?
What
What does
person says yeah but what does it mean?
What does it
What does it mean?
person says yeah but what does it mean?
What does it mean? People
What does it mean? People pess
person says yeah but what does it mean?
What does it mean? People pess the
American
American public
American public wants
American public wants the
American public wants the details.
American public wants the details. Yeah
but
but what
American public wants the details. Yeah
but what does
but what does it
American public wants the details. Yeah
but what does it mean?
but what does it mean? I
American public wants the details. Yeah
but what does it mean? I mean
but what does it mean? I mean it's
American public wants the details. Yeah
but what does it mean? I mean it's what
it
it means.
it means. People
it means. People write
it means. People write me
it means. People write me about
it means. People write me about the
it means. People write me about the book
so
so and
it means. People write me about the book
so and so,
you
you know,
you know, the
you know, the apostrophe
you know, the apostrophe should
you know, the apostrophe should have
been
been here
you know, the apostrophe should have
been here or
been here or there.
you know, the apostrophe should have
been here or there. Yeah,
been here or there. Yeah, but
you know, the apostrophe should have
been here or there. Yeah, but but
been here or there. Yeah, but but what
does
does the
does the book
does the book mean?
does the book mean? You
does the book mean? You know,
does the book mean? You know, I
does the book mean? You know, I don't
know.
know. All right.
does the book mean? You know, I don't
know. All right. So,
know. All right. So, this
does the book mean? You know, I don't
know. All right. So, this is
know. All right. So, this is more
emotional.
emotional. This
emotional. This is
emotional. This is more
emotional. This is more abstract.
emotional. This is more abstract. This
is
is limited
emotional. This is more abstract. This
is limited and
is limited and specific.
emotional. This is more abstract. This
is limited and specific. This
is limited and specific. This is
emotional. This is more abstract. This
is limited and specific. This is more,
you
you know,
you know, what's
you know, what's the
you know, what's the gist
you know, what's the gist of
you know, what's the gist of it?
you know, what's the gist of it? These
people
people want
you know, what's the gist of it? These
people want to
people want to ponder
you know, what's the gist of it? These
people want to ponder it
people want to ponder it a
you know, what's the gist of it? These
people want to ponder it a bit,
people want to ponder it a bit, you
know?
know? I
know? I mean,
know? I mean, what's
know? I mean, what's the
know? I mean, what's the meaning
know? I mean, what's the meaning of
that?
that? I
know? I mean, what's the meaning of
that? I don't
that? I don't know.
know? I mean, what's the meaning of
that? I don't know. because
that? I don't know. because these
know? I mean, what's the meaning of
that? I don't know. because these people
personalize
personalize it
personalize it and
personalize it and these
personalize it and these people
personalize it and these people begin
personalize it and these people begin to
see
see it
personalize it and these people begin to
see it more
see it more impersonally.
personalize it and these people begin to
see it more impersonally. What
see it more impersonally. What does
personalize it and these people begin to
see it more impersonally. What does it
mean
mean for
mean for mankind?
mean for mankind? What
mean for mankind? What does
mean for mankind? What does it
mean for mankind? What does it mean
mean for mankind? What does it mean for
the
the United
mean for mankind? What does it mean for
the United States?
the United States? What
mean for mankind? What does it mean for
the United States? What does
the United States? What does it
mean for mankind? What does it mean for
the United States? What does it mean?
Uh
Uh because
Uh because it
Uh because it begins
Uh because it begins to
Uh because it begins to see
significance.
significance. Therefore,
Uh because it begins to see
significance. Therefore, these
significance. Therefore, these people
become
become more
become more detached.
become more detached. Detached.
become more detached. Detached. People
complain
complain they're
become more detached. Detached. People
complain they're detached.
complain they're detached. Why?
become more detached. Detached. People
complain they're detached. Why? Because
they're
they're reflecting
they're reflecting on
they're reflecting on something.
they're reflecting on something. They're
trying
trying to
they're reflecting on something. They're
trying to get
trying to get what
they're reflecting on something. They're
trying to get what is
trying to get what is the
they're reflecting on something. They're
trying to get what is the significance
and
and the
and the meaning
and the meaning of
and the meaning of that?
and the meaning of that? You
and the meaning of that? You know,
they're
they're trying
and the meaning of that? You know,
they're trying to
they're trying to get,
and the meaning of that? You know,
they're trying to get, you
they're trying to get, you know,
and the meaning of that? You know,
they're trying to get, you know, what
they're trying to get, you know, what am
I
I supposed
I supposed to
I supposed to learn
I supposed to learn out
I supposed to learn out of
I supposed to learn out of that?
because
because you're
I supposed to learn out of that?
because you're looking
because you're looking at
I supposed to learn out of that?
because you're looking at at
because you're looking at at meaning.
What
What is
What is the
What is the meaning
What is the meaning of
What is the meaning of things?
What is the meaning of things? So
What is the meaning of things? So you
move
move more
What is the meaning of things? So you
move more from
move more from the
What is the meaning of things? So you
move more from the particular
move more from the particular to
What is the meaning of things? So you
move more from the particular to the
general.
Instead
Instead of
general.
Instead of looking
Instead of looking at
general.
Instead of looking at morals,
Instead of looking at morals, you're
worrying
worrying more
worrying more about
worrying more about ethics.
worrying more about ethics. You're
worrying more about ethics. You're more
worried
worried what
worrying more about ethics. You're more
worried what is
worried what is the
worrying more about ethics. You're more
worried what is the philosophic
implication.
Instead
Instead of
implication.
Instead of just
Instead of just examples,
implication.
Instead of just examples, you're
Instead of just examples, you're looking
what
what are
what are the
what are the principles.
what are the principles. Instead
what are the principles. Instead of
accumulating
accumulating things
what are the principles. Instead of
accumulating things you're
accumulating things you're interested
what are the principles. Instead of
accumulating things you're interested in
growing
growing instead
growing instead of
growing instead of acquiring
growing instead of acquiring uh
growing instead of acquiring uh to
growing instead of acquiring uh to savor
them.
them. If
growing instead of acquiring uh to savor
them. If you
them. If you savor
growing instead of acquiring uh to savor
them. If you savor what
them. If you savor what you
growing instead of acquiring uh to savor
them. If you savor what you got,
them. If you savor what you got, you
find
find you
find you don't
find you don't really
find you don't really need
find you don't really need it
find you don't really need it anymore.
So
So this
find you don't really need it anymore.
So this person
So this person wants
find you don't really need it anymore.
So this person wants to
So this person wants to remember,
find you don't really need it anymore.
So this person wants to remember, this
person
person reflects.
This
This person
person reflects.
This person thinks,
This person thinks, this
person reflects.
This person thinks, this person
processes,
this
this one
processes,
this one person
this one person tends
processes,
this one person tends to
this one person tends to be
processes,
this one person tends to be literal.
this one person tends to be literal. And
this
this person
this person wants
this person wants to
this person wants to know
this person wants to know what
this person wants to know what does
this person wants to know what does that
what's
what's the
this person wants to know what does that
what's the inference?
what's the inference? What
this person wants to know what does that
what's the inference? What so
what's the inference? What so what
this person wants to know what does that
what's the inference? What so what does
it
it all
it all mean?
it all mean? So
it all mean? So what
it all mean? So what does
it all mean? So what does it
it all mean? So what does it all
it all mean? So what does it all mean?
What
What does
it all mean? So what does it all mean?
What does it
What does it mean
it all mean? So what does it all mean?
What does it mean for
What does it mean for us?
it all mean? So what does it all mean?
What does it mean for us? What
What does it mean for us? What does
it all mean? So what does it all mean?
What does it mean for us? What does it
mean
mean for
mean for mankind?
mean for mankind? What
mean for mankind? What does
mean for mankind? What does it
mean for mankind? What does it mean
mean for mankind? What does it mean for
my
my family?
mean for mankind? What does it mean for
my family? Yeah.
my family? Yeah. All
mean for mankind? What does it mean for
my family? Yeah. All right.
my family? Yeah. All right. So
mean for mankind? What does it mean for
my family? Yeah. All right. So let's
see.
see. Let's
see. Let's look
see. Let's look at
see. Let's look at one
see. Let's look at one more
see. Let's look at one more and
see. Let's look at one more and see
see. Let's look at one more and see if
there's
there's any
see. Let's look at one more and see if
there's any more
there's any more to
see. Let's look at one more and see if
there's any more to mine.
there's any more to mine. I
see. Let's look at one more and see if
there's any more to mine. I want
there's any more to mine. I want to
see. Let's look at one more and see if
there's any more to mine. I want to get
rid
rid of
rid of mine
rid of mine before
rid of mine before we
rid of mine before we go
rid of mine before we go for
rid of mine before we go for lunch.
>> What?
>> I
>> I think
>> I think in
>> I think in the
>> I think in the brochure
>> I think in the brochure it
>> I think in the brochure it said
>> I think in the brochure it said two
hours
hours for
>> I think in the brochure it said two
hours for lunch
hours for lunch and
>> I think in the brochure it said two
hours for lunch and you
hours for lunch and you announced
>> I think in the brochure it said two
hours for lunch and you announced an
hour
hour and
hour and a
hour and a half.
hour and a half. So
hour and a half. So which
hour and a half. So which is
hour and a half. So which is it?
>> What?
>> You
>> You announced
>> You announced an
>> You announced an hour
>> You announced an hour and
>> You announced an hour and a
>> You announced an hour and a half
>> You announced an hour and a half for
lunch
lunch and
>> You announced an hour and a half for
lunch and it's
lunch and it's two
>> You announced an hour and a half for
lunch and it's two hours
lunch and it's two hours in
>> You announced an hour and a half for
lunch and it's two hours in the
brochure.
brochure. So
brochure. So which
>> Oh,
>> Oh, all
brochure. So which
>> Oh, all right.
>> Oh, all right. We
brochure. So which
>> Oh, all right. We got
>> Oh, all right. We got our
brochure. So which
>> Oh, all right. We got our choice.
>> Oh, all right. We got our choice. I
didn't
didn't know
didn't know that.
didn't know that. I
didn't know that. I don't
didn't know that. I don't know.
>> Should
>> Should we
didn't know that. I don't know.
>> Should we do
>> Should we do an
didn't know that. I don't know.
>> Should we do an hour
>> Should we do an hour and
didn't know that. I don't know.
>> Should we do an hour and a
>> Should we do an hour and a half
didn't know that. I don't know.
>> Should we do an hour and a half for
lunch
lunch or
lunch or two
lunch or two hours?
lunch or two hours? How
lunch or two hours? How many
lunch or two hours? How many vote
lunch or two hours? How many vote for
lunch or two hours? How many vote for an
hour
hour and
lunch or two hours? How many vote for an
hour and a
hour and a half?
How
How many
How many vote
How many vote for
How many vote for two
How many vote for two hours?
Thank
Thank you.
All
All right.
All right. So,
All right. So, I
All right. So, I want
All right. So, I want to
All right. So, I want to get
All right. So, I want to get rid
All right. So, I want to get rid of
All right. So, I want to get rid of mine
before
before lunch.
All right. So, I want to get rid of mine
before lunch. I
before lunch. I don't
All right. So, I want to get rid of mine
before lunch. I don't want
before lunch. I don't want to
All right. So, I want to get rid of mine
before lunch. I don't want to drag
before lunch. I don't want to drag mine
to
to lunch
to lunch with
to lunch with me.
Lower
Lower mind
to lunch with me.
Lower mind desires
Lower mind desires things,
to lunch with me.
Lower mind desires things, but
Lower mind desires things, but higher
mind
mind values
mind values them.
mind values them. Lower
mind values them. Lower mind
mind values them. Lower mind wants
mind values them. Lower mind wants to
mind values them. Lower mind wants to be
exclusive.
exclusive. Higher
mind values them. Lower mind wants to be
exclusive. Higher mind
exclusive. Higher mind is
mind values them. Lower mind wants to be
exclusive. Higher mind is inclusive.
This
This wants
This wants to
This wants to control
This wants to control things.
This
This wants
This wants to control things.
This wants to
This wants to use
This wants to control things.
This wants to use it
This wants to use it up.
This wants to control things.
This wants to use it up. This
This wants to use it up. This wants
This wants to control things.
This wants to use it up. This wants to
see
see see
see see its
see see its potential.
see see its potential. This
see see its potential. This has
see see its potential. This has to
see see its potential. This has to be
constrictive.
constrictive. This
see see its potential. This has to be
constrictive. This is
constrictive. This is expansive.
This
This wants
This wants to
This wants to exploit
This wants to exploit things
This wants to exploit things and
This wants to exploit things and use
them
them up.
This wants to exploit things and use
them up. This
them up. This wants
This wants to exploit things and use
them up. This wants to
them up. This wants to preserve
This wants to exploit things and use
them up. This wants to preserve them
them up. This wants to preserve them and
enhance
enhance them.
enhance them. This
enhance them. This one's
enhance them. This one's a
enhance them. This one's a little
enhance them. This one's a little harder
to
to harder
enhance them. This one's a little harder
to harder to
to harder to understand.
enhance them. This one's a little harder
to harder to understand. Design
to harder to understand. Design versus
art.
art. It's
art. It's a
art. It's a different
art. It's a different uh
art. It's a different uh way
art. It's a different uh way of
art. It's a different uh way of looking
at
at art.
art. It's a different uh way of looking
at art. This
at art. This is
art. It's a different uh way of looking
at art. This is competitive.
at art. This is competitive. This
art. It's a different uh way of looking
at art. This is competitive. This is
cooperative.
This
This is
cooperative.
This is gullible.
This is gullible. This
cooperative.
This is gullible. This tends
This is gullible. This tends to
cooperative.
This is gullible. This tends to be
This is gullible. This tends to be more
balanced.
balanced. This
balanced. This is
balanced. This is interested
balanced. This is interested in
balanced. This is interested in force.
This
This is
balanced. This is interested in force.
This is interested
This is interested in
balanced. This is interested in force.
This is interested in power.
This is interested in power. This
balanced. This is interested in force.
This is interested in power. This is
smart.
smart. Very
smart. Very often
smart. Very often very
smart. Very often very smart.
smart. Very often very smart. You
smart. Very often very smart. You can
make
make billions
smart. Very often very smart. You can
make billions over
make billions over here.
smart. Very often very smart. You can
make billions over here. This
make billions over here. This is
intelligent
intelligent because
intelligent because this
intelligent because this exploits
intelligent because this exploits life.
This
This serves
intelligent because this exploits life.
This serves life.
This serves life. This
intelligent because this exploits life.
This serves life. This is
This serves life. This is insensitive.
This
This is
This is gracious.
Now
Now look
This is gracious.
Now look at
Now look at the
This is gracious.
Now look at the bottom
Now look at the bottom and
This is gracious.
Now look at the bottom and then
Now look at the bottom and then we'll
have
have concluded
have concluded this
have concluded this morning.
have concluded this morning. This
have concluded this morning. This side
wants
wants things
have concluded this morning. This side
wants things and
wants things and this
have concluded this morning. This side
wants things and this side
wants things and this side chooses
have concluded this morning. This side
wants things and this side chooses them.
Oh,
Oh, what
Oh, what a
Oh, what a difference.
Oh, what a difference. So
Oh, what a difference. So your
Oh, what a difference. So your option
Oh, what a difference. So your option is
not
not want
Oh, what a difference. So your option is
not want or
not want or not
Oh, what a difference. So your option is
not want or not want.
not want or not want. It's
Oh, what a difference. So your option is
not want or not want. It's merely
not want or not want. It's merely to
choose.
choose. So
choose. So you
choose. So you can
choose. So you can choose
choose. So you can choose what
choose. So you can choose what is.
Therefore,
Therefore, you
choose. So you can choose what is.
Therefore, you release
Therefore, you release from
choose. So you can choose what is.
Therefore, you release from all
Therefore, you release from all the
negatives.
negatives. You
negatives. You say,
negatives. You say, "Oh
negatives. You say, "Oh Lord,
negatives. You say, "Oh Lord, whatever
negatives. You say, "Oh Lord, whatever I
am
am today,
negatives. You say, "Oh Lord, whatever I
am today, by
am today, by thy
negatives. You say, "Oh Lord, whatever I
am today, by thy grace
am today, by thy grace do
negatives. You say, "Oh Lord, whatever I
am today, by thy grace do I
am today, by thy grace do I choose
negatives. You say, "Oh Lord, whatever I
am today, by thy grace do I choose to
am today, by thy grace do I choose to be
that
that which
that which I
that which I am."
And
And by
that which I am."
And by grace
And by grace you
that which I am."
And by grace you say,
And by grace you say, "So
that which I am."
And by grace you say, "So I'm
And by grace you say, "So I'm short,
that which I am."
And by grace you say, "So I'm short, fat
ugly,
ugly, and
ugly, and stupid
and
and broke."
ugly, and stupid
and broke." So,
I
I was
I was poor
I was poor until
I was poor until I
I was poor until I was
I was poor until I was 40.
I was poor until I was 40. Hear
I was poor until I was 40. Hear all
I was poor until I was 40. Hear all the
people
people crying
I was poor until I was 40. Hear all the
people crying about
people crying about being
I was poor until I was 40. Hear all the
people crying about being poverty.
people crying about being poverty. Yeah,
right.
right. You
right. You should
right. You should know
right. You should know what
right. You should know what poverty
right. You should know what poverty is.
I
I was
right. You should know what poverty is.
I was poor
I was poor till
right. You should know what poverty is.
I was poor till 40.
I was poor till 40. So,
so
so you
so you live
so you live on
so you live on $3
so you live on $3 a
so you live on $3 a week
so you live on $3 a week for
so you live on $3 a week for food.
so you live on $3 a week for food. So,
so,
so
so nothing.
Every
Every time
so nothing.
Every time you
Every time you catch
so nothing.
Every time you catch your
Every time you catch your mind
so nothing.
Every time you catch your mind saying
so,
so, you
so, you say
so, you say so.
so, you say so. So
so, you say so. So what?
so, you say so. So what? So
so, you say so. So what? So nothing.
So
So so
so, you say so. So what? So nothing.
So so and
So so and so
so, you say so. So what? So nothing.
So so and so is
So so and so is wrong.
so, you say so. So what? So nothing.
So so and so is wrong. So
he's
he's wrong.
So
So So
he's wrong.
So So I'm
So So I'm wrong.
he's wrong.
So So I'm wrong. So
So So I'm wrong. So you're
he's wrong.
So So I'm wrong. So you're wrong.
So So I'm wrong. So you're wrong. So
he's
he's wrong.
he's wrong. He
he's wrong. He was
he's wrong. He was wrong.
Right.
The
The best
The best way
The best way to
The best way to get
The best way to get off
The best way to get off blame
The best way to get off blame is
The best way to get off blame is admit
you
you were
The best way to get off blame is admit
you were wrong.
What
What does
What does it
What does it take?
What does it take? Nothing.
What does it take? Nothing. You're
What does it take? Nothing. You're lying
anyway.
anyway. You
What does it take? Nothing. You're lying
anyway. You know
anyway. You know that.
It's
It's part
It's part of
It's part of being
It's part of being polite.
You're
You're wrong.
It's part of being polite.
You're wrong. Well,
You're wrong. Well, I
It's part of being polite.
You're wrong. Well, I must
You're wrong. Well, I must agree
It's part of being polite.
You're wrong. Well, I must agree I
You're wrong. Well, I must agree I was.
And
And now
And now I'm
And now I'm looking
And now I'm looking at
And now I'm looking at how
And now I'm looking at how you
And now I'm looking at how you see
And now I'm looking at how you see it
and
and I
And now I'm looking at how you see it
and I see
and I see the
And now I'm looking at how you see it
and I see the value
and I see the value of
And now I'm looking at how you see it
and I see the value of it.
They
They don't
They don't have
They don't have to
They don't have to see
They don't have to see your
They don't have to see your fingers.
They don't have to see your fingers. You
got
got them
They don't have to see your fingers. You
got them crossed.
>> Okay,
>> Okay, we'll
>> Okay, we'll resume
>> Okay, we'll resume in
>> Okay, we'll resume in an
>> Okay, we'll resume in an hour
>> Okay, we'll resume in an hour and
>> Okay, we'll resume in an hour and a
half.
Well,
Well, here
Well, here we
Well, here we are
Well, here we are again.
>> Here
>> Here we
Well, here we are again.
>> Here we are
>> Here we are again.
Okay,
Okay, we're
Okay, we're wired
Okay, we're wired up
Okay, we're wired up for
Okay, we're wired up for sound.
Wow,
Wow, it
Okay, we're wired up for sound.
Wow, it seems
Wow, it seems very
Okay, we're wired up for sound.
Wow, it seems very loud.
Are
Are we
Are we too
Are we too loud?
Are we too loud? Okay.
My
My This
Are we too loud? Okay.
My This is
My This is a
Are we too loud? Okay.
My This is a new
My This is a new microphone.
Are we too loud? Okay.
My This is a new microphone. Cost
My This is a new microphone. Cost a
fortune.
I
I never
fortune.
I never know
I never know where
fortune.
I never know where it
I never know where it is.
It
It scares
It scares me
It scares me a
It scares me a little.
It scares me a little. So,
It scares me a little. So, I
It scares me a little. So, I try
It scares me a little. So, I try not
It scares me a little. So, I try not to
look
look at
It scares me a little. So, I try not to
look at it.
Something's
Something's something's
Something's something's following
Something's something's following me
around.
Instant
Instant paranoia.
Instant paranoia. Yeah.
Instant paranoia. Yeah. H
Instant paranoia. Yeah. H how
Instant paranoia. Yeah. H how did
Instant paranoia. Yeah. H how did things
come
come about?
Instant paranoia. Yeah. H how did things
come about? We
come about? We said
Instant paranoia. Yeah. H how did things
come about? We said it's
come about? We said it's that
Instant paranoia. Yeah. H how did things
come about? We said it's that which
you
you have
you have become
you have become expressing
you have become expressing itself
spontaneously.
All
All right.
All right. When
All right. When you
All right. When you get
All right. When you get beyond
All right. When you get beyond cause
All right. When you get beyond cause and
effect
effect and
All right. When you get beyond cause and
effect and you
effect and you see
All right. When you get beyond cause and
effect and you see all
effect and you see all is
All right. When you get beyond cause and
effect and you see all is occurring
effect and you see all is occurring by
as
as a
as a consequence
as a consequence of
as a consequence of the
as a consequence of the field
as a consequence of the field is
as a consequence of the field is a
consequence
consequence of
as a consequence of the field is a
consequence of what
consequence of what you
as a consequence of the field is a
consequence of what you are
consequence of what you are in
as a consequence of the field is a
consequence of what you are in the
field.
The
The next
field.
The next thing
The next thing you
field.
The next thing you notice
The next thing you notice is
field.
The next thing you notice is that
everything
everything is
everything is happening
everything is happening of
everything is happening of its
everything is happening of its own.
Everything
Everything is
everything is happening of its own.
Everything is happening
Everything is happening of
everything is happening of its own.
Everything is happening of its
Everything is happening of its own.
There's
There's no
There's no nothing
There's no nothing causing
There's no nothing causing it.
There's no nothing causing it. If
there's
there's nothing
There's no nothing causing it. If
there's nothing causing
there's nothing causing anything
There's no nothing causing it. If
there's nothing causing anything that's
happening,
happening, then
happening, then everything
happening, then everything is
happening, then everything is happening
spontaneously.
Now,
Now, the
Now, the illusion
Now, the illusion is
Now, the illusion is there's
Now, the illusion is there's a
Now, the illusion is there's a you
causing
causing it
Now, the illusion is there's a you
causing it to
causing it to be
Now, the illusion is there's a you
causing it to be that
causing it to be that way.
There
There isn't
There isn't any
There isn't any you.
There isn't any you. And
There isn't any you. And if
There isn't any you. And if there
There isn't any you. And if there was,
it's
it's not
There isn't any you. And if there was,
it's not causing
it's not causing it
There isn't any you. And if there was,
it's not causing it anyway.
Everything's
Everything's happening.
Everything's happening. So,
Everything's happening. So, you
Everything's happening. So, you get
Everything's happening. So, you get to
enjoy.
I
I didn't
I didn't decide
I didn't decide to
I didn't decide to do
I didn't decide to do that.
What
What are
I didn't decide to do that.
What are you
What are you up
I didn't decide to do that.
What are you up to,
What are you up to, you
I didn't decide to do that.
What are you up to, you idiot?
What are you up to, you idiot? I
I didn't decide to do that.
What are you up to, you idiot? I don't
know.
Everything
Everything is
know.
Everything is just
Everything is just happening
know.
Everything is just happening of
Everything is just happening of its
know.
Everything is just happening of its own.
In
In the
In the meantime,
In the meantime, you're
In the meantime, you're completely
In the meantime, you're completely and
totally
totally free
In the meantime, you're completely and
totally free because
totally free because that
In the meantime, you're completely and
totally free because that what's
totally free because that what's that
which
which you
which you are
which you are is
which you are is what's
which you are is what's determining
uh
uh how
which you are is what's determining
uh how you
uh how you know
which you are is what's determining
uh how you know what's
uh how you know what's happening.
Uh
Uh it's
Uh it's sort
Uh it's sort of
Uh it's sort of a
Uh it's sort of a different
Uh it's sort of a different paradigm.
Different
Different paradigm.
The
The reason
The reason science
The reason science can't
The reason science can't get
The reason science can't get what
consciousness
consciousness is
The reason science can't get what
consciousness is about
consciousness is about is
The reason science can't get what
consciousness is about is because
consciousness is about is because it's
in
in a
in a different
in a different paradigm
and
and it
in a different paradigm
and it struggles
and it struggles hard.
in a different paradigm
and it struggles hard. In
and it struggles hard. In fact,
in a different paradigm
and it struggles hard. In fact, I
and it struggles hard. In fact, I read
these
these learn
these learn learned
these learn learned dissertations
these learn learned dissertations and
you
you can
these learn learned dissertations and
you can hear
you can hear the
these learn learned dissertations and
you can hear the ego
you can hear the ego almost
these learn learned dissertations and
you can hear the ego almost groaning
with
with pain
with pain trying
with pain trying to
with pain trying to push
with pain trying to push the
with pain trying to push the intellect,
you
you know,
with pain trying to push the intellect,
you know, past
you know, past 499.5,
but
but you
but you can't
but you can't get
but you can't get it
but you can't get it past
but you can't get it past there.
but you can't get it past there. You
but you can't get it past there. You got
to
to you
but you can't get it past there. You got
to you got
to you got to
but you can't get it past there. You got
to you got to shift
to you got to shift to
but you can't get it past there. You got
to you got to shift to a
to you got to shift to a different
dimension.
But
But you
dimension.
But you see,
But you see, you're
dimension.
But you see, you're talking
But you see, you're talking to
dimension.
But you see, you're talking to fish
who've
who've never
who've never experienced
who've never experienced error.
who've never experienced error. So,
who've never experienced error. So, you
realize
realize that
who've never experienced error. So, you
realize that they
realize that they don't
who've never experienced error. So, you
realize that they don't get
realize that they don't get what
who've never experienced error. So, you
realize that they don't get what you're
saying.
The
The average
saying.
The average mind
The average mind does
saying.
The average mind does not
The average mind does not grasp
saying.
The average mind does not grasp paradigm
or
or paradigm
or paradigm jump
or paradigm jump or
or paradigm jump or contextualization.
Doesn't
Doesn't know
or paradigm jump or contextualization.
Doesn't know what
Doesn't know what you're
or paradigm jump or contextualization.
Doesn't know what you're talking
Doesn't know what you're talking about.
So
So let's
So let's say
So let's say you're
So let's say you're a
So let's say you're a fish.
So let's say you're a fish. You've
always
always been
So let's say you're a fish. You've
always been a
always been a fish.
So let's say you're a fish. You've
always been a fish. All
always been a fish. All your
So let's say you're a fish. You've
always been a fish. All your friends
always been a fish. All your friends are
fish.
fish. Your
fish. Your family's
fish. Your family's been
fish. Your family's been fish.
fish. Your family's been fish. In
fish. Your family's been fish. In fact,
you've
you've been
fish. Your family's been fish. In fact,
you've been fish
you've been fish for
fish. Your family's been fish. In fact,
you've been fish for millions
you've been fish for millions of
fish. Your family's been fish. In fact,
you've been fish for millions of years.
All
All you
All you know
All you know is
All you know is water.
So
So if
All you know is water.
So if I
So if I say
All you know is water.
So if I say to
So if I say to a
All you know is water.
So if I say to a fish,
So if I say to a fish, tell
All you know is water.
So if I say to a fish, tell me
So if I say to a fish, tell me about
water.
water. He'd
water. He'd say,
water. He'd say, what
water. He'd say, what are
water. He'd say, what are you
water. He'd say, what are you talking
about?
Right?
Right? If
Right? If I
Right? If I ask
Right? If I ask human
Right? If I ask human beings,
Right? If I ask human beings, tell
Right? If I ask human beings, tell me
about
about space,
Right? If I ask human beings, tell me
about space, they
about space, they tell
Right? If I ask human beings, tell me
about space, they tell you,
about space, they tell you, what
Right? If I ask human beings, tell me
about space, they tell you, what can
about space, they tell you, what can I
say
say about
say about space?
So
So for
say about space?
So for the
So for the fish
say about space?
So for the fish to
So for the fish to be
say about space?
So for the fish to be able
So for the fish to be able to
say about space?
So for the fish to be able to describe
water,
water, it
water, it would
water, it would have
water, it would have to
water, it would have to experience
nonwater.
So
So the
So the more
So the more evolved
So the more evolved fish
So the more evolved fish fly
So the more evolved fish fly out
So the more evolved fish fly out into
the
the air
So the more evolved fish fly out into
the air and
the air and can
So the more evolved fish fly out into
the air and can go
the air and can go back
So the more evolved fish fly out into
the air and can go back and
the air and can go back and tell
So the more evolved fish fly out into
the air and can go back and tell their
friends.
The
The thought
friends.
The thought thoughts
The thought thoughts you
friends.
The thought thoughts you see
The thought thoughts you see arise
friends.
The thought thoughts you see arise out
of
of the
of the sea
of the sea of
of the sea of nothingness
of the sea of nothingness and
of the sea of nothingness and you
of the sea of nothingness and you see
flying
flying fish
of the sea of nothingness and you see
flying fish you
flying fish you know
of the sea of nothingness and you see
flying fish you know there
flying fish you know there was
of the sea of nothingness and you see
flying fish you know there was some
uh
uh ocean
uh ocean during
uh ocean during the
uh ocean during the war
uh ocean during the war I
uh ocean during the war I forget
uh ocean during the war I forget what
saso
saso sea
uh ocean during the war I forget what
saso sea or
saso sea or some
uh ocean during the war I forget what
saso sea or some place
saso sea or some place anyway
uh ocean during the war I forget what
saso sea or some place anyway it's
phosphorescent
phosphorescent and
phosphorescent and uh
phosphorescent and uh fine
phosphorescent and uh fine fish
phosphorescent and uh fine fish kept
coming
coming out
phosphorescent and uh fine fish kept
coming out of
coming out of the
phosphorescent and uh fine fish kept
coming out of the water
coming out of the water and
phosphorescent and uh fine fish kept
coming out of the water and landing
coming out of the water and landing on
the
the deck
the deck and
the deck and flopping
the deck and flopping around
the deck and flopping around well
the deck and flopping around well you
see
see when
the deck and flopping around well you
see when the
see when the fish
the deck and flopping around well you
see when the fish come
see when the fish come out
the deck and flopping around well you
see when the fish come out of
see when the fish come out of the
the deck and flopping around well you
see when the fish come out of the water
like
like that
like that this
like that this fish
like that this fish is
like that this fish is not
like that this fish is not causing
like that this fish is not causing this
fish
fish to
like that this fish is not causing this
fish to come
fish to come out
like that this fish is not causing this
fish to come out of
fish to come out of the
like that this fish is not causing this
fish to come out of the water
fish to come out of the water is
like that this fish is not causing this
fish to come out of the water is it
doing
doing it
doing it spontaneously
as
as an
doing it spontaneously
as an expression
as an expression of
doing it spontaneously
as an expression of that
as an expression of that which
doing it spontaneously
as an expression of that which it
as an expression of that which it is.
So
So your
So your thoughts
So your thoughts are
So your thoughts are like
So your thoughts are like these
So your thoughts are like these fish
So your thoughts are like these fish you
see
see and
they're
they're spontaneously
they're spontaneously coming
they're spontaneously coming out
they're spontaneously coming out of
nothing.
The
The nothingness
in
in fact
The nothingness
in fact where
in fact where the
The nothingness
in fact where the absolute
in fact where the absolute certainty
where
where the
where the certainty
where the certainty of
where the certainty of the
where the certainty of the absolute
resides
resides is
where the certainty of the absolute
resides is right
resides is right prior
where the certainty of the absolute
resides is right prior right
resides is right prior right pri
where the certainty of the absolute
resides is right prior right pri prior
to
to a
to a thought.
We
We said
to a thought.
We said 99%
We said 99% of
to a thought.
We said 99% of the
We said 99% of the we
to a thought.
We said 99% of the we used
We said 99% of the we used to
to a thought.
We said 99% of the we used to say
We said 99% of the we used to say it
to a thought.
We said 99% of the we used to say it was
98%
98% but
98% but maybe
98% but maybe maybe
98% but maybe maybe things
98% but maybe maybe things have
improved.
improved. Now
98% but maybe maybe things have
improved. Now only
improved. Now only 99%
98% but maybe maybe things have
improved. Now only 99% 99%
improved. Now only 99% 99% of
98% but maybe maybe things have
improved. Now only 99% 99% of the
improved. Now only 99% 99% of the mind
is
is blank
is blank at
is blank at all
is blank at all times.
is blank at all times. Only
is blank at all times. Only 1%
is blank at all times. Only 1% is
is blank at all times. Only 1% is busy.
Used
Used to
is blank at all times. Only 1% is busy.
Used to be
Used to be 2%
is blank at all times. Only 1% is busy.
Used to be 2% now
Used to be 2% now it's
is blank at all times. Only 1% is busy.
Used to be 2% now it's down
Used to be 2% now it's down to
is blank at all times. Only 1% is busy.
Used to be 2% now it's down to 1%.
Probably
Probably we
Probably we can
Probably we can squish
Probably we can squish it
Probably we can squish it right
Probably we can squish it right down
Probably we can squish it right down to
half
half a
Probably we can squish it right down to
half a percent.
So
So people
So people bemoan
So people bemoan that
So people bemoan that they're
So people bemoan that they're at
So people bemoan that they're at the
effect
effect of
So people bemoan that they're at the
effect of the
effect of the mind.
So people bemoan that they're at the
effect of the mind. No,
effect of the mind. No, you're
So people bemoan that they're at the
effect of the mind. No, you're not
effect of the mind. No, you're not at
the
the effect
the effect of
the effect of the
the effect of the mind.
the effect of the mind. 99%
the effect of the mind. 99% of
the effect of the mind. 99% of the
the effect of the mind. 99% of the mind
is
is silent.
the effect of the mind. 99% of the mind
is silent. Only
is silent. Only 1%
the effect of the mind. 99% of the mind
is silent. Only 1% is
is silent. Only 1% is speaking.
Therefore,
all
all you
Therefore,
all you have
all you have to
Therefore,
all you have to do
all you have to do is
Therefore,
all you have to do is watch
all you have to do is watch the
Therefore,
all you have to do is watch the 1%.
all you have to do is watch the 1%. It's
what
what attracts
what attracts your
what attracts your attention
what attracts your attention because
what attracts your attention because you
become
become entranced
what attracts your attention because you
become entranced by
become entranced by the
what attracts your attention because you
become entranced by the 1%
become entranced by the 1% because
what attracts your attention because you
become entranced by the 1% because it's
the
the only
the only thing
the only thing that
the only thing that seems
the only thing that seems to
the only thing that seems to be
happening.
Because
Because it's
Because it's happening
Because it's happening there,
Because it's happening there, you
Because it's happening there, you think
there's
there's a
Because it's happening there, you think
there's a you
there's a you that's
Because it's happening there, you think
there's a you that's causing
there's a you that's causing it
Because it's happening there, you think
there's a you that's causing it to
happen.
happen. No,
happen. No, no.
happen. No, no. Thinkingness
happen. No, no. Thinkingness is
happen. No, no. Thinkingness is just
happening.
happening. And
happen. No, no. Thinkingness is just
happening. And if
happening. And if you
happen. No, no. Thinkingness is just
happening. And if you want
happening. And if you want to
happen. No, no. Thinkingness is just
happening. And if you want to find
happening. And if you want to find that
out,
out, you
out, you tell
out, you tell thinkingness
out, you tell thinkingness to
out, you tell thinkingness to stop
out, you tell thinkingness to stop doing
so.
How
How long
How long can
How long can will
How long can will it
How long can will it stay
How long can will it stay silent
How long can will it stay silent if
How long can will it stay silent if you
command
command it
How long can will it stay silent if you
command it to
command it to be
How long can will it stay silent if you
command it to be silent?
Tenth
Tenth of
Tenth of a
Tenth of a second
Tenth of a second maybe
Tenth of a second maybe in
Tenth of a second maybe in the
Tenth of a second maybe in the average
person.
Uh
Uh okay.
Uh okay. So
Uh okay. So what's
Uh okay. So what's happened
Uh okay. So what's happened then
Uh okay. So what's happened then is
Uh okay. So what's happened then is we
have
have become
Uh okay. So what's happened then is we
have become we
have become we are
Uh okay. So what's happened then is we
have become we are in
have become we are in a
Uh okay. So what's happened then is we
have become we are in a hypnotic
have become we are in a hypnotic trance
of
of the
of the 1%.
See,
See, you
of the 1%.
See, you don't
See, you don't have
of the 1%.
See, you don't have to
See, you don't have to save
of the 1%.
See, you don't have to save 99
See, you don't have to save 99 all
of the 1%.
See, you don't have to save 99 all 100%
of
of yourself.
of yourself. 1%
of yourself. 1% is
of yourself. 1% is all
of yourself. 1% is all you
of yourself. 1% is all you got
of yourself. 1% is all you got to
of yourself. 1% is all you got to say.
All
All right.
So,
So, what's
So, what's happened
So, what's happened is
So, what's happened is we've
So, what's happened is we've come
So, what's happened is we've come into
So, what's happened is we've come into a
hypnotic
hypnotic trance
So, what's happened is we've come into a
hypnotic trance of
hypnotic trance of the
So, what's happened is we've come into a
hypnotic trance of the 1%.
That's
That's a
That's a fact.
That's a fact. Resist.
That's a fact. Resist. It's
That's a fact. Resist. It's a
That's a fact. Resist. It's a fact.
That's a fact. Resist. It's a fact. 99%
of
of your
That's a fact. Resist. It's a fact. 99%
of your mind
of your mind is
That's a fact. Resist. It's a fact. 99%
of your mind is already
of your mind is already cleared
That's a fact. Resist. It's a fact. 99%
of your mind is already cleared away.
Only
Only 1%
Only 1% you
Only 1% you got
Only 1% you got to
Only 1% you got to worry
Only 1% you got to worry about.
That's
That's feel
Only 1% you got to worry about.
That's feel better
That's feel better already.
I
I need
I need to
I need to feel
I need to feel better.
I need to feel better. I
I need to feel better. I like
I need to feel better. I like people
feel
feel better.
That's
That's why
That's why I
That's why I was
That's why I was 5
That's why I was 5 minutes
That's why I was 5 minutes late
That's why I was 5 minutes late after
lunch.
lunch. Then
That's why I was 5 minutes late after
lunch. Then all
lunch. Then all the
That's why I was 5 minutes late after
lunch. Then all the people
lunch. Then all the people that
That's why I was 5 minutes late after
lunch. Then all the people that were
late
late wouldn't
late wouldn't have
late wouldn't have to
late wouldn't have to feel
late wouldn't have to feel guilty.
I
I was
late wouldn't have to feel guilty.
I was late
I was late just
late wouldn't have to feel guilty.
I was late just for
I was late just for you
late wouldn't have to feel guilty.
I was late just for you folks.
I
I 20
I 20 minutes
I 20 minutes late.
I 20 minutes late. That's
I 20 minutes late. That's something
different.
So
people
people say
So
people say well
people say well if
So
people say well if I
people say well if I let
So
people say well if I let go
people say well if I let go of
So
people say well if I let go of my
people say well if I let go of my ego
how
how will
how will I
how will I survive?
How
How will
how will I survive?
How will who
How will who survive?
Whatever
Whatever is
Whatever is destined
Whatever is destined to
Whatever is destined to be
Whatever is destined to be will
Whatever is destined to be will be.
Whatever is destined to be will be. You
know,
know, so
Whatever is destined to be will be. You
know, so surrendering
know, so surrendering to
Whatever is destined to be will be. You
know, so surrendering to God
know, so surrendering to God means
without
without the
without the considerations.
Considerations
though
though many
though many people
though many people are
aligned
aligned with
though many people are
aligned with the
aligned with the truth
though many people are
aligned with the truth except
aligned with the truth except for
though many people are
aligned with the truth except for the
considerations.
considerations. They
considerations. They have
considerations.
All right.
All right. So
All right. So how
All right. So how can
All right. So how can you
All right. So how can you tell
All right. So how can you tell when
All right. So how can you tell when your
mind
mind is
All right. So how can you tell when your
mind is completely
mind is completely made
All right. So how can you tell when your
mind is completely made up?
mind is completely made up? When
All right. So how can you tell when your
mind is completely made up? When your
when
when your
when your mind
when your mind is
when your mind is 100%
when your mind is 100% made
when your mind is 100% made up
when your mind is 100% made up about
when your mind is 100% made up about a
thing,
then
the
the intention
then
the intention manifests.
Otherwise,
Otherwise, what's
Otherwise, what's happening
Otherwise, what's happening is
Otherwise, what's happening is the
Otherwise, what's happening is the mind
has
has considerations
considerations.
It's
It's not
considerations.
It's not 100%
It's not 100% in
considerations.
It's not 100% in agreement
It's not 100% in agreement with
considerations.
It's not 100% in agreement with your
intention.
Let's
spiritual
spiritual work
spiritual work then
spiritual work then is
spiritual work then is finding
spiritual work then is finding out
spiritual work then is finding out what
those
those considerations
spiritual work then is finding out what
those considerations are
those considerations are and
spiritual work then is finding out what
those considerations are and being
willing
willing to
willing to let
willing to let them
willing to let them go.
willing to let them go. People
willing to let them go. People would
say,
say, "Well,
willing to let them go. People would
say, "Well, I'm
say, "Well, I'm not
willing to let them go. People would
say, "Well, I'm not willing
say, "Well, I'm not willing to
willing to let them go. People would
say, "Well, I'm not willing to admit
that
that I'm
that I'm wrong."
So
So that's
that I'm wrong."
So that's pride,
So that's pride, right?
that I'm wrong."
So that's pride, right? And
So that's pride, right? And when
that I'm wrong."
So that's pride, right? And when you
So that's pride, right? And when you let
go
go of
go of the
go of the pride,
then
then you're
go of the pride,
then you're proud
then you're proud of
go of the pride,
then you're proud of your
then you're proud of your humility.
Ain't
Ain't nobody
Ain't nobody more
Ain't nobody more humble
Ain't nobody more humble than
Ain't nobody more humble than I
Ain't nobody more humble than I am
Ain't nobody more humble than I am on
this
this planet,
Ain't nobody more humble than I am on
this planet, folks.
this planet, folks. I
Ain't nobody more humble than I am on
this planet, folks. I am
this planet, folks. I am the
Ain't nobody more humble than I am on
this planet, folks. I am the number
this planet, folks. I am the number one
humble.
Okay,
Okay, we're
humble.
Okay, we're gonna
Okay, we're gonna just
humble.
Okay, we're gonna just do
Okay, we're gonna just do this
humble.
Okay, we're gonna just do this lecture,
then
then we're
then we're going
then we're going to
um
um they
then we're going to
um they say
um they say we're
then we're going to
um they say we're going
um they say we're going to
then we're going to
um they say we're going to take
um they say we're going to take a
then we're going to
um they say we're going to take a break
and
and then
and then we're
and then we're going
and then we're going to
and then we're going to have
and then we're going to have have
chanting
chanting and
and then we're going to have have
chanting and then
chanting and then we're
and then we're going to have have
chanting and then we're going
chanting and then we're going to
and then we're going to have have
chanting and then we're going to have
questions
questions and
questions and answers.
questions and answers. I
questions and answers. I think
questions and answers. I think that's
correct.
correct. But
questions and answers. I think that's
correct. But Gigi's
correct. But Gigi's going
questions and answers. I think that's
correct. But Gigi's going to
correct. But Gigi's going to get
questions and answers. I think that's
correct. But Gigi's going to get up
correct. But Gigi's going to get up and
tell
tell us
tell us about
tell us about that.
We
We followed
tell us about that.
We followed the
We followed the development
tell us about that.
We followed the development of
consciousness
consciousness uh
consciousness uh from
consciousness uh from the
consciousness uh from the beginning.
consciousness uh from the beginning. the
bacteria,
bacteria, the
consciousness uh from the beginning. the
bacteria, the first
bacteria, the first things
consciousness uh from the beginning. the
bacteria, the first things thirsting
that
that experiences
that experiences that
that experiences that it
that experiences that it is
all
all the
that experiences that it is
all the way
all the way up
that experiences that it is
all the way up to
all the way up to the
that experiences that it is
all the way up to the evolution
all the way up to the evolution of
that experiences that it is
all the way up to the evolution of the
prefrontal
prefrontal cortex
and
and the
prefrontal cortex
and the great
and the great difficulty
prefrontal cortex
and the great difficulty that
and the great difficulty that that
causes
causes because
causes because now
causes because now the
causes because now the animal
causes because now the animal ego
causes because now the animal ego merely
uses
uses the
causes because now the animal ego merely
uses the intellect,
uses the intellect, the
causes because now the animal ego merely
uses the intellect, the prefrontal
cortex
for
for its
cortex
for its animal
for its animal instinctual
cortex
for its animal instinctual drives.
for its animal instinctual drives. It
becomes
becomes subservient.
becomes subservient. So
becomes subservient. So in
becomes subservient. So in unevolved
person
person the
becomes subservient. So in unevolved
person the prefernal
person the prefernal cortex
becomes subservient. So in unevolved
person the prefernal cortex merely
becomes
becomes the
becomes the clever
becomes the clever way
becomes the clever way in
becomes the clever way in which
becomes the clever way in which you
becomes the clever way in which you seek
gain
gain and
becomes the clever way in which you seek
gain and dominance
gain and dominance in
becomes the clever way in which you seek
gain and dominance in which
gain and dominance in which you
becomes the clever way in which you seek
gain and dominance in which you can
justify
justify killing
justify killing others
justify killing others etc.
justify killing others etc. So
justify killing others etc. So the
the
the intellect
justify killing others etc. So the
the intellect then
the intellect then becomes
justify killing others etc. So the
the intellect then becomes the
the intellect then becomes the tool
that's
that's what's
that's what's called
that's what's called lower
that's what's called lower mind.
that's what's called lower mind. It's
the
the thinking
that's what's called lower mind. It's
the thinking animal.
An
An animal's
An animal's okay
An animal's okay until
An animal's okay until you
An animal's okay until you teach
An animal's okay until you teach it
An animal's okay until you teach it how
to
to think.
An animal's okay until you teach it how
to think. Then
to think. Then it's
An animal's okay until you teach it how
to think. Then it's in
to think. Then it's in big
An animal's okay until you teach it how
to think. Then it's in big trouble.
That's
That's the
That's the history
That's the history of
That's the history of mankind.
The
The evolution
That's the history of mankind.
The evolution of
The evolution of consciousness
That's the history of mankind.
The evolution of consciousness reached
The evolution of consciousness reached a
really
really high
really high level
really high level about
really high level about 350
really high level about 350 400
really high level about 350 400 BC
really high level about 350 400 BC in
ancient
ancient Greece
really high level about 350 400 BC in
ancient Greece and
the
the great
the great books
the great books of
the great books of the
the great books of the western
the great books of the western world
really
really track.
the great books of the western world
really track. So
really track. So the
the great books of the western world
really track. So the animal
consciousness
consciousness at
consciousness at 155
consciousness at 155 lower
consciousness at 155 lower mind
consciousness at 155 lower mind evolves
to
to higher
consciousness at 155 lower mind evolves
to higher higher
to higher higher mind
consciousness at 155 lower mind evolves
to higher higher mind which
to higher higher mind which was
consciousness at 155 lower mind evolves
to higher higher mind which was I
to higher higher mind which was I forget
255 or
255 or something
255 or something and
255 or something and then
255 or something and then it
255 or something and then it becomes
even
even more
255 or something and then it becomes
even more refined
even more refined as
255 or something and then it becomes
even more refined as a
even more refined as a tool.
255 or something and then it becomes
even more refined as a tool. So
even more refined as a tool. So here
255 or something and then it becomes
even more refined as a tool. So here we
see
see the
see the refinement
see the refinement of
see the refinement of the
see the refinement of the prefrontal
cortex
cortex historically
see the refinement of the prefrontal
cortex historically displayed
cortex historically displayed in
see the refinement of the prefrontal
cortex historically displayed in the
great
great books
great books of
great books of the
great books of the western
great books of the western world
great books of the western world which
cover
cover roughly
great books of the western world which
cover roughly 2500
cover roughly 2500 years.
uh
uh the
uh the most
uh the most pristine
uh the most pristine thinking
uh the most pristine thinking of
uh the most pristine thinking of which
man
man is
uh the most pristine thinking of which
man is capable.
Socrates
Socrates who
Socrates who uh
Socrates who uh my
Socrates who uh my hero
Socrates who uh my hero was
Socrates who uh my hero was my
Socrates who uh my hero was my hero
Socrates who uh my hero was my hero I
forget
forget what
Socrates who uh my hero was my hero I
forget what he
forget what he uh
Socrates who uh my hero was my hero I
forget what he uh calibrates
forget what he uh calibrates at
Socrates who uh my hero was my hero I
forget what he uh calibrates at 540
forget what he uh calibrates at 540 I
think.
think. Socrates
think. Socrates was
think. Socrates was quite
think. Socrates was quite interesting
because
because he
think. Socrates was quite interesting
because he was
because he was a
think. Socrates was quite interesting
because he was a theist
because he was a theist who
think. Socrates was quite interesting
because he was a theist who was
dedicated
dedicated to
dedicated to truth
dedicated to truth and
dedicated to truth and dedicated
dedicated to truth and dedicated to
dedicated to truth and dedicated to God
and
and rather
dedicated to truth and dedicated to God
and rather than
and rather than veer
dedicated to truth and dedicated to God
and rather than veer from
and rather than veer from that
dedicated to truth and dedicated to God
and rather than veer from that he
and rather than veer from that he took
hemlock.
If
If he'd
hemlock.
If he'd lied
If he'd lied a
hemlock.
If he'd lied a little,
If he'd lied a little, if
hemlock.
If he'd lied a little, if he'd
If he'd lied a little, if he'd switched
to
to a
to a little
to a little rhetoric,
to a little rhetoric, he
to a little rhetoric, he could
to a little rhetoric, he could have
gotten
gotten out
to a little rhetoric, he could have
gotten out of
gotten out of it.
to a little rhetoric, he could have
gotten out of it. And
gotten out of it. And they
to a little rhetoric, he could have
gotten out of it. And they told
gotten out of it. And they told him
to a little rhetoric, he could have
gotten out of it. And they told him so.
He
He refused
He refused because
He refused because he
He refused because he felt
He refused because he felt it
He refused because he felt it would
He refused because he felt it would deny
the
the value
He refused because he felt it would deny
the value and
the value and purpose
He refused because he felt it would deny
the value and purpose of
the value and purpose of his
He refused because he felt it would deny
the value and purpose of his life.
There
There 350
There 350 years
There 350 years before
There 350 years before the
There 350 years before the birth
There 350 years before the birth of
Christ
Christ and
There 350 years before the birth of
Christ and completely
Christ and completely separated
There 350 years before the birth of
Christ and completely separated from
Christ and completely separated from the
east
east and
east and Buddhism.
east and Buddhism. How
east and Buddhism. How was
east and Buddhism. How was it
east and Buddhism. How was it that
Socrates
Socrates was
east and Buddhism. How was it that
Socrates was so
Socrates was so committed
east and Buddhism. How was it that
Socrates was so committed to
Socrates was so committed to God
east and Buddhism. How was it that
Socrates was so committed to God and
Socrates was so committed to God and to
the
the truth
the truth of
the truth of God?
the truth of God? How
the truth of God? How could
the truth of God? How could he
the truth of God? How could he be
the truth of God? How could he be such
the truth of God? How could he be such a
profound
profound theist?
the truth of God? How could he be such a
profound theist? because
profound theist? because the
the truth of God? How could he be such a
profound theist? because the Greek
profound theist? because the Greek gods
like
like the
like the Roman
like the Roman gods
like the Roman gods were
um
um secular
like the Roman gods were
um secular figures
um secular figures really.
like the Roman gods were
um secular figures really. So
um secular figures really. So how
like the Roman gods were
um secular figures really. So how did
Socrates
Socrates come
Socrates come to
Socrates come to that
Socrates come to that great
Socrates come to that great area
edition?
edition? We'll
Socrates come to that great area
edition? We'll see
edition? We'll see later
set
set the
set the paradigm
set the paradigm of
set the paradigm of intellectual
set the paradigm of intellectual truth
for
for all
set the paradigm of intellectual truth
for all time.
for all time. Intellectual
set the paradigm of intellectual truth
for all time. Intellectual truth
for all time. Intellectual truth and
set the paradigm of intellectual truth
for all time. Intellectual truth and its
pristine
pristine expressions
pristine expressions is
pristine expressions is around
pristine expressions is around 460
and
and 455
pristine expressions is around 460
and 455 460.
490 and
490 and up
490 and up is
490 and up is genius
490 and up is genius and
490 and up is genius and not
490 and up is genius and not many
490 and up is genius and not many people
can
can follow
490 and up is genius and not many people
can follow genius.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So of
All right. So of usefulness
All right. So of usefulness to
All right. So of usefulness to western
man.
of
of useful
of useful of
of useful of usefulness
of useful of usefulness to
of useful of usefulness to western
of useful of usefulness to western man.
We
We have
of useful of usefulness to western man.
We have already
We have already a
of useful of usefulness to western man.
We have already a paradigm
We have already a paradigm of
of useful of usefulness to western man.
We have already a paradigm of the
capacity
capacity of
capacity of the
capacity of the intellect
capacity of the intellect set
capacity of the intellect set out
capacity of the intellect set out and
historically
historically tested
capacity of the intellect set out and
historically tested over
historically tested over hund
capacity of the intellect set out and
historically tested over hund you
historically tested over hund you know
many
many centuries.
many centuries. So
many centuries. So it
many centuries. So it isn't
many centuries. So it isn't like
many centuries. So it isn't like last
week's
week's editorial
many centuries. So it isn't like last
week's editorial page.
week's editorial page. This
many centuries. So it isn't like last
week's editorial page. This has
week's editorial page. This has stood
this
this test
this test of
this test of time
this test of time and
this test of time and the
this test of time and the rigors
this test of time and the rigors of
academic
academic demand
this test of time and the rigors of
academic demand and
academic demand and the
dialectic
dialectic the
dialectic the dialectic
dialectic the dialectic of
dialectic the dialectic of reason
dialectic the dialectic of reason and
intellect
intellect following
dialectic the dialectic of reason and
intellect following the
intellect following the rules
dialectic the dialectic of reason and
intellect following the rules of
intellect following the rules of logic.
Yeah,
Yeah, setting
Yeah, setting up
Yeah, setting up categories
Yeah, setting up categories of
Yeah, setting up categories of of
thought
thought and
Yeah, setting up categories of of
thought and of
thought and of course
Yeah, setting up categories of of
thought and of course the
thought and of course the difficulty
with
with current
with current thinking
with current thinking is
with current thinking is the
with current thinking is the collapse
mixing
mixing levels
with current thinking is the collapse
mixing levels and
mixing levels and mixing
with current thinking is the collapse
mixing levels and mixing levels
mixing levels and mixing levels and
with current thinking is the collapse
mixing levels and mixing levels and by
not
not staying
not staying within
not staying within a
not staying within a level
not staying within a level then
not staying within a level then it
sounds
sounds good
not staying within a level then it
sounds good but
sounds good but it's
not staying within a level then it
sounds good but it's facious.
sounds good but it's facious. Yeah.
Sounds
Sounds convincing
Sounds convincing but
Sounds convincing but it's
Sounds convincing but it's facious.
Sounds convincing but it's facious. All
right.
right. So
Sounds convincing but it's facious. All
right. So here
right. So here these
Sounds convincing but it's facious. All
right. So here these are
right. So here these are people
Sounds convincing but it's facious. All
right. So here these are people of
course
course who
course who are
course who are who
course who are who deserve
course who are who deserve respect
course who are who deserve respect to
the
the best
course who are who deserve respect to
the best best
the best best thinkers
course who are who deserve respect to
the best best thinkers over
the best best thinkers over all
course who are who deserve respect to
the best best thinkers over all of
the best best thinkers over all of time
and
and the
and the great
and the great books
and the great books of
and the great books of the
and the great books of the western
and the great books of the western world
of
of which
and the great books of the western world
of which I've
of which I've spoken
and the great books of the western world
of which I've spoken before.
of which I've spoken before. I
and the great books of the western world
of which I've spoken before. I had
of which I've spoken before. I had the
good
good fortune
good fortune to
good fortune to fall
good fortune to fall in
good fortune to fall in a
good fortune to fall in a fall
good fortune to fall in a fall into
good fortune to fall in a fall into a
used
used set
good fortune to fall in a fall into a
used set of
used set of them.
good fortune to fall in a fall into a
used set of them. I
used set of them. I forget
good fortune to fall in a fall into a
used set of them. I forget when
used set of them. I forget when they
came
came out.
came out. I
came out. I think
came out. I think back
came out. I think back in
came out. I think back in the
came out. I think back in the 50s
came out. I think back in the 50s and
came out. I think back in the 50s and it
was
was out
came out. I think back in the 50s and it
was out of
was out of the
came out. I think back in the 50s and it
was out of the University
was out of the University of
came out. I think back in the 50s and it
was out of the University of Chicago
was out of the University of Chicago and
the
the best
the best thinkers,
the best thinkers, academic
the best thinkers, academic thinkers
the best thinkers, academic thinkers of
the
the world
the best thinkers, academic thinkers of
the world congregated
the world congregated and
the best thinkers, academic thinkers of
the world congregated and spent
the world congregated and spent a
the best thinkers, academic thinkers of
the world congregated and spent a great
deal
deal of
deal of time
deal of time deciding
deal of time deciding which
deal of time deciding which book
deal of time deciding which book should
be
be included,
deal of time deciding which book should
be included, which
be included, which book
deal of time deciding which book should
be included, which book should
be included, which book should be
included
included in
included in the
included in the great
included in the great books
included in the great books of
included in the great books of the
western
western world.
included in the great books of the
western world. So
western world. So I
included in the great books of the
western world. So I have
western world. So I have a
included in the great books of the
western world. So I have a certain
respect
respect because
respect because it's
respect because it's the
respect because it's the it's
respect because it's the it's the
respect because it's the it's the best
of
of the
respect because it's the it's the best
of the intellect
of the intellect over
respect because it's the it's the best
of the intellect over the
of the intellect over the centuries
respect because it's the it's the best
of the intellect over the centuries and
we
we see
we see that
we see that collectively
we see that collectively uh
we see that collectively uh collectively
the
the great
we see that collectively uh collectively
the great books
the great books of
we see that collectively uh collectively
the great books of the
the great books of the western
we see that collectively uh collectively
the great books of the western world
the great books of the western world uh
celebrate
celebrate I
celebrate I think
celebrate I think uh
celebrate I think uh as
celebrate I think uh as they
celebrate I think uh as they are
celebrate I think uh as they are on
celebrate I think uh as they are on the
screen
screen calibrate
celebrate I think uh as they are on the
screen calibrate around
screen calibrate around 450
celebrate I think uh as they are on the
screen calibrate around 450 but
screen calibrate around 450 but if
celebrate I think uh as they are on the
screen calibrate around 450 but if you
remove
remove uh
remove uh one
remove uh one who
remove uh one who calibrates
remove uh one who calibrates at
remove uh one who calibrates at 130
remove uh one who calibrates at 130 then
they
they jump
remove uh one who calibrates at 130 then
they jump to
they jump to 465
which
which is
which is very
which is very impressive
which is very impressive right
which is very impressive right 465
is
is an
which is very impressive right 465
is an impressive
is an impressive calibration
which is very impressive right 465
is an impressive calibration of
intellectual
intellectual integrity.
intellectual integrity. It's
intellectual integrity. It's about
intellectual integrity. It's about what
the
the intellect
intellectual integrity. It's about what
the intellect can
the intellect can do.
intellectual integrity. It's about what
the intellect can do. So
the intellect can do. So we
intellectual integrity. It's about what
the intellect can do. So we have
the intellect can do. So we have the
great
great thinkers
great thinkers of
great thinkers of all
great thinkers of all time.
great thinkers of all time. Thomas
Aquinus
Aquinus we
great thinkers of all time. Thomas
Aquinus we know
Aquinus we know all
great thinkers of all time. Thomas
Aquinus we know all these
Aquinus we know all these names.
Archimedes
Archimedes principle
Archimedes principle Aristophanes
Aristotle
Aristotle at
Aristotle at 498
not
not quite
Aristotle at 498
not quite Socrates.
Uh
Uh Augustine
Uh Augustine however
Uh Augustine however jumps
Uh Augustine however jumps the
Uh Augustine however jumps the 500
Uh Augustine however jumps the 500 level
to
to 503
Uh Augustine however jumps the 500 level
to 503 St.
to 503 St. Augustine.
Uh
Uh Marcus
Uh Marcus Aurelius
Uh Marcus Aurelius as
Uh Marcus Aurelius as I
Uh Marcus Aurelius as I say
Uh Marcus Aurelius as I say signs
Uh Marcus Aurelius as I say signs of
Uh Marcus Aurelius as I say signs of a
misspent
misspent youth.
Uh Marcus Aurelius as I say signs of a
misspent youth. I
misspent youth. I used
Uh Marcus Aurelius as I say signs of a
misspent youth. I used to
misspent youth. I used to sit
Uh Marcus Aurelius as I say signs of a
misspent youth. I used to sit there
misspent youth. I used to sit there and
read
read the
read the apherisms
read the apherisms of
read the apherisms of Marcus
read the apherisms of Marcus Aurelius.
Poor
Poor boy.
read the apherisms of Marcus Aurelius.
Poor boy. I
Poor boy. I don't
read the apherisms of Marcus Aurelius.
Poor boy. I don't know
Poor boy. I don't know Marcus
read the apherisms of Marcus Aurelius.
Poor boy. I don't know Marcus Aurelius.
Anyway,
Anyway, great
Anyway, great apherisms.
Anyway, great apherisms. Francis
Anyway, great apherisms. Francis Bacon
the
the great
Anyway, great apherisms. Francis Bacon
the great genius.
the great genius. Berkeley,
Boswell,
Boswell, Shasser,
Boswell, Shasser, Cap,
Boswell, Shasser, Cap, Capernicus,
Boswell, Shasser, Cap, Capernicus, who
upset
upset the
Boswell, Shasser, Cap, Capernicus, who
upset the world
upset the world by
Boswell, Shasser, Cap, Capernicus, who
upset the world by telling
upset the world by telling the
Boswell, Shasser, Cap, Capernicus, who
upset the world by telling the truth.
upset the world by telling the truth. Uh
he
he was
he was not
he was not popular
he was not popular for
he was not popular for a
he was not popular for a while
he was not popular for a while anymore
than
than was
he was not popular for a while anymore
than was Galileo.
than was Galileo. U
because
because people
because people have
because people have a
because people have a fixed
because people have a fixed idea
because people have a fixed idea of
things
things and
because people have a fixed idea of
things and you
things and you can
because people have a fixed idea of
things and you can see
things and you can see that
because people have a fixed idea of
things and you can see that the
things and you can see that the truth
was
was not
was not too
was not too welcome.
Fact,
Fact, the
was not too welcome.
Fact, the church
Fact, the church didn't
was not too welcome.
Fact, the church didn't forgive
Fact, the church didn't forgive Galileo
for
for 450
for 450 years.
Guess
Guess it
for 450 years.
Guess it was
Guess it was poed,
for 450 years.
Guess it was poed, huh?
450 years.
We're
We're saying
450 years.
We're saying things
We're saying things of
450 years.
We're saying things of course
We're saying things of course in
450 years.
We're saying things of course in these
uh
uh rooms,
uh rooms, you
uh rooms, you know,
uh rooms, you know, that
uh rooms, you know, that are
uh rooms, you know, that are the
actually
actually the
uh rooms, you know, that are the
actually the equivalent,
actually the equivalent, you
uh rooms, you know, that are the
actually the equivalent, you know,
actually the equivalent, you know, that
what
what half
what half the
what half the world
what half the world believes
what half the world believes is
what half the world believes is facious.
Half
Half what
what half the world believes is facious.
Half what half
Half what half the
what half the world believes is facious.
Half what half the people
Half what half the people in
what half the world believes is facious.
Half what half the people in America
believe
believe is
believe is facious.
believe is facious. Half
believe is facious. Half of
believe is facious. Half of America
believe is facious. Half of America is
below
below 200.
believe is facious. Half of America is
below 200. And
below 200. And what
believe is facious. Half of America is
below 200. And what 85%
below 200. And what 85% of
believe is facious. Half of America is
below 200. And what 85% of the
below 200. And what 85% of the world
dedicates
dedicates it
dedicates it to
dedicates it to is
dedicates it to is also
dedicates it to is also fallacy.
Therefore,
Therefore, some
dedicates it to is also fallacy.
Therefore, some of
Therefore, some of the
dedicates it to is also fallacy.
Therefore, some of the things
Therefore, some of the things we
dedicates it to is also fallacy.
Therefore, some of the things we talk
about
about and
about and especially
about and especially in
about and especially in this
about and especially in this forthcoming
book
book will
about and especially in this forthcoming
book will be
book will be about
about and especially in this forthcoming
book will be about as
book will be about as welcome
about and especially in this forthcoming
book will be about as welcome as
Galileo.
Oh,
Oh, lordy.
Galileo.
Oh, lordy. All right.
Oh, lordy. All right. So,
Galileo.
Oh, lordy. All right. So, now
Oh, lordy. All right. So, now we've
Galileo.
Oh, lordy. All right. So, now we've got
um
um Dante
um Dante whose
um Dante whose knowledge
um Dante whose knowledge of
um Dante whose knowledge of the
um Dante whose knowledge of the level
um Dante whose knowledge of the level of
hell
hell was
um Dante whose knowledge of the level of
hell was shocking.
hell was shocking. I
um Dante whose knowledge of the level of
hell was shocking. I don't
hell was shocking. I don't know
um Dante whose knowledge of the level of
hell was shocking. I don't know that
hell was shocking. I don't know that he
knew
knew that
knew that how
knew that how he
knew that how he knew
knew that how he knew that.
knew that how he knew that. I
knew that how he knew that. I still
haven't
haven't had
knew that how he knew that. I still
haven't had a
haven't had a chance
knew that how he knew that. I still
haven't had a chance to
haven't had a chance to investigate
knew that how he knew that. I still
haven't had a chance to investigate it
because
because there
because there is
because there is the
because there is the level
because there is the level that
because there is the level that says
abandon
abandon all
because there is the level that says
abandon all hope
abandon all hope forever.
because there is the level that says
abandon all hope forever. Forever
abandon all hope forever. Forever more.
You
You get
You get what
You get what forever
You get what forever means.
You get what forever means. And
You get what forever means. And then
You get what forever means. And then the
dread
dread hits
You get what forever means. And then the
dread hits a
dread hits a depth
You get what forever means. And then the
dread hits a depth you
dread hits a depth you never
You get what forever means. And then the
dread hits a depth you never dreamed
dread hits a depth you never dreamed of.
Forever.
Forever. You
Forever. You get
Forever. You get what
Forever. You get what forever
Forever. You get what forever means.
Forever. You get what forever means. So
then
then along
Forever. You get what forever means. So
then along comes
then along comes Darwin.
Forever. You get what forever means. So
then along comes Darwin. The
then along comes Darwin. The Darwinian
theory
theory of
theory of evolution.
theory of evolution. And
theory of evolution. And of
theory of evolution. And of course
theory of evolution. And of course what
we
we say
theory of evolution. And of course what
we say is
we say is that
theory of evolution. And of course what
we say is that evolution
we say is that evolution and
theory of evolution. And of course what
we say is that evolution and uh
we say is that evolution and uh creation
are
are one
are one and
are one and the
are one and the same
are one and the same thing.
are one and the same thing. So
are one and the same thing. So Darwinian
theory
theory calibrates
are one and the same thing. So Darwinian
theory calibrates around
theory calibrates around 450.
are one and the same thing. So Darwinian
theory calibrates around 450. That's
theory calibrates around 450. That's the
idea
idea of
idea of causality.
idea of causality. Uh
idea of causality. Uh something
idea of causality. Uh something is
causing
causing something
idea of causality. Uh something is
causing something else.
The
The only
The only thing
The only thing lacking
The only thing lacking with
The only thing lacking with that,
and
and I
The only thing lacking with that,
and I would
and I would wonder
The only thing lacking with that,
and I would wonder why
and I would wonder why Darwinius
The only thing lacking with that,
and I would wonder why Darwinius don't
notice
notice that,
notice that, is
notice that, is that
notice that, is that there
notice that, is that there aren't
notice that, is that there aren't any
missing
missing links
notice that, is that there aren't any
missing links out
missing links out there.
There
There aren't
There aren't any.
There aren't any. So,
There aren't any. So, you
There aren't any. So, you go
There aren't any. So, you go from
There aren't any. So, you go from u
Neanderthal
Neanderthal man
There aren't any. So, you go from u
Neanderthal man and
Neanderthal man and then
There aren't any. So, you go from u
Neanderthal man and then there's
Neanderthal man and then there's nothing
till
till you
till you get
till you get to
till you get to Homoctus
till you get to Homoctus and
till you get to Homoctus and then
there's
there's nothing
till you get to Homoctus and then
there's nothing until
there's nothing until you
till you get to Homoctus and then
there's nothing until you get
there's nothing until you get to
Highleberg
Highleberg man
Highleberg man and
Highleberg man and there's
Highleberg man and there's nothing
the
the same
Highleberg man and there's nothing
the same in
the same in the
Highleberg man and there's nothing
the same in the animal
the same in the animal kingdom.
Highleberg man and there's nothing
the same in the animal kingdom. And
the same in the animal kingdom. And you
don't
don't see
don't see what's
don't see what's already
don't see what's already in
don't see what's already in form
evolving
evolving within
don't see what's already in form
evolving within form
evolving within form to
don't see what's already in form
evolving within form to become
evolving within form to become a
different
different form.
different form. It
different form. It goes
different form. It goes out
different form. It goes out of
different form. It goes out of form,
reemerges
reemerges in
different form. It goes out of form,
reemerges in a
reemerges in a new
different form. It goes out of form,
reemerges in a new form.
reemerges in a new form. And
different form. It goes out of form,
reemerges in a new form. And therefore
all
all that
all that is
all that is happening
all that is happening on
all that is happening on the
all that is happening on the level
all that is happening on the level of
consciousness.
consciousness. So
all that is happening on the level of
consciousness. So creation
consciousness. So creation and
creativity
creativity is
creativity is coming
creativity is coming out
creativity is coming out of
and
and I
creativity is coming out of
and I can
and I can never
creativity is coming out of
and I can never think
and I can never think of
creativity is coming out of
and I can never think of his
and I can never think of his name
causitive
causitive formation
causitive formation or
causitive formation or what
causitive formation or what formative
causation.
Well
Well we
Well we can
Well we can do
Well we can do without
Well we can do without the
Well we can do without the left
Well we can do without the left brain
but
but not
Well we can do without the left brain
but not really
but not really well
Well we can do without the left brain
but not really well and
but not really well and you're
Well we can do without the left brain
but not really well and you're lecturing
go
go back
go back to
go back to where
go back to where you
go back to where you were.
>> What's
>> What's his
go back to where you were.
>> What's his name?
>> What's his name? Formative
go back to where you were.
>> What's his name? Formative causation.
Huh?
>> Sheldrake.
>> Sheldrake. There
Huh?
>> Sheldrake. There you
>> Sheldrake. There you go.
>> I
>> I don't
>> I don't know
>> I don't know why
>> I don't know why I
>> I don't know why I can't
>> I don't know why I can't remember
Sheldrake.
Sheldrake. I
>> I don't know why I can't remember
Sheldrake. I should
Sheldrake. I should put
>> I don't know why I can't remember
Sheldrake. I should put a
Sheldrake. I should put a shell
>> I don't know why I can't remember
Sheldrake. I should put a shell on
Sheldrake. I should put a shell on my
shoe
shoe when
shoe when I'm
shoe when I'm lecturing
shoe when I'm lecturing it.
shoe when I'm lecturing it. Sheldrake.
There
There you
shoe when I'm lecturing it. Sheldrake.
There you go.
Sheldrake's
Sheldrake's form
Sheldrake's form of
Sheldrake's form of causation.
Sheldrake's form of causation. So
Sheldrake's form of causation. So he
Sheldrake's form of causation. So he saw
that
that that.
Sheldrake's form of causation. So he saw
that that. So
that that. So what
Sheldrake's form of causation. So he saw
that that. So what happens
that that. So what happens is
Sheldrake's form of causation. So he saw
that that. So what happens is a
that that. So what happens is a group
has
has a
has a group
has a group energy
has a group energy and
has a group energy and it's
has a group energy and it's the
has a group energy and it's the group
energy
energy the
has a group energy and it's the group
energy the attractor
energy the attractor field
has a group energy and it's the group
energy the attractor field of
energy the attractor field of the
has a group energy and it's the group
energy the attractor field of the the
group
group that
group that learns
group that learns because
group that learns because when
group that learns because when you
group that learns because when you think
of
of it
group that learns because when you think
of it whatever
of it whatever you've
group that learns because when you think
of it whatever you've learned
of it whatever you've learned is
group that learns because when you think
of it whatever you've learned is going
to
to die.
to die. You
to die. You and
to die. You and your
to die. You and your genes
to die. You and your genes are
to die. You and your genes are all
to die. You and your genes are all going
to
to die
to die. You and your genes are all going
to die in
to die in your
to die. You and your genes are all going
to die in your chromosomes
to die in your chromosomes and
to die. You and your genes are all going
to die in your chromosomes and your
to die in your chromosomes and your DNA.
So
So what
So what you've
So what you've learned
So what you've learned you
So what you've learned you can't
transmit
transmit to
So what you've learned you can't
transmit to the
transmit to the next
So what you've learned you can't
transmit to the next generation
transmit to the next generation because
you
you just
you just took
you just took it
you just took it with
you just took it with you.
So
So how
you just took it with you.
So how is
So how is it
you just took it with you.
So how is it a
So how is it a species
you just took it with you.
So how is it a species learns?
So how is it a species learns? Because
there's
there's a
there's a group
there's a group consciousness.
there's a group consciousness. So
there's a group consciousness. So the
experience
experience of
there's a group consciousness. So the
experience of this
is
is shared
is shared with
is shared with the
is shared with the group
is shared with the group and
is shared with the group and then
is shared with the group and then the
intelligence
intelligence moves
is shared with the group and then the
intelligence moves from
intelligence moves from there.
is shared with the group and then the
intelligence moves from there. It
intelligence moves from there. It builds
on
on that
on that and
on that and the
on that and the next
on that and the next thing
on that and the next thing emerges
on that and the next thing emerges fully
formed.
formed. Neanderthal
on that and the next thing emerges fully
formed. Neanderthal man
formed. Neanderthal man doesn't
on that and the next thing emerges fully
formed. Neanderthal man doesn't evolve
from
from primitive
from primitive Neanderthal
from primitive Neanderthal man
from primitive Neanderthal man to
from primitive Neanderthal man to more
mature
mature Neanderthal
from primitive Neanderthal man to more
mature Neanderthal man.
mature Neanderthal man. He
from primitive Neanderthal man to more
mature Neanderthal man. He just
mature Neanderthal man. He just comes
out
out as
out as Neanderthal
out as Neanderthal man
out as Neanderthal man and
out as Neanderthal man and stays
out as Neanderthal man and stays there.
Then
Then he
out as Neanderthal man and stays there.
Then he disappears
Then he disappears into
out as Neanderthal man and stays there.
Then he disappears into the
Then he disappears into the branch
out as Neanderthal man and stays there.
Then he disappears into the branch of
the
the tree
the tree and
the tree and then
the tree and then he
the tree and then he reemer.
the tree and then he reemer. So
the tree and then he reemer. So the
energy
energy of
the tree and then he reemer. So the
energy of homo
energy of homo sapiion
the tree and then he reemer. So the
energy of homo sapiion emerges
energy of homo sapiion emerges then
sequentially.
sequentially. So
sequentially. So there
sequentially. So there you
sequentially. So there you see
sequentially. So there you see creation,
evolution
evolution as
sequentially. So there you see creation,
evolution as a
evolution as a contrast.
sequentially. So there you see creation,
evolution as a contrast. Um
evolution as a contrast. Um all
sequentially. So there you see creation,
evolution as a contrast. Um all right.
So
So Darwin
So Darwin then
So Darwin then gave
So Darwin then gave us
So Darwin then gave us something
So Darwin then gave us something to
argue
argue about
So Darwin then gave us something to
argue about and
argue about and of
So Darwin then gave us something to
argue about and of course
argue about and of course it's
interesting
interesting what
interesting what goes
interesting what goes on
interesting what goes on in
interesting what goes on in the
interesting what goes on in the schools
about
about that
interesting what goes on in the schools
about that whether
about that whether it's
whether
whether it's
whether it's um
whether it's um politically
whether it's um politically correct
whether it's um politically correct to
present
present to
whether it's um politically correct to
present to the
present to the students
whether it's um politically correct to
present to the students that
present to the students that there
whether it's um politically correct to
present to the students that there is
present to the students that there is an
alternate
alternate theory
alternate theory called
alternate theory called uh
alternate theory called uh creation.
Uh
Uh Dastesi
alternate theory called uh creation.
Uh Dastesi Engles
Uh Dastesi Engles linked
alternate theory called uh creation.
Uh Dastesi Engles linked up
Uh Dastesi Engles linked up with
alternate theory called uh creation.
Uh Dastesi Engles linked up with Marx
and
and you
and you see
and you see he's
and you see he's wishy-washy.
and you see he's wishy-washy. He's
and you see he's wishy-washy. He's at
200.
200. So
and you see he's wishy-washy. He's at
200. So you
200. So you could
and you see he's wishy-washy. He's at
200. So you could really
200. So you could really tip
and you see he's wishy-washy. He's at
200. So you could really tip him
200. So you could really tip him either
way.
I
I could
way.
I could persuade
I could persuade Engles
way.
I could persuade Engles to
I could persuade Engles to go
way.
I could persuade Engles to go this
I could persuade Engles to go this way
and
and somebody
and somebody else
and somebody else could
and somebody else could persuade
and somebody else could persuade him
and somebody else could persuade him to
go
go another
and somebody else could persuade him to
go another way.
go another way. So
and somebody else could persuade him to
go another way. So 200
go another way. So 200 is
and somebody else could persuade him to
go another way. So 200 is you
go another way. So 200 is you still
and somebody else could persuade him to
go another way. So 200 is you still have
maybe
maybe a
maybe a few
maybe a few decisions
maybe a few decisions to
maybe a few decisions to make.
maybe a few decisions to make. You'd
maybe a few decisions to make. You'd be
a
a little
maybe a few decisions to make. You'd be
a little safer
a little safer over
maybe a few decisions to make. You'd be
a little safer over 200.
a little safer over 200. Then
maybe a few decisions to make. You'd be
a little safer over 200. Then you
a little safer over 200. Then you have
Uklid,
Uklid, you
Uklid, you know,
Uklid, you know, the
Uklid, you know, the great
Uklid, you know, the great names
Uklid, you know, the great names Faraday
Fielding
Fielding uh
Uklid, you know, the great names Faraday
Fielding uh for
Fielding uh for your
Uklid, you know, the great names Faraday
Fielding uh for your electricity.
Fielding uh for your electricity. Sigman
Freud
Freud at
Freud at 499.
Sigman
Sigman Freud
Freud at 499.
Sigman Freud at
Sigman Freud at 499.
Freud at 499.
Sigman Freud at 499. And
Sigman Freud at 499. And of
Freud at 499.
Sigman Freud at 499. And of course,
we've
we've already
we've already discussed
we've already discussed Freud
we've already discussed Freud when
we've already discussed Freud when he
showed
showed that
we've already discussed Freud when he
showed that the
showed that the negative
we've already discussed Freud when he
showed that the negative depictions
showed that the negative depictions of
God
God were
God were facious
God were facious and
God were facious and projections
God were facious and projections from
the
the unconscious,
God were facious and projections from
the unconscious, the
the unconscious, the cruel,
God were facious and projections from
the unconscious, the cruel, punitive,
punishing
punishing God.
punishing God. Uh
punishing God. Uh Freud
punishing God. Uh Freud um
was
was helpful
punishing God. Uh Freud um
was helpful in
was helpful in resolving
punishing God. Uh Freud um
was helpful in resolving that.
was helpful in resolving that. However,
he
he then
he then came
he then came when
he then came when he
he then came when he concluded
he then came when he concluded that
there
there was
he then came when he concluded that
there was false
there was false gods
he then came when he concluded that
there was false gods don't
there was false gods don't exist,
he then came when he concluded that
there was false gods don't exist, he
then
then made
then made the
then made the illogical
then made the illogical jump.
then made the illogical jump. Therefore,
the
the true
then made the illogical jump. Therefore,
the true one
the true one doesn't.
then made the illogical jump. Therefore,
the true one doesn't. That's
the true one doesn't. That's that
then made the illogical jump. Therefore,
the true one doesn't. That's that you
know
know the
know the facious
know the facious god
know the facious god we
know the facious god we agree
know the facious god we agree but
know the facious god we agree but you
can't
can't jump
know the facious god we agree but you
can't jump from
can't jump from there
know the facious god we agree but you
can't jump from there god
can't jump from there god no
know the facious god we agree but you
can't jump from there god no felacious
god
god exists
god exists that
god exists that a
god exists that a true
god exists that a true god
god exists that a true god doesn't
god exists that a true god doesn't yeah
anyway
anyway so
god exists that a true god doesn't yeah
anyway so freud
anyway so freud is
god exists that a true god doesn't yeah
anyway so freud is at
anyway so freud is at 499
god exists that a true god doesn't yeah
anyway so freud is at 499 and
anyway so freud is at 499 and there
god exists that a true god doesn't yeah
anyway so freud is at 499 and there you
see
see Galileo
and
and all
see Galileo
and all the
and all the great
see Galileo
and all the great names
and all the great names in
see Galileo
and all the great names in history
and all the great names in history gate
um
um all
um all the
um all the great
um all the great inventors
um all the great inventors hypocrates
the
the father
um all the great inventors hypocrates
the father of
the father of medicine
um all the great inventors hypocrates
the father of medicine at
the father of medicine at 485
um all the great inventors hypocrates
the father of medicine at 485 who
emphasized
emphasized holistic
emphasized holistic health
emphasized holistic health so
emphasized holistic health so it's
emphasized holistic health so it's not
exactly
exactly new
emphasized holistic health so it's not
exactly new on
exactly new on the
emphasized holistic health so it's not
exactly new on the planet
exactly new on the planet Nicolistic
health
health was
health was the
health was the established
health was the established in
health was the established in fact
health was the established in fact the
primary
primary mode
health was the established in fact the
primary mode of
primary mode of healing
health was the established in fact the
primary mode of healing uh
primary mode of healing uh established
by
by Hypocrates
by Hypocrates thousands
by Hypocrates thousands of
by Hypocrates thousands of years
by Hypocrates thousands of years ago.
You
You see
by Hypocrates thousands of years ago.
You see Homer
You see Homer and
by Hypocrates thousands of years ago.
You see Homer and you
You see Homer and you see
by Hypocrates thousands of years ago.
You see Homer and you see there's
You see Homer and you see there's one
name
name they
name they forgot
name they forgot to
name they forgot to put
name they forgot to put in
name they forgot to put in here.
name they forgot to put in here. I
name they forgot to put in here. I would
have
have helped
name they forgot to put in here. I would
have helped them
have helped them out
name they forgot to put in here. I would
have helped them out but
have helped them out but they
name they forgot to put in here. I would
have helped them out but they didn't
have helped them out but they didn't ask
me.
me. I
me. I would
me. I would have
me. I would have put
me. I would have put Hegel
me. I would have put Hegel in
me. I would have put Hegel in there.
me. I would have put Hegel in there. Is
Hegel
Hegel in
me. I would have put Hegel in there. Is
Hegel in there?
Hegel in there? Oh,
me. I would have put Hegel in there. Is
Hegel in there? Oh, he
Hegel in there? Oh, he is
me. I would have put Hegel in there. Is
Hegel in there? Oh, he is Hegel
Hegel in there? Oh, he is Hegel is
there.
there. Yeah,
there. Yeah, Hegel
there. Yeah, Hegel is
there. Yeah, Hegel is there.
there. Yeah, Hegel is there. It's
important
important because
there. Yeah, Hegel is there. It's
important because he
important because he was
there. Yeah, Hegel is there. It's
important because he was a
important because he was a predominant
the
the father
the father really
the father really of
the father really of philosophy
the father really of philosophy in
Germany.
Germany. The
the father really of philosophy in
Germany. The German
Germany. The German school
the father really of philosophy in
Germany. The German school of
Germany. The German school of philosophy
was
was very
was very strong.
was very strong. It
was very strong. It was
was very strong. It was the
was very strong. It was the predominant
school
school of
was very strong. It was the predominant
school of philosophy
school of philosophy and
was very strong. It was the predominant
school of philosophy and Hegel
school of philosophy and Hegel was
was very strong. It was the predominant
school of philosophy and Hegel was the
authority
authority figure
which
which we'll
authority figure
which we'll come
which we'll come to
authority figure
which we'll come to later.
which we'll come to later. And
authority figure
which we'll come to later. And basic
which we'll come to later. And basic to
Hegel's
Hegel's philosophy
Hegel's philosophy is
Hegel's philosophy is the
Hegel's philosophy is the principle
Hegel's philosophy is the principle of
the
the absolute
that
that there
that there is
that there is an
that there is an absolute
and
and experientially
that there is an absolute
and experientially there
and experientially there is
that there is an absolute
and experientially there is an
and experientially there is an absolute.
It
It is
It is absolute
It is absolute beyond
It is absolute beyond one's
It is absolute beyond one's conception
of
of the
It is absolute beyond one's conception
of the absolute.
It
It is
It is more
It is more absolute
It is more absolute than
It is more absolute than absolute.
It is more absolute than absolute. So
anyway
uh
uh that's
uh that's that's
uh that's that's plays
uh that's that's plays a
uh that's that's plays a part
uh that's that's plays a part later.
Uh
Uh you've
uh that's that's plays a part later.
Uh you've got
Uh you've got Homer,
uh that's that's plays a part later.
Uh you've got Homer, you've
Uh you've got Homer, you've got
uh that's that's plays a part later.
Uh you've got Homer, you've got Higgins,
you've
you've got
you've got all
you've got all the
you've got all the great
you've got all the great names.
you've got all the great names. William
James,
James, you
you've got all the great names. William
James, you know
James, you know who
uh
uh William
uh William James
uh William James at
uh William James at 490
uh William James at 490 very
uh William James at 490 very close
uh William James at 490 very close to
understanding
understanding spirituality,
uh William James at 490 very close to
understanding spirituality, the
varieties
varieties of
varieties of religious
varieties of religious experience
uh
uh is
varieties of religious experience
uh is a
uh is a classic
varieties of religious experience
uh is a classic textbook
uh is a classic textbook and
varieties of religious experience
uh is a classic textbook and he
describes
describes the
describes the spiritual
describes the spiritual experience
describes the spiritual experience as
ineffable.
ineffable. So
describes the spiritual experience as
ineffable. So at least
ineffable. So at least he's
describes the spiritual experience as
ineffable. So at least he's able
ineffable. So at least he's able to
contextualize
contextualize that
contextualize that it's
contextualize that it's not
contextualize that it's not within
contextualize that it's not within the
paradigm
paradigm of
contextualize that it's not within the
paradigm of science.
So
So that
So that was
So that was William
So that was William James
So that was William James can't
So that was William James can't set
So that was William James can't set up
of
of course
So that was William James can't set up
of course the
of course the the
So that was William James can't set up
of course the the categories
of course the the categories of
So that was William James can't set up
of course the the categories of thought
categories
categories of
categories of abstraction
categories of abstraction and
categories of abstraction and those
categories of abstraction and those are
what
what are
categories of abstraction and those are
what are violated
what are violated by
categories of abstraction and those are
what are violated by the
what are violated by the rhetoric
categories of abstraction and those are
what are violated by the rhetoric of
current
current politics
is
is to
current politics
is to violate
is to violate the
current politics
is to violate the basic
is to violate the basic uh
current politics
is to violate the basic uh tenants
is to violate the basic uh tenants of
current politics
is to violate the basic uh tenants of uh
logic.
logic. Yeah.
logic. Yeah. Then
logic. Yeah. Then we
logic. Yeah. Then we get
logic. Yeah. Then we get down
logic. Yeah. Then we get down to
machavelli
machavelli who
logic. Yeah. Then we get down to
machavelli who has
machavelli who has also
logic. Yeah. Then we get down to
machavelli who has also a
machavelli who has also a a
logic. Yeah. Then we get down to
machavelli who has also a a bad
machavelli who has also a a bad rep.
logic. Yeah. Then we get down to
machavelli who has also a a bad rep. And
then
then when
then when you
then when you get
then when you get down
then when you get down to
then when you get down to marks
then when you get down to marks uh
then when you get down to marks uh so
stunningly
stunningly in
then when you get down to marks uh so
stunningly in the
stunningly in the middle
then when you get down to marks uh so
stunningly in the middle of
stunningly in the middle of all
then when you get down to marks uh so
stunningly in the middle of all this
stunningly in the middle of all this is
130 130
130 130 what's
130 130 what's it
130 130 what's it doing
130 130 what's it doing in
130 130 what's it doing in the
130 130 what's it doing in the company
of
of 460
130 130 what's it doing in the company
of 460 I
of 460 I guess
130 130 what's it doing in the company
of 460 I guess for
of 460 I guess for historical
130 130 what's it doing in the company
of 460 I guess for historical because
of 460 I guess for historical because of
historical
historical importance
historical importance marks
historical importance marks is
historical importance marks is at
historical importance marks is at 130
however
however we
historical importance marks is at 130
however we see
however we see that
historical importance marks is at 130
however we see that it
however we see that it brings
historical importance marks is at 130
however we see that it brings down
however we see that it brings down the
calibration
calibration of
calibration of the
calibration of the great
calibration of the great books
calibration of the great books uh
generally
generally and
calibration of the great books uh
generally and but
generally and but we
calibration of the great books uh
generally and but we see
generally and but we see today
calibration of the great books uh
generally and but we see today people
think
think they're
think they're very
think they're very vguard
think they're very vguard you
think they're very vguard you know
think they're very vguard you know all
corrant
corrant and
think they're very vguard you know all
corrant and of
corrant and of course
think they're very vguard you know all
corrant and of course because
corrant and of course because they're
talking
talking about
talking about some
talking about some current
talking about some current v
talking about some current v variety
talking about some current v variety of
Marxism.
Marxism. Well,
talking about some current v variety of
Marxism. Well, Marxism
Marxism. Well, Marxism was
talking about some current v variety of
Marxism. Well, Marxism was a
Marxism. Well, Marxism was a big
talking about some current v variety of
Marxism. Well, Marxism was a big deal
back
back in
back in the
back in the mid
back in the mid 1800s
to
to being
back in the mid 1800s
to being a
to being a around
back in the mid 1800s
to being a around thinking
to being a around thinking you're
back in the mid 1800s
to being a around thinking you're at
to being a around thinking you're at the
front
front of
front of political
front of political thinking
front of political thinking when
front of political thinking when you
what
what all
front of political thinking when you
what all you're
what all you're talking
front of political thinking when you
what all you're talking about
what all you're talking about is
front of political thinking when you
what all you're talking about is some
variation
variation of
variation of Marxism.
Um
Um what's
variation of Marxism.
Um what's the
Um what's the downside
variation of Marxism.
Um what's the downside of
Um what's the downside of Marxism?
variation of Marxism.
Um what's the downside of Marxism? It's
um
um dualistic
um dualistic in
um dualistic in that
um dualistic in that it
um dualistic in that it divides
um dualistic in that it divides all
phenomena
into
into perpetrator
into perpetrator and
into perpetrator and victim.
into perpetrator and victim. It
into perpetrator and victim. It sees
perpetrator
perpetrator and
into perpetrator and victim. It sees
perpetrator and victim
perpetrator and victim in
into perpetrator and victim. It sees
perpetrator and victim in everything.
and
and projects
and projects that
and projects that onto
and projects that onto the
and projects that onto the world.
and projects that onto the world. So
res
res interna
and projects that onto the world. So
res interna is
res interna is the
and projects that onto the world. So
res interna is the distortion
res interna is the distortion of
and projects that onto the world. So
res interna is the distortion of the
dualistic
dualistic perception
dualistic perception of
dualistic perception of blame,
victim
and
and therefore
and therefore the
and therefore the basis
and therefore the basis of
and therefore the basis of hatred
and therefore the basis of hatred and
paranoia.
paranoia. So
and therefore the basis of hatred and
paranoia. So the
paranoia. So the reason
and therefore the basis of hatred and
paranoia. So the reason Markx
paranoia. So the reason Markx brings
and therefore the basis of hatred and
paranoia. So the reason Markx brings it
down
down so
down so far
down so far is
down so far is because
down so far is because this
down so far is because this is
down so far is because this is the
intellectualization
that
that justifies
blame
blame uh
that justifies
blame uh paranoia
the
the perpetrator
the perpetrator victim
the perpetrator victim module
the perpetrator victim module as
the perpetrator victim module as you
the perpetrator victim module as you see
if
if each
the perpetrator victim module as you see
if each thing
if each thing is
the perpetrator victim module as you see
if each thing is being
if each thing is being what
the perpetrator victim module as you see
if each thing is being what it
if each thing is being what it is
the perpetrator victim module as you see
if each thing is being what it is and
attracts
attracts to
attracts to it
attracts to it that
attracts to it that because
attracts to it that because like
attracts to it that because like you're
like
like a
attracts to it that because like you're
like a magnet
like a magnet attract
attracts to it that because like you're
like a magnet attract attracts
like a magnet attract attracts to
yourself
yourself then
yourself then the
yourself then the whole
yourself then the whole perpetrator
victim
victim mo
yourself then the whole perpetrator
victim mo model
uh
uh is
uh is erroneous
uh is erroneous and
uh is erroneous and facious
uh is erroneous and facious you
But
But this
uh is erroneous and facious you
But this sees
But this sees everything
uh is erroneous and facious you
But this sees everything as
But this sees everything as victim
uh is erroneous and facious you
But this sees everything as victim and
martyr.
martyr. And
martyr. And of
martyr. And of course
martyr. And of course that
martyr. And of course that sets
martyr. And of course that sets up
contention,
uh,
uh, distrust,
uh, distrust, uh,
uh, distrust, uh, revolution,
uh, distrust, uh, revolution, uh,
hatred,
hatred, blame,
uh, distrust, uh, revolution, uh,
hatred, blame, paranoia,
hatred, blame, paranoia, and
uh, distrust, uh, revolution, uh,
hatred, blame, paranoia, and war.
Because
Because all
Because all you
Because all you have
Because all you have to
Because all you have to do
Because all you have to do is
Because all you have to do is go
Because all you have to do is go into
perpetrator
perpetrator or
Because all you have to do is go into
perpetrator or victim
perpetrator or victim and
Because all you have to do is go into
perpetrator or victim and then
perpetrator or victim and then you
Because all you have to do is go into
perpetrator or victim and then you can
justify
exterminating
exterminating 6
justify
exterminating 6 million
exterminating 6 million people,
justify
exterminating 6 million people, killing
10 million
10 million people.
10 million people. The
10 million people. The Germans
10 million people. The Germans didn't
win
win the
10 million people. The Germans didn't
win the war,
win the war, so
10 million people. The Germans didn't
win the war, so they
win the war, so they deserve
10 million people. The Germans didn't
win the war, so they deserve to
win the war, so they deserve to lose.
10 million people. The Germans didn't
win the war, so they deserve to lose. So
as
as far
as far as
as far as Hitler
as far as Hitler was
as far as Hitler was concerned,
as far as Hitler was concerned, all
as far as Hitler was concerned, all the
people,
people, German
as far as Hitler was concerned, all the
people, German people
people, German people could
as far as Hitler was concerned, all the
people, German people could be
eliminated.
eliminated. You
eliminated. You know,
eliminated. You know, you
eliminated. You know, you get
eliminated. You know, you get the
justification
justification for
eliminated. You know, you get the
justification for jihad
because
because those
because those who
because those who are
because those who are not
because those who are not us
because those who are not us are
because those who are not us are the
enemy.
enemy. They
because those who are not us are the
enemy. They deserve
enemy. They deserve to
because those who are not us are the
enemy. They deserve to die.
enemy. They deserve to die. So
because those who are not us are the
enemy. They deserve to die. So Marxism
reflects
reflects the
reflects the worst
reflects the worst of
reflects the worst of the
reflects the worst of the downside
reflects the worst of the downside of
the
the mind.
reflects the worst of the downside of
the mind. Yeah.
the mind. Yeah. The
reflects the worst of the downside of
the mind. Yeah. The the
the mind. Yeah. The the most
reflects the worst of the downside of
the mind. Yeah. The the most serious
distortion
distortion because
distortion because it
distortion because it interferes
distortion because it interferes with
one's
one's capacity
distortion because it interferes with
one's capacity to
one's capacity to perceive
distortion because it interferes with
one's capacity to perceive reality.
Instead,
Instead, you
Instead, you see
Instead, you see a
Instead, you see a perceived
Instead, you see a perceived distortion
which
which you
Instead, you see a perceived distortion
which you projected
which you projected out
Instead, you see a perceived distortion
which you projected out there.
Perpetrator
Perpetrator victim
Perpetrator victim is
Perpetrator victim is rest
Perpetrator victim is rest intern.
That's
That's an
Perpetrator victim is rest intern.
That's an internalization.
It's
It's a
It's a something
It's a something you
It's a something you then
It's a something you then project
It's a something you then project onto
the
the world
It's a something you then project onto
the world because
the world because I
It's a something you then project onto
the world because I can
the world because I can look
It's a something you then project onto
the world because I can look out
the world because I can look out the
window
window and
window and see
window and see perpetrator
window and see perpetrator victim
anywhere
anywhere I
window and see perpetrator victim
anywhere I want
anywhere I want to
window and see perpetrator victim
anywhere I want to look.
anywhere I want to look. The
window and see perpetrator victim
anywhere I want to look. The big
anywhere I want to look. The big tree,
as
as you
as you can
as you can see,
as you can see, is
as you can see, is victimizing
as you can see, is victimizing the
as you can see, is victimizing the small
tree
tree because
as you can see, is victimizing the small
tree because it's
tree because it's standing
as you can see, is victimizing the small
tree because it's standing in
tree because it's standing in its
as you can see, is victimizing the small
tree because it's standing in its sun.
The
The small
The small tree
The small tree therefore
The small tree therefore should
The small tree therefore should sue
The small tree therefore should sue and
go
go to
The small tree therefore should sue and
go to the
go to the ninth
The small tree therefore should sue and
go to the ninth circuit
go to the ninth circuit court
The small tree therefore should sue and
go to the ninth circuit court of
go to the ninth circuit court of appeals
that
that its
that its rights
that its rights are
that its rights are being
that its rights are being interfered
with.
with. You
that its rights are being interfered
with. You see,
with. You see, so
that its rights are being interfered
with. You see, so you
with. You see, so you you
that its rights are being interfered
with. You see, so you you deal
with. You see, so you you deal in
fallacy
fallacy that
fallacy that reaches
fallacy that reaches the
fallacy that reaches the point
fallacy that reaches the point of
idiocy.
idiocy. So
fallacy that reaches the point of
idiocy. So Marxism
idiocy. So Marxism is
fallacy that reaches the point of
idiocy. So Marxism is not
idiocy. So Marxism is not a
fallacy that reaches the point of
idiocy. So Marxism is not a friend
idiocy. So Marxism is not a friend to
truth.
Um
Um Marx's
truth.
Um Marx's problem
Um Marx's problem was
truth.
Um Marx's problem was um
Um Marx's problem was um let's
truth.
Um Marx's problem was um let's see
Um Marx's problem was um let's see if
I'm
I'm holding
I'm holding it
I'm holding it if
I'm holding it if I
I'm holding it if I got
I'm holding it if I got it
I'm holding it if I got it right.
I
I got
I'm holding it if I got it right.
I got Marx's
I got Marx's problem.
I'm holding it if I got it right.
I got Marx's problem. It's
I got Marx's problem. It's correct.
Resist.
Resist. All
Resist. All right.
Resist. All right. Um,
Resist. All right. Um, you
Resist. All right. Um, you see,
Resist. All right. Um, you see, because
Hegel
Hegel was
Resist. All right. Um, you see, because
Hegel was the
Hegel was the father
Resist. All right. Um, you see, because
Hegel was the father figure,
Hegel was the father figure, so
Resist. All right. Um, you see, because
Hegel was the father figure, so how
people
people handle
people handle the
people handle the edible
people handle the edible complex,
people handle the edible complex, how
they
they handle
people handle the edible complex, how
they handle how
they handle how they
people handle the edible complex, how
they handle how they see
they handle how they see authority
determines
determines whether
determines whether you're
determines whether you're going
determines whether you're going to
become
become a
determines whether you're going to
become a Marxist
become a Marxist or
determines whether you're going to
become a Marxist or not.
become a Marxist or not. So,
um,
um, in
um, in the
um, in the unconscious
um, in the unconscious then
um, in the unconscious then the
um, in the unconscious then the father
stands
stands for,
um, in the unconscious then the father
stands for, you
stands for, you know,
um, in the unconscious then the father
stands for, you know, the
stands for, you know, the authority.
Now
Now either
Now either the
Now either the authority
Now either the authority is
Now either the authority is you
Now either the authority is you either
see
see authority
Now either the authority is you either
see authority as
see authority as protective
Now either the authority is you either
see authority as protective and
nurturing
nurturing and
nurturing and a
nurturing and a power
nurturing and a power that
nurturing and a power that is
nurturing and a power that is aligned
with
with your
nurturing and a power that is aligned
with your well-being
or
or you
or you become
or you become competitive
or you become competitive with
or you become competitive with it
or you become competitive with it and
see
see the
or you become competitive with it and
see the authority
see the authority as
or you become competitive with it and
see the authority as a
see the authority as a threat
or you become competitive with it and
see the authority as a threat as
see the authority as a threat as the
enemy.
enemy. How
enemy. How you
enemy. How you resolve
enemy. How you resolve the
enemy. How you resolve the edible
complex
complex then
how
how you
how you see
how you see authority
how you see authority either
how you see authority either a
how you see authority either a threat
how you see authority either a threat a
threat
threat what
how you see authority either a threat a
threat what is
threat what is it
how you see authority either a threat a
threat what is it a
threat what is it a threat
how you see authority either a threat a
threat what is it a threat to
it's
it's a
it's a threat
it's a threat to
it's a threat to the
it's a threat to the ego
the
the core
it's a threat to the ego
the core of
the core of the
it's a threat to the ego
the core of the infantile
the core of the infantile ego
it's a threat to the ego
the core of the infantile ego is
the core of the infantile ego is it
wishes
wishes to
wishes to be
wishes to be recognized
wishes to be recognized as
wishes to be recognized as god
the
the omnipotence
wishes to be recognized as god
the omnipotence of
the omnipotence of the
wishes to be recognized as god
the omnipotence of the narcissistic
the omnipotence of the narcissistic ego
then
then runs
then runs up
then runs up against
then runs up against the
then runs up against the reality
presented
presented by
then runs up against the reality
presented by the
presented by the father
then runs up against the reality
presented by the father figure
presented by the father figure or
then runs up against the reality
presented by the father figure or the
fathering
fathering via
fathering via the
fathering via the mother.
fathering via the mother. I'm
fathering via the mother. I'm talking
about
about fathering
fathering via the mother. I'm talking
about fathering as
about fathering as setting
fathering via the mother. I'm talking
about fathering as setting limits,
limits
limits of
limits of society,
limits of society, expected
limits of society, expected codes
limits of society, expected codes of
behavior,
which
which the
which the mother
which the mother does
which the mother does equally
which the mother does equally and
which the mother does equally and even
more
more so
which the mother does equally and even
more so in
more so in today's
which the mother does equally and even
more so in today's society.
more so in today's society. But
classically
classically let's
classically let's say
um
um what
classically let's say
um what came
um what came up
classically let's say
um what came up in
um what came up in my
classically let's say
um what came up in my idipal
um what came up in my idipal complex
classically let's say
um what came up in my idipal complex was
not
not fear
not fear of
not fear of being
not fear of being killed
not fear of being killed by
not fear of being killed by my
not fear of being killed by my mother
but
but fear
not fear of being killed by my mother
but fear being
but fear being killed
not fear of being killed by my mother
but fear being killed by
but fear being killed by the
not fear of being killed by my mother
but fear being killed by the father
figure
figure with
figure with whom
figure with whom one
figure with whom one is
figure with whom one is unconsciously
competitive
competitive in
figure with whom one is unconsciously
competitive in a
competitive in a power
figure with whom one is unconsciously
competitive in a power struggle
competitive in a power struggle in
figure with whom one is unconsciously
competitive in a power struggle in the
unconscious.
So
So what
unconscious.
So what happened
So what happened with
unconscious.
So what happened with Markx
So what happened with Markx is
unconscious.
So what happened with Markx is Hegel
So what happened with Markx is Hegel was
the
the father
the father figure,
the father figure, the
the father figure, the authority,
the father figure, the authority, uh
the father figure, the authority, uh the
one
one who
the father figure, the authority, uh the
one who was
one who was respected.
The
The unresolved
The unresolved edible
The unresolved edible complex,
The unresolved edible complex, the
narcissistic
narcissistic ego
The unresolved edible complex, the
narcissistic ego hates
narcissistic ego hates anything
The unresolved edible complex, the
narcissistic ego hates anything that
successful,
successful, authoritarian,
and
and is
successful, authoritarian,
and is labeled,
and is labeled, you
successful, authoritarian,
and is labeled, you know,
and is labeled, you know, chief,
successful, authoritarian,
and is labeled, you know, chief, CEO,
president,
president, top,
president, top, successful,
president, top, successful, whatever
president, top, successful, whatever you
want
want to
president, top, successful, whatever you
want to call
want to call it.
president, top, successful, whatever you
want to call it. It
want to call it. It instantly
president, top, successful, whatever you
want to call it. It instantly hates
success.
The
The way
success.
The way to
The way to become
success.
The way to become successful
The way to become successful is
success.
The way to become successful is to
The way to become successful is to study
success
success and
success and be
success and be like
success and be like that.
success and be like that. The
success and be like that. The way
success and be like that. The way to
become
become unsuccessful
is
is to
is to attack
is to attack it.
is to attack it. Yep.
Those
Those who
is to attack it. Yep.
Those who attack
Those who attack success
is to attack it. Yep.
Those who attack success then
Those who attack success then are
is to attack it. Yep.
Those who attack success then are faded
to
to failure
to failure because
to failure because the
to failure because the way
to failure because the way you
to failure because the way you become
successful
successful is
to failure because the way you become
successful is you
successful is you follow
to failure because the way you become
successful is you follow the
successful is you follow the path
to failure because the way you become
successful is you follow the path to
success.
success. All right.
success. All right. So
success. All right. So Marx's
success. All right. So Marx's unresolved
edible
edible complex
success. All right. So Marx's unresolved
edible complex then
edible complex then has
success. All right. So Marx's unresolved
edible complex then has cost
edible complex then has cost the
success. All right. So Marx's unresolved
edible complex then has cost the world
how
how many
how many million
how many million Marx
how many million Marx is
how many million Marx is unresolved
complex
complex has
how many million Marx is unresolved
complex has cost
complex has cost the
how many million Marx is unresolved
complex has cost the world
complex has cost the world over
10 million
10 million dead
10 million dead resist
10 million dead resist 20
10 million dead resist 20 million
10 million dead resist 20 million dead
30 million
30 million dead
10 million dead resist 20 million dead
30 million dead 40
30 million dead 40 million
10 million dead resist 20 million dead
30 million dead 40 million dead
30 million dead 40 million dead 50
million
million dead
45 million
45 million dead
million dead
45 million dead 45
45 million dead 45 million
million dead
45 million dead 45 million dead
45 million dead 45 million dead because
he
he was
he was too
he was too cheap
he was too cheap to
he was too cheap to see
he was too cheap to see an
he was too cheap to see an analyst.
Now
Now you
he was too cheap to see an analyst.
Now you see
Now you see why
he was too cheap to see an analyst.
Now you see why one
Now you see why one has
he was too cheap to see an analyst.
Now you see why one has to
Now you see why one has to be
he was too cheap to see an analyst.
Now you see why one has to be stringent
for
for truth.
Philosophy
Philosophy is
for truth.
Philosophy is just
Philosophy is just not
for truth.
Philosophy is just not an
Philosophy is just not an airy
for truth.
Philosophy is just not an airy fairy
thing.
thing. You
thing. You know,
thing. You know, people
thing. You know, people say,
thing. You know, people say, "Oh,
philosophy."
philosophy." No,
thing. You know, people say, "Oh,
philosophy." No, it's
philosophy." No, it's what
thing. You know, people say, "Oh,
philosophy." No, it's what determines
whether
whether you
whether you live
whether you live or
whether you live or you
whether you live or you die.
whether you live or you die. It's
extraordinarily
extraordinarily important.
whether you live or you die. It's
extraordinarily important. And
extraordinarily important. And in
whether you live or you die. It's
extraordinarily important. And in the
new
new book,
new book, I
new book, I put
new book, I put a
new book, I put a little
new book, I put a little energy
new book, I put a little energy into
discerning
discerning philosophic
new book, I put a little energy into
discerning philosophic truth
discerning philosophic truth from
falsehood.
falsehood. The
falsehood. The current
the
the current
falsehood. The current
the current um
the current um relativism
falsehood. The current
the current um relativism which
the current um relativism which then
is
is the
is the opposite
is the opposite of
is the opposite of integrity,
is the opposite of integrity, truth,
morality,
morality, and
is the opposite of integrity, truth,
morality, and ethics
morality, and ethics and
is the opposite of integrity, truth,
morality, and ethics and takes
morality, and ethics and takes it
is the opposite of integrity, truth,
morality, and ethics and takes it all
down
down as
down as an
down as an unwanted
down as an unwanted obstruction.
down as an unwanted obstruction. It's
down as an unwanted obstruction. It's an
unwanted
unwanted obstruction
down as an unwanted obstruction. It's an
unwanted obstruction to
unwanted obstruction to what?
It's
It's the
It's the unwanted
It's the unwanted obstruction
It's the unwanted obstruction of
It's the unwanted obstruction of reason
and
and logic
uh
uh to
uh to the
uh to the unrestrained
uh to the unrestrained narcissistic
uh to the unrestrained narcissistic ego
which
which feels
uh to the unrestrained narcissistic ego
which feels it
which feels it should
uh to the unrestrained narcissistic ego
which feels it should be
which feels it should be able
uh to the unrestrained narcissistic ego
which feels it should be able to
which feels it should be able to do
anything
anything it
anything it wants
anything it wants to
anything it wants to do
anything it wants to do anytime
anything it wants to do anytime it
anything it wants to do anytime it wants
to
to do
anything it wants to do anytime it wants
to do it
to do it and
anything it wants to do anytime it wants
to do it and says
to do it and says freedom
anything it wants to do anytime it wants
to do it and says freedom of
to do it and says freedom of speech
means
means I
means I can
means I can take
means I can take off
means I can take off all
means I can take off all my
means I can take off all my clothes
means I can take off all my clothes and
fornicate
fornicate in
means I can take off all my clothes and
fornicate in the
fornicate in the park
means I can take off all my clothes and
fornicate in the park and
fornicate in the park and it's
means I can take off all my clothes and
fornicate in the park and it's my
fornicate in the park and it's my right
it's
it's your
it's your right
it's your right but
it's your right but also
it's your right but also gets
it's your right but also gets arrested
but
but they
it's your right but also gets arrested
but they feel
but they feel you
it's your right but also gets arrested
but they feel you shouldn't
but they feel you shouldn't be
it's your right but also gets arrested
but they feel you shouldn't be arrested
for
for that
for that you
for that you know
for that you know all
for that you know all right
for that you know all right so
for that you know all right so this
for that you know all right so this is
then
then anarchy
So
So current
So current anarchists
So current anarchists also
So current anarchists also calibrate
So current anarchists also calibrate way
below
below 200.
So current anarchists also calibrate way
below 200. So
below 200. So anarchy
So current anarchists also calibrate way
below 200. So anarchy then
below 200. So anarchy then is
So current anarchists also calibrate way
below 200. So anarchy then is the
rebellion
rebellion of
rebellion of the
rebellion of the narcissistic
rebellion of the narcissistic bull
rebellion of the narcissistic bull and
it's
it's really
rebellion of the narcissistic bull and
it's really the
it's really the denial
rebellion of the narcissistic bull and
it's really the denial of
it's really the denial of the
rebellion of the narcissistic bull and
it's really the denial of the reality
it's really the denial of the reality of
God
God and
God and therefore
God and therefore it
God and therefore it usually
God and therefore it usually calibrates
about
about the
God and therefore it usually calibrates
about the same
about the same as
God and therefore it usually calibrates
about the same as atheism.
about the same as atheism. Atheism
all
all right
all right so
all right so that's
all right so that's the
all right so that's the importance
all right so that's the importance of
that.
Then
Then we
Then we come
Then we come on
Then we come on to
Then we come on to new
Then we come on to new sir
Then we come on to new sir Isaac
Then we come on to new sir Isaac Newton
who
who developed
Then we come on to new sir Isaac Newton
who developed the
who developed the differential
Then we come on to new sir Isaac Newton
who developed the differential calculus
an
an astonishing
an astonishing genius
an astonishing genius of
an astonishing genius of the
an astonishing genius of the same
an astonishing genius of the same level
as
as Freud
an astonishing genius of the same level
as Freud and
uh
and
and Einstein
uh
and Einstein and
and Einstein and Newton
uh
and Einstein and Newton at
and Einstein and Newton at 499.
uh
and Einstein and Newton at 499. Now
and Einstein and Newton at 499. Now this
is
is strange
is strange because
is strange because many
is strange because many of
is strange because many of these
scientists
scientists who
is strange because many of these
scientists who calibrated
scientists who calibrated 499
is strange because many of these
scientists who calibrated 499 in
scientists who calibrated 499 in their
personal
personal lives
personal lives were
personal lives were quite
personal lives were quite religious.
Einstein
Einstein was
personal lives were quite religious.
Einstein was very
Einstein was very religious.
personal lives were quite religious.
Einstein was very religious. So
Einstein was very religious. So was
Newton.
Newton. All
Newton. All these
Newton. All these sir
Newton. All these sir Francis
Newton. All these sir Francis Bacon
Newton. All these sir Francis Bacon all
these
these great
Newton. All these sir Francis Bacon all
these great geniuses
these great geniuses scientific
Newton. All these sir Francis Bacon all
these great geniuses scientific were
these great geniuses scientific were in
their
their own
their own personal
their own personal lives
their own personal lives religious
religious
religious is
their own personal lives religious
religious is not
religious is not the
their own personal lives religious
religious is not the same
religious is not the same as
their own personal lives religious
religious is not the same as spiritual
religious
religious can
religious can be
within
within the
religious can be
within the like
within the like theology
religious can be
within the like theology calibrates
within the like theology calibrates in
the
the 400s.
the 400s. So
the 400s. So one
the 400s. So one can
the 400s. So one can be
the 400s. So one can be religious
the 400s. So one can be religious and
yet
yet still
the 400s. So one can be religious and
yet still within
yet still within the
the 400s. So one can be religious and
yet still within the paradigm
yet still within the paradigm that
the 400s. So one can be religious and
yet still within the paradigm that this
side
side of
side of a
side of a paradigm
side of a paradigm that
side of a paradigm that starts
side of a paradigm that starts at
side of a paradigm that starts at 500
because
because 500
side of a paradigm that starts at 500
because 500 is
because 500 is a
side of a paradigm that starts at 500
because 500 is a different
because 500 is a different energy
side of a paradigm that starts at 500
because 500 is a different energy field
of
of the
of the subjective
of the subjective and
of the subjective and it
of the subjective and it its
of the subjective and it its onset
of the subjective and it its onset is
heralded
heralded by
of the subjective and it its onset is
heralded by and
heralded by and and
of the subjective and it its onset is
heralded by and and dominated
heralded by and and dominated by
of the subjective and it its onset is
heralded by and and dominated by love.
At
At first
At first love
At first love is
At first love is dualistic.
At first love is dualistic. It's
At first love is dualistic. It's between
a
a me
At first love is dualistic. It's between
a me and
a me and a
At first love is dualistic. It's between
a me and a you.
a me and a you. And
At first love is dualistic. It's between
a me and a you. And then
a me and a you. And then with
At first love is dualistic. It's between
a me and a you. And then with the
regression
regression of
regression of consciousness,
regression of consciousness, love
becomes
becomes a
regression of consciousness, love
becomes a state
becomes a state of
regression of consciousness, love
becomes a state of being.
becomes a state of being. It's
regression of consciousness, love
becomes a state of being. It's the
becomes a state of being. It's the way
you
you are.
you are. You
you are. You have
you are. You have become
you are. You have become that.
you are. You have become that. So
instead
instead of
you are. You have become that. So
instead of talking
instead of talking about
you are. You have become that. So
instead of talking about it
instead of talking about it or
you are. You have become that. So
instead of talking about it or between
instead of talking about it or between a
me
me and
me and a
me and a you,
me and a you, one
me and a you, one becomes
me and a you, one becomes that.
One
One becomes
me and a you, one becomes that.
One becomes it.
One becomes it. Once
me and a you, one becomes that.
One becomes it. Once you
One becomes it. Once you become
me and a you, one becomes that.
One becomes it. Once you become it,
there's
there's nothing
there's nothing you
there's nothing you can
there's nothing you can say
there's nothing you can say about
there's nothing you can say about it.
What
What can
there's nothing you can say about it.
What can you
What can you say
there's nothing you can say about it.
What can you say about
What can you say about that?
there's nothing you can say about it.
What can you say about that? What
What can you say about that? What you
are?
are? Well,
are? Well, I'd
are? Well, I'd say
are? Well, I'd say you'd
are? Well, I'd say you'd have
are? Well, I'd say you'd have to
are? Well, I'd say you'd have to get
outside
outside of
are? Well, I'd say you'd have to get
outside of who
outside of who you
are? Well, I'd say you'd have to get
outside of who you are
outside of who you are and
are? Well, I'd say you'd have to get
outside of who you are and look
outside of who you are and look at
yourself
yourself and
yourself and say
how
how can
yourself and say
how can we
how can we describe
yourself and say
how can we describe that?
how can we describe that? I
yourself and say
how can we describe that? I don't
how can we describe that? I don't know.
All
All right.
All right. So,
All right. So, love
All right. So, love then
All right. So, love then starts
All right. So, love then starts out
All right. So, love then starts out at
500 and
500 and the
All right. So, love then starts out at
500 and the reality
500 and the reality is
All right. So, love then starts out at
500 and the reality is purely
subjective.
subjective. You
subjective. You cannot
subjective. You cannot scientifically
verify
verify it.
subjective. You cannot scientifically
verify it. We
verify it. We see
subjective. You cannot scientifically
verify it. We see that
verify it. We see that physiologically
it
it has
it has profound
it has profound effects.
it has profound effects. Uh
it has profound effects. Uh the
condolini
condolini really
it has profound effects. Uh the
condolini really starts
condolini really starts to
it has profound effects. Uh the
condolini really starts to move
condolini really starts to move at
it has profound effects. Uh the
condolini really starts to move at 500
and
and by
and by 530,
and by 530, 540,
and by 530, 540, 550
and by 530, 540, 550 it's
and by 530, 540, 550 it's it's
and by 530, 540, 550 it's it's a
and by 530, 540, 550 it's it's a it
knocks
knocks you
and by 530, 540, 550 it's it's a it
knocks you over.
knocks you over. So
uh
uh these
uh these are
uh these are the
uh these are the roads
uh these are the roads leading
uh these are the roads leading to
uh these are the roads leading to that.
So
So we
uh these are the roads leading to that.
So we transcend
So we transcend these
by
by mastering
by mastering them
by mastering them and
by mastering them and then
by mastering them and then moving
by mastering them and then moving on.
So
So if
by mastering them and then moving on.
So if you
So if you reject
by mastering them and then moving on.
So if you reject logic
So if you reject logic and
by mastering them and then moving on.
So if you reject logic and rationality,
ethics
ethics and
ethics and morality,
ethics and morality, then
ethics and morality, then you
ethics and morality, then you can't
ethics and morality, then you can't get
beyond
beyond the
ethics and morality, then you can't get
beyond the 400s
beyond the 400s because
ethics and morality, then you can't get
beyond the 400s because to
beyond the 400s because to pass
ethics and morality, then you can't get
beyond the 400s because to pass that
class,
class, you
class, you have
class, you have to
class, you have to be
class, you have to be able
class, you have to be able to
class, you have to be able to understand
the
the whole
class, you have to be able to understand
the whole dialectic
the whole dialectic of
class, you have to be able to understand
the whole dialectic of uh
the whole dialectic of uh reason
class, you have to be able to understand
the whole dialectic of uh reason and
logic
logic and
logic and scientific
logic and scientific proof.
logic and scientific proof. So
logic and scientific proof. So now
logic and scientific proof. So now we
have
have Plato
logic and scientific proof. So now we
have Plato at
have Plato at 485,
logic and scientific proof. So now we
have Plato at 485, Sir
have Plato at 485, Sir Isaac
logic and scientific proof. So now we
have Plato at 485, Sir Isaac Newton
have Plato at 485, Sir Isaac Newton at
499,
499, Plutinus
499, Plutinus at
499, Plutinus at 503
499, Plutinus at 503 breaks
499, Plutinus at 503 breaks through
499, Plutinus at 503 breaks through the
500 barrier.
500 barrier. Plutinus
and
and you
and you got
and you got Russo.
and you got Russo. The
and you got Russo. The reason
and you got Russo. The reason another
reason
reason these
and you got Russo. The reason another
reason these people
reason these people are
and you got Russo. The reason another
reason these people are so
reason these people are so important
and you got Russo. The reason another
reason these people are so important is
because
because the
because the United
because the United States
because the United States Constitution
which
which calibrates
because the United States Constitution
which calibrates higher
which calibrates higher than
because the United States Constitution
which calibrates higher than any
which calibrates higher than any country
on
on earth
on earth at
on earth at 710
is
is a
on earth at 710
is a is
is a is a
on earth at 710
is a is a masterful
is a is a masterful work
on earth at 710
is a is a masterful work of
is a is a masterful work of genius.
on earth at 710
is a is a masterful work of genius. It's
masterful
masterful when
masterful when you
masterful when you look
masterful when you look at
masterful when you look at how
masterful when you look at how it's
constructed
constructed and
masterful when you look at how it's
constructed and crafted.
constructed and crafted. how
masterful when you look at how it's
constructed and crafted. how it
completely
completely separates
completely separates makes
completely separates makes the
difference
difference between
completely separates makes the
difference between religion
difference between religion and
spirituality
because
because the
spirituality
because the origin
because the origin of
spirituality
because the origin of man
because the origin of man is
spirituality
because the origin of man is spiritual
reality
reality divinity
reality divinity itself
reality divinity itself his
reality divinity itself his rights
reality divinity itself his rights come
from
from God
reality divinity itself his rights come
from God therefore
from God therefore they
reality divinity itself his rights come
from God therefore they cannot
from God therefore they cannot be
reality divinity itself his rights come
from God therefore they cannot be voted
away
by
by virtue
away
by virtue of
by virtue of the
away
by virtue of the divinity
by virtue of the divinity of
away
by virtue of the divinity of one's
creation
creation it
creation it says
creation it says in
creation it says in the
creation it says in the constitution
that's
that's where
creation it says in the constitution
that's where the
that's where the rights
creation it says in the constitution
that's where the rights of
that's where the rights of man
creation it says in the constitution
that's where the rights of man come
that's where the rights of man come from
and
and the
and the equality
and the equality of
and the equality of all
and the equality of all men
and the equality of all men at
and the equality of all men at 710
and the equality of all men at 710 10,
huh?
huh? 710.
That
That is
That is extraordinary.
And
And by
That is extraordinary.
And by freedom
And by freedom from
That is extraordinary.
And by freedom from religion,
And by freedom from religion, we
therefore
therefore allow
therefore allow for
therefore allow for the
therefore allow for the freedom
therefore allow for the freedom of
religion.
But
But of
But of course,
But of course, the
But of course, the founding
But of course, the founding fathers
But of course, the founding fathers had
had
had it
But of course, the founding fathers had
had it with
had it with Europe.
But of course, the founding fathers had
had it with Europe. Europe
had it with Europe. Europe had
But of course, the founding fathers had
had it with Europe. Europe had suffered
for
for from
for from centuries
for from centuries of
for from centuries of theocracy,
for from centuries of theocracy, the
downside
downside of
for from centuries of theocracy, the
downside of theocracy,
and
and wanted
and wanted to
and wanted to make
and wanted to make sure
and wanted to make sure that
and wanted to make sure that theocracy
would
would not
and wanted to make sure that theocracy
would not recur
would not recur in
and wanted to make sure that theocracy
would not recur in America.
would not recur in America. So
and wanted to make sure that theocracy
would not recur in America. So they
would not recur in America. So they were
very
very sharp
very sharp on
very sharp on that
very sharp on that issue.
very sharp on that issue. They
very sharp on that issue. They realized
u
u so
very sharp on that issue. They realized
u so many
u so many of
very sharp on that issue. They realized
u so many of the
u so many of the senators
very sharp on that issue. They realized
u so many of the senators were
u so many of the senators were also
freethinkers.
freethinkers. Well
um
um atheism
freethinkers. Well
um atheism I
um atheism I think
freethinkers. Well
um atheism I think calibrates
um atheism I think calibrates about
freethinkers. Well
um atheism I think calibrates about 130.
Uh
Uh secularism
Uh secularism about
Uh secularism about I
Uh secularism about I don't
Uh secularism about I don't know
Uh secularism about I don't know 170
Uh secularism about I don't know 170 or
something.
something. But
Uh secularism about I don't know 170 or
something. But freethinker
something. But freethinker calibrates
over
over 350.
Okay.
>> Freethinker
calibrates
calibrates over
>> Freethinker
calibrates over 350.
calibrates over 350. Am
>> Freethinker
calibrates over 350. Am I
calibrates over 350. Am I calcul?
>> Freethinker
calibrates over 350. Am I calcul? It's
over
over 355.
over 355. 360.
over 355. 360. Freethinker
over 355. 360. Freethinker is
over 355. 360. Freethinker is at
over 355. 360. Freethinker is at 355.
See
See what
over 355. 360. Freethinker is at 355.
See what a
See what a difference
over 355. 360. Freethinker is at 355.
See what a difference that
See what a difference that is
over 355. 360. Freethinker is at 355.
See what a difference that is from
See what a difference that is from the
skeptic
skeptic or
skeptic or the
skeptic or the secularist.
So
So if
skeptic or the secularist.
So if you
So if you don't
skeptic or the secularist.
So if you don't want
So if you don't want to
skeptic or the secularist.
So if you don't want to believe
So if you don't want to believe in
skeptic or the secularist.
So if you don't want to believe in God,
you
you can
you can be
you can be a
you can be a freethinker
you can be a freethinker and
you can be a freethinker and still
you can be a freethinker and still be
integrous.
You
You don't
You don't have
You don't have to
You don't have to become
You don't have to become an
You don't have to become an atheist.
You don't have to become an atheist. You
don't
don't have
You don't have to become an atheist. You
don't have to
don't have to become
You don't have to become an atheist. You
don't have to become a
don't have to become a secularist.
You don't have to become an atheist. You
don't have to become a secularist. The
secularism
secularism pulls
secularism pulls the
secularism pulls the calibrated
secularism pulls the calibrated level
down
down below
secularism pulls the calibrated level
down below 200.
All right.
All right. So
a
a freethinker.
All right. So
a freethinker. So
a freethinker. So I
All right. So
a freethinker. So I started
a freethinker. So I started out
All right. So
a freethinker. So I started out before
being
being a
being a atheist
being a atheist as
being a atheist as a
being a atheist as a freethinker.
It
It was
being a atheist as a freethinker.
It was wonderful.
It was wonderful. Wonderful.
Three
Three free
Three free freethinkerism
Three free freethinkerism is
Three free freethinkerism is great.
Anybody
Anybody who
Three free freethinkerism is great.
Anybody who has
Anybody who has any
Three free freethinkerism is great.
Anybody who has any doubts
Anybody who has any doubts about
Three free freethinkerism is great.
Anybody who has any doubts about God
Anybody who has any doubts about God and
all,
all, I'd
all, I'd say
all, I'd say be
all, I'd say be a
all, I'd say be a freethinker
all, I'd say be a freethinker straight.
Why?
Why? Because
all, I'd say be a freethinker straight.
Why? Because you
Why? Because you get
all, I'd say be a freethinker straight.
Why? Because you get away
Why? Because you get away from
all, I'd say be a freethinker straight.
Why? Because you get away from the
downside
downside of
downside of Christian
downside of Christian theology
downside of Christian theology which
downside of Christian theology which is
very
very heavy
downside of Christian theology which is
very heavy on
very heavy on sin
downside of Christian theology which is
very heavy on sin and
very heavy on sin and guilt.
downside of Christian theology which is
very heavy on sin and guilt. Yeah.
very heavy on sin and guilt. Yeah. And
once
once you
once you become
once you become a
once you become a freethinker,
once you become a freethinker, then
you're
you're free
once you become a freethinker, then
you're free of
you're free of the
once you become a freethinker, then
you're free of the chains
you're free of the chains of
once you become a freethinker, then
you're free of the chains of sin
you're free of the chains of sin and
guilt
guilt and
guilt and penance
guilt and penance and
guilt and penance and graveling
and
and all
guilt and penance and graveling
and all the
and all the things
guilt and penance and graveling
and all the things that
and all the things that made
guilt and penance and graveling
and all the things that made that
and all the things that made that kind
of
of Christianity
of Christianity which
of Christianity which was
of Christianity which was pretty
predominant
predominant back
of Christianity which was pretty
predominant back in
predominant back in the
of Christianity which was pretty
predominant back in the 20s
predominant back in the 20s and
of Christianity which was pretty
predominant back in the 20s and the
predominant back in the 20s and the 30s
and
and Christianity
and Christianity is
and Christianity is now
and Christianity is now dropped
and Christianity is now dropped a
and Christianity is now dropped a great
deal
deal of
and Christianity is now dropped a great
deal of that.
deal of that. Christianity
and Christianity is now dropped a great
deal of that. Christianity now
emphasizes
emphasizes the
emphasizes the upside,
emphasizes the upside, hope
emphasizes the upside, hope and
emphasizes the upside, hope and joy
emphasizes the upside, hope and joy and
love
love and
emphasizes the upside, hope and joy and
love and and
love and and has
emphasizes the upside, hope and joy and
love and and has decreased
love and and has decreased the
emphasizes the upside, hope and joy and
love and and has decreased the emphasis
on
on the
on the downside.
on the downside. But
on the downside. But anyway,
on the downside. But anyway, the
founders
founders of
on the downside. But anyway, the
founders of the
founders of the Constitution,
on the downside. But anyway, the
founders of the Constitution, United
States,
States, want
States, want to
States, want to make
States, want to make sure
States, want to make sure this
States, want to make sure this would
States, want to make sure this would not
be
be a
States, want to make sure this would not
be a theocracy
and
and therefore
and therefore there's
and therefore there's to
and therefore there's to be
and therefore there's to be no
and therefore there's to be no let
Congress
Congress pass
and therefore there's to be no let
Congress pass no
Congress pass no law
and therefore there's to be no let
Congress pass no law establishing
Congress pass no law establishing a
religion.
On
On the
religion.
On the other
On the other hand,
he
he allows
he allows for
he allows for it
he allows for it allowed
he allows for it allowed for
he allows for it allowed for freedom
he allows for it allowed for freedom of
religion.
religion. Okay.
he allows for it allowed for freedom of
religion. Okay. So
religion. Okay. So the
he allows for it allowed for freedom of
religion. Okay. So the differentiate
between
between spirituality
between spirituality and
between spirituality and religion
between spirituality and religion makes
makes
makes a
between spirituality and religion makes
makes a big
makes a big difference.
Uhhuh.
Uhhuh. God,
Uhhuh. God, of
Uhhuh. God, of course,
Uhhuh. God, of course, is
Uhhuh. God, of course, is a
Uhhuh. God, of course, is a noun
Uhhuh. God, of course, is a noun like
any
any other
Uhhuh. God, of course, is a noun like
any other noun.
any other noun. And
Uhhuh. God, of course, is a noun like
any other noun. And the
any other noun. And the fact
Uhhuh. God, of course, is a noun like
any other noun. And the fact that
any other noun. And the fact that you
mention
mention God
mention God doesn't
mention God doesn't mean
mention God doesn't mean that
mention God doesn't mean that you've
established
established a
mention God doesn't mean that you've
established a religion.
established a religion. You
mention God doesn't mean that you've
established a religion. You 92%
established a religion. You 92% of
mention God doesn't mean that you've
established a religion. You 92% of the
population
population in
population in the
population in the United
population in the United States
population in the United States right
now
now according
population in the United States right
now according to
now according to CNN
population in the United States right
now according to CNN poll
now according to CNN poll uh
population in the United States right
now according to CNN poll uh believe
now according to CNN poll uh believe in
God.
God. So
God. So if
God. So if just
God. So if just believing
God. So if just believing in
God. So if just believing in God
God. So if just believing in God or
speaking
speaking the
God. So if just believing in God or
speaking the name
speaking the name of
God. So if just believing in God or
speaking the name of God
speaking the name of God made
God. So if just believing in God or
speaking the name of God made you
speaking the name of God made you uh
God. So if just believing in God or
speaking the name of God made you uh a
religion
religion formally,
religion formally, which
religion formally, which is
religion formally, which is the
religion formally, which is the tax,
religion formally, which is the tax, you
know,
know, then
religion formally, which is the tax, you
know, then 92%
know, then 92% of
religion formally, which is the tax, you
know, then 92% of the
know, then 92% of the people
religion formally, which is the tax, you
know, then 92% of the people in
know, then 92% of the people in the
United
United States
United States would
United States would be
United States would be taxexempt.
Now
Now I'm
United States would be taxexempt.
Now I'm afraid
to
to establish
to establish a
to establish a religion
to establish a religion you
to establish a religion you have
to establish a religion you have to
fulfill
fulfill the
to establish a religion you have to
fulfill the tax
fulfill the tax code.
to establish a religion you have to
fulfill the tax code. It's
fulfill the tax code. It's quite
to establish a religion you have to
fulfill the tax code. It's quite a
fulfill the tax code. It's quite a thick
thing
thing to
thing to become
thing to become a
thing to become a taxexempt
thing to become a taxexempt religion.
You
You got
thing to become a taxexempt religion.
You got to
You got to do
thing to become a taxexempt religion.
You got to do more
You got to do more than
thing to become a taxexempt religion.
You got to do more than just
You got to do more than just mention
God.
In
In order
God.
In order it
In order it takes
God.
In order it takes more
In order it takes more than
God.
In order it takes more than mentioning
God. You
God. You have
God. You have to
God. You have to have
God. You have to have a
God. You have to have a a
God. You have to have a a curriculum.
You
You have
God. You have to have a a curriculum.
You have to
You have to have
God. You have to have a a curriculum.
You have to have a
You have to have a whole
God. You have to have a a curriculum.
You have to have a whole body
You have to have a whole body of
knowledge
knowledge etc.
knowledge etc. So
knowledge etc. So anyway,
knowledge etc. So anyway, I
knowledge etc. So anyway, I just
knowledge etc. So anyway, I just thought
I'd
make
make those
make those remarks
make those remarks on
make those remarks on the
make those remarks on the passing
currency.
Sophocles
Sophocles at
Sophocles at 465,
Sophocles at 465, Spinos
Sophocles at 465, Spinos at
Sophocles at 465, Spinos at 480.
Sophocles at 465, Spinos at 480. There
are
are some
Sophocles at 465, Spinos at 480. There
are some great
are some great thinkers
Sophocles at 465, Spinos at 480. There
are some great thinkers in
are some great thinkers in there.
Sophocles at 465, Spinos at 480. There
are some great thinkers in there. Okay,
so
so we'll
so we'll move
so we'll move on
so we'll move on from
so we'll move on from there.
We
We mentioned
so we'll move on from there.
We mentioned that
We mentioned that one
so we'll move on from there.
We mentioned that one reason
We mentioned that one reason no
definition.
definition. You
definition. You see
definition. You see most
definition. You see most of
definition. You see most of the
definition. You see most of the great
thinkers
thinkers of
definition. You see most of the great
thinkers of the
thinkers of the western
definition. You see most of the great
thinkers of the western world
thinkers of the western world were
concerned
concerned with
concerned with what
concerned with what is
concerned with what is truth
concerned with what is truth and
concerned with what is truth and how
does
does one
concerned with what is truth and how
does one know
does one know it?
concerned with what is truth and how
does one know it? How
does one know it? How can
concerned with what is truth and how
does one know it? How can truth
does one know it? How can truth be
identified?
identified? In
identified? In the
identified? In the scientific
identified? In the scientific method,
the
the Darwinian
identified? In the scientific method,
the Darwinian theory
of
of causation
of causation and
of causation and the
of causation and the sequence
of causation and the sequence of
of causation and the sequence of the
dialectic
dialectic was
of causation and the sequence of the
dialectic was as
dialectic was as close
of causation and the sequence of the
dialectic was as close as
dialectic was as close as man
of causation and the sequence of the
dialectic was as close as man could
dialectic was as close as man could get
to
to truth,
to truth, which
to truth, which is
to truth, which is really
to truth, which is really a
to truth, which is really a problem
to truth, which is really a problem in
epistemology
epistemology and
to truth, which is really a problem in
epistemology and semantics.
epistemology and semantics. Actually,
to truth, which is really a problem in
epistemology and semantics. Actually, if
I
I define
I define a
I define a thing
I define a thing as
I define a thing as meeting
I define a thing as meeting this
I define a thing as meeting this and
this
this meets
I define a thing as meeting this and
this meets this,
this meets this, then
I define a thing as meeting this and
this meets this, then I
this meets this, then I have,
you
you know,
you know, said
you know, said something
you know, said something about
you know, said something about reality.
The
The jump
you know, said something about reality.
The jump there
The jump there is
you know, said something about reality.
The jump there is if
The jump there is if you've
you know, said something about reality.
The jump there is if you've proved
The jump there is if you've proved it
you know, said something about reality.
The jump there is if you've proved it in
mind
mind and
mind and the
mind and the intellect
mind and the intellect that
mind and the intellect that doesn't
mind and the intellect that doesn't mean
you've
you've said
mind and the intellect that doesn't mean
you've said anything
you've said anything about
mind and the intellect that doesn't mean
you've said anything about the
you've said anything about the world
mind and the intellect that doesn't mean
you've said anything about the world out
there.
there. It
there. It may
there. It may there
there. It may there may
there. It may there may not
there. It may there may not be
there. It may there may not be an
there. It may there may not be an accord
between
between the
there. It may there may not be an accord
between the belief
between the belief system
there. It may there may not be an accord
between the belief system and
between the belief system and reality.
So
So truth
So truth has
So truth has to
So truth has to be
So truth has to be more
So truth has to be more than
So truth has to be more than just
logical
logical and
So truth has to be more than just
logical and provable.
logical and provable. See
So truth has to be more than just
logical and provable. See in
logical and provable. See in the
So truth has to be more than just
logical and provable. See in the world
of
of science
of science things
of science things are
of science things are provable.
of science things are provable. In
of science things are provable. In the
world
world of
of science things are provable. In the
world of spirituality
world of spirituality nothing
of science things are provable. In the
world of spirituality nothing is
provable.
provable. You
provable. You tell
provable. You tell me
provable. You tell me something
provable. You tell me something is
provable,
provable, it
provable. You tell me something is
provable, it can't
provable, it can't be
provable. You tell me something is
provable, it can't be spiritual
provable, it can't be spiritual because
the
the pro
the pro the
the pro the provability
the pro the provability applies
the pro the provability applies to
the pro the provability applies to a
different
different paradigm.
the pro the provability applies to a
different paradigm. Nothing
different paradigm. Nothing within
spiritual
spiritual reality
spiritual reality can
spiritual reality can be
spiritual reality can be proven.
Nothing.
Nothing. Nothing.
spiritual reality can be proven.
Nothing. Nothing. You
Nothing. Nothing. You can
spiritual reality can be proven.
Nothing. Nothing. You can demonstrate
it.
it. You
it. You can
it. You can validate
it. You can validate it.
it. You can validate it. You
it. You can validate it. You can
experience
experience it.
it. You can validate it. You can
experience it. When
experience it. When we
it. You can validate it. You can
experience it. When we calibrate
experience it. When we calibrate levels
of
of consciousness,
of consciousness, then
of consciousness, then we
of consciousness, then we document
of consciousness, then we document over
and
and over
of consciousness, then we document over
and over and
and over and over
of consciousness, then we document over
and over and over again
and over and over again an
of consciousness, then we document over
and over and over again an affirmation.
But
But we
But we haven't
But we haven't proven
But we haven't proven anything.
Therefore,
Therefore, somebody
But we haven't proven anything.
Therefore, somebody I'm
Therefore, somebody I'm sure
But we haven't proven anything.
Therefore, somebody I'm sure when
Therefore, somebody I'm sure when I
But we haven't proven anything.
Therefore, somebody I'm sure when I come
out
out with
out with a
out with a new
out with a new book
out with a new book will
out with a new book will say,
out with a new book will say, "You
haven't
haven't proven."
out with a new book will say, "You
haven't proven." I
haven't proven." I have
out with a new book will say, "You
haven't proven." I have no
haven't proven." I have no intention
out with a new book will say, "You
haven't proven." I have no intention to
prove
prove it.
prove it. I
prove it. I have
prove it. I have no
prove it. I have no intention
prove it. I have no intention to
prove it. I have no intention to prove
it.
it. If
prove it. I have no intention to prove
it. If if
it. If if I
prove it. I have no intention to prove
it. If if I proved
it. If if I proved it,
prove it. I have no intention to prove
it. If if I proved it, I
it. If if I proved it, I would
prove it. I have no intention to prove
it. If if I proved it, I would be
disproving
disproving myself.
disproving myself. I
disproving myself. I would
disproving myself. I would be
disproving myself. I would be saying
disproving myself. I would be saying I'm
talking
talking from
disproving myself. I would be saying I'm
talking from a
talking from a different
disproving myself. I would be saying I'm
talking from a different paradigm.
Provable
Provable is
Provable is in
Provable is in the
Provable is in the 400s.
But
But we
Provable is in the 400s.
But we don't
But we don't live
Provable is in the 400s.
But we don't live by
But we don't live by provability.
Provable is in the 400s.
But we don't live by provability. We
live
live within
live within a
live within a field
live within a field of
live within a field of awareness.
live within a field of awareness. We
live
live in
live within a field of awareness. We
live in a
live in a field
live within a field of awareness. We
live in a field of
live in a field of subjectivity.
live within a field of awareness. We
live in a field of subjectivity. Okay?
So
So subjectivity
So subjectivity then
So subjectivity then even
So subjectivity then even if
So subjectivity then even if I
So subjectivity then even if I say
So subjectivity then even if I say even
if
if I
So subjectivity then even if I say even
if I say
if I say a
So subjectivity then even if I say even
if I say a certain
if I say a certain paradigm
So subjectivity then even if I say even
if I say a certain paradigm is
if I say a certain paradigm is reality
mechanistic
mechanistic reductionism
mechanistic reductionism is
mechanistic reductionism is if
mechanistic reductionism is if you
mechanistic reductionism is if you can't
weigh
weigh it
mechanistic reductionism is if you can't
weigh it and
weigh it and measure
mechanistic reductionism is if you can't
weigh it and measure it
weigh it and measure it it's
mechanistic reductionism is if you can't
weigh it and measure it it's not
weigh it and measure it it's not real.
That's
That's a
That's a proposition
and
and the
That's a proposition
and the only
and the only reason
That's a proposition
and the only reason it
and the only reason it has
That's a proposition
and the only reason it has any
and the only reason it has any validity
is
is because
is because I
is because I choose
is because I choose to
is because I choose to believe
is because I choose to believe that
is because I choose to believe that it
has
has validity.
is because I choose to believe that it
has validity. So
has validity. So in
is because I choose to believe that it
has validity. So in the
has validity. So in the end
is because I choose to believe that it
has validity. So in the end even
mechanistic
mechanistic reductionism
mechanistic reductionism and
mechanistic reductionism and complete
secularism
secularism depends
mechanistic reductionism and complete
secularism depends on
secularism depends on subjectivity.
It's
It's only
It's only because
It's only because subjectively
It's only because subjectively I
It's only because subjectively I accept
that.
So
So we
So we talk
So we talk about
So we talk about we
So we talk about we talk
So we talk about we talk about
So we talk about we talk about what's
logical.
logical. We
So we talk about we talk about what's
logical. We talk
logical. We talk about
So we talk about we talk about what's
logical. We talk about the
logical. We talk about the world
Newtonian
Newtonian world.
Newtonian world. But
Newtonian world. But we
Newtonian world. But we don't
Newtonian world. But we don't live
there.
there. Nobody's
Newtonian world. But we don't live
there. Nobody's living
there. Nobody's living there
Newtonian world. But we don't live
there. Nobody's living there right
there. Nobody's living there right now.
Nobody
Nobody here.
Nobody here. There's
Nobody here. There's not
Nobody here. There's not a
Nobody here. There's not a person
Nobody here. There's not a person in
this
this room
Nobody here. There's not a person in
this room living
this room living there.
We're
We're all
We're all living
We're all living in
We're all living in the
We're all living in the non-measurable,
non-definable,
non-definable, and
We're all living in the non-measurable,
non-definable, and nonprovable
non-definable, and nonprovable realm
called
called subjectivity.
If
If there
called subjectivity.
If there was
If there was anything
called subjectivity.
If there was anything here
If there was anything here that
called subjectivity.
If there was anything here that wasn't,
we'd
we'd all
we'd all go,
we'd all go, "Oo,
it'd
it'd be
we'd all go, "Oo,
it'd be scary.
Somebody
Somebody from
Somebody from some
Somebody from some other
Somebody from some other paradigm
Somebody from some other paradigm is
now
now we
Somebody from some other paradigm is
now we all
now we all live
Somebody from some other paradigm is
now we all live within
now we all live within the
Somebody from some other paradigm is
now we all live within the val
now we all live within the val within
subjectivity.
The
The experiential
subjectivity.
The experiential sense
The experiential sense of
subjectivity.
The experiential sense of of
The experiential sense of of presence
subjectivity.
The experiential sense of of presence of
experience,
experience, the
experience, the basis
experience, the basis of
experience, the basis of experiencing
which
which is
experience, the basis of experiencing
which is awareness.
which is awareness. We
experience, the basis of experiencing
which is awareness. We all
which is awareness. We all live
experience, the basis of experiencing
which is awareness. We all live within
the
the level
the level of
the level of awareness.
the level of awareness. That's
the level of awareness. That's where
the level of awareness. That's where we
live.
live. And
the level of awareness. That's where we
live. And then
live. And then we
the level of awareness. That's where we
live. And then we talk
live. And then we talk about
the level of awareness. That's where we
live. And then we talk about out
live. And then we talk about out there,
but
but we
but we don't
but we don't live
but we don't live out
but we don't live out there.
but we don't live out there. We
but we don't live out there. We live
but we don't live out there. We live it,
we
we live
but we don't live out there. We live it,
we live within
we live within the
but we don't live out there. We live it,
we live within the unspoken
inner
sense
sense of
inner
sense of things.
sense of things. Anybody
inner
sense of things. Anybody else
sense of things. Anybody else live
anywhere
anywhere else?
And
And even
anywhere else?
And even if
And even if you
anywhere else?
And even if you thought
And even if you thought it
anywhere else?
And even if you thought it was
elsewhere,
elsewhere, it
elsewhere, it would
elsewhere, it would be
elsewhere, it would be because
subjectively
subjectively that's
elsewhere, it would be because
subjectively that's how
subjectively that's how you
elsewhere, it would be because
subjectively that's how you feel
subjectively that's how you feel it
elsewhere, it would be because
subjectively that's how you feel it is.
People
People who
People who have
People who have gone
People who have gone out
People who have gone out of
People who have gone out of body
People who have gone out of body real,
you
you know,
People who have gone out of body real,
you know, know
you know, know that
People who have gone out of body real,
you know, know that the
you know, know that the sense
People who have gone out of body real,
you know, know that the sense of
subjectivity
subjectivity goes
subjectivity goes with
subjectivity goes with you.
subjectivity goes with you. There
subjectivity goes with you. There you
are.
are. There's
subjectivity goes with you. There you
are. There's the
are. There's the body
subjectivity goes with you. There you
are. There's the body laying
are. There's the body laying in
subjectivity goes with you. There you
are. There's the body laying in the
are. There's the body laying in the bed
and
and you're
and you're on
and you're on the
and you're on the other
and you're on the other side
and you're on the other side of
and you're on the other side of the
and you're on the other side of the room
witnessing
witnessing the
and you're on the other side of the room
witnessing the phenomena.
Surgeon
Surgeon is
Surgeon is just
Surgeon is just sewing
Surgeon is just sewing you
Surgeon is just sewing you up
Surgeon is just sewing you up and
Surgeon is just sewing you up and there
you
you are
Surgeon is just sewing you up and there
you are down
you are down there.
Surgeon is just sewing you up and there
you are down there. The
you are down there. The sense
Surgeon is just sewing you up and there
you are down there. The sense of
you are down there. The sense of me,
Surgeon is just sewing you up and there
you are down there. The sense of me, I
myself
goes
goes with
myself
goes with consciousness.
goes with consciousness. It
myself
goes with consciousness. It doesn't
goes with consciousness. It doesn't go
with
with the
with the body.
with the body. And
with the body. And if
with the body. And if you
with the body. And if you do
with the body. And if you do past
with the body. And if you do past life
recall,
recall, go
with the body. And if you do past life
recall, go into
recall, go into hypnotic
with the body. And if you do past life
recall, go into hypnotic states
recall, go into hypnotic states etc.
Past
Past life
Past life recall
Past life recall is
Past life recall is really
Past life recall is really frankly
Past life recall is really frankly very
easy.
easy. It's
Past life recall is really frankly very
easy. It's only
easy. It's only a
Past life recall is really frankly very
easy. It's only a matter
easy. It's only a matter of
Past life recall is really frankly very
easy. It's only a matter of learning
self
self hypnosis.
self hypnosis. You
self hypnosis. You can
self hypnosis. You can really
self hypnosis. You can really learn
self hypnosis. You can really learn in
about,
about, you
self hypnosis. You can really learn in
about, you know,
about, you know, 20
self hypnosis. You can really learn in
about, you know, 20 minutes
about, you know, 20 minutes and
self hypnosis. You can really learn in
about, you know, 20 minutes and go
about, you know, 20 minutes and go back
anywhere
anywhere you
anywhere you want.
anywhere you want. You
anywhere you want. You know,
anywhere you want. You know, if
anywhere you want. You know, if I
anywhere you want. You know, if I wanted
to
to relive
anywhere you want. You know, if I wanted
to relive the
to relive the life
anywhere you want. You know, if I wanted
to relive the life I
to relive the life I had
anywhere you want. You know, if I wanted
to relive the life I had with
to relive the life I had with horses,
but
but I've
but I've already
but I've already seen
but I've already seen the
but I've already seen the life
but I've already seen the life I
but I've already seen the life I had
with
with the
but I've already seen the life I had
with the horses.
with the horses. Uh
but I've already seen the life I had
with the horses. Uh it's
with the horses. Uh it's very
but I've already seen the life I had
with the horses. Uh it's very simple
with the horses. Uh it's very simple in
a
a matter
a matter of
a matter of minutes.
You
You just
a matter of minutes.
You just go
You just go into
a matter of minutes.
You just go into a
You just go into a deep
a matter of minutes.
You just go into a deep state
You just go into a deep state and
a matter of minutes.
You just go into a deep state and uh
your
your intention
your intention takes
your intention takes you
your intention takes you to
your intention takes you to what
your intention takes you to what you
want
want to
your intention takes you to what you
want to see.
want to see. Yeah.
your intention takes you to what you
want to see. Yeah. All
want to see. Yeah. All right.
your intention takes you to what you
want to see. Yeah. All right. So
want to see. Yeah. All right. So that
means
means you've
means you've moved
means you've moved out
means you've moved out of
means you've moved out of this
means you've moved out of this field.
means you've moved out of this field. So
this
this is
means you've moved out of this field. So
this is the
this is the provable
means you've moved out of this field. So
this is the provable world,
this is the provable world, the
Newtonian
Newtonian paradigm
Newtonian paradigm which
Newtonian paradigm which is
Newtonian paradigm which is form,
Newtonian paradigm which is form, the
limitation
limitation of
Newtonian paradigm which is form, the
limitation of form.
This
This is
This is the
This is the world
This is the world of
This is the world of provability.
This is the world of provability. This
is
is the
This is the world of provability. This
is the world
is the world of
This is the world of provability. This
is the world of science.
H
H but
H but when
H but when is
H but when is a
H but when is a thing
H but when is a thing true?
H but when is a thing true? It's
H but when is a thing true? It's only
true
true within
H but when is a thing true? It's only
true within a
true within a certain
H but when is a thing true? It's only
true within a certain context.
You
You can
You can make
You can make a
You can make a statement
You can make a statement that
You can make a statement that sounds
100%
100% true.
You can make a statement that sounds
100% true. All
100% true. All I
You can make a statement that sounds
100% true. All I have
100% true. All I have to
You can make a statement that sounds
100% true. All I have to do
100% true. All I have to do is
You can make a statement that sounds
100% true. All I have to do is change
one
one condition
one condition and
one condition and it
one condition and it becomes
one condition and it becomes falsehood.
So
So what
one condition and it becomes falsehood.
So what is
So what is a
one condition and it becomes falsehood.
So what is a sensibly
So what is a sensibly truth
one condition and it becomes falsehood.
So what is a sensibly truth is
So what is a sensibly truth is true
one condition and it becomes falsehood.
So what is a sensibly truth is true only
because
because it's
because it's within
because it's within a
because it's within a stated
because it's within a stated context.
The
The problem
because it's within a stated context.
The problem with
The problem with politics
because it's within a stated context.
The problem with politics etc
The problem with politics etc is
because it's within a stated context.
The problem with politics etc is it
takes
takes a
takes a statement
takes a statement out
takes a statement out of
takes a statement out of context.
takes a statement out of context. Out
takes a statement out of context. Out of
context
context very
takes a statement out of context. Out of
context very often
context very often out
takes a statement out of context. Out of
context very often out of
context very often out of historical
context.
context. Was
context. Was slavery
context. Was slavery wrong
context. Was slavery wrong from
context. Was slavery wrong from an
absolute
absolute viewpoint?
context. Was slavery wrong from an
absolute viewpoint? You
absolute viewpoint? You could
context. Was slavery wrong from an
absolute viewpoint? You could say
absolute viewpoint? You could say of
course.
course. Was
course. Was it
course. Was it wrong
course. Was it wrong at
course. Was it wrong at the
course. Was it wrong at the time?
course. Was it wrong at the time? The
whole
whole world
course. Was it wrong at the time? The
whole world practiced
whole world practiced slavery.
course. Was it wrong at the time? The
whole world practiced slavery. You
realize
realize every
realize every and
realize every and every
realize every and every everyone
realize every and every everyone here,
the
the ancestors
realize every and every everyone here,
the ancestors of
the ancestors of everyone
realize every and every everyone here,
the ancestors of everyone in
the ancestors of everyone in this
realize every and every everyone here,
the ancestors of everyone in this room
were
were at
were at one
were at one time
were at one time slaves
were at one time slaves without
exception.
All
All of
All of the
All of the world
All of the world practice
All of the world practice slavery
at
at that
All of the world practice slavery
at that time.
at that time. The
All of the world practice slavery
at that time. The Vikings
at that time. The Vikings were
All of the world practice slavery
at that time. The Vikings were one
at that time. The Vikings were one of
the
the first
the first ones
the first ones to
the first ones to discover
the first ones to discover it.
the first ones to discover it. They
the first ones to discover it. They used
to
to just
the first ones to discover it. They used
to just kill
to just kill you.
the first ones to discover it. They used
to just kill you. Then
to just kill you. Then they
the first ones to discover it. They used
to just kill you. Then they found
to just kill you. Then they found if
they
they didn't
they didn't kill
they didn't kill you,
they didn't kill you, they
they didn't kill you, they could
they didn't kill you, they could sell
you.
you. Oh.
So
So out
So out of
So out of greed,
So out of greed, out
So out of greed, out of
So out of greed, out of greed,
So out of greed, out of greed, then
So out of greed, out of greed, then they
stopped
stopped slaughtering.
If
If it
If it wasn't
If it wasn't for
If it wasn't for greed,
If it wasn't for greed, few
If it wasn't for greed, few of
If it wasn't for greed, few of us
If it wasn't for greed, few of us would
be
be in
If it wasn't for greed, few of us would
be in this
be in this room
because
because of
because of their
because of their greed.
because of their greed. They
because of their greed. They found
because of their greed. They found out,
oh,
oh, we
because of their greed. They found out,
oh, we can
oh, we can market
because of their greed. They found out,
oh, we can market these
oh, we can market these people.
because of their greed. They found out,
oh, we can market these people. Nice
pretty
pretty young
pretty young woman,
pretty young woman, nice
pretty young woman, nice young
pretty young woman, nice young boy,
pretty young woman, nice young boy, etc.
So
So they
pretty young woman, nice young boy, etc.
So they began
So they began to
pretty young woman, nice young boy, etc.
So they began to market
So they began to market people
pretty young woman, nice young boy, etc.
So they began to market people and
slavery
slavery was
slavery was born.
slavery was born. But
slavery was born. But slavery
slavery was born. But slavery was
everywhere
everywhere in
slavery was born. But slavery was
everywhere in this
everywhere in this world.
slavery was born. But slavery was
everywhere in this world. Everywhere
without
without exception.
without exception. In
without exception. In fact,
without exception. In fact, the
without exception. In fact, the last
country
country to
uh
uh make
uh make slavery
uh make slavery illegal,
uh make slavery illegal, I
uh make slavery illegal, I think,
uh make slavery illegal, I think, was
uh make slavery illegal, I think, was in
1987.
Is
Is Brock
Is Brock here?
Is Brock here? Where
Is Brock here? Where is
Is Brock here? Where is Brock?
Is Brock here? Where is Brock? Brock.
>> He's
>> He's not.
Is Brock here? Where is Brock? Brock.
>> He's not. I
>> He's not. I looked
Is Brock here? Where is Brock? Brock.
>> He's not. I looked it
>> He's not. I looked it up
Is Brock here? Where is Brock? Brock.
>> He's not. I looked it up on
>> He's not. I looked it up on the
Is Brock here? Where is Brock? Brock.
>> He's not. I looked it up on the computer
for
for me.
for me. Um
for me. Um I
for me. Um I think
for me. Um I think the
for me. Um I think the last
for me. Um I think the last country,
for me. Um I think the last country, I
forget
forget which
for me. Um I think the last country, I
forget which one
forget which one it
for me. Um I think the last country, I
forget which one it was.
forget which one it was. Saudi
for me. Um I think the last country, I
forget which one it was. Saudi Arabia.
>> Saudi
>> Saudi Arabia.
>> Saudi Arabia. Yes.
Only
Only a
Only a few
Only a few years
Only a few years ago.
Only a few years ago. So
Only a few years ago. So slavery
Only a few years ago. So slavery was
Only a few years ago. So slavery was a
prevailing
prevailing condition
Only a few years ago. So slavery was a
prevailing condition of
prevailing condition of all
Only a few years ago. So slavery was a
prevailing condition of all of
prevailing condition of all of mankind.
So
So slavery
So slavery wasn't
So slavery wasn't just
So slavery wasn't just here
So slavery wasn't just here in
So slavery wasn't just here in a
So slavery wasn't just here in a right
or
or wrong,
So slavery wasn't just here in a right
or wrong, yes
or wrong, yes or
So slavery wasn't just here in a right
or wrong, yes or no.
or wrong, yes or no. It
So slavery wasn't just here in a right
or wrong, yes or no. It was
or wrong, yes or no. It was the
So slavery wasn't just here in a right
or wrong, yes or no. It was the field
or wrong, yes or no. It was the field of
h
h the
h the human
h the human condition.
h the human condition. It
h the human condition. It was
h the human condition. It was karmically
the
the human
h the human condition. It was karmically
the human condition.
the human condition. In
h the human condition. It was karmically
the human condition. In the
the human condition. In the days
h the human condition. It was karmically
the human condition. In the days of
ancient
ancient Rome,
ancient Rome, the
ancient Rome, the slaves
ancient Rome, the slaves outnumbered
ancient Rome, the slaves outnumbered the
free
free men
ancient Rome, the slaves outnumbered the
free men by
free men by 10
ancient Rome, the slaves outnumbered the
free men by 10 to
free men by 10 to one.
ancient Rome, the slaves outnumbered the
free men by 10 to one. 10
free men by 10 to one. 10 to
ancient Rome, the slaves outnumbered the
free men by 10 to one. 10 to one.
the
the people
the people walking
the people walking down
the people walking down the
the people walking down the street
the people walking down the street and
10 were
10 were slaves
the people walking down the street and
10 were slaves for
10 were slaves for every
the people walking down the street and
10 were slaves for every free
10 were slaves for every free man.
the people walking down the street and
10 were slaves for every free man. Okay.
So
So then
So then what
So then what happens
So then what happens is
So then what happens is the
So then what happens is the evolution
So then what happens is the evolution of
consciousness
consciousness we
So then what happens is the evolution of
consciousness we begin
consciousness we begin to
So then what happens is the evolution of
consciousness we begin to see
consciousness we begin to see a
So then what happens is the evolution of
consciousness we begin to see a thing
differently.
differently. Now
differently. Now we
differently. Now we see
differently. Now we see slavery
differently. Now we see slavery as
undesirable,
undesirable, wrong,
differently. Now we see slavery as
undesirable, wrong, etc.
undesirable, wrong, etc. But
differently. Now we see slavery as
undesirable, wrong, etc. But you
undesirable, wrong, etc. But you can't
project
project it
project it backward
project it backward in
project it backward in time.
project it backward in time. Therefore
at
at the
project it backward in time. Therefore
at the time
at the time it
project it backward in time. Therefore
at the time it was
at the time it was not
project it backward in time. Therefore
at the time it was not non-integrous.
at the time it was not non-integrous. In
fact
fact it
fact it was
fact it was legal
fact it was legal a
fact it was legal a lifestyle
fact it was legal a lifestyle everywhere
in
in the
fact it was legal a lifestyle everywhere
in the world.
in the world. Everywhere
fact it was legal a lifestyle everywhere
in the world. Everywhere in
in the world. Everywhere in the
fact it was legal a lifestyle everywhere
in the world. Everywhere in the world.
Okay.
Okay. So
Okay. So when
Okay. So when we
Okay. So when we get
Okay. So when we get um
Okay. So when we get um moralistic
Okay. So when we get um moralistic about
history,
history, you
Okay. So when we get um moralistic about
history, you see
history, you see it's
Okay. So when we get um moralistic about
history, you see it's because
history, you see it's because you're
creating
creating a
creating a fallacy.
creating a fallacy. I
creating a fallacy. I want
creating a fallacy. I want to
creating a fallacy. I want to go
creating a fallacy. I want to go back.
You're
You're creating
creating a fallacy. I want to go back.
You're creating a
You're creating a fallacy
creating a fallacy. I want to go back.
You're creating a fallacy of
You're creating a fallacy of uh
creating a fallacy. I want to go back.
You're creating a fallacy of uh false
context.
context. In
context. In today's
context. In today's world,
context. In today's world, it
context. In today's world, it is
context. In today's world, it is very
unethical.
In
In the
In the world
In the world of
In the world of a
In the world of a few
In the world of a few centuries
In the world of a few centuries ago,
there
there was
In the world of a few centuries ago,
there was nothing
there was nothing unethical
In the world of a few centuries ago,
there was nothing unethical about
there was nothing unethical about it.
In the world of a few centuries ago,
there was nothing unethical about it. So
the
the I
the I think
the I think some
the I think some of
the I think some of the
the I think some of the presidents
the I think some of the presidents even
owned
owned slave,
the I think some of the presidents even
owned slave, didn't
owned slave, didn't they?
the I think some of the presidents even
owned slave, didn't they? Early
presidents
>> because
>> because well
presidents
>> because well at
>> because well at the
presidents
>> because well at the time
>> because well at the time it
presidents
>> because well at the time it was
>> because well at the time it was the
presidents
>> because well at the time it was the way
it
it was,
it was, you
it was, you see.
it was, you see. and
it was, you see. and then
it was, you see. and then you
it was, you see. and then you can
it was, you see. and then you can pass
it was, you see. and then you can pass a
law
law later
it was, you see. and then you can pass a
law later that
law later that it's
it was, you see. and then you can pass a
law later that it's no
law later that it's no longer
it was, you see. and then you can pass a
law later that it's no longer legal,
law later that it's no longer legal, but
that
that doesn't
that doesn't make
that doesn't make it
that doesn't make it retrospectively
uh
uh non-integrous.
that doesn't make it retrospectively
uh non-integrous. You
uh non-integrous. You can
that doesn't make it retrospectively
uh non-integrous. You can check
uh non-integrous. You can check that
that doesn't make it retrospectively
uh non-integrous. You can check that out
with
with kinesiology
with kinesiology to
with kinesiology to see
with kinesiology to see if
with kinesiology to see if it's
with kinesiology to see if it's so.
with kinesiology to see if it's so. All
right.
right. So,
with kinesiology to see if it's so. All
right. So, a
right. So, a thing
with kinesiology to see if it's so. All
right. So, a thing is
right. So, a thing is only
with kinesiology to see if it's so. All
right. So, a thing is only so
right. So, a thing is only so within
with kinesiology to see if it's so. All
right. So, a thing is only so within a
stated
stated con
stated con context
and
and retrograde
stated con context
and retrograde blame,
and retrograde blame, you
stated con context
and retrograde blame, you know,
and retrograde blame, you know, which
stated con context
and retrograde blame, you know, which is
the
the current
the current headlines.
the current headlines. Why
the current headlines. Why didn't
the current headlines. Why didn't who
the current headlines. Why didn't who do
what
what when,
the current headlines. Why didn't who do
what when, etc.
what when, etc. And
the current headlines. Why didn't who do
what when, etc. And they
what when, etc. And they go
the current headlines. Why didn't who do
what when, etc. And they go back
what when, etc. And they go back several
presidencies.
presidencies. It
presidencies. It wasn't,
presidencies. It wasn't, you
presidencies. It wasn't, you know,
presidencies. It wasn't, you know, just
the
the current
presidencies. It wasn't, you know, just
the current president,
the current president, but
presidencies. It wasn't, you know, just
the current president, but the
the current president, but the president
before
before him
before him and
before him and the
before him and the president
before him and the president before
before him and the president before him.
And
And then
before him and the president before him.
And then what
And then what about
before him and the president before him.
And then what about the
And then what about the congressman
before him and the president before him.
And then what about the congressman that
passed
passed these
passed these laws?
So
So the
passed these laws?
So the game
So the game of
passed these laws?
So the game of blame
So the game of blame is
passed these laws?
So the game of blame is endless.
So the game of blame is endless. And
passed these laws?
So the game of blame is endless. And how
far
far do
far do you
far do you want
far do you want to
far do you want to go
far do you want to go back
far do you want to go back in
far do you want to go back in history?
How
How far
far do you want to go back in history?
How far do
How far do you
far do you want to go back in history?
How far do you want
How far do you want to
far do you want to go back in history?
How far do you want to go
How far do you want to go back?
So
So a
So a thing
So a thing is
So a thing is only
So a thing is only true
So a thing is only true by
So a thing is only true by definition
within
within a
So a thing is only true by definition
within a stated
within a stated field
So a thing is only true by definition
within a stated field which
within a stated field which is
So a thing is only true by definition
within a stated field which is called
the
the proximate
the proximate field.
the proximate field. The
the proximate field. The proximate
the proximate field. The proximate field
can
can be
the proximate field. The proximate field
can be political
uh
uh positions
uh positions at
uh positions at the
uh positions at the time.
uh positions at the time. can
uh positions at the time. can be
uh positions at the time. can be the
weather
weather and
uh positions at the time. can be the
weather and it
weather and it can
uh positions at the time. can be the
weather and it can be
weather and it can be glamour.
uh positions at the time. can be the
weather and it can be glamour. One
weather and it can be glamour. One of
the
the most
the most powerful
the most powerful approximate
the most powerful approximate fields
the most powerful approximate fields is
the
the media
the most powerful approximate fields is
the media in
the media in which
the most powerful approximate fields is
the media in which you
the media in which you can
the most powerful approximate fields is
the media in which you can take
the media in which you can take anything
and
and glamorize
and glamorize it.
Torturing
Torturing people,
and glamorize it.
Torturing people, whatever
Torturing people, whatever you
and glamorize it.
Torturing people, whatever you want
Torturing people, whatever you want to
do,
do, you
do, you can
do, you can glamorize
do, you can glamorize it
do, you can glamorize it and
do, you can glamorize it and sell
do, you can glamorize it and sell it
do, you can glamorize it and sell it and
make
make money
do, you can glamorize it and sell it and
make money at
make money at it.
do, you can glamorize it and sell it and
make money at it. All right.
make money at it. All right. So
do, you can glamorize it and sell it and
make money at it. All right. So the
infinite
infinite context
infinite context which
infinite context which is
infinite context which is the
infinite context which is the infinite
context
context of
infinite context which is the infinite
context of kinesiology
is
is not
is not the
is not the approximate
is not the approximate field
is not the approximate field but
is not the approximate field but the
it's
it's the
is not the approximate field but the
it's the field
it's the field which
is not the approximate field but the
it's the field which makes
it's the field which makes the
is not the approximate field but the
it's the field which makes the an
it's the field which makes the an which
has
has the
has the power
has the power to
has the power to transform
has the power to transform the
unmanifest
unmanifest into
has the power to transform the
unmanifest into the
unmanifest into the manifest.
has the power to transform the
unmanifest into the manifest. The
unmanifest into the manifest. The power
of
of creation
of creation comes
of creation comes out
of creation comes out of
of creation comes out of an
of creation comes out of an infinite
field.
field. Uh
of creation comes out of an infinite
field. Uh the
field. Uh the unmanifest
of creation comes out of an infinite
field. Uh the unmanifest becoming
manifest
manifest and
manifest and the
manifest and the mechanism
manifest and the mechanism is
manifest and the mechanism is intention.
Yeah.
Yeah. All right.
manifest and the mechanism is intention.
Yeah. All right. So
Yeah. All right. So truth
manifest and the mechanism is intention.
Yeah. All right. So truth then
Yeah. All right. So truth then can
manifest and the mechanism is intention.
Yeah. All right. So truth then can only
be
be defined
be defined within
be defined within a
be defined within a certain
be defined within a certain context.
This
This this
be defined within a certain context.
This this can
This this can meet
be defined within a certain context.
This this can meet all
This this can meet all the
be defined within a certain context.
This this can meet all the criteria
This this can meet all the criteria of
the
the intellect.
But
But in
the intellect.
But in this
But in this field
the intellect.
But in this field it's
But in this field it's facious.
So
So you
So you have
So you have to
So you have to always
So you have to always state
So you have to always state the
So you have to always state the field.
So
So we
So you have to always state the field.
So we can
So we can move
So you have to always state the field.
So we can move on.
That's
That's never
That's never been
That's never been done
That's never been done before.
That's never been done before. Nobody's
ever
ever defined
That's never been done before. Nobody's
ever defined truth.
ever defined truth. And
That's never been done before. Nobody's
ever defined truth. And that's
ever defined truth. And that's one
reason
reason they
reason they argue
reason they argue about
reason they argue about truth
reason they argue about truth is
reason they argue about truth is because
it's
it's not
reason they argue about truth is because
it's not within
it's not within the
reason they argue about truth is because
it's not within the structure.
it's not within the structure. It's
reason they argue about truth is because
it's not within the structure. It's the
structure
structure within
structure within a
structure within a specific
structure within a specific field.
structure within a specific field. Okay.
Uh
Uh so
structure within a specific field. Okay.
Uh so this
Uh so this is
structure within a specific field. Okay.
Uh so this is just
Uh so this is just a
structure within a specific field. Okay.
Uh so this is just a delineation
Uh so this is just a delineation of
structure within a specific field. Okay.
Uh so this is just a delineation of that
that
that the
that the ego
that the ego you
that the ego you see
that the ego you see the
that the ego you see the content
that the ego you see the content of
that the ego you see the content of the
field
field is
that the ego you see the content of the
field is the
field is the ego.
that the ego you see the content of the
field is the ego. The
field is the ego. The proximate
that the ego you see the content of the
field is the ego. The proximate field
field is the ego. The proximate field is
the
the spiritualized
the spiritualized ego
the spiritualized ego and
the spiritualized ego and the
the spiritualized ego and the infinite
context
context is
the spiritualized ego and the infinite
context is the
context is the spirit.
It
It is
It is because
It is because of
It is because of the
It is because of the spirit
It is because of the spirit that
It is because of the spirit that man
even
even concerns
It is because of the spirit that man
even concerns himself
even concerns himself with
It is because of the spirit that man
even concerns himself with ethics
even concerns himself with ethics or
morality.
morality. It
morality. It doesn't
morality. It doesn't dawn
morality. It doesn't dawn on
morality. It doesn't dawn on other
species
species other
morality. It doesn't dawn on other
species other than
species other than men.
morality. It doesn't dawn on other
species other than men. The
species other than men. The content
morality. It doesn't dawn on other
species other than men. The content as
you
you saw
you saw from
you saw from the
you saw from the diagram
you saw from the diagram is
you saw from the diagram is linear
you saw from the diagram is linear and
specific.
specific. The
you saw from the diagram is linear and
specific. The approximate
specific. The approximate field
you saw from the diagram is linear and
specific. The approximate field which
specific. The approximate field which is
really
really the
really the field
really the field of
really the field of nonlinear
really the field of nonlinear dynamics
is
is semilinear.
really the field of nonlinear dynamics
is semilinear. It's
is semilinear. It's somewhat
really the field of nonlinear dynamics
is semilinear. It's somewhat linear
is semilinear. It's somewhat linear but
it's
it's also
it's also somewhat
it's also somewhat nonlinear.
Uh
Uh and
it's also somewhat nonlinear.
Uh and the
Uh and the infinite
it's also somewhat nonlinear.
Uh and the infinite context
Uh and the infinite context is
it's also somewhat nonlinear.
Uh and the infinite context is beyond
time.
That
That which
time.
That which is
That which is within
time.
That which is within the
That which is within the box
time.
That which is within the box is
definable.
That
That which
definable.
That which is
That which is outside
definable.
That which is outside the
That which is outside the box
definable.
That which is outside the box can
That which is outside the box can no
longer
longer be
longer be defined
longer be defined but
longer be defined but it
longer be defined but it can
longer be defined but it can be
described.
the
the situation
the situation was
the situation was favorable.
the situation was favorable. You
the situation was favorable. You can't
measure
measure favorable.
the situation was favorable. You can't
measure favorable. I
measure favorable. I mean,
the situation was favorable. You can't
measure favorable. I mean, and
measure favorable. I mean, and yet
the situation was favorable. You can't
measure favorable. I mean, and yet if
it's
it's favorable
it's favorable or
it's favorable or unfavorable
it's favorable or unfavorable will
it's favorable or unfavorable will make
make
make a
it's favorable or unfavorable will make
make a difference
make a difference in
it's favorable or unfavorable will make
make a difference in the
make a difference in the outcome.
Uh
Uh all
Uh all right.
Uh all right. So
the
the approximate
Uh all right. So
the approximate field
the approximate field we
Uh all right. So
the approximate field we can
the approximate field we can say
Uh all right. So
the approximate field we can say is
describable
describable and
describable and subjectively
describable and subjectively it's
experiential.
You
You walk
You walk into
You walk into a
You walk into a room,
You walk into a room, you
You walk into a room, you get
You walk into a room, you get where
You walk into a room, you get where the
room
room is
You walk into a room, you get where the
room is at
room is at totally.
You walk into a room, you get where the
room is at totally. No
room is at totally. No way
You walk into a room, you get where the
room is at totally. No way you
room is at totally. No way you can
You walk into a room, you get where the
room is at totally. No way you can prove
that.
that. No
that. No way
that. No way you
that. No way you can
that. No way you can demonstrate
that. No way you can demonstrate it.
that. No way you can demonstrate it. You
can't
can't measure
that. No way you can demonstrate it. You
can't measure it.
can't measure it. You
that. No way you can demonstrate it. You
can't measure it. You know
can't measure it. You know they're
that. No way you can demonstrate it. You
can't measure it. You know they're up
can't measure it. You know they're up to
no
no good
no good or
no good or not.
Instantly,
Instantly, you
no good or not.
Instantly, you know
Instantly, you know that.
All
All right.
All right. So,
All right. So, this
All right. So, this this
All right. So, this this world
All right. So, this this world here,
All right. So, this this world here, the
Newtonian
Newtonian world
All right. So, this this world here, the
Newtonian world is
Newtonian world is predictable.
As
As we
As we get
As we get outside
As we get outside the
As we get outside the limitation
As we get outside the limitation of
As we get outside the limitation of the
box,
box, then
As we get outside the limitation of the
box, then you
box, then you start
As we get outside the limitation of the
box, then you start to
box, then you start to see
As we get outside the limitation of the
box, then you start to see randomness.
You
You see
You see the
You see the nonlinear
You see the nonlinear dynamics.
You see the nonlinear dynamics. And
You see the nonlinear dynamics. And you
know
know why
You see the nonlinear dynamics. And you
know why I
know why I always
You see the nonlinear dynamics. And you
know why I always counsel
know why I always counsel against
You see the nonlinear dynamics. And you
know why I always counsel against uh
extreme
extreme sports
extreme sports that
extreme sports that after
extreme sports that after 19
extreme sports that after 19 free
extreme sports that after 19 free falls
you
you know
extreme sports that after 19 free falls
you know doesn't
you know doesn't determine
extreme sports that after 19 free falls
you know doesn't determine that
you know doesn't determine that the
likelihood
likelihood of
likelihood of the
likelihood of the 20th
likelihood of the 20th one
likelihood of the 20th one going
likelihood of the 20th one going wrong
is
is the
likelihood of the 20th one going wrong
is the same
is the same after
likelihood of the 20th one going wrong
is the same after number
is the same after number 20
likelihood of the 20th one going wrong
is the same after number 20 as
is the same after number 20 as it
likelihood of the 20th one going wrong
is the same after number 20 as it was
is the same after number 20 as it was at
number
number one.
number one. You
number one. You haven't
number one. You haven't changed
number one. You haven't changed the
likelihood
likelihood at
number one. You haven't changed the
likelihood at all.
likelihood at all. And
number one. You haven't changed the
likelihood at all. And I
likelihood at all. And I always
number one. You haven't changed the
likelihood at all. And I always give
that
that example
that example of
that example of the
that example of the two
that example of the two guys
that example of the two guys in
that example of the two guys in Sedona
who
who caught
that example of the two guys in Sedona
who caught the
who caught the rattlesnakes.
One
One guy
One guy got
One guy got bitten
One guy got bitten 19
One guy got bitten 19 times
One guy got bitten 19 times and
One guy got bitten 19 times and the
One guy got bitten 19 times and the 20th
bite
bite killed
One guy got bitten 19 times and the 20th
bite killed him.
bite killed him. So
One guy got bitten 19 times and the 20th
bite killed him. So uh
bite killed him. So uh that's
One guy got bitten 19 times and the 20th
bite killed him. So uh that's pushing
the
the box.
Here
Here it's
the box.
Here it's measurable.
Here it's measurable. Here
the box.
Here it's measurable. Here it's
identifiable.
identifiable. We
identifiable. We can
identifiable. We can describe
identifiable. We can describe that
identifiable. We can describe that which
is
is within
identifiable. We can describe that which
is within form.
is within form. Uh
identifiable. We can describe that which
is within form. Uh beyond
is within form. Uh beyond form
identifiable. We can describe that which
is within form. Uh beyond form you
is within form. Uh beyond form you can
only
only know
only know it.
only know it. You
only know it. You can
only know it. You can know
only know it. You can know what
only know it. You can know what love
only know it. You can know what love is.
It's
It's a
only know it. You can know what love is.
It's a subjective
It's a subjective awareness.
It's
It's not
It's not really
It's not really possible
It's not really possible to
It's not really possible to describe
It's not really possible to describe it.
The
The poet
It's not really possible to describe it.
The poet tries
The poet tries to
It's not really possible to describe it.
The poet tries to but
The poet tries to but uh
It's not really possible to describe it.
The poet tries to but uh he
The poet tries to but uh he he
It's not really possible to describe it.
The poet tries to but uh he he doesn't
really
really get
really get there.
Within
Within the
really get there.
Within the box,
Within the box, you've
really get there.
Within the box, you've got
Within the box, you've got force.
really get there.
Within the box, you've got force. The
approximate
approximate field
approximate field has
approximate field has an
approximate field has an influence.
And
And the
approximate field has an influence.
And the infinite
And the infinite field
approximate field has an influence.
And the infinite field potentiates.
The
The power
The power to
The power to go
The power to go from
The power to go from the
The power to go from the unmanifest
The power to go from the unmanifest to
the
the manifest
The power to go from the unmanifest to
the manifest is
the manifest is the
The power to go from the unmanifest to
the manifest is the infinite
the manifest is the infinite power
The power to go from the unmanifest to
the manifest is the infinite power of
divinity.
divinity. Huh?
divinity. Huh? This
divinity. Huh? This is
divinity. Huh? This is within
divinity. Huh? This is within time.
divinity. Huh? This is within time. This
is
is outside
divinity. Huh? This is within time. This
is outside of
is outside of time.
divinity. Huh? This is within time. This
is outside of time. This
is outside of time. This is
divinity. Huh? This is within time. This
is outside of time. This is located.
This
This is
This is generalized.
This is generalized. This
This is generalized. This is
This is generalized. This is provable.
And
And here
This is generalized. This is provable.
And here you're
And here you're talking
This is generalized. This is provable.
And here you're talking about
likelihoods.
Can
Can you
likelihoods.
Can you prove
Can you prove anything
likelihoods.
Can you prove anything about
kinesiology?
kinesiology? No.
kinesiology? No. I
kinesiology? No. I know
kinesiology? No. I know that
kinesiology? No. I know that right
kinesiology? No. I know that right off
the
the bat
kinesiology? No. I know that right off
the bat because
the bat because I
kinesiology? No. I know that right off
the bat because I know
the bat because I know calibrates
kinesiology? No. I know that right off
the bat because I know calibrates at
600.
600. Nothing
600. Nothing at
600. Nothing at 600
600. Nothing at 600 is
600. Nothing at 600 is provable.
600. Nothing at 600 is provable. You
600. Nothing at 600 is provable. You can
demonstrate
demonstrate it.
You
You can
You can explain
You can explain it.
You
You can
You can explain it.
You can be
You can be it,
You can explain it.
You can be it, but
You can be it, but you
You can explain it.
You can be it, but you can't
You can be it, but you can't prove
You can explain it.
You can be it, but you can't prove it.
Okay,
Okay, we'll
Okay, we'll go
Okay, we'll go to
Okay, we'll go to the
Okay, we'll go to the next.
Oh,
Oh, this
Okay, we'll go to the next.
Oh, this we've
Oh, this we've shown
Okay, we'll go to the next.
Oh, this we've shown before
Oh, this we've shown before that
Okay, we'll go to the next.
Oh, this we've shown before that when
Oh, this we've shown before that when we
were
were in
were in France,
were in France, uh,
were in France, uh, we
were in France, uh, we just
were in France, uh, we just had
were in France, uh, we just had to
were in France, uh, we just had to do
the
the Lou
were in France, uh, we just had to do
the Lou calibrates
the Lou calibrates at
were in France, uh, we just had to do
the Lou calibrates at 500.
the Lou calibrates at 500. And
were in France, uh, we just had to do
the Lou calibrates at 500. And here's
this
this modernistic
this modernistic uh
abomination
abomination in
this modernistic uh
abomination in the
abomination in the middle.
Yeah.
Yeah. So
Yeah. So there
Yeah. So there you
Yeah. So there you have
Yeah. So there you have modern
Yeah. So there you have modern theor
modern
modern philosophy.
Yeah. So there you have modern theor
modern philosophy. This
modern philosophy. This is
postmodernism,
postmodernism, you
postmodernism, you know,
postmodernism, you know, with
deconstructionism.
This
This is
This is oldfashioned
This is oldfashioned constructionism.
Let's
Let's take
This is oldfashioned constructionism.
Let's take it
Let's take it down
This is oldfashioned constructionism.
Let's take it down and
Let's take it down and put
This is oldfashioned constructionism.
Let's take it down and put up
Let's take it down and put up something
more
more vital.
more vital. It's
more vital. It's more
more vital. It's more vital,
more vital. It's more vital, but
more vital. It's more vital, but it
calibrates
calibrates at
more vital. It's more vital, but it
calibrates at 180.
calibrates at 180. It
more vital. It's more vital, but it
calibrates at 180. It really
calibrates at 180. It really does
more vital. It's more vital, but it
calibrates at 180. It really does jar
you.
you. Uh
you. Uh this
you. Uh this these
you. Uh this these are
you. Uh this these are this
you. Uh this these are this first
appeared
appeared in
you. Uh this these are this first
appeared in the
appeared in the AA
you. Uh this these are this first
appeared in the AA grapevine
appeared in the AA grapevine back
you. Uh this these are this first
appeared in the AA grapevine back in
appeared in the AA grapevine back in the
50s.
50s. Two
50s. Two different
50s. Two different ways
50s. Two different ways of
50s. Two different ways of life.
50s. Two different ways of life. One
leading
leading to
50s. Two different ways of life. One
leading to barrenness
leading to barrenness and
50s. Two different ways of life. One
leading to barrenness and defeat,
leading to barrenness and defeat, the
other
other leading
other leading to
other leading to fulfillment.
other leading to fulfillment. Okay,
we'll
we'll go
other leading to fulfillment. Okay,
we'll go to
we'll go to the
other leading to fulfillment. Okay,
we'll go to the next.
Um
Um this
Um this I
Um this I thought
Um this I thought was
Um this I thought was important
uh
uh when
Um this I thought was important
uh when I
uh when I started
Um this I thought was important
uh when I started doing
uh when I started doing the
Um this I thought was important
uh when I started doing the calibrated
levels
levels of
levels of uh
levels of uh various
levels of uh various countries
levels of uh various countries and
levels of uh various countries and the
importance
importance of
levels of uh various countries and the
importance of diplomacy.
importance of diplomacy. You
levels of uh various countries and the
importance of diplomacy. You see
importance of diplomacy. You see the
life
life of
life of everybody
life of everybody depends
life of everybody depends on
life of everybody depends on the
life of everybody depends on the success
of
of diplomacy.
life of everybody depends on the success
of diplomacy. Diplomacy
of diplomacy. Diplomacy has
life of everybody depends on the success
of diplomacy. Diplomacy has no
of diplomacy. Diplomacy has no basis
life of everybody depends on the success
of diplomacy. Diplomacy has no basis in
anything
anything rational
anything rational whatsoever
anything rational whatsoever as
anything rational whatsoever as the
history
history of
anything rational whatsoever as the
history of mankind
history of mankind demonstrates.
anything rational whatsoever as the
history of mankind demonstrates. You
know,
know, you
know, you watch
know, you watch the
know, you watch the History
know, you watch the History Channel
know, you watch the History Channel on
the
the history
know, you watch the History Channel on
the history of
the history of Europe
know, you watch the History Channel on
the history of Europe and
the history of Europe and you'll
know, you watch the History Channel on
the history of Europe and you'll say,
"Good
"Good God."
"Good God." I
"Good God." I mean,
"Good God." I mean, it's
"Good God." I mean, it's unbelievable.
You
You know,
"Good God." I mean, it's unbelievable.
You know, just
You know, just the
"Good God." I mean, it's unbelievable.
You know, just the history
You know, just the history of
"Good God." I mean, it's unbelievable.
You know, just the history of the
British
British throne.
British throne. I
British throne. I mean,
British throne. I mean, it's
British throne. I mean, it's the
bloodiest
bloodiest story
British throne. I mean, it's the
bloodiest story you
bloodiest story you ever
British throne. I mean, it's the
bloodiest story you ever heard.
bloodiest story you ever heard. You
know,
know, never
know, never never
know, never never heard
know, never never heard anything
know, never never heard anything or
worse.
worse. All
know, never never heard anything or
worse. All right.
worse. All right. So
know, never never heard anything or
worse. All right. So this
worse. All right. So this is
know, never never heard anything or
worse. All right. So this is what
worse. All right. So this is what I
know, never never heard anything or
worse. All right. So this is what I call
uh
uh the
uh the raw
uh the raw chart
uh the raw chart and
uh the raw chart and you
uh the raw chart and you can
uh the raw chart and you can define
anything
anything in
uh the raw chart and you can define
anything in terms
anything in terms of
uh the raw chart and you can define
anything in terms of us
anything in terms of us and
uh the raw chart and you can define
anything in terms of us and them
politics
politics business
products
research
and
and and
research
and and I
and and I used
research
and and I used it
and and I used it to
research
and and I used it to demonstrate
international
international politics
international politics you
international politics you can
international politics you can this
international politics you can this is
us
us this
international politics you can this is
us this can
us this can be
international politics you can this is
us this can be our
us this can be our family
international politics you can this is
us this can be our family this
us this can be our family this can
international politics you can this is
us this can be our family this can be
us this can be our family this can be a
political
political position
political position a
political position a philosophic
position
position scientific
political position a philosophic
position scientific challenge
position scientific challenge or
whatever
whatever and
whatever and this
whatever and this is
whatever and this is them
whatever and this is them that's
whatever and this is them that's the
audience
audience to
whatever and this is them that's the
audience to be
audience to be contacted
So
So if
So if we
So if we calibrate
So if we calibrate the
So if we calibrate the energy
So if we calibrate the energy fuel
So if we calibrate the energy fuel of
the
the audience
So if we calibrate the energy fuel of
the audience and
the audience and then
So if we calibrate the energy fuel of
the audience and then we
the audience and then we calibrate
So if we calibrate the energy fuel of
the audience and then we calibrate where
we
we are,
we are, we
we are, we see
we are, we see what
we are, we see what our
we are, we see what our task
we are, we see what our task is,
we are, we see what our task is, it
gives
gives some
we are, we see what our task is, it
gives some reality
gives some reality basis
we are, we see what our task is, it
gives some reality basis to
gives some reality basis to diplomacy
other
other than
other than the
other than the facious
other than the facious power
other than the facious power struggles
you
you see
other than the facious power struggles
you see right
you see right now
other than the facious power struggles
you see right now where
you see right now where the
other than the facious power struggles
you see right now where the UN
calibrates
calibrates about
calibrates about 198
calibrates about 198 or
calibrates about 198 or something.
calibrates about 198 or something. I
mean,
mean, it's
calibrates about 198 or something. I
mean, it's barely
mean, it's barely over
calibrates about 198 or something. I
mean, it's barely over the
mean, it's barely over the edge
calibrates about 198 or something. I
mean, it's barely over the edge of,
mean, it's barely over the edge of, you
know,
know, being
know, being able
know, being able to
know, being able to function
know, being able to function at
know, being able to function at all.
It's
It's the
know, being able to function at all.
It's the biggest
It's the biggest committee
know, being able to function at all.
It's the biggest committee in
It's the biggest committee in the
know, being able to function at all.
It's the biggest committee in the world.
And
And you
And you know
And you know when
And you know when you
And you know when you want
And you know when you want to
And you know when you want to kill
something
something dead,
And you know when you want to kill
something dead, you
something dead, you assign
And you know when you want to kill
something dead, you assign it
something dead, you assign it to
committee.
If
If you
committee.
If you want
If you want action
committee.
If you want action that
If you want action that you
committee.
If you want action that you oppose,
If you want action that you oppose, you
assign
assign to
assign to a
assign to a committee
assign to a committee and
assign to a committee and that
assign to a committee and that it
assign to a committee and that it it
that's
that's the
assign to a committee and that it it
that's the end
that's the end of
assign to a committee and that it it
that's the end of it.
that's the end of it. All
assign to a committee and that it it
that's the end of it. All right.
that's the end of it. All right. So
let's
let's say
let's say here's
let's say here's America
let's say here's America currently
let's say here's America currently at
421.
Now
Now if
Now if we
Now if we were
Now if we were coming
Now if we were coming out
Now if we were coming out of
Now if we were coming out of Chicago,
we'd
we'd have
Now if we were coming out of Chicago,
we'd have to
we'd have to come
Now if we were coming out of Chicago,
we'd have to come up
we'd have to come up a
Now if we were coming out of Chicago,
we'd have to come up a little
we'd have to come up a little bit
Now if we were coming out of Chicago,
we'd have to come up a little bit higher
as
as we
as we found
as we found last
as we found last week.
as we found last week. All
as we found last week. All right.
as we found last week. All right. So
here's
here's the
as we found last week. All right. So
here's the general
here's the general level
as we found last week. All right. So
here's the general level of
consciousness
consciousness of
consciousness of the
consciousness of the country
consciousness of the country overall.
However,
However, in
consciousness of the country overall.
However, in calibrating
However, in calibrating countries,
consciousness of the country overall.
However, in calibrating countries, you
need
need three
need three things.
need three things. You
need three things. You need
need three things. You need the
need three things. You need the the
ruler,
ruler, you
need three things. You need the the
ruler, you need
ruler, you need the
need three things. You need the the
ruler, you need the government,
ruler, you need the government, and
need three things. You need the the
ruler, you need the government, and you
need
need the
need the people.
need the people. So,
need the people. So, these
need the people. So, these numbers
need the people. So, these numbers are
just
just a
need the people. So, these numbers are
just a combination
just a combination of
need the people. So, these numbers are
just a combination of all
just a combination of all three.
need the people. So, these numbers are
just a combination of all three. There
are
are countries
are countries led
are countries led by
are countries led by very
are countries led by very integrous
people
people and
are countries led by very integrous
people and have
people and have the
are countries led by very integrous
people and have the the
people and have the the very
are countries led by very integrous
people and have the the very integrous
population
population and
population and the
population and the government
population and the government is
population and the government is totally
corrupt.
We
We don't
We don't drive
We don't drive there
We don't drive there in
We don't drive there in our
We don't drive there in our car
We don't drive there in our car because
if
if you
We don't drive there in our car because
if you get
if you get a
We don't drive there in our car because
if you get a nick
if you get a nick in
We don't drive there in our car because
if you get a nick in your
if you get a nick in your car,
We don't drive there in our car because
if you get a nick in your car, you'll
find
find yourself
find yourself in
find yourself in jail
find yourself in jail and
find yourself in jail and your
find yourself in jail and your family's
being
being blackmailed
find yourself in jail and your family's
being blackmailed for
being blackmailed for $20,000.
And
And if
And if you
And if you pay
And if you pay off
And if you pay off the
And if you pay off the judge
And if you pay off the judge and
And if you pay off the judge and you
And if you pay off the judge and you pay
off
off the
And if you pay off the judge and you pay
off the attorney
off the attorney and
And if you pay off the judge and you pay
off the attorney and pay
off the attorney and pay off
And if you pay off the judge and you pay
off the attorney and pay off the
prosecutor,
prosecutor, you
prosecutor, you get
prosecutor, you get free.
prosecutor, you get free. So
prosecutor, you get free. So we
prosecutor, you get free. So we don't
drive
drive our
prosecutor, you get free. So we don't
drive our own
drive our own car
prosecutor, you get free. So we don't
drive our own car there.
All
All right.
All right. The
All right. The people
All right. The people however
All right. The people however calibrate
in
in the
All right. The people however calibrate
in the 300s
in the 300s and
All right. The people however calibrate
in the 300s and the
in the 300s and the current
All right. The people however calibrate
in the 300s and the current president
calibrates
calibrates very
calibrates very high.
calibrates very high. But
calibrates very high. But the
calibrates very high. But the system
calibrates very high. But the system is
rotten.
rotten. That
calibrates very high. But the system is
rotten. That was
rotten. That was what
calibrates very high. But the system is
rotten. That was what happened
rotten. That was what happened in
calibrates very high. But the system is
rotten. That was what happened in Russia
too.
too. You
too. You see,
too. You see, Gorbachef
too. You see, Gorbachef calibrates
really
really quite
too. You see, Gorbachef calibrates
really quite high.
really quite high. But
too. You see, Gorbachef calibrates
really quite high. But the
really quite high. But the system,
too. You see, Gorbachef calibrates
really quite high. But the system, as
soon
soon as
soon as you
soon as you withdrew,
soon as you withdrew, the
soon as you withdrew, the structure,
soon as you withdrew, the structure, it
collapsed
collapsed into
soon as you withdrew, the structure, it
collapsed into endless
collapsed into endless chaos
soon as you withdrew, the structure, it
collapsed into endless chaos and
collapsed into endless chaos and the
economy
economy was
economy was taken
economy was taken over
economy was taken over by
economy was taken over by the
economy was taken over by the white
mafia
mafia or
economy was taken over by the white
mafia or the
mafia or the I
economy was taken over by the white
mafia or the I guess
mafia or the I guess that's
economy was taken over by the white
mafia or the I guess that's what
mafia or the I guess that's what they
called
called them,
called them, the
called them, the white
called them, the white mafia
called them, the white mafia or
something.
something. All
called them, the white mafia or
something. All right.
something. All right. So,
called them, the white mafia or
something. All right. So, here's
something. All right. So, here's the
United
United States
United States and
United States and here's
United States and here's who
United States and here's who we
United States and here's who we want
United States and here's who we want to
deal
deal with.
United States and here's who we want to
deal with. Here's
deal with. Here's who
United States and here's who we want to
deal with. Here's who we
deal with. Here's who we want
United States and here's who we want to
deal with. Here's who we want to
deal with. Here's who we want to deal
with.
with. You
with. You see,
with. You see, here's
with. You see, here's who
with. You see, here's who we
with. You see, here's who we want
with. You see, here's who we want to
deal
deal with.
with. You see, here's who we want to
deal with. Let's
deal with. Let's say
with. You see, here's who we want to
deal with. Let's say we
deal with. Let's say we want
with. You see, here's who we want to
deal with. Let's say we want to
deal with. Let's say we want to deal
with
with a
with a country
with a country that
with a country that calibrates
with a country that calibrates at
with a country that calibrates at 180.
Well,
Well, this
with a country that calibrates at 180.
Well, this is
to
to 190,
175 around
175 around there
175 around there is
175 around there is where
175 around there is where North
175 around there is where North Africa
is.
is. All
175 around there is where North Africa
is. All right.
is. All right. Now,
175 around there is where North Africa
is. All right. Now, we
is. All right. Now, we want
175 around there is where North Africa
is. All right. Now, we want to
is. All right. Now, we want to go
175 around there is where North Africa
is. All right. Now, we want to go to
North
North Africa
North Africa or
North Africa or an
North Africa or an Arab
North Africa or an Arab country
North Africa or an Arab country that
calibrates
calibrates there
North Africa or an Arab country that
calibrates there and
calibrates there and tell
North Africa or an Arab country that
calibrates there and tell them
calibrates there and tell them about
North Africa or an Arab country that
calibrates there and tell them about how
wonderful
how
how wonderful
wonderful
how wonderful democracy
how wonderful democracy is.
wonderful
how wonderful democracy is. Yeah.
how wonderful democracy is. Yeah. Right.
You
You want
You want to
You want to go
You want to go to
You want to go to Rwanda
You want to go to Rwanda and
You want to go to Rwanda and tell
You want to go to Rwanda and tell them
Yeah.
Yeah. Vote
You want to go to Rwanda and tell them
Yeah. Vote for
Yeah. Vote for democracy,
You want to go to Rwanda and tell them
Yeah. Vote for democracy, the
Yeah. Vote for democracy, the American
American
American way.
American way. Yeah,
American way. Yeah, that's
American way. Yeah, that's meaningless,
isn't
isn't it?
American way. Yeah, that's meaningless,
isn't it? All
isn't it? All right.
American way. Yeah, that's meaningless,
isn't it? All right. So,
isn't it? All right. So, where
American way. Yeah, that's meaningless,
isn't it? All right. So, where you
isn't it? All right. So, where you are
now?
now? You
now? You I
now? You I know
now? You I know where
now? You I know where I
now? You I know where I am.
now? You I know where I am. I
now? You I know where I am. I don't
now? You I know where I am. I don't have
to
to worry
now? You I know where I am. I don't have
to worry where
to worry where we
now? You I know where I am. I don't have
to worry where we are.
to worry where we are. I
now? You I know where I am. I don't have
to worry where we are. I mean,
to worry where we are. I mean, who
now? You I know where I am. I don't have
to worry where we are. I mean, who are
we
we trying
we trying to
we trying to impress?
we trying to impress? We
we trying to impress? We have
we trying to impress? We have to
we trying to impress? We have to know
where
where they
we trying to impress? We have to know
where they are.
where they are. When
we trying to impress? We have to know
where they are. When a
where they are. When a patient
we trying to impress? We have to know
where they are. When a patient comes
into
into the
into the office,
into the office, I
into the office, I don't
into the office, I don't expect
into the office, I don't expect them
into the office, I don't expect them to
be
be where
into the office, I don't expect them to
be where I
be where I am.
into the office, I don't expect them to
be where I am. I
be where I am. I got
into the office, I don't expect them to
be where I am. I got to
be where I am. I got to go
into the office, I don't expect them to
be where I am. I got to go where
be where I am. I got to go where they
are,
are, you
are, you know?
are, you know? I
are, you know? I have
are, you know? I have to
are, you know? I have to go
are, you know? I have to go where
are, you know? I have to go where they
are
are to
are, you know? I have to go where they
are to understand
are to understand them.
You're
You're dealing
You're dealing with
You're dealing with countries
You're dealing with countries then
You're dealing with countries then great
countries
countries and
You're dealing with countries then great
countries and of
countries and of course
You're dealing with countries then great
countries and of course you
countries and of course you can
calibrate
calibrate what
calibrate what these
calibrate what these countries
calibrate what these countries have
calibrate what these countries have done
over
over the
calibrate what these countries have done
over the past
over the past decades
calibrate what these countries have done
over the past decades you'll
over the past decades you'll see
calibrate what these countries have done
over the past decades you'll see China
is
is coming
is coming up
is coming up very
is coming up very fast
is coming up very fast India
is coming up very fast India is
is coming up very fast India is coming
up
up very
is coming up very fast India is coming
up very fast
up very fast America
is coming up very fast India is coming
up very fast America is
up very fast America is starting
is coming up very fast India is coming
up very fast America is starting to
up very fast America is starting to go
down
down you
down you know
down you know many many
down you know many many ways
uh
all
all right
all right so
all right so when
all right so when you're
all right so when you're dealing
all right so when you're dealing with
all right so when you're dealing with a
country
country then
all right so when you're dealing with a
country then you
country then you have
all right so when you're dealing with a
country then you have to
country then you have to deal
all right so when you're dealing with a
country then you have to deal with
country then you have to deal with what
is
is a
is a value
is a value to
is a value to them
if
if you're
is a value to them
if you're start
if you're start so
is a value to them
if you're start so countries
if you're start so countries below
is a value to them
if you're start so countries below 200
are
are not
are not enamored
are not enamored of
are not enamored of honesty
they
they haven't
are not enamored of honesty
they haven't sliced
they haven't sliced interest
are not enamored of honesty
they haven't sliced interest in
they haven't sliced interest in that
they
they want
they want to
they want to know
they want to know what's
they want to know what's in
they want to know what's in it
they want to know what's in it for
they want to know what's in it for us
below
below 200
they want to know what's in it for us
below 200 the
below 200 the ego
they want to know what's in it for us
below 200 the ego is
below 200 the ego is interested
they want to know what's in it for us
below 200 the ego is interested in
below 200 the ego is interested in gain
what
what can
what can do
what can do we
what can do we get
what can do we get out
what can do we get out of
what can do we get out of it
what can do we get out of it gimme
what can do we get out of it gimme gimme
gimme
gimme so
what can do we get out of it gimme gimme
gimme so how
gimme so how do
what can do we get out of it gimme gimme
gimme so how do you
gimme so how do you deal
what can do we get out of it gimme gimme
gimme so how do you deal with
gimme so how do you deal with people
that
that are
that are don't
that are don't have
that are don't have tomorrow
that are don't have tomorrow anything
that are don't have tomorrow anything to
eat.
You
You want
You want to
You want to sell
You want to sell them
the
the best
You want to sell them
the best intellectual
product
product of
product of French
product of French philosophy?
product of French philosophy? Yeah,
right.
Meaningless.
Meaningless. All right.
Meaningless. All right. So,
Meaningless. All right. So, we
Meaningless. All right. So, we go
Meaningless. All right. So, we go where
they
they are.
Our
Our job
Our job is
Our job is not
Our job is not to
Our job is not to sell
Our job is not to sell them
Our job is not to sell them on
Our job is not to sell them on what
Our job is not to sell them on what we
are.
are. Our
Our job is not to sell them on what we
are. Our job
are. Our job is
Our job is not to sell them on what we
are. Our job is to
are. Our job is to understand
Our job is not to sell them on what we
are. Our job is to understand who
are. Our job is to understand who they
are.
are. As
are. As a
are. As a psychoanalyst,
are. As a psychoanalyst, I
are. As a psychoanalyst, I know
are. As a psychoanalyst, I know who
are. As a psychoanalyst, I know who I
are. As a psychoanalyst, I know who I am
and
and I've
are. As a psychoanalyst, I know who I am
and I've been
and I've been psychoanalyzed
are. As a psychoanalyst, I know who I am
and I've been psychoanalyzed myself.
and I've been psychoanalyzed myself. I
know
know what
know what all
know what all my
know what all my positions
know what all my positions are
know what all my positions are about
everything.
everything. I
know what all my positions are about
everything. I want
everything. I want to
know what all my positions are about
everything. I want to know
everything. I want to know where
know what all my positions are about
everything. I want to know where they
are.
are. I
are. I already
are. I already know
are. I already know where
are. I already know where I
are. I already know where I am.
are. I already know where I am. We
are. I already know where I am. We know
we're
we're a
are. I already know where I am. We know
we're a wonderful
we're a wonderful country.
are. I already know where I am. We know
we're a wonderful country. We
we're a wonderful country. We calibrated
421.
421. The
421. The Constitution
421. The Constitution calibrates
421. The Constitution calibrates to
421. The Constitution calibrates to 710.
We're
We're the
421. The Constitution calibrates to 710.
We're the world
We're the world leader
421. The Constitution calibrates to 710.
We're the world leader in
We're the world leader in everything.
In
In fact,
In fact, we
In fact, we have
In fact, we have the
In fact, we have the biggest,
In fact, we have the biggest, most
powerful,
powerful, and
In fact, we have the biggest, most
powerful, and richest
powerful, and richest corporation
In fact, we have the biggest, most
powerful, and richest corporation in
powerful, and richest corporation in all
of
of history,
of history, right
of history, right in
of history, right in Cottonwood.
So,
so
the
the product
so
the product of
the product of the
so
the product of the American
the product of the American way,
integrity,
integrity, hard
integrity, hard work
integrity, hard work and
integrity, hard work and of
integrity, hard work and of course
integrity, hard work and of course I
integrity, hard work and of course I got
to
to corresponding
integrity, hard work and of course I got
to corresponding with
to corresponding with Sam
integrity, hard work and of course I got
to corresponding with Sam because
to corresponding with Sam because I
integrity, hard work and of course I got
to corresponding with Sam because I was
impressed
impressed by
impressed by the
impressed by the principles
impressed by the principles by
impressed by the principles by upon
which
which he
impressed by the principles by upon
which he based
which he based his
impressed by the principles by upon
which he based his business
which he based his business and
impressed by the principles by upon
which he based his business and then
which he based his business and then I
calibrated
calibrated it
calibrated it was
calibrated it was 380
calibrated it was 380 and
calibrated it was 380 and began
calibrated it was 380 and began a
correspondence
correspondence with
calibrated it was 380 and began a
correspondence with him
correspondence with him and
calibrated it was 380 and began a
correspondence with him and so
correspondence with him and so that's
how
how I
how I got
how I got sort
how I got sort of
how I got sort of interested.
And
And I've
how I got sort of interested.
And I've been
And I've been tracking
how I got sort of interested.
And I've been tracking them
And I've been tracking them ever
how I got sort of interested.
And I've been tracking them ever since.
After
After Sam
After Sam died,
After Sam died, it
After Sam died, it went
After Sam died, it went down
After Sam died, it went down from
After Sam died, it went down from like
380 uh
380 uh 385
After Sam died, it went down from like
380 uh 385 to
380 uh 385 to 360
After Sam died, it went down from like
380 uh 385 to 360 or
380 uh 385 to 360 or something
After Sam died, it went down from like
380 uh 385 to 360 or something where
380 uh 385 to 360 or something where it
is
is now.
is now. And
is now. And uh
is now. And uh it's
is now. And uh it's hanging
is now. And uh it's hanging in
is now. And uh it's hanging in around
that
that same
is now. And uh it's hanging in around
that same area.
All
All right.
All right. Where
All right. Where is
All right. Where is 355
All right. Where is 355 on
All right. Where is 355 on the
All right. Where is 355 on the map?
All right. Where is 355 on the map? Uh
that's
that's acceptance.
All right. Where is 355 on the map? Uh
that's acceptance. That's
that's acceptance. That's willingness.
How
How can
How can I
How can I help
How can I help you?
How can I help you? Um
How can I help you? Um no
How can I help you? Um no questions
asked.
asked. Return
How can I help you? Um no questions
asked. Return it.
asked. Return it. Your
How can I help you? Um no questions
asked. Return it. Your money
asked. Return it. Your money cheerfully
friended.
friended. That
friended. That that's
friended. That that's 350
friended. That that's 350 right
friended. That that's 350 right there.
That's
That's acceptance.
friended. That that's 350 right there.
That's acceptance. And
That's acceptance. And you're
harmonious.
harmonious. harmonious.
harmonious. harmonious. All right.
harmonious. harmonious. All right. So
now
now you
harmonious. harmonious. All right. So
now you see
now you see the
harmonious. harmonious. All right. So
now you see the let's
now you see the let's say
harmonious. harmonious. All right. So
now you see the let's say our
now you see the let's say our diplomatic
core.
core. What
core. What level
core. What level are
core. What level are they
core. What level are they at?
core. What level are they at? What
core. What level are they at? What is
the
the level
core. What level are they at? What is
the level of
the level of the
core. What level are they at? What is
the level of the diplomatic
the level of the diplomatic core
core. What level are they at? What is
the level of the diplomatic core they're
going
going to
going to be
going to be speaking
going to be speaking to
going to be speaking to and
going to be speaking to and what
motivates
motivates those
going to be speaking to and what
motivates those people?
motivates those people? So
going to be speaking to and what
motivates those people? So the
motivates those people? So the first
thing
thing is
thing is a
thing is a diplomat.
thing is a diplomat. Let's
thing is a diplomat. Let's say
thing is a diplomat. Let's say I'm
thing is a diplomat. Let's say I'm going
to
to some
thing is a diplomat. Let's say I'm going
to some particular
to some particular country.
thing is a diplomat. Let's say I'm going
to some particular country. I
to some particular country. I want
thing is a diplomat. Let's say I'm going
to some particular country. I want to
know
know the
know the calibration
know the calibration of
know the calibration of the
know the calibration of the leader.
Where
Where is
know the calibration of the leader.
Where is he
Where is he at?
know the calibration of the leader.
Where is he at? I
Where is he at? I want
know the calibration of the leader.
Where is he at? I want to
Where is he at? I want to know
know the calibration of the leader.
Where is he at? I want to know integrity
of
of his
of his government.
of his government. And
of his government. And I
of his government. And I don't
of his government. And I don't want
of his government. And I don't want to
know
know where
of his government. And I don't want to
know where his
know where his people
of his government. And I don't want to
know where his people are.
You
You go
You go to
You go to countries
You go to countries where
You go to countries where the
You go to countries where the people
You go to countries where the people are
terrific.
terrific. The
You go to countries where the people are
terrific. The police
terrific. The police force
You go to countries where the people are
terrific. The police force is
terrific. The police force is rotten.
Yeah.
Yeah. You
Yeah. You go
Yeah. You go to
Yeah. You go to countries
Yeah. You go to countries that
Yeah. You go to countries that survive
based
based on
Yeah. You go to countries that survive
based on the
based on the structure
Yeah. You go to countries that survive
based on the structure of
based on the structure of the
government,
government, but
government, but the
government, but the heads
government, but the heads of
government, but the heads of government
are
are idiots
government, but the heads of government
are idiots and
are idiots and they
government, but the heads of government
are idiots and they get
are idiots and they get blown
government, but the heads of government
are idiots and they get blown out
are idiots and they get blown out con
constantly.
constantly. There's
constantly. There's always
constantly. There's always somebody
constantly. There's always somebody new
coming
coming in
constantly. There's always somebody new
coming in as
coming in as president
constantly. There's always somebody new
coming in as president or
coming in as president or premier
constantly. There's always somebody new
coming in as president or premier or
whatever
whatever the
whatever the title
whatever the title they
whatever the title they have.
whatever the title they have. But
whatever the title they have. But um
bureaucracy
bureaucracy hangs
whatever the title they have. But um
bureaucracy hangs together
bureaucracy hangs together very
integrously.
integrously. All
integrously. All the
integrously. All the trains
integrously. All the trains run
integrously. All the trains run on
integrously. All the trains run on time.
We
We travel
integrously. All the trains run on time.
We travel across
We travel across Europe.
integrously. All the trains run on time.
We travel across Europe. All
We travel across Europe. All the
integrously. All the trains run on time.
We travel across Europe. All the trains
leave
leave on
leave on time.
leave on time. The
leave on time. The planes
leave on time. The planes leave
leave on time. The planes leave on
leave on time. The planes leave on time.
Everything's
Everything's orderly.
leave on time. The planes leave on time.
Everything's orderly. Everything's
clean.
clean. Everything's
clean. Everything's neat.
clean. Everything's neat. The
clean. Everything's neat. The government
is
is pristine
clean. Everything's neat. The government
is pristine and
is pristine and reliable.
The
The people
The people are.
The people are. But
The people are. But the
The people are. But the rulers,
The people are. But the rulers, you
The people are. But the rulers, you can
buy
buy them
The people are. But the rulers, you can
buy them and
buy them and sell
The people are. But the rulers, you can
buy them and sell them
buy them and sell them crooks.
right.
right. So
right. So we
right. So we need
right. So we need to
right. So we need to know
right. So we need to know that
right. So we need to know that is
right. So we need to know that is the
head
head of
right. So we need to know that is the
head of the
head of the so
right. So we need to know that is the
head of the so we
head of the so we know
right. So we need to know that is the
head of the so we know how
head of the so we know how to
right. So we need to know that is the
head of the so we know how to deal
head of the so we know how to deal with
them.
them. the
them. the people,
the
the culture,
them. the people,
the culture, and
the culture, and the
them. the people,
the culture, and the ruler.
the culture, and the ruler. All
them. the people,
the culture, and the ruler. All three
different
different entities.
different entities. Each
different entities. Each one
different entities. Each one will
different entities. Each one will have
different entities. Each one will have a
different
different number.
different entities. Each one will have a
different number. But
different number. But now
different entities. Each one will have a
different number. But now we
different number. But now we know
exactly
exactly where
exactly where we're
exactly where we're going
exactly where we're going to.
exactly where we're going to. So
exactly where we're going to. So if
you're
you're going
exactly where we're going to. So if
you're going to
you're going to a
exactly where we're going to. So if
you're going to a place
you're going to a place that
exactly where we're going to. So if
you're going to a place that is
you're going to a place that is based
exactly where we're going to. So if
you're going to a place that is based on
rage,
rage, anger,
rage, anger, hate,
rage, anger, hate, paranoia,
revenge.
revenge. We
rage, anger, hate, paranoia,
revenge. We blow
revenge. We blow up
rage, anger, hate, paranoia,
revenge. We blow up a
revenge. We blow up a busload
rage, anger, hate, paranoia,
revenge. We blow up a busload of
revenge. We blow up a busload of kids
and
and next
and next day
and next day they
and next day they blow
and next day they blow up
and next day they blow up a
and next day they blow up a busload
and next day they blow up a busload of
kids.
kids. Then
and next day they blow up a busload of
kids. Then we
kids. Then we shoot
and next day they blow up a busload of
kids. Then we shoot them.
kids. Then we shoot them. They
and next day they blow up a busload of
kids. Then we shoot them. They shoot
kids. Then we shoot them. They shoot us.
They're
They're antagonistic.
They're antagonistic. They're
They're antagonistic. They're coming
They're antagonistic. They're coming out
of
of anger.
They're antagonistic. They're coming out
of anger. They're
of anger. They're living
They're antagonistic. They're coming out
of anger. They're living out
of anger. They're living out of
They're antagonistic. They're coming out
of anger. They're living out of the
spleen.
spleen. And
spleen. And they
spleen. And they calibrate
spleen. And they calibrate right
spleen. And they calibrate right in
here.
here. Prideful
spleen. And they calibrate right in
here. Prideful hatred
here. Prideful hatred and
spleen. And they calibrate right in
here. Prideful hatred and completely
indifferent
indifferent to
spiritual
spiritual reality.
Nobody
Nobody there
Nobody there is
Nobody there is interested
Nobody there is interested in
Nobody there is interested in spiritual
reality.
reality. What
Nobody there is interested in spiritual
reality. What religion
reality. What religion is
Nobody there is interested in spiritual
reality. What religion is to
reality. What religion is to them
Nobody there is interested in spiritual
reality. What religion is to them is
just
just another
just another political
just another political gamesmanship.
So
So that
just another political gamesmanship.
So that to
So that to that
just another political gamesmanship.
So that to that which
So that to that which is
just another political gamesmanship.
So that to that which is non-intigorous,
religion
religion then
religion then becomes
religion then becomes just
religion then becomes just another
religion then becomes just another tool
of
of rhetoric.
religion then becomes just another tool
of rhetoric. just
of rhetoric. just another
religion then becomes just another tool
of rhetoric. just another tool
of rhetoric. just another tool like
religion then becomes just another tool
of rhetoric. just another tool like a
peace
peace parade.
peace parade. You
peace parade. You know,
peace parade. You know, peace
peace parade. You know, peace parades,
peace parade. You know, peace parades, a
lot
lot of
peace parade. You know, peace parades, a
lot of them
lot of them are
peace parade. You know, peace parades, a
lot of them are just
lot of them are just a
peace parade. You know, peace parades, a
lot of them are just a manipulative
lot of them are just a manipulative tool
from
from some
from some political
from some political group
from some political group and
from some political group and they
from some political group and they all
have
have names
from some political group and they all
have names and
have names and if
from some political group and they all
have names and if you
have names and if you calibrate
from some political group and they all
have names and if you calibrate them,
you
you see
you see where
you see where they're
you see where they're at.
Mother
Mother Teresa,
you see where they're at.
Mother Teresa, you
Mother Teresa, you know,
you see where they're at.
Mother Teresa, you know, would
Mother Teresa, you know, would not
you see where they're at.
Mother Teresa, you know, would not march
in
in an
in an antivietnam
in an antivietnam parade.
Mother
Mother Teresa
in an antivietnam parade.
Mother Teresa refuses.
She
She would
She would stand.
She would stand. She
She would stand. She would
She would stand. She would go
She would stand. She would go in
She would stand. She would go in a
She would stand. She would go in a peace
parade,
parade, but
She would stand. She would go in a peace
parade, but not
parade, but not an
She would stand. She would go in a peace
parade, but not an anti-war
parade, but not an anti-war parade.
which
which illustrates
which illustrates the
which illustrates the basic
which illustrates the basic principle
that
that you
which illustrates the basic principle
that you don't
that you don't have
which illustrates the basic principle
that you don't have to
that you don't have to hate
which illustrates the basic principle
that you don't have to hate chocolate
because
because you
because you like
because you like vanilla.
The
The way
because you like vanilla.
The way out
The way out of
because you like vanilla.
The way out of the
The way out of the current
because you like vanilla.
The way out of the current political
situation
tell
tell me
situation
tell me what's
tell me what's wonderful
situation
tell me what's wonderful about
chocolate.
chocolate. You
chocolate. You don't
chocolate. You don't have
chocolate. You don't have to
chocolate. You don't have to vilify
vanilla.
Sell
Sell me
Sell me on
Sell me on chocolate.
Sell me on chocolate. Sell
Sell me on chocolate. Sell me
Sell me on chocolate. Sell me on
vanilla.
vanilla. I
Sell me on chocolate. Sell me on
vanilla. I don't
vanilla. I don't want
Sell me on chocolate. Sell me on
vanilla. I don't want to
vanilla. I don't want to hear
Sell me on chocolate. Sell me on
vanilla. I don't want to hear what
vanilla. I don't want to hear what you
think
think about
think about the
think about the opposite
think about the opposite side
think about the opposite side because
that's
that's all
think about the opposite side because
that's all of
that's all of it
think about the opposite side because
that's all of it calibrates
that's all of it calibrates below
think about the opposite side because
that's all of it calibrates below all
vilification
vilification of
vilification of the
vilification of the opposite
vilification of the opposite party
calibrates
calibrates below
vilification of the opposite party
calibrates below 200.
calibrates below 200. You
vilification of the opposite party
calibrates below 200. You don't
calibrates below 200. You don't have
vilification of the opposite party
calibrates below 200. You don't have to
bother
bother calibrating
bother calibrating it.
bother calibrating it. It's
bother calibrating it. It's all
bother calibrating it. It's all below
200.
200. So
bother calibrating it. It's all below
200. So vilification
200. So vilification then
bother calibrating it. It's all below
200. So vilification then in
200. So vilification then in and
bother calibrating it. It's all below
200. So vilification then in and of
itself
itself already
itself already calibrates
itself already calibrates below
itself already calibrates below 200.
itself already calibrates below 200. All
right.
Of
Of great
Of great value
Of great value then
Of great value then in
Of great value then in business.
Of great value then in business. This
Of great value then in business. This is
who
who we
Of great value then in business. This is
who we are
who we are and
Of great value then in business. This is
who we are and this
who we are and this is
Of great value then in business. This is
who we are and this is the
who we are and this is the calibrated
level
level of
level of our
level of our audience.
Let's
Let's take
level of our audience.
Let's take the
Let's take the MSN
level of our audience.
Let's take the MSN commercial
Let's take the MSN commercial right
level of our audience.
Let's take the MSN commercial right now.
I
I don't
I don't know
I don't know who
I don't know who they're
I don't know who they're aiming
I don't know who they're aiming for.
Here's
Here's a
I don't know who they're aiming for.
Here's a chunky
Here's a chunky butterfly
I don't know who they're aiming for.
Here's a chunky butterfly with
Here's a chunky butterfly with blue
wings.
I
I mean,
wings.
I mean, who
I mean, who is
wings.
I mean, who is he
I mean, who is he appealing
wings.
I mean, who is he appealing to?
I
I don't
I don't know
I don't know what
I don't know what MSN
I don't know what MSN sells.
I
I just
I don't know what MSN sells.
I just still
I just still I
I don't know what MSN sells.
I just still I don't
I just still I don't know
I don't know what MSN sells.
I just still I don't know what
I just still I don't know what they
sell.
sell. I
sell. I know
sell. I know the
sell. I know the company
sell. I know the company that's
sell. I know the company that's behind
it,
it, but
sell. I know the company that's behind
it, but what
it, but what it
sell. I know the company that's behind
it, but what it is
it, but what it is they're
sell. I know the company that's behind
it, but what it is they're selling,
it, but what it is they're selling, I
don't
don't know.
Anyway,
Anyway, if
don't know.
Anyway, if they
Anyway, if they want
don't know.
Anyway, if they want me
Anyway, if they want me to
don't know.
Anyway, if they want me to buy
Anyway, if they want me to buy with
their
their product,
their product, they
their product, they missed
their product, they missed it.
their product, they missed it. They
missed
missed it.
their product, they missed it. They
missed it. All
missed it. All right.
their product, they missed it. They
missed it. All right. So,
missed it. All right. So, as
their product, they missed it. They
missed it. All right. So, as a
missed it. All right. So, as a company,
here's
here's where
here's where we
here's where we are.
here's where we are. Here's
here's where we are. Here's our
here's where we are. Here's our target.
And
And this
here's where we are. Here's our target.
And this is
And this is how
here's where we are. Here's our target.
And this is how does
And this is how does this
here's where we are. Here's our target.
And this is how does this target
And this is how does this target see
things?
things? What
things? What do
things? What do they
things? What do they value?
things? What do they value? Where
things? What do they value? Where is
their
their head
things? What do they value? Where is
their head at?
their head at? Because
things? What do they value? Where is
their head at? Because if
their head at? Because if you
things? What do they value? Where is
their head at? Because if you want
somebody
somebody to
somebody to buy
somebody to buy a
somebody to buy a Jaguar,
I
I wouldn't
somebody to buy a Jaguar,
I wouldn't design
I wouldn't design like
somebody to buy a Jaguar,
I wouldn't design like their
I wouldn't design like their current
commercial
commercial uh
commercial uh in
commercial uh in which
commercial uh in which a
commercial uh in which a slightly
intoxicated
intoxicated teenager
commercial uh in which a slightly
intoxicated teenager takes
intoxicated teenager takes wild
commercial uh in which a slightly
intoxicated teenager takes wild risks
through
through the
through the town.
through the town. Uh,
through the town. Uh, you
through the town. Uh, you know,
through the town. Uh, you know, that
that's
that's the
through the town. Uh, you know, that
that's the muscle
that's the muscle car
through the town. Uh, you know, that
that's the muscle car age.
that's the muscle car age. But
through the town. Uh, you know, that
that's the muscle car age. But the
muscle
muscle car
muscle car age
muscle car age can't
muscle car age can't afford
muscle car age can't afford Jaguars,
muscle car age can't afford Jaguars, can
they?
they? You're
muscle car age can't afford Jaguars, can
they? You're talking
they? You're talking about
muscle car age can't afford Jaguars, can
they? You're talking about 60,000
they? You're talking about 60,000 up
car.
car. You're
car. You're talking
car. You're talking about
car. You're talking about people
car. You're talking about people of
car. You're talking about people of a
different
different caliber.
car. You're talking about people of a
different caliber. So,
different caliber. So, they
car. You're talking about people of a
different caliber. So, they miscalibrate
their
their audience.
I
I mean,
their audience.
I mean, racing
I mean, racing a
their audience.
I mean, racing a Jaguar,
I mean, racing a Jaguar, you
their audience.
I mean, racing a Jaguar, you know,
I mean, racing a Jaguar, you know, like
you're
you're 19
you're 19 years
you're 19 years old
you're 19 years old and
you're 19 years old and you're
you're 19 years old and you're on
you're 19 years old and you're on meth
is
is their
you're 19 years old and you're on meth
is their current
is their current ad.
you're 19 years old and you're on meth
is their current ad. And
is their current ad. And I
you're 19 years old and you're on meth
is their current ad. And I think,
is their current ad. And I think, are
they
they appealing
they appealing to
they appealing to a
they appealing to a few
multi-millionaire
multi-millionaire teenagers
they appealing to a few
multi-millionaire teenagers out
multi-millionaire teenagers out there?
they appealing to a few
multi-millionaire teenagers out there? I
guess
guess that's
guess that's who
guess that's who they're
guess that's who they're appealing
guess that's who they're appealing to.
guess that's who they're appealing to. I
think
think of
guess that's who they're appealing to. I
think of the
think of the money
guess that's who they're appealing to. I
think of the money they
think of the money they throw
guess that's who they're appealing to. I
think of the money they throw away.
think of the money they throw away. So
we
we found
we found out
we found out that
we found out that with
we found out that with consciousness
calibration
calibration you
we found out that with consciousness
calibration you can
calibration you can return
we found out that with consciousness
calibration you can return the
investment
investment on
investment on your
investment on your investment
investment on your investment in
investment on your investment in in
advertising
advertising by
investment on your investment in in
advertising by 250%.
advertising by 250%. Okay.
investment on your investment in in
advertising by 250%. Okay. The
advertising by 250%. Okay. The use
investment on your investment in in
advertising by 250%. Okay. The use of
consciousness
consciousness calibration
consciousness calibration techniques
consciousness calibration techniques and
graphs
graphs such
consciousness calibration techniques and
graphs such as
graphs such as we
consciousness calibration techniques and
graphs such as we described
graphs such as we described I
consciousness calibration techniques and
graphs such as we described I have
permission
permission to
permission to ask
permission to ask this
permission to ask this in
permission to ask this in front
permission to ask this in front of his
audience
audience for
permission to ask this in front of his
audience for the
audience for the sake
permission to ask this in front of his
audience for the sake of
audience for the sake of truth.
permission to ask this in front of his
audience for the sake of truth. the
audience for the sake of truth. the sake
of
of the
of the highest
of the highest good
of the highest good truth
of the highest good truth then
of the highest good truth then is
of the highest good truth then is you
could
could return
of the highest good truth then is you
could return the
could return the return
of the highest good truth then is you
could return the return on
could return the return on your
investment
investment would
investment would be
investment would be over
investment would be over 250%
investment would be over 250% more
investment would be over 250% more more
than
than 260%.
investment would be over 250% more more
than 260%. 250%.
All
All right.
All right. Using
All right. Using consciousness
calibration
calibration then
All right. Using consciousness
calibration then you
calibration then you say
All right. Using consciousness
calibration then you say who's
calibration then you say who's my
target?
target? Where
target? Where are
target? Where are we
target? Where are we coming
target? Where are we coming from?
target? Where are we coming from? What
is
is our
target? Where are we coming from? What
is our advertisement
is our advertisement calibrate
target? Where are we coming from? What
is our advertisement calibrate at?
Sometimes
Sometimes the
Sometimes the the
Sometimes the the visuals
Sometimes the the visuals are
Sometimes the the visuals are good
Sometimes the the visuals are good but
the
the music
Sometimes the the visuals are good but
the music is
the music is horrible.
Sometimes the the visuals are good but
the music is horrible. There's
the music is horrible. There's some
that
that you
that you if
that you if you
that you if you do
that you if you do the
that you if you do the visual,
that you if you do the visual, calibrate
the
the energy
that you if you do the visual, calibrate
the energy of
the energy of the
that you if you do the visual, calibrate
the energy of the visual,
the energy of the visual, it's
that you if you do the visual, calibrate
the energy of the visual, it's fine.
the energy of the visual, it's fine. If
you
you calibrate
you calibrate the
you calibrate the energy
you calibrate the energy of
you calibrate the energy of the
you calibrate the energy of the music,
it's
it's a
you calibrate the energy of the music,
it's a complete
it's a complete turnoff.
There's
There's some
There's some advertisements
There's some advertisements out
There's some advertisements out there.
This
This part
There's some advertisements out there.
This part of
This part of the
There's some advertisements out there.
This part of the advertisement
This part of the advertisement makes
There's some advertisements out there.
This part of the advertisement makes you
go
go strong.
go strong. This
go strong. This part
go strong. This part makes
go strong. This part makes you
go strong. This part makes you go
go strong. This part makes you go weak.
There's
There's an
go strong. This part makes you go weak.
There's an advertisement
There's an advertisement out
go strong. This part makes you go weak.
There's an advertisement out there
There's an advertisement out there for
an
an antiscychotic
an antiscychotic drug,
an antiscychotic drug, Geodon.
And
And there's
an antiscychotic drug, Geodon.
And there's a
And there's a big
an antiscychotic drug, Geodon.
And there's a big visual.
And there's a big visual. Every
psychiatric
psychiatric news
psychiatric news I
psychiatric news I get,
psychiatric news I get, there's
psychiatric news I get, there's about
three
three pages
psychiatric news I get, there's about
three pages of
three pages of this
psychiatric news I get, there's about
three pages of this horrible
three pages of this horrible woman's
face.
face. When
face. When you
face. When you calibrate
face. When you calibrate her,
face. When you calibrate her, she's
face. When you calibrate her, she's 130.
I
I hate
face. When you calibrate her, she's 130.
I hate Geodon.
Even
Even if
Even if you
Even if you were
Even if you were dying
Even if you were dying and
Even if you were dying and needed
Geodon,
Geodon, I
Even if you were dying and needed
Geodon, I won't
Geodon, I won't prescribe
Even if you were dying and needed
Geodon, I won't prescribe it.
Geodon, I won't prescribe it. I
Even if you were dying and needed
Geodon, I won't prescribe it. I just
have
have an
have an aversion
have an aversion to
have an aversion to Geodon.
have an aversion to Geodon. I
have an aversion to Geodon. I hate
Geodon.
I
I hate
I hate it
I hate it so
I hate it so much
I hate it so much I
I hate it so much I never
I hate it so much I never think
I hate it so much I never think of
I hate it so much I never think of it.
If
If a
I hate it so much I never think of it.
If a patient's
If a patient's sitting
I hate it so much I never think of it.
If a patient's sitting there
If a patient's sitting there and
I hate it so much I never think of it.
If a patient's sitting there and they're
hearing
hearing voices,
hearing voices, I
hearing voices, I never
hearing voices, I never think
hearing voices, I never think write
Geodon.
Geodon. No.
Why?
Why? Because
Why? Because conditioned
Why? Because conditioned reflex.
Why? Because conditioned reflex. So
Why? Because conditioned reflex. So you
see
see negative
Why? Because conditioned reflex. So you
see negative advertising
which
which is
which is an
which is an argu
which is an argu arguable
which is an argu arguable thing
which is an argu arguable thing but
which is an argu arguable thing but what
they
they mean
which is an argu arguable thing but what
they mean by
they mean by negative
which is an argu arguable thing but what
they mean by negative art
they mean by negative art advertising
which is an argu arguable thing but what
they mean by negative art advertising is
something
something else
something else than
something else than what
something else than what I'm
something else than what I'm talking
about.
about. Uh
something else than what I'm talking
about. Uh that's
about. Uh that's a
something else than what I'm talking
about. Uh that's a different
about. Uh that's a different concept.
So
So it
So it has
So it has val
So it has val great
So it has val great value
So it has val great value in
So it has val great value in business.
Let's
Let's say
So it has val great value in business.
Let's say you're
Let's say you're um
So it has val great value in business.
Let's say you're um a
Let's say you're um a government
So it has val great value in business.
Let's say you're um a government group
and
and this
and this is
and this is your
and this is your problem
and this is your problem out
and this is your problem out there
and this is your problem out there you
know
know and
and this is your problem out there you
know and your
know and your program.
and this is your problem out there you
know and your program. So
know and your program. So you
and this is your problem out there you
know and your program. So you calibrate
where
where your
where your program
where your program is.
where your program is. What's
where your program is. What's out
where your program is. What's out there?
For
For instance,
where your program is. What's out there?
For instance, the
For instance, the 12step
where your program is. What's out there?
For instance, the 12step program
calibrates
calibrates what
calibrates what do
calibrates what do you
calibrates what do you need
calibrates what do you need to
calibrates what do you need to overcome
addiction.
You'll
You'll find
You'll find you
You'll find you need
You'll find you need a
You'll find you need a program
You'll find you need a program that
calibrates
calibrates 540
You'll find you need a program that
calibrates 540 or
calibrates 540 or over
you
you launch
you launch it.
you launch it. I
you launch it. I know
you launch it. I know that
you launch it. I know that already.
you launch it. I know that already. To
overcome
overcome addiction,
you launch it. I know that already. To
overcome addiction, it's
overcome addiction, it's so
you launch it. I know that already. To
overcome addiction, it's so powerful.
overcome addiction, it's so powerful. So
powerful.
powerful. It
powerful. It so
powerful. It so programs
powerful. It so programs the
powerful. It so programs the brain
neurons.
neurons. It's
powerful. It so programs the brain
neurons. It's the
neurons. It's the neurons
powerful. It so programs the brain
neurons. It's the neurons that
neurons. It's the neurons that are
programmed.
programmed. You
programmed. You know,
programmed. You know, you
programmed. You know, you can
programmed. You know, you can raise
neurons
neurons in
uh
uh petri
uh petri dish
uh petri dish with
uh petri dish with alcohol
uh petri dish with alcohol or
uh petri dish with alcohol or drugs
uh petri dish with alcohol or drugs and
they
they become
uh petri dish with alcohol or drugs and
they become dependent
they become dependent on
uh petri dish with alcohol or drugs and
they become dependent on it.
they become dependent on it. Now,
uh petri dish with alcohol or drugs and
they become dependent on it. Now, you
withdraw
withdraw the
withdraw the alcohol,
withdraw the alcohol, the
withdraw the alcohol, the drugs
withdraw the alcohol, the drugs from
withdraw the alcohol, the drugs from the
culture
culture medium
withdraw the alcohol, the drugs from the
culture medium in
culture medium in the
withdraw the alcohol, the drugs from the
culture medium in the petri
culture medium in the petri dish
withdraw the alcohol, the drugs from the
culture medium in the petri dish and
culture medium in the petri dish and the
neurons
neurons will
neurons will [ __ ]
neurons will [ __ ] up
neurons will [ __ ] up and
neurons will [ __ ] up and die.
neurons will [ __ ] up and die. So,
it's
it's more
neurons will [ __ ] up and die. So,
it's more than
it's more than just
neurons will [ __ ] up and die. So,
it's more than just you
it's more than just you and
neurons will [ __ ] up and die. So,
it's more than just you and your
it's more than just you and your ego.
It's
It's it's
It's it's your
It's it's your brain
It's it's your brain cells.
It's it's your brain cells. Your
It's it's your brain cells. Your brain
is
is now
It's it's your brain cells. Your brain
is now addicted.
is now addicted. So,
It's it's your brain cells. Your brain
is now addicted. So, it
is now addicted. So, it started
It's it's your brain cells. Your brain
is now addicted. So, it started out
is now addicted. So, it started out as
It's it's your brain cells. Your brain
is now addicted. So, it started out as a
pleasure.
pleasure. Now,
pleasure. Now, you
pleasure. Now, you become
pleasure. Now, you become your
pleasure. Now, you become your neurons
have
have become
pleasure. Now, you become your neurons
have become addicted.
have become addicted. Oh.
pleasure. Now, you become your neurons
have become addicted. Oh. So
have become addicted. Oh. So what
pleasure. Now, you become your neurons
have become addicted. Oh. So what does
it
it take
it take to
it take to overcome
it take to overcome the
it take to overcome the pain
it take to overcome the pain and
it take to overcome the pain and agony
you
you got
it take to overcome the pain and agony
you got to
you got to go
it take to overcome the pain and agony
you got to go through
you got to go through to
it take to overcome the pain and agony
you got to go through to come
you got to go through to come out
it take to overcome the pain and agony
you got to go through to come out of
you got to go through to come out of the
addiction
addiction is
addiction is a
addiction is a powerful
addiction is a powerful and
addiction is a powerful and a
addiction is a powerful and a powerful
drive
drive to
addiction is a powerful and a powerful
drive to do
drive to do so.
addiction is a powerful and a powerful
drive to do so. What
drive to do so. What does
addiction is a powerful and a powerful
drive to do so. What does it
drive to do so. What does it have
addiction is a powerful and a powerful
drive to do so. What does it have to
calibrate
calibrate at?
calibrate at? It
calibrate at? It has
calibrate at? It has to
calibrate at? It has to calibrate
calibrate at? It has to calibrate at
540.
540. It
calibrate at? It has to calibrate at
540. It has
540. It has to
calibrate at? It has to calibrate at
540. It has to calibrate
540. It has to calibrate at
calibrate at? It has to calibrate at
540. It has to calibrate at 540.
540. It has to calibrate at 540. So
there's
there's various
there's various other
there's various other secularbased
recovery
recovery programs
there's various other secularbased
recovery programs around
recovery programs around when
there's various other secularbased
recovery programs around when you
calibrate
calibrate them.
calibrate them. Uh
calibrate them. Uh they
calibrate them. Uh they avoid
calibrate them. Uh they avoid um
calibrate them. Uh they avoid um go
calibrate them. Uh they avoid um go any
mention
mention of
calibrate them. Uh they avoid um go any
mention of God.
mention of God. So
calibrate them. Uh they avoid um go any
mention of God. So I
mention of God. So I guess
calibrate them. Uh they avoid um go any
mention of God. So I guess they're
mention of God. So I guess they're for
atheists.
atheists. I
atheists. I miss
atheists. I miss the
atheists. I miss the atheist
atheists. I miss the atheist version
atheists. I miss the atheist version of
AA.
They
They base
They base it
They base it on
They base it on nutrition,
They base it on nutrition, eating
They base it on nutrition, eating a
They base it on nutrition, eating a lot
of
of vitamins
They base it on nutrition, eating a lot
of vitamins and
of vitamins and becoming
They base it on nutrition, eating a lot
of vitamins and becoming a
of vitamins and becoming a vegetarian
and
and getting
and getting massage
and getting massage and
and getting massage and exercises
and getting massage and exercises and
doing
doing yoga.
and getting massage and exercises and
doing yoga. Good,
doing yoga. Good, good,
and getting massage and exercises and
doing yoga. Good, good, good
doing yoga. Good, good, good wishes.
Cuz
Cuz I
Cuz I already
Cuz I already know
Cuz I already know it
Cuz I already know it takes
Cuz I already know it takes 540.
Cuz I already know it takes 540. So,
Cuz I already know it takes 540. So, we
can
can save
Cuz I already know it takes 540. So, we
can save enormous
can save enormous amounts
Cuz I already know it takes 540. So, we
can save enormous amounts of
can save enormous amounts of money
Cuz I already know it takes 540. So, we
can save enormous amounts of money in
research.
research. I
research. I don't
research. I don't have
research. I don't have to
research. I don't have to go
research. I don't have to go out
research. I don't have to go out there
and
and expend
research. I don't have to go out there
and expend all
and expend all kinds
research. I don't have to go out there
and expend all kinds of
and expend all kinds of money
research. I don't have to go out there
and expend all kinds of money on
research.
research. I
research. I already
research. I already know
research. I already know what
research. I already know what works
before
before the
research. I already know what works
before the experiment
before the experiment starts
from
from the
from the experimental
from the experimental design
from the experimental design and
from the experimental design and the
intention.
intention. You
from the experimental design and the
intention. You already
intention. You already know
from the experimental design and the
intention. You already know the
intention. You already know the result
that
that will
that will be
that will be found.
that will be found. Huh?
that will be found. Huh? Because
that will be found. Huh? Because it
that will be found. Huh? Because it was
already
already set
that will be found. Huh? Because it was
already set up
already set up is
that will be found. Huh? Because it was
already set up is part
already set up is part and
that will be found. Huh? Because it was
already set up is part and parcel
already set up is part and parcel the
way
way it's
way it's set
way it's set up
way it's set up and
way it's set up and the
way it's set up and the intentionalities
involved.
If
If the
If the thing
If the thing is
If the thing is politically
If the thing is politically favor
favored,
favored, you
If the thing is politically favor
favored, you will
favored, you will always
If the thing is politically favor
favored, you will always get
favored, you will always get grants
If the thing is politically favor
favored, you will always get grants for
that
that to
that to prove
that to prove that
that to prove that something
that to prove that something or
that to prove that something or other
causes
causes something.
that to prove that something or other
causes something. If
causes something. If you
that to prove that something or other
causes something. If you want
causes something. If you want to
that to prove that something or other
causes something. If you want to set
causes something. If you want to set one
up
up equally
up equally that
up equally that proves
up equally that proves it
up equally that proves it doesn't
up equally that proves it doesn't do
that,
that, you
up equally that proves it doesn't do
that, you won't
that, you won't get
up equally that proves it doesn't do
that, you won't get funding.
you
you won't
you won't get
you won't get funding.
you won't get funding. You
you won't get funding. You know,
you won't get funding. You know, it's
not
not in
you won't get funding. You know, it's
not in favor.
not in favor. All right.
you won't get funding. You know, it's
not in favor. All right. So,
not in favor. All right. So, here
you won't get funding. You know, it's
not in favor. All right. So, here here's
who
who we
who we are.
who we are. This
who we are. This can
who we are. This can be
who we are. This can be anybody.
who we are. This can be anybody. And
here's
here's uh
who we are. This can be anybody. And
here's uh where
here's uh where we're
who we are. This can be anybody. And
here's uh where we're moving.
here's uh where we're moving. It
who we are. This can be anybody. And
here's uh where we're moving. It can
here's uh where we're moving. It can be
any
any kind
any kind of
any kind of an
any kind of an audience.
any kind of an audience. It
any kind of an audience. It can
any kind of an audience. It can be
any kind of an audience. It can be a
buyer
buyer group.
any kind of an audience. It can be a
buyer group. It
buyer group. It can
any kind of an audience. It can be a
buyer group. It can be
buyer group. It can be a
any kind of an audience. It can be a
buyer group. It can be a political
group.
group. And
group. And of
group. And of course,
group. And of course, we
group. And of course, we use
group. And of course, we use it
group. And of course, we use it all
group. And of course, we use it all the
time
time in
group. And of course, we use it all the
time in spirituality.
time in spirituality. Okay,
group. And of course, we use it all the
time in spirituality. Okay, let's
time in spirituality. Okay, let's move
on
on to
on to the
on to the next.
We're
We're almost
on to the next.
We're almost done,
We're almost done, are
on to the next.
We're almost done, are we?
Hallelujah.
Hallelujah.AlleluAllelu.
Hallelu.