Praise
God.
and
>> Okay. Yeah.
>> Yeah.
>> Ready? Fire away.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Here's your first one. Yes,
>> I'm your first customer today.
>> Yes.
>> When you are seeing the sanctity and
beauty of all life and all of creation,
how do you see the love for like
hardened criminals, the Komodo dragon,
serial killers
>> that's trying to force a a shift in
perception?
>> Uh you hold what you envision. No,
you're trying to change things out
there.
>> Uh don't try and change your perception.
Just be with the idealization of what
you envision for yourself and then the
perception will take care of itself.
In other words, you can't force yourself
to love criminals. That's that's that's
a pseudo spiritual proposition. You
can't do it.
>> As long as you see them as a criminal,
you're not going to love them.
>> So, don't see them as a criminal. See
them as someone with a lot of karma to
work off and hope they don't come into
>> That's still a program. That's still a
program. You laying a program on them.
If you're going to ask to to be shown
what they are in truth, then don't lay
programs on it.
>> See them as perfect.
>> You're adding a program. Don't you see?
If I ask you to look at this, I don't
want you to tell me that you want to see
it as beautiful. You've already laid a
program on it.
>> Right?
>> So, it's shifting positionality that it
is a criminal in the first place.
That's a leas.
>> Did you ever do the course of miracles?
>> Nope.
>> Oh, okay. All right. One principle is
the miracle is
you ask the Holy Spirit to show you
something as it is in truth. As it is in
truth. But you don't try to tell the
Holy Spirit what the truth is. Right?
>> That's called outlining.
You want to see criminals as lovable.
Right?
>> You're laying a program on it, trying to
tell God how you think you should be
seeing it.
>> Right?
>> Those are presumptions, illusions,
presumptions you're projecting onto it.
>> You know, you know the program they have
in prisons for prisoners teaching dogs
how to become blind, seeing eye dogs.
Do you know that those people in the
prison will even stay longer after their
sentence is over to finish training a
dog?
>> They're due out in March and they'll
hang until end of June because this dog
isn't ready for the world yet.
>> Right.
>> Okay.
>> So, it's innate in everybody for
divinity. Okay. Thank you.
>> It's a wonderful program. I forget what
it's called.
dogs.
Totally narcissistic, selfish, greedy
people who only care about themsel and
spent their life kicking dogs now learn
what love is, what concern for another
human, what another being is, begin to
pour themsel into that and instantly,
you know, they go over 200.
>> I don't have a question, but I'm
wondering whether the dollar special is
still in effect. I brought my dollar.
>> Depends on what you want for a dollar.
>> A hug.
>> You can have a hug for a dollar.
>> Kisses are more expensive.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you for everything today.
>> Thanks a lot. Kisses will cost you two.
Yep.
>> All right. So, there's our
>> He's been here before.
>> I know he's been here before.
>> Okay.
>> You know where these dollars go? They
they go to all the people who help you
in the airports
and push the wheelchairs and
turn you around. They get them all.
They're wonderful in Phoenix. They all
come from a certain place in Africa.
They're the most loving, wonderful
people. You know, you'll see one guy's
carrying your baggage and other people
showing you where to go. Another one's
pushed in a wheelchair. And they have a
integrated lovingness with each other
and communication. They all come from
someplace, Kenya or some place, you
know, a stunning
uh sort of integrity of who they are to
the world, you know, and it's sort of
beautiful to watch, you know, they just
they pass each other and they send each
other loving messages as they pass the
hallway. It's sort of a fun thing, you
know,
sort of a fun thing.
>> Uh Dr. Hawkins, I just want to thank you
uh for being my teacher uh for the last
year and a half. I've been coming since
uh I guess February of 2003
and I read your book Power Bar versus
Force
uh which helped me finish my book uh the
CEO challenge.
>> Mhm.
>> And I would just like to share that book
with you.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay.
>> And I guess I want to ask you
>> this is this has to do with spirit and
business. Huh.
>> Yes. Getting spirituality in business.
And I've asked you and I've heard you
talk from the platform about CEOs and
and your compassion for CEOs
and the difficult job they have. And I
guess my question is u
you mentioned I think sometime early
this week this year that CEOs were
somewhere at the 197 or 198 level.
>> One time we did uh CEOs of the top 500
uh in Fortune magazine. Mhm. Yeah.
>> That was
>> that was I think before the collapse of
all those uh inrons and people
>> and uh I guess my question is I've been
working with CEOs my whole life. I'm a
consultant and
>> what how do we get CEOs to a to a 200
level? What what is the awareness they
need in your experience?
>> I don't want to control them
>> and I don't either.
>> Yeah, you do.
Touche.
What's happened is that the field the
overall field of consciousness which was
at 190
uh you know until the late 80s it moved
up am I my numbers right moved up to uh
no I'm sorry to the late ' 80s the time
of the harmonic concordance suddenly it
went from 190 where it' been for many
centuries jumped to 205
well the world of 205 is different than
the world of 190 I'll tell you what you
can get away with at 190
is going to surface because like now
it's like oil and water. It's going to
surface and then to make it worse in
October 14th of last year it jumped from
205 to 207. Well, if the overall field
of consciousness is 207,
then that which is not integrous is
going to come to the surface. It's going
to be finessed out like a poker game.
So what
uh was the old boy way of doing things?
A little here, a little there. We just
close our eyes. We'll wink at this and
wink at that. Uh doesn't work anymore
because in a more integrous field, that
which is non integrous begins to show
up.
One reason women CEOs uh their companies
did better according to Fortune magazine
in 203 2003. The reason the companies
run by women did better than those run
by men is because women are new to the
game. They watch their P's and Q's.
They're not part of the old boy network.
They're not used to closing their eyes
to this little uh irregularity
in return for which the other guy gets
you favors. On the contrary, the women
are very scrupulous. So the women are
scrupulously honest.
That'll last for a generation or so and
then they'll learn to play the old girl
network.
Hazel,
I know they're a little out of date, but
can't you just change the date on and
ship them to me? Nobody's going to
notice. You know what I mean?
That's the way it's been done. Yeah.
Don't work that way no more. Okay.
>> Very good. Thank you. The field has
changed.
>> Okay, great.
>> So, the non-integrate CEO is going to
have a tough time now.
At 190, he thrived. At 207, he's going
to be called into court.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> So, you see corp corporate America's
cleaning house.
>> Corporate America. You can see a
celebrity. If she just had a little
humility, you wouldn't even be in jail,
would she?
You said, "So, I'm sorry. I made a
mistake." That's all that was required.
That's all required. Gee, I'm sorry I
made a mistake. Everybody would have
said, "So what?"
Thank you.
>> Hi, Dr. Hawkins. Um, I'm the fellow who
was involved in a a cult group in
Colorado,
and I had emailed you some information
on it.
I'm thankful for Lou and Shelly.
>> Oh, that one.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh,
>> all the cult stories are horrible. Some
are worse than others.
>> Yeah. I think they cal calibrated the
group at like 65.
>> Where do you want me to sign? Yeah.
>> Uh, my question is we were involved or
my wife and two daughters are still
involved in the group. I've been was
with the group for three years and
>> by the grace of God I'm out of it. But
I'm in a custody battle with uh my
13-year-old daughter.
>> Yeah.
>> She's been in the group 3 years and
brainwashed and
>> right,
>> you know, I'm working to get custody of
her. My question is then,
>> you know, you gave me gave us some great
ideas for just living the concepts that
of goodness, of patience, of kindness.
Is there anything else that I can do for
my daughter um as far as uh
reprogramming her and helping her?
>> She's with her the mother
>> with the mother right now.
>> The mother's in in the cult.
>> Yes.
>> And what are you trying to do, sir? I
want her because the mother's in a cult.
>> No, we're going through a divorce and
we're um I'm trying to get custody of
>> On what basis are you going to get
custody?
>> That she's involved in this cult group.
>> Oh, everybody's got a cult. So, what
that what was that going to get you in
court just because you called a cult?
>> Well, we're having a child advocate uh
work with us on that.
>> You're going to have some professional
opinion.
>> Yes.
>> In a child custody case, that may carry
weight.
>> Yes.
>> In a major major case, that doesn't
carry weight.
>> It doesn't carry weight.
>> No.
>> That doesn't negate the mother's rights.
She's got a right of freedom to believe
as she wants to believe. Just the fact
that you differ with her and you want to
make her wrong. That's not a legal
basis.
>> You know, the the group has done some
pretty unscrupulous things.
>> I'm sure they've done things that I
don't want to even hear about.
>> Right.
>> But is there anything like, you know, if
I would get custody of, you know, things
that you would recommend uh
reprogramming or
>> I would recommend you go to uh Elan.
>> Okay.
because you're going to try force.
>> I don't want to do that.
>> Yeah. I don't think you're going to win
with force. See, you have to increase
your own spiritual power so that
that which you are attracts the
resolution. Besides, you don't know what
her karma is.
>> You want the court to negate her karma.
I don't know.
>> So, yeah. you see
doing the course of miracles or doing
the 12step program.
I mean in the office I would tell you go
go to Alanon pick up the basic
principles of Alanon and apply it in
this case. See
>> and then it'll resolve itself. Of course
within the world world you do what you
can within reason
but then don't forget that force results
in counterforce.
attraction. There's no resistance.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> I know what kind of anguish you're
talking about
and other than the fir you know
other than like joining an I would join
on
>> just to get the principles.
>> Well, you got a heck of a problem here.
and the the problems that you're running
into are almost identical. You're trying
to save the drowning person, etc., etc.
So,
you know, you're going to be a savior
here and and you know, you so you've got
multiple things going on. I think you
need the spiritual strength of a group
for one thing and their shared
experience who've been through
impossible situations
and of course the best legal advice you
can get as well. Doesn't mean to be
stupid.
>> Mhm.
>> But you need you're going to win it with
power not with force. I don't think you
got enough legal basis.
>> I have legal I have a attorney.
>> Yeah. You got an attorney, right?
Everybody's got an attorney. attorney.
>> I mean, has she been tortured,
raped, burned?
>> Starved?
>> No.
>> Oh, then how do you show child abuse?
>> Just because you don't believe what they
believe?
>> Yeah. There's, you know,
>> I mean, in a court of law, you
understand what I'm saying?
>> Yes.
>> The the raw law of it is you don't have
a case that I can hear except that you
allege that they're weird people in
culcating her with weird ideas. Mhm.
>> Well,
>> you know, there has been some pretty,
you know, some
>> to them. You have very weird ideas. You
understand what I'm saying?
>> Yes.
>> Okay. Okay. Now, you got where you're at
legally. That's why I'd say the other
attorney and you got really weird ideas,
man. You don't believe this stuff.
>> This is the truth of God. Don't you know
>> it's coming from master blah blah on the
other side or something.
>> Okay.
>> All right. Thank you very much. Allen
dry alone just because of the wisdom and
the strength there. You understand?
>> Because you don't you don't want to do
this on all alone. It's too too
ravaging.
>> You need friends compadres.
>> It's too hard. It's a tough one.
Why don't you get down go down the drain
of the cult?
This is really This is really frivolous.
But what cat foods
Oh.
That's okay.
>> I'll tell you the one she likes.
Whiskers. Fancy feast.
Mention some cat foods. Mention some cat
foods. What do you see on the
supermarket shelf?
>> What's
>> Oh, well, there's that pyina cat chow.
>> I don't have a cat yet, but you know,
I'm in the market.
>> We We'll whisper to you which one not to
buy.
That's right. We have to be
>> nine lives.
>> Got it. Thank you. My cat to be Thank
you.
>> That'll be a dollar.
>> No, sweetheart. That That's the That's
correct. Now, I recalibrated those
brands again, and uh by God, it's
same. And I tried her on that same cat
food that she turned her nose up at
before because it's cheaper
and fancy fees is expensive. But anyway,
no. She turned it down again. So I said,
"Well, we recalibrate it." My god, it
was like 190. Huh?
>> Yeah.
In your last uh uh tape set that you did
um the LA the night and Gal Conan one,
you mentioned that when we are born that
we have a a date set for our death.
>> Yep.
>> And I wondered how um you also mentioned
several times that you could you have
permission to leave whenever you want.
>> You have to what?
>> That you have permission to leave.
>> Uh you'll get because in that space
you're not not controlled by karma. It's
nonlinear. So once you're beyond that,
you don't either.
>> Well, you're outside of time. So there
is no time in which you're going to
leave because your reality isn't in the
time you're living to begin with.
>> Okay.
>> So the leavingness has to do with
bodiness,
>> right? So what about when you talk about
us, you know, uh getting into the uh
culture and the downtown uh inner cities
and that and getting killed, would we
not get killed unless it was the right
date?
Uh, in that case,
uh, you're coming from a different
context.
>> You're coming from a different context.
Uh, you're saying if it's when I'm set
to leave, why can't I just close my eyes
when I'm driving on the highway and be
safe?
>> Well, no. I could get paralyzed for
life. You know, I'd be could be mangled,
but I wouldn't die. That's what I'm
wondering.
>> You're misconceiving then.
>> Okay, then what do I where am I wrong?
that if if I mean I have to take care of
myself if I don't want to be
>> you take care of yourself to the best of
ability and one of the reasons you'll
probably live longer
>> is because that's the way how that karma
expresses itself with you
in other words people say well if I
hadn't taken the vitamins all all these
years I wouldn't have lived this long
but it's because of the spirit in you
lighting up your karmic inheritance that
you value your life enough to do that.
Don't you understand?
>> Yeah.
>> So, you're trying to make linear that
which is nonlinear.
>> It's it's perceived within
time which is linear,
>> right?
>> But it doesn't happen within time. The
reality of that which you are
>> uh doesn't shift.
>> Um
it's not so much a calendar time as a
sequence time. That was
>> in fact you read with some teachers that
every single move you make was already
preset at the moment you were born.
>> Everything you said and done in this
life so far was already already preset.
Of course the miracle says you know
this you've already lived this all just
recalling it.
>> You're recalling it. Yeah.
>> So it's the the answer is really that
it's it doesn't be a linear idea
>> and it's really
>> point is you don't have to worry about
it.
>> I don't want to go till I'm supposed to
>> Well, if you're destined to leave early,
you'll be very careless about your
health.
>> I see.
whether you live or or stay is relevant.
>> Dr. Hawkins, my my name is Qui Curry and
uh I'm from Littleton, Colorado. And my
question is sort of built around uh uh
the idea of holding on to things and um
you know in your perspectives and I I
know that you have a a fine Cadillac car
and I I'd like to ask you if you would
like to sell your Cadillac
He went to buy my Cadillac car.
>> He says, "You have a fine Cadillac car."
And he wants to know if you want to sell
that Cadillac car.
>> You saw it on the parking lot, right? No
wonder he wants it.
>> Beautiful.
Beautiful.
If you if I washed it, it would help.
>> No, no, it's beautiful.
>> Uh, it just is a classic design.
>> It's a classic design. Exactly.
>> And of course, what I really like the
the great cars in the 20s.
>> Mhm.
>> You know, the great old Packards, the
>> 12cylinder eight I used to have an eight
cylinder straight eight Packard that had
90. It floated.
>> Wow.
>> Down the New Jersey turnpike. That was a
46.
Yeah. And it weighed a lot. Weighed a
lot. But if you backed into it, you got
the dead fender. I didn't say it was a
big heavy
46 Packer convertible.
>> Straight A engine, you know. Now, this
is an 84. And uh I I think it'll be uh
you know it's moving from oldie to
collectible and I figure if I just to
keep it polished
I can get a good price out of you 10
more years
your phone number.
>> Okay.
>> Now she keeps saying you're not going to
go to town in that radial car are you?
That's I love that car. Oh,
>> so so I guess the answer is however stay
in touch
and when when I pass on I'll leave a
note in my will your name and phone
number and we'll call you.
You can have it when I pass on. I don't
I won't I won't need it after that.
I'll have an etheoric car,
a 46 theory car.
>> After everything I have to know for
enlightenment, I only want to thank you,
Lord, and ask you if I get a free hug.
>> A free hug?
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, he wants a free one.
I have to, of course, prove I'm
non-material by giving a free one.
>> Where are you from?
>> Austria.
>> Oh, yeah.
>> He came all his way to see you.
>> Yes, that's true.
>> I hope to visit Austria. I want to have
chocolate cake in Vienna.
I want chocolate cake in Vienna with
whipped cream.
>> Well together.
>> Okay. So
>> this is a book is for you is written by
my wife.
>> Oh.
>> And this is about the for children
teaching them the power of love.
>> Oh.
>> That can heal. And so we she like to
rewrite this book
>> and we like to ask you for calibration
if
>> is it about love.
>> This is about the power of love.
>> The power of love. It's over 500
>> if it's about love and the power of
love. It's over 500. Yeah. And we
planned just now she my wife
>> to wrote the next series of the book for
children inspirational
>> uh based on your teachings.
>> Oh yes
>> and we would like to ask you for
permission to contact you in this regard
because also I will have few questions.
So if possible to contact us on her next
book
>> or you'll send us an email about it
>> by letter
or some she usually will get it.
>> Yes the email.
>> So I just like to ask for permission. I
know that you your universe is one for
like complete and sometimes you came
here to teach but this why I'm asking
for permission to contact you. Oh,
>> so you just email Gigi.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah.
>> GG. You should give me the email
address.
>> Mhm.
>> So, we were born in Poland, live in
Canada, and we where we will die, we
don't know.
>> First of all, we will not die.
>> I I love
>> We will not die.
>> Where? Where?
>> Probably on this planet. Probably on
this
Thank you very much.
>> Thank you very much.
>> My sister,
>> she she writes about uh she writes about
bringing love to children. Huh?
That's a wonderful thing. Yeah.
Yeah. Who are these books by? Well, I'll
sign them anyway.
>> Oh, you got it backwards.
>> Says these books are by Punker
Hoopington. Well, that's all right. I'll
sign them.
They're all green. I didn't know they
were green.
>> Okay. What?
>> So, basically,
if we take on and reflect the qualities
of divinity
and own all the levels of human
consciousness within ourselves, then we
will transcend
that and all questions will be answered.
That's sort of how it goes.
There won't be any questions to be
answered.
>> Everything becomes obvious.
Everything becomes obvious.
And there aren't any questions left.
The only questions we ask have to do
with the with form and linearity
and the world to
adjust that which is witnessed to
contextualize it in ways that are
comprehensible to the intellect
in and of themsel they're meaningless.
But because you have to go that way on
the highway, somebody should leave the
map of this is the right turn, this is
the wrong turn.
It isn't that you won't get there
because your intention will eventually.
But instead of going this way and that
way,
you know,
>> shortcut.
>> Mhm.
>> I think I can give you another inch. I'm
a roller.
>> Oh, yes.
>> Probably you could. You know,
>> he's cheating. He just saw me limping
and he knows he's got me.
>> Inch and a half and I'll call you.
only shrinking of a quarter of an inch a
year.
My your feet get longer and you get
shorter. It's like you're a gummy bear
and you're like
I used to wear a size seven. These are
10 10 and a half.
I used to be 57. I'm 5'5 and a half or
something.
>> You're puddling.
>> I'm puddling. She says
you slowly melt like a gummy bear.
You get shorter and shorter and your
feet get longer. Is that funny or what?
I don't know if Ralphin can do much with
that.
I'd have to make my feet shorter and
make me taller. Push it all back up the
other way.
Yeah.
>> Okay. I have I have the uh following
question. I recall on one of your last
chapters of the book of the eye.
>> Yeah.
>> The the shortest cut or straight path
for self-realization was to ask
yourself, how am I aware?
>> Or how do I know that I even exist?
>> How do I know I exist? How do I know I
exist?
>> How do I know that I exist? Or how do I
know that I'm aware?
>> You look to the substrate of
subjectivity itself.
>> Okay. that which uh that out of which
experiencing your own existence is
arising. Yeah.
>> Okay. Because in some moments I feel
comfortable starting to do that but I I
have also started with a course of
miracles by myself. I'm like I'm in
lesson like 35 or so.
Is there any easier or straighter or
get there in a hurry?
>> Just with those questions to get there
in a hurry.
start at 35 and do every fifth lesson.
Actually, you only need one. You get
that one completely, it'll save you
doing 364 more.
Mhm.
So each one you can get the totality of
it or you can get it peacemeal
but surrendering is not something that
people are familiar with. It's con, you
know, they confuse it with being
defeated, giving up.
And um it is a profound uh it's profound
when you totally give up. It is coming
from a much greater depth than you'd
realized. And you've now and then now
now you know why it was so hard to
surrender things because that ego is
ferocious. I mean its tenacity is like
and it hangs on
and it's only
uh the combination of your will
empowered by divine divine will that can
overcome it.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
Plus the conviction that it can be done,
the knowingness that can be done. That's
the value of a teacher is it conveys the
knowingness.
>> Well, doctor, that's for my friend Jim.
He's been kind of hard on your book, but
he'd still like it.
>> Autograph.
>> Um, I have a question about you
calibrated Tai Chi and yoga. I wonder if
there's any other disciplines or
>> sports in your upcoming book.
>> Y
>> I was wondering about
>> sunbathing. We forgot sunbathing.
>> Sunbathing.
>> I was wondering about archery. I thought
I might take that up, but not if it was
going to be like 35 or something like
that.
>> I don't I don't think we remembered
archery. Did you ever read Zen and the
art of archery?
>> That's what I'm reading now.
>> Oh, I used to do archery. Uh, no, we
didn't calibrate it. It's a good one.
See, this is why we never finished the
book on the way home. I'll think of
three things. She'll think of three
things. We'll get an email about and
don't forget Babacha who wrote so and so
back in 1622. And I said, and she'll
say, I can't go anymore today.
>> Anyway,
what was it you said?
>> I just wonder where archery would come.
>> Oh, archery. Yes. Okay, we'll have to do
archery, huh? You want to do archery?
>> Sure.
>> You want to do archery now?
>> Yep.
>> All right. Uh, we have permission to ask
archery? Let's see. Archery is done by
whom you mean? Um, the highest form.
Let's take it the highest form of
archery. The highest form of archery
calibrates over 360, 380, 390.
Highest form of archery calibrates over
390, 395. Okay? So, it's purity of
intention. See, because the way you
learn to do it is to not think it and
just let the arrow fly itself. See,
that's 390. That's so it's I would think
let me go a different archery. Um, the
kind of archery I'm envisioning, the Zen
archery calibrates over 450, 480, 475.
Yeah, Zen archery is about 475. Ordinary
archery is about, what did I say? 390.
>> 390.
>> Yeah, that's very high intention. 390.
>> Yeah,
>> thank you very much.
>> I gave it up because without a thumb,
you can't do it anymore.
I had to give up the bag pipes
and archery.
>> Playing the piano.
>> And playing the piano. Yeah. I will,
however, I will play a musical
instrument. The next the next lecture I
will play a musical instrument.
>> Yep.
Or I'll make music. I'd like some
clarification about where I'd like some
clarification about where the expression
of love and compassion run into or where
where they run out and
where interfering with people's lives,
interfering with their destiny starts.
>> I don't understand the question. Um, she
wants to know where love and compassion
for mankind comes in and where
interfering with their destiny or lives.
What's
>> now? That's a very sophisticated
question.
>> You know, on a calibration scale, love
it calibrates at 500.
Love is a meu kind of a relationship
until you get to a higher state in which
love is what you have become. Now how
you perceive life, how you understand
life is different at the various levels.
So what was the question?
>> When does it become interfering with
one's life? Uh with another person's
karma or
>> Yes. Correct. Yes. Correct. Mhm. Um
that's a sensitivity of knowing when
intervention is appropriate.
when it's appropriate and when it is
um
inappropriate.
Uh if you know kinesiology, I might ask
that. I might say uh this is the
person's karma. Yes. No. It it would
serve the highest good for me to
intervene. Yes. No.
That would be a way of finding because
it's a complex question. Uh a simple
answer in the name of the highest good
it would be best that I intervene. Yes.
No.
In a situation I'm thinking about now we
got no
that that lesson can only be learned
by hitting bottom.
That's why I suggest a lot of times
Elanon because the temptation there is
to try to intervene and keep the person
from hitting bottom when it's by hitting
that hitting bottom is the source of
their salvation. So what you're doing is
killing them. See, you pay all their
bills, they can't pay them anymore, etc.
So you could follow a spiritual group.
The whole way of looking at it of
Elanon, let's say, and the way of
looking at of the course of miracles,
you could use kinesiology to ask
specifically,
you know, and what's my karmic
uh what's coming up for me karmically,
not just what the other person.
This could be a lesson where you learn
to be self-sacrificing for the good of
something greater than yourself.
Or it could be that you've got a
program.
So I would say what would I get out of
it to see what kind of a program
you're fooling yourself into thinking
you're doing it for their sake. The
communist program is to prove that
you're right.
>> But if someone's lying by the roadside
needs help,
>> you do what's automatic. You don't have
to think about that.
>> Drive on quickly.
G giving to charities.
>> The good Samaritan lived in a different
era.
>> But giving to charities. Giving to
charities.
>> You do you do that which is appropriate
for the level that you're at.
So there is no absolute answer to the
question uh because it would depend on
on where the person is at in their own
evolution. There's a point at which the
lesson is to stop by the side of the
road and there's a very advanced lesson
where the lesson is not to stop by the
side of the road and it takes a great
deal of discernment to know which is up.
>> Thank you. And could I have a hug
please? Yes.
>> So
New Zealand for this.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> The question is when are you being an
enabler? You see, so it's a subtle
question. It depends on many other
things. Depends on what lesson is being
learned at this time by both people. You
know, that's why I think, you know,
physiology in the highest name of the
highest good, which would be the best
way to go when you really can't figure
it out.
>> I first want to say I'm grateful for
your consciousness because I definitely
am feeling something that is almost like
I can't speak. Um, but my question was
about when spiritual energy begins to
move, do you have any words of wisdom,
state of being, blessings for people?
I need to speak directly into the mic.
Okay. Oh. Oh, the wrong one.
>> I was just saying when people begin to
feel spiritual energy, your third their
brain, whatever, start moving through
them. Do you have any words of wisdom,
any states of being or blessings?
>> The movement of kind of lending energy
into the brain is exquisite.
>> Yes.
>> It may last for years.
lasted oh I don't know five seven years
something like that
uh
if you focus your attention on one side
of the brain you'll feel it blow flow
more into that side if you focus your
attention over here you'll feel it more
into this side
um there's nothing to do about it except
be thankful and enjoy it
This one I've reached a real block. I
feel that I have I've reached a real
pinnacle of intellectual understanding
of spirituality and I have a lot of
spiritual realizations but it's like
stuck there and I feel like all these
questions I'm asking is just running in
circles. All this reading is just
running in circles and it's like and I
know the to take that jump into the
subjective is like the last step is
taken by God. But how do I like kick
that door in or what am I doing or not
doing? It's like a thorn in my mind that
I just cannot get rid of.
>> You can't get rid of what?
>> This it's like I'm just stuck in place.
It's like I'm not I'm at this wall that
I cannot break through to get to the
subjective actual experience. I
understand it, but I don't experience
the action.
>> Oh, you're trying to achieve something,
a spiritual experience.
Let go of that.
>> Let yourself be defeated by the wall.
Okay, well, you win.
>> There you are. No conflict.
>> Well, that was pretty easy.
>> All this time for nothing.
That's trying to solve a Zen Cohen, you
see, and finally you surrender and give
up.
>> Yeah.
>> But then also part of that is like I
feel I have a lot of obligations to
people in my life. Like I've say a lot
of things like, you know, I'm going to
be here for to help you through this
business thing, whatever it is. But I
feel like a tied to these obligations
and I feel like if I take that step, I'm
going to be so out of it that I'm not
even going to be functioning in real
life.
>> How do you know you're going to be out
of it?
>> I don't know. I just have this, you
know, it's like a a fear or a feeling.
It's because he looks at you and you can
tell that's what happened.
>> Yeah. I don't have some
help drive.
>> You say if I become if I become
enlightened, the business is going to go
down the drain, right?
>> Yeah. Exactly.
>> See, that's very that's very sad. That's
very sad. Stuck in some
>> Oh, that's a g Oh god, that is a
tragedy.
>> Put off being enlightened till you
finish the business.
Yeah, that's not going to work.
>> Well, if you're unable to function and
uh support yourself, it'll be God's
problem.
And if he doesn't, then you die. So, no
>> That works for me.
>> No problem.
>> Well, thanks so much.
>> Okay.
We can buy probably buy his company
cheap right now. Then
>> I'd like to thank you for your sharing
your sense of humor. I very much enjoyed
it. And I'm here with a group of 10
people from uh around the country. We're
>> working to manifest a theater in the
Sedona area and it has to do with
helping people find their heart and
using marionets. And I brought some
information on and I'd simply like to
leave it if that's okay.
Yeah. Who was it that couldn't find his
heart? The tin woodman. No, with the
lion.
>> Oh, they had to get him a heart, didn't
they?
>> Oh, yes.
>> And I'd like to ask you a question.
If you can provide any insight in
understanding the or insight on
communication with the higher self and
what that experience feels like in
contrast to the and in discernment to
the admonitions you gave about um the
the astral and such to avoid other words
how would you know is there anything you
can say about that
>> you've asked me three or four questions
what was the first question
>> if you can provide insight on how to
know when you're communicating with a
higher self. When you're in
>> I wouldn't try and communicate with it.
>> Okay.
>> Heck with it.
It's your higher self's problem. So,
you're setting up a dualistic. There's a
me and then there's my higher self.
>> That's a duality and you projecting a a
separation which doesn't exist.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. You just be
uh what you're inspired to be.
uh thereby fulfilling your destiny and
uh the working out of whatever karmic
momentum you have. If it's to do what
you're doing, then that is the artistic
expression that it's taking at this
particular point. You know what I mean?
So it isn't like there's a you and then
your higher self. Your higher self
is what is guy guides you. You might say
I say people say, "Well, I'm alive
because of the ego. If it weren't for
the ego, I'd forget to take my vitamin
pills. But it's because of the spirit
that your ego values taking uh vitamin
pills and supporting your life. So it's
still coming out of the spiritual field,
you know. So you're in you feel inspired
to do this at this time in your life.
Must be the right way to go. Thank you.
>> Mhm.
Great question.
>> Yeah,
>> I'm still u trying to understand the
concept of causality.
Does the fact that nothing causes
anything else to happen mean that when I
go to play golf next Tuesday and hit
that ball wherever it goes that I didn't
cause that to happen?
>> Cause would be a grandiose delusion.
>> So is that creation unfolding?
>> Yep.
Okay. So you see the propensity
uh you release the trigger.
Let me use a different analogy. You
cannot
uh force a apple to fall to the ground.
If you snip the stem, the apple falls to
the ground. But you didn't cause it to
fall to the ground. Gravity did.
So you triggered the release of the golf
ball, but then you're done.
Potentiality becomes an actuality.
>> If I drop that, right,
>> I didn't cause it. Gravity.
>> Gravity did it.
>> Okay.
>> If you say I caused it to fall,
then you are greater than the power of
gravity. So you must be divinity. See
what I'm saying? As the ego is claiming
authorship
uh claiming the qualities of divinity
that's why it sees things out there that
way because that way it can still
maintain that it really is in
it really is omnipotent.
Anyway, as you can see from the apple
falling from the tree that it's the
field. So you release the potentiality
uh by intention. So that's the power of
intentionality. That's what's his name's
latest book. What is that?
>> Diary.
>> Yeah. There. Um so intentionality then
you might say sets the program. But the
unfolding of the program is up to karmic
propensity and the power of divinity.
Okay.
>> Hitting the golf ball.
>> Yeah. Well, it's same as an apple
dropping from the tree.
Uh,
intention releases a potentiality become
to become an actuality.
You don't create any of those, but you
are the intention.
>> Yep.
>> Um, Nico suggested that perhaps I should
ask that of Susan, but you two can
decide obviously. Um
some some tips about calibrating. I'm
trying to calibrate all the usual
things. Cat, food, people, books. Um I
have I'm getting no kind of um they're
very arbitrary calibrations seemingly. I
can't get two answers the same.
>> Takes practice. Yeah. You got a good
partner to work with?
>> Um
>> which microphone is the one you're
talking into?
>> I'm trying to talk into the silver
>> here.
Thank you. Is that your microphone?
That's what I'm
>> Maybe it's this one
>> that goes to the video camera.
>> Yeah, I was aiming for the silver one.
That was
>> Okay. All right. This is yours. Okay.
Now, what is the question again?
>> Um I I'm asking about some tips about
calibrating. I'm getting no
um consistency in my calibration.
>> Oh, yeah. Trying to calibrate the usual
things.
>> Are you doing it by yourself or with a
partner?
>> With a partner.
>> Okay. Uh it takes practice. Um
we we go over the basics of it. We got
time to go over the basics. One more
time. How much time we got? Yeah, we got
enough. You want to do the basics of
kinesiology again? All right. Both
people have to calibrate integrously.
The intention of the question has to be
integrous.
Therefore,
seeking gain may bias. So, you don't
want to bias the answer. Uh, I don't
care what archery calibrates at. You
know what I'm saying? Um, I'm looking at
in now in my mind. I can hold different
visions of archery and that may explains
why sometimes you get different
calibrations for the same thing. You
always have to hold the same. So if
you're a visual person, all right, now
I'm looking at
uh medieval archery. I'm looking at a
courtyard and I'm looking at as a
military discipline. These are the royal
archers. The Royal Archers calibrate
over 480,
430,
calibrate over 390, 395.
The perfection of archery then as a
discipline is 390.
Now with Zen, you're looking at a
different kind of archery. No, I'm
looking at
um
I'm looking at the bow releasing itself.
When I'm doing zen archery, I don't aim
at anything. When I'm doing military
archery,
I aim I have an estimation of the wind,
the number of yards. I know how many
pounds pull there is on this bow. I know
the design. I'd feathered the arrows
myself, and I can pretty well guarantee
that I'll fall within
a certain designated area.
Practice makes that perfect.
Then there's another way of doing
archery,
which is the way I do it.
You can tell by all the people walking
around with band-aids.
There's no one to release it. There's no
one releasing it and there's nothing
happening. The whole phenomena is a
unitary oneness unfolding
uh to the witnessing of perception.
So there's various ways of doing it.
Yeah. All right. So
the way we do it then is simple. Uh I
press down with how many ounces would
you say? This is more than 2 ounces, 3
oz, 4 oz, 5 oz,
>> more than 6 ounces, more than 5 oz.
about 5 oz. That's just one finger
pressing down. All right. So, she
resists
um equal to the pressure pressing down.
Now, the answer is quick.
Zen archery calibrates over 400.
You see, I don't wait. If I say Zen
Archery calibrates over 400, then I wait
a minute while I talk to you and then I
push her. So the kinesiologic response
through the
acupuncture system is very fast. So
she'll tell you in fact I also the
minute I answer ask the question I
already feel the energy and she feels it
running down her arm and now it's over.
So it's quick
and you're detached.
You're detached. It's irrelevant what
the answer is. Okay. Now there's a way
you can corroborate the answer.
If a certain thing the answer to that is
yes, then many other things would
follow. So you can cross check the
validity of an answer.
Um now you don't want any background
music.
It's best
uh to not have metal crossing the
midline,
steel belts, glasses, etc. Uh you don't
want to do it in a loving way.
You do it in a detached clinical way
because if we're smiling at each other
and thinking of lovely things, we're
going to get a false positive. She's
going to go strong because I'm radiating
love towards her. So you act detached
clinical doctor patient.
Look at yourself as a scientist. You're
only interested in the answer. You got
no you got no investment in the answer
that the figures you get. It doesn't
make any difference what they are. If
they come out different than what you
expect, then
uh with further inquiry, you can find
out.
>> Yeah. All right. If you're getting false
answers, the other thing, yes, you may
be contaminated by heavy metal music and
things like that. You know, if you
listen to music, uh MTV and that kind of
music, uh kill killer rapster rock. Um
kick your pregnant wife in the belly.
And if that don't work, blow her away
with a hollow bullet kind of this music.
You'll find that you the acupuncture is
blow blown system is blown for about
half an hour. So if you've been in the
radio in the car and your radio is
playing, some of that's played as
background music to advertisements. You
just got to program without knowing it.
So you could clear it doing the thyc
thump, you know, Dr. um
>> Diamond
>> Diamond John Diamond, you know. uh we
showed the the effect on the thymus of
negativity is suppression. So you pound
the thymus is right behind the breast
bone. You pound on the thymus. I won't
do it because I got a microphone on, but
you go ha
at that time and while you're doing it,
just smile and think of someone you love
or your kitty or your grandmother or
whatever. See? All right. Now, that
rebalances your acupuncture system.
All right. Sometimes certain people
don't work well together for karmic
reasons. Sometimes husbands and wives
can't use each other. So you sometimes
have to experiment and maybe go to a
class on it and find somebody that you
can work. Then it takes practice like
riding a bicycle. It's it's a subtlety.
It's a subtlety and people look for
something gross, you know. And when we
were in Korea, we had a heck of a time
and we couldn't get anybody to go ne,
you know, say no to anything because
they were like into anti-gravity. You
know, the harder you push, the harder
they push back. You know, it was like a
misamorphic struggle. And I kept, you
know, it's not a it's not strength, you
know, it's a relative. Then there's ways
of doing it yourself. Of course, this
fingers like this, you hold them tightly
together. You picture Ben Louden and
pull as hard as you can. And then you
alternate. You picture Abraham Lincoln
and you pull as hard as you can and
you'll see there's a difference in
strength. See? And if all those things
don't work, give it up.
All right.
>> It's not for everyone. I mean, you know,
>> there's certain things I can't. Oh,
yeah. Let's do the audience. Okay, we
have permission to do the audience. The
audience energy before and after the
lecture went up over nine points. 10
points, 12 points, 14 points, 13 points,
12 points, 13 points, 12 points. That's
a big jump in one day. The average human
being evolves
five points in a lifetime.
And the audience collectively went up 10
points this afternoon. So that means
some people went up over 100 and some
people weren't paying attention.
Once in a while the question answer
thing people ask me a question. I say
were you at the lecture today? You know
they'll ask me something that the whole
lecture was about. What can I do to
advance myself spiritually? I say
eight hours of talking I'm exhausted.
Then they asked me, "What could I do?"
>> Isn't that lovely?
>> Yeah. So,
>> Dr. Hoggins, thank you for your service
to mankind.
>> Yes.
and I serve a church as its pastor and
I'm wanting to find a way to describe or
explain
the role of conversion because there is
a common impression that it is something
that happens outside oneself such as the
Holy Spirit which appeared in one part
of scripture to be external.
uh it can't be external but anyway
>> within the world of the
duality and linear domain and Newtonian
domain it would seem like it's external
obviously it's an internal propensity
and you open the gate to it with your
own consent by your own consent
yeah
by commitment
I commit myself to thee oh Lord to thy
truth into thy divine love and I hold
back nothing.
That doesn't do it. They should going to
church.
>> I have
that. Don't worry. Threaten him with
hell.
Either that or hell, baby. You pick. You
choose.
This lady gave this to us. Aren't they
beautiful?
>> Yeah.
>> Hello. My name is Tammy. I'm from
Oklahoma.
Um
I I come uh unsure of what question to
ask and I've been um consulting uh
higher self even though there isn't
really a higher self because it's not
separate. Um, well, I've been standing
in line as to what the question is and
um
I think the question is what is the
question that I have?
>> I knew you're going to say that.
My mind said she's going to ask him what
is the question?
I don't know.
Um,
>> what is the question? Huh?
>> Yes, that's the question.
>> Why is there a question?
>> And getting into why gets into the
separation, the duality.
>> That's an accusation. You don't have to
know the answer to that one. Just be who
you are.
>> Don't ask the question.
Just be who we are.
>> It's so ultra simple. That's why it's
difficult to see
>> to be a thing. See, to think about it,
that's easy. You've been doing that for
lifetimes.
To just be that.
Okay. You got the power to be that. I
just saw it. You got the power to be
that. Just be it. Be just what you just
sensed this second.
>> Just be that because that's who you are.
>> May I May I share?
>> Okay, let's celebrate it.
>> You saw You saw what I was seeing. You
saw what I was seeing. That's what
you're looking for.
>> Okay. Mhm.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
Mhm.
>> Dr. Hawkins, thank you for allowing me
to find you.
>> Yes,
>> I've seen you a great teacher of
humanity. You have raised the
calibrations of this world many many
times over and uh vibrations are raised
because of your presence. Inspired by
you when I first met you, I asked you at
um about the presidency of the United
States
and you said it calibrates between 4 and
500.
>> The presidency calibrates 460. Yeah.
>> Okay. Inspired by that, I wrote prayer
for the president.
>> If you like, I'll read it or I'll give
it to you. Whatever you think proper and
it is a one-page prayer for the
president. It's a generic prayer for
whoever becomes president.
>> They all need it.
>> Just a minute.
>> Yeah. Mhm.
>> Would you like me to read it?
>> I don't think we have got time to read
it.
>> Okay. I'm going to give it to you. This
is one.
>> I I will value it.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you very much. This is ma this is
manush.
Uh in the forthcoming book there's a
chapter on America. What's the truth
about America?
Nobody nobody seems to get what is the
truth about America. So there was of
course a great book written about it by
a Frenchman
something about democracy. What's it
name?
>> Right. Okay. In the meantime people seem
to have difficulty finding out what it
is. So,
I read an article uh an article
editorial in Arizona Republic. It was
stunning.
10 points. What America is. I thought,
God, where did she come from? It's so
obvious. She got it with absolute
clarity, purity of heart. She saw the
heart of America. And I calibrated it.
It was way up there. So I wrote her and
I said, you know, I would in this
chapter on America, it's so maligned,
people don't even know what they're
talking about. I said, I would like the
the privilege to reprint it. So Manttosh
Montto gave came up and gave me
permission. So in the book on America,
you'll see her name uh and the 10 points
of what America is. So she comes from a
different culture. She comes in and sees
it. It's all so simple.
and she wrote it with great simplicity
and beauty. So I'm very thankful to have
you here today and we are honored by
your presence.
>> May I may I have your permission?
According to the Indian tradition, when
we meet a great teacher, we touch his
feet.
>> I understand the tradition. Yes.
>> Thank you,
>> man. So thank you.
from India.
Americans may not know what America is,
but it's pretty clear to her what it is,
so you'll get to read it.
>> I haven't got time to read it now.
Yeah. A masterful job.
>> Hello.
>> My name is Wendy. Um I I'm new to your
works and um I was in Toronto and and I
live in Toronto and Wayne Dyer gave uh
spoke of your book very highly and I
bought your book that day. Power of
course
>> when you appeared in Toronto I was in
Sedona so I missed you.
>> So I flew back down yesterday to see to
see you here.
>> Um I wish I'd have seen you earlier. Um
do you know Dr. Z game shop. It's uh one
of the I'm I've been searching for a
path and I'm wondering how do people
like myself avoid um getting into
I don't know for lack of a better word I
guess almost cultlike yes things.
>> All right. So that's one of the reasons
I wrote the book that's about to be
published. I think there's about 30 ways
to differentiate the true from the
false. 30 points.
Uh, I can just give you a brief of it.
We got to be done here in what? We got
enough time to finish everything.
>> Five. We'll be done. Five's okay. We're
happy.
>> Okay, we're okay.
>> Um,
>> yeah. Truth is nonlinear. It's always
the same throughout all ages.
Every enlightened mystic has said
exactly the same thing in all cultures
and in all times and in all generations.
That which sounds weird probably is.
Now a a true spiritual teaching seeks
nothing for itself.
It has nothing to gain. Doesn't want
anything from the world. Doesn't want to
change anything. Doesn't want to control
anything.
Doesn't try to enroll people.
is not a pyramid structure. It's not
multi-layered marketing.
You don't get
brownie points for bringing in a
convert. There are no converts. People
are free to come and go without
question.
The teacher is only a teacher. Avoids
agilation titled self agrandisment.
Avoids
seduction by spiritual trappings.
Has no need for edififices.
He's not out to impress anybody.
Neither gains nor loses loses
whether people attend or listen or not.
It has no real opinion on outside
issues. It'll tell you the truth of what
it it thinks it sees. Yeah.
There's nothing to sign, no
subscription, no membership, no dues, no
obligations.
A true spiritual teacher is not
interested in how you dress, your clo
your clothing, your family, or your sex
life, or what you eat.
Doesn't prescribe any weird diets,
exercises, contortions.
does not advise altered states of
consciousness brought about by altered
breathing patterns, exercise patterns,
bio feedback and things like this
because it has no doctrine.
It is essentially non-dualistic.
The only thing a teacher could say that
would be true
would have been true of all the great
teachers throughout all the time because
that which illuminates that which comes
forth as the reality
is always the same.
It is never different.
Therefore it recognizes no partiality,
no specialness.
Each person is within a group like that
what they are because of their
particular energies, talents,
muscles or lack thereof, you know.
So it
it's a it's pristine.
It has nothing to gain. Doesn't want
anything. Doesn't want to own anything.
Doesn't seek any kind of converts gain
power over others.
It just is what it is and that attracts
so it it attracts those who are
interested in that kind of an evolution
of consciousness.
So
the leader or the teacher is not treated
with any kind of specialness any kind of
ooh ah every time his name is mentioned
and his name and his picture goes up on
the screen everybody goes
That's seduction by glamorization.
So
with the music and the hair and the
sandals and the bald head, the staff.
The staff.
The pseudo poverty.
Ah, give me a break.
So, self dramatization would tell you
that they're out. Why why the theatrics?
You know, why the 32-piece band? I mean,
you know what? What is the program?
>> So, it's difficult. Um I I met this uh
gentleman through the learning annex was
appearing with Sri Baba who I felt was a
and I put the two together. So I it's u
sometimes difficult to differentiate
when they're on the same
stage together.
>> Look there's lineages that have been
going on for thousands of years. You
see,
uh, so some entity on the other side,
you know, that it was discovered in
1973,
you know, is unlikely to be divinity.
You know what I'm saying?
>> Master Gingong on the other side to sell
everything and buy horses or something.
>> Understood. Thank you.
>> Are you coming back to Toronto?
>> I like Toronto. in a beautiful city.
>> And of course, that's where we met uh
Elvis or that's where we heard of Elvis.
>> I heard about it when I got home.
>> Elvis was on the front page of the
paper. And this guy had what was it? 18
high power rifles, 6,000 rounds of ammo.
>> And Elvis with a
>> frisbee in his mouth runs up to this
guy, goes like this, and the guy says,
"Geez, what am I doing? What's on the
gun?"
>> Turn himself in.
>> So that was nice of you. Wonderful
>> to arrange while I was there.
>> Yeah. No, I love Toronto. I thought it
was a beautiful, beautiful city.
>> May I have a hug?
>> Oh, you can have a hug, too. Yes.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Mhm.
Yes. Love Toronto is a lovely city. Very
much like Chicago. Calibrated very high
too.
People are lost and can't find
themselves. Chicago calibrates at 4:45.
I advise them to go to Chicago.
>> Did you get my CD?
>> You didn't get it? I sent it to the
office.
>> I don't know. Yes, I think I did.
>> Yes, it came.
>> Yes.
>> Okay.
Okay. I remember.
>> I want to thank your wife for
encouraging you to write and come out
more.
>> There you go.
What have you been doing behind me?
>> She says for me encouraging you to come
out and talk.
>> Oh.
Um
my question has to do with um
experiencing everything as not being
separate and feeling the love and
feeling
that nothing is solid and that
everything is transparent
and how to encourage that to come and
stay.
>> Uh don't try to own it. Don't try and
control it.
spiritual experience as you move up will
as I said during the lecture you
sometimes move ahead of your karma and
you're floating above your karma you're
in an excellent space and then your
karma catches up with you so you can be
like in a butivic space and then it will
fade away. Huh? However, the butivic
space is to give you an advance of how
it's going to be in the future. So
instead of mourning that it has left,
take that as encouragement that you're
on the right track because people who
are not headed in a spiritual direction
are not having you know psychedelic
beautiful experiences of the sunset
except with alchemical assistance.
So it means you it's encouraging
you just continue in that direction.
See, and the hardest thing I think to
learn about it all is patience. That the
phenomena has to unfold of its own.
The phenomena have to uh the phenomena
unfold as the field can handle it. If
you try to force it past the what the
field can hold,
um you can fragment.
You know, I used to be a consultant of
the Zen monastery in the simultaneously
Episcopal Catholic dasis and the places
what they call them communities of nuns
etc. And I would sometimes see people
trying to force a level of consciousness
faster than what their consciousness can
handle and they would have like you know
nervous breakdowns etc.
uh let uh let it the rapidity with which
it then evolves uh be up to divinity.
Also there's changes as you can see in
brain function. There's changes in the
nervous system
past certain points there's very um
agonizing things even that can happen in
the nervous system. So there's a certain
speed I think as you evolve I think the
the the nerves the protein in the nerves
I think the nerves literally begin to
increase their capacity to carry energy
that's a fact resist all right so if you
speed up see because you're talking
about logarithmic power you think moving
from 410 to 420 is is not that all big a
deal that's a logarithm 410 to 420 20 is
a big energy jump. Now I notice
audiences very often collectively go
about the same.
My guess would be physiologically that
is the optimal.
You move faster than that and you'll
start having you might say side effects
from trying to force the condundolini
too fast.
Um
and a major jump in uh consciousness can
have major physiologic uh uh downside.
If you look up the encyclopedia
Britannica mystics, you'll see
the mystics of history. And one of the
advices is be prepared to spend six
months of the year in bed.
So that's moving it too fast. See, uh on
the other hand, sometimes you can't hold
it back. And so
be content with however it goes and just
constantly ask for guidance and be as
gentle and loving towards yourself and
everyone as you can be. And then the
field moves of its own. It fuels its own
capacity. Mhm. Not to do high jumps
before you've mastered the things
because it's almost like a gym. In other
words, don't try certain things until
you build up the muscles and then you
can handle that.
What if everything you believe in is too
suddenly collapses? Can you handle that?
Shock to the nervous system is
tremendous. So,
>> it's happened before.
>> All right. So, therefore, your body, you
see, your physiology is already building
up to handle it. So, I wouldn't worry
about it. You're moving perfectly well.
Let divinity decide, you know, there's
also
a
Thank you.
>> Yeah. Right. Thank you.
>> Yeah. The bag pipes calibrate over 500.
You know, bag pipes 500.
>> No questions.
>> Wonderful.
>> I was in the line. I thought of 20
questions.
>> Uhhuh.
>> I answer them all.
>> The self answers them.
>> Yes. Just gratitude
>> that happens. Yes, that's right. Yeah.
That's how you
question your mind. The energy just
answered it for you.
>> Yeah.
Interesting.
People say, "What was it I was going to
ask?" I don't know.
>> A fairly new visitor.
uh community activist, sometimes office
holder and hopefully states person. But
a concern I've got is is when you look
at uh those people you're trying to help
and yet when you could let the energy
for an awful lot of people is below 200.
>> Mhm.
How do you or or should we be out there
trying and how do we try to move people
again if we want them to have their own
freedom? But h how do we help and or
should we try to help people move into a
better in into a better society and an
environment
>> there?
Yeah. Well, the teacher serves the
function. Um I I think through
inspiration, you know, through
inspiration.
Therefore,
that's one of the functions of the hero.
In Freudian terminology, there's the
ego. There's also what's called the ego
ideal. The ego ideal is those who become
heroes to us. We pattern oursel after
them. They're the yard stick by which we
measure oursel henceforth in life
consciously or unconsciously
to be that which is heroic to those who
need a hero. To demonstrate what that
looks like, how that is. Um to try to
lift the overall field of consciousness
by intention.
uh as they say what you know as you
raise the level of the sea all the ships
on the ocean are effortlessly raised at
the same time I believe in what Bill
Cosby said I think he was dead right uh
what's needed is less excusing less
blaming and a lot more inspiration hard
work and um
so what he was saying is that the way
out the way up is by emphasizing the
importance of the things that we call
spiritual basics. Responsibility,
answerability,
to find the joy, to find the joy in
being all that that you can be.
Uh so he sees them as brainwashed into
failure and using the perpetrator victim
model. He sees them as being victimized
by that kind of ideology and he's pissed
about it. So, as a father, he's saying,
"Jason, don't fall for all this crap.
Get working. Get moving. Get a bicycle.
Get a paper out. Make some bucks.
Respect yourself and everybody around
you. In the meantime, pick up the litter
because you can't come out of it when
surrounded by litter.
So to energize self-esteem,
the value of self-esteem, true
self-esteem,
not self-esteem that's stolen by kicking
down others. See, that's not real
self-esteem. That's cheating your way to
it. See,
so I like what Cosby said. I think we
calibrated it was pretty high, too. He
was saying as a father,
who cares?
And of course, many of the children that
he's talking about don't have a father.
So the men, I think,
everybody thinks it's a mother's got a
job. I don't think so. I think that
there's no father.
Self-indulgence etc.
uh getting things things that the
maternal would usually supply
uh are everywhere. No, what's lacking is
the contribution of uh the male
archetype.
Yeah. And that's what's missing, the
strength. So when the kid looks inside
of himself for the grit to carry him
through the white neckllet, he ain't got
it.
So I see adequate males responsibility
for his children as modeling and being
all that you can be and then inspiring
him and giving him feedback.
When I learned how to box, you know, the
trainer, I'd give the guy a quick one.
He say,
you know what I mean? So you got a coach
cheering for you. So these kids don't
seem to have a coach cheering for them.
So they grab the nearest thing, you
know, rock stars kick pregnant women in
the belly and crap like that, which is
pure garbage. It's garbage, you know.
But so I think people who are integrates
should model that and interface with the
people and present a different
alternative, a different way to go.
>> Yeah. Thank you.
>> You asked me
I'm watching. Yeah. Okay, we'll make it.
>> This will be very fast.
>> Um, today has been magnificent. I thank
both of you for devoting your life to
illuminate the path just a little bit.
>> And my question is, may I have a hug?
Mhm.
>> How's your dad?
>> Hi.
>> My name is Mary and I'm a teacher.
>> Uhhuh.
>> And you had mentioned that um classrooms
now are about at 190 and they used to be
about 400.
>> Yes. And so my question is about how can
I be
a teacher and help my classes and be the
best teacher that I can to bring that
up. I think somehow instilling pride see
what I see lacking is pride. When you
see yourself as victim when anything
goes when there's no truth when there's
no integrity when there's no
answerability
then you get a collapse of society. you
get the you know the fall of the Roman
Empire that's how it came about so the
teacher I think should you know be in
you know first of all instructional but
primarily inspirational
I see my role as a teacher is to be
inspirational convey certain data yes
but then be all that you can be for them
to identify with and be like that you
know to be the kind of teacher they
admire to be somebody they admire are
and respect and in your classroom they
somehow behave. See?
>> Okay. Can I have a hug?
>> Be the kind of teacher that would make a
student feel like they want to behave
around you, like your for thing, your
love is valuable. So you love that which
is integrous and you hold back from that
which is not integrous. See, pretty soon
they want you. They want your approval
and you become important to them. So now
you use that relationship, the positive
transference to help train them.
positive transference. So they must
respect you as a human being. So you got
to hold yourself in high regard and say
I'm not going to put up with that in my
class and forget it. Not as a
disciplinarian but because of who you
are. See
not respecting me and I'm not how do you
expect me to expect respect you if you
don't respect me. So it's like teaching
self-esteem and self-respect which seems
to be why the classes have gone down so
far.
Okay.
>> It's not an intellectual thing.
>> I came Sorry.
>> Excited, huh?
>> My first time here and I've been a
course and student for two years and I
look at my closet. I look at my um
bookcase and there's too many books that
I keep on my time. I want to dump it.
There's one book that I hold on to. I
think it's Course of Miracles. And
besides yours, what's the calibration
level of course of miracles?
>> Course of miracles. I advise people do
the workbook.
One sentence a day is all you can handle
to begin with
>> rather than the lesson.
>> People think they can read whole chapter
and get it. No, you're lucky if you got
half the first sentence. You know,
>> I'm on lesson 35. It took me two days.
>> Yeah. Okay. Just do one lesson. Do one
lesson a day.
If you read the 30 35 lessons the first
day. No, you're not kidding.
No, I would just do one lesson a day for
a year
and I would leave the textbook aside
because that's going to be an
intellectual elaboration. It's going to
set up a dual set up the ego as sort of
an enemy or something. The course of
miracles in of itself the you know
calibrates at 600. Therefore, but it
says to be faithful one sentence, but it
means to like reflect on that sentence
that day. See?
>> Yeah. Like you play with it in your head
like you hold it in your mind, you know.
Let's say it says all birds are
wonderful. H you never thought of birds
being wonderful. Suddenly you start
noticing you know what all birds are
really wonderful.
So then
I think that's if you want one book that
certainly is a great book.
>> When you get further along, you can just
take the bug of a gita with you, but
that's different.
>> Okay, that's the next book.
>> Mhm.
>> Yeah,
>> there's a camera out there.
>> Thank you.
>> Boom. Boom. Boom.
>> Wait. Right here. Right here. Right
here.
>> I think he took my shoes. She took my
shoes.
>> Oh, okay.
>> Blew her shoes right off.
>> Hello.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh, my name is John
>> and I was really glad to hear about
Chicago.
>> Mhm. I have a child in Chicago and um he
mentioned to me a while back that he had
been tested for some reason he had an
extremely high use of his right brain
was mostly all about all he had and um
>> all you guys right
>> yeah pretty much and he's kind of like
that
>> but I was wondering if this uh since
he's my child it's so different uh the
way he is that does this imply
some vulnerability when you're talking
about different paradigms and u going
between them. I just wonder about um
I don't know exactly what I'm trying to
say, but sometimes it seems that he's
very vulnerable because of his way of
looking at the world.
>> How old is he?
>> He's 19. He's an artist.
>> Yeah. 19year-old artist. Yeah. is very
vulnerable to the world.
>> Yeah, I I know that.
>> I think about that a lot.
>> Tell him to move to Paris and right here
>> to Paris.
>> Then you don't have to watch him put
down the tubes, right?
>> He wants to go to Paris.
>> You want to go to Paris?
>> Oh, yeah.
>> Of course.
>> He He should live on the left bank
>> in an attic.
>> I think that's
>> with practically no money.
>> I think he could do that. And around
Christmas, you have to burn the
furniture to stay warm.
>> Sounds about right.
>> He's in love with that paradigm, you
know. Labo,
>> he's what?
>> He you know, lab.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. So that he's he's caught up in
that. And uh it's a beautiful
experience, you know, being
soon as you get tired of being hungry,
you get a job.
I talked to him a few days ago. How do
you feel? And he said, I feel really
unemployed. It's hard to get a job. And
she
>> No, he you know because what what
carries you through that revelation of
that is inspiration, the dedication to
one's heart, the dedication to one's
pathway
depending on the student, you know, is
so that's part of youth and so he should
take advantage of that inspiration while
he's got it.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you.
Isn't this something else?
If you were going to be an artist, I'd
say, "God bless it. Start painting, boy.
Get out of here. Quit driving a cab. Get
some paint in the canvas. Move to Paris.
Move to the left bank."
Yeah. Move to the left bank.
And you have to find a girlfriend named
Mimi.
>> It's hard to get a chest X-ray, though.
>> I basically just want to be in your
presence.
>> Yeah.
>> But um
as humans, we're on the Earth school and
we continue to learn and evolve
and become more conscious. And I was
wondering, I don't know if you can
answer this question or not because
you're not there yet, but when you die,
will you be evolving and continuing to
gain more consciousness? Will your
calibration go up?
>> When I die, will my calibration come go
up?
>> Will you become a
>> I would imagine it would disappear
altogether, would you?
>> Is there is there possibility to become
an archangel?
I have no idea what the ultimate destiny
is.
>> True
>> because
the everything of allness is not does
not have gradations.
Uh
the quality of oneness
uh does not have gradations. Huh? It's
from outside the reality that it seems
to for with from within the reality.
Each thing is complete and total.
Every thing is complete and total. It
leaves nothing more to be gained.
Consequently,
there isn't the fantasy of being
promoted to archangel.
It's a hell of a job to tell you the
truth. I turned it down and I said, "No.
who wants it.
>> I was on the waiting list and I
>> So when you're done, you're done.
>> Well, the completeness of the totality
is complete and then
the whatever
The reality is to the evolution of
consciousness. It is you see and if it
is that which helps support the
advancement of consciousness then it
serves by virtue of what it is not by
virtue of what it does etc. So the
completion is already complete. So
>> understand thank you.
>> So we made it by five. At 5 they're
sending in the cops.
They said to be done by 5. And we're all
supposed to be good little scouts and
pick up our good campers and bring up
our bring our stuff with us. It's been
exquisite. It's been
complete.
There's nothing more I could desire or
wish. It is uh completely 100% complete
at this moment.
>> They would like you to do a prayer.
>> A prayer?
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, a prayer.
I'm praying on top of it.
Dear God, uh we thank thee for the
blessing of our existence. For the
blessing of our existence which is
already the miraculous, the experiencing
of our own existence. We pray for the
awareness
of the reality and the truth of the
source of our existence.
um
for its own sake
to reflect back that reality.
So we are thankful to be together
and I think thankful together to be
again
again all of us have been here together
like a flock of birds many times and now
we've swooped into this little place now
and then we'll all be swooping out. God
knows where are we going next.
>> I'll try to go ahead and signal back to
you where we're going.
Amen. Thank you so much for your
presence. Yeah.
Yeah.
Where are we going as a flock? I don't
know.
>> I think the same place in the celestial
realm. Frankly,
I think we come and return to the same
place in the celestial realm.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu.