thought I would sort of tell you how the day is going to go. We originally
allocated two hours for lunch. I think that's too long. Is that sort of boring
after two hours? I think maybe we'll resume the lecture at 1.30. There's a
group here from out of state. Are there a bunch of people here from Wisconsin or
that group? Oh, goopoo. I thought the Wisconsin group, I'll meet with them in
the viewing room about 1.15. We'll meet with you especially and then we'll vacate
the viewing room for the others at 1.30 and go on the lecture. But I thought we'd
meet together. You know, I grew up in Wisconsin and I've been back there in a
long time. 60 years, I guess, or something. A long time. Well, the evolution of
consciousness. Do we have, we'll explain how the ego
arose.
People in spiritual work are concerned with the ego. And in the 400s, people are
intelligent and well-read. They know that that's their problem, how to transcend
this ego, how to approach the ego. The reason I like the Course in Miracles
workbook, it calibrates at 600. The text calibrates at 550. The difference is that
I don't like about the textbook is that it tends to demonize the ego and set up a
duality.
And part of your mind sees the ego as the enemy. I brought my ego with me to show you
the true nature of the ego. The ego is troublesome, but it's really a pussycat when you begin
to understand what it's about. We have the evolution of consciousness beginning back
in time. If you've got this, on this wonderful machine here, we've got, you know, the evolution
of consciousness – we've got paleontology, we've got Epcox.
See life, if you understand the ego, then you begin to – you stop demonizing it.
I don't know what's going on. Somebody has to tell me half the time.
So, you see, there's no life on Mars. To speak the person on Mars, there is notсудy,
We knew that with kinesiology before they went there.
They ain't done that yet.
All right, so, Sanyo, oh.
So anyway, on this planet, there was no life,
and then a life appeared.
It appeared, you see, if you were going to establish life
on a, let's say, hostile, it's not really hostile,
but not friendly planet, it's just all rocks and dirt, you know.
In the middle of this planet is molten.
The center of the Earth, then, is a fireball,
which over zillions of years, quadrillions of years,
gradually cooled down enough that the surface
was congenial to life circumstances.
While it's a fiery ball at a couple thousand degrees Fahrenheit,
it's not too friendly to life.
Although life did manage, there is bacteria
that live in the earth.
In the center of the earth, in the molten lava.
So life is tenacious.
So what would be the first principle and rule of life
if it were going to establish itself on this planet?
It would have to be programmed, then,
to serve its own existence.
The core of the ego, then, is self-serving,
because without self-servingness,
no existence is possible.
Life, then, requires energy.
It doesn't have enough energy.
And so the essence of life is to get energy.
The amoeba goes out there and gets energy.
In the beginning, the first signs of life, bacteria,
I got this thing here.
I'm not used to it yet.
It says, be careful, don't shine it in anybody's eyes.
I'm a little scared of it.
And, you know, this is so far long ago
that I don't even know what those words mean.
If we calibrate what's at this time of the rock age,
age of oldest dated rocks,
1, 8, 50, with about 10 zeros after it,
ago, first signs of life,
actually, it's below this.
It's at 1.
Bacteria are at 1.
Algae aren't aware they are.
And viruses are not aware they are.
Virus just reproduces DNA,
but it doesn't know that it is.
Bacteria is the first, it calibrates at 1.
Then you see the evolution of consciousness
throughout the ages.
You see consciousness gradually.
Scorpions at 17.
Now I know why I never liked scorpions much.
And sharks, you see, shell-crushing sharks.
And so you see, life has to evolve.
Self-interest, self-interest is the necessity.
So if it wasn't for the selfishness of life,
none of us would be here.
There's no point in demonizing selfishness.
If it wasn't for selfishness, you wouldn't be.
Because life would not have survived.
It survives because it's interested in me, that I get.
I don't have enough energy, enough molecules,
so I'll eat somebody and then I'll have more energy.
So energy acquisition, then, is necessary to life.
All right.
And you see, life then evolves.
And birds, you see, primitive mammals, modern mammals.
So you see, the evolution of consciousness
over great eons of time
is completely and totally self-interested
until you see the animal kingdom at 200.
We got animal kingdom there?
Animal kingdom.
So the core of your ego better be interested in self-interest.
It better be selfish.
Otherwise, you won't live long enough to become spiritual.
Thank you, bacteria.
We love the protozoas.
And I got a present from my sweet wife.
She gave me a, what is it?
A trilobite, yes.
So we calibrated our trilobite back here.
Our crustacean at three.
So my trilobite at home calibrates at three.
We get up to six, the fish at 20, sharks.
You see how these are all self-interested.
Here's a Komodo dragon.
Can you believe there's somebody crazy enough
to get into a Komodo dragon's cage with him?
That was Neville Chamberlain before World War II.
As long as you're nice to the Komodo dragon,
he'll be nice to you.
Mr. Bin Laden is just misguided.
And if we're nice,
if we're nice to him,
he'll be nice with us.
Thank you.
So Komodo dragon bit the guy.
Well, he didn't die,
so he had some good karma.
Reptiles at 40.
And then we get to the predatory mammals, snakes.
The thing about predatory mammals
is you can make them pets for a while.
As they get older,
they revert and will kill you,
as the lady who raised the lion found out.
And remember,
some years ago back in maybe the 50s,
their ocelots were sort of a craze with ocelots.
The only trouble was the ocelot got older,
he started to eat your child,
so you had to get rid of him.
So we find out ocelots don't work
because their inner nature is the way it is.
Therefore, freedom is not denial.
Freedom is relinquishing denial
and seeing it as childish naivete.
Yeah?
Then we see the whales and the dolphins.
Some people cheer for them,
some people cheer for the dolphins.
Let's hear it for the dolphins.
Hey!
Migratory birds, birds of prey,
rodents, rhinoceros, songbirds, doves,
polar bears, grizzly bears, water buffalo.
You see, a bear is fun, but he'll also kill you.
If you wait long enough,
as he gets older,
one day he's going to get pissed.
Ha ha ha!
It's over for you.
I'm trying to get people out of spiritual naivete.
People become spiritual,
it's hearts and flowers and piety.
And they're deadly.
They walk you right over the cliff.
Walk you right over the cliff.
Why?
Because that's not discernment.
Discernment is the opening of the third eye,
the knowingness that you just know
what is integrous and what is not.
Until the third eye of the Buddhic body opens up,
you have to take the word of others.
And kinesiology certainly serves that purpose.
So the water buffalo is a renowned killer of humans.
The wolves, the hippopotamus,
the hippopotamus kills more humans
than any other animal.
That's always a strange statistic to hear.
Why are people in the water
with the hippopotamus in the first place?
It isn't really the alligator.
The alligator kills a lot of people too.
It's not their fault. It's not the hippopotamus' fault.
The hippopotamus isn't enough to get in there with them.
It's just picked how they're going to leave this planet.
Some things, some things
become sanctified.
Very interesting.
We did food before and after it's blessed.
The highest quality food,
the highest energy is homemade food.
It's then blessed.
When you bless food,
it jumps quite a few points in the calibrated energy.
You actually transform food.
That which is made by love
calibrates much higher than that
which is made by machine.
Very often makes you go weak, actually.
There's a couple brands of cat food
which I won't mention
that my cat won't touch.
We calibrated them. They're below 200.
Amazing. Cat knew it.
Won't eat calibrated food below 190.
They're established brands.
I think of all those poor kitties out there
being forced to eat that stuff.
So we bless our kitties' food too.
God bless this food for our kitty.
You know?
Bless your kitty's food.
The reason I started to say that was
it was really interesting for this new book.
This new book I'm just finishing.
Oh, God bless us when it's out.
We try to tell the truth about everything.
You know how popular that will make you.
There's a famous quote.
I forgot who it was. Montaigne or somebody.
It says, after you tell the truth, leave town.
Laughter
That's funny.
The Ganges River
is disgusting.
Laughter
I was once floating in the
Huangpu River in Formosa, China
or some other place.
It was full of feces,
dead bodies.
I was laying in my bunk on a minesweeper
and I hear the thump, thump, thump.
As we get out there,
it's a dead body.
His head is bumping against the...
So that's what...
So the Ganges River goes by
100 metropolitan areas that all
dump their sewage.
The sewage of 100 metropolitan areas
dumps into the Ganges River.
Plus countless dead bodies,
feces of all kinds of animals, humans, etc.
And the Ganges River,
help me God, calibrates over 500.
The Ganges River.
If you have permission, oh Lord.
Calibrates over 500.
505, 510,
515.
That's the power
of spiritual intention.
For thousands of years, the Hindus
worshipfully
bathed for purification
in the Ganges.
And the Ganges is 510.
That's higher than your tap water at home.
Let's do the animals again.
That's the power of prayer.
The power of prayer.
So, you see,
by being worshipful in the world,
one comes to a feeling
of safety and peace.
And through prayer.
So the way you are to the world,
once you've owned
and recontextualized
who you are,
the way you are to the world
is a prayer.
You are a living prayer.
You don't have to get out your silly prayer card
and go through the recitation.
Be that which a prayer is.
Because the universe
automatically responds to it.
So worshipfully,
in all the feces and dead bodies
and garbage,
the Ganges River calibrates at
five something.
Isn't that incredible, huh?
So then the hippopotamus, you get the
at 200,
I'm going to figure out how to work this thing in here.
At 200, then, you see
a shift of consciousness.
You go from those who live
rapaciously through the death of others
by breaking the back of their neck,
by ripping out
their jugular vein,
and you see those that
now survive by eating grass.
It still needs energy
from out there, but it's in the form of grass.
And now it's benign.
It doesn't have to kill anything
to kill life to eat.
But you see the core of the ego
then is rapacious.
Now here it becomes
benevolent. So you see
the emergence of benevolence
in the animal kingdom calibrated
at level 200.
You're safer with a zebra
or a gazelle or a giraffe
than 85% of the people
on the planet.
They'll steal you
blind. Deer,
bison, domestic pig, elk,
dairy cow, sheep,
range cattle.
Now when I calibrated some of these things,
sometimes I did them too quickly.
A reader of one of the books
sent me a letter.
So when you calibrate something,
I realized I'd made a difference in the
calibration of elephants.
It's because
when you're doing calibrated energies,
if you're in a hurry, you may do
one time you picture
a herd of African wild elephants.
And one of those
elephants could be a male who's in
Musk.
Another time I picture
Indian elephants. Another time
I remember I did picture an Indian elephant
with a mahat
or what do they call them on the back?
Mahat pushing up a tree.
And then you've got certain
circus elephants. So it makes a difference
which of those elephants you picture.
And I didn't always picture the same one.
One time I pictured, I remember, African
elephants in the wild.
And another I pictured a guy with a
hauta on his back.
Also we process things differently.
We process how a thing looks,
how it sounds, how it feels.
So
when it gets down to microscopic
calibration, we don't do microscopic.
What we're trying to convey is a
generality. But there may be
research problems in which
a variation of a couple of degrees
is significant. In that point
you have to be consistent.
So if you're going to calibrate a
thing and what you're picturing is how your mother
feels or how she
looks or how she sounded,
it's going to be different.
So you'll have to use the same
way every time you do it.
So I didn't realize
that and I'm glad he brought it to my attention.
There was the elephants and there was some other
one in which I calibrated
differently. Oh, monkeys.
See the monkeys in the African wild
and the tree, it gives you a different
energy than monkeys in a zoo
and gives you a different picture
than monkeys
that hang out in
places in India. The different monkeys will give you
different calibrations.
Most people are just trying to get a generality.
Really what we usually ask is
a thing is either
integrous or not. That's the main thing we want to know.
So I'm not
going to say that these are exact.
They're probably plus or minus.
In the book we just finished we've got at least
a thousand calibrations.
Let's just see how accurate that
book is.
The calibrations in the book I'm just finishing
are very
more than 1%, 2%.
The calibrations
last time we did it was 3% but I corrected
some of them.
Plus or minus 3%.
Before it goes into print
we'll recalibrate them again.
But I do want to admit that error.
That's the tenth step in AA.
When you're wrong you admit it.
Something world leaders have never
discovered.
I've heard some of the biggest names in America
get up there and lie through their teeth and I say
why don't they just admit that and say
yeah, I mean so.
And go on with it.
I mean it's unbelievable.
So you just say yeah I was wrong.
So here
we see then and also a race horse
is more evolved than a regular farm horse.
So when these animals become
involved with humans their consciousness
advances. So a kitty cat
feline nature is
240 but a house
cat jumps to about 250.
And the same with the
dog. He becomes a family
dog. He jumps to at least 5 points.
And the monkeys that I was
calibrating one time were friendly
happy monkeys at 250.
A gorilla is a very nice
person to be with. Chimpanzees are
and as we said before
Alex the gray
trained elephant gray
is 401.
Alex actually knows how to think and so does
Coco. And here
comes love yelping up through the heart
chakra bypassing
the whole rest of the
animal kingdom. And you got
a kitty's purr is 500.
A dog's
songbird's song 500.
And a dog's wagging tail is 500.
Isn't that
amazing? So
consciousness then is the
essence of life. Life
in order to survive has to be
self serving. So there's
no point in feeling guilty about
ego because
it had to be self
centered in order for you to get here.
However then it evolves
past that and
the spiritual
energy begins to flow at
200. The transformation
begins at 200.
Let's just do that for fun.
Kundalini energy
we have permission in front of this audience oh lord
begins to flow at 200.
It does not flow
below 200. And the etheric
brain does not exist below 200.
The etheric brain starts
at 200 and it's a consequence
of the flow of the kundalini energy.
So
people below 200 don't have an etheric brain.
What's the point of faulting
them for being non-integrous?
By what way would they be?
They've got no
means of knowing
truth from falsehood.
So now here is your
ego. As you can see
he's evolved from the animal kingdom.
The way to be with your ego is to
realize that without your ego you wouldn't
even be here. So thank you.
The other way
to disarm is to not get polarized
against the ego.
To just know that the ego
and every time
somebody jumps ahead of us in traffic
we hate him, don't we?
He should die, shouldn't he?
Of course he should die.
Because he's bad.
People who get in front of us in traffic
and drive slow are bad people.
And we hate them.
Instead of denying your ego
which led to World War II
you see what happened with denial?
It cost the lives of 10 million people.
10 million people
died due to a lie.
So the best way to
de-energize the ego is to tell the truth about him.
You're greedy, yes.
You want more, yes.
You want to be right, yes.
Of course he wants to be right.
You want to win, right.
He wants to win.
He always wants to win.
So he hasn't learned yet.
It's better to succeed
than to win.
In the end what counts as succeeding
winning doesn't mean anything.
Every winner sooner or later
is a loser.
Every winner is polarized
eventually a loser
because he's playing the win-lose game.
We know from quantum mechanics
you play win-lose often enough
sooner or later
the 26th decimal point
is going to come up and kick you in the butt.
So you listen to me now, will you?
Yes.
It's better to succeed
than to win.
So,
the way we dissolve the ego
is through love,
through compassion.
Not because we read it in a book,
not because Krishna said it,
not because Jesus said it,
but because we see it for what it is.
What else could the little bear in us do
except do all the candidate things
it's supposed to do for survival?
He thinks he's supposed to win.
Okay, go on.
That's number one.
What was the next slide after the last one?
Well, we'll skip that one anyway.
Huh?
No, we'll skip that one.
Alright, we'll just blank it out.
So,
we said it's a way to be in the world.
The way you are
to the world.
I want you to focus on that.
I want you to focus on content all the time.
Look at the context.
You can waste all the lifetimes you wasted
fooling around with content.
Once you get your content
in context and not content,
that recontextualizes that content
and the content is no longer a problem to you.
I tried to recontextualize
the ego to you.
There's nothing but a teddy bear within you
who's doing his duty to try and win
because he thinks that's what he's supposed to do.
He thought that for
hundreds of millions of years.
Good ego.
You go ahead, win for me.
Alright.
People constantly send me questions
about various spiritual teachers.
Many people are,
oh that's really good, yes.
Leave that on.
They're always asking me to calibrate
somebody or some
entity on the other side or something
I really don't want to calibrate.
I don't like to be quoted as
he said so and so.
If you know
what integrity is about then
you don't have to calibrate a teacher.
Let's say, what is a
pure spiritual pathway?
First of all,
it doesn't glamorize itself.
It doesn't
dramatize itself.
It doesn't come on with theatrical presentations.
It's non-exclusive.
You don't have to sign up.
Nobody pays a penalty
if they decide to leave.
There's no dues.
It doesn't adulate the leader.
Where was the leader? That's just his job.
Leading or teaching. Teaching is a function.
So,
the person serves that function.
Therefore you call them
respect because he's fulfilling the function.
Just like I do the milkman who delivers the milk.
The street cleaner cleans the street.
We accord them the respect
due to the fact that they fulfill their function.
Without their function
we wouldn't exist.
When garbage delivery
removal stops on the streets of New York City
it's really a disaster. I lived there through it.
And you really learn to respect
the garbage man.
So we respect people
for what they are.
So adulation of gurus
is a great trap.
The gurus that fall into it
there's a whole group of them
on the other side of the planet
eight or nine of them
all fell at the same time.
And I only realized
what the reason was.
I was having breakfast with somebody
who was a friend of Gopi Krishna
painted Gopi Krishna
who wrote the famous book on Kundalini energy.
And he said
when he first went to India
he says
the Indian people explained to him
we're not scrupulous here.
Oh, scrupulosity
is not a requirement
of success in that culture.
Just saying whatever you think will get the sale
or win is fine.
There's nothing wrong with it.
See, we grew up in a judo-Christian culture
in which that's wrong.
There it's not wrong.
It's a organic culture
and snake charmers
and everybody who can
boon-boggle you and get your pennies
do so.
And there's nothing wrong with it.
So there's no point in demonizing.
So a true teacher then
teaches from
what it is.
The teacher is teaching from
what the teacher has become.
Doesn't teach by
authority of external
levels.
Doesn't quote something
and then quote it to you as a teaching.
There's known as
it stands on its own.
Integrous spirituality and truth
stands on its own.
It doesn't have quotes from famous
people.
What famous people think about it
is totally irrelevant.
It stands on its own.
Why?
And it has nothing to gain.
Nothing to be gained, you see.
What it's looking for
is not looking for any kind of gain.
It doesn't need followers.
Why would they want followers?
Can you imagine everywhere you go
they're trailing behind you.
You go to get on a streetcar
you wonder if all your followers got in.
Everywhere you look you got followers.
Power over others and controlling others.
A good teacher doesn't tell anybody
how they should live.
Their personal life.
What you should wear.
What you should eat.
Why would a spiritual teacher
be interested in your personal life?
That could be more and more boring.
Want to get divorced?
It's up to you.
Want to stay with her? Fine.
Want to eat meat? Yep.
Want to eat meat on Fridays? Yep.
Eat meat on Fridays? Boy.
That's worse than any other day, you know.
Eat meat on a good Friday, man,
and you are really...
Or you gotta wear a hat.
Or you gotta wear a hat or not wear a hat.
Take your hat off. Respect God.
Respect God.
I don't know, put my hat on or off.
You know what I'm saying?
Alright.
So you don't need fancy strange garb.
You don't need long hair.
You don't need sandals.
You don't need piety.
Piety is a strange thing.
It's a naturalness
to the way you are within the world.
True piety is worshipful
in that
you present
that which you are
to divinity
as what you have become.
In so doing,
one serves God and one's fellow man.
So there's nothing to gain.
There's no desire to control people.
Have them sign up.
There's no reward.
You sign up three of them
and you get an extra $50.
So there isn't any market level marketing,
multi-level marketing.
The thing stands on its own
due to its own integrity, you see.
It's not interested in money.
It's interested in covering expenses.
Expenses are quite high, by the way.
The Radisson cost you about 10 grand up in front
just to walk in the front door.
And there were other places we wanted to meet
and there was even more than that.
So you cover the expense
and then you've got to have enough left over
for operations
because you have to have quite a sizable staff
as time goes on.
You've got half a dozen people
answering the phone and shipping out things
and mailing and answering questions
and making reservations.
So instead from 12 to 2,
I thought we'll stop at 12.30.
At 1.15 I'll meet with that group in the side room.
And I remembered somebody said
there's leaflets telling you
there's restaurants that'll give you a discount
if you go there.
And those leaflets are out there.
So we were talking about
you don't need to calibrate a teacher
if you're comfortable.
See, because whether a teacher
is right for a prisoner or not depends.
When you begin,
I'll tell you a great place to begin
and that's to join the scouts.
Boy Scouts and Girl Scouts of America.
They calibrate way up there.
And Eagle Scout calibrates even higher.
I forget what they calibrate
but it's quite impressive.
A good place to start.
Scouts start you off right at 4.50 or 4.60
or something like that.
That's a hell of a good place to start.
That beats about 90% of the world
to start out at 4.60.
So you don't have to go
to strange places and seek out
people in esoteric garb.
Because those are dramatizations.
And India is the home of that.
They've learned the art of spiritual seduction.
The art of spiritual seduction.
So what you're looking for
in a teacher is somebody
who has the recognition
of the relatively erudite spiritual seekers
alias that you won't waste time.
Not interested in status.
Not interested in control.
Not interested in money.
Doesn't self-assert.
Doesn't design any special titles.
What is the title of the teacher?
Well, if you're teaching,
then I guess teacher.
If you're a swimmer, you'd be swimmer.
If you're a skier, you'd be the skier.
The group skier, right?
So teacher just does teaching
because that's the function.
So one is one's function
and one's function comes out
of one's realization.
So the true teacher then
is merely
the reflection of the inner knowingness.
There is no personal self
that decides to say this.
It doesn't process things.
There's no processing.
It is that
and then speaks spontaneously
of that which it is.
Therefore, there is no design.
Everything happens spontaneously.
When you become
that which you can be
to the utmost, to the world,
you are a prayer.
Recitations are nice.
We were talking about piety.
There's a certain level of which
piety is
natural for a moment.
The minute I look at this audience,
I feel worshipful.
And
if I don't watch it, tears begin to flow.
Sort of joyful ecstasy.
Then there's
another kind of piety
that's sort of holier than now
piety.
Draped in
robes and incense
and dingle bells and things.
It's sort of a dramatization.
It can itself become an addiction.
Just like asceticism.
I went through asceticism.
You can live without anything.
It's great.
However,
extreme poverty and asceticism
becomes in itself an addiction.
So you transcend that.
It's alright to have stuff.
You don't have to have an aversion
and you don't have to have an attraction.
So what the person is looking for
when they want to calibrate a true teacher
is somebody who is naturally
the expression of that which they have become.
Therefore, they don't require
falsity
because all they are is just being
that which they are.
To just be that which you are.
Like Satchmo.
Just is who he is.
Louis Armstrong calibrates
way up there, 5 or 10 or something.
He's one of the top guys.
Satchmo.
Just came from universal love.
Just was what he was.
Didn't have to make any poses.
Didn't have to control people.
Doesn't need anything from you.
Doesn't want to tell you
what you should wear,
who you should be with,
all about your sex life,
what you should eat,
meat, fish, what.
Non-controlling.
So freedom then.
Freedom is the natural expression
and then
you find a teacher that you're comfortable with.
And as you grow along
you may go through
a progression of teachers.
Because the teacher who is right
solves this problem.
And now you're ready to move on to another teacher
because you've moved along.
And you've learned what this teacher has to teach.
The actual teaching of course
that goes on
from an advanced consciousness
is not the content at all.
It's the frequency and the vibration
of the field.
of the aura, of the field
of the teacher.
See, content is in here.
This is prayers and mantras and all.
And what makes them work
is because it generates a field.
But what's actually teaching
is the field.
Is the field.
The frequency of the energy
of the vibration of the aura
of the teacher
by your ascent becomes
trained in your own aura
throughout all of time.
That's what the Buddha meant
when he said.
The teaching
in my understanding
my inner understanding
is the frequency and the energy
of that has within it
the information.
The information that you need to know
at a certain point is encoded in the frequency.
Having brought that
frequency into your own aura
you're going to reach
a state eventually
those of you...
How many here are going to be enlightened?
Everybody! God bless you!
Why else would you be here?
That's what I prepare
people for along the whole trip.
Because in either this
or some lifetime
you reach the final door
and at that point
you're not going to remember
anything because you don't have
any memory to remember it with.
You say, oh I'll remember that
when I get there. No you won't.
There ain't nothing to remember.
They took away your cell phone.
You forgot God's
number. What the hell was his number?
No, because it's very
vivid, the knowing.
Knowingness replaces
thinkingness. You don't need thinkingness
what you need is knowingness.
So as you walk through the last
door, there's a moment of
terror because
there's nothing left to surrender
to God except
the self.
That which you think you have been
through all eternity.
The core of life itself.
You now surrender to God
and now
you die for the first
and only and last time.
The other time you just left the body.
That's why I don't go for melodrama
about dying. Give me a break.
How many times have we all died here?
Quizzle. You're out of the body.
I mean what's the big deal?
All the drama on this side. God bless it.
Now this time
you're really going to need
the knowingness because without the knowingness
it's terrifying to walk
through because you realize you are
actually walking into actual
death. This is death
that you do have to give up your
life. Wow.
Now the full understanding of that
comes forth. Then
out of non-thinkingness because
you're beyond thought at this point.
There's no thinking to think with.
There's no thinker left.
Comes the knowingness.
So the teacher must have
absolute concrete certainty.
The only concrete
absolute certainty for which
one is taking karmic responsibility
for that which is being said
because everything I say I take
karmic responsibility and I'm very
aware of the price of error.
At the doorway the knowingness
comes to you.
To surrender life itself.
The knowingness.
Comes out of like Zen.
To walk straight ahead no matter what.
Because all fear is
illusion.
Maybe except this instance.
That's okay for 99.99%.
But what about the last iota?
And there takes the great
courage. There you walk
through it and you experience
death. I won't kid you.
Agonizing. You experience
the experience of death itself.
So what carries you through
is the energy field of the
aura. See the frequency
cast within it the information.
Nothing said that to me.
There's no other beings there.
Forget other beings. There are no other
higher beings.
No spiritual guides or whatever crap
they think about. No such thing.
I've never met any along the way.
And they aren't there either.
There is the inner knowingness
to walk straight ahead no matter what
all fear is illusion.
Therefore I repeat
where I heard it originally apparently
from the aura of the Buddha or
one of the great
teachers of the ancient Vedas. I don't know
where in history. I never tracked it out.
But it was there.
It's encoded as a
frequency. And when
you need it you've reached that frequency
and at that frequency the knowingness
is known.
And you walk through.
And then all splendor
shines forth.
So that's the purpose then
is
to share with
the students
where the teacher
has been and where
he knows he is.
And doesn't pretend to be beyond that.
The integrity of many organizations
like AA etc.
You see all of them humility.
Humility is what?
It's the courage to tell the truth about yourself.
And the true teacher will say
you know I got this far
and if you want to go farther
you'll have to find somebody who teaches that way.
Teachers of religion
do not teach enlightenment.
They'll say look
I belong to a religion and we teach
such and such and that's as far as we go.
So that person is being honest.
He says I only believe in God transcendent.
The world of the mystic
is still
suspect.
We gave up burning them at the stake.
Or putting them under house arrest.
But
Galileo was put under house arrest.
Anyway.
So you move from religion
which has its core spirituality
and you say I want to transcend religion
I want to go
to where religion came from.
I want to rediscover
the spiritual core out of which
a religion arose.
Then you have to go from
traditional religion into spirituality.
And of course that
brings you in contact with the world's great religions.
The great
Vedas out of India.
The enlightened masters
arose in the Vedic
and Aryan culture
of ancient India.
They were enlightened gurus
by 7,000 BC.
7,000 BC.
They were a great
enlightened master.
5,000 BC.
The Buddha came along
500 BC
and the reason the Buddha was never a Christian
is Christ hadn't been born for another 500 years.
Here people
knock the Buddha. He's not a Christian.
He's a heathen.
Christ wasn't born yet.
So the core of all truth.
So the teacher has to
have humility
of knowing where the limitations are.
Willingness to admit a mistake.
If I miscalibrated monkeys
I miscalibrated monkeys.
I must have been monkeying around
that day.
Monkeying with the figures.
Alright.
So I just wanted to make that clear.
That by their fruits
you should know them.
Don't be impressed by the miraculous.
The miraculous is nothing at all.
Once the kundalini energy comes up
it performs the miraculous.
There's no
you that performs the miraculous.
There are no
miracle workers.
And the kundalini is very powerful.
It will heal that
to which it is destined to go.
And you don't select it.
You don't think oh look at that poor sick woman there.
She's all crippled up.
And start sending her healing energy.
Give me a break. No.
The kundalini energy does it.
It doesn't consult you at all.
It just goes there.
And all of a sudden the lady who's all
twisted up looks at you and goes
walks away.
There isn't any you
that did that.
Also the kundalini energy is not
predictable.
You can't perform miracles on the hour.
See?
Because it acts of its own.
It's a divine energy.
It's like it comes from on high.
You're a conduit.
You're like a telephone, telegraph
radio station.
And it goes there.
You're just a radio station.
You're not the source of that divine energy.
So you've all become
spiritually perfect.
Your past is healed.
Your future is certain.
And from this point on
we have become
we are each one of us
a prayer to this world
and a blessing.
At 1.15 I'll meet with the Wisconsin group.
We'll slice cheese and sausage.
At 1.30
the main group will resume.
Sheboygan is the world's foremost
producer of sausage.
Boy, I'll tell you
good old Wisconsin summer sausage.
Well, we met with
a group there.
So we're a little bit late.
We didn't know how long it would take
to get in town, out of town
and meet with the group and get here.
I wanted to just bring
the group did bring up
one of the
spiritual errors is
there's two of them. One is falling into the Lord.
The upper astral, the middle astral.
Which the New Agers tend to do.
Middle astral more.
And then altered states of consciousness.
See, altered states of consciousness
like learning biofeedback
to go into alpha states, etc.
And various altered breathing styles.
Anything that's artificial.
You can create an altered state
which is interesting.
You can do astral projection
and all kinds of wondrous tricks with it.
But it is not the same thing.
You see, you don't have to do anything
to make a thing happen.
That's dualistic.
There's a you doing a certain practice
to make a thing happen.
You understand? That's dualistic.
In reality, nothing is causing anything.
So to save 60 lifetimes
I guarantee 60 lifetimes
if you get
that the way to be in the world
you see
is like allowing.
Nothing is causing anything.
That's the big bypass.
Today I want you to forget cause.
Nothing is causing anything.
There is no cause
in this world
anywhere.
Everything is spontaneously
being what it is
because of the
infinite field of divinity
potentiality
becomes actuality.
You see, the cloud
coalesces out of the totality
of the sky
and its potentiality
is expressed then
within form.
But nothing is causing the cloud
to be there.
Have you got that last slide?
The potentiality
becomes the actuality.
The potentiality is the product
of evolution.
Potentiality is in the non-linear domain.
It's really within
the morphogenetic fields
of, what's his name?
So the potentiality
in form. So evolution occurs
on the level of consciousness
in the invisible realm
and then by intentionality
it manifests forth.
So you see there's no transitory
forms. You don't
see a zebra
becoming a horse.
It comes out zebra, it comes out
horse, it's complete and total when it comes off.
So the evolution is
occurring in the invisible domain
and then it appears
so that evolution and creation are one
and the same thing.
Evolution is the way creation appears
sequentially to perception.
Continuous and ongoing.
That which has no beginning
and no end.
No, the previous one.
Content, field and
content and field.
Look at that wonderful thing.
Yeah, yeah.
We had to get God on the slide here.
This is content. This is Newtonian
science, you see.
Now whether a thing manifests or not
depends on several
things. One is
the favorability of conditions.
Therefore you can put
a seed in the ground.
Now what happens
is it has a
potentiality to become an
actuality. But nothing
can force it to do so.
Under favorable conditions
then. So it's
karmic design is that under favorable
conditions, it's
potentiality becomes an actuality.
But you cannot
force a flower to do anything.
You can't force it
to become a turtle either.
People don't believe in karma.
I say, well how come a butterfly isn't a turtle then?
Tell me that.
Because
the flower has the karmic propensity
to become a flower and nothing else.
So truth cannot be
defined except within context.
Except within context
nothing is true except under certain
conditions. So the
conditions are the proximate field.
This is the weather,
this is political climate,
many other things.
Cause is not the
explanation of phenomena.
Then how do you explain phenomena?
First of all, phenomena
is an arbitrary selection.
Everything is in continuous flow
and if you say
this moment started now, this moment
started there, well you just picked it out of there.
There is no such thing as a moment there.
A moment is all in your mind.
There are no moments in the world.
Therefore there is no happenings to explain.
Isn't that nice?
Gets you off the hook with everything.
So one
inherits by karmic
evolution over
great periods of time
a potentiality
which by intention
or by the power of the field
becomes an actuality.
I always liken
God as an infinite
electromagnetic field.
Now you know how an electromagnetic
condenser works.
An electromagnetic condenser is still
until you present it with a charge.
And then
the charges line up on the
electromagnetic condenser
equal and opposite
to the charge.
If you present it with a lot of electrons
it will automatically, so it
only reacts to that which is
presented to it.
The field of consciousness then
is still unmoving,
doesn't do anything.
But it is
the giant electromagnetic field
in which all the us
little iron filings line up
by virtue of our design.
So freedom
is the freedom to choose
within the options
that we have karmically earned
to have presented to us.
We cannot say yes or no
to becoming a turtle.
So,
that which you have become
gravitates by
the power of the field.
That which you have become
automatically aligns itself
in the field over here.
Because that which you
therefore, there is nobody
paddling your canoe except you.
Nobody has the rudder on your
destiny except yourself.
Which is a little scary.
That which by choice
you choose determines
where you settle out
within the field.
So like is attracted to like
and
each one filters.
So as we leave the body one automatically
is aligned
with the field of that which
you have become.
There is no necessity for an arbitrary god
to give you a good smack
for being bad.
Because you are in hell already.
Having chosen hell
some guy will blow up a big building
and do that.
He says, well I know I am destined for hell.
He was probably correct.
Having been there I don't advise it.
Blowing up people
I guess that's just the upper level of hell.
Nothing is causing
anything out there.
Therefore
there is no such thing
as a perpetrator or a victim.
Each one brings to himself
his own
consequences of his own karma.
Each person
at birth
already has a calibrated level of consciousness.
Each person at birth
is born in the optimal
karmic possibility.
The circumstances
of your birth are perfect
for that which you are
designed for learning.
We have permission to ask that
with this group.
The circumstances of one's birth
are perfect.
The circumstances of your birth
For that which you have become
up to this point.
Cold Wisconsin winters
was perfect.
18 miles a day on a bicycle
in a Wisconsin winter
with 100 pounds of newspapers
was what I needed
to learn
what would you call it?
Steely determination no matter what.
Despite anything
you grit your teeth and you do it.
How to walk ahead straight ahead.
That got me through medical school.
You try working your way through medical school
you know what I mean.
100 hours a week as an intern for $100 a month.
People talk about low paying nowadays
it makes me laugh.
$100 a month for 100 hours a week.
So the steely
determination that it takes
so I guess that was
perfect to learn that
steeliness.
That walk ahead no matter what.
And then when the great test
of it came
the walk straight ahead
no matter what
came up in spades.
Well I didn't realize that.
So
there's no point bewailing one's birth
there's no point feeling sorry
for people.
Sentimentality calibrates below 200.
Gets a lot of air time.
Everybody's always
looking for the culprit.
It's always somebody's fault.
So the newest paradigm of reality
is nothing is anybody's fault.
It's always the fault of somebody out there.
Society, society.
Somebody is
the perpetrator victim
which is the core of Marxism
and calibrates 130.
The perpetrator victim model
has had a very derogatory
detrimental
effect on the
quality of the fabric of society
in which one is always looking for
the guilty
the guilty one.
Hmm.
Oh truth keeps
disappearing all the time.
What did we pay rent on?
She's saving electricity
I know it.
So this is the infinite
infinite
all encompassing fuel
of consciousness
omnipotent, omnipresent,
omniscient.
As one lets go of the limitations
of form
and one progresses beyond this
one comes into the field
of knowingness.
That's what speaking
what is speaking to you today
is knowingness.
I have nothing to do with it.
It speaks spontaneously.
Everything is happening of its own
which is a fact
that comes to you
with sudden surprise.
There's the belief there's a you
causing all these things to happen.
I'll tell you the trick of the ego
is to claim credit for a thing
I caught it once doing it.
The ego claims credit
for what is actually spontaneous
and it takes about
1 ten-thousandth of a second
that's when the Buddha
said you could glimpse
the ultimate infinite truth
is between two thoughts
no it's not between two thoughts
it's right prior to two thoughts
between two thoughts
sort of sets up the
Newtonian image
of thoughts being like
billiard balls
where one thought is causing another one.
Every thought is arising
out of nothing.
out of nothingness.
Prior to that thought
there is nothing.
You'll find right now
at the back of your mind
there is a still field
which doesn't do anything
or say anything
but registers everything.
It's unverbal.
The capacity for hearingness
the capacity for knowingness
the mind is actually silent.
Out of the silence
arises
out of sort of an
of a thought
dogginess
and then if you allow that
thought to progress
it's going to become old rover
and it's going to be old rover
was hit by the truck
and then how we all cried
redoing rover
getting run over by the truck
rerunning the whole story
in your head.
No, you see that coming.
It's not even rover yet.
By focused meditation
you can see how this
once you let it loose
it begins to amplify itself
because we're enamored of our thoughts.
As you watch the thoughts
you see the thoughts
they crest and then they fall away.
In meditation
be quiet
because contemplation
is a way of being in the world
a contemplative way of being in the world
therefore it's continuous
whereas meditation
tends to be something
in which you separate yourself from the world
go off, go into a very special state
all kinds of postures
and breathing and weird things
that's separate from all dayness
so you go into a great state
in meditation
then you get up
and that's meditation.
Not that much.
Meditation is good for
discerning how all this happens
and
in a focused meditation
as you watch
the thoughts arise
you'll see
they are like the cresting of a wave
and no sooner do they crest
then they're falling away
so thoughts are like music
no sooner do you hear the tone of the music
that tone is already fading away
anxiety
or always trying to control the future
anticipate the future
so they live in front of the wave
they're always one up
and always anxious about the next moment
trying to control the next moment
people who live on the back of the wave
are clinging to the moment
that's just left
they can't let that last tone of music go
they're trying to make it last longer
so they're constantly ruminating
about the past
so these people are frightened of the future
clinging to the past
so you focus your attention
your awareness
on the exact presence
of that which is the crest
now the crest itself
is arising out of an intention
intentionality of thinkingness
this intentionality
is an enamour, a hypnotic state
you let go
the wanting to think
and you'll find that thinkingness
is coming from an intention
and you can finally actually find
the source within the silent field itself
and let go of the intentionality
of thinkingness itself
what good is that
you discover
that it has no life of its own
it's coming out of something else
a life lived as a prayer
one's life lived as a contemplative style
is to me
the most rapid
and rewarding
means of spiritual evolution
to be aware at all times
of that which you are
to be what you are
like a mudra
you know what a mudra is
it's a hand position
to be so that your life itself
is a presentation to God
as you are
I am as I am
to thee oh Lord
and to thee do I surrender
that which I have become
other than that
what would you have to do
there is nothing further
to do
one lives one's life
like a mudra
so to pray
then
one holds one's consciousness
thusly
the Holy Spirit knows
what you mean by that
I've lost my dog
I asked for a miracle
to find my doggie
every time Kitty gets lost
I just go like that
and Kitty gets found
I wish I make a big donation
to the church
the kundalini energy
does it for you
you understand
spiritual evolution
is effortless
like a cork floating
in the ocean
to be
that which you are
in supplication to divinity
already
summons forth
the infinite powers of the universe
in your behalf
you don't have to do anything else
that which you have become
is like a cork
and you automatically rise
not because there is a me
doing that
but by virtue of that
which you have become
one floats higher and higher
in the water
effortlessly
to me spiritual work
is effortless
it's a decision
it's an intention
that intention then aligns you
with whatever you need to be aligned with
a decent regret
takes care of the past
trust, faith and surrender
takes care of the future
and in the present moment
you don't have any problems
consequently
what would the mind think about
what would you think about mind
you would probably fight for existence
are you going to fight for existence
that which has no reality
you don't have to be killed
I don't have to kill your mind
you don't even exist
I've got it beat before it starts
so one more or less
lets go
and becomes
that which you seek
because that which you seek
is not different
than that which you discover
so
spiritual work
is merely being thus
it's like the ultimate
yin posture
the ultimate yin posture
to get to the ultimate yin posture
you go through
the spiritual night
the ultimate yang posture
and you kill people for Jesus
you kill infidels
you hate evil
evil
but those are all
the archetypes we go through
as we evolve spiritually
you see
to cross over 200
is merely an intention
as I say
if you're a boy scout or a bro scout
boy scouts are 450
eagle scouts are 460
same for both the girls and the boys
that's when hell of an integrity starts in life
to live by integrity
helpfulness
kindness, consideration, cordiality
I mean those are
you're halfway there already
as I say
and when you get that master
move on
the minute you align to
integrity
in any of its forms
the minute you begin to
really
appreciate beauty
it can start anywhere
you can be walking through the woods
and suddenly
time stops
there's this absolute stillness
and you realize
that something has just happened
and as everybody
is arrived
the Kundalini energy
begins to flow
below 200
the Kundalini energy
does not flow yet
it's still
you're run by the animal
above 200
now the Kundalini energy
begins to flow
the Kundalini energy
body knows that. So what people try to manufacture by various rituals and
techniques is to control this kundalini energy which all you have to do
is get out of its way. It begins to flow. When it flows, let's go to the
you know the one about brain chemistry. When the kundalini energy begins to flow
it has a transformative effect. It changes brain chemistry. It changes brain
physiology. It creates an etheric body. It's responsible for the miraculous. The
experience of it going through one's body is incredible. It has a healing, the
healing capacity for healing. The healingness then, the kundalini energy
together with your karmic merit etc. begins to heal things.
In this physicality here there was at least 15 or 20 grave illnesses that cured
all by themselves. There's what the brain looks like in case you haven't looked at
yours lately. Here's the limbic system. Let's go to the next one. All right so
this of course is hard to see from the back of the room. It's in the new book
which will be out by summer hopefully. This sort of is short for what I'm
talking about kundalini energy and physiology. And in the animal, the animal
is primarily, I'm talking now in a right-handed person, is primarily left
brain. It's concerned with survival. This and that. It has to stay alert to
survive. So the left brain then, sensory input goes very fast via the relay
center in the thalamus. The fast track
is to the emotional center in the amygdala. You don't have to remember
these names. I don't remember them myself. That's why they're printed up there.
You study all this, you pass the exam, you get a straight A, you forget it, like that.
How often do you run into an amygdala in your everyday life, you know? All right, so
the person who's not spiritual then sees something out there by the fast track
where it's relayed really quickly and
it's relayed to the emotional center. Now there's a slow track, a slow track, that
goes to the prefrontal cortex and then to the amygdala. I've got a spotter
somewhere, yeah. So although the brain gets the message sooner or later, it's,
it's... So the fast track is this way to the emotional center. Kill. Prefrontal
cortex says,
sinful, but you've already decided to kill him. Now you attenuate it, but the killer came up first.
Now you're hit with the guilt of the killer, too. Not only did you think of killing him,
now you feel, oh God, I'm sorry I thought that. Oh, you know, dear, dear, you know, I confess that I
thought of killing somebody. That experience, then, is stored in the hippocampus. The hippocampus
is where we store memory. So what kind of memories of the past does the person
who is not spiritual hold? Negative ones. Resentment, anger. He builds up a hit list
of all his enemies, because it's memory. When he goes into memory, it's all of painful hatred,
guilt, envy, jealousy, competition, get even, revenge, because that's what he's
storing.
He's stored up in his hippocampus. His experience of the world was that of an animal. So the
unattenuated ego, then, is the animal. There's nothing in your ego that you don't see in the
animal kingdom. Everybody's ego is on display every day in Monkey Island. Territorial dispute,
alpha males, who's going to get the alpha female, who gets more, bites, scratch, tear, hate.
When you look at what people die for,
they'll show a thing from some place in North Africa, usually. As far as the eye can see,
there's nothing but dust and sand. Dust and sand. That's all there is. No water, no gold,
no nothing. And they kill each other by the thousands. So who's going to own this?
They're dying over this? When you see pictures of it, you say, you've got to be kidding.
You've got to be kidding. 500 miles of nothing.
500 miles of nothing. They're going to kill each other over that. So the animal, then,
unattenuated. This is consciousness level below 200. People above 200 presume that other people
are like you. I'm going to tell you something that's going to save your life and that of
everybody on the planet. They do not think like you. They do not think like you at all.
They do not think like you. They do not think like you.
They'll take your eye teeth, folks. Not because they're bad, because they're good. Good animals
take everybody's eye teeth. It's their duty, you see. I once applied for a job. It was
in Wisconsin, too, I think. And you're supposed to sell peanut vending machines to retired
farmers. I think they're 25 bucks a piece. And the pitch was, you just go around and
collect the money. We've got a new version of that on TV. ATM machines and various things.
And you put them in filling stations. So the guy pictures,
he's going to drive around in his old pickup truck and dump out all this money.
What you don't tell him is that only happens once a year.
It's full of pennies, all right, but it takes a year.
So I got, you know, this is ripping off old people for their retirement money,
and it's completely fraudulent. And you know what he said to me, the training guy who was
trying to sign me up as a salesman? He says, if you don't get their money, somebody else will.
Remember that. If you think other people are like you, they're not. Because if they don't get
your money, somebody else will, is the prevailing message, okay? I don't want to make you paranoid,
except it's best to be paranoid. Now, paranoia is what we substitute before spiritual vision.
Let's say when the third eye of the Buddha body opens up, you have discernment. But until that
happens, you're anybody's company.
You're anybody's victim. All right, above 200, what happens? The consciousness now shifts. So
below 200, you got left brain dominance. You live in a linear domain. Everything is stressful,
releases adrenaline. You get cellulase alarm reaction, resistance, and then finally exhaustion.
You get cannons, fight or flight reaction. You're constantly reducing. It's an adrenaline world.
This suppresses the stress response.
It suppresses the killer cells and depresses immunity. It suppresses the thymus. That's why
Dr. John Diamond recommended the thymus thump. Because this blows the acupuncture meridian.
Repeatedly blowing the acupuncture meridian, because the various meridians are associated
with various organs in the body, you're constantly interrupting the energy to the heart,
or to the liver, or the stomach, small intestine, big intestine, whatever. You repeatedly do that,
and you finally kill yourself. Enough interference in the energy to the heart chakra, and the heart
begins to get heart disease. Okay, so you keep blowing the acupuncture meridians, and you end up
with a negative physical state. Depleting is constantly shooting out adrenaline. You deplete
the neurotransmitters in the brain. Which serotonin is the most effective? The serotonin is the most
common. You repair this with Prozac. A lot of people in our society suffer from a Prozac deficiency.
At least a third of the population at some time during their lifetime will be seriously depressed.
This is due to genetic factors. Genetic factors and depression and alcoholism tend to run genetically
in the same family. So if you've got a brother who's an alcoholic, the likelihood is about four
times higher that you may become depressed. So there's a genetic factor involved. There's a genetic factor
involved as well. Brain physiology and genetics. And what happens above consciousness level 200 now
is in common parlance, you become a right brain person. We're talking about now is the right-handed
person as the standard model. Left-handed person is the other way. Above consciousness level 200 now,
the kundalini energy begins to flow. And now the same sensor input goes fast track, fast track,
through the etheric brain to the emotional center. And your experience of the world is totally different.
Above 200, you think everybody in New York City is friendly. It's a fact. You can talk to any cab driver,
you can talk to anybody. I'll do it on video. I'll just walk down the street, stop any stranger, and immediately start a conversation with them.
What the hell do you think of so-and-so? Right where they're talking to you like they've known you for 20 years.
It's like we know each other.
You know what I mean? The cab drivers are friendly. Everybody's friendly. Everybody's helpful. It's a wonderful place.
Why? Because you're experiencing a different world. This is a different world. So this person now in the emotional center says New York City is a wonderful place.
He stores in his hippocampus the memory of New York being friendly and helpful and happy.
All the waitresses were friendly. The cab drivers were great. The hotel was wonderful. What more can you ask?
Mm-hmm.
They actually live in two different worlds. So when I say, don't think that these people do not think the way you do because they do not live in the same world you do.
You think everybody thinks in the same world. That's very naive. They do not live in the same world you do.
You say, how can people indulge in so much hate? Well, it's because they see a hateful world.
To you, that's astonishing. To them, they're surrounded by enemies. So forgiveness comes out of understanding.
Oh. They live in a world. They see that way. And that's why they think the way they do. Huh?
Their experience of the world is not the same. So to you, it seems crazy because you don't experience that kind of a world that would justify that kind of hatred.
Blowing up busloads of children, bombing trade centers and God knows what all. Huh. Whatever they can think to blow up.
All right. Conscious level about this.
Consciousness level about 200, then the kundalini energy results in right brain dominance.
You now become dominated by the non-linear.
As I said, it's not what you say. You don't have to go through some kind of a ritual.
You become non-linear. You become the field.
You become the field. You begin to reflect the field and not the content of the field.
Because you experience life as peace, you release endorphins instead of adrenaline.
Endorphins are healing. They're anabolic.
Adrenaline is catabolic.
Endorphins are anabolic and tend to heal.
So kundalini energy is a healing energy.
It supports the thymus and the killer cells which fight off infection.
It results in positive emotions.
The person is more peaceful, have greater immunity,
and I can say from personal experience,
healing of the most incredibly impossible and curable conditions
is the most important thing.
It happens of their own.
The acupuncture system remains imbalanced.
If it does go out of balance, it quickly is restored.
You get a positive kinesiologic response.
And the track to the emotions is slower.
So you see, the slow track is now to the emotions.
The fast track is to the cerebral cortex
and specifically the etheric brain.
Specifically the etheric brain.
So spiritual knowledge.
The understanding and learning is stored or is processed
through a special place in the prefrontal cortex of the etheric brain.
What I just stated is true.
You won't read that any place, folks.
You heard it hurt here.
I'll tell you, it took me a long time to draw this thing.
I drew it about 18 ways.
I could not get it to be the way I knew it was.
Finally it came out.
Okay.
So what is the conclusion?
The importance is.
It's spiritual endeavor and intention.
Change the brain function, which changes how you experience the world,
changes who you are, changes the body physiology,
establishes an area for spiritual information in the right brain,
cerebral cortex and etheric brain.
When I told you, you're not the same as those people, you are not.
You are not the same person.
You are.
Let's go back to field and we got fuel and content.
That sort of pulls together a lot, doesn't it?
Healing modality, physiology, spiritual work, kundalini energy.
It pulls it all together.
See here in left brain, you're identifying with just this and this believes in causality
and duality.
This is where a Marxist lives.
He sees the world as perpetrator and victim, see.
Then you begin to see that the worker and the capitalist are congruent.
The latest thing is to heap abuse on Walmart.
Woe to those who heap abuse on Walmart.
Well, anything that becomes successful in our world, you know, becomes a target for
abuse, you know.
Walmart is no exception.
This week's issue of Fortune magazine, good or evil, is Walmart good or evil, you know?
It's terrible.
And of course, the thing about Walmart is that it's so big and successful and a certain
segment of society hates anything that's big and successful, no matter what it is.
And of course, the question is who made Walmart rich and successful?
How many people here made Walmarts rich and successful?
We all made Walmart rich and successful.
Show me the evil capitalists when we're the ones that did it.
We went there because prices were cheaper.
What about mom and pop?
Well, mom and pop get phased out, don't they?
When the telephone came along, the Pony Express died.
So you see evolution then goes through change.
It doesn't mean that there's a bad guy perpetrator and a poor victim.
It means that slavery passed as a human phenomenon.
Slavery was widespread across the whole world for thousands of years.
In ancient Rome, the slaves outnumbered the free men ten to one.
It was the way life was.
Then it slowly phased itself out in various parts of the world.
So it's a transitor.
It's a mandatory phase.
The same as women's position in society.
In an agrarian society, the woman's position was in the home and the guy was out in the
field.
Did she want to go out there and sweat with the horses?
I don't think so.
I didn't want to go out there and sweat with the horses either.
In Wisconsin, they didn't have electric on the other side of the highway.
Nobody had a milking machine.
Nobody could afford a tractor.
You had a big horse.
And a plow.
And you were solid sweat from morning till night.
So he wasn't interested in washing the kids' clothes and bathing the kids and cooking and
all that crap.
She took care of that.
The mother reigned supreme in the house.
Reigned supreme.
Modern society doesn't understand the position of the woman in the early part of the last
century.
Especially in the Midwest, everybody in Wisconsin knows what that means.
The mother, when a woman entered the room, you stood up.
You stood up.
And you honored her by opening the door for her.
The mother reigned supreme in the house.
And my grandmother would say, my grandfather would try to sneak through the living room
with his pipe.
He'd try and hide it by his pants.
And she'd run through and say, Frank, Frank, the drips.
You weren't allowed to use bad language in the presence of God.
I knew that.
Women had a separate entrance to the bar in the back.
Men were vulgar.
They were at the bar.
They used bad language.
Women sat at the back.
And men watched their language around women.
Don't you see how respected they were?
They were loved and respected.
The mother was supreme.
Out in the field, the man ruled.
He ruled.
But he ruled over what?
The inanimate.
In fact, machines and crap like that.
Horses.
Shoveling horse poo.
he was the king of shoveling cow poo
getting sunburned and all sweaty
and of course
Saturday night you found out who was who
Saturday night in Wisconsin
I used to babysit all the time
that's how I made a living
and I can still smell
the smell of it
the kerosene light, the kerosene lamp
every house you went to
smelled like kerosene
then there was all those baby diapers hanging on
the wood stove
the big tub and the baby diapers
so the place smelled of kerosene
and baby diapers
and sauerkraut
but the woman, don't you see, was revered
she wasn't being
abused
and kept out of the workplace
she didn't want any place in the workplace
she wasn't being abused
if I said to my grandmother
would you like to get a job
so she'd look at me like I was crazy
she had her job
and she was
so the woman was really
in a way respected
because she reflected an aspect of divinity
that you don't get through the masculine
through the masculine
you get the macho yang power
but it was through the woman
that you got nurturance
it's nurturance by which we survive
you know
so I just wanted people to know how it really was
then after World War II
the woman was needed in the workplace
and Rosie the Riveter
we shifted around then because of Rosie the Riveter
but again you see it's not victim
I'm trying to get past the whole victim perpetrator thing
it's not an evil society suppressing women
women weren't even interested in it
my mother didn't hanker for a job at Woolworths
laughter
the world I brought up in
if a woman had to go to work
the man was disgraced
it was a disgrace
that your wife had to go to work
so
I just want to show you how
twisting a paradigm
makes a thing look like what it isn't
you see
it isn't there's an evil perpetrator
and an innocent victim
nobody had more power
than my mother in the house
my father took his shoes off
and you better not get mud on the rug
and people went
to work
to bed when mother decided
yeah
so power was equally distributed between the two
nobody was perpetrating anybody
you see retrospectively backwards in time
you can project the perpetrator victim model
and what do you get out of that
you get hatred
you don't get justice
so what I meant to say
laughter
when you see men and women as equals
you realize
all these positionalities are done
people get up there and they like to
grandstand
because their ego loves causes
there's nothing the ego likes better than causes
save the grasshoppers
save the forest
save women
I'm always worried
where are they with the Iraqi women
they're busy beating up
the president about Iraq
where are the women now about the suppression of women?
in Iraq
I haven't seen a parade yet
I haven't heard anybody on television
these women can be killed
murdered at the guy
all he has to do is say
I divorce you
you're done
I suspect somebody told me
you were flirting around
he can kill her
it's legal
where's the complaint about
you call out a woman now
where it's real
where women are really being repressed
they weren't repressed in Wisconsin in 1930
laughter
so the field then
everything is the conflict
the conflict
the consequence of the field
so everything is coming about
is the consequence of the prevalence of a certain culture
a certain culture
precipitates out
just like
so if you get beyond cause and effect
let's go on to some more exciting slides
if you get beyond
oh yeah
well this just says what I've been saying
we'll go on to the next one
see what
what the future could hold for us
in the next slide
what number is this
oh
So, this is the Louvre. Well, we spoke in Oxford, you know, this last fall, and a few of us went together, a spiritual group,
and here's the Louvre, which calibrates at 500, and in the middle is this abomination, this strange glass and aluminum cube.
This is magnificent, you know, magnificent, and in the middle is this cube, modernism, calibrates at 180.
I just thought it was interesting. Functionally, you can't beat it. Functionally, it's terrific.
It just looks really weird there.
This is something that was in the A.A. Grapevine back about 1950s, I think.
It was originally in the A.A. Grapevine, which was a monthly publication in A.A.
It came out of the work of several people, and I think it's such a magnificent way of, in shorthand,
dealing with teenagers.
Teenagers and adolescents and people, or even children, not to mention your own inner child.
Here's the tree of self-realization. You see, it's built on the roots of worth, trust, kindness, gratitude.
This is all the source of the kundalini energy, which blossoms forth as creativity, purposefulness, health, joy, commitment, fulfillment.
That's the tree of self-realization. To say yes to one's potential is to release the kundalini energy,
which then manifests in all these various forms.
To say no to it, to say no to it, to say no to it then condemns you to this tree here.
Self-defeating, mistrustful, paranoid, jealous, hateful, fear, guilt, self-pity, drugs and alcohol, crime dependency,
all kinds of conflicts. Bad enough it becomes apathy, a feeling of emptiness, alienation,
and mental illness.
So, it's very simple. I didn't have this when I was working with the girls at Mingus Mountain.
But the last lecture I gave there, I finally retired from there, and I've got it meant to bring my watch with me.
I got one of those watches like you get when you've been with the railroad 20 years. Fantastic.
You push it, boing, and it tells you the time. It's wonderful. I love it.
Got my name engraved on the back and all.
So, I gave a parting lecture, and I had just come across this.
It was sent to me by a gentleman that thought we might use it in our work.
So, I thought with teenagers especially, it's very simple to say,
look, which life do you want, you know? You can have this tree or this tree.
It just makes it so clear, diagrammed, and obvious.
Which do you want? Drugs and crime, the recidivism, most criminals end up back in prison,
or you want a rebirth.
And emerge as a tree.
I like a quick visual like that.
So, we, I wanted to get a bunch of them made up for today,
because I think some of the people, when they see it, they just want one.
So, some of our office staff, Gil, in fact, and Karen, made up.
So, I've got 20. We've got to put 20 of them out in the bookstore.
Anybody wants them. But I just think it's just a great thing.
And, of course, if you blew it up to poster size and do it in color, and the original, this is green.
This is green.
It's sort of very shades of brown.
I mean, it's just a confrontation with which do you want?
Which do you want? Which do you want?
And it should make it very simple.
There are people who hate the green tree.
They do. They really are.
They say no to God, and they hate God.
And, so those who say no, that's your, that's your freedom.
Freedom is to say yes or to say no.
When you say no,
you cut off the flow of the green tree.
You cut off the flow of the Kundalini energy, and the consequences thereof.
But, isn't that neat?
So, we made 20 of them.
I just thought maybe some of you from out of town.
We'll get more made by the next one, and we'll probably put them on the website or something.
I just think, you know, for people doing work with kids, teachers and group therapists with kids and all.
Yeah, this is Ralph.
This is in the grapevine, 1952 or something.
Came probably out of the work of Harry Thiebaud.
And, who else?
I forget.
But, it's just a beautiful contribution somebody made to us.
So, we should take a break.
And, then we'll do, I'll finish a few more things I wanted to say.
And, then we'll have questions and answers.
As you know, we share, we share the dialogue with people with the audience.
People ask questions, and I answer them, and sign books, and whatever.
And, the whole group shares with it.
It's sort of fun.
You never know what's going to come up.
So, we'll take a break, and we'll meet again.
Then, we'll do a grand finale.
What is that?
I don't know if there's that great.
I know it.
I wanted you to see that.