I was starting to say, I got this letter about criticizing how I was handling the,
or presented during a lecture, I guess, to transcend thinkingness,
and pointing out that in classic Buddhism, there's 32 steps or something to it.
And, of course, the answer to that is you don't have to transcend it.
You don't have to understand the mind in order to understand the mind,
because you're not the mind.
And, besides, the source of thinkingness is an infinite silence,
the substrate of the mind, which is present.
Otherwise, nobody would be able to hear me.
It's because your mind is silent, you can hear what's being said.
That which you are is the matrix, the silence that exists the instant prior to a thought,
not in a horizontal fashion, but in a surface fashion,
if you give up being fascinated, the narcissistic investment in your thinkingness,
and devalue it, see it as sort of a hindrance,
and you say, how can I make the mind stop?
How can I get beyond this?
You don't have to make the mind stop.
You don't even have to understand anything about it.
There's no point in 32 years of meditation on the various stages of transcending the mind,
because the mind has no existence and no reality.
It's only catching.
If you begin to live in the field, so this morning we're talking about being the field
instead of the content of the field,
you begin to witness that everything is happening spontaneously.
When you stop projecting res cogitans upon res externa,
you will stop seeing out there what you have projected out there.
There's nothing to think about.
Everything is happening spontaneously,
as a consequence of that which it has become.
As a consequence of that which it is.
It doesn't cause other things to happen,
but as a consequence of that which it is,
we see what we call motion or change about it.
That's also projection, but anyway.
You become the field.
Now you'll notice the first thing about the field.
Let's say I would like to be considerate of others
instead of always,
I'd like to be loving and considerate of them.
So, you can think about it from now for the next 40 years
and it will not diminish it at all.
You've already done that.
It doesn't work.
You bypass the mind.
There's no point in mastering the mind.
You just bypass it.
Don't go there.
You become the field of that which you aspire to.
You don't think about being nice to people.
You choose.
You choose that that is what you value.
So, you become the expression of the field.
Now, as you become the field,
its expression in the linear domain is automatic.
You don't have to think about what to say.
The bird goes,
and you go,
what's to think about?
It's the automatic response of isness with isness,
of joy with joy.
It's the way of life, acknowledging life.
It doesn't require any thinking.
It doesn't require separateness.
It's an automatic consequence.
It doesn't involve thinking.
It's the way you're being in the world,
the way you are, what you've chosen,
what you've chosen to be.
So, as you choose to be something,
you begin to pull to it that which is appropriate to that way of being.
The thought.
The thought to respond to the bird with knock-knock was automatic.
It was spontaneous.
Then, as you catch the spontaneity,
as you identify more with the field,
you begin to catch that everything is happening spontaneously.
There's nothing causing anything.
That even the decision to be deliberate is happening spontaneously.
You didn't deliberately decide to be deliberate.
It was spontaneously.
You just said,
I think I'll be deliberate.
It just came out of nothing, didn't it?
You want to take credit.
So, you don't have to take credit,
nor do you have to disparage yourself.
So, you get out of the moralistic, ethical dialogue with yourself,
which entertains people for years.
I shouldn't have done that.
Forty years later, you're still puzzling.
There is no answer to it because the mind is very clever.
The ego, in order to survive, will create conundrums faster than you can.
Faster than you can solve them.
Unless you're getting paid to solve them,
in which case it will take you quite a while to solve them.
At 75 an hour, it would take me a couple of years to psychoanalyze you.
When I was in psychoanalysis, I got a special reduced rate.
It was $20 an hour by the leading professor of Columbia Psychoanalytic.
$20 an hour, yeah.
So, it took four years.
But the value every day of the week.
So, the value was
that you stop projecting into the world
and you own what Freud called the id.
So, it's popular to put down Freud and the edible complex and all.
It's a great mistake.
Great mistake.
Because what he said is,
unless you own a thing, you're going to repress it or project it.
Or you're going to deny it and isolate it.
And isolate it.
And we see isolation, interestingly, in history, in the book.
I noticed we came across some very interesting examples.
This solves some political problems of many a year.
We find out that some people,
we got two different calibration numbers on the same person.
Wow.
One of the greatest political conundrums of history.
We solved it the other day.
I said, one day I'll get he's at.
What did we get him at?
I forget his name even.
It's in the book anyway.
Anyway, one of the great political discussions of history,
which is still unresolved.
And so we got him one time at 420 or something like that.
And another time I got him like at 160.
I said, oh, what is this here?
It's happened to us a number of times.
Especially in double agents.
They can compartmentalize.
And the guy you know and think highly of,
in the world honors,
in this particular case, he was quite prominent,
calibrated, you know, 420.
At the same time,
he was secretly an espionage agent
and selling all our secrets to Russia.
How could a guy who calibrates at 420
sell secrets to Russia and create the whole,
because those duplicitous people in World War II
and the nuclear thing,
or why we went through the whole Cold War.
I mean, we set up the whole Cold War.
And the fear of nuclear energy, of course,
is what's triggered current events.
It's the fear they're going to get the nuclear power.
So,
the negative fallout of this is enormous.
So, we couldn't figure it out.
I said, well,
I wasn't that familiar with that amount of history.
So, Brock looked it up on the computer for me.
We got the history of that.
And politically, it didn't make sense.
He was a guy that supposedly,
and they never did really resolve it,
that sold the most important secrets
that we had to the Russians.
At the same time, he was a respectable, prominent person.
And we got,
so then when we got,
he calibrated, I think, at 160.
I'm not sure about the numbers.
They're in the book, anyway.
We found compartmentalization.
Compartmentalization is not really well known in society.
It explains the nice guy who murders his wife.
He's a really wonderful guy.
And then she gets pregnant and he kills her.
All kinds of duplicities now suddenly make,
espionage agents,
the Manhattan Project,
some of the great scientists there.
How did they manage to do
what they did, you know?
It's because you'll find they've got two numbers.
They're compartmentalized.
And we've run across it a couple times in personal life
where somebody wanted to come and see us.
We got with the arm.
Yes, it was okay.
And the next time we did it,
we got, no, he's like 150.
And frankly, he'd like to kill you.
Oh, okay.
Well, compartmentalization.
A person can literally have two personalities.
So many of the ambiguities of history.
How can such a wonderful person
like this, this, this, do what they did?
It's because that personality didn't.
The other actually did.
So society wonders if multiple personality
is a psychiatric fantasy or not.
So I'm not calling them multiple personalities,
but people can compartmentalize
so that one part is this way.
So you'll read about the respectable married man
with five children who goes to work every day
and he's also a serial murderer.
He's murdered 20 people.
Green killer murderer or something.
And how could he be a respectable guy
with a family and four kids
and murdered 23 people?
Because this personality went to work
and was responsible,
but this one was a vicious killer.
All right.
So if you own within yourself the downside,
you don't have to compartmentalize it
and act it out.
You don't have to project it into the world
and think you see it out there.
You own that the darkest part of the id
is a vicious Komodo dragon.
So if you own your Komodo dragon,
then under the right circumstances,
I'll bite him and I'll come back later after he's dead,
there's within us, all of us,
in the base of the id, the old animal.
All right.
So if you own yourself during the course of evolution there,
that you can be what the males do in wolf things.
They challenge each other.
They snarl.
So you own the whole animalness of yourself
as a so what because you're not that.
And then you begin to transcend that.
You don't have to project it into the world anymore.
When you don't project it into the world anymore,
the world is a safer place.
You just own that everybody in our society
has a human brain.
With a human brain, the primitive is still there.
And you just own it.
So you see, if you're guilty about it,
you repress it and then you project it into the world.
And that's what happened with Karl Marx.
And so we'll move on.
Marx, of course, would have benefited a lot by Freud.
Okay.
So what we're saying is this is the infinite field, the absolute.
Hegel stated there is an absolute.
All spiritual reality, every state of enlightenment
has a reconfirmation.
We call it divinity.
We call it the infinite field.
The book Power Versus Force, I think, is being translated.
It's being published in China.
China is still not too happy about religiosity.
So we have to transform the word God into the infinite,
infinite power, infinite.
So we use secular terminology then.
So we'll say this is the infinite power source of the universe.
And then it's okay.
If you call it, so you got to cross out God
and just say infinite power source and it's okay.
All right.
Then this is the proximate field.
This is the conditions.
So we said things don't happen by virtue of causality.
They happen as potentiality becomes an actuality
if prevailing conditions are favorable.
If prevailing conditions are favorable.
The seed that's been laying in there in the dirt for 150 years
suddenly shoots out of the ground.
150 years, all the conditions were absolutely perfect.
The potential was unaffected by the weather conditions.
The potential laid there for 150 years.
Finally, this proximate field, the proximate field was perfect.
And then it came forth as a century plant.
You know what they call them?
Century plants?
Yeah.
So we actually asked that about that particular seed.
How long did it lay there?
150 years.
And then conditions prevail.
When the right conditions prevailed,
an African gray parrot appeared in my living room.
See what I mean?
Nothing caused it.
All right.
The content.
So here's the content.
Here's the Newtonian paradigm.
The Newtonian paradigm.
And here's the problem with logic.
The problem with logic and political discourse
is a statement is made within form.
And what they don't realize is that truth depends not just on form,
but on context.
And even not only in that,
but context, again, aligned within the absolute.
You cannot define truth.
So we looked at the great thinkers of the Western world over the centuries,
let's say 350 BC until the present time.
Not a single one of them would be able to decide what is truth.
All the best minds of history cannot decide what is truth.
Why?
Because they're trying to define truth in the here.
You cannot define truth except within the context.
What time, what place, what level of abstraction.
And even then you cannot verify it unless you compare it
to an absolute.
You can calibrate it and verify whether you've arrived at truth or not.
So the thing that we're studying about power versus force,
because I'm just the witness of it,
was the discovery of how to tell truth from falsehood
in the first time in human history.
How to tell it within an instant.
And then how to convey that to the world.
So from a detached viewpoint,
it's the first time the world has had any
definition of what is truth that is verifiable.
So that's the subject of the book that I'm finishing up,
is truth or falsehood, truth or falsehood.
We saw the greatest minds that ever lived
cannot decide on what is truth.
All the greatest minds that have ever lived
And here we are in a second.
What I just stated is a fact.
How long did that take?
That's why the mind has such difficulty in thinking.
Understanding kinesiology is because
they're used to a complex Newtonian paradigm
and an explanation within reason
that calibrates in the 400s.
And the response, kinesiology calibrates at 600.
That's beyond linearity.
It's a non-linear response.
It's a response to the field, to this field here.
Things are only true within certain conditions.
Things are only true within certain conditions,
within the phenomenal world,
within the phenomenal world.
Whether a law is just or restrictive
depends on this here.
People complain about the restrictions
of current post-9-11 legislation,
and they always neglect to mention 9-11.
They always miss it.
It's like after Pearl Harbor,
you know, like Roosevelt was wrong.
You forget about Pearl Harbor.
Oh, yeah, right.
So that changes the context.
So retrospective falsification of history, then,
is an attempt to justify a distorted statement
and make it look logical by twisting the context.
Is a certain thing wrong?
Depends on when you're talking about it.
Is slavery wrong?
It is in our world.
Was it wrong in Athens or Rome?
In ancient Rome, 90% of the populace were slaves.
All the doctors, the astronomers,
all the learned professionals,
they're all slaves.
Slavery was the way human life was lived.
It prevailed everywhere.
In fact, it only disappeared around 1961, I think,
at the urging of JFK Jr.
And it probably still exists in certain worlds.
Is it wrong?
Depends on what era of society.
It's the way business was done.
Nobody suspected it being the way things were
when I grew up in the 1930s.
I considered that normal.
Things the way they were?
Nobody thought it was wrong.
It's the way life was.
So that explains a lot of the things
people like to make political hay out of.
Taking something, projecting it in a different timeframe,
and now doing a make-wrong with it.
The make-wrong, the reason they do that
is if you put it in the correct timeframe,
the make-wrong disappears.
And they don't get to play victim.
Deprive them of being victimized.
Truth is only true within a certain context.
All right.
Also, nothing seems to happen
except a potentiality becomes an actuality
when the field,
when the field is appropriate.
Nothing is causing anything.
Each thing happens in and of its own
as a consequence of that which it is
depending on its appearance.
Going from potentiality into actuality
depends on the conditions in the proximate field.
The fact that potentiality can become actuality at all
is due to the infinite field.
Infinite field.
All right.
The core of the ego is grandeur.
The core of the ego,
the ego thinks it's God.
It thinks it has within itself the power of causality.
Therefore, when a thing happens,
it presumes that there's a causer there called me.
And it takes,
it becomes the author then.
It claims sovereignty.
So the real difficulty then
in transcending the ego,
is its innate delusion of sovereignty.
Sovereignty.
That there is an I that decided that.
No I decided for that arm to just shoot over there.
It did it by itself.
Yeah.
If you're smart,
you will catch
that the mind,
ego,
will claim authorship
one ten-thousandth of a second after it has happened.
Can you catch it?
Not in the classic teaching.
The Buddhist teaching of
trying to catch reality between two thoughts
won't work.
It's prior to thought.
How can you find this if it happens in one ten-thousandth of a second?
Sounds hopeless, doesn't it?
But I tell you, look,
I want you to catch the reality that
exists one ten-thousandth of a second
prior to a mental event.
You'd say, God, I don't think I can be that fast.
No, you can't.
That's a fact.
You can't.
That's why there are very few enlightened people on the planet.
You can meditate for ninety years sitting cross-legged
and going through all kinds of fancy breathing
and eat fancy diets
and it'll get you nowhere.
One ten-thousandth of a second
because you don't know where to look for it.
You don't know how to look for it.
So I'll tell you how to look for it.
Save you fifty-thousand lifetimes.
We'll have to move on.
We'll have to move on to the next slide.
We'll catch how to catch it somewhere along here.
That's not really where we want to catch it,
but I don't know where it is.
We'll find it.
It's the witness-observer.
The witness-observer that is faster than the mind.
Can we move ahead to that and we can back up?
I forget where witness-observer is.
I don't have my list of slides here.
Well, okay, go back one.
Alright, so this is the observed event, you see.
This is just causality.
We'll go to the next one.
I want to get to the next one.
No, go ahead.
Go ahead.
More.
There we go.
Alright, so the person reads in the book,
and it's a mistranslation.
I've spoken to the Buddha about this,
and he affirms me that I'm correct.
No, it's just a mistranslation from the Sanskrit or something.
The reality that you're looking for is just prior,
just prior to thinking this.
You see, thinking this is not like billiard balls.
That's thinking in terms of Newtonian causality.
And everybody's trying to look between the billiard balls
and catch reality there.
But I'll tell you, the billiard balls are moving too fast.
You won't do it.
You won't make it there.
Alright, so where do you catch it then?
You catch it just prior to the event.
Alright, prior to the moment of a thought,
there is a nothingness.
There's no point in perfecting thought,
because the reality of that which you is,
you is?
That's what you is.
Is-ness is present reality, so it's correct.
That which you is, is the condition prior to the thought.
You're the ocean out of which the flying fish fly.
See?
Trying to catch God between the flying fish, you know?
You can't, because the mind tries to connect them.
And I think I said last time,
if you see three flying fish,
the mind projects out there,
look, the flying fish made a triangle.
You know what I mean?
There is no intentionality between these fish.
This fish comes up spontaneously
as a consequence of that which it is
in the ocean at that temperature.
And whatever kind of a tuna fish it is or whatever.
It automatically does what it does
because of that which it is.
Not caused by anything.
Nor did this fish cause this fish over here
to appear.
They have no secret communication.
All right.
How can you catch this phenomenon?
Right now your mind is silent.
Your mind isn't thinking anything.
Thoughts are going on.
How can you know this?
All right, so thoughts then are form.
Where's my magic wand here?
Thoughts are form.
Gil found this one.
A great find, I'll tell you.
It's worth a fortune.
Here's form, here's thought in form.
And here's the registering of it.
And the recognition of it.
And all this goes on.
And how are you going to make that
in one ten-thousandth of a second?
So what the average person does
is take form and witness form.
So you're watching the mind's thinkingness.
You say, I can't get my mind to stop thinking.
Well, what is it that knows that it's thinking?
This is what knows that it's thinking
is that you're registering.
And it's thinking because you recognize that.
All right, so what's prior to the thinkingness, etc.
You wouldn't know any of this at all
if it wasn't for the watcher.
It's because you're experiencing and watching.
And how can you experience or watch?
It's only because of awareness.
So you retreat then.
That I'm not the content of my thoughts.
I must be the witness.
I'm the camera that's seeing this movie going on.
You begin to identify
now, and as you move back in here,
you see, if you stay in mind,
so your mind says, I'm going to catch it,
the infinite reality between two thoughts.
Your mind is thinking that,
and now your mind is trying to do that.
But your mind can't catch one ten-thousandth of a second.
Can't do that.
What can catch the one ten-thousandth of a second
is right here.
Right here, in here,
you become the awareness that you're the light
out of which thinkingness is recognizable.
The watcher, the witness,
is faster than ten-thousandth of a second.
Let's see where on the map we got to catch it.
You know, come over and we'll research this map.
Let's see.
If you try to get in light through meditation,
and you go across this Newtonian track,
this is capable of moving faster
than one ten-thousandth of a second.
It's capable of it because,
oh, I see, because of the watcher experience here.
So the capacity is coming from back here.
It's coming from back here.
Okay, it's coming from back here.
Alright, it's coming, oh, I see where it's coming from.
Okay, thank you.
The watcher witness then
is capable of moving faster than ten-thousandth of a second.
So if you use form to try and catch form,
it's not fast enough.
I didn't word that correctly, I'm sorry.
But if we come from here,
it's because I'm trying to save time.
What time is it?
I've got to finish this in five minutes, I'm sorry.
We'll go back and do it again.
Alright, so if you look from the field,
the field will catch it out of the corner of the eye
in less than one ten-thousandth of a second.
And you will catch that the thoughts
are arising out of nothing.
Thoughts are arising out of nothing.
Out of a complete nothing, silence, stillness,
each thought arises.
What a nice, pretty dog.
What a nice day.
There's a level of consciousness
that puts it together in sequence.
Because of attractor fields,
it throws it into a sequence so that it's logical.
But the source of it is silent.
Right here, nobody's mind is thinking of anything.
If I focus on that level right now,
I don't hear anything there.
Nobody there.
Nobody's thinking.
How come?
How come nobody's thinking out there?
Because nobody is thinking out there.
The source of all thinkingness is coming out of a silence.
So you focus on the silence.
You walk around in the silence.
You walk around and you become the silence
by identifying with the field
instead of the content of the field.
So can we back up again to the
field, content, and context?
The diagrams?
We'll just back up there
because we'll resume there.
All right, okay.
So here in thinkingness,
you're thinking in terms of
linear,
Newtonian paradigm.
Then you begin to realize that intention,
here's the field of intention.
This can't even happen without intention.
So now, instead of identifying with this,
you would begin to identify progressively with the field.
Actually, this diagram isn't right.
We're going to do a better one.
It should really be quite dark here
and then get lighter and lighter and lighter.
So as you identify more and more with the field,
the impersonal field out of which all that is arising,
you begin to identify with qualities, qualities.
So stop being Mary or Sue or JoJo.
Forget about two years of college.
Forget about all the job and car
and all that stuff.
You just be the field.
You be the field.
You know, you can lecture for eight hours
and never think of anything.
You say, what are you going to talk about today?
How would I know?
How would I know what I'm going to talk about?
It's preposterous.
But to people who live,
I guess that reality is here,
it seems, and they want you to announce
what the lecture's going to be about.
How the heck should I know
what the lecture's going to be about?
I didn't even get here yet.
How are you going to make love
the next time you make love?
Or how are you going to eat the next hamburger?
I don't know until I eat the hamburger.
Are you going to start from the left
or are you going to go from the right?
You don't think about eating a hamburger.
You just do it.
So the way is simple, quick.
You be what you are
in its expression as the quality that you deify.
Therefore, if that which you
see as sacred is truthfulness,
consideration for others,
the openness to see the sacredness
and beauty of all life.
The open sesame to the sacredness of all life
is to focus on the beauty of all that exists.
Everything that exists has within itself
an intrinsic beauty.
So you don't think about that.
It's like you increase your awareness
that, first of all, you just heard it.
It's a fact.
Everything within it has an absolute beauty.
Why?
Because everything within it exists
because out of the source of existence
is the unmanifest within the manifest.
And the first thing that hits you
as the ego dies and it crashes painfully
is suddenly the stunning presentation
of the radiance of divinity shining forth
out of all of existence.
It shines forth as a stunning
incredible overwhelming beauty, paralyzing.
The beauty is so intense that one can barely move
that all thought stops
and it never starts again.
And then you have to learn how to function in the world.
You're surrounded by a paralyzing stunning beauty.
It's like the moment of the most highest
exquisite music you ever heard
that made the hair stand up in the back of your head
and now you're supposed to go to work feeling that way.
That took 30 years, really.
Years.
It's irrelevant.
People say, what's going to happen if I become enlightened?
Who's going to look after the kids?
I say, don't worry about it.
It's the universe's worry.
The universe will take care of it
because of the quality of that which you are
brings to you that which is needed
and the same applies to them.
That which they are,
by their karmic inheritance,
will pull forth
that which is karmically within possibility.
Alright, so,
you be and reflect that which you are.
So instead of being a person or a definable,
you become a quality.
You become the expression of that quality.
Don't worry about learning to love.
Just be love.
Love does not go from here to there.
Love is a way of being in the world.
I think the reason a bird's consciousness
or a dog or a kitty,
it's because of the field of love.
Within the field of love,
its potentiality becomes an actuality.
Otherwise, it stays a wild animal.
So we open ourself
to experience the intrinsic beauty
of all that exists.
All that exists in form
has within itself the formless.
Because all that exists
comes out of the infinite potentiality
of the unmanifest becoming manifest.
It becomes manifest
because of the power of the field.
That which I hold in mind
becomes an actuality
because of the power of the field.
The ego would like to say,
I made it happen.
You can't make anything happen.
You cannot make anything happen.
You can increase the likelihood,
statistically,
but you cannot make anything happen.
Why?
To make means the power of creation.
That which it was
now becomes this.
That's creation, not causality.
Only divinity has the power of creation.
So therefore,
to claim that you have the power
to cause anything to happen
is a grandiosity.
A normal grandiosity.
Allah,
great and terrible,
we have to sacrifice maidens.
I understand everything in the universe.
Time for lunch.
Poor flower.
Trampled.
A victim of man's brutality.
There.
He's a veteran now of the wars.
Well, we...
We were someplace.
I don't know where we were.
Well, we had to do with
trying to transcend duality.
And we see the worst expressions
of it when it's put into social action.
Because the perpetrator-victim model
is very...
It doesn't see things as mutuality,
symbiotically beneficial.
It sees things as saprophytic.
This is the winner,
this is the loser.
And that's all in the vision
of res interna, res cogitans.
It doesn't see things as mutuality.
Eh?
Big company comes to a little town.
I was in a little town like that.
Deansville, Wisconsin.
Population.
Seventy, I think.
And the cannery came there.
Now, you know, in the depression,
there was no money.
So here comes a company.
Now everybody's suddenly got a job.
Now they can afford a car.
They can get their teeth.
Kids send the kids to the dentist.
Everybody has a way to take a living.
And, of course, the company,
now makes a profit
because they've got...
They went to where labor was inexpensive.
Because that's what's called common sense.
People worry about wages in the U.S.
I said, you know who sets the wages in the U.S.?
Hong Kong.
That's who sets your wages.
Forget about Wal-Mart.
It's not Wal-Mart.
It's Hong Kong.
It's Singapore.
It's India that sets your wages here.
They don't have to pay
$11 an hour in side benefits.
So instead of $21 an hour,
you can do it for $10.
So to survive,
to survive,
you're going to have to offshore.
So you see,
the economy then survives
because it offshores.
So, in other words,
mutuality is seeing that
the company and the populace,
the worker,
they all benefit mutually.
The same things, you know, go on
in other things.
In other ways of looking at things.
And for instance,
the book that's coming out
would not happen without Susan.
So I want you to come up here.
Come in, please.
Show them what happened to your arm
by the time we finish the book.
7,000 calibrations later.
Even now, you know, it's not,
it hasn't gone to the printer quite yet.
And so I'll come up with one more thing.
And she'll say, no.
So you see,
it's not men against women,
it's men with women.
So the weak masculine derides women.
The weak masculine puts down women,
is frightened of them,
doesn't want them to have any power.
The same cultures also put down dogs,
by the way.
Yes, certain cultures, dogs,
the treatment of dogs calibrates at 40.
In America, the treatment of dogs
calibrates in the 400s.
And the same corollary goes on
how those cultures treat women and children.
See, the strong masculine
honors and protects women.
So the weak exploits.
So the weak is,
the reason you can't take chances with the weak
is because the weak
savages weakness.
It savages vulnerability.
The invitation to disaster
is to be a wimp.
And walk through the inner city.
Because that's a different culture,
has different rules.
The way to get yourself killed
is to be a wimp
in a savage culture.
Because your wimpism
attracts the predator-prey response.
They can't resist to savage you.
So,
the strong masculine does not feel threatened
by the feminine and honors her.
Therefore, in traditional America,
when a woman entered the room,
you stood up out of respect.
You didn't use vulgar, obscene language.
Men hung out in the bar,
and women had the family entrance in the rear,
where they weren't exposed to
obscene language, dirty jokes,
vulgar passes by drunken men.
Testosterone let loose.
Testosterone is bad enough,
but you get the testosterone intoxicated
and put a woman near it.
Therefore,
the difference between weakness and strength,
so vulnerability is attractive.
And if you allow yourself to be dissed
in the neighborhood,
you just got yourself killed.
If you allow somebody to insult you
without standing up to them.
There are two cultures.
It's suicidal to mix them up.
Markeia Quinsberry rules
on the street will get you killed.
The history of all the great wars
has been the West,
Britain or whoever,
came from Markeia Quinsberry rules.
And the other side was coming from
inner city rules.
And I've told you the story before.
You know, as a skinny ectomorph
with bifocals,
et cetera.
I was getting beat up all the time,
so I found a way home
that would avoid the bullies.
But once the bullies catch a vulnerable rabbit,
you know, so.
Finally my grandfather got tired of me
getting beat up all the time.
Plus I was brought up strictly Christian,
turned the other cheek.
You're never supposed to be aggressive,
hostile.
So I was a good Christian,
but I wouldn't have lived long enough to enjoy it.
So my grandfather McCutcheon,
who grew up in northern Michigan,
also traditional America,
says enough is enough.
And he took me to Richie Mitchell's
gym.
And Richie Mitchell was the former
medium heavyweight champion of the world.
He had a professional gym in Milwaukee.
And they opened a new category.
I didn't make fly weights,
so they opened mosquito weight.
Eighty pounds or under, I think it was.
So anyway,
this stick of a kid, you know,
and there's these huge gloves, you know.
Gloves are bigger than a kid.
I gotta lift the gloves.
Anyway, I learned boxing.
So, and I learned how to be very fast.
So what was my asset?
I was, I made a very small target.
And I was fast.
Did you see that happen?
You did not see that happen.
Neither did he.
So then he would have a bloody nose.
And he'd go home.
Everybody left me alone.
I was in the boys' choir.
I was a boy soprano.
And it was a beautiful church,
boy soprano.
Anyway, we had practice,
choir practice every Wednesday night.
All the guys, all the, you know,
we all had the katas with the white thing and all,
you know, like in a movie.
And Wednesday night, though,
we had choir practice,
and then we had basketball.
And somebody would always beat me up there, too.
So after I beat the first kid up,
well, I didn't beat him up.
I just gave him a bloody nose.
Anyway, every bully,
I gave him a bloody nose,
and they all left me alone.
I didn't have to kill them.
I just had to respond strongly.
That's the law of the jungle.
That's the law of the pack,
the wolf pack.
The male who lords his head to the other
just got himself taken out.
Anyway, with my newfound confidence,
so I went to visit my other grandmother,
newfound mother,
nearer to a lower socioeconomic group,
and I played with the kids in the alley out there.
So the kids in the alley,
you know, challenged me.
Well, I was never afraid of a fight.
That's how I got beat up all the time.
If I'd run away,
I was too stupid.
I was too macho to run away,
but not an mesomorph enough to win.
So anyway, this kid challenged me.
So I had my newfound confidence.
So I get all set, you know,
to give him a fast left,
with a right cross.
I was good with a fast left and a right cross.
One-two shot.
By that time, you kick me in the groin.
You can't do a left jab with a right cross,
which is the basic boxing move
when you're crippled and hanging out on the floor
trying to get your breath.
Once you're down, he then kicks you in the ribs
and stomps you in the solar plexus.
That's the lesson.
Don't mix paradigms.
All right, so the male and the female, then,
are not competitive.
They're symbiotic.
The capitalist and the taxpayer,
however you want to envision it,
the government and the citizen,
you know, are mutually helpful, you see.
You can shift the balance a little bit,
but to demonize them
in a dualistic projection of perpetrator-victim
is the downside.
It sucks in large portions
of people's minds.
Okay, so I wanted to clear that up,
that the upside is symbiotic.
Okay, so let's have the next one.
This is just an explanation of that diagram.
We're working on a better diagram.
I thought for the content,
we should have a kitty with a ball
or a dog with a bone or something.
It's just the...
geometric figures.
So this is the content.
This is, we call it, you know,
the ego and the spiritual ego and the spirit.
So you could say
the linear, the semi-linear,
and the non-linear.
In the middle of the diagram,
we have what's limited.
Approximate field is semi-limited,
and the context is unlimited.
Therefore, if you identify,
it's not too hard to move from this...
from this world to this world.
This is the world of quantum mechanics,
non-linear dynamics.
It has to do with what appears.
Instead of circumscribed and limited,
which is the Newtonian paradigm,
you begin to see randomness.
You begin to see creativity.
So it's a looser field,
approximate field.
And then, of course, the ultimate context here.
So to move ahead spiritually,
what I'm saying is don't identify with this,
because this is, first of all, boring.
Don't you think you're boring?
I mean, you're dreadfully boring.
How many times can you look in the mirror
and still be interested?
Every time I look in the mirror,
it's the same boring image again.
It's getting older, so...
So...
The personal self and its ambitions
and all is boring.
All right, so what is energizing it
is the approximate field.
Approximate field.
You're saying to go to college
because this is going to lead someplace.
Why would a person want to improve themself anyway?
It's because they intuit
that there is a progression possible.
So what you begin to identify yourself with
is context.
You identify yourself with the field.
The field in which you exist.
As a consequence of the field, then,
that you choose to value,
you see things the way you see them.
If you value truth above political positionality,
then you see through the illusions of politics
and you wonder how a man's going to survive.
The most frightening thing, folks,
is to calibrate all the politicians out in the media,
and it's scary.
Our survival is in their hands.
And I will say, as you'll see in the book,
how would you like to have a brain surgeon
who calibrates at 190?
How about the pilot on your next airplane?
You meet the pilot, you calibrate him,
good God, 185.
Now we're going to put our country
and our survival in the hands of politicians
who calibrate 180 or 195.
All right.
We are in a philosophy.
We see the downside of...
So philosophy is not just an academic exercise
because it is presuming to present truth.
And when it presents rhetoric instead of truth,
we're the ones, mankind, the population,
is who pays the price.
They get the salary for their job
and we get to pay the price,
which is known as death.
Death.
Which can be serious.
I'm thinking of Secretary of State Simpson,
or whatever his name,
who said,
gentlemen don't read gentleman's mail.
And that's why I was out at sea
in World War II chasing mines.
Because of that idiot.
If he'd read the mail,
he had plenty of warning about the Japanese
in Purview 4, Pearl Harbor.
Can you imagine this guy said,
gentlemen don't read other gentleman's mail.
So he turned down the intelligence reports,
which are routine,
went across to this, the Secretary of State.
All right.
So we then became blind.
And there we were,
playing Marquis of Queensberry rules
in the alley.
Oh God.
All right.
So truth would take you out of that illusion.
See?
So if you now identify with the field,
identify with the field
instead of the content of the field,
then the field,
without any kind of doubt,
without any kind of doingness such as thinking,
thinking is a doingness, you know,
without any kind of a person
involved in a doingness,
involved in a duality,
of a me chasing a that,
you just become that which you honor.
You become that which you honor.
Become that.
Witness it.
Watch it.
See how it moves and behaves.
I always tell people who are envious of rich people,
watch how they behave and be that way.
How can I make more money?
I found out years ago.
Get two jobs, idiot.
That I did.
I doubled my income in one day.
One job during the day,
drove cab at night.
Double income, simple.
Oh yeah.
So in a way,
you see yourself,
hold yourself as unlimited.
Hold yourself as automatically,
look at yourself like a magnet.
Instead of a hungry dog
going after a bone,
look at yourself as a magnet.
See yourself as magnetic
to that which you wish to attract.
That's why.
Holding in mind
that which you value,
then what is held in mind tends to manifest.
What is held in mind as a wantingness
tends to avoid,
tends to
retreat.
If you see something because you want it,
that tends to repel it.
If you see a thing because you
appreciate and love its value,
then it tends to gravitate towards you.
Huh?
Gravitate towards you.
So you become a magnet then.
Instead of a hungry dog chasing a rabbit,
you see.
You become a magnet.
As a magnet,
you don't have any positionality to defend
and therefore you're not attackable.
Yeah?
You see yourself.
If it's okay to be fallible,
you can admit your downside.
Greedy liar.
Nothing wrong with being a greedy liar.
You get elected.
We have fun with politics.
It's a comedy, you know, so.
If you take politics seriously,
you're gonna have a bad life.
It's a game.
Okay.
It's a fun game.
It's like a sport, you know.
It's like a sport.
And the pollsters play their part.
You know, it's really fun.
So then how you see a thing
is how you begin to experience it.
The game is a, you know, life is fun.
It's an endless game.
It's incredibly funny.
You have to keep a straight face
all the time,
so people won't get upset
that you're laughing at things.
It's hard to keep a straight face
when you see things in a certain way.
So you see, you become impersonal,
but not impersonal in the way
people understand impersonal.
Not impersonal, you become nonpersonal.
Nonpersonal.
In other words, you're the focus
of a certain energy field.
And by holding in mind
that which you envision as desirable,
you tend to begin to reflect that.
So instead of a separate individual person,
you're really only the reflection
of a field of consciousness.
That's all you are.
You're like a little mirror
in which this field of consciousness,
which you have now accessed
by freedom of the will.
So the freedom of the will, then,
is to choose that with which you identify
by that which you value.
That which you value is highly,
highly valuable,
is what you tend to become.
So you picture yourself, then,
as easygoing, lovable, attractive, friendly,
and obviously the universe is going to take care of you.
Isn't it?
Even if you starve to death,
it'll be pleasant.
I've been under terrible circumstances,
and so I was ready to go.
You know, the truck's on fire,
10 miles from any place,
and you've got no water.
So?
If you go, you go.
Well, then, the thought came to mind
to take this much coffee
in the bottom of the thing,
punch a hole in the bottom
of the glove compartment of the old truck.
I still have the old truck.
I still have the hole in it.
You pour it through there.
There was no way for the intellect,
the mind, to know that.
All of a sudden, it went,
and the source of the electrical fire went out.
The smoke cleared away.
I was sort of disappointed.
I could leave the world
without feeling guilty at all.
You know what I mean?
I had the perfect setup.
And then this voice said,
take the cup and pour the water in.
Boy, a pal like that.
Who needs a pal like that?
I had a guiltless exit
with no karmic consequences.
And this voice says,
pour that in there.
Oh, well.
Okay.
So that's why I'm still here.
So this field of thought,
so this field is knowable.
It's pulled to you.
It's timeless.
It's always there.
You don't have to create something new.
It's a very general knowable.
It's a subjective state.
It's a spiritual state.
It exists in and of itself,
and it only waits for you to call upon it.
It only waits for you to call upon it.
So the efficacy of prayer
is really you're calling in a certain field,
are you not?
On the other hand,
the prayer is by their wantingness
and seeing themselves as separate and individual
instead of thanking God
for something they ask Him for it.
Okay, let's see the next exciting slide.
Ah, spiritual foundation.
Now, these are things which are,
it's currently fashionable to vilify,
but they are, frankly,
the very basis of spiritual reality.
To be,
and this was traditional America.
This is where I thought everybody was.
Everybody acted normal.
Everybody was orderly.
You picked up after yourself.
Everybody lived up to ideals as best they could.
Everybody was friendly,
polite,
cordial,
reliable.
You lent somebody something,
they gave it back to you.
People tried to be thoughtful
and tolerant,
easygoing.
So these were the,
these are the basics of,
frankly, being a Boy Scout
or a Girl Scout,
4-H club.
These are the basics of life,
and this is what we send our kids,
hoping they will learn.
This is what we think they're going to get at school.
Right.
How to be sane, fair, ethical, balanced,
and sense of humor.
Sense of humor.
So, I think one of the best ways to teach
is to share,
I mean, all I do is share my own sense of humor,
because those thoughts just come out of nowhere,
and therefore,
they knock me over because they're so funny,
and I got to share them just because they're so funny.
But they just come out of nowhere.
You can be driving along the highway,
and the most funny thing will come along.
God, where'd that come from?
It's hysterical.
So, humor is close to divinity,
and I don't know if God stays serious long enough
to worry about the world, frankly.
But everything is sort of comical.
All right.
We all try to,
everybody who's,
be faithful,
a sense of humor.
So, faithfulness is another interesting thing.
Because faithful means to persist,
to persist with a positive attitude.
A lot of people do spiritual work sporadically,
because they haven't got time.
Time to what?
Time to read the book.
Why are you reading the book
if you're doing spiritual work?
Haven't got time to meditate.
You're wasting time meditating
if you're interested in spiritual work.
Spiritual work is a way of being in the world.
So, what are you going to do?
Be holy now?
.
And then,
and then you get in your car,
right back to,
oh,
this is what we call reality.
So, this is non-reality,
spiritual work,
meditation.
And we get back in the car,
and then we call that reality.
So, spiritual work gets separated from life,
through finesse,
to finesse the phenomena
of enlightenment then.
It's really almost like a finesse.
It's a finesse.
It's not a going after.
It's not a doingness.
It's not a performance.
It's a way of being.
That being pulls to you.
So, the answer to a thing
is found not by asking a question.
The answer to a thing is
found by holding
something in mind.
You just hold it in mind.
You see?
It's like you're supplicating
infinite wisdom.
It's like you're
coming from supplication.
You're coming from a humility.
Your humility is a way of being
in the world.
It's not an artificiality.
You hold in mind
beauty of all things.
Beauty of all things.
You see the beauty of all things?
So, you just hold in mind
the knowingness
that intrinsic to all that exists
is a beauty of stunning,
a stunning beauty.
Stunning.
You can't look at anything
and still function.
It's very hard.
Everything.
The beauty of it.
The texture.
The geometric form.
The intention.
The allness of it
shines forth
because
nothing comes into existence
except by virtue of divinity.
Therefore,
within the manifest,
which is what you're witnessing,
is the unmanifest
which radiates forth
the presence of divinity.
And when you first see it,
you just go,
you're looking at God.
God expressed in form.
Yeah.
So, people look at form.
They don't see the beauty.
They don't sense
the presence within.
And they're busy looking for God
someplace.
It's right there.
So, that is an awareness
that is
that happens of its own.
But you're seeing beauty
as one of the attributes of God.
Beauty, like love,
are the attributes of God.
Then,
to love all that exists
is simple
because one sees
the exquisite beauty
of all that exists.
It's very hard
to let go
of a nice old piece of wood.
I've got lots of them
around the place.
Boxes of nice old
pieces of wood.
It's very hard
to let go
of a nice old piece of wood.
I've got lots of them
around the place.
Boxes of nice old
pieces of wood
that are so aged
and twisted sort of
and like
this little piece of wood
just lays there
all sort of crumpled up
in 50 years of rain,
et cetera.
And it's just
the most impossible
to throw it out.
Because you see
the intrinsic beauty
of all that exists.
So, out of this
way of being in the world,
faithfulness is automatic.
Loyalty is automatic.
All these qualities
are automatic.
You don't have
to pursue them
because your attitude
towards that
which is beautiful
is benign.
It's benign.
You see
the intrinsic value
of all that exists.
Therefore,
all these other things
being diplomatic,
trying to be diplomatic
and not hurt
other people's feelings,
all these come out
of the way
of being in the world.
To see the sacredness
of all of life
and all of its expressions
then,
is a way
of seeing it.
So, you don't get it
by asking a question
because a question
is already a linearity.
What you're looking for
is a non-linear
understanding-ness,
comprehension,
awareness.
The minute
you ask a question,
you just put it
into the limitation
of form.
Now, you're talking
a dualistic ego
kind of language.
You're talking
a dualistic ego
kind of language.
You don't have
a dualistic ego
kind of language.
God, what does
so and so mean?
What do you expect?
A voice to come out
of the heavens
and says it means
you're no good, kid?
No.
Because,
when you hold
something in mind,
the knowingness
comes out
of the Purusha
within.
The presence
of divinity
within.
The all knowingness
Then,
like,
illuminates
the understanding
effortlessly
within.
So,
it's not
different
than something
that is already
within you.
So,
it's not
an otherness
coming to a thisness,
which is a
dualistic way
of holding it
in mind
and limits
the phenomena.
You become
all these things.
that which
is positive,
pleasant,
sensible,
grateful
for all of life,
protective
towards that
which is the weak.
The strong
protect the weak.
The weak
in the back
alleys.
The savage
the weak.
the women,
the children,
the dogs,
and the
skinny ectomorphs.
All right.
So,
you automatically
become loyal
because there is
a lovingness
towards all
that exists,
whether it's
you and a
parrot,
whether it's
you and your
comrades at
arms,
whether it's
one you see
that after
great catastrophes,
you see that
after 9-11,
you see the
fire department,
the police department,
the mayor,
the whole town
comes together.
There's a coming
togetherness,
a coming
togetherness
and bravery
that shows up
under those
circumstances
because everybody
forgets their
personal
selfishness
for a change.
So,
catastrophe
and war,
you know,
the ambiance
that you would
like in
World War II
was a oneness.
You could go out
and hitchhike
and get a ride
that fast.
Nobody locked
their doors.
Nobody stole anything.
It was a world
in which everybody
shared with
honor and
integrity.
So,
sometimes
what the
world looks
at as
catastrophe
is the
doorway
through which
you can drop
the ego
and for once
be who you
really are.
Fearless.
Who you really
are in a
really fantastic
situation.
You'd be shocked
and surprised.
You can actually
walk right through it.
If it's my turn
then the bullets
will get me.
If they're not,
they won't get me.
Hell with it.
Because something
higher is pulling
you.
Either the mind
blows up
and we all go
bye-bye
or they won't.
So,
you poke the
man.
Oh,
it didn't.
What do you know?
That would have
been fun.
Two or three
of us go at
once.
Wow,
man,
what a trip.
Two 18-year-olds
going out
of body
at the same
time.
Man,
that was cool.
Let's do
that again.
One minute
you're here,
next minute
you're out
of it.
Wow,
look at the
ship down
there.
There we
are up
in space
in
in talking
then.
In talking.
What's trying
to be conveyed
is a feelingness
for a field.
See?
And the data
is just,
you know,
really to
support it.
This is how
the mind keeps
itself busy.
You don't need
instructions on
that.
Turn it off
before they
begin to do
it.
I don't want
positive suggestions
and negative
suggestions.
The ego,
it's not supposed
to do,
you know.
Don't think
about a green
camel for a
whole minute.
Okay, I don't
want anybody
to think
about a green
camel for a
whole minute.
Yeah.
Immediately
it's going
to do
that.
What happened
to the,
oh,
I thought
we didn't
pay our
dues.
You need
a quarter,
another quarter
for that
and not
this.
I hear people,
they're all praying
for abundance.
They got big
workshops on
abundance.
I mean,
who wants the
problem of
abundance?
Haven't you
got enough
problems?
Do you want
abundance too?
I got a little
rich kid at
Christmas.
He's got all
this crap.
He can't even
carry it all.
His mother's
got to carry
it.
Servant's
got to carry
it.
If you had
one little
dog like
this,
you see,
if you got
this guy
here,
why would
you need
another toy?
I don't
know why
you need
another toy.
This is a
universal
toy.
Oh,
it's
adorable.
If it
wasn't
so bad,
I could
love him.
All right,
we'll
move on to
the next
thing.
This one's
literal,
this one's
intuitive,
et cetera.
But you'll
see what
I'm
advising is
that you
hang out
generally
over on
this side.
And
we're
going to
move on
to the
next
thing.
This one's
literal,
this one's
intuitive,
et cetera.
Try to
make the
spiritual
understanding
concordant
with prevailing
human
understanding
and knowledge
so there's
not something
strange and
foreign.
The reason
religion hasn't
gotten farther
than it has
is because it
gets segmented
from life
and made
to sound
strange and
foreign.
It,
first of all,
gets its
roots in
the
spiritual
reality.
And
I think
spiritual
reality should
be comprehensible
by any
intelligent
human
being.
Be able
to comprehend
how it
all arises,
how the
ego
arises,
how the
ego
works,
how that's
been celebrated
with the
great books
of the
western
world,
and how
the
spiritual
reality
is purely
subjective.
So the mind
thinks in
terms of
linearity.
So you have
to move
from linearity
to non-linearity
so you don't
sound crazy,
spooky,
carried away,
one of those
ooh-la-la
people,
ooh-ooh.
I filled
in for some
local clinic
around here.
He talked
about
the ooh-ooh
people.
I know
what he means,
them ooh-ooh
people.
All right,
so we get
our feet
here on
the ground
with the
Schrodinger
equations,
quantum
mechanics,
the Heisenberg
principle,
and as you
know,
you collapse
the wave
function,
the world
of
potentiality
moves to
actuality.
Now,
triggered
by the
infinite field
of consciousness,
the quality
of God,
which makes
the unmanifest
become manifest.
Triggered
by intention,
the potentiality
becomes the
actuality.
The only thing
that's missing
out of here
is divinity.
He doesn't
get that
it's divinity
that's behind
all this,
but he does
have the
mathematics
and the
von Neumann
principle.
And as you'll
see,
we've said
before,
the Ganges
River,
which is
filthy,
the dumping
ground for
100 cities
calibrates
over 500.
Why?
Because the
intentionality
of sacredness
of the
Hindus
over centuries
by the
millions
has sanctified
the river.
Sanctified
it.
Okay,
so let's
move to the
next question.
This is
from
a
friend
of
mine.
He
says,
I
don't
like
extreme
sports
because
all you're
dealing
with is
a
likelihood
but not
a certainty.
And the
only people
who constantly
engage in
them
have an
unconscious
that's
a possibility.
So after
three times
crashing on
the racetrack,
you get in
for the fourth
time.
You say,
what's
wrong with
this idiot?
His father
went up
in flames.
He just
went up
in flames.
He can't
wait to
do it
again.
What the
hell's
the
matter
with
his head?
Gotcha.
That's
a good
night.
That's
the stock
market.
There you
go.
It's
the
unpredictability.
So that's
what this
person
forgets.
I'm
never
going to
do
sky
diving.
Never.
Never,
never.
The fact
that I've
done it
14 times
in my
life.
Anyhow,
there's
nothing wrong
with dying.
I'm not
putting it
down.
If you
want to
go that
way.
15,000
feet and
then splat.
Not the
15,000
feet,
it's
the splat
that makes
me nervous.
I don't
like loud
noises.
Imagine
when you
hit the
ground.
I should
have gone
a quieter
way,
like an
overdose or
something.
Accidental
overdose,
that would
have been
better.
Every time
people
splat
themselves,
I say,
what's
wrong
with a
nice,
quiet
overdose?
I mean,
what's
wrong
with that?
Why?
I mean,
that's the
way I'd
like to
go.
Make sure
your tie
is proper.
Splat is
just not
appealing.
Okay,
let's move
on.
These we've
said before,
that we
had a
duality
to see
there is
no such
thing.
Those are
just ways
of seeing
things.
Descartes
res
light.
There's
either lots
of light
or there's
not light.
There are
not two
opposites
called light
and dark.
Okay,
Nico.
We did
this before.
We wanted
to bring
this into,
let's
tell you,
what time
do we
have to
quit
lecture?
Huh?
We have
to be out
here at
5,
you're
right.
I have
permission
at this
point,
all they
ever need
to know,
ever
resist.
I know
people have
150 spiritual
books
at home,
you calibrate
them,
take the ones
that make
your arm go
weak,
throw them
there,
there goes
most of
your
pile.
Because
by the astral circus.
The astral circus, all right.
When you're truly spiritually committed then,
the value of going over 200 is when you reincarnate
or in this lifetime,
now you will have a different brain physiology.
Below 200, you have the same brain as an animal
even though you're a human being.
The brain of a person below 200 reacts like an animal.
Does that sound insulting?
No, because I love animals.
It's an animal brain.
It thinks like an animal.
If it sees something weak, it will savage it
because the predator-prey response
is automatic in the animal.
We see it on the streets of the inner city.
The left brain, you see the stimulus,
the input comes in through the relay center.
It's fast to the emotional center.
This is the emotional center.
And the input then is slow.
Through the prefrontal cortex to the emotional center.
And now the memory of this gets stored back here.
This isn't exactly accurate,
but we're gonna clean it up before we post it.
This arrow shouldn't be here.
Anyhow, the slow track is through reason and the intellect.
The fast track is through the emotional centers.
So the person who is left brain below 200
reacts via their thalamus, their left brain, their linear,
fight or flight, alarm resistance, stress to the thalamus.
Their acupuncture meridian goes out
every time they think, kill the bastard.
Just going out.
They're prone to disease
because they're all throwing out their neurotransmitters.
And they run out of serotonin.
So this results in impairment of the neurotransmitters.
Above level 200 now, a new energy begins to flow,
classically called the Kundalini energy.
It's got such a weird name.
Maybe I should invent a better name for it.
Spiritual energy, generically, classically called Kundalini,
and very, very experiential.
It is very, very strong and very, very real.
Now, the Kundalini energy begins to flow from 200 up.
One of the most important things it does
is it creates an etheric brain.
The energy of it then creates a purely energetic brain,
the etheric brain.
Why?
Because the frequencies and vibrations above 200
is so high that the protoplasmic brain
cannot respond that fast.
It would like you need a computer chip
because the old vacuum tube isn't fast enough
to handle the high frequency of today's transmissions.
The protoplasmic brain.
So the neuroscience trying to be devoted
to science and consciousness,
most of those, this conference is all calibrated
around 420, 420, they're looking for,
God, no, looking for consciousness
in the neurotransmitters of the brain
and presuming that it will not be found there.
And there's a very interesting example.
I don't know if I have permission to say this or not.
I have permission to mention who I'm mentioning.
He's pleased with it.
Okay.
I knew he'd be pleased with it.
I sent him my prayers.
God bless you.
So, Francis Crick, co-discoverer of the, you know, Hillel.
Yeah, Helix, you know.
I think he got the Nobel Prize for it.
Well, anyway, the research that led to the discovery
of the double helix calibrates at 440.
And then recently, recently, he'll forgive me.
He got a grant in with, I forget where, Columbia or Harvard
or Yale, I forget where.
They were researching finding consciousness
within the neurotransmitter system.
So, Francis.
Francis, not too long ago, said that the success
of this research, I calibrated that research.
He said about 140.
I can tell you where it's going to go before he starts it.
I calibrated it 140 to prove that, he said,
mankind after this research, mankind will no longer believe
in the afterlife of the spirit.
So, as long as he stuck to science, he was in his own field.
That research was at 440.
It was worth funding.
Now, he just wasted a lot of the taxpayer's money
because he's going to try and prove that there is no spirit,
there is no soul.
And after he finishes his research,
man will be convinced that there is no soul and no afterlife.
Well, Francis went over just a couple weeks ago.
Oh, no, the pressure's on.
That's not true.
Well, we're going to make a statement.
Francis was glad and happy to find he was wrong, resisting.
Now, the reason I had permission to do that is
because he felt a little guilty as he went out,
God almighty, misleading people.
So, I got it from him.
But I got that he was like, pow.
Then he got me focusing in on it and I'm getting like an okay.
Yeah. So, he discovered the heart
and the same thing.
Out of heart, he wants to convey that he was happy
and surprised as he went out of body.
Transcended the intellect, went through the heart.
So, we'll get together before we both come back again, I'm sure.
All right.
So, now the right brain, you see,
what happens is you have an etheric brain
and the etheric brain is very fast, very fast.
So, if I send an electronic message through a computer chip
and at the same time, one through the old-fashioned,
vacuum tube, the one that goes through the computer switch
will have been there a week or two before it gets
through the old vacuum tube.
Remember the old radio, we used to have vacuum tubes all over.
And so, they were limited.
So, the right brain, the etheric brain then,
can pick up the complexity of a whole field.
It can, it doesn't deal in a linear fashion.
Therefore, to become the field of that which you value,
that which you see the innate sacredness,
that then automatically pulls to you from the non-linear,
from the non-linear, see?
How to become enlightened is to transcend the intellect
and the mind, well, that's the linear world.
So, you have to move to the non-linear.
So, I'm telling you the shortcut, you don't have to work
through all the fallacies of the mind.
It'll take you another 40, 50, 100 years
and 36 more incarnations to move beyond that.
It's the slow way, it's the slow way.
It doesn't work too well.
No. You bypass the whole phenomena.
You become that which you know is an aspect of divinity.
The aspects of divinity are infinite mercy, infinite love,
patience, gentleness, beauty, the appreciation
of all those qualities, to see the sacredness of life,
that all life is equally sacred, whether it's a bird,
tapping to you, trying to establish some kind of a contact,
whether it's a mother with children.
It's all the same divinity, the same sacredness of life,
to hold the sacredness.
And the beauty of life and the sacredness are very entwined.
You see them almost simultaneously.
And because there are qualities of divinity,
they shine forth of their own.
There's no point to look for it.
Or the beauty of what is there.
Don't even try it, because everything will look ugly.
No. You drive it away by desiring it.
What you do is you see its sacredness,
and you value it because of its sacredness.
You see the sacredness of all that exists.
When you see it, it is then hard to talk or function.
So I better stop talking about it, because it wipes you out.
It wipes you out.
Okay. So the etheric brain is very fast.
You get the spiritual intention as a reading.
You read it, just like that.
And instantly, it goes through here and now.
It's stored in your hippocampus as a memory.
Right brain dominance is nonlinear.
It's peaceful. It supports life.
Increases killer cells from the thymic gland.
Increases immunity and healing.
Balances the acupuncture system.
And you see that it's a different way of experiencing life.
So that's a good reason not to be judgmental
about those who are impaired.
They're stuck with this way of processing,
and you've been blessed with this.
If you weren't blessed with this,
you wouldn't be at a lecture like this.
Anyway, it allows you to make mistakes.
I don't know how I get through from morning till night.
It's because if it wasn't for Susan, I don't know.
You're going down the...
What do you mean the wrong way of the story?
You're going down the street.
They all have their headlights coming in our lane.
Oh, okay.
I guess that's a hint, right.
Just say, let me drive.
No, I can drive, Heinz.
That's all right. I'll drive.
All right, so I realized that when you get way over
in this side here, I don't know which is the top
and which is the bottom, well, above 200.
If you get too far over here, it becomes less and less possible
to function in the world.
Eventually, you sort of fade out of it.
The women will say, well, who will take care of my children?
I don't know.
Let God worry about it.
Maybe they're destined to die or something.
I don't know.
But I can't let that go.
That's right.
You can't let that go.
That's why you're where you are.
That's what you've got to let go of.
Not to which you're attached.
You think they won't survive without you?
I've been surviving for hundreds of thousands of years without you.
Move on.
Okay.
We're going to skip to 42, I think.
We did all these before.
These were just tracking the book.
We're going to go to 42.
22 to 42.
Yeah.
No, that's not 42.
Let me look at the numbers again.
42.
Well, a lot of what we've done in the last...
In the last year, we were presenting sequentially the research that we did for the book.
We did a lot of movies, the social problems, war and peace.
We did the Louvre.
We did a lot of...
Well, if you're devoted to truth, then you're devoted to truth.
And of course, if you knew what the truth was, you wouldn't be here.
Yeah.
You'd be sitting blissed out in the cornfields someplace.
All right.
So we just went through current society and calibrated.
How do they calibrate?
We just calibrated them to see how they calibrate.
These are, you know, I get all kinds of things like science and theology from the Templeton Institute.
And there's articles on these various phenomena.
And so we calibrate them.
There's an article on it.
So we say, what is the truth of that?
I don't know what anti-creation is.
What anti-creationism even is.
Against creation?
What does anti-creationism mean?
I don't even know.
It means you don't believe in creation.
Oh, okay.
Anti-evolutionism is the other side of the field.
All right.
So because, as people who attend these lectures know, evolution and creation are one and the same thing.
Evolution is how creation unfolds itself sequentially to awareness.
Because you can't grasp the totality of the infinite time of the universe.
You have to view it sequentially.
You can't, you know.
A movie has to be taken in frame at a time.
Now if you condense all those frames at once, you wouldn't get the story.
So evolution is God's way of telling us the story.
Chapter by chapter.
Once you get the whole story, you don't really care how it came about.
It just is.
But the human mind is.
So evolution is the way creation presents itself.
The infinite.
The unmanifest becoming manifest.
The potentiality becoming the actuality.
It doesn't happen in sequence.
It's perceived as sequence.
So what looks like sequence is not a reality.
It's not a reality but a perception.
There is no sequence going on.
Just as in a hologram.
You walk around it.
You think that's sequence.
You walk around a hologram.
You see the arm goes like this.
You say that is sequence.
Walk around the hologram this way.
Is that sequence?
If you look at the hologram, nothing's moving.
All that exists, exists simultaneously in its totality.
So what we think is sequence is a sequence of perception, not of reality.
Right?
That's simple.
I don't know.
These are all things we take out of the newspapers.
Journals that we get.
Advertisements.
Newspaper articles.
Quarter page ad.
Go and see so and so.
So we said, what is all this worth?
Biofeedback.
Everybody's tried that.
Bodywork.
All these are over 200.
That means they're integrous.
Creationism.
I guess that's the belief in creation.
Crystals are sort of neutral.
Depends on what you do with them.
The Da Vinci Code.
The whole concept of it.
It's pretty complicated.
I don't know how it goes.
But anyway.
Calvary is 190.
Jesus married somebody or other and had children and God knows what.
It's pretty fanciful.
All right.
The druids come out remarkably high.
I don't know how come they're that high.
Each one of these, as you can see, is a whole research project in itself.
You could spend months researching many of these things.
Why does Machu Picchu calibrate what it calibrates at?
Why are the druids 450?
Weren't they a rather primitive kind of people in a way?
They were really into astrology more than anything.
I don't know.
So each one of these, you can see,
is a subject for a scholar.
So I presume that people who attend the lectures will get picked up on something,
research it, and give us a report on it.
How come the druids calibrate 450?
These are all individual takeoffs on spirituality.
Enneagrams.
A lot of these things, what happens is they get a certain ooh ooh ooh about them.
People go ooh la la about it.
This is the latest fad.
Everybody's getting their something read.
Everybody's going for holographic breathing.
Everybody's going for rebirthing.
Keeping up with it is hard.
It's a workshop every weekend, folks.
So Enneagrams then have their certain.
That was just esoteric.
How many people here did est?
All the old folks.
Any old esters here?
Still around?
Est was 400.
You remember that?
And what was the value of est?
Was that you had to own your stuff.
You had to go over 200.
You had to admit the reason you're late is because you decided to be late.
You couldn't play perpetrator-victim game with it.
And therefore, 400 is a very high number.
I mean, 400, you're above the vast majority of mankind.
When we said that 85% of,
people on the planet calibrate below 200,
then what percentage ever gets beyond even 400?
So est certainly was very interesting.
Ethical culture.
I don't know anything about Falun Gong.
Feng Shui was a disappointment.
We redid it over and over again.
I said, we had to remove all these damn mirrors and pools and ponds.
I don't know.
Don't ask me.
Maybe it started out as a good thing and it got knocked over or something.
I don't know.
We have permission to do Feng Shui.
The numbers we've gotten before are correct.
Don't ask me why.
Oh, maybe because, oh, it's sort of in a way dealing with magic in a way or something.
Yeah, it's sort of dealing with magic or something.
I don't know. I was very disappointed.
So we moved all the mirrors and put the pond back where it was.
It cost me $4,000 to move this goddamn pond from here to there.
So the energy flow down would be correct.
Actually, that's when my back went out when I moved it.
I was doing fine when the energies were screwed up.
Anyway.
I don't know.
Freemasonry, of course, has a very big history.
Most of the signers of the Declaration of Independence and most of the, many of the presidents.
Fundamentalism is just anything that ends in "-ism," usually calibrates at 190.
Out of fundamentalism, you've got the 200 beyond me.
Anyway, most things that end up as "-ism," means a positionality about that.
It doesn't mean the reality to which you're referring.
It means you've made a thing about it.
It isn't spiritual, it's spiritual "-ism."
The minute you turn a thing into an "-ism," you've just brought it down.
And religions have done that over and over again.
You turn it into an "-ism."
Once it's an "-ism," now it's a basis for war, conflict, revolution, murder.
Hatha yoga is, of course, very positive.
These are all very positive things.
Intelligent design is sort of a, what is it, secular substitute for God or something.
It's in religion and theology news, which I read because I thought I should stay up with what's happening.
These are all over 200.
Kirlian photography, which was a fun thing.
I have to throw in my Kirlian photography box.
I've got Kirlian photographs at my fingertips from back in the 60s.
It was very big back in the 60s.
Everybody had a Kirlian photography box.
And you looked at your aura, you know?
That's the fun.
And then people would read the aura.
Pink means you're so-and-so and green means you're so-and-so.
Anyway, it all calibrates to 160, eh?
I was disappointed in that.
Ah, heck.
Kung fu, 410.
Metaphysics, 460.
Numerology, 210, higher than I thought it would be.
Qigong, I'm rebirthing.
Rolfing.
Everybody been wolfed?
Oh, my God.
Now you can stand up straighter.
Now you can say, look, he's half an inch taller.
Yeah.
Oh, those are all fun things.
Rosicrucians, soul midwifery.
Now, should you let go of wanting to control a thing or surrender it to God?
Makes a big difference.
One is secular and the other is secular.
The other is not.
Should I let go of wanting to control something or should I surrender it to God?
Letting go of wanting to control it calibrates about four something.
Surrendering it to God is 535.
Huh.
Tai Chi at 310 is fun.
Theosophy is wonderful.
Universalist church.
White Brotherhood, of course, is very well known.
The work of Alice Bailey.
White magic.
People are always saying, well, it's only white magic.
But you're playing close to the line.
I was just leaving magic alone altogether.
White or any color, whatever it is.
And Wu Den, I don't know what it is.
Okay, we'll move on.
These are just things we took out.
I thought people would know what they are.
I said, there's somebody out there that knows what it is.
Wu Den.
I've never been Wu Den-ed.
I thought you might be interested in this.
What time do we have to stop?
Okay, well, we only got a couple minutes.
But we'll have another lecture.
What I've been doing this past year is trying to keep you up with the book as we did the research.
Reporting the research as it came forth.
The Lord's Prayer at 650.
You see, there's a big difference between om and ah and mispronouncing it.
Om is pronounced oh.
Not ahm.
Ahm calibrates like lousy.
Ah-oom calibrates even, I think, less than 200.
It's either oh.
There's 210.
There's a, I think, Patanjali or whatever his name is, aphorisms.
One of them, translated by Satchitananda, recommends this pronunciation.
There's a translation of somebody, I think it was, by Satchitananda, recommending this sound.
And you see this sound, a-u-m, it's quite a difference.
You see the enormous difference.
Therefore, spiritual awareness can be quite decisive.
You can spend a lot of lifetimes at 210 and not get too far.
And a half a lifetime at 740 and find yourself right in front of the Lord.
Om namah shivaya.
Om namah shivaya is wonderful.
Om namah shivaya, I think I remember picking that up from Makananda.
Makananda, I think.
Om mani padme hum.
Gregorian chants, japa.
The Jesus Prayer.
Rosary.
All these things, they are very positive.
12 steps of Alcoholics Anonymous at 540 calibrates higher than a great deal of what's on the planet.
The Golden Rule, Transcendental Notation.
Walking the Maze, Chartres Cathedral.
Now you notice all these acts, genuflexing, kneeling to pray, holding one's hand prayerfully.
Devotional acts, turning prayer wheels.
People say, look at those idiot Tibetans, turning prayer wheels.
Aren't they ignorant?
It's because of the devotion behind it.
Turning the prayer wheels, burning of incense, the Wailing Wall.
All 540.
You see then, the power of devotion.
Devotion then, makes anything sacred.
And the prayer of Saint Francis of Assisi at 580.
Which is about where you would expect it to be.
Way up there.
Have we got time left for another slide?
People are always asking for spiritual teachers, so we did a hundred.
We did a hundred that calibrate over 460.
They're alphabetical, easy reference.
Any one of them is all you need.
All you need is one of them.
Spiritual students, we always pour all over.
You know, we get excited about spirituality.
We read them all.
If you've got spiritual friends that go to their house,
you'll see they've got probably 150 books at least.
Everything.
So these all, I thought we'll find at least 400 in.
They calibrate over, you know, 460 is really reliable truth.
So we took 460.
We asked the arm, what would be the right cutoff point?
We got 460.
Right?
You're saying yes?
Are you signaling me?
Was that a secret signal meaning something?
What does it mean?
What?
Oh, you have to tell me.
Oh.
All right, we'll quit.
We're going to have a break.
Then we're going to do questions and answers.
And in the coming year, we'll probably spend more and more time with questions and answers,
more in traditional style for people who are really intensely spiritually devoted.
So these are the spiritual teachers.
We've got 100.
It's not necessary to find some obscure oddball thing that was, you know,
channeled from the other side about beings from other planets in the future and crap.
And if you go out there with an UFO,
they're going to take you to the sixth dimension of the 32nd future realm
where you can meet Master Bom-Bum.
You don't need that.
That's how you avoid spiritual work.
That's how you avoid it.
It's called diversionary.
Diversionary.
Now, there's nothing wrong with it,
but it is diversionary.
It's not possible to master all the writings of all these people.
You don't have to feel guilty.
Out of all 100 of them, you've only read two.
The other 98 are, and so forth.
And so forth.
Because once you get the truth of any teaching, you've got them all.
You've got the essence of all of them.
And therefore, I think it's a very interesting list.
A very interesting list.
Most of these names are familiar to all of us.
And you see some of the great names.
At 750, the aphorisms, etc.
And my favorite, if any author was my favorite,
it's Huang Po.
I get Huang Po right away.
And I get Krishna in the Bhagavad Gita.
I just understand it like that because that's how it is.
So each one will appeal to you at a different time.
Different teachers appeal at different phases of spiritual growth.
So people say, which is the right teacher for me?
It all depends on where you're at,
what you're up against,
what kind of karma you're getting pulled up.
And the teacher that's perfect for you here may not be perfect for you there later.
Sometimes people outgrow the teacher and have to go on.
Okay?
All right.
Anything else on this?
Did we finish it all?
Is that it?
Huh?
Forty?
Oh, okay.
Anyway, I think there's a hundred altogether.
Where is it?
Are we moving?
What's after this?
Forty?
You're going backwards.
Forty-two is the last one.
We're going to go from twenty-two to forty-two.
Forty-two and that's the last thing.
Oh, that's the last slide.
Forty-two.
Well, let's go.
Well, let's go to forty-two again.
No, that's wrong, isn't it?
Okay, they got the numbers backwards.
Okay, go backwards.
Oh, that's the way it is.
Oh, okay.
Well, okay.
We changed the slides around, so I want to apologize for that.
Anyway, I just tell you, the work, you know, it's progressing.
We took calibrating levels of consciousness.
We looked at the world and all the aspects of the world.
Went through it extensively.
Did thousands of calibrations.
And now in the last part of the book,
we're looking at religions and spiritual truth and the teachers.
And so we've left the world.
We've looked at the world to see how it reflects by calibrating levels of consciousness.
And now we're moving into religion.
And then we end up looking at pure spirituality aside from religion.
And that pretty much concludes then what is really a very,
the book is coming out.
I'm calling it the first encyclopedia of truth ever written.
That's a fact.
Okay.
All right.
So now we're going to have a break.
After that, we'll have questions and answers and discussions.