Dr. Hawkins, good to see you again.
Hello. Hello.
It's good to see you.
>> Hello, sweethearts. Hi.
You can do two at a time.
>> Two at a time. Two. Oh, you got one
already. She's cheating. Look.
>> Good morning, Doc.
>> The head in the wall. Look at this here.
>> And he talks and he thinks
>> the talking head.
>> A talking head. He's a talking head.
That's Yeah.
>> From where? Where are you from?
>> London.
>> Outside. London.
>> London. Oh, yeah. We're going to go down
this line and then we done everybody.
>> So nice to see you.
>> Yeah.
>> Excellent.
>> That's a nice jacket. Looks like it's
from space. Looks like it came in from
space.
Hey.
So, we're set, eh?
>> Here we go.
>> Well,
I can tune into the world.
Where's Gigi?
>> In the back.
>> Isn't she going to make an announcement?
>> She did.
>> She did. Oh, heavens. It started
already. Nobody told me.
I didn't get any message from
Well, we're all here because we're here
and uh
we've arranged special weather for you
this weekend.
>> Sedona is usually horrible in August and
now it's a very nice day and it's good
to see so many people that we know from
around the country. We speak all over
the country and there's the same people.
I think I'm in the same place all the
time.
Okay. So,
we need to know um how many people are
here for the first time? Anybody here
for the first time? Oh my goodness. Six.
All right. So the reason I asked that is
because there's certain basics
and uh and so I give attention to the
basics for those who have not been here
before and those who have heard it
before every time you hear it you hear
something new. Uh so
uh and we have some new slides today and
uh
uh just finished the book and and I oh I
have a message from broccoli.
Uh, Broccoli is my new African gray uh,
parrot.
And broccoli calibrated at 375 when I
got her and she's now 380.
That's in about 6 weeks time. I'm
watching the seeing with you and of
course she's competitive with Coco with
no not Coco with uh,
>> Alex. Yes. So she says, "I don't want to
hear about Alex."
So we have a new game. I tap on the
branch and she taps back. And
so anyway, she did have a message for
you this morning. She said, "Merry
Christmas.
Every day is Christmas,
but it's a fun uh it's a joy." And uh
it's a joy. And of course when you're at
the room, you think there's a you think
there's a a small party going on in the
next room because you have different
voices, you know. Hello. Yeah. Look at
all
I I love you. I love you. It sounds like
all these people talking and then
whistling
songs.
It's like a 5-year-old playing in their
sandbox all by himself. You know, they
do that. So that's a a new joy of life.
And um who knows what joy brings us. So
the many blessings all those things
happen as a consequence of the field. Uh
that which you are automatically tends
to attract that which is um natural to
that field.
And therefore
um instead of seeking something
uh be that quality be that quality.
Today has to do with the lectures has a
title called um
today has a lecture and the title is uh
so we'll speak on that.
Instead of meditating on a thing or
wishing or desiring to be uh something
um just be that quality.
Don't you know forget the identification
with the physical and the mental and
your name and occupation and all those
ways of specifying linear
separateness.
And see yourself as reflecting a a
reflecting qualities.
See yourself as
so that you walk around as a reflection
of the field.
Instead of
seeking something,
what you do is you act out and be that
quality.
You act out and be that quality.
That's if you reflect that quality then
you don't have to think anymore
because you just are that
and that which you are automatically
does that which is concordant with the
field.
So to be polite and considerate then
means that you value that quality and
you become that which you value.
So if you want people to be considerate
and generous and nice to you, then all
you have to do is reflect that quality.
So right away you see, you're out of the
linear domain and now you you've become
a field. You're the reflection of a
field instead of a person. Forget being
a person. It's so boring being a person.
All we want to know about you, we can
look up on the internet.
Everybody's so paranoid about their
privacy and the government and all. It's
hysterical.
Don't worry about your privacy. You
don't have any.
You can't lose what you don't have.
I can call Brock and say, "Look up
something other than and the the print
out is all over the floor. where you've
ever been, where have you ever shopped,
everything you thought, everything you
bought, everything you ever bought,
every place you've ever been, every
every store you go in, you're on video,
privacy.
So
that's all the the individual the
individual see
and that's all the linear domain and
that's what people get stuck in. They
think that they are all those
specifications.
So to move ahead spiritually then it's
better to identify with fields rather
than content of the field
to be the quality with which you find
yourself surrounded.
Then that which you have become reflects
back reflects that back to the world.
You'll find that New York is a loving
wonderful place. Everybody is generous.
Everybody was solicitous. Everybody was
very polite. Everybody knocked
themselves out to be as um congenial as
possible. We stayed in a lovely place.
Everybody treated us elegantly.
We went for a handsome ride in the in
the park.
The horses were friendly. Everybody was
friendly. So what is the complaint?
Uh so
you become the become the quality become
the quality you become the reflection of
that quality
because there isn't really any any
entity there anyway.
When the entity disappears, that which
you've become continues to walk around
in the world, talk and it even gives
lectures.
I didn't know what it was going to do
for many years.
I had no idea what it was going to do
for many years, much less talk again or
write again. No such thing was even
imaginable. So then
um sharing uh that which you've come to
know by being it uh became
the energy that resulted in uh writing
books and giving lectures etc.
You say why did you do that? It's sort
of like when Sir Alexander Fleming
discovered penicellin.
You know what I mean? You've discovered
penicellin here. You're going to leave
the world and you've just discovered
penicellin.
I mean, the responsibility of that, you
know what I'm saying?
So, Fleming ran around, everybody tried
to get him interested in uh antibiotics,
you know, penicellin was the onset of
antibiotics.
And nobody paid any attention. They all
thought it was sort of outrageous idea
and ridiculous, etc.
And it was only because of the infection
in the wounds of the soldiers in World
War II that the army, I believe it was,
paid attention to him. And
anyway, you can see if Fleming had the
opportunity to leave,
uh once he's discovered penicellin, he
can't leave.
So, it's the penicellin that's keeping
me here
until I finish this book. Anyway,
do we have uh we have slides today?
>> We do.
>> We do. Do we have the What's the last
slide? Can you go backwards with this
machine or can you only go forwards?
>> I can.
>> You can go to the end first?
>> In a computer world, you should be able
to go to the end first.
Yeah.
No, that's not the end.
Not yet. There he is.
Can Can we turn the spotlights down?
We have to turn the spotlights down. Can
anybody Who's in charge?
Is there anybody in charge?
God.
There's nobody in charge here, folks.
Just think of that. There's nobody in
charge.
Well, well, well.
It's party time. Party time.
Nobody running this place. There's
nobody in charge. Nobody's watching
property. We could just walk off with
the place and they wouldn't even notice
it.
Okay, we'll fill our pockets. I'll take
the speaker. You take the Uhoh.
Anyway,
that book is going to be out in October
and uh
hysterical.
We got any more? Oh dear. Oh golly. I
think there's one more. He needs his
hair comb, too. Well, he didn't know his
picture was going to be taken.
So, you get some idea what it's been
about. And uh
it's been two years of that. So, that
answers that question. So, we go back to
the beginning.
So, we took care of the important
things. Now, we can get
to be that which you are. You see, you
value equality. Value of the value
equality, not a person or a thing. See,
don't get into guruism either.
The quality that you wish to own within
yourself is already a reality. It only
waits for you to own it. Once you own
it, once you identify with it, if that's
if that is what you cherish, then that
is what you become.
That's what you begin to reflect to the
world. Now, the world will reflect back
a confirmation of that.
The world will reflect back a
confirmation.
If you wish to be hateful, the world
will oblige you and hate you. See, then
you can say how hateful the world is and
hate it without feeling guilty about it.
See?
So you envision that which that quality
which you wish to own because it's
already a reality. So you don't have to
create it. You don't have to create it.
You don't have to wish for it. You have
to you can't there's no point chasing it
or desiring it. It's just just a quality
and you just be that quality. You
reflect that quality which is already
present.
So if you value then kindness,
consideration, you'll find yourself
going through the world being polite,
saying thank you.
Saying thank you is fun. And we were in
some restaurant and they had pan fried
trout. Pan fried trout. It was the best
pan fried trout I've ever eaten. Usually
I don't get pan fried trout. It's got
little bones and stuff. Anyway, it said
pan fried trout. So anyway, it was a
knockout. So on the way out, I went back
and said to the chef, you know, that's
the best pan fried uh trout I've ever
had in my life. I mean, he just went
long. He just beamed. He was so happy. I
can tell he went home to his wife that
night and says, "The customers are
telling me how good a cook I am." You
know what I mean? And then you realize
how rare that is. How rare that is. how
rare it is for people to even, you know,
to express their joy back to people. Uh,
somebody knocks their brains out to
shine your shoes and you don't say,
"Man, that's the best job I've ever
seen." You know what I mean? Just those
simple things to be gracious, to be uh
to confirm for other people their joy in
life, their value in life, that what
they're doing is appreciated. See,
because whatever they're doing is there
is no scale of worth on on the things
you do, action has no scale of worth.
The simplest thing can be of critical.
You know, somebody holds the dumpster up
for you and your back is out and that
somebody hold the dumpster out for up
the hill for you, you know, because
you're worrying how you're going to get
it up there and then suddenly you find
it's up there. So those little joys of
life. So you reflect back to the world
that which you envision um as the
qualities that you admire. Yeah. In that
way you quickly go up the scale of
consciousness which just disappeared.
How long does it take? People think,
"Oh, it's going to take lifetimes and
lifetimes and lifetimes."
Well, the way it used to be, it probably
did.
The knowledge about consciousness was
extremely limited.
A few gurus existed, but they lived in
ashrams and enclaves, had little
exposure to the world,
and uh often had peculiar requirements.
Weird food,
crazy headdresses,
odd strange things you had to do and
eat,
funny ways to breathe.
That's all form. Huh? What you're
seeking is the formless which is a
realization. It's an awareness which
comes upon you. It's like a cloud that
envelops you. See, people think
enlightenment is over here and I'm going
to grab it. Yeah.
It's like a cloud, a myasma that
gradually takes you over and then
suddenly
how long does it take to get from down
here
to way up there?
Tenth of a second. Tenth of a second.
Let's see.
permission on that one. A tenth of a
second is correct. Resist. Tenth of a
second is correct.
One instant.
It's this way. The next instant
a totally different universe.
Takes one/10enth
1/100th of a second one 10,000th of a
second. That's all. the longer it takes.
So why worry about lifetimes when it
only takes one 10,000 of a second?
Therefore, when the willingness is total
and complete,
then it happens automatically of its
own.
It happens. It's like you pull out the
last prop. You pull out the last prop
and the door swings open. Huh? So it
doesn't require effort, doesn't require
suffering, doesn't require agony,
doesn't require penance.
It also needs a teacher to tell you
that.
So you can skip all those steps without
feeling guily.
All right? So the way from the bottom to
the top is can be very rapid. So people
get um discouraged. They say, "Well,
I've been meditating for years and then
they're this, they're at this and
they're at that place." Huh? Uh not to
worry.
Consciousness of its own seeks
uh the realization
of its own selfidentity as the source of
one's own existence.
The movement overall of human
consciousness is progressive.
So you're going with the stream. For one
thing, you're going with the stream and
not against the stream. Human
consciousness is evolving. And as we
said before, the last time the last
harmonic concordance in October 14th in
San Francisco, the consciousness level
of mankind went from 205 to 207
uh all by itself.
What can we do to change the world? The
first thing you can do is do the world a
favor and and don't try to change it.
The naive person tries to change the
world.
Wisdom teaches you to change yourself.
Change yourself. You don't have to
bother changing the world. And the world
is serving its karmic purpose. So why
would you want to change it anyway?
If you relieved all suffering, all war,
all poverty, and all this, there
wouldn't be any people here.
Where would you go to evolve in
consciousness? I mean, this is the
ultimate teaching ground, isn't it? You
can go from people who are lower than a
komodo dragon on their calibrated level
of consciousness uh to Christ himself.
So what more do you want here? You've
got uh a springboard. Here you've got
the uh the perfect school,
you know, a staging area. So I look at
human population on the earth as a
staging area. Is there anything you want
to change about it?
No.
As long as I got Pepsi,
espresso, coffee, there nothing I want
to change.
Why? Because each thing is serving its
purpose. Each thing, each of us is born
with an already calibratable level of
consciousness. If your calibratable
level of consciousness is 70,
you're not going to come here if this
has become a celestial realm due to all
the dogooders.
This will not be inhabitable by us who
are trying to get off being miserable,
cowardly,
sneaky cheaters.
Where are we going to go
to learn that honesty is the best
policy?
Where's this guy here gonna go? He needs
Enron and Worldcom,
Martha Stewart. He needs those people
need that. Where else are you going to
crash?
You run this number is about 190. They
run about 190. You run 190 to its
ultimate end and then you hit the wall.
Bang. You hit the wall. That's the
purpose of it. So if we didn't have an
Enron or a Worldcom or whatever, we'd
have to create one.
So we can stop uh making the world wrong
and being judgmental about it if we see
that it serves the ultimate karmic
purpose.
Free will choice is so unlimited because
you have a whole panorama.
You can go down here
from
killing yourself and a busload of
children in the name of God
In the name of God, you're going to blow
up a busload of children. That's a tough
one to sell yourself.
But if I by doing that I go to heaven,
then screw you kids
because I got 30 virgins waiting for me.
He's going to blow up a busload of kids
so he can have 20 virgins
>> or was 75 virgins. I don't know.
Yeah.
>> 75 for young guys, 20 version.
The other thing they they don't tell you
is that those virgins are 900 years old,
too.
and they're ugly and toothless.
And they hate men.
I got you, Dary.
They don't tell them those are the
virgins.
There's only one reason they're a
virgin.
Okay.
And you get there after blowing out the
bustle of the kids and they say, "Okay,
to Okay, boy. Go to it now.
Go to it.
And you better perform or else.
No Playboy magazines in heaven." No.
So from the from the most the lowest
what we look at as the lowest levels of
consciousness then which are primarily
primitive the residual of the animal
brain.
The difficulty with an animal brain is
when you put a prefrontal cortex on it
now it becomes a very clever animal.
Now you teach this clever animal with a
brain of a
dinosaur
religion.
That's what you've got.
You got a dinosaur brain. You've taught
it religion and now it eats you in the
name of God.
That's the condition of the world.
All right. So
on the one hand it's humorous you know
when you put it all together
and because all of it is humorous
if it was reality it would be sad but
it's not reality and that's why people
come here is to discover
uh what is re real and what is not real.
Each and everything then fits together
uh perfectly. The karmic
debt of the 30 children in the bus just
got paid off.
Bumped, right?
So each thing is perfectly in accord
with everything else.
That which gets blown up had the karma
of getting blown up or it couldn't have
been blown up. Right? Because nothing
happens by accident.
The in infinite field of consciousness
is like an infinite electrostatic
magnetic field of infinite power.
Each one that comes in has a karmic
inheritance of karmic pattern
within that infinite field. Then the
karmic pattern can only go where the
pattern takes it.
An iron filing cannot defy a giant
electromagnetic field of infinite power.
The iron filing can't say I've decided I
don't want to go this way.
I've decided I don't want to go this
way.
Now
each thing can only be then the
fulfillment of its own karmic propensity
and therefore everything is in accord
with everything else in an absolute
perfection.
To see imperfection then is a projection
the dance of Shiva.
Then how you see it is it terrible is it
wonderful is it terrible is it wonderful
depends if I want it and if I don't want
it terrible if I like it it's wonderful
that out there is
hasn't moved at all.
It's the same.
So we become then the reflection of that
which we hold
with reverence.
Therefore to re revere those qualities
means you automatically in due time
become them.
That which you hold in mind.
That which you worship, that which you
deify,
uh that is what you become. That's what
you reflect by choice.
There's an infinite field of infinite
frequencies and vibrations that
accompany all these attitudes and views
and emotions.
So what happens is that you become the
automatic consequence. You become the
reflection of the field.
No longer a person.
Stop thinking about yourself as a person
or an identity
because you aren't that anyway.
You're a karmic windup toy. Let loose.
Karmic windup toy. let loose in a world
of infinite possibilities
and infinite gradations of energies.
So you automatically float to the locust
of maximum benefit.
Each one is born under circumstances
that are karmically perfect.
Anybody got a resentment about the
circumstances of your birth?
Oh, you've been to the lecture before,
eh?
Everybody, the circumstances of your
birth are perfect.
Whatever impairments you have, whatever
the circumstances, they are the most
propitious for your own karmic benefit.
So
that's why self-pity
uh is invalid because you don't know it,
but you're born with a certain
calibrated level consciousness under
circumstances that are most propitious
for that.
Now, if that's the fact for you, then
it's a fact for everyone. It's a fact
for everyone.
You you left people to die of starvation
and slaughtered them mercilessly, then
you're going to get born in a place
where you left to die of starvation and
slaughtered mercilessly.
And now you just undid that.
So then you see that the world is like a
theater of maximum benefit.
You see that you have the option to
stop identifying as an isolated person,
you know, a linear
definition
and become just the reflection of the
qualities that you respect.
If you respect honesty, hard work and
responsibility, then you'll
automatically be to work on time. You'll
automatically finish the project. You
automatically give the boss his due for
your pay etc. You automatically become
integrity. If integrity is what you
value, you become that.
Now as you become generosity,
lovingness,
the desire to see the sacredness of all
of life, the sacredness of all of life
begins to reveal itself to you.
Merry Christmas
is the joy of life coming through that
birdness.
The bird has learned that it's part of a
relationship.
The new game is I tap on the branch
with a pin and he and she tap tap tap
with her nose. Bump bump bump. First
time she did that, I'm sitting in the
chair. She goes bump bump bump. I said
h. So I went over and took my pen. I
went bump bump. She went
the joy of discovery of relationship,
meaningfulness,
significance.
Immediately she was a somebody to me,
you know, and of course the joy was
equal on this side because now I
realized I was a somebody to her.
So we just birthed a meaning meaningful
relationship.
in which you intuit it the other the
other being's joy.
So then life becomes the unfolding of
endless discovery and joy of kindness
and love and responsibility
and um
so you don't have to fight your way up
the ladder of consciousness which keeps
disappearing on me. Every time I turn my
back on you notice that it disappears.
It does that. I've got this wonderful
this is now this is a real one
the calibrated levels of consciousness
um
as I remember way back in the 70s it got
discovered back in the 70s and uh so I
started to calibrate these are out of
psychoanalysis uh
Columbia University psychoanalytic uh
school these are um emergency emotions
and these are the welfare emotions
classified by Shandra back in the 30s
also by young by by everyone uh it's the
perennial philosophy this
uh the way these levels lay out are in
accord with the perennial philosophy
which is very ancient mankind is always
considered
um the stratification of these qualities
uh pretty much in that way. And you'll
notice that hell is at the bottom of the
chart and divinity is at the top. It's
extremely important to notice that
the way to God through shame, guilt,
sackcloth, and ashes,
grief, fear of God,
anger at God, and pridefulness in how
religious you are doesn't get you there.
Doesn't get you there. because
pridefulness in religion etc is what
leads to war.
So it isn't that religion
uh which is very much in the public
view.
Uh it isn't religion, it's what people
have done with religion, what people
have done with it.
So we learn not to blame religion for
the Inquisition and various other
horrible things in the past as well as
the present. It's what people do with
it. It's what people do with it. You can
give somebody a pillow and they will
enjoy it. Another person will take the
pillow and smother somebody to death
with it. So it isn't the pillow.
It's what you do with it
that saves you making various religions
wrong. Yeah. Which in today today's
world is a temptation. Every time you
see somebody show blowing off a bomb on
the name of some religion, you blame it
on the religion. No, that's the
perversion. That's the misuse. That's
the exploitation.
Um all kinds of things go go on the
camouflage of religion. It's a
camouflage. Camouflage.
All right. So at the bottom then we
calibrated all these things. Uh and we
did a scale of one to a thousand. First
I start out mathematically and the
numbers got so huge uh mathematically
and that I had to switch the
logarithmic.
So the calibrated scale of consciousness
uh begins to ascend very rapidly and the
degree of power becomes infinite.
It's no longer even trackable.
The energies at when they reach a
certain level
uh become too powerful and too high a
frequency
for the protoplasmic biologic nervous
system the neuronal structure to handle.
And therefore there is the birth of the
pure not the birth but the emergence of
the atheric body which is
nonprotoplasmic
concordant with the physical brain and
we call it the spirit. This happens at
consciousness level 200.
So at 200 you see a whole change of
quality.
You see the courage to face the truth,
the willingness to face the truth. And
you see that the c
what's going on in consciousness is
empowerment.
So from here down you have force.
Force people have to resort to force
because they don't have power.
Because they don't have power and they
envy power. So they think they can get
power by getting more money or
uh beating up more people etc.
It keeps eluding them because power is
of a different quality. Power is of a
different quality.
Power then attracts to it exactly that
which it needs and doesn't have to do
anything except accept what the world
offers. Huh?
So this is all seekingness and gain and
even if it's successful it lead then
leads to an ego inflation called pride
narcissistic
over evaluation of oneself and
arrogance. Arrogance
uh and the downside of that is of course
uh quite painful.
we cross over 200 and that that is the
critical point critical point we know
that in America 51% of the people now
51% of people America calibrate over 200
51%.
The chances of meeting somebody who's
integrous now are 50/50
that's pretty good
5050.
In the rest of the world, the chances
are only 15%. The chances in the world
are 85%
of the world caliber rates below 200. So
there's no point be bemoning the world.
When you read the paper, just tell
yourself that's what the world below 200
looks like.
What did you think it was going to be? A
fairy dance?
Those who live below 200 kill each other
routinely.
And if you try to stop them from killing
each other, they will hate you.
They will hate you. They live off of it.
They live out of hatred. They live out
of the spleen. And that's their
livelihood. That's their
self-identification.
Therefore,
you can't really deprive them of it.
You'll find that out. Try to get
somebody to stop feeling sorry for
themsel, you know how difficult that is.
50 years in psychiatry, the toughest job
in all 50 years
uh was to get people off the victim
martyr role. They cling to it. I mean,
they cling ten to nasciously. And if you
begin to threaten it, they become very
hostile.
I am the victim of how my mother treated
me. I am the victim of how my husband
did to me. I'm the victim of society.
Uh victimhood, that's the biggest
addiction in our world. People think
it's alcohol and drugs. Forget alcohol
and drugs. They're nothing compared to
victimhood. Victimhood. People cling to
it. Cling to it. Cling to it. Injustice.
victimhood and injustice without which
you can't blame anybody. So
with nobody to blame, no injustice and
no vict victimhood and no martyrdom.
Doc tell me
now that's the hardest one to get people
off of it because it the ego thrives on
it. The ego thrives on injustice
and blame and self-pity and martyrdom
and victimhood.
The perpetrator victim model which is
very popular in society.
I mean the doorways to victimhood are
jammed
the society for this and that you know
thousands of things all victimhood.
Okay. So then we get beyond that and we
own that we're just getting we're ju
we're juicing it. The ego loves to juice
negativities. That's why it's hard to
get people off anger, hatred, blame. 30
years later they're still hating and
blaming a person for something. It's
because the ego gets so much juice out
of it. That's the only juice the ego
gets is the juice of negativity. And you
want to take it away from them. That's
why they get angry at you. So, America
is about as popular in waring parts of
the world as you would be if you go down
the block, you hear a waring uh couple.
You know, you hear a couple down the
block, I hate you, Harry. I hate you,
Jenn Genevie. You know, say you run down
the block to help with these people.
Next thing that happened, you're going
to have a black guy. They're having you
arrested.
What's he doing here? Oh, he's the one
you're having. I think you're you went
down to help the people.
Uh I found it's best to go there when
they invite you.
and take a third party with you better.
All right. So integrity then we enter a
whole different uh domain. We feel a
different responsibility.
You can't leave the world with
penicellin when nobody's until you know
till somebody's seen the value of the
penicellin because you feel what a
responsibility
uh you have something you want to share.
So out of love, out of love then one
does many things out of love. So you can
do things out of love that you cannot do
out of anything else. Out of love for
one's fellow. I mean in World War II,
you know, out of love for your your
comrades, you'll do things that are
absolutely ridiculous. You turn your
back to the enemy and take a riddle full
of bullets and and you'll take risks.
You'll do things for love that you
wouldn't do for anything else. It's not
bravery. It's not courage. It's because
um really love uh interestingly enough
the love of uh men in the military for
each other or women now calibrates at
510.
510 there's it's the sound of bag pipes.
The sound of bag pipes. You wonder that
you feel that the hair go up in the back
of head. So we calibrated it in
Scotland. It's 510.
At 510, you lay down your life for your
brother.
Profound
uh brotherly love. True brotherly love.
Loving the other person
as yourself really. So it's a very
advanced.
So that's one of the purposes served by
the military is you jump over 200 and
will now do things out of integrity,
love, and courage. So you see,
everything serves something. Everything
serves something. So you can't say,
"Isn't that terrible? They're at war
with each other. Where's this guy going
to cross the line?
He left the last time out of Cardis.
This time he's going to come back. If I
got to walk into the bullets, the hell
with it." So you walk into the bullets.
You literally walk in and you got to
literally walk into the bullets. And as
you leave the body, you made it.
You made it. And all your buddies are
there, too.
Instant recognition. I remember doing
that in the Crusades, you know. And I
told you about that guy. Boy. Boy, I
really put it through him. And he put it
through me. And we looked at each other
and like
I did it for Jesus. He did it for Allah.
Man, we both broke into circle laughter.
All right. So, you you go up.
I did it. I did it for Jesus, too.
Yeah.
And he did it for all, too. I mean, he
was no uh he was very ferocious. I mean,
he was a son of a gun. All right. So
that's how we transcend the scale of
consciousness
is the willingness to be the field, the
willingness to let go positionalities.
Uh the the need to be right. It isn't
just being right. It's like you need to
be right. You see how how that
wantingness it's like needing. I need to
be right. I need to be respected. I need
to make money. I need to be a success.
So, it's that neediness. It's the
neediness that you get off.
Instead, you become that which attracts
those things. You become that which is
attracts those things. You build a
better mousetrap and the world will come
to your door. I guarantee it. I
guarantee it. Guarantee it. You become
trustworthy,
pleasant, cheerful.
Uh,
and when they call the cleaning service,
they say, "I want so- and so. She's
terrific. She's terrific." We had a
couple recently that I thought were just
great, you know, and we wanted them. So,
you become that which would attract that
which you wish to be and then
automatically discover that you already
are it.
You don't have to seek it. You already
are that. I mean, you'd tap back to
broccoli, wouldn't you?
Broccoli goes
and you're sitting there. You go, hm.
I mean, you just got it, right? You
don't have to struggle to be that.
Struggle to be that. You already are
that.
So you open yourself to your own
infinite possibilities by owning
yourself as what you desire to be
because you are that already. It's just
that you haven't owned it. You just
haven't known it yet.
Yeah. Well, we'll go on to something
less serious. Let's go on to something.
We changed the slides all around, so I
have no idea what's going to come up
this morning.
the discovery that you could calibrate
the truth of anything in time or space.
That the infinite field of consciousness
is a vibrational field of infinite
power.
It goes up a whole scale much like the
electromagnetic
uh spectrum to extremely high and very
powerful frequencies. Too high and too
powerful for the human nervous system to
tolerate.
The human ner nervous system can
comfortably tolerate up to about 600 or
700 and from here on it becomes
extremely difficult and hardly anybody
goes there only a few people on the
planet in the 700s nobody it's extremely
rare uh I don't think this is the right
dimension to do it
and uh because the protoplasmic nervous
system is not equipped to handle those
high frequencies and energies and must
be able to go over this level here will
complain about all kinds of aches and
pains and racked with all kinds of uh
things. So, we calibrated uh every all
everything that could be calibrated and
we found that the highest level that's
ever walked this planet was 1,000.
Highest beings were 1,000.
Did the scale of consciousness goes up
to 600. At 600 you shift over from the
uh linear to the nonlinear reality. At
600 is called traditionally
enlightenment in which
the identification with a personal self
is who you are dissolves and is replaced
by a field. It's replaced by at 600 it's
replaced by bliss.
It's an overwhelming bliss.
The state is self-sufficient.
In that state, one needs nothing.
The physiology seems to come to a halt,
don't need to eat, don't need to drink
water, don't need to have to go to the
bathroom, don't have to move.
And uh there's even the choice to
breathe or not.
The breathing will actually stop. You
can either breathe or not breathe.
You can either hang out with the body or
let it fall over.
Sort of relevant.
Then because I would say of karmic
propensities, some phenomena may occur
in the world
in response to which you breathe again.
that your father will think that you
have just died and spend the rest of his
life in guilt berating himself. So out
of caringness out of love then one may
breathe and reown the the bodiness
again. So 600 most people leave the
planet they hit 650%
I think we said uh will leave the body
they just won't breathe it again. and um
and then some for strange reasons most
people will go from below down and
suddenly land at like 700 or something
like Mr. Maharaja. So, and the other
thing curious about it is they stay
there. Practically never happens that
anybody arrives at like 700 and then
moves on from there. They stay the rest
of their life at 700. Uh lived at around
by the mountain there or Mr. Gada
Maharaj. They stay at at that level.
This probably smarter. You come back,
move from here to there, another realm.
So anyway, once once in a millennium
somebody will continue on up. So we
calibrated these levels and we got the
divinity is sort of like a step down
transformer. The infinite power of God
is so enormous
u so enormous that
that with man doesn't encounter the
power of divinity directly you might say
through the nervous system. Uh but
they're sort of like step down
transformers. So he said, "What are
archangels or 50 thou 50,000 and up?"
50,000 and up. You want to buy an
archangel, it's going to cost you 50,000
and up.
Yeah.
All right. So, we'll move on to the
next. So, that's as far as the scale
goes to a thousand. And this is the way
it graphs out. Uh, this is the way it
graphs graphs out in microwatts.
Uh, here's the level of consciousness.
Here's the power in microwatts and you
see it goes up to infinity. Infinity.
Okay. So, we like to correlate the known
world, the world of logic, the Newtonian
paradigm, and then move from the
Newtonian to the nonlinear quantum
mechanics. And then at 500, you're
moving in fromo supposed objectivity
into subjectivity as the absolute
reality.
From 500 up, it's the subjective that's
important. From 500 down, it's the
so-called objective world. Okay, so
we'll move on.
And this is the way the world is
distributed. It's not accurate. We
redrew this graph. It's really 85% of
the world calibrates. So the great mass
of humanity, this is the great mass of
humanity. And as you can see, as the
numbers gets higher, there's fewer and
fewer people on the planet. You can see
uh here in America it's about 50/50.
85% of the population on the in on the
planet then is below 200. That's the
great masses.
I was reading yesterday
67% of the people on the planet live on
$2 a day. Two US dollars a day. 67% of
the people on the planet live on $2 or
less. Two American dollars or less per
day. 67%.
All right.
Then when you get to the level, here's
America 421.
Here's America 421. You see, of all the
people on the planet, you're just a a
few folks here.
You're just a few folks. If you go from
421 up, you're seeking who you got to
talk to. Huh?
Kill these people. Don't you think
democracy is wonderful?
Get out of your bastard. I'll kill you.
A boy in Afghanistan. I want you to vote
for democracy and give me your gun, boy.
He just prescribed his death without a
gun. He's going to die. All right. So,
that's where we stand. It gives us sort
of a a feeling of where we are and who
we are and the way we see the rest of
the world. Let's go to the next one.
Huh? These are familiar to people who've
been to these lectures before. Uh but so
we just quickly we're going to review
them. Here's the 15% on the planet. This
is the 85% of the people. And we'll move
to the next one.
And you see how the 15%
C counterbalances the 85%. The reason is
from 200 up power increases
logarithmically.
One person at 500 is more powerful than
I don't know 10,000 people below 200 or
something like that. Probably more than
that. Okay. So otherwise the world would
self-destruct. Humanity would kill
itself off. Why didn't uh Russia set off
the ultimate bomb that was going to
destroy all of life? They had it
planned, the mega bomb, etc. Uh it's
because of this 15%. You see, because of
this 15%, propitious things happen that
preclude man from killing himself off
completely. Gorbachef without a single
shot takes down monolithic communism. So
the cold war and all our bearing our
teeth and all was probably necessary at
the time, but that isn't what we didn't
defeat Russia in the cold war. Now
Gorbachev just pulled the prop out and
it collapsed.
He's at 500 or over 500. One person at
500 then can
collapse the entire Russian communist
regime. Is that power what? Gorbachev
and what who was our president then?
>> Oh Reagan. Yeah. They were both over
500. Curiously. Yeah. Both of them just
pulled the thing and the whole thing
went.
Not a shot. No war. No fire. No bomb. No
atomic bomb.
Wonderful. Okay. So that's so that's the
function of these people here to just be
who they are. So the president at that
time and Gorbachef were just being who
they were. Just being who they were.
Just being who they were. And who they
were as a consequence counterbalanced
that which was going to set off the mega
bomb. The plan was it would destroy all
of life on this planet permanently.
That's sort of a negative thought, isn't
it?
Let's go to the next one.
And we see the rise of consciousness for
those who haven't been in these lectures
before. How the the way to relate to ego
is like a pet because the ego then
instead of being uh vilified, instead of
setting yourself against the ego, you
see it as the automatic consequence of
the evolution of life on this planet.
This was a whirling ball of molten
millions of thousands degrees Fahrenheit
flying through the universe. It
gradually cooled down. A crust formed
enough that
matter formed.
Then the energy of divinity, the light
of consciousness itself, the light of
consciousness when it interacts with
matter has the propensity
uh potentiality to create create life.
Mhm.
Uh that's a fact. Resist.
Okay. In
scripture, it's the light of God. The
light of God consciousness itself
interacts with inert matter.
And it's because of the life of
divinity, the light of God because of
consciousness
that a life arises.
So it does not arise as a happy
um accident of chemical reactions.
Uh
it happens as a consequence
of the infinite power out of which
existence arises.
So on this planet, the chances of
survival of life were probably slim,
right? It's red hot in the middle. It's
still molten in the middle. What is a
couple thousand degrees in the middle of
the earth? Right below my feet. Couple
thousand degrees down there, folks.
So on this uh you might say hostile uh
matter uh life begins to evolve. It has
to in order to evolve it has to be
interested in survival. Its primary
programming has to be survive. If we
land on Mars, that's going to be our
program. Survive.
So life then in its earliest form, the
first conscious life is bacteria. Uh
does not have within it a source of its
own energy. And I always say the saddest
part of being a human being is your is
we're not green. If we were green, had
go chlorophyll, we wouldn't have to work
or nothing.
You just walk around the sunshine,
recharge your batteries, and you're
fine.
Now, you've got to get you got to eat.
You got to If you got to eat, then you
got to have something to eat. Now, you
got to go to work.
Also, you don't have fur. I mean, we
really came in here poorly prepared. No
fur, no feathers. You can't fly. You got
to walk.
Got to buy a car. So, you can see
So to survive life had to become
self-interested.
So the core of the ego then in its most
primitive form is me me survival.
Therefore there's no point in making it
wrong in other people or in yourself.
It's supposed to be that way
for the bacteria. So the amoeba doesn't
have an energy factory. The amoeba has
to go out there and get energy in
chemical form, whatever form.
Therefore, life in its primitive form
then has to acquire energy. So the first
signs of life here are bacteria at one.
And these are the archaeologic ages
which are so prehistoric that I can't
even figure them out.
The age of the oldest dated rocks is
about
trillion years old.
Can't too big a number to read.
All right. So slowly over great eons of
time then primitive life becomes more
clever at acquiring energy. It learns to
swim in the ocean for it. Learns to eat
other things that have arisen at the
same time. So life you see is not evil.
It's just deficient. It has to get in
order to live. It has to get.
Here you see we finally get up to the
dinosaurs
uh primitive mammals consciousness level
at this time is only uh here it is in
the 40s. the rise of reptiles
in the 40s.
And that's about Bin Laden in the 40s.
40s to 60s. Yes.
You think you're dealing with? What do
you think you're dealing with?
The prefrontal cortex then has taught
this thing how to be a better reptile.
Here you go up here. you finally get up
to
uh
the beginning of modern mammals and then
you finally get up to 212 here and more
evolved. So you see life becomes
uh more and more clever at survival and
when you get to a certain level
consciousness level uh it changes form.
So let's go to the next chart. It
changes its nature. And so here you have
the bacteria we were talking about. And
then protozoa, the arachnids, fish,
vipers. Uh we put octopus in here.
Where's octopus? Oh, not on there.
Octopus is 20. Anyway, so life becomes
more and more complex, but you still see
you've got to go out there to get energy
to live. The polar bear has to eat. All
these animals have to eat. They have to
get it from someplace and we call them
voracious and uh
dangerous animals. And then when you get
to consciousness level 200, the same as
in human consciousness 200, you see a
major transformation
from voracious to benign. Uh suddenly at
we just calibrated a whole bunch of
animals. We just did all these animals
we could think of. They were not
arranged in a chart like this. We just
did them random. And Sus and I just
spent one weekend doing all the animals
around and the birds around everything
else.
This was animal weekend. So
then we arranged them according to their
calibrated number. And here's how they
came out. And you see how they arrange
themsself. You see that which is below
here is carnivorous and voracious. It
has to get and then suddenly when you
get to 200 you see a shift to the kind
of animals. So here are the herbivores.
So here are the carnivores and here are
the herbivores.
So these don't have to kill anything in
order to live.
They have a different mechanism and they
become vegetarians.
Uh, all the vegetarians can now feel
superior to the non-vegetarians.
You become as smart as the sheep. Now,
nothing is serious, folks.
The only things that are serious are
things that you make serious, you know,
in and of himself. Yeah. So, here's the
kitty and the family cat. And of course,
uh we did um
uh
broccoli. Now, let's see what broccoli
was when she was born. What was broccoli
born in? We're going to take an African
gray at birth. We have permission to ask
that calibrates at birth over 250 255.
So, it's a pretty evolved It's pretty
evolved. It comes in at 250. Wow. It
comes in at 250. Wow. So, she came in at
250. When we got her, she was What did I
say? She was at 350.
Something like that. All right. So, here
you see then these animals are more
evolved. You see the uh the effect of
human interaction with the cat, it jumps
five points in consciousness. The human
interaction with dogs, they jump five
points. uh you come up to the gorilla
chimpanzees.
Chimpanzees are extremely intelligent.
And here are the exceptions that we of
course have fun with. Alex the trained
African gray parrot of Dr. Pepperdine
from the university down in Tucson. Uh
who can count and knows all kinds of
things. Calibrates at 400. And Koko
uh who recently had a tooth extracted.
Koko got that there was something wrong
and tooth wrong.
Went to the dentist, had her tooth
extracted. That was in the news this a
week ago and Koko had a tooth extracted.
And then you come to these exceptional
things where a trained African gray. So
we're tracking the African gray that we
got as a present and she came into us at
two 350. So she had already moved up
during the year and a half of her
previous life. and now in the last 6
weeks has moved from 350 to 355.
So that's interesting.
Uh and of course we're going to train
her because Alex is at 401 and we're not
going to be happy till
trouble is Dr. Pepperdine spent months
and years blue cube red thing. I'm not
going to do that without
uh okay song bird song at 500. And here
we have uh puzzles that we still haven't
solved. Why is it that a cat's purr
calibrates at 500? Why is it that a
dog's wagging tail calibrates at 500?
And when we were in Toronto, the front
page of the paper, I don't know if I
told you told you about it in the last
lecture, but um a dog by the name of
Elvis, it was a a pretty mentally
disturbed p person who had a whole bunch
of high-powered rifles and ammunition,
6,000 rounds. He was going to kill
everybody in sight and then kill
himself.
And Elvis was in the park and Elvis had
a Frisbee in his mouth and ran over to
this guy and wanted him to play. And
this guy suddenly like came to his
senses. What the hell am I doing? People
couldn't talk him out of everything. But
Elvis just by being what Elvis is, this
guy instantly changed. I must be going
crazy. He threw all the guns away and
they surrendered. So uh the power then
you see that's 500. So,
here's a guy who probably calibrated
what 120 or something about to kill
people. And a 500 energy comes up and
says, "Play with me."
And of course, karmically, this guy had
the choice at that point. He could have
shot the dog. use
a lot of people do because a couple
weeks ago in Prisc or some place like
that the option was
taken the other direction to shoot the
dogs. Uh no he didn't shoot the dog he
got it and lay down his guns and is
probably getting a professional help. So
that 500. So you see how all the how the
world comes together like that when it
doesn't meet the when it's not logical
we call it a miracle. It certainly was a
miracle for the people that he was about
to shoot
but the miracle. So the propensity of
everything involved then uh moved
impersonally
and Elvis just saw the man
and reached out to the man and man
looked at the dog
and you see how it all when you put it
all in slow motion then you see what
life is about.
If you want to understand a situation,
don't ask a question about it.
Reflect on it. Just hold it in mind
and then look at it in slow motion.
And its true nature just reveals itself
to you as come and play with me.
The intrinsic innocence of all of life
then reveals itself.
Therefore, you stop vilifying life
because you see the innate innocence.
The children who are brainwashed into
thinking that if you blow up a busload
of kids, you'll go to heaven because
you're serving God. You see, they're
they're innate innocents
like Hitler youth in the 30s.
They're just brainwashed and therefore
the defect is ignorance. The defect is
ignorance. What the Buddha said, what
Christ said, the reason to forgive
people is because intrinsically
h everyone is innocent.
They're innocent because what you
inherit as a human being then is an ego.
You inherit a mind which is like the
hardware of a computer and life then
comes in and programs it.
You're born with hardware. What's And
you're born with the software of your
pre-existing karma, but you now have
software that has options. So the disc
isn't finished yet. The disc is only
half done. You come in with a certain
programming. But that man had his
choice. He could have kicked Elvis right
in the chops, said, "Get away from me,
you bad dog." and shot him. And he
didn't. So he, you see, the option was
right there. So if you do a stillife
snapshot of things, it reveals itself.
That's the beauty of photography. The
the genius of photography to me is that
it takes something like that and it does
a stop frame. Now you get to see it for
what it is.
You get to see it in the middle of the
stop frame. Huh.
All right. So,
that's enough for you folks now. We're
going to have to take a break pretty
soon. Let's see. We'll go to the next
one. I think we'll take a break at
10:30. Is that okay?
>> 10:30.
All right.
>> Yeah. Okay. So, we got All right. So, I
just wanted you to see the the evolution
of the ego. To transcend the ego to
become enlightened then is means to
transcend the ego. How do you transcend
the ego? The easiest way is by
completely and totally understanding it.
By understanding its origin, how it
developed and what its qualities are.
There's no point of berating it, listing
all the negative qualities of the ego as
sins and then feeling guilty about them
and berating yourself
and hating other people because their
consciousness level is below 200.
You see how it evolved? So the
difficulty with becoming a human being
is that you inherit uh an animal brain.
You inherit an animal brain and then you
got a prefrontal cortex plastered on the
front of it. They didn't remove the old
animal brain. They now put a prefrontal
cortex prefrontal cortex.
So instead of teeth and fangs, now you
can do atomic bombs or bullets or
machine guns.
the wolf just bears his teeth and
slashes the other one's throat. Uh we
use machine guns.
So you see the basic primitive animaless
hasn't changed and the preffrontal
cortex now has just been added to it. So
what's the problem of being a man is
that you got a prefrontal cortex. Now
you've got the birth of spiritual
awareness and you've got it birthed in
an animal.
So self-hatred and conflict is
inevitable if you're born human
and born human. So the karma of being a
human is the karmic battle then between
the animal below between
calibrated levels below 200 and above
200. So we are the stage of evolution
that transcends the animal. It owns the
spiritual reality of its own existence.
And we then progressively transcend the
animal and become and realize that we
are only the spirit of life itself. We
are the energy, the spirit of life. Huh?
What does all this mean? Well, of
course, it's all led to great philosophy
and discussion and epistemology and
theology and metaphysics,
all kinds of religions, theological
propositions, philosophic systems.
So, how did the man evolve then? So, he
gets a prefrontal cortex and now he has
to make some kind of a peace with his
animal nature. Religion certainly serves
that purpose to a certain degree. The
one reason enlightenment is extremely
rare is because religion will only take
you a certain part of it and then
religion itself becomes the block.
Religion itself takes you from here to
there. Then it becomes the block beyond
which you have to transcend. And
therefore enlightened people have
traditionally been called mystics. The
mystic then transcends the religion
itself and reveals the spiritual core
out of which the religion arose in the
first place. Uh all right so the
investigation of this is interesting
throughout history. The great books of
the western world of course were put
together in 19 I don't know 55 I guess
uh by mortml Adler at the University of
Chicago with a whole group of the
world's best scholars. They they still
have a a scholarship committee uh which
still is still active and they still
recommend that you study the great books
of the western world over a 10-year
period. They have a 10 10 year study and
you spread it out over 10 years and then
you can say that you are liberally
educated.
To be liberally educated takes 10 years
and you have to have read every one of
these and known what they meant.
volunteers.
I read them as a kid. That was a
misspent youth to be speckled, skinny,
60 pounds, bif focals,
sitting in a big chair, skinny, reading
books while everybody else is playing
football.
Muddy, disgusting game. Violent.
All right. So, I'd rather read the
apherisms of Marcus Cerillius myself. So
that was the misspent youth. Mispent
youth.
All right. So you find this is very
interesting. The greatest thinking of
all times of course what does it mean
today? It means it set up the categories
of logic, truth and reason. All this was
done categories of logic, truth and
reason were really pretty much finished
by about 350 BC. However, then in later
uh term times uh they became embellished
and interpreted in greater depth. All of
them are very interesting reading. Every
every single one of these is
interesting. And we wondered how they
calibrated. So we calibrated the great
books of the western world. I happen to
have a set which due to good karma I
came upon in a used condition and got
them cheap. I had to pay for them. Uh I
think $500 I got something like that.
Oh, so
here's the best thinking. Of course, it
the best thinking uh is all also in
inculcated into our our political
system, the constitution etc. came out
of uh ancient Greece as we find through
the philosophers 16 1700s etc. So you
have the best thinking of the world from
the ancient world of ancient Greece uh
on through the intellectual development
of the western world. Uh and so we have
the most uh craftily thought out
government, political system,
constitution,
bill of rights etc. comes out of is
distilled out of all this thinking
starting out from Aristotle, Plato and
Socrates. Socrates is not on the list.
Socrates didn't write anything. He was
too smart.
He says he was short and ugly. He had a
had a vicious wife. So couldn't get any
peace at home. He couldn't write
anything probably because she never shut
up.
Her name was Zantippi. And she's famous
in history just as Socrates is, but for
other reasons.
All right. So Socrates calibrates, I
think, at 540. About 540 or 550. So he's
not on the chart because he didn't write
anything. But of course he he what he
had to say is included in Plato and uh
Aristotle. So here you've got all the
great thinkers of all time. And you see
Aristotle at 498.
498. And Socrates as I say was at 540.
Uh Socrates uh also strangely had a
profound faith in God, a profound
spiritual belief.
uh now Christianity hadn't been born
yet. Christianity didn't exist yet and
neither Buddhism, Hinduism had crossed
over to ancient Greece. So somewhere
I'm still not sure where oh yes I think
he got he was a mystic anyway through
his study of truth plus his own inner
intuition he was committed to truth to
God as divinity to truth as as
representative god. So when Socrates was
accused of corrupting the youth of
Athens by teaching him such things as
I'm telling about today
corrupting the youth uh he was condemned
to death and um he was ordered to drink
um
himlock. Yep. Well he could have
bartered his way out of it. He could
have hemmed and hawed backed off and
Socrates refused. He says uh he believes
in God as truth. He teaches truth and he
cannot negate truth in order to save his
physical life. So there was a great hero
long before and one not well recognized
the greatness of Socrates as he also
said other things that uh have a great
bearing on today's society. All right.
So here you see the evolution then of
this prefrontal cortex which is put on
the old animal animal brain and you see
Francis Bacon you see Berkeley all the
great names of history Shasser
Capernicus
Di Charles Darwin at 450
Darwin is of course very interesting
because Darwin science calibrates in the
mid 400s and the theory of evolution all
of science so The mid 400s are the
birthing then in the western world of
science.
The great wealth uh of which everybody
supposedly hates America. The great
wealth and power of America is birthed
out of consciousness level 450 460. the
great wonders of science,
engineering, and the great discoveries.
And think of all what America has
discovered. Everything from the airplane
to just about everything else that sells
anywhere in the world, you know, it
originated in America.
So the capital of America, uh, which
people like to vilify, uh, is not money
at all. The capital is inventing
electricity.
Thomas Edison zip just created more
capital than half the country's in the
world annual income
electricity think just one thought so
capital is creative genius
Henry Ford you can name one after
another Westinghouse
the people who invented the cotton gin
invention creativity and genius that's
capital.
If you want to take something with you
that's worthwhile, you take one
brilliant idea and from that you can put
me anywhere on the planet and I'll start
all over again.
Put me in a deserted island in the
middle of nowhere. Come back in two
years, you'll see employment.
I'm manufacturing swings and
coconut fruities.
Yeah. So creativity, inventiveness, then
genius. So what is capital? Capital is
genius. Uh the money is automatic
because as I said, you just be what you
are and the consequences are automatic.
If you invent a gasoline engine, if you
invent an airplane, uh you'll create a
whole new industry. So what the world
really envys, although they don't know
it because they don't want to face it,
is the genius of creativity and the
value that we give to individuality and
creativity. That's the genius. They
think it's the money. It's got it's not
the money at all. The money is the
automatic consequence. The automatic
consequence. You build a better
mousetrap, everybody's going to buy.
You're going to be rich. So I believe to
pull people from the lower to the higher
means to encourage and give recognition
to their creativity and their potential.
When the bird went tap tap tap I
instantly went to back to the bird and
said tap tap tap. You understand? In
that moment the bird became a
capitalist.
Ensured its survival the rest of its
life.
We have to we have to put her in our
will.
The person says you got to put this bird
in your will cuz they live to be 100
years old. And he wasn't kidding. So the
bird has to go in the will.
You see, it's the openness and the
recognition.
Perhaps somebody else would would not
have gotten that the bird was trying to
open a gate of communication by tapping.
See, maybe the bird even wasn't. Maybe
I'm the one that opened it as
communication.
But that's capital. That's the source of
capital to see the source of electricity
to have it come down the wire. All
right. So, this is the great there. I
call it genius
because the birth of the intellect in
itself is genius. You see Freud at 499.
You see Galileo.
Uh these are the great geniuses of
history. and the great inventors Emanuel
Kant. Um the categories of thought and
the difficulty with um problematic
relative uh the problem with the
difficulty hermeneutics of relativistic
epistemology is that it violates
the problematic hermeneutics of
relativistic epistemology.
is due to violating the categories of
Emanuel Kant. Seeing Emanuel Kant as
authoritarian instead of an authority.
Uh because without structure and logic,
you can't think logically. And if you
can't think logically, you end up
writing books on postmodernism and Zen
and postmodernism.
I defy anybody to comprehend it. I
bought it.
I calibrated as 160. I said, "Okay, what
is one what does 160 look at?" Like,
so I strove to understand what 160 looks
like and how it thinks. I cannot
comprehend how it thinks. It starts out
writing a pref a forward saying that u
there is no reason to write a forward
because this is not really a forward nor
is it actually forward of anything and
playing gobbledegook. So there we were
with Alice, Carol, and Louiswis Carol
and Alice's Wonderland,
the Madhatter's Tea Party. So at 10:30,
we'll stop. You say, "It's time for the
Mad Hatters Tea Party." She said, "It's
time for the Mad Hatter's tea party."
Nobody has to make sense at all during
the break.
Come back in here. You this minute.
>> If they're late, we want to kill them,
don't we? Yes.
>> We want to get them.
>> Well, here we have the ego for you.
Okay, we can uh
>> So you can see your ego is just a little
animal inside of you. And the best thing
to do instead of vilifying him is adopt
him as a pet and encourage him to be
nastier, more hateful, etc.
And uh that way you own them. So
if you own if you own the ego, if you
own the unconscious,
uh you don't have to project it onto the
world.
uh you recognize that it's uh the
inheritance inheritance and you don't
have to go into uh
uh
intellectual tricks to try to disown it.
Inside of you uh born into you is all
the animal kingdom that we just saw.
Uh, it hates anybody that cuts in front
of them in traffic.
It wants to kill people.
Anybody who cuts in front of you in
traffic deserves to die, don't they?
Kill them.
Road rage.
So,
here's the source of road rage right
there.
All right. So
can you defeat the ego? You can't
really. No, you can transcend the ego.
People do temporarily go into very high
spaces and but then they collap. They go
back out of it. And I get a lot of
letters. I went into this so and so high
space and then it came and then it left
and bewail their fate. How can that be?
It's because you've transcended your
karma for the time being. But now your
karma's caught up with you again.
There's other things you have to let go
of.
When we talk about devotional
non-duality, which is going to be the
next book after this one is uh
uh transcending the ego and of course
our lectures have been devoted to
preparing the way preparing the way.
Anybody who stands understands the
lectures and the videos and all uh gets
pretty much what it's all about. And
then we'll focus more on uh how to
transcend it. We did this morning by
transcending identification
by being that which you envision, being
that which you admire. Being that you
don't have to work for it or go to
artificial means you just become that.
Become that.
I got I got a letter from some guy who
took issue with how I talked about
transcending the ego supposedly Zen or
something and um
how to trans know no how to transcend
the mind and the stages you're supposed
to go through. You know the old Buddhist
literature has uh they were obsessed
with numbers. You know the eight ways of
this and the 33 stages of our hot chip.
What stage are you? I'm in stage 27.
It creates a whole structure and then
you've got to struggle through the
structure.
So each one has within it spiritual
truth and then it becomes encrusted with
accretions that are distractions from
the truth. There's no 33 steps to
anything. Uh because the instant the
bird goes you can go
didn't take 33 steps you know what I
mean
you the being the bird presents
beingness and you respond from your
beingness and it doesn't require
intellectually you don't have to go
through the intellect so I thought to
know what you don't need to know about
we should study
Yeah.
Because why? Because before you can
transcend a thing, you first have to
master it.
Before you can transcend the logic, the
ego, the whole
Newtonian paradigm of reality of cause
and effect. Yeah.
the world of cause and effect. This is
the birth of the world of cause and
effect of logic and reason
and
it is uplifting. The world of science is
the world of great benefit to mankind.
Doubled mankind's
lifespan. Cured most of the diseases
prevalent.
Um, however, you still have to get out
of get get off of this world somehow.
And I'm worried that science is going to
block all the exits.
How are we going to get out of here,
folks? That's what worries me.
Somebody wrote a book you can live
forever. Boy, what?
He wants to live forever. I mean, God.
Yeah.
How to make the body eternal. Oh, golly.
Well, the Egyptians tried it. You just
cover it up with gold and course you
can't breathe inside of all that gold.
But all right, so here's the world that
we're going to transcend on the way. Uh
first you master it. You have to have
respect for logic, reason, lo morality.
It's the whole basis of morality. Uh so
even the secular person of course claims
his secular rights uh but his rights are
based on
um religion.
So the rights of the constitution of
United States you know constitution
United States calibrates is 710. It's
based on
the the realization that the source of
existence is divinity and by virtue of
the source of our existence or all men
are equal. They are equal by virtue of
the divinity of their source of their
creation.
That's not up to anybody's vote.
So the equality then the constitution at
710 is stunningly high. It shows an
amazing area. It knows the difference
between spirituality and religion.
Doesn't confuse the two. By recognizing
the reality of spirituality, it ensures
our freedom from religion and freedom
for religion. Freedom from and freedom
for. And it means that your rights are
not up to the vote of the populace or
some dictator because the the source is
the truth of divinity itself, which is
the source of one's own creation.
Extremely sophisticated,
extremely ariodite.
710. Nothing on this planet has ever
approached 710 as a constitution and
there's nothing out there that
calibrates anywhere in even in that
realm. So how did that all come about?
It came about then. And don't forget
many of the writers of the constitution
etc. the revolutionaries were
freethinkers. They were not theists. You
know we were founded out of the freedom
of the oppression of religion. the
Puritans came here. Uh so the structure
of our society then is already set up
and reinforced by man's logic. Rouso all
the people that have contributed to it
over the centuries. Uh and here here are
the best thinkings and Hegel at 425 is
very interesting. uh one of Hegel's
principles. He was the leading
philosopher of Germany of the or early
1800s. He was the father of philosophy.
Uh Hegel was very respected. And one of
Hegel's principles was the principle of
the absolute.
The absolute.
The absolute which scares people.
So when we calibrate levels of
consciousness we are doing what we're
getting is the calibration of truth as
compared to the absolute
as compared to the absolute just as all
temperatures then on a thermometer are
as compared to absolute zero as compared
to absolute zero this temperature is at
so and so.
All right. So, Hegel uh then stated a
premise which we verify every day with
kinesiology. We did it on stage this
morning that there is an absolute
compared to an absolute. This calibrates
at such and such a number. Compared to
the absolute which represents truth.
This is either truth or not truth. And
consciousness recognizes truth because
truth has existence.
Everybody who walks the planet radiates
out an invisible energy,
visible energy
into the infinite field of consciousness
which is imprinted forever. It is a
literal fact. Every hair on your head is
counted. It's being counted right now,
folks.
I thought I was after I did. No, it's
counted right now
because that which you are is already
as you see positioned by the power of
the field as your configuration as you
karmmically come into this world. Your
propensities, your likes, your dislikes,
your debts etc are automatically every
hair on your head is already counting
itself automatically
not as an external
moralistic judge uh but as a consequence
of the reality of that which you are. So
Hegel's principle is extraordinarily
important
important because we'll see what happens
when you negate uh the principle of the
ab absolute as we get farther down the
list. Uh so here you have can't the
categories of logic. You see logic and
reason have a certain dialectic. You
can't just say anything you want to say.
There are certain rules of logic and
ethics and etc. And can't set up the
categories. And to violate these
categories means that you're mixing
levels. When you mix levels, you're
ignoring context and therefore much of
relativistic
epistemology.
Therefore, much of the problematic
pedentry of relativistic epistemology is
based on the extreme violation of all
these rules and regulations. So that
which calibrates at 160 is not higher
than truth than can at 460.
uh 160 is not higher than 460. So if you
want to know whether relativist
relativistic epistemology is a
philosophy of relativism,
what does relativism say? It says there
are no absolutes. So anything is
anything we want to say it is. H
pedestri is good and legal.
Men should pursue young boys and
we have organizations that support them
legally.
Yeah. Anything can mean anything you
want it to mean because everything is
just a semantic convenience and thereby
the society collapsed into chaos.
Society collapses because without
structure uh nothing has any meaning. If
anything can mean anything I want it to
mean. Uh then I'll take my clothes off
now and murder somebody and that's all
freedom of expression.
Who's to say it's wrong? If there is no
absolute then there's no structure to
society and of course we wouldn't be
able to do kinesiology at all. So
can't categories then are are important
and by following all of this the great
scientist the great scientists arose by
following logic and mathematics which is
a refinement of logic.
uh and so all collectively they
calibrate around 4
uh50 or something and if you then we
come to marks and if you remove marks
from the list of the entire list that
the whole list goes from 450 to 460 wow
uh then of course angles is at 200 so he
doesn't help a lot
he's not dragging his feet but he's
going to seek him saw so I never
calibrated did it without marks and
angles. But you see, they're the lowest
of all. Uh, and what is the difficulty
with marks? Well, marks
uh had an unresolved edible complex.
We'll verify what I'm saying. 50 years I
was a psychoanalyst. I mean, I can read
it from
I can take it a glance and tell you what
that person's conflicts is and what his
early life was. So, anyway, Markx
obviously had an unresolved edible
complex. He had allowed this you know
violent hostility towards authority. So
he rebelled against Hegel and he wrote
really what is a complete violation and
desecration of truth.
If you want to see a violation and
desecration of truth that beats
relativism
marks. So if you haven't read Markx you
really should because if you want to
know what horrible error is, you got to
get familiar with it. And what was the
error and why does it have such a
devastating downside? I mean the writing
of marks you see the pen is mightier
than the sword. So
to know what is truth then uh makes the
difference between survival and death.
So it's not exactly just an intellectual
nicity.
The diff to know the difference between
truth and falsehood is the difference
between life and death.
The writings of this man
cost the lives of 100 million people
across the world. Huh? 100 million in my
lifetime. Stalin put to death 30
million. So the the price of not of not
being able to discern truth from
falsehood is death and war, devastation,
nuclear bombs,
uh, and devastation. So is the fact that
he's at 130. What does that mean? Well,
what was the problem with the man? He
couldn't handle he misidentified
authority as authoritarianism
which is a common mistake in today's
society of rebellion is really sort of
an adolescent immaturity. Huh?
So Markx misinterpreted and what he did
was
uh create a duality. See the way to
truth is through non-duality. So the
maximum duality would then to be create
to create everything in terms of
perpetrator and victim. The fallout of
this in our society is what is tearing
the apart the fabric of our society. The
the dualistic projection onto everything
in the world of perpetrator victim.
Perpetrator victim.
If I take the perpetrator victim
paradigm I can apply it to anything.
anything, anytime, anywhere. And I can
do it retroactively in history. And I
can spend a whole lifetime doing make
wrongs in history.
You can do it with everything in
society. Everything in society. So you
end up with a contentious society. You
end up with sedition.
uh disguise, you know, sedition
disguised as patriotism or homicide
disguised as religiosity.
Anything could be whatever you say it it
is. Uh
so the perpetrator victim then appeals
to being the martyr, appeals to being
the victim, it appeals to blame. Then it
causes repression of that which is
within yourself. So from a
psychoanalytic viewpoint, it is very
sick.
You can't transcend something that you
haven't owned. And so if you repress it,
then you project it into the world and
you see it out there. That's why a
paranoid never gets better.
And why all the narcissistic
messianic megalomaniacs who calibrate at
35 such as Stalin and Hitler and all uh
were so vicious. They killed
Hitler's best generals. that buddy did
was he exterminated them all as Stalin
did the same thing.
Stalin did the same thing
of the 135 people that were there when
Stalin was elected
commasur whatever the hell it was out of
the 135
something like 98 were executed.
So in return for loyalty he executed
you. Huh. All right. So, uh, the appeal
of that kind of thinking then is not too
attractive.
130 just doesn't appeal to me. But you
see, if you pick, you can picture
yourself the payoff, the juice that you
get out of martyrdom, that you're being
wronged, that you're being perpetrated
against. So, the perpetrator victim
mode of thinking becomes a meme. Meme
me. Anybody not familiar with meme?
Meme.
Meme is like a virus, a thought that is
contagious and it becomes a saying. It
becomes a saying. And so everybody's
talking about rights and being a victim
and all this and dividing all of society
then into perpetrator victim. Of course,
Marx did it with capitalism etc.
Um and of course we we was tried out and
Russia tried it out for a long time and
you see what happened with it. Uh and so
it's been a disaster. So calibrating the
levels of consciousness then is very
very informative. Uh did Karl Marx have
an unresolved edible complex?
We have permission to ask this resist.
He did indeed resist.
Thank you. After 50 years of
psychoanalysis, I couldn't I mean I mean
you could tell what's wrong with him.
Here's the adolescent rebellion. Of
course, the adolescent rebellion
appealed to a lot of adolescence. So, he
attracted a lot of adolescence and we
see violence and bloodshed and
guillotine coming out of all this kind
of thinkingness. And as I say, this guy
here at 200 didn't help much angles. He
just sort of the fall guy went along
with it.
All right. So then area edition means
the 400s. Why are they important?
Because they are science, logic and
reason. Um it's the shoot off from which
the Newtonian paradigm of reality is a
very great advance. many parts of the
world, I'm sure the parts of the world
that lives on less than $2 a day, uh,
logic and reason and the kenchin
categories of abstraction are not
dominant in their society.
And because I've employed people like
that and uh, they didn't show up for
work yesterday. And you say, why didn't
where were you yesterday? I don't know.
I didn't feel like going to work.
Coming from a Protestant background, you
didn't feel like going to work. No,
that's how you live on two less than $2
a day. You don't feel like going to
work. So, all right.
So, these are the great thinkers of all
time, logic and reason. Then so you
transcend a certain paradigm after
you've mastered it, after you've learned
to be orderly and on time and reliable
and etc. Uh then you can become sloppy
again because you've transcended it, not
because you haven't gotten there yet.
All right? So you see Sir Isaac Newton
uh uh the differential calculus. So the
real master of mathematics in the modern
world was Sir Isaac Newton and his uh
development of the differential calculus
uh out of which all advanced mathematics
and sciences evolved. So we owe these
men all the conveniences that we have
today. The healing from illness half of
us in this audience are probably dead
already if there were that many even
left to die because childhood diseases
killed us off. And when I was still when
I was in practice,
uh, out of medical school, uh, my first
job was the hospital for infectious
diseases, u, typhoid and malaria and
dtheria,
uh, measles and smallpox,
and the dread disease where they bring
the kid in and one arm is down. What's
the name of that one?
>> Polio.
>> Polio, right? So they bring the kid in
like this in the middle of the night. So
here I'm an intern and the doctor who's
in charge has an alcohol problem. He's
gone
and it's me all alone with the family,
the diagnosis. So I got to, you know, do
a spinal tap on the kid, handle the
family, uh spin the spin it down, see
what the white souls are, and then tell
the family uh the news. And of course,
uh the look on my face, they got it. I
can remember many a time I'd walk into
the waiting room.
So we don't have to go through that
anymore. Uh thanks to these men.
So there's no point of putting them down
which relativism tends to do. just, you
know, um, look down on science and logic
and reason. And the downside of that
kind of thinking is that, uh, the school
room of 1900 calibrated at 400.
The school room of today calibrates at
190.
Therefore,
progressive education is regressive. No,
it's time to take responsibility, Billy.
It's time to stop writing graffiti and
stop giving him an A for graffiti in
class. They have classes in graffiti.
You know what I'm saying? The problem is
not to become better at graffiti. The
problem is to transcend graffiti. So
that kind of thinkingness uh has a
delletterious. So we have to respect
then the integrity of the 400s and the
intellect. At the same time as spiritual
students, we have to transcend it.
So first you master it then you
transcend it then you begin to see that
this is a way of thinking this is uh
deart's res internons
the way of the mind so
the basic problem with duality is the
resumption that the way my mind thinks
is the way it is out there if I see this
happen and this happen my mind says
causality now I think causality is a
principle of nature.
Causality is a principle of res
kajetons. It's a way of thinking to see
victim and perpetrator is all in your
head. There's no victims and no
perpetrators out there. The big tree
falls on the little tree because it got
blown over by the wind. It doesn't mean
the little tree is the victim and the
big tree is a perpetrator. You
understand?
So
to differentiate rest kajetans from rest
externa the way the world is the way
nature is is the big jump. That is the
big jump very seldom frankly is it made
that's why enlightenment is not coming.
It presumes that the mentation then is
reality. So our problem because a group
like this is very area day to begin with
because the intellect then
on the one hand is the barrier on the
other hand is the springboard because we
hear about spirituality we begin to
study it we read the ma the great
masters we begin to contemplate it and
now we want to get beyond how do you get
beyond thinkingness and how do we get
beyond thinkingness?
Hallelujah.
Hallelu.