in
in something
in something you
in something you know
in something you know with
in something you know with a
in something you know with a friend
in something you know with a friend of
mine
mine who
in something you know with a friend of
mine who spiritual
mine who spiritual life
in something you know with a friend of
mine who spiritual life and
mine who spiritual life and he
in something you know with a friend of
mine who spiritual life and he said
mine who spiritual life and he said we
have
have to
have to do
have to do so
have to do so and
have to do so and so
have to do so and so I
have to do so and so I said
have to do so and so I said don't
have to do so and so I said don't worry
about
about it
have to do so and so I said don't worry
about it just
about it just then
have to do so and so I said don't worry
about it just then I
about it just then I said
have to do so and so I said don't worry
about it just then I said that
about it just then I said that limo
have to do so and so I said don't worry
about it just then I said that limo came
over
over and
over and I
over and I open
over and I open the
over and I open the door
over and I open the door says
over and I open the door says you're
over and I open the door says you're all
right
that
that was
that was something
after
after the
that was something
after the event
after the event was
that was something
after the event was We
after the event was We go
that was something
after the event was We go back
after the event was We go back out
that was something
after the event was We go back out on
the
the street
the street and
the street and he
the street and he says,
the street and he says, "Well,
the street and he says, "Well, let's
the street and he says, "Well, let's see
you
you do
the street and he says, "Well, let's see
you do it
you do it again."
the street and he says, "Well, let's see
you do it again." So,
I
I said,
I said, "Well,
I said, "Well, who
I said, "Well, who knows?"
I said, "Well, who knows?" And
I said, "Well, who knows?" And sure
enough,
enough, another
I said, "Well, who knows?" And sure
enough, another woman
enough, another woman came
I said, "Well, who knows?" And sure
enough, another woman came up
enough, another woman came up this
I said, "Well, who knows?" And sure
enough, another woman came up this time
a
a brown
a brown one
a brown one and
a brown one and soon
a brown one and soon God
a brown one and soon God said,
a brown one and soon God said, "You
a brown one and soon God said, "You need
a
a ride."
a brown one and soon God said, "You need
a ride." Yep.
a ride." Yep. Whoa.
a brown one and soon God said, "You need
a ride." Yep. Whoa. So,
a ride." Yep. Whoa. So, that
a brown one and soon God said, "You need
a ride." Yep. Whoa. So, that was
a ride." Yep. Whoa. So, that was him
a brown one and soon God said, "You need
a ride." Yep. Whoa. So, that was him up
for
because
because what
for
because what you
because what you hold
for
because what you hold in
because what you hold in mind
for
because what you hold in mind manifests.
Well,
Well, when
Well, when that
Well, when that energy
Well, when that energy becomes
Well, when that energy becomes very
strong,
strong, it
Well, when that energy becomes very
strong, it strongly
strong, it strongly h
Well, when that energy becomes very
strong, it strongly h uh
strong, it strongly h uh what
Well, when that energy becomes very
strong, it strongly h uh what you
strong, it strongly h uh what you hold
in
in mind
in mind has
in mind has a
in mind has a very
in mind has a very strong
in mind has a very strong propensity
in mind has a very strong propensity to
manifest.
manifest. So,
in mind has a very strong propensity to
manifest. So, it
manifest. So, it brings
in mind has a very strong propensity to
manifest. So, it brings about
manifest. So, it brings about the
miraculous.
It
It gives
miraculous.
It gives you
It gives you all
miraculous.
It gives you all these
It gives you all these so-called
miraculous.
It gives you all these so-called cities.
Those
Those things
Those things are
Those things are not
Those things are not of
Those things are not of yourself.
Those things are not of yourself. They
are
are the
Those things are not of yourself. They
are the condolini
are the condolini energy
Those things are not of yourself. They
are the condolini energy independent
are the condolini energy independent of
any
any personal
any personal you
any personal you don't
any personal you don't make
any personal you don't make it
any personal you don't make it happen.
People
People become
any personal you don't make it happen.
People become healed
People become healed in
any personal you don't make it happen.
People become healed in the
People become healed in the presence
any personal you don't make it happen.
People become healed in the presence of
it.
it. You
it. You would
it. You would sit
it. You would sit down
it. You would sit down in
it. You would sit down in front
it. You would sit down in front of
it. You would sit down in front of the
clock
in
in um
at
at the
in um
at the hotel
at the hotel and
in um
at the hotel and you
at the hotel and you say
in um
at the hotel and you say FL.
at the hotel and you say FL. Yeah.
Anyway,
Anyway, you're
Anyway, you're sitting
Anyway, you're sitting there
Anyway, you're sitting there and
Anyway, you're sitting there and you're
supposed
supposed to
Anyway, you're sitting there and you're
supposed to meet
supposed to meet somebody
Anyway, you're sitting there and you're
supposed to meet somebody and
supposed to meet somebody and the
Anyway, you're sitting there and you're
supposed to meet somebody and the lady
sits
sits down
sits down next
sits down next to
sits down next to you
sits down next to you and
sits down next to you and she's
sits down next to you and she's all
crippled
crippled up
sits down next to you and she's all
crippled up and
crippled up and she's
sits down next to you and she's all
crippled up and she's also
crippled up and she's also delusional.
She's
She's obviously
She's obviously hallucinating
She's obviously hallucinating and
She's obviously hallucinating and she's
talking
talking to
She's obviously hallucinating and she's
talking to imaginary
talking to imaginary people
She's obviously hallucinating and she's
talking to imaginary people about
imaginary
imaginary things
imaginary things are
imaginary things are supposed
imaginary things are supposed to
imaginary things are supposed to happen
and
and she's
imaginary things are supposed to happen
and she's disappointed
and she's disappointed that
imaginary things are supposed to happen
and she's disappointed that her
boyfriend
boyfriend hasn't
boyfriend hasn't showed
boyfriend hasn't showed up.
boyfriend hasn't showed up. I
boyfriend hasn't showed up. I know
boyfriend hasn't showed up. I know it's
an
an imaginary
boyfriend hasn't showed up. I know it's
an imaginary boyfriend.
an imaginary boyfriend. She
boyfriend hasn't showed up. I know it's
an imaginary boyfriend. She hasn't
an imaginary boyfriend. She hasn't got
boyfriend hasn't showed up. I know it's
an imaginary boyfriend. She hasn't got a
boyfriend.
boyfriend. Anyway,
boyfriend. Anyway, she's
boyfriend. Anyway, she's psychotic,
delusional,
delusional, and
boyfriend. Anyway, she's psychotic,
delusional, and uh
delusional, and uh multiple
boyfriend. Anyway, she's psychotic,
delusional, and uh multiple impairments.
Anyway,
Anyway, this
Anyway, this energy
Anyway, this energy just
Anyway, this energy just goes
Anyway, this energy just goes over
Anyway, this energy just goes over to
her.
her. I'm
Anyway, this energy just goes over to
her. I'm not
her. I'm not paying
Anyway, this energy just goes over to
her. I'm not paying attention
her. I'm not paying attention to
Anyway, this energy just goes over to
her. I'm not paying attention to her
watching
watching the
watching the clock.
watching the clock. The
watching the clock. The energy
watching the clock. The energy is
watching the clock. The energy is doing
everything.
everything. All
watching the clock. The energy is doing
everything. All of
everything. All of a
watching the clock. The energy is doing
everything. All of a sudden,
everything. All of a sudden, she
watching the clock. The energy is doing
everything. All of a sudden, she gets
up,
up, walks
up, walks away,
up, walks away, feels
up, walks away, feels fine,
up, walks away, feels fine, psychos,
disappeared,
walks
walks away
walks away on
walks away on her
walks away on her own.
walks away on her own. So
walks away on her own. So the
walks away on her own. So the miraculous
then
and
and when
and when it
and when it happens
and when it happens subsequently
has
has nothing
and when it happens subsequently
has nothing to
has nothing to do
and when it happens subsequently
has nothing to do with
has nothing to do with yourself.
and when it happens subsequently
has nothing to do with yourself. You
has nothing to do with yourself. You can
see
see why
see why the
see why the person's
see why the person's in
see why the person's in front
see why the person's in front of
see why the person's in front of you.
They're
They're hoping
see why the person's in front of you.
They're hoping for
They're hoping for that.
But
But it's
But it's like
in
in that
But it's like
in that presence
in that presence the
But it's like
in that presence the apple
in that presence the apple that's
But it's like
in that presence the apple that's that's
right
right falls
right falls from
right falls from the
right falls from the tree.
right falls from the tree. It's
right falls from the tree. It's up
right falls from the tree. It's up to
the
the karmic
right falls from the tree. It's up to
the karmic rightness
the karmic rightness of
right falls from the tree. It's up to
the karmic rightness of the
the karmic rightness of the situation.
It's
It's not
It's not like
It's not like a
It's not like a you
It's not like a you doing
It's not like a you doing it
It's not like a you doing it that
because
because elephant
It's not like a you doing it that
because elephant each
because elephant each thing
It's not like a you doing it that
because elephant each thing that's
happening
happening of
happening of it
happening of it own
happening of it own when
happening of it own when the
happening of it own when the apple
happening of it own when the apple gets
sufficiently
sufficiently right
happening of it own when the apple gets
sufficiently right it
sufficiently right it falls
happening of it own when the apple gets
sufficiently right it falls of
sufficiently right it falls of its
happening of it own when the apple gets
sufficiently right it falls of its own.
See
See all
See all right
See all right so
See all right so these
See all right so these are
See all right so these are things
characteristic
characteristic of
See all right so these are things
characteristic of these
characteristic of these levels.
uh
uh as
uh as you
uh as you get
uh as you get higher
uh as you get higher which
uh as you get higher which is
uh as you get higher which is extremely
rare.
rare. Point
uh as you get higher which is extremely
rare. Point over
rare. Point over 700
uh as you get higher which is extremely
rare. Point over 700 is
rare. Point over 700 is extremely
uh as you get higher which is extremely
rare. Point over 700 is extremely rare.
Correct.
The
The subjective
Correct.
The subjective experience
The subjective experience because
Correct.
The subjective experience because it
becomes
becomes increasingly
becomes increasingly painful.
becomes increasingly painful. Uh
becomes increasingly painful. Uh nervous
system
system is
becomes increasingly painful. Uh nervous
system is overt
system is overt taxed.
becomes increasingly painful. Uh nervous
system is overt taxed. You
system is overt taxed. You get
becomes increasingly painful. Uh nervous
system is overt taxed. You get aches
system is overt taxed. You get aches and
pains
pains and
pains and horrific
pains and horrific uh
pains and horrific uh a
pains and horrific uh a negative
pains and horrific uh a negative thought
is
is so
pains and horrific uh a negative thought
is so painful
is so painful that
pains and horrific uh a negative thought
is so painful that that
is so painful that that excruciating
to
to have
to have a
to have a negative
to have a negative thought
to have a negative thought with
to have a negative thought with that
kind
kind of
to have a negative thought with that
kind of energy
kind of energy flowing
to have a negative thought with that
kind of energy flowing like
kind of energy flowing like you're
to have a negative thought with that
kind of energy flowing like you're like
fried
fried still
fried still alive
fried still alive being
fried still alive being fried.
fried still alive being fried. So
fried still alive being fried. So the
nervous
nervous system
fried still alive being fried. So the
nervous system is
nervous system is not
fried still alive being fried. So the
nervous system is not really
nervous system is not really able
fried still alive being fried. So the
nervous system is not really able to
handle
handle uh
handle uh things
handle uh things from
handle uh things from here
handle uh things from here up
handle uh things from here up up
handle uh things from here up up to
handle uh things from here up up to this
far.
far. It's
handle uh things from here up up to this
far. It's fine
far. It's fine from
handle uh things from here up up to this
far. It's fine from here
far. It's fine from here up.
We
We were
We were in
We were in Korea
We were in Korea one
We were in Korea one time.
We were in Korea one time. I
We were in Korea one time. I said,
We were in Korea one time. I said, "God,
I
I I
We were in Korea one time. I said, "God,
I I think
I I think I
We were in Korea one time. I said, "God,
I I think I can
I I think I can stand
We were in Korea one time. I said, "God,
I I think I can stand this
I I think I can stand this Jesus
Christ."
And
And just,
Christ."
And just, you
And just, you know,
Christ."
And just, you know, out
And just, you know, out of
Christ."
And just, you know, out of the
And just, you know, out of the side
Christ."
And just, you know, out of the side of
the
the bed,
the bed, as
the bed, as soon
the bed, as soon as
the bed, as soon as he
the bed, as soon as he pulls
the bed, as soon as he pulls it
the bed, as soon as he pulls it out,
opens
opens the
the bed, as soon as he pulls it out,
opens the page
opens the page and
the bed, as soon as he pulls it out,
opens the page and says,
opens the page and says, "And
the bed, as soon as he pulls it out,
opens the page and says, "And the
opens the page and says, "And the Buddha
felt
felt like
felt like his
felt like his bones
felt like his bones were
felt like his bones were being
felt like his bones were being broken.
He
He was
felt like his bones were being broken.
He was racked
He was racked with
felt like his bones were being broken.
He was racked with pain
He was racked with pain and
felt like his bones were being broken.
He was racked with pain and he
He was racked with pain and he was
attacked
attacked by
attacked by demons."
attacked by demons." I
attacked by demons." I said,
attacked by demons." I said, "Oh,
attacked by demons." I said, "Oh, and
it's
it's okay."
>> I
>> I my
>> I my guess
>> I my guess would
>> I my guess would be
>> I my guess would be when
>> I my guess would be when you
>> I my guess would be when you get
>> I my guess would be when you get to
>> I my guess would be when you get to 700,
it's
it's better
>> I my guess would be when you get to 700,
it's better to
it's better to go
>> I my guess would be when you get to 700,
it's better to go to
it's better to go to other
>> I my guess would be when you get to 700,
it's better to go to other realms
it's better to go to other realms if
you're
you're going
you're going to
you're going to continue
you're going to continue on.
Now,
Now, the
you're going to continue on.
Now, the human
Now, the human nervous
you're going to continue on.
Now, the human nervous system
Now, the human nervous system is
you're going to continue on.
Now, the human nervous system is not
really
really and
really and on
really and on its
really and on its way
really and on its way up
really and on its way up the
really and on its way up the the
condalini
condalini energy
really and on its way up the the
condalini energy brings
condalini energy brings about
really and on its way up the the
condalini energy brings about changes
condalini energy brings about changes in
the
the actual
the actual physical
the actual physical nervous
the actual physical nervous system.
the actual physical nervous system. Uh
it
it actually
the actual physical nervous system. Uh
it actually gets
it actually gets heavier
the actual physical nervous system. Uh
it actually gets heavier and
um
um it
um it actually
um it actually gets
um it actually gets modified.
The
The nervous
um it actually gets modified.
The nervous system
The nervous system itself
um it actually gets modified.
The nervous system itself actually
The nervous system itself actually goes
through
through modification.
through modification. This
through modification. This nervous
system
system is
through modification. This nervous
system is considerably
system is considerably different.
through modification. This nervous
system is considerably different. It
system is considerably different. It was
many
many years
many years ago.
many years ago. Yes.
many years ago. Yes. Considerably
different.
different. Okay.
many years ago. Yes. Considerably
different. Okay. Also
different. Okay. Also people
many years ago. Yes. Considerably
different. Okay. Also people say
different. Okay. Also people say why
many years ago. Yes. Considerably
different. Okay. Also people say why uh
in
in United
in United States
in United States a
in United States a very
in United States a very advanced
in United States a very advanced stage.
We're
We're not
in United States a very advanced stage.
We're not talking
We're not talking about
in United States a very advanced stage.
We're not talking about saints
We're not talking about saints because
there's
there's many
there's many Christian
there's many Christian saints
there's many Christian saints that
there's many Christian saints that are
women.
women. Why
there's many Christian saints that are
women. Why are
women. Why are those
there's many Christian saints that are
women. Why are those at
women. Why are those at the
there's many Christian saints that are
women. Why are those at the top
women. Why are those at the top always
men?
men? It's
men? It's not
men? It's not a
men? It's not a sexist
men? It's not a sexist problem.
men? It's not a sexist problem. You
men? It's not a sexist problem. You see
people
people project
men? It's not a sexist problem. You see
people project sexism
people project sexism on
men? It's not a sexist problem. You see
people project sexism on everything.
people project sexism on everything. if
has
has to
has to do
has to do with
has to do with the
has to do with the with
has to do with the with the
has to do with the with the strength
has to do with the with the strength of
the
the nervous
has to do with the with the strength of
the nervous system.
the nervous system. You
has to do with the with the strength of
the nervous system. You just
the nervous system. You just have
has to do with the with the strength of
the nervous system. You just have to
have
have a
have a more
have a more of
have a more of a
have a more of a misomorphic
have a more of a misomorphic body
have a more of a misomorphic body and
have a more of a misomorphic body and a
tougher
tougher nervous
have a more of a misomorphic body and a
tougher nervous system
tougher nervous system to
have a more of a misomorphic body and a
tougher nervous system to handle
tougher nervous system to handle the
voltage.
voltage. That's
voltage. That's all.
voltage. That's all. So,
voltage. That's all. So, if
voltage. That's all. So, if you're
destined
destined to
voltage. That's all. So, if you're
destined to become
destined to become an
voltage. That's all. So, if you're
destined to become an avatar
destined to become an avatar at
voltage. That's all. So, if you're
destined to become an avatar at a
thousand,
thousand, apparently
thousand, apparently you
thousand, apparently you leave
thousand, apparently you leave this
sandy
sandy woman's
thousand, apparently you leave this
sandy woman's life
sandy woman's life and
thousand, apparently you leave this
sandy woman's life and come
sandy woman's life and come back
thousand, apparently you leave this
sandy woman's life and come back as
sandy woman's life and come back as an
avatar.
It
It doesn't
avatar.
It doesn't have
It doesn't have to
avatar.
It doesn't have to do
It doesn't have to do with
avatar.
It doesn't have to do with sexism.
It doesn't have to do with sexism. It
has
has to
has to do
has to do with
has to do with the
has to do with the capacity
has to do with the capacity of
has to do with the capacity of the
nervous
nervous system.
has to do with the capacity of the
nervous system. That
nervous system. That was
has to do with the capacity of the
nervous system. That was the
nervous system. That was the answer
has to do with the capacity of the
nervous system. That was the answer we
got
got because
got because people
got because people have
got because people have asked
got because people have asked that
got because people have asked that out
of
of curiosity.
got because people have asked that out
of curiosity. I
of curiosity. I myself
got because people have asked that out
of curiosity. I myself was
of curiosity. I myself was curious.
got because people have asked that out
of curiosity. I myself was curious. But
at
at that
at that level,
at that level, one
at that level, one is
at that level, one is beyond
at that level, one is beyond gender.
at that level, one is beyond gender. So
the
the question
at that level, one is beyond gender. So
the question is
the question is not
at that level, one is beyond gender. So
the question is not really
the question is not really a
at that level, one is beyond gender. So
the question is not really a valid
the question is not really a valid one.
It
It just
It just has
It just has to
It just has to do
It just has to do with
It just has to do with the
It just has to do with the physicality
of
of a
It just has to do with the physicality
of a human
of a human the
It just has to do with the physicality
of a human the human
of a human the human uh
It just has to do with the physicality
of a human the human uh structure
of a human the human uh structure of
It just has to do with the physicality
of a human the human uh structure of the
human
human nervous
human nervous system
human nervous system and
human nervous system and its
human nervous system and its capacity.
So
So those
human nervous system and its capacity.
So those are
So those are the
human nervous system and its capacity.
So those are the higher
So those are the higher states
human nervous system and its capacity.
So those are the higher states and
conditions
conditions that
conditions that tend
conditions that tend to
conditions that tend to happen
conditions that tend to happen there.
Let's
Let's go
conditions that tend to happen there.
Let's go to
Let's go to the
conditions that tend to happen there.
Let's go to the next
Let's go to the next one.
The
The highest
The highest level
The highest level of
The highest level of consciousness
possible
possible in
The highest level of consciousness
possible in the
possible in the human
The highest level of consciousness
possible in the human domain
possible in the human domain is
recalibrated
recalibrated as
recalibrated as a
recalibrated as a thousand.
recalibrated as a thousand. The
recalibrated as a thousand. The nervous
system
system just
recalibrated as a thousand. The nervous
system just can't.
system just can't. It
recalibrated as a thousand. The nervous
system just can't. It handles
system just can't. It handles that
recalibrated as a thousand. The nervous
system just can't. It handles that with
great
great difficulty.
great difficulty. Of
great difficulty. Of course,
great difficulty. Of course, sweat
great difficulty. Of course, sweat with
blood.
blood. Build
great difficulty. Of course, sweat with
blood. Build this
blood. Build this rapid
great difficulty. Of course, sweat with
blood. Build this rapid thing.
blood. Build this rapid thing. Um,
great difficulty. Of course, sweat with
blood. Build this rapid thing. Um, when
you
you get
you get to
you get to the
you get to the higher
you get to the higher dimensions,
you get to the higher dimensions, the
archangel
archangel calibrates
you get to the higher dimensions, the
archangel calibrates 50,000
archangel calibrates 50,000 and
you get to the higher dimensions, the
archangel calibrates 50,000 and up.
You're
You're talking
You're talking about
You're talking about those
You're talking about those big
You're talking about those big cables
coming
coming out
You're talking about those big cables
coming out of
coming out of the
You're talking about those big cables
coming out of the generators.
A
A passing
A passing thought
A passing thought from
A passing thought from an
A passing thought from an archangel
A passing thought from an archangel will
blow
blow you
A passing thought from an archangel will
blow you right
blow you right out.
So
So I
So I was
So I was in
So I was in the
So I was in the depths
So I was in the depths of
So I was in the depths of hell.
A
A voice
So I was in the depths of hell.
A voice within
A voice within said,
So I was in the depths of hell.
A voice within said, "If
A voice within said, "If there
So I was in the depths of hell.
A voice within said, "If there is
A voice within said, "If there is a
So I was in the depths of hell.
A voice within said, "If there is a God,
I
I ask
I ask you
I ask you to
I ask you to help
I ask you to help me."
I ask you to help me." I
I ask you to help me." I was
I ask you to help me." I was got
I ask you to help me." I was got the
feeling
feeling there
I ask you to help me." I was got the
feeling there was
feeling there was a
I ask you to help me." I was got the
feeling there was a cruising
feeling there was a cruising archangel.
Archangel
Archangel just
Archangel just happened
Archangel just happened to
Archangel just happened to be
Archangel just happened to be cruising
guy
guy by
Archangel just happened to be cruising
guy by heard
guy by heard the
Archangel just happened to be cruising
guy by heard the thought
guy by heard the thought went
Archangel just happened to be cruising
guy by heard the thought went over
guy by heard the thought went over and
passed
passed on.
passed on. Wow.
Went
Went silent
passed on. Wow.
Went silent and
Went silent and has
passed on. Wow.
Went silent and has never
Went silent and has never spoken
passed on. Wow.
Went silent and has never spoken again.
Passing
Passing thought
Passing thought of
Passing thought of an
Passing thought of an archangel.
Silence
Silence is
Passing thought of an archangel.
Silence is gone
Silence is gone because
Passing thought of an archangel.
Silence is gone because after
Silence is gone because after the
transformation,
transformation, I
transformation, I never
transformation, I never spoke
transformation, I never spoke of
transformation, I never spoke of it
transformation, I never spoke of it for
35 years
until
until I
until I wrote
until I wrote the
until I wrote the book
until I wrote the book power
until I wrote the book power versus
force.
force. What
until I wrote the book power versus
force. What can
force. What can you
until I wrote the book power versus
force. What can you say
force. What can you say to
until I wrote the book power versus
force. What can you say to people?
Because
Because they
Because they would
Because they would not
Because they would not understand
anything
anything you're
Because they would not understand
anything you're saying.
If
If there's
If there's nobody
If there's nobody here
If there's nobody here speaking
If there's nobody here speaking to
If there's nobody here speaking to you
now
now is
If there's nobody here speaking to you
now is not
now is not comprehensible.
That's
That's the
That's the truth.
speaking
speaking this
That's the truth.
speaking this happens
speaking this happens of
That's the truth.
speaking this happens of its
speaking this happens of its own
That's the truth.
speaking this happens of its own as
speaking this happens of its own as the
potentiality
potentiality of
potentiality of becoming
potentiality of becoming an
potentiality of becoming an actuality
uh
uh in
potentiality of becoming an actuality
uh in in in
uh in in in a
potentiality of becoming an actuality
uh in in in a form
uh in in in a form which
potentiality of becoming an actuality
uh in in in a form which is
uh in in in a form which is of
potentiality of becoming an actuality
uh in in in a form which is of service.
In
In meditation
In meditation you
In meditation you go
In meditation you go through
In meditation you go through the
awareness.
awareness. First
In meditation you go through the
awareness. First you
awareness. First you meditate
In meditation you go through the
awareness. First you meditate on
awareness. First you meditate on form.
We
We were
We were talking
We were talking about
We were talking about ABCD
We were talking about ABCD and
We were talking about ABCD and all
We were talking about ABCD and all that.
Then
Then you
We were talking about ABCD and all that.
Then you begin
Then you begin to
We were talking about ABCD and all that.
Then you begin to realize
Then you begin to realize I'm
We were talking about ABCD and all that.
Then you begin to realize I'm not
Then you begin to realize I'm not the
content
content of
content of of
content of of that.
content of of that. I'm
content of of that. I'm that
content of of that. I'm that which
content of of that. I'm that which how
do
do I
content of of that. I'm that which how
do I know
do I know ABC
content of of that. I'm that which how
do I know ABC is
do I know ABC is happening?
content of of that. I'm that which how
do I know ABC is happening? because
do I know ABC is happening? because I'm
somehow
somehow registering
somehow registering it.
somehow registering it. I'm
somehow registering it. I'm recognizing
it.
it. And
somehow registering it. I'm recognizing
it. And therefore,
it. And therefore, I
somehow registering it. I'm recognizing
it. And therefore, I must
it. And therefore, I must be
somehow registering it. I'm recognizing
it. And therefore, I must be the
it. And therefore, I must be the watcher
and
and the
and the experiencer.
and the experiencer. How
and the experiencer. How do
and the experiencer. How do you
and the experiencer. How do you know
you're
you're thinking?
and the experiencer. How do you know
you're thinking? Because
you're thinking? Because you're
experiencing.
How
How do
experiencing.
How do you
How do you know
experiencing.
How do you know what
How do you know what you're
experiencing.
How do you know what you're thinking?
Because
Because you're
Because you're watching.
Because you're watching. Why
Because you're watching. Why are
Because you're watching. Why are you
watching
watching and
Because you're watching. Why are you
watching and experiencing
watching and experiencing in
Because you're watching. Why are you
watching and experiencing in the
watching and experiencing in the first
place?
What's
What's the
place?
What's the capacity
What's the capacity to
place?
What's the capacity to watch
What's the capacity to watch and
experience
experience content
experience content of
experience content of thinkingness
experience content of thinkingness or
meditation
meditation is
experience content of thinkingness or
meditation is because
meditation is because of
experience content of thinkingness or
meditation is because of an
meditation is because of an infinite
field
field called
field called awareness.
Awareness
Awareness exists
field called awareness.
Awareness exists in
Awareness exists in and
field called awareness.
Awareness exists in and of
Awareness exists in and of itself.
field called awareness.
Awareness exists in and of itself. It's
obviously
obviously not
obviously not a
obviously not a personality.
Observing
Observing and
obviously not a personality.
Observing and witnessing
Observing and witnessing is
obviously not a personality.
Observing and witnessing is a
manifestation
manifestation of
manifestation of the
manifestation of the light
manifestation of the light of
consciousness
consciousness itself.
You
You begin
You begin to
You begin to identify
with
with consciousness
You begin to identify
with consciousness itself.
Not
Not the
Not the what,
not
not the
Not the what,
not the content,
but
but consciousness
but consciousness itself.
Beyond
Beyond that,
but consciousness itself.
Beyond that, with
Beyond that, with a
but consciousness itself.
Beyond that, with a very
Beyond that, with a very advanced
but consciousness itself.
Beyond that, with a very advanced state
of
of awareness,
of awareness, one
of awareness, one realizes
of awareness, one realizes that
of awareness, one realizes that is
of awareness, one realizes that is the
manifest
arising
arising out
arising out of
arising out of the
arising out of the unmanifest.
And
And then
arising out of the unmanifest.
And then one
And then one begins
arising out of the unmanifest.
And then one begins to
And then one begins to realize
all
all comes
all comes into
all comes into existence
all comes into existence spontaneously.
The
The unmanifest
all comes into existence spontaneously.
The unmanifest becomes
The unmanifest becomes manifest
all comes into existence spontaneously.
The unmanifest becomes manifest as
The unmanifest becomes manifest as the
infinite
infinite potentiality
which
which becomes
infinite potentiality
which becomes actuality
when
when conditions
when conditions permit
when conditions permit it.
In
In reality
when conditions permit it.
In reality becomes
In reality becomes the
when conditions permit it.
In reality becomes the actuality
because
because of
because of the
because of the power
because of the power of
because of the power of the
because of the power of the unmanifest
to
to become
because of the power of the unmanifest
to become manifest.
Therefore
Therefore bow
Therefore bow David
Therefore bow David B
Therefore bow David B wrote
Therefore bow David B wrote a
Therefore bow David B wrote a book
Therefore bow David B wrote a book about
it
it the
Therefore bow David B wrote a book about
it the unfolded
it the unfolded and
Therefore bow David B wrote a book about
it the unfolded and unfold
it the unfolded and unfold the
Therefore bow David B wrote a book about
it the unfolded and unfold the universe.
B
B calibrates
B calibrates over
B calibrates over 500.
B calibrates over 500. Most
B calibrates over 500. Most of
B calibrates over 500. Most of the
physicists
physicists calibrated
B calibrates over 500. Most of the
physicists calibrated in
physicists calibrated in the
B calibrates over 500. Most of the
physicists calibrated in the 400s.
Einstein
Einstein at
Einstein at 499.
Only
Only the
Einstein at 499.
Only the great
Only the great physicists
Einstein at 499.
Only the great physicists will
Only the great physicists will get
Einstein at 499.
Only the great physicists will get to
them.
them. Uclid
them. Uclid of
them. Uclid of all
them. Uclid of all the
them. Uclid of all the greatest
them. Uclid of all the greatest minds,
scientific
scientific minds
them. Uclid of all the greatest minds,
scientific minds ever
scientific minds ever existed.
Uh
Uh and
Uh and at
Uh and at 499,
Uh and at 499, Einstein
Uh and at 499, Einstein 499.
Boom.
Boom. We
Uh and at 499, Einstein 499.
Boom. We saw
Boom. We saw unmanifest
Uh and at 499, Einstein 499.
Boom. We saw unmanifest and
Boom. We saw unmanifest and the
Uh and at 499, Einstein 499.
Boom. We saw unmanifest and the manifest
unfolded
unfolded and
unfolded and the
unfolded and the unfolded
unfolded and the unfolded operates
unfolded and the unfolded operates at
505.
505. So
unfolded and the unfolded operates at
505. So 500
505. So 500 is
unfolded and the unfolded operates at
505. So 500 is quite
505. So 500 is quite a
unfolded and the unfolded operates at
505. So 500 is quite a different
paradigm
paradigm jump.
Science
Science can't
paradigm jump.
Science can't take
Science can't take us
paradigm jump.
Science can't take us there
Science can't take us there because
paradigm jump.
Science can't take us there because the
inlect
inlect column
inlect column stops
inlect column stops in
inlect column stops in the
inlect column stops in the 400s.
inlect column stops in the 400s. Quantum
mechanics,
all
all the
all the most
all the most advanced
all the most advanced theoretical
all the most advanced theoretical math
on
on the
all the most advanced theoretical math
on the face
on the face of
all the most advanced theoretical math
on the face of the
on the face of the earth
all the most advanced theoretical math
on the face of the earth only
on the face of the earth only gets
all the most advanced theoretical math
on the face of the earth only gets you
to
to the
to the 400s.
Einstein,
Einstein, you
to the 400s.
Einstein, you know,
Einstein, you know, we'll
to the 400s.
Einstein, you know, we'll get
Einstein, you know, we'll get to
to the 400s.
Einstein, you know, we'll get to the
Heisenberg
Heisenberg principle
Heisenberg principle later.
But
But when
Heisenberg principle later.
But when presented
But when presented with
Heisenberg principle later.
But when presented with the
But when presented with the Heisenberg
principle
principle that
principle that you
principle that you cannot
principle that you cannot do
principle that you cannot do the
principle that you cannot do the same
experiment
experiment twice
principle that you cannot do the same
experiment twice because
experiment twice because merely
observing
observing it,
observing it, witnessing
observing it, witnessing it,
participating
participating in
observing it, witnessing it,
participating in it
participating in it already
observing it, witnessing it,
participating in it already changes
participating in it already changes its
re
re its
re its reality.
re its reality. It
re its reality. It collapses
re its reality. It collapses the
re its reality. It collapses the wave
function
creates
creates a
creates a new
creates a new universe
starts
starts as
creates a new universe
starts as the
starts as the shredder
creates a new universe
starts as the shredder equations
starts as the shredder equations ends
creates a new universe
starts as the shredder equations ends up
as
as the
as the direct
as the direct equations.
as the direct equations. In
as the direct equations. In the
as the direct equations. In the middle
is
is the
as the direct equations. In the middle
is the Heisenberg
is the Heisenberg principle,
as the direct equations. In the middle
is the Heisenberg principle, the
is the Heisenberg principle, the merely
witnessing.
witnessing. And
witnessing. And therefore
witnessing. And therefore we
witnessing. And therefore we get
witnessing. And therefore we get to
witnessing. And therefore we get to the
power
power of
witnessing. And therefore we get to the
power of intention.
power of intention. Power
witnessing. And therefore we get to the
power of intention. Power of
power of intention. Power of intention.
And
And of
And of course
And of course Wayne
And of course Wayne Dyer's
And of course Wayne Dyer's latest
And of course Wayne Dyer's latest book
power
power of
And of course Wayne Dyer's latest book
power of intention.
I
I read
I read the
I read the last
I read the last chapter.
I read the last chapter. You
I read the last chapter. You can
I read the last chapter. You can get
I read the last chapter. You can get it
free
free off
I read the last chapter. You can get it
free off the
free off the internet.
So
So anyway,
power
power of
So anyway,
power of intention.
power of intention. Yes.
So anyway,
power of intention. Yes. Intentionality
then
then is
then is what
then is what determines
then is what determines things.
then is what determines things. We
then is what determines things. We can
calibrate
calibrate various
then is what determines things. We can
calibrate various movies.
calibrate various movies. We
then is what determines things. We can
calibrate various movies. We have a
calibrate various movies. We have a book
coming
coming out.
coming out. You
coming out. You know,
coming out. You know, we
coming out. You know, we did
coming out. You know, we did 7,000
calibrations
calibrations for
coming out. You know, we did 7,000
calibrations for this
calibrations for this book
coming out. You know, we did 7,000
calibrations for this book that's
calibrations for this book that's going
to
to be
to be out
to be out this
to be out this year
to be out this year if
to be out this year if you
to be out this year if you are
to be out this year if you are willing.
And
And very
to be out this year if you are willing.
And very often
you
you have
you have to
you have to be
you have to be back.
So
So anyhow,
she's
she's she
she's she walks
she's she walks around
she's she walks around like
she's she walks around like this
she's she walks around like this trying
to
to give
she's she walks around like this trying
to give me
to give me the
she's she walks around like this trying
to give me the idea.
Just
Just one
Just one more
Just one more calibration.
Just one more calibration. We
Just one more calibration. We forgot
Buckminister
Buckminister Fuller.
She
She goes
She goes like
She goes like this.
She goes like this. Makes
She goes like this. Makes me
She goes like this. Makes me feel
She goes like this. Makes me feel fills
me
me with
She goes like this. Makes me feel fills
me with guilt.
I
I just
I just wanted
I just wanted to
I just wanted to know
I just wanted to know Buckminister
Fuller.
Fuller. That's
I just wanted to know Buckminister
Fuller. That's all.
Fuller. That's all. No,
I just wanted to know Buckminister
Fuller. That's all. No, no,
Fuller. That's all. No, no, forget
I just wanted to know Buckminister
Fuller. That's all. No, no, forget it.
I
I see.
I see. Look,
I see. Look, I
I see. Look, I don't
I see. Look, I don't need
I see. Look, I don't need Buckminister
Fuller.
Fuller. All
I see. Look, I don't need Buckminister
Fuller. All those
Fuller. All those people
I see. Look, I don't need Buckminister
Fuller. All those people out
Fuller. All those people out there
I see. Look, I don't need Buckminister
Fuller. All those people out there can
live
live with
live with it.
live with it. They
live with it. They don't
live with it. They don't need
live with it. They don't need to
live with it. They don't need to know
what
what Bucky.
Okay,
Okay, she
Okay, she say.
Okay, she say. All right.
Okay, she say. All right. 4:45.
Okay, she say. All right. 4:45. Okay,
the
the bunny's
Okay, she say. All right. 4:45. Okay,
the bunny's in
the bunny's in the
Okay, she say. All right. 4:45. Okay,
the bunny's in the book.
the bunny's in the book. Oh,
Okay, she say. All right. 4:45. Okay,
the bunny's in the book. Oh, I
the bunny's in the book. Oh, I just
slipped
slipped in
slipped in at
slipped in at the
slipped in at the last
slipped in at the last minute.
Can't
Can't leave
slipped in at the last minute.
Can't leave Bucky
Can't leave Bucky out
slipped in at the last minute.
Can't leave Bucky out in
Can't leave Bucky out in the
slipped in at the last minute.
Can't leave Bucky out in the cold.
Okay,
Okay, so
Okay, so this
Okay, so this is
Okay, so this is um
Okay, so this is um Okay,
Okay, so this is um Okay, we'll
Okay, so this is um Okay, we'll go
Okay, so this is um Okay, we'll go to
the
the next
Okay, so this is um Okay, we'll go to
the next slide.
Um
Um the
Um the calibrated
Um the calibrated levels
Um the calibrated levels of
consciousness
consciousness is
Um the calibrated levels of
consciousness is not
consciousness is not going
Um the calibrated levels of
consciousness is not going to
consciousness is not going to make
Um the calibrated levels of
consciousness is not going to make sense
really
really until
really until we
really until we get
really until we get to
really until we get to the
really until we get to the evolution
really until we get to the evolution of
the
the ego
really until we get to the evolution of
the ego and
the ego and how
really until we get to the evolution of
the ego and how it
the ego and how it comes
really until we get to the evolution of
the ego and how it comes about.
the ego and how it comes about. How
really until we get to the evolution of
the ego and how it comes about. How is
it
it distributed?
it distributed? The
it distributed? The the
it distributed? The the book
it distributed? The the book that
it distributed? The the book that we're
finishing
finishing now
it distributed? The the book that we're
finishing now is
uh
uh we
uh we know
uh we know what
uh we know what spiritual
uh we know what spiritual truth
uh we know what spiritual truth is.
uh we know what spiritual truth is. We
know
know the
uh we know what spiritual truth is. We
know the levels
know the levels of
uh we know what spiritual truth is. We
know the levels of truth.
If
If we
If we calibrate
If we calibrate everything
If we calibrate everything on
If we calibrate everything on the
planet,
planet, what
If we calibrate everything on the
planet, what kind
planet, what kind of
If we calibrate everything on the
planet, what kind of picture
planet, what kind of picture do
If we calibrate everything on the
planet, what kind of picture do we
planet, what kind of picture do we get?
It's
It's never
It's never been
It's never been done
It's never been done before.
So,
So, we
It's never been done before.
So, we calibrated
everything
everything that
everything that would
everything that would sit
everything that would sit still.
Every
Every everyone,
everything that would sit still.
Every everyone, every
Every everyone, every writer,
everything that would sit still.
Every everyone, every writer, you
Every everyone, every writer, you know,
of
of course,
of course, we
of course, we can't
of course, we can't do
of course, we can't do them
of course, we can't do them all.
of course, we can't do them all. We
of course, we can't do them all. We did,
you
you know,
of course, we can't do them all. We did,
you know, art,
you know, art, music,
of course, we can't do them all. We did,
you know, art, music, creativity,
sculpture,
uh,
uh, rulers,
Alexander
Alexander the
Alexander the Great,
artists,
music,
music, Americana,
TV
TV ads,
music, Americana,
TV ads, and
TV ads, and then
music, Americana,
TV ads, and then 200
TV ads, and then 200 movies.
music, Americana,
TV ads, and then 200 movies. They
TV ads, and then 200 movies. They said,
"The
"The world
"The world loves
"The world loves movies."
"The world loves movies." So,
"The world loves movies." So, we
"The world loves movies." So, we said,
"Let's
"Let's go
"The world loves movies." So, we said,
"Let's go for
"Let's go for it."
"The world loves movies." So, we said,
"Let's go for it." One
"Let's go for it." One weekend,
"The world loves movies." So, we said,
"Let's go for it." One weekend, we
"Let's go for it." One weekend, we just
sat
sat there
sat there and
sat there and went
sat there and went 200
sat there and went 200 movies.
sat there and went 200 movies. We
sat there and went 200 movies. We done
one
one after
sat there and went 200 movies. We done
one after another.
All
All right.
All right. So
All right. So why?
All right. So why? Because
All right. So why? Because we
All right. So why? Because we want
All right. So why? Because we want to
see
see you
All right. So why? Because we want to
see you know
see you know how
All right. So why? Because we want to
see you know how does
see you know how does that
All right. So why? Because we want to
see you know how does that how
see you know how does that how does
All right. So why? Because we want to
see you know how does that how does that
express
express itself
express itself in
express itself in mankind
express itself in mankind in
express itself in mankind in human
history.
history. So
express itself in mankind in human
history. So we
history. So we calibrated
express itself in mankind in human
history. So we calibrated everything
since
since since
since since the
since since the beginning
since since the beginning of
since since the beginning of time
since since the beginning of time since
the
the beginning
since since the beginning of time since
the beginning of
the beginning of human
since since the beginning of time since
the beginning of human history
the beginning of human history which
we'll
we'll finish
we'll finish but
we'll finish but this
we'll finish but this afternoon
we'll finish but this afternoon we'll
finish
finish all
we'll finish but this afternoon we'll
finish all the
finish all the time.
Why?
Why? Because
Why? Because the
Why? Because the field
Why? Because the field of
Why? Because the field of consciousness
is
is beyond
Why? Because the field of consciousness
is beyond time
is beyond time and
Why? Because the field of consciousness
is beyond time and place.
I
I can
I can calibrate
I can calibrate exactly
I can calibrate exactly what
I can calibrate exactly what went
I can calibrate exactly what went on
I can calibrate exactly what went on in
the
the year
I can calibrate exactly what went on in
the year 10,000
the year 10,000 BC
I can calibrate exactly what went on in
the year 10,000 BC right
the year 10,000 BC right now
because
because we're
because we're not
because we're not separated
because we're not separated by
because we're not separated by 10,000
years
years ago.
because we're not separated by 10,000
years ago. 10,000
years ago. 10,000 years
because we're not separated by 10,000
years ago. 10,000 years BC
years ago. 10,000 years BC and
because we're not separated by 10,000
years ago. 10,000 years BC and now
years ago. 10,000 years BC and now are
all
all the
all the same
all the same in
all the same in the
all the same in the nonlinear
all the same in the nonlinear domain.
There's
There's neither
all the same in the nonlinear domain.
There's neither here
There's neither here nor
all the same in the nonlinear domain.
There's neither here nor there,
There's neither here nor there, now
all the same in the nonlinear domain.
There's neither here nor there, now or
then.
then. That
then. That which
then. That which is
then. That which is is
then. That which is is beyond
then. That which is is beyond time,
place,
place, location.
It
It is
It is just
It is just as
It is just as available
It is just as available right
It is just as available right now
It is just as available right now as
It is just as available right now as it
was
was 100,000
It is just as available right now as it
was 100,000 years
was 100,000 years ago.
It is just as available right now as it
was 100,000 years ago. All
was 100,000 years ago. All right.
It is just as available right now as it
was 100,000 years ago. All right. How
was 100,000 years ago. All right. How do
the
the how
the how do
the how do these
the how do these levels
the how do these levels of
the how do these levels of consciousness
display
display out
the how do these levels of consciousness
display out on
display out on the
the how do these levels of consciousness
display out on the planet?
display out on the planet? Because
that'll
that'll give
that'll give us
that'll give us a
that'll give us a whole
that'll give us a whole different
understanding
understanding of
that'll give us a whole different
understanding of politics,
understanding of politics, war,
that'll give us a whole different
understanding of politics, war, and
peace
peace and
peace and all
peace and all the
peace and all the things
peace and all the things that
peace and all the things that um
peace and all the things that um are
contentious.
We
We see
We see that
We see that uh
We see that uh North
We see that uh North America
We see that uh North America runs
generally
generally 410
We see that uh North America runs
generally 410 to
generally 410 to 421.
We see that uh North America runs
generally 410 to 421. As
generally 410 to 421. As I
We see that uh North America runs
generally 410 to 421. As I said,
generally 410 to 421. As I said, Toronto
run
run it
run it is
run it is 423.
It's
It's a
run it is 423.
It's a very
It's a very arodite
run it is 423.
It's a very arodite place
It's a very arodite place folks
run it is 423.
It's a very arodite place folks and
It's a very arodite place folks and and
then
then here
then here you
then here you run
then here you run into
then here you run into 300
then here you run into 300 400
then here you run into 300 400 and
then here you run into 300 400 and in
the
the middle
then here you run into 300 400 and in
the middle in
the middle in the
then here you run into 300 400 and in
the middle in the middle
the middle in the middle of
then here you run into 300 400 and in
the middle in the middle of a
the middle in the middle of a this
then here you run into 300 400 and in
the middle in the middle of a this whole
hemisphere
hemisphere is
hemisphere is very
hemisphere is very evolved.
hemisphere is very evolved. South
America.
America. Uh,
hemisphere is very evolved. South
America. Uh, this
America. Uh, this is
hemisphere is very evolved. South
America. Uh, this is a
America. Uh, this is a very
hemisphere is very evolved. South
America. Uh, this is a very involved
region.
region. Right
region. Right in
region. Right in the
region. Right in the middle,
region. Right in the middle, suddenly
you
you come
region. Right in the middle, suddenly
you come up
you come up with
region. Right in the middle, suddenly
you come up with something
you come up with something 55.
55.
55. The
55. The world
55. The world is
55. The world is that
55. The world is that Haiti.
55. The world is that Haiti. Haiti
55. The world is that Haiti. Haiti comes
out
out in
55. The world is that Haiti. Haiti comes
out in 55.
Uh,
in
in which
Uh,
in which you
in which you see
Uh,
in which you see extreme
in which you see extreme cruelty,
extreme
extreme negativity,
um,
um, sacrifice,
extreme negativity,
um, sacrifice, blood
um, sacrifice, blood sacrifice,
extreme negativity,
um, sacrifice, blood sacrifice, primism,
and
and everybody's
and everybody's tried
and everybody's tried to
and everybody's tried to help
and everybody's tried to help Haiti
and everybody's tried to help Haiti out
of
of it,
and everybody's tried to help Haiti out
of it, and
of it, and nobody's
and everybody's tried to help Haiti out
of it, and nobody's been
of it, and nobody's been able
and everybody's tried to help Haiti out
of it, and nobody's been able to.
of it, and nobody's been able to. So
and everybody's tried to help Haiti out
of it, and nobody's been able to. So we
begin
begin to
begin to get
begin to get a
begin to get a feeling
begin to get a feeling that
begin to get a feeling that something
karmically
karmically must
begin to get a feeling that something
karmically must be
karmically must be going
begin to get a feeling that something
karmically must be going on.
karmically must be going on. You
begin to get a feeling that something
karmically must be going on. You know,
you
you begin
you begin to
you begin to get
you begin to get that
you begin to get that human
you begin to get that human life
evolves.
evolves. Then
you begin to get that human life
evolves. Then like
evolves. Then like a
you begin to get that human life
evolves. Then like a bunch
evolves. Then like a bunch of
you begin to get that human life
evolves. Then like a bunch of whistling
swans,
swans, we
swans, we all
swans, we all sort
swans, we all sort of
swans, we all sort of migrate.
swans, we all sort of migrate. We
swans, we all sort of migrate. We come
onto
onto the
swans, we all sort of migrate. We come
onto the planet
onto the planet together.
swans, we all sort of migrate. We come
onto the planet together. Then
onto the planet together. Then we
swans, we all sort of migrate. We come
onto the planet together. Then we all
sort
sort of
sort of leave.
sort of leave. Then
sort of leave. Then we
sort of leave. Then we swoop
sort of leave. Then we swoop in
sort of leave. Then we swoop in again.
You
You see?
sort of leave. Then we swoop in again.
You see? And
You see? And folks
sort of leave. Then we swoop in again.
You see? And folks that
You see? And folks that are
sort of leave. Then we swoop in again.
You see? And folks that are sort
You see? And folks that are sort of
aligned
aligned with
aligned with each
aligned with each other
aligned with each other tend
aligned with each other tend to
aligned with each other tend to swoop
aligned with each other tend to swoop in
together.
together. See,
aligned with each other tend to swoop in
together. See, we
together. See, we sort
aligned with each other tend to swoop in
together. See, we sort of
together. See, we sort of swoop
aligned with each other tend to swoop in
together. See, we sort of swoop in.
So
So this
So this whole
So this whole continent
So this whole continent we
So this whole continent we probably
So this whole continent we probably just
swoop
swoop in
So this whole continent we probably just
swoop in all
swoop in all the
So this whole continent we probably just
swoop in all the time.
swoop in all the time. Sometimes
So this whole continent we probably just
swoop in all the time. Sometimes we're
Canadians
Canadians Americans
one
one side
Canadians Americans
one side of the
one side of the river
Canadians Americans
one side of the river with
one side of the river with this
Canadians Americans
one side of the river with this side.
one side of the river with this side. So
all
all right
all right here
all right here we
all right here we have
all right here we have Greenland.
Greenland
Greenland you
all right here we have Greenland.
Greenland you see.
Greenland you see. And
all right here we have Greenland.
Greenland you see. And so
Greenland you see. And so you
all right here we have Greenland.
Greenland you see. And so you see
Greenland you see. And so you see a
certain
certain concordance.
certain concordance. So
certain concordance. So if
certain concordance. So if you
certain concordance. So if you look
certain concordance. So if you look at
the
the western
certain concordance. So if you look at
the western hemisphere
the western hemisphere you
certain concordance. So if you look at
the western hemisphere you say
the western hemisphere you say I
certain concordance. So if you look at
the western hemisphere you say I don't
see
see any
see any trouble
see any trouble rising
see any trouble rising anywhere
see any trouble rising anywhere here.
You
You know
see any trouble rising anywhere here.
You know what
You know what I
see any trouble rising anywhere here.
You know what I mean?
You know what I mean? These
see any trouble rising anywhere here.
You know what I mean? These are
reasonable
reasonable rational
reasonable rational people
reasonable rational people coherent.
These
These people
reasonable rational people coherent.
These people at
These people at 55
are
are so
are so far
are so far down
are so far down in
are so far down in the
are so far down in the scale,
are so far down in the scale, they're
too
too weak
are so far down in the scale, they're
too weak to
too weak to do
are so far down in the scale, they're
too weak to do anything
too weak to do anything except
are so far down in the scale, they're
too weak to do anything except cause
too weak to do anything except cause a
lot
lot of
lot of damage
lot of damage to
lot of damage to themselves.
lot of damage to themselves. They
haven't
haven't got
lot of damage to themselves. They
haven't got the
haven't got the energy
lot of damage to themselves. They
haven't got the energy to
haven't got the energy to cause
lot of damage to themselves. They
haven't got the energy to cause a
problem.
problem. So,
problem. So, it's
problem. So, it's some
problem. So, it's some kind
problem. So, it's some kind of
problem. So, it's some kind of an
endemic
endemic karmic
problem. So, it's some kind of an
endemic karmic problem.
endemic karmic problem. Let's
problem. So, it's some kind of an
endemic karmic problem. Let's see.
That's
That's true.
We
We have
That's true.
We have permission
We have permission to
That's true.
We have permission to ask
We have permission to ask that.
That's true.
We have permission to ask that. It's
We have permission to ask that. It's an
endemic
endemic karmic
endemic karmic problem.
endemic karmic problem. It's
endemic karmic problem. It's current.
Okay.
Okay. So,
endemic karmic problem. It's current.
Okay. So, they
Okay. So, they got
endemic karmic problem. It's current.
Okay. So, they got their
Okay. So, they got their own
endemic karmic problem. It's current.
Okay. So, they got their own karmic
problem.
They
They nothing
problem.
They nothing out
They nothing out there
problem.
They nothing out there is
They nothing out there is causing
anything.
anything. These
anything. These are
anything. These are people
anything. These are people just
anything. These are people just being
what
what they
anything. These are people just being
what they are.
It's
It's simple
It's simple enough.
You
You don't
It's simple enough.
You don't have
You don't have to
It's simple enough.
You don't have to guilt
You don't have to guilt give
It's simple enough.
You don't have to guilt give yourself
guilt
guilt that
guilt that you
guilt that you are
guilt that you are causing
guilt that you are causing them
guilt that you are causing them to
guilt that you are causing them to be
that.
that. Nobody's
guilt that you are causing them to be
that. Nobody's causing
that. Nobody's causing them
guilt that you are causing them to be
that. Nobody's causing them to
that. Nobody's causing them to be
guilt that you are causing them to be
that. Nobody's causing them to be that.
We
We express
We express that
We express that which
We express that which we
We express that which we are
We express that which we are that
We express that which we are that which
we
we have
We express that which we are that which
we have become
and
and we
and we get
and we get ourselves
and we get ourselves born
and we get ourselves born apparently
and we get ourselves born apparently in
places
places where
and we get ourselves born apparently in
places where we're
places where we're compatible.
and we get ourselves born apparently in
places where we're compatible. Okay,
let's
let's go
let's go next.
All
All right,
let's go next.
All right, if
All right, if we
let's go next.
All right, if we do
All right, if we do this,
let's go next.
All right, if we do this, this
All right, if we do this, this one
let's go next.
All right, if we do this, this one is
sort
sort of
sort of a
sort of a messy
sort of a messy one.
sort of a messy one. This
sort of a messy one. This is
sort of a messy one. This is very
sort of a messy one. This is very messy.
Anyway,
Anyway, we
sort of a messy one. This is very messy.
Anyway, we we
Anyway, we we can
sort of a messy one. This is very messy.
Anyway, we we can see
Anyway, we we can see 410.
Uh
Uh I
Uh I think
Uh I think there's
Uh I think there's a
Uh I think there's a better
Uh I think there's a better one
Uh I think there's a better one of
Uh I think there's a better one of this
later.
Uh
Uh what's
Uh what's the
Uh what's the previous
Uh what's the previous one?
Uh
Uh oh.
Uh what's the previous one?
Uh oh. Yeah.
Uh oh. Yeah. Well,
Uh what's the previous one?
Uh oh. Yeah. Well, this
Uh oh. Yeah. Well, this is
Uh what's the previous one?
Uh oh. Yeah. Well, this is just
Uh oh. Yeah. Well, this is just this
Uh what's the previous one?
Uh oh. Yeah. Well, this is just this one
again.
again. 410
again. 410 Alaska.
again. 410 Alaska. This
again. 410 Alaska. This is
again. 410 Alaska. This is really
again. 410 Alaska. This is really around
420 now.
>> 45.
>> You
>> You see
>> 45.
>> You see South
>> You see South America.
>> 45.
>> You see South America. You
>> You see South America. You don't
>> 45.
>> You see South America. You don't see
>> You see South America. You don't see any
real
real problem
real problem coming
real problem coming up
real problem coming up here.
real problem coming up here. Okay,
real problem coming up here. Okay, let's
go
go to
real problem coming up here. Okay, let's
go to the
go to the next
real problem coming up here. Okay, let's
go to the next one.
>> Now,
>> Now, here
>> Now, here you're
>> Now, here you're going
>> Now, here you're going to
>> Now, here you're going to see
>> Now, here you're going to see some
problem.
problem. Huh?
Here
Here you
Here you have
Here you have Here's
Here you have Here's Australia.
Here
Here you
Here you have Here's Australia.
Here you see
Here you see Russia,
Here you have Here's Australia.
Here you see Russia, China,
Here you see Russia, China, Mongolia.
Here's
Here's India.
Here's India. Huh?
Now
Now you
Here's India. Huh?
Now you see
Now you see Northern
Here's India. Huh?
Now you see Northern Europe.
You
You see
You see South
You see South Southern
You see South Southern Africa,
Madagascar.
And
And here
And here you
And here you see
And here you see the
And here you see the most
And here you see the most tragic
And here you see the most tragic places
on
on the
And here you see the most tragic places
on the planet
on the planet today,
And here you see the most tragic places
on the planet today, the
on the planet today, the middle
And here you see the most tragic places
on the planet today, the middle of
Africa.
Africa. Savagery.
The
The world
Africa. Savagery.
The world of
The world of uh
mountain
mountain gorillas.
World
World of
mountain gorillas.
World of mountain
World of mountain gorillas.
mountain gorillas.
World of mountain gorillas. Calibrates
higher
higher than
higher than the
higher than the people.
The
The people,
higher than the people.
The people, you're
The people, you're safe
higher than the people.
The people, you're safe with
The people, you're safe with mountain
gorillas.
gorillas. You
gorillas. You can
gorillas. You can walk
gorillas. You can walk around
gorillas. You can walk around them,
gorillas. You can walk around them, but
the
the people
gorillas. You can walk around them, but
the people will
the people will kill
gorillas. You can walk around them, but
the people will kill you.
The
The people
The people will
The people will kill
The people will kill you.
The people will kill you. Not
The people will kill you. Not only
The people will kill you. Not only they
kill
kill you,
The people will kill you. Not only they
kill you, they
kill you, they will
The people will kill you. Not only they
kill you, they will slowly
kill you, they will slowly torture
The people will kill you. Not only they
kill you, they will slowly torture you
to
to death.
You're
You're better
to death.
You're better here
You're better here to
to death.
You're better here to be
You're better here to be a
to death.
You're better here to be a mountain
gorilla
gorilla than
gorilla than a
gorilla than a people.
Wow.
Here
Here we
Here we run
Here we run 70
Here we run 70 185
Here we run 70 185 North
Here we run 70 185 North Africa.
Here we run 70 185 North Africa. You
Here we run 70 185 North Africa. You see
there's
there's going
Here we run 70 185 North Africa. You see
there's going to
there's going to be
Here we run 70 185 North Africa. You see
there's going to be a
there's going to be a big
Here we run 70 185 North Africa. You see
there's going to be a big problem
there's going to be a big problem in
North
North Africa.
North Africa. So
North Africa. So we
North Africa. So we come
North Africa. So we come from
North Africa. So we come from another
universe
universe and
North Africa. So we come from another
universe and we
universe and we just
North Africa. So we come from another
universe and we just study
universe and we just study this
North Africa. So we come from another
universe and we just study this with
universe and we just study this with a
microscope
microscope like
microscope like a
microscope like a microscope.
microscope like a microscope. We
microscope like a microscope. We want
microscope like a microscope. We want to
examine
examine the
microscope like a microscope. We want to
examine the human
examine the human condition
microscope like a microscope. We want to
examine the human condition and
examine the human condition and all
microscope like a microscope. We want to
examine the human condition and all we
know
know is
know is these
know is these numbers.
know is these numbers. We
know is these numbers. We can
know is these numbers. We can already
predict
predict what's
know is these numbers. We can already
predict what's going
predict what's going to
know is these numbers. We can already
predict what's going to go
predict what's going to go on
know is these numbers. We can already
predict what's going to go on there.
predict what's going to go on there. You
can
can see
can see in
can see in North
can see in North Africa
can see in North Africa you're
can see in North Africa you're going
can see in North Africa you're going to
have
have endless
can see in North Africa you're going to
have endless strikes
have endless strikes there
can see in North Africa you're going to
have endless strikes there 180
have endless strikes there 180 190
can see in North Africa you're going to
have endless strikes there 180 190 those
people
people are
people are going
people are going to
people are going to be
people are going to be added
and
and here
people are going to be added
and here you
and here you come
people are going to be added
and here you come to
and here you come to uh
people are going to be added
and here you come to uh Scandinavia
and here you come to uh Scandinavia and
Europe
Europe so
Europe so we
Europe so we don't
Europe so we don't expect
Europe so we don't expect any
Europe so we don't expect any big
problem
problem coming
Europe so we don't expect any big
problem coming out
problem coming out of
Europe so we don't expect any big
problem coming out of Europe
problem coming out of Europe Scandinavia
we
we would
we would expect
we would expect it
we would expect it where
we would expect it where people
we would expect it where people are
calibrating
calibrating 180
we would expect it where people are
calibrating 180 190
uh
and
and that's
uh
and that's just
and that's just what
uh
and that's just what the
and that's just what the difficulty
uh
and that's just what the difficulty is
okay
okay so
okay so let's
okay so let's move
okay so let's move on
okay so let's move on to
okay so let's move on to the
okay so let's move on to the next
okay so let's move on to the next one
this
this is
okay so let's move on to the next one
this is the
this is the details
okay so let's move on to the next one
this is the details of
this is the details of the
okay so let's move on to the next one
this is the details of the countries
which
which is
which is too
which is too small
which is too small to
which is too small to read
which is too small to read but
which is too small to read but but
which is too small to read but but these
are
are the
which is too small to read but but these
are the places
are the places uh
which is too small to read but but these
are the places uh that
are the places uh that we
which is too small to read but but these
are the places uh that we read
are the places uh that we read about
which is too small to read but but these
are the places uh that we read about in
the
the paper
the paper Rwanda
the paper Rwanda etc.
the paper Rwanda etc. Okay,
the paper Rwanda etc. Okay, let's
the paper Rwanda etc. Okay, let's go
the paper Rwanda etc. Okay, let's go to
the
the next
the paper Rwanda etc. Okay, let's go to
the next one.
We
We already
We already talked
We already talked about
We already talked about this
We already talked about this that
We already talked about this that the
world
world thinks
We already talked about this that the
world thinks that
world thinks that this
We already talked about this that the
world thinks that this causes
world thinks that this causes this
causes
causes this
causes this whereas
causes this whereas actually
they're
they're all
causes this whereas actually
they're all coming
they're all coming out
causes this whereas actually
they're all coming out of
they're all coming out of this
causes this whereas actually
they're all coming out of this is
they're all coming out of this is really
Sheldrick's
uh
uh field
Sheldrick's
uh field of
uh field of eventuality
and
and coming
and coming out
and coming out of
and coming out of an
and coming out of an attractive
and coming out of an attractive pattern
that
that people
and coming out of an attractive pattern
that people of
that people of a
and coming out of an attractive pattern
that people of a sim
that people of a sim similar
and coming out of an attractive pattern
that people of a sim similar calibrated
level
level of
level of consciousness
level of consciousness tend
level of consciousness tend to
level of consciousness tend to think
level of consciousness tend to think in
certain
certain patterns
level of consciousness tend to think in
certain patterns certain
certain patterns certain ways.
level of consciousness tend to think in
certain patterns certain ways. They
certain patterns certain ways. They like
to
to think
to think that
to think that this
to think that this is
to think that this is individual
actually
actually is
to think that this is individual
actually is the
actually is the radiance
to think that this is individual
actually is the radiance of
actually is the radiance of an
to think that this is individual
actually is the radiance of an attractor
field.
field. Everybody
field. Everybody in
field. Everybody in that
field. Everybody in that field
field. Everybody in that field tends
field. Everybody in that field tends to
think
think in
field. Everybody in that field tends to
think in the
think in the same
field. Everybody in that field tends to
think in the same way.
think in the same way. Let's
field. Everybody in that field tends to
think in the same way. Let's go
think in the same way. Let's go to
field. Everybody in that field tends to
think in the same way. Let's go to the
next
next one.
We
We mentioned
next one.
We mentioned the
We mentioned the transition.
next one.
We mentioned the transition. You
We mentioned the transition. You go
next one.
We mentioned the transition. You go from
the
the Newtonian
the Newtonian dimension
the Newtonian dimension of
the Newtonian dimension of causality.
The
The next
the Newtonian dimension of causality.
The next step
The next step up
the Newtonian dimension of causality.
The next step up is
The next step up is uh
the Newtonian dimension of causality.
The next step up is uh quantum
The next step up is uh quantum mechanics
to
to nonlinear
to nonlinear dynamics
to nonlinear dynamics and
to nonlinear dynamics and f
to nonlinear dynamics and f finally
to nonlinear dynamics and f finally to
the
the calibration
to nonlinear dynamics and f finally to
the calibration the
the calibration the science
to nonlinear dynamics and f finally to
the calibration the science of
consciousness
consciousness itself.
consciousness itself. Each
consciousness itself. Each one
consciousness itself. Each one is
consciousness itself. Each one is a
paradigm
paradigm jump.
consciousness itself. Each one is a
paradigm jump. Each
paradigm jump. Each one
consciousness itself. Each one is a
paradigm jump. Each one is
paradigm jump. Each one is a
consciousness itself. Each one is a
paradigm jump. Each one is a paradigm
jump.
jump. Uh
jump. Uh Ze
jump. Uh Ze Einstein
at
at the
jump. Uh Ze Einstein
at the Copenhagen
at the Copenhagen out
jump. Uh Ze Einstein
at the Copenhagen out at
at the Copenhagen out at the
jump. Uh Ze Einstein
at the Copenhagen out at the Copenhagen
conference
conference on
conference on quantum
conference on quantum mechanics
withdrew
withdrew from
the
the Heisenberg
the Heisenberg principle.
the Heisenberg principle. Heisenberg
process
process that
the Heisenberg principle. Heisenberg
process that is
process that is this
the Heisenberg principle. Heisenberg
process that is this is
process that is this is the
the Heisenberg principle. Heisenberg
process that is this is the condition
process that is this is the condition of
the
the universe
the universe right
the universe right now.
the universe right now. The
the universe right now. The straighter
process
process time
the universe right now. The straighter
process time dependent
process time dependent time
the universe right now. The straighter
process time dependent time independent
two
two sets
two sets of
two sets of equations
trader
trader equations
two sets of equations
trader equations that's
trader equations that's potentiality
that
that by
that by intention
that by intention by
that by intention by intention
potential
potential can
that by intention by intention
potential can become
potential can become actualized
that by intention by intention
potential can become actualized when
conditions
conditions are
conditions are right.
conditions are right. One
conditions are right. One of
conditions are right. One of the
conditions are right. One of the things
that
that makes
conditions are right. One of the things
that makes it
that makes it happen
conditions are right. One of the things
that makes it happen is
that makes it happen is intention.
Intention
Intention collapses
Intention collapses the
Intention collapses the wave
Intention collapses the wave function.
We
We now
Intention collapses the wave function.
We now have
We now have a
Intention collapses the wave function.
We now have a different
We now have a different state
Intention collapses the wave function.
We now have a different state of
We now have a different state of the
universe.
One
One is
universe.
One is is
One is is a
universe.
One is is a potential
One is is a potential next
universe.
One is is a potential next it's
One is is a potential next it's an
actual
actual then
actual then the
actual then the actual
actual then the actual is
actual then the actual is the
actual then the actual is the potential
for
for the
actual then the actual is the potential
for the next.
for the next. So
actual then the actual is the potential
for the next. So each
for the next. So each decision
actual then the actual is the potential
for the next. So each decision each
choice
that's
that's karmic
choice
that's karmic responsibility
that's karmic responsibility from
choice
that's karmic responsibility from moment
to
to moment
to moment we
to moment we are
to moment we are constantly
to moment we are constantly choosing
to moment we are constantly choosing to
look
look this
to moment we are constantly choosing to
look this way
look this way to
to moment we are constantly choosing to
look this way to look
look this way to look this
to moment we are constantly choosing to
look this way to look this way
look this way to look this way to
to moment we are constantly choosing to
look this way to look this way to feel
favorable
favorable to
favorable to feel
favorable to feel unfavorable
favorable to feel unfavorable to
favorable to feel unfavorable to look
to.
to. So
favorable to feel unfavorable to look
to. So we
to. So we are
favorable to feel unfavorable to look
to. So we are constantly
to. So we are constantly collapsing
favorable to feel unfavorable to look
to. So we are constantly collapsing wave
function.
It's
It's done
function.
It's done via
It's done via what's
function.
It's done via what's called
It's done via what's called the
function.
It's done via what's called the vonment
process.
People
People interested
process.
People interested in
People interested in this
process.
People interested in this Henry
People interested in this Henry stap
process.
People interested in this Henry stap sap
has
has an
has an interesting
has an interesting website
has an interesting website in
has an interesting website in which
has an interesting website in which he
goes
goes into
has an interesting website in which he
goes into the
goes into the fond
has an interesting website in which he
goes into the fond process
goes into the fond process process
has an interesting website in which he
goes into the fond process process one
process
process two
process two explains
process two explains it
process two explains it all.
process two explains it all. At
process two explains it all. At this
point
point Einstein
process two explains it all. At this
point Einstein however
um
um drew
um drew back.
um drew back. Einstein
um drew back. Einstein did
um drew back. Einstein did 499
um drew back. Einstein did 499 did
um drew back. Einstein did 499 did not
jump
jump over
um drew back. Einstein did 499 did not
jump over 500.
Einstein
Einstein is
Einstein is alleged
Einstein is alleged to
Einstein is alleged to have
Einstein is alleged to have said,
Einstein is alleged to have said, "I
would
would prefer
Einstein is alleged to have said, "I
would prefer to
would prefer to think
Einstein is alleged to have said, "I
would prefer to think that
would prefer to think that there's
Einstein is alleged to have said, "I
would prefer to think that there's an
independent
independent objective
independent objective universe
independent objective universe out
independent objective universe out there
independent
independent of
independent objective universe out there
independent of consciousness."
Independent,
Independent, self-existent,
Independent, self-existent, independent
of
of consciousness.
And
And so
And so I
And so I Einstein
And so I Einstein grew
And so I Einstein grew back
And so I Einstein grew back because
And so I Einstein grew back because 500
is
is a
And so I Einstein grew back because 500
is a paradigm
is a paradigm jump.
And so I Einstein grew back because 500
is a paradigm jump. The
is a paradigm jump. The world
And so I Einstein grew back because 500
is a paradigm jump. The world of
is a paradigm jump. The world of science
goes
goes up
goes up to
goes up to 499.
Now
Now you
goes up to 499.
Now you shift
Now you shift to
goes up to 499.
Now you shift to a
Now you shift to a new
goes up to 499.
Now you shift to a new paradigm.
A
A new
A new paradigm.
A new paradigm. Einstein
A new paradigm. Einstein refused
A new paradigm. Einstein refused the
jump.
Just
Just as
Just as Freud
Just as Freud refused
Just as Freud refused it,
Just as Freud refused it, Roy
Just as Freud refused it, Roy stopped
Just as Freud refused it, Roy stopped at
499.
Many
Many of
Many of the
Many of the great
Many of the great mathematical
Many of the great mathematical geniuses,
scientific
scientific geniuses
Many of the great mathematical geniuses,
scientific geniuses stopped
scientific geniuses stopped at
Many of the great mathematical geniuses,
scientific geniuses stopped at 499
because
because in
because in 500
because in 500 reality
because in 500 reality jumps
because in 500 reality jumps to
because in 500 reality jumps to the
subjective.
It
It stops
It stops being
It stops being a
It stops being a calculable
It stops being a calculable out
It stops being a calculable out there
and
and you
It stops being a calculable out there
and you have
and you have to
It stops being a calculable out there
and you have to jump
and you have to jump to
It stops being a calculable out there
and you have to jump to the
and you have to jump to the subjective.
Spiritual
Spiritual reality
Spiritual reality is
Spiritual reality is subjective.
It
It is
Spiritual reality is subjective.
It is not
It is not provable.
Spiritual reality is subjective.
It is not provable. It's
It is not provable. It's demonable.
Spiritual reality is subjective.
It is not provable. It's demonable. It's
experiential
experiential but
experiential but it's
experiential but it's not
experiential but it's not provable
because
because it's
experiential but it's not provable
because it's not
because it's not within
experiential but it's not provable
because it's not within the
because it's not within the Newtonian
paradigm
paradigm of
paradigm of reality.
paradigm of reality. So
paradigm of reality. So you
paradigm of reality. So you jump
paradigm of reality. So you jump from
the
the Newtonian
paradigm of reality. So you jump from
the Newtonian then
the Newtonian then at
paradigm of reality. So you jump from
the Newtonian then at 500.
Now
Now you
Now you have
Now you have a
Now you have a new
Now you have a new set
Now you have a new set by
Now you have a new set by the
Now you have a new set by the direct
equations.
equations. You
Now you have a new set by the direct
equations. You can
equations. You can calculate
Now you have a new set by the direct
equations. You can calculate by
equations. You can calculate by the
strainer
strainer equations
strainer equations you
strainer equations you get
strainer equations you get what
strainer equations you get what is
strainer equations you get what is the
condition
condition the
strainer equations you get what is the
condition the potential
condition the potential of
strainer equations you get what is the
condition the potential of the
condition the potential of the universe
at
at this
at this second
at this second look
at this second look at
at this second look at the
at this second look at the experiment
instantly
instantly you've
at this second look at the experiment
instantly you've changed
instantly you've changed it
at this second look at the experiment
instantly you've changed it you've
collapsed
collapsed the
collapsed the wave
collapsed the wave function
collapsed the wave function now
collapsed the wave function now you
collapsed the wave function now you can
recalculate
recalculate the
collapsed the wave function now you can
recalculate the condition
recalculate the condition of
collapsed the wave function now you can
recalculate the condition of the
universe
universe but
universe but direct
universe but direct process
universe but direct process and
universe but direct process and now
universe but direct process and now you
have
have the
universe but direct process and now you
have the new
have the new equations
universe but direct process and now you
have the new equations which
have the new equations which is
universe but direct process and now you
have the new equations which is the
have the new equations which is the new
next
next state
next state you
next state you see
next state you see the
next state you see the state
next state you see the state the
potentiality
potentiality becomes
next state you see the state the
potentiality becomes actuality
potentiality becomes actuality which
becomes
becomes the
becomes the potentiality
becomes the potentiality of
becomes the potentiality of the
becomes the potentiality of the next
sexuality
and
and that's
and that's how
and that's how creation
and that's how creation unfolds.
and that's how creation unfolds. simple
this
>> it's
>> it's very
>> it's very simple
>> it's very simple okay
so
so anyway
>> it's very simple okay
so anyway Einstein
so anyway Einstein 499
>> it's very simple okay
so anyway Einstein 499 so
so anyway Einstein 499 so intellectual
genius
genius is
genius is one
genius is one thing
genius is one thing spiritual
genius is one thing spiritual genius
genius is one thing spiritual genius is
another
you
you can
you can flunk
you can flunk math
you can flunk math and
you can flunk math and be
you can flunk math and be a
you can flunk math and be a spiritual
genius
genius or
you can flunk math and be a spiritual
genius or you
genius or you can
you can flunk math and be a spiritual
genius or you can be
genius or you can be a
you can flunk math and be a spiritual
genius or you can be a mathematical
genius
genius and
genius and not
genius and not be
genius and not be able
genius and not be able to
genius and not be able to cross
genius and not be able to cross over
that
that 499
genius and not be able to cross over
that 499 is
that 499 is the
genius and not be able to cross over
that 499 is the big
that 499 is the big is
genius and not be able to cross over
that 499 is the big is the
that 499 is the big is the big
genius and not be able to cross over
that 499 is the big is the big stopping
block
block very
block very few
block very few people
block very few people how
block very few people how many
block very few people how many people
cross
cross over
block very few people how many people
cross over 499
cross over 499 to
block very few people how many people
cross over 499 to 500.
cross over 499 to 500. 4%
block very few people how many people
cross over 499 to 500. 4% of
cross over 499 to 500. 4% of the
block very few people how many people
cross over 499 to 500. 4% of the world's
population
4%
4% of
population
4% of the
4% of the world's
population
4% of the world's population
4% of the world's population calibrates
over
over 500.
0.4
get
get as
get as far
get as far as
get as far as 540.
get as far as 540. 540
get as far as 540. 540 is
get as far as 540. 540 is unconditional
love.
What
What does
What does 500
What does 500 or
What does 500 or 540?
What does 500 or 540? What
What does 500 or 540? What do
What does 500 or 540? What do they
What does 500 or 540? What do they mean?
People
People think
What does 500 or 540? What do they mean?
People think love
People think love means
What does 500 or 540? What do they mean?
People think love means an
People think love means an emotionality.
It's
It's a
It's a feeling
It's a feeling that
It's a feeling that goes
It's a feeling that goes from
It's a feeling that goes from me
It's a feeling that goes from me to
It's a feeling that goes from me to you.
Love
Love is
It's a feeling that goes from me to you.
Love is almost
Love is almost in
It's a feeling that goes from me to you.
Love is almost in a
Love is almost in a pos
It's a feeling that goes from me to you.
Love is almost in a pos possessiveness
like
like that.
like that. That's
like that. That's why
like that. That's why it
like that. That's why it leads
like that. That's why it leads to
like that. That's why it leads to murder
and
and suicide
like that. That's why it leads to murder
and suicide with
and suicide with frequency.
like that. That's why it leads to murder
and suicide with frequency. Leave
and suicide with frequency. Leave me
like that. That's why it leads to murder
and suicide with frequency. Leave me and
you're
you're going
you're going to
you're going to die.
you're going to die. You
you're going to die. You know
you're going to die. You know what
you're going to die. You know what I
mean?
mean? Love
you're going to die. You know what I
mean? Love is
mean? Love is an
you're going to die. You know what I
mean? Love is an emotion
mean? Love is an emotion that
you're going to die. You know what I
mean? Love is an emotion that goes
mean? Love is an emotion that goes from
here
here to
here to there.
here to there. Very
here to there. Very often
here to there. Very often possessive
more
more solar
here to there. Very often possessive
more solar plexus
more solar plexus than
here to there. Very often possessive
more solar plexus than heart.
more solar plexus than heart. But
here to there. Very often possessive
more solar plexus than heart. But as
more solar plexus than heart. But as it
evolves,
evolves, it
evolves, it becomes
evolves, it becomes more
evolves, it becomes more and
evolves, it becomes more and more
evolves, it becomes more and more heart.
it
it eventually
at
at 500
at 500 people
at 500 people show
at 500 people show a
at 500 people show a dramatic
at 500 people show a dramatic change
at 500 people show a dramatic change and
at
at 540
at 500 people show a dramatic change and
at 540 you
at 540 you just
at 500 people show a dramatic change and
at 540 you just become
at 540 you just become a
at 500 people show a dramatic change and
at 540 you just become a different
person.
Love
Love is
person.
Love is not
Love is not an
person.
Love is not an emotion,
Love is not an emotion, it's
person.
Love is not an emotion, it's a
Love is not an emotion, it's a way
person.
Love is not an emotion, it's a way of
being.
being. At
being. At 540
being. At 540 love
being. At 540 love is
being. At 540 love is a
being. At 540 love is a way
being. At 540 love is a way of
being. At 540 love is a way of being
with
with the
being. At 540 love is a way of being
with the world.
540 is
540 is what
540 is what you
540 is what you are.
You
You just
540 is what you are.
You just have
You just have a
540 is what you are.
You just have a reverence
You just have a reverence for
540 is what you are.
You just have a reverence for life
You just have a reverence for life the
way
way it
way it is.
You
You walk
way it is.
You walk around
You walk around the
way it is.
You walk around the ant
You walk around the ant not
way it is.
You walk around the ant not because
you're
you're superstitious,
you're superstitious, not
you're superstitious, not because
you're superstitious, not because you
belong
belong to
you're superstitious, not because you
belong to some
belong to some weird
you're superstitious, not because you
belong to some weird religious
belong to some weird religious sect,
but
but because
but because you
but because you don't
but because you don't destroy
but because you don't destroy life
but because you don't destroy life if
you
you can
but because you don't destroy life if
you can avoid
you can avoid it.
At
At 540,
At 540, there
At 540, there is
At 540, there is the
At 540, there is the emergence
At 540, there is the emergence of
At 540, there is the emergence of a
reverence
reverence for
At 540, there is the emergence of a
reverence for life
reverence for life because
At 540, there is the emergence of a
reverence for life because of
reverence for life because of that
At 540, there is the emergence of a
reverence for life because of that which
you
you have
you have become.
you have become. You
you have become. You see,
you have become. You see, it's
you have become. You see, it's not
you have become. You see, it's not a
this
this and
you have become. You see, it's not a
this and a
this and a that
you have become. You see, it's not a
this and a that anymore.
You
You have
You have become
Your
Your life
You have become
Your life becomes
Your life becomes your
You have become
Your life becomes your spiritual
pathway.
pathway. Your
pathway. Your life
pathway. Your life becomes
pathway. Your life becomes a
pathway. Your life becomes a prayer.
You
You become
pathway. Your life becomes a prayer.
You become that.
You
You become
You become that.
And
And by
You become that.
And by becoming
And by becoming that
You become that.
And by becoming that your
And by becoming that your life
You become that.
And by becoming that your life is
And by becoming that your life is like
You become that.
And by becoming that your life is like a
mudra.
mudra. You
mudra. You are
mudra. You are like
mudra. You are like positioned
God.
You
You stand
You stand at
You stand at the
You stand at the crossway
You stand at the crossway and
You stand at the crossway and you
You stand at the crossway and you go,
>> your
>> your life
You stand at the crossway and you go,
>> your life is
>> your life is that
You stand at the crossway and you go,
>> your life is that way
>> your life is that way like
You stand at the crossway and you go,
>> your life is that way like open
>> your life is that way like open to
guidance,
guidance, open
guidance, open to
guidance, open to the
guidance, open to the presence
guidance, open to the presence of
divinity
divinity because
guidance, open to the presence of
divinity because you
divinity because you become
guidance, open to the presence of
divinity because you become more
divinity because you become more like
the
the the
the the leaf
the the leaf in
the the leaf in the
the the leaf in the wind
the the leaf in the wind and
life
life becomes
the the leaf in the wind and
life becomes progressively
life becomes progressively effortless.
What
What you
What you need
What you need materializes.
You
You run
What you need materializes.
You run out
You run out of
What you need materializes.
You run out of Diet
You run out of Diet Pepsi.
What you need materializes.
You run out of Diet Pepsi. Your
You run out of Diet Pepsi. Your best
friend
friend says,
friend says, "Here's
friend says, "Here's a
friend says, "Here's a six-pack.
Well,
y'all
y'all don't
y'all don't buy
y'all don't buy six
y'all don't buy six packs.
y'all don't buy six packs. He
y'all don't buy six packs. He buys
y'all don't buy six packs. He buys 12
packs.
packs. I
y'all don't buy six packs. He buys 12
packs. I don't
packs. I don't know.
Anyway,
>> all right.
>> all right. So,
Anyway,
>> all right. So, now
>> all right. So, now you
Anyway,
>> all right. So, now you understand
quantum
quantum mechanics
equations.
You
You don't
You don't need
You don't need numbers.
You don't need numbers. That's
You don't need numbers. That's really
boring.
They're
They're in
They're in the
They're in the back
They're in the back of
They're in the back of the
They're in the back of the book.
They're in the back of the book. If
They're in the back of the book. If you
want
want to
They're in the back of the book. If you
want to look
want to look up
They're in the back of the book. If you
want to look up these
want to look up these equations,
uh,
uh, forget
uh, forget it.
uh, forget it. You
uh, forget it. You don't
uh, forget it. You don't have
uh, forget it. You don't have to.
Potentiality
Potentiality becomes
uh, forget it. You don't have to.
Potentiality becomes an
Potentiality becomes an actuality
through
through intention.
through intention. So
through intention. So what
through intention. So what can
through intention. So what can we
through intention. So what can we do
through intention. So what can we do for
the
the poor
through intention. So what can we do for
the poor people
the poor people of
through intention. So what can we do for
the poor people of the
the poor people of the world?
through intention. So what can we do for
the poor people of the world? Should
the poor people of the world? Should we
have
have a
have a parade
have a parade for
have a parade for peace?
have a parade for peace? Huh?
have a parade for peace? Huh? Pass
have a parade for peace? Huh? Pass the
hat.
hat. That's
have a parade for peace? Huh? Pass the
hat. That's all
hat. That's all nice.
What
What we
What we can
What we can do
What we can do for
What we can do for them?
What we can do for them? Well,
intention
intention is
What we can do for them? Well,
intention is so
intention is so powerful
What we can do for them? Well,
intention is so powerful that
what
what we
what we hold
what we hold as
what we hold as our
what we hold as our intention
what we hold as our intention for
what we hold as our intention for them
already
already beguns
what we hold as our intention for them
already beguns to
already beguns to affect
what we hold as our intention for them
already beguns to affect them.
What
What you
What you can
What you can do
What you can do you
What you can do you see
What you can do you see each
What you can do you see each person
rises
rises in
What you can do you see each person
rises in the
rises in the sea
What you can do you see each person
rises in the sea like
rises in the sea like a
What you can do you see each person
rises in the sea like a cork.
rises in the sea like a cork. What
What you can do you see each person
rises in the sea like a cork. What we
have
have become
have become determines
have become determines our
have become determines our buoyancy.
Therefore
Therefore how
have become determines our buoyancy.
Therefore how high
Therefore how high we
have become determines our buoyancy.
Therefore how high we rise
Therefore how high we rise in
have become determines our buoyancy.
Therefore how high we rise in the
Therefore how high we rise in the sea
calibrated
calibrated level
calibrated level of
calibrated level of consciousness.
calibrated level of consciousness. It
calibrated level of consciousness. It is
by
by our
calibrated level of consciousness. It is
by our own
by our own hand
calibrated level of consciousness. It is
by our own hand only
by our own hand only by
calibrated level of consciousness. It is
by our own hand only by our
by our own hand only by our own
calibrated level of consciousness. It is
by our own hand only by our own choice
and
and by
and by our
and by our own
and by our own decision
and by our own decision we
and by our own decision we develop
and by our own decision we develop a
certain
certain buoyancy.
and by our own decision we develop a
certain buoyancy. Huh?
The
The consequence
The consequence of
The consequence of that
The consequence of that which
The consequence of that which we
The consequence of that which we have
become
become within
The consequence of that which we have
become within the
become within the field.
The
The field
The field itself
The field itself we
The field itself we can
The field itself we can affect.
The field itself we can affect. We
The field itself we can affect. We can
affect
affect the
The field itself we can affect. We can
affect the proximate
affect the proximate field
The field itself we can affect. We can
affect the proximate field in
affect the proximate field in which
these
these people
these people live
these people live by
these people live by our
these people live by our intention.
By
By our
these people live by our intention.
By our intention
By our intention we
these people live by our intention.
By our intention we can
By our intention we can lift
these people live by our intention.
By our intention we can lift the
By our intention we can lift the sea
these people live by our intention.
By our intention we can lift the sea and
collective
collective consciousness
collective consciousness of
collective consciousness of mankind.
When
When you
collective consciousness of mankind.
When you lift
When you lift the
collective consciousness of mankind.
When you lift the sea
When you lift the sea you
collective consciousness of mankind.
When you lift the sea you lift
When you lift the sea you lift all
collective consciousness of mankind.
When you lift the sea you lift all the
ships
ships on
ships on the
ships on the sea
ships on the sea effortlessly.
You
You can
ships on the sea effortlessly.
You can put
You can put all
ships on the sea effortlessly.
You can put all the
You can put all the power
ships on the sea effortlessly.
You can put all the power you
You can put all the power you can
collect
collect from
collect from all
collect from all over
collect from all over the
collect from all over the world
collect from all over the world and
collect from all over the world and pour
it
it into
collect from all over the world and pour
it into one
it into one place.
collect from all over the world and pour
it into one place. And
it into one place. And I'll
collect from all over the world and pour
it into one place. And I'll tell
it into one place. And I'll tell you,
it's
it's going
it's going to
it's going to go
it's going to go down
it's going to go down the
it's going to go down the rat
it's going to go down the rat hole,
down
down the
it's going to go down the rat hole,
down the rattle
down the rattle hole.
It's
It's got
It's got such
It's got such a
It's got such a big
It's got such a big hole.
It's got such a big hole. I
It's got such a big hole. I don't
It's got such a big hole. I don't care
how
how much
It's got such a big hole. I don't care
how much you
how much you pour
It's got such a big hole. I don't care
how much you pour into
how much you pour into it,
It's got such a big hole. I don't care
how much you pour into it, it's
how much you pour into it, it's going
It's got such a big hole. I don't care
how much you pour into it, it's going to
go
gone.
But
But if
But if you
But if you effortlessly
But if you effortlessly then
But if you effortlessly then begin
But if you effortlessly then begin to
raise
raise the
But if you effortlessly then begin to
raise the sea
raise the sea by
But if you effortlessly then begin to
raise the sea by collective
raise the sea by collective intention,
then
then all
then all the
then all the ships
then all the ships are
then all the ships are lifted
then all the ships are lifted equally.
Nobody's
Nobody's got
then all the ships are lifted equally.
Nobody's got the
Nobody's got the strength
then all the ships are lifted equally.
Nobody's got the strength to
Nobody's got the strength to do
then all the ships are lifted equally.
Nobody's got the strength to do it.
Nobody's got the strength to do it. But
how
how much
how much strength
how much strength will
how much strength will it
how much strength will it take
how much strength will it take to
how much strength will it take to lift
the
the battleship
how much strength will it take to lift
the battleship out
the battleship out of
how much strength will it take to lift
the battleship out of the
the battleship out of the water?
None
None of
None of these
None of these countries
None of these countries are
None of these countries are like
None of these countries are like dead
weight
weight battleships.
None of these countries are like dead
weight battleships. You
weight battleships. You tried
None of these countries are like dead
weight battleships. You tried lifting
them
them out
them out of
them out of the
them out of the water.
them out of the water. It
them out of the water. It doesn't
them out of the water. It doesn't work
because
because it's
them out of the water. It doesn't work
because it's just
because it's just every
them out of the water. It doesn't work
because it's just every asset
because it's just every asset you
them out of the water. It doesn't work
because it's just every asset you can
put
put in
put in there
put in there goes
gone
by
by our
by our collective
by our collective intention
by our collective intention by
by our collective intention by the
radiance
radiance of
by our collective intention by the
radiance of our
radiance of our love.
by our collective intention by the
radiance of our love. You
radiance of our love. You can
by our collective intention by the
radiance of our love. You can focus
radiance of our love. You can focus it
where
where it's
where it's needed
where it's needed the
where it's needed the most.
where it's needed the most. However,
they
they also
where it's needed the most. However,
they also still
they also still have
where it's needed the most. However,
they also still have their
they also still have their own
where it's needed the most. However,
they also still have their own karma.
I'm
I'm not
I'm not going
I'm not going to
I'm not going to do
I'm not going to do anything
I'm not going to do anything about
I'm not going to do anything about that.
So
So the
I'm not going to do anything about that.
So the willingness
So the willingness to
I'm not going to do anything about that.
So the willingness to surrender
So the willingness to surrender one's
intention
intention to
intention to God
collectively
collectively you
intention to God
collectively you see
collectively you see the
intention to God
collectively you see the consciousness
of
of mankind
of mankind was
of mankind was at
of mankind was at 90
of mankind was at 90 the
of mankind was at 90 the time
of mankind was at 90 the time of
of mankind was at 90 the time of the
Buddha
Buddha 100
of mankind was at 90 the time of the
Buddha 100 at
Buddha 100 at the
of mankind was at 90 the time of the
Buddha 100 at the time
Buddha 100 at the time of
of mankind was at 90 the time of the
Buddha 100 at the time of Christ
Buddha 100 at the time of Christ it
of mankind was at 90 the time of the
Buddha 100 at the time of Christ it went
up
up into
up into the
up into the high
up into the high hundreds
up into the high hundreds 180
up into the high hundreds 180 190
so
so you
up into the high hundreds 180 190
so you see
so you see prayer
up into the high hundreds 180 190
so you see prayer then
so you see prayer then the
up into the high hundreds 180 190
so you see prayer then the collective
intentionality
somehow
somehow has
intentionality
somehow has a
somehow has a collective
intentionality
somehow has a collective the
somehow has a collective the collective
human
human consciousness
human consciousness keeps
human consciousness keeps evolving
One
One of
human consciousness keeps evolving
One of the
One of the most
human consciousness keeps evolving
One of the most surprising
One of the most surprising things
human consciousness keeps evolving
One of the most surprising things we
calibrated
calibrated was
calibrated was the
calibrated was the Ganges
calibrated was the Ganges River.
calibrated was the Ganges River. But
calibrated was the Ganges River. But we
calibrated
calibrated a
calibrated was the Ganges River. But we
calibrated a number
calibrated a number of
calibrated was the Ganges River. But we
calibrated a number of things
calibrated a number of things that
calibrated was the Ganges River. But we
calibrated a number of things that are
surprising.
surprising. Food
surprising. Food before
surprising. Food before you,
surprising. Food before you, if
surprising. Food before you, if you
calibrate
calibrate food
surprising. Food before you, if you
calibrate food before
calibrate food before you
surprising. Food before you, if you
calibrate food before you bless
calibrate food before you bless it
surprising. Food before you, if you
calibrate food before you bless it and
calibrate
calibrate food
calibrate food again
calibrate food again after
calibrate food again after you
calibrate food again after you bless
calibrate food again after you bless it,
it
it jumps
calibrate food again after you bless it,
it jumps way
it jumps way up.
calibrate food again after you bless it,
it jumps way up. Wow.
Biggest
Biggest demonstration
Biggest demonstration of
Biggest demonstration of that
Biggest demonstration of that was
Biggest demonstration of that was when
we
we calibrated
Biggest demonstration of that was when
we calibrated the
we calibrated the Ganges
Biggest demonstration of that was when
we calibrated the Ganges River.
I
I mean,
I mean, you've
I mean, you've been
I mean, you've been in
I mean, you've been in Asia
I mean, you've been in Asia and
I mean, you've been in Asia and any
I mean, you've been in Asia and any of
the
the big
I mean, you've been in Asia and any of
the big rivers,
the big rivers, they
I mean, you've been in Asia and any of
the big rivers, they all
the big rivers, they all look
I mean, you've been in Asia and any of
the big rivers, they all look alike.
Dead
Dead bodies,
Dead bodies, feces,
Dead bodies, feces, garbage.
I
I floated
Dead bodies, feces, garbage.
I floated down
I floated down the
Dead bodies, feces, garbage.
I floated down the Wool
I floated down the Wool River
Dead bodies, feces, garbage.
I floated down the Wool River once.
Anyway,
Anyway, the
Anyway, the Ganges
Anyway, the Ganges River.
Anyway, the Ganges River. That's
Anyway, the Ganges River. That's why
Anyway, the Ganges River. That's why 100
100 cities
100 cities dump
Anyway, the Ganges River. That's why 100
100 cities dump their
100 cities dump their crap
Anyway, the Ganges River. That's why 100
100 cities dump their crap in
100 cities dump their crap in the
Anyway, the Ganges River. That's why 100
100 cities dump their crap in the GI
River.
River. Dead
River. Dead bodies,
River. Dead bodies, feces,
River. Dead bodies, feces, etc.
River. Dead bodies, feces, etc. You
River. Dead bodies, feces, etc. You know
the
the Ganges
River. Dead bodies, feces, etc. You know
the Ganges River?
the Ganges River? That's
River. Dead bodies, feces, etc. You know
the Ganges River? That's what
the Ganges River? That's what they
River. Dead bodies, feces, etc. You know
the Ganges River? That's what they call
it.
it. It's
it. It's over
it. It's over 500.
How
How can
it. It's over 500.
How can the
How can the Ganges
it. It's over 500.
How can the Ganges River
How can the Ganges River full
it. It's over 500.
How can the Ganges River full of
How can the Ganges River full of feces,
dead
dead bodies,
dead bodies, garbage,
the
the sewage
dead bodies, garbage,
the sewage of
the sewage of a
dead bodies, garbage,
the sewage of a 100
the sewage of a 100 cities
dead bodies, garbage,
the sewage of a 100 cities calibrate
over
over 500?
over 500? I
over 500? I forget
over 500? I forget what
over 500? I forget what it
over 500? I forget what it calibrates.
Manges
Manges is
over 500? I forget what it calibrates.
Manges is over
Manges is over 500.
over 500? I forget what it calibrates.
Manges is over 500. Iowa
Manges is over 500. Iowa 5,
over 500? I forget what it calibrates.
Manges is over 500. Iowa 5, 510,
Manges is over 500. Iowa 5, 510, 515,
520.
520. I
520. I forget
520. I forget 15.
The
The combined
520. I forget 15.
The combined intention
The combined intention of
520. I forget 15.
The combined intention of for
The combined intention of for thousands
of
of years
of years of
of years of Hindus
sacred
sacred sanctifying
of years of Hindus
sacred sanctifying by
sacred sanctifying by sanctifying
of years of Hindus
sacred sanctifying by sanctifying the
holy
holy river
the
the Ganges
holy river
the Ganges river
the Ganges river calibrates
holy river
the Ganges river calibrates at
the Ganges river calibrates at 550
there
there is
there is the
there is the power
there is the power of
there is the power of intention
there is the power of intention of
prayer
prayer therefore
there is the power of intention of
prayer therefore to
prayer therefore to sanctify
to
to sanctify
to sanctify by
to sanctify by unconditional
to sanctify by unconditional love.
No.
No. What
to sanctify by unconditional love.
No. What do
No. What do you
to sanctify by unconditional love.
No. What do you say?
No. What do you say? For
to sanctify by unconditional love.
No. What do you say? For thee,
No. What do you say? For thee, oh
to sanctify by unconditional love.
No. What do you say? For thee, oh Lord,
do
do I
do I bless
do I bless this
do I bless this soul.
You
You radiate
do I bless this soul.
You radiate great
You radiate great power.
do I bless this soul.
You radiate great power. Never
underestimate
underestimate the
underestimate the power.
In
In thy
underestimate the power.
In thy name,
In thy name, oh
underestimate the power.
In thy name, oh Lord,
In thy name, oh Lord, do
underestimate the power.
In thy name, oh Lord, do I
In thy name, oh Lord, do I bless
underestimate the power.
In thy name, oh Lord, do I bless this
because
because you're
because you're witnessing
because you're witnessing the
because you're witnessing the truth
because you're witnessing the truth of
the
the sacredness
because you're witnessing the truth of
the sacredness of
the sacredness of all
because you're witnessing the truth of
the sacredness of all creation.
Therefore,
Therefore, you're
Therefore, you're sanctifying
Therefore, you're sanctifying it
by
by divine
Therefore, you're sanctifying it
by divine truth.
Power
Power of
Power of prayer
Power of prayer is
Power of prayer is an
Power of prayer is an expression
Power of prayer is an expression of
attention
attention whereby
Power of prayer is an expression of
attention whereby we
attention whereby we lift
Power of prayer is an expression of
attention whereby we lift all
attention whereby we lift all the
Power of prayer is an expression of
attention whereby we lift all the ships
in
in the
in the sea.
All
All the
in the sea.
All the ships
All the ships in
in the sea.
All the ships in the
All the ships in the sea.
in the sea.
All the ships in the sea. Forget
All the ships in the sea. Forget blame.
It
It will
It will get
It will get you
It will get you nowhere.
It will get you nowhere. We've
It will get you nowhere. We've taken
care
care of
It will get you nowhere. We've taken
care of all
care of all the
It will get you nowhere. We've taken
care of all the blames
care of all the blames and
It will get you nowhere. We've taken
care of all the blames and the
conditions.
conditions. So
conditions. So just
conditions. So just know
conditions. So just know by
conditions. So just know by our
conditions. So just know by our combined
intention,
intention, we
conditions. So just know by our combined
intention, we have
intention, we have enormous
conditions. So just know by our combined
intention, we have enormous power
intention, we have enormous power and
conditions. So just know by our combined
intention, we have enormous power and we
can
can lift
can lift the
can lift the sea.
can lift the sea. So
can lift the sea. So we
can lift the sea. So we will
can lift the sea. So we will all
can lift the sea. So we will all hold
peace
peace in
can lift the sea. So we will all hold
peace in mind.
peace in mind. That's
can lift the sea. So we will all hold
peace in mind. That's what
peace in mind. That's what we
can lift the sea. So we will all hold
peace in mind. That's what we did
peace in mind. That's what we did on
October
October what
October what was
October what was it
October what was it 14th
October what was it 14th in
October what was it 14th in San
Francisco.
I
I say
I say a
I say a group
I say a group like
I say a group like this,
I say a group like this, we
I say a group like this, we calibrated
the
the level
I say a group like this, we calibrated
the level of
the level of mankind
I say a group like this, we calibrated
the level of mankind consciousness
the level of mankind consciousness at
2:05
and
and then
2:05
and then at
and then at 5:15
2:05
and then at 5:15 then
and then at 5:15 then we
2:05
and then at 5:15 then we all
collectively
collectively prayed
collectively prayed and
collectively prayed and chanted
collectively prayed and chanted etc.
collectively prayed and chanted etc. and
at
at 5:35
collectively prayed and chanted etc. and
at 5:35 it
at 5:35 it had a
collectively prayed and chanted etc. and
at 5:35 it had a jump
at 5:35 it had a jump from
collectively prayed and chanted etc. and
at 5:35 it had a jump from 205
at 5:35 it had a jump from 205 207.
Whoa.
Whoa. Huh?
Whoa. Huh? Doesn't
Whoa. Huh? Doesn't sound
Whoa. Huh? Doesn't sound like
Whoa. Huh? Doesn't sound like much.
Whoa. Huh? Doesn't sound like much. Two
points.
points. Two
Whoa. Huh? Doesn't sound like much. Two
points. Two points.
Two
Two points
Two points once
Two points once once
Two points once once you
Two points once once you get
Two points once once you get over
Two points once once you get over 200.
Two
Two points
Two points once once you get over 200.
Two points is
Two points is a
Two points once once you get over 200.
Two points is a lot
Two points is a lot of
Two points once once you get over 200.
Two points is a lot of power,
Two points is a lot of power, a
Two points once once you get over 200.
Two points is a lot of power, a lot
Two points is a lot of power, a lot of
strength.
strength. That
strength. That two
strength. That two points
strength. That two points is
strength. That two points is more
strength. That two points is more power
and
and strength
strength. That two points is more power
and strength than
and strength than any
strength. That two points is more power
and strength than any of
and strength than any of those
strength. That two points is more power
and strength than any of those countries
we
we looked
we looked at
we looked at have
we looked at have within
we looked at have within them
completely.
completely. And
we looked at have within them
completely. And I
completely. And I mean
we looked at have within them
completely. And I mean you
completely. And I mean you have
we looked at have within them
completely. And I mean you have an
amount
amount of
amount of two
amount of two points.
amount of two points. So
amount of two points. So let's
amount of two points. So let's go
amount of two points. So let's go to
amount of two points. So let's go to the
next.
next. So
amount of two points. So let's go to the
next. So that's
next. So that's about
amount of two points. So let's go to the
next. So that's about you
next. So that's about you see
amount of two points. So let's go to the
next. So that's about you see that
that's
that's the
that's the purpose
that's the purpose of
that's the purpose of seeing
that's the purpose of seeing quantum
mechanics.
mechanics. You
that's the purpose of seeing quantum
mechanics. You can
mechanics. You can be
that's the purpose of seeing quantum
mechanics. You can be scientifically
sane
sane and
sane and sensible
sane and sensible and
sane and sensible and pray
sane and sensible and pray for
sane and sensible and pray for things
and
and be
sane and sensible and pray for things
and be scientific.
and be scientific. Why?
sane and sensible and pray for things
and be scientific. Why? Because
and be scientific. Why? Because of
sane and sensible and pray for things
and be scientific. Why? Because of this
equation.
equation. You
equation. You can
equation. You can show
that
that you
equation. You can show
that you have
that you have collapsed
equation. You can show
that you have collapsed the
that you have collapsed the wave
function.
function. You
function. You can
function. You can measure
function. You can measure the
function. You can measure the level
function. You can measure the level of
consciousness
consciousness of
function. You can measure the level of
consciousness of mankind
consciousness of mankind and
function. You can measure the level of
consciousness of mankind and show
consciousness of mankind and show that
it
it has
it has increased.
it has increased. You
it has increased. You can
it has increased. You can be
it has increased. You can be very
scientific
scientific and
it has increased. You can be very
scientific and very
scientific and very spiritual
it has increased. You can be very
scientific and very spiritual at
scientific and very spiritual at the
same
same time
same time and
same time and anybody
same time and anybody who
same time and anybody who doesn't
same time and anybody who doesn't think
so
so is
same time and anybody who doesn't think
so is dumb
doctor.
There
There was
doctor.
There was a
There was a certain
doctor.
There was a certain intellectual
arrogance,
arrogance, you
arrogance, you know,
arrogance, you know, we
arrogance, you know, we had
arrogance, you know, we had when
arrogance, you know, we had when we
arrogance, you know, we had when we were
atheists,
atheists, you
arrogance, you know, we had when we were
atheists, you know,
atheists, you know, that
arrogance, you know, we had when we were
atheists, you know, that we
atheists, you know, that we were
rational
rational and
rational and logical
rational and logical and
rational and logical and we
rational and logical and we were
scientific.
And
And my
And my analyst
And my analyst and
And my analyst and I
And my analyst and I both
And my analyst and I both agreed
And my analyst and I both agreed we
And my analyst and I both agreed we were
logical
logical and
And my analyst and I both agreed we were
logical and scientific
logical and scientific and
And my analyst and I both agreed we were
logical and scientific and and
logical and scientific and and religious
people
people were
people were a
people were a little
people were a little delusional.
people were a little delusional. What
does
does that
people were a little delusional. What
does that say?
does that say? Do
people were a little delusional. What
does that say? Do we
does that say? Do we have
people were a little delusional. What
does that say? Do we have to
does that say? Do we have to stop?
Uhoh.
Uhoh. She
Uhoh. She said
Uhoh. She said we
Uhoh. She said we got
Uhoh. She said we got a
Uhoh. She said we got a snapshot.
Uhoh. She said we got a snapshot. What?
What?
What? What's
Uhoh. She said we got a snapshot. What?
What? What's the
What? What's the next
Uhoh. She said we got a snapshot. What?
What? What's the next slide?
What? What's the next slide? Just
Uhoh. She said we got a snapshot. What?
What? What's the next slide? Just so
What? What's the next slide? Just so we
can
can see.
can see. Oh,
can see. Oh, take
can see. Oh, take it
can see. Oh, take it off
can see. Oh, take it off quickly.
Quickly.
Quickly. That's
can see. Oh, take it off quickly.
Quickly. That's after
Quickly. That's after lunch.
can see. Oh, take it off quickly.
Quickly. That's after lunch. I
Quickly. That's after lunch. I don't
want
want to
want to spoil
want to spoil your
want to spoil your lunch.
All right,
All right, we
want to spoil your lunch.
All right, we got
All right, we got a
want to spoil your lunch.
All right, we got a nice
All right, we got a nice background
want to spoil your lunch.
All right, we got a nice background to
start
start with.
start with. You
start with. You see,
start with. You see, you
start with. You see, you can
start with. You see, you can undo
start with. You see, you can undo the
ego
ego relatively
start with. You see, you can undo the
ego relatively easily
ego relatively easily once
start with. You see, you can undo the
ego relatively easily once you
understand
understand what
understand what it
understand what it is.
understand what it is. And
understand what it is. And you
understand
understand what
understand what it is. And you
understand what it
understand what it is
understand what it is. And you
understand what it is when
understand what it is when you
understand what it is. And you
understand what it is when you see
understand what it is when you see how
it
it evolves.
it evolves. You
it evolves. You stop
it evolves. You stop identifying
it evolves. You stop identifying with
it evolves. You stop identifying with it
as
as me.
it evolves. You stop identifying with it
as me. You
as me. You stop
becoming
becoming marginalized,
becoming marginalized, becoming
oppositionalized
oppositionalized with
becoming marginalized, becoming
oppositionalized with ego.
You
You begin
You begin to
You begin to see
You begin to see what
You begin to see what it
You begin to see what it is.
You begin to see what it is. And
You begin to see what it is. And once
you
you understand
You begin to see what it is. And once
you understand what
you understand what it
You begin to see what it is. And once
you understand what it is,
you understand what it is, you
You begin to see what it is. And once
you understand what it is, you can
you understand what it is, you can begin
to
to dissolve
to dissolve it.
Traditional
Traditional ways
to dissolve it.
Traditional ways of
Traditional ways of overcoming
to dissolve it.
Traditional ways of overcoming the
Traditional ways of overcoming the ego,
frankly,
frankly, I
frankly, I wouldn't
frankly, I wouldn't give
frankly, I wouldn't give you
frankly, I wouldn't give you a
frankly, I wouldn't give you a nickel
for
for it.
If
If they
If they work,
If they work, the
If they work, the place
If they work, the place would
If they work, the place would be
If they work, the place would be folded
like
like the
If they work, the place would be folded
like the masters.
like the masters. You
If they work, the place would be folded
like the masters. You know
like the masters. You know what
If they work, the place would be folded
like the masters. You know what I
like the masters. You know what I mean?
kind
kind of
kind of instructions
kind of instructions mankind
kind of instructions mankind has
kind of instructions mankind has been
following
following not
kind of instructions mankind has been
following not been
following not been too
kind of instructions mankind has been
following not been too fruitful
following not been too fruitful or
kind of instructions mankind has been
following not been too fruitful or we
see
see advanced
see advanced consciousness
see advanced consciousness appearing
with
with commonality
see advanced consciousness appearing
with commonality commonality.
No,
No, it's
No, it's because
No, it's because the
No, it's because the traditional
teachings
teachings have
No, it's because the traditional
teachings have been
directed
directed us
directed us to
directed us to the
directed us to the bottom
directed us to the bottom of
directed us to the bottom of the
directed us to the bottom of the chart
of
of consciousness
directed us to the bottom of the chart
of consciousness instead
of consciousness instead of
directed us to the bottom of the chart
of consciousness instead of how
of consciousness instead of how do
directed us to the bottom of the chart
of consciousness instead of how do you
get
get to
get to the
get to the top?
get to the top? It's
get to the top? It's been
positionalizing
positionalizing us
get to the top? It's been
positionalizing us in
positionalizing us in a
get to the top? It's been
positionalizing us in a dualistic
opposition
opposition of
opposition of our
opposition of our spiritual
opposition of our spiritual self
opposition of our spiritual self versus
our
our ego.
opposition of our spiritual self versus
our ego. It's
our ego. It's our
opposition of our spiritual self versus
our ego. It's our enemy.
And
And once
And once it
And once it becomes
And once it becomes your
And once it becomes your enemy,
And once it becomes your enemy, it's
And once it becomes your enemy, it's got
you.
Once
Once you
Once you make
Once you make the
Once you make the ego
Once you make the ego your
Once you make the ego your enemy
Once you make the ego your enemy and
Once you make the ego your enemy and sin
your
your enemy,
Once you make the ego your enemy and sin
your enemy, it's
your enemy, it's got
Once you make the ego your enemy and sin
your enemy, it's got you.
your enemy, it's got you. It's
Once you make the ego your enemy and sin
your enemy, it's got you. It's got
your enemy, it's got you. It's got you.
Like
Like a
Like a motor
Like a motor dragon,
Like a motor dragon, he's
Like a motor dragon, he's got
Like a motor dragon, he's got his
Like a motor dragon, he's got his teeth
right
right in
Like a motor dragon, he's got his teeth
right in your
right in your ankle
and
and the
and the chances
and the chances of
and the chances of escaping
and the chances of escaping are
and the chances of escaping are slim.
That's
That's why
and the chances of escaping are slim.
That's why we
That's why we have
and the chances of escaping are slim.
That's why we have a
That's why we have a savior
and the chances of escaping are slim.
That's why we have a savior savior
because
because left
because left to
because left to our
because left to our own
because left to our own devices
likelihood
likelihood of
because left to our own devices
likelihood of even
likelihood of even getting
because left to our own devices
likelihood of even getting to
likelihood of even getting to heaven
because left to our own devices
likelihood of even getting to heaven was
slum
Buddha
Buddha who
slum
Buddha who had
Buddha who had no
slum
Buddha who had no previous
Buddha who had no previous human
lifetimes
purpose
purpose of
lifetimes
purpose of the
purpose of the Buddha
lifetimes
purpose of the Buddha is
purpose of the Buddha is to
lifetimes
purpose of the Buddha is to teach
enlightenment
g
g I
enlightenment
g I mean
g I mean did
enlightenment
g I mean did you
g I mean did you got
enlightenment
g I mean did you got it
g I mean did you got it back
the
the Buddha
the Buddha who
the Buddha who had
the Buddha who had many
the Buddha who had many previous
lifetimes
lifetimes came
the Buddha who had many previous
lifetimes came here
lifetimes came here to
the Buddha who had many previous
lifetimes came here to teach
lifetimes came here to teach us
enlightenment
Jesus
Jesus Christ
enlightenment
Jesus Christ we
Jesus Christ we never
enlightenment
Jesus Christ we never had
Jesus Christ we never had any
enlightenment
Jesus Christ we never had any previous
human
human lifetimes
human lifetimes came
human lifetimes came directly
human lifetimes came directly from
human lifetimes came directly from the
celestial
celestial realms
human lifetimes came directly from the
celestial realms of
celestial realms of heaven
human lifetimes came directly from the
celestial realms of heaven directly
celestial realms of heaven directly to
tell
tell us
tell us about
tell us about salvation.
tell us about salvation. Jesus
tell us about salvation. Jesus Christ
never
never had
tell us about salvation. Jesus Christ
never had any
never had any previous
tell us about salvation. Jesus Christ
never had any previous human
incarnations
incarnations exist.
incarnations exist. The
incarnations exist. The Buddha
incarnations exist. The Buddha had
numerous
numerous exist.
incarnations exist. The Buddha had
numerous exist. What
numerous exist. What I
incarnations exist. The Buddha had
numerous exist. What I just
numerous exist. What I just said
incarnations exist. The Buddha had
numerous exist. What I just said is
numerous exist. What I just said is the
truth
truth exist.
truth exist. Okay.
truth exist. Okay. So
truth exist. Okay. So the
truth exist. Okay. So the Buddha
truth exist. Okay. So the Buddha teaches
us
us enlightenment
truth exist. Okay. So the Buddha teaches
us enlightenment pathway
us enlightenment pathway of
truth exist. Okay. So the Buddha teaches
us enlightenment pathway of nonuality.
Jesus
Jesus Christ
Jesus Christ teaches
Jesus Christ teaches us
Jesus Christ teaches us salvation.
Salvation
Salvation is
Jesus Christ teaches us salvation.
Salvation is one
Salvation is one thing
Jesus Christ teaches us salvation.
Salvation is one thing and
Salvation is one thing and blamement
Jesus Christ teaches us salvation.
Salvation is one thing and blamement is
another.
another. Although
another. Although the
another. Although the other
another. Although the other inner
relationship
relationship and
another. Although the other inner
relationship and crossover
relationship and crossover at
another. Although the other inner
relationship and crossover at a
relationship and crossover at a certain
point,
point, I
point, I want
point, I want to
point, I want to make
point, I want to make the
point, I want to make the difference
clear.
clear. The
point, I want to make the difference
clear. The difference
clear. The difference clear.
And
And uh
And uh so
And uh so now
And uh so now we're
And uh so now we're going
And uh so now we're going to
And uh so now we're going to have
And uh so now we're going to have a
break
break for
And uh so now we're going to have a
break for lunch.
break for lunch. 12
And uh so now we're going to have a
break for lunch. 12 to
break for lunch. 12 to 1
And uh so now we're going to have a
break for lunch. 12 to 1 to
>> 12
>> 12 to
>> 12 to 1.
>> 12 to 1. Okay.
>> 12 to 1. Okay. Okay,
>> 12 to 1. Okay. Okay, we
>> 12 to 1. Okay. Okay, we will
>> 12 to 1. Okay. Okay, we will resume
>> 12 to 1. Okay. Okay, we will resume at
1:00.
Now
Now we
Now we have
Now we have to
Now we have to resume.
Now we have to resume. We've
Now we have to resume. We've got
Now we have to resume. We've got 1
Now we have to resume. We've got 1 hour
to
to finish
Now we have to resume. We've got 1 hour
to finish a
to finish a few
Now we have to resume. We've got 1 hour
to finish a few eons
to finish a few eons of
Now we have to resume. We've got 1 hour
to finish a few eons of time,
to finish a few eons of time, which
Now we have to resume. We've got 1 hour
to finish a few eons of time, which will
be
be no
be no problem
be no problem at
be no problem at all.
I
I want
be no problem at all.
I want you
I want you to
be no problem at all.
I want you to understand
I want you to understand the
be no problem at all.
I want you to understand the essential
nature
nature of
nature of the
nature of the ego.
the
the eco.
nature of the ego.
the eco. You
the eco. You see,
nature of the ego.
the eco. You see, when
the eco. You see, when life
nature of the ego.
the eco. You see, when life first
appears
appears on
appears on this
appears on this planet,
this
this hot
appears on this planet,
this hot energy
this hot energy running
appears on this planet,
this hot energy running through
this hot energy running through the
universe
universe for
universe for millennia,
universe for millennia, millennia,
millennia,
millennia, billions
universe for millennia, millennia,
millennia, billions of
millennia, billions of years,
universe for millennia, millennia,
millennia, billions of years, cools
down,
down, becomes
down, becomes liquid.
down, becomes liquid. The
down, becomes liquid. The molten
liquid
liquid that's
down, becomes liquid. The molten
liquid that's still
liquid that's still at
down, becomes liquid. The molten
liquid that's still at the
liquid that's still at the center
down, becomes liquid. The molten
liquid that's still at the center of
liquid that's still at the center of the
earth.
earth. The
earth. The surface
earth. The surface cooled
earth. The surface cooled down.
earth. The surface cooled down. The
crust
crust formed,
the
the conditions
the conditions were
the conditions were okay
the conditions were okay for
the conditions were okay for life
because
because the
the conditions were okay for life
because the level
because the level because
the conditions were okay for life
because the level because consciousness
is
is an
is an infinite
is an infinite field.
is an infinite field. When
is an infinite field. When consciousness
interacts
interacts with
is an infinite field. When consciousness
interacts with matter,
interacts with matter, then
is an infinite field. When consciousness
interacts with matter, then it
interacts with matter, then it spawns
life.
The
The basic
life.
The basic essential
The basic essential then
life.
The basic essential then of
The basic essential then of life
life.
The basic essential then of life to
survive
survive on
survive on let's
survive on let's say
survive on let's say not
survive on let's say not hostile
survive on let's say not hostile but
certainly
certainly not
survive on let's say not hostile but
certainly not friendly
certainly not friendly planet.
survive on let's say not hostile but
certainly not friendly planet. It
certainly not friendly planet. It has
survive on let's say not hostile but
certainly not friendly planet. It has to
be
be oriented
be oriented to
be oriented to survival.
Life
Life does
be oriented to survival.
Life does not
Life does not have
be oriented to survival.
Life does not have within
Life does not have within it
be oriented to survival.
Life does not have within it sufficient
energy
energy for
energy for its
energy for its own
energy for its own survival.
energy for its own survival. It
energy for its own survival. It must
get.
get. The
energy for its own survival. It must
get. The basic
get. The basic law
energy for its own survival. It must
get. The basic law of
get. The basic law of the
energy for its own survival. It must
get. The basic law of the ego
get. The basic law of the ego then
energy for its own survival. It must
get. The basic law of the ego then is
get. The basic law of the ego then is to
get.
The
The amoeba
get.
The amoeba in
The amoeba in order
get.
The amoeba in order to
The amoeba in order to live
get.
The amoeba in order to live has
The amoeba in order to live has to
get.
The amoeba in order to live has to get
energy.
Life
Life has
energy.
Life has to
Life has to get
energy.
Life has to get it
Life has to get it doesn't
energy.
Life has to get it doesn't have
Life has to get it doesn't have within
itself.
itself. Now
itself. Now if
itself. Now if you
itself. Now if you were
itself. Now if you were born
itself. Now if you were born colored
green,
green, you
itself. Now if you were born colored
green, you could
green, you could sit
itself. Now if you were born colored
green, you could sit in
green, you could sit in the
itself. Now if you were born colored
green, you could sit in the sunlight
green, you could sit in the sunlight and
manufacture
manufacture chlorophyll.
manufacture chlorophyll. You
manufacture chlorophyll. You don't
manufacture chlorophyll. You don't have
to
to get
manufacture chlorophyll. You don't have
to get anything.
Unfortunately,
Unfortunately, you're
Unfortunately, you're not
Unfortunately, you're not color
Unfortunately, you're not color green.
You're
You're not
Unfortunately, you're not color green.
You're not filled
You're not filled with
Unfortunately, you're not color green.
You're not filled with chlorophyll.
So
So you're
So you're going
So you're going to
So you're going to always
So you're going to always have
So you're going to always have to
So you're going to always have to get
get
get to
So you're going to always have to get
get to survive.
get to survive. Get
So you're going to always have to get
get to survive. Get your
get to survive. Get your lunch,
So you're going to always have to get
get to survive. Get your lunch, get
get to survive. Get your lunch, get your
money,
money, get
money, get your
money, get your gas.
money, get your gas. All
money, get your gas. All right.
money, get your gas. All right. So
money, get your gas. All right. So the
essential
essential core
money, get your gas. All right. So the
essential core of
essential core of the
money, get your gas. All right. So the
essential core of the ego
essential core of the ego then
money, get your gas. All right. So the
essential core of the ego then instead
of
of being
of being shocked
of being shocked and
of being shocked and being
of being shocked and being moralistic
and
and condemning
of being shocked and being moralistic
and condemning it,
and condemning it, it
of being shocked and being moralistic
and condemning it, it has
and condemning it, it has to
of being shocked and being moralistic
and condemning it, it has to be
concerned
concerned with
concerned with survival.
Unless
Unless it's
concerned with survival.
Unless it's oriented
Unless it's oriented completely
concerned with survival.
Unless it's oriented completely to
survival,
survival, it
survival, it would
survival, it would not
survival, it would not survive.
survival, it would not survive. If
survival, it would not survive. If we
put
put you
survival, it would not survive. If we
put you on
put you on Mars,
survival
survival is
survival is going
survival is going to
survival is going to be
survival is going to be your
survival is going to be your problem.
Everything
Everything has
survival is going to be your problem.
Everything has to
Everything has to be
survival is going to be your problem.
Everything has to be oriented
Everything has to be oriented to
survival.
survival. There's
survival. There's how
survival. There's how this
survival. There's how this So
survival. There's how this So that's
survival. There's how this So that's how
life
life evolved.
You
You see
You see how
You see how old
You see how old it
You see how old it is?
You see how old it is? Oldest
You see how old it is? Oldest data
rocks.
rocks. This
You see how old it is? Oldest data
rocks. This is
rocks. This is so
You see how old it is? Oldest data
rocks. This is so many
rocks. This is so many billions
You see how old it is? Oldest data
rocks. This is so many billions of
years.
years. I
years. I can't
years. I can't even
years. I can't even read
years. I can't even read this
years. I can't even read this number.
Three
Three something
years. I can't even read this number.
Three something earlier.
Three something earlier. Over,300
million
million rock
million rock years
million rock years or
million rock years or whatever
million rock years or whatever they
million rock years or whatever they they
call
call it.
million rock years or whatever they they
call it. 70%
call it. 70% of
million rock years or whatever they they
call it. 70% of time
call it. 70% of time evolved
million rock years or whatever they they
call it. 70% of time evolved at
call it. 70% of time evolved at 75%
million rock years or whatever they they
call it. 70% of time evolved at 75% of
elapsed
elapsed time.
Life
Life only
elapsed time.
Life only calibrates
Life only calibrates at
elapsed time.
Life only calibrates at once.
70%
70% of
70% of archaeologic
70% of archaeologic time
70% of archaeologic time had
70% of archaeologic time had already
passed
passed before
70% of archaeologic time had already
passed before life
passed before life even
70% of archaeologic time had already
passed before life even began
passed before life even began to
70% of archaeologic time had already
passed before life even began to appear.
The
The first
The first one
The first one is
The first one is bacteria
The first one is bacteria calibrates
The first one is bacteria calibrates as
one.
Algae
Algae already
Algae already arrived.
Algae already arrived. But
Algae already arrived. But algae
Algae already arrived. But algae do
Algae already arrived. But algae do not
know
know they
Algae already arrived. But algae do not
know they are.
know they are. They
Algae already arrived. But algae do not
know they are. They do
know they are. They do not
Algae already arrived. But algae do not
know they are. They do not experience
that
that they
that they are.
So
So if
that they are.
So if you're
So if you're color
that they are.
So if you're color green,
So if you're color green, you
that they are.
So if you're color green, you don't
So if you're color green, you don't know
you
you are.
The
The price
you are.
The price of
The price of not
you are.
The price of not being
The price of not being green
you are.
The price of not being green is
The price of not being green is you
you are.
The price of not being green is you know
you
you are
you are therefore
you are therefore you're
you are therefore you're hungry.
You
You need
you are therefore you're hungry.
You need money.
You need money. You
you are therefore you're hungry.
You need money. You need
You need money. You need gas.
you are therefore you're hungry.
You need money. You need gas. You
You need money. You need gas. You need
you
you see
you see the
you see the my
you see the my marine
you see the my marine vertebbrates
calibrate
calibrate at
you see the my marine vertebbrates
calibrate at eight.
As
archaeologic
archaeologic time
you
you see
you see the
you see the scorpions
you see the scorpions arose
you see the scorpions arose out
you see the scorpions arose out of
you see the scorpions arose out of the
sea.
sea. I
you see the scorpions arose out of the
sea. I once
sea. I once read
you see the scorpions arose out of the
sea. I once read a
sea. I once read a book
you see the scorpions arose out of the
sea. I once read a book on
sea. I once read a book on scorpions.
you see the scorpions arose out of the
sea. I once read a book on scorpions. I
was
was a
was a an animologist.
was a an animologist. And
was a an animologist. And um
was a an animologist. And um they
was a an animologist. And um they are
climbed
climbed out
was a an animologist. And um they are
climbed out of
climbed out of the
was a an animologist. And um they are
climbed out of the sea
climbed out of the sea about
was a an animologist. And um they are
climbed out of the sea about 400
climbed out of the sea about 400 million
years
years ago.
years ago. The
years ago. The first
years ago. The first sea
years ago. The first sea calibrated
level
level of
years ago. The first sea calibrated
level of life
level of life is
years ago. The first sea calibrated
level of life is 17.
level of life is 17. Brachopods
years ago. The first sea calibrated
level of life is 17. Brachopods first
amphibians
amphibians snails
amphibians snails primitive
amphibians snails primitive life
calibrates
calibrates to
amphibians snails primitive life
calibrates to say
calibrates to say what
amphibians snails primitive life
calibrates to say what is
calibrates to say what is the
amphibians snails primitive life
calibrates to say what is the energy
calibrates to say what is the energy of
life
life on
life on the
life on the planet
life on the planet at
life on the planet at this
life on the planet at this time
life on the planet at this time is
calibrates
calibrates at
life on the planet at this time is
calibrates at 27.
Shell
Shell cursing
Shell cursing sharks
Shell cursing sharks primitive
Shell cursing sharks primitive ammonites
trilobytes
trilobytes 33.
Shell cursing sharks primitive ammonites
trilobytes 33. Susie
trilobytes 33. Susie gave
Shell cursing sharks primitive ammonites
trilobytes 33. Susie gave me
trilobytes 33. Susie gave me a
Shell cursing sharks primitive ammonites
trilobytes 33. Susie gave me a trillab
bike
bike one
bike one time
bike one time for
bike one time for Christmas
bike one time for Christmas or
bike one time for Christmas or for
bike one time for Christmas or for my
birthday
birthday or
bike one time for Christmas or for my
birthday or something
birthday or something and
bike one time for Christmas or for my
birthday or something and we
birthday or something and we calibrated
it.
it. It's
it. It's about
it. It's about 33
it. It's about 33 35.
Primitive
Primitive uh
it. It's about 33 35.
Primitive uh primitive
Primitive uh primitive insects
it. It's about 33 35.
Primitive uh primitive insects first
reptiles
35.
35. Rise
reptiles
35. Rise of
35. Rise of reptiles.
reptiles
35. Rise of reptiles. Insects
35. Rise of reptiles. Insects many
animal
animal groups
animal groups begin
animal groups begin to
animal groups begin to appear.
animal groups begin to appear. Calibrate
level
level 45.
The
The rise
The rise of
The rise of dinosaurs
The rise of dinosaurs around
The rise of dinosaurs around 60.
Dinosaurs.
Dinosaurs. This
The rise of dinosaurs around 60.
Dinosaurs. This is
Dinosaurs. This is the
The rise of dinosaurs around 60.
Dinosaurs. This is the commotive
Dinosaurs. This is the commotive dragon
here
here by
here by 40.
You
You realize
here by 40.
You realize a
You realize a great
here by 40.
You realize a great many
You realize a great many of
here by 40.
You realize a great many of the
You realize a great many of the people
in
in the
in the world's
in the world's headlines
in the world's headlines calibrate
exactly
exactly here
exactly there.
So
So we
So we tell
So we tell our
politicians
politicians speak
So we tell our
politicians speak nicely
politicians speak nicely to
So we tell our
politicians speak nicely to them.
speak
speak nicely
speak nicely to
speak nicely to the
speak nicely to the komodo
speak nicely to the komodo dragon.
Motor
Motor dragon
speak nicely to the komodo dragon.
Motor dragon says,
Motor dragon says, "Come
speak nicely to the komodo dragon.
Motor dragon says, "Come on
Motor dragon says, "Come on in
speak nicely to the komodo dragon.
Motor dragon says, "Come on in and
Motor dragon says, "Come on in and talk
to
to me."
That
That was
to me."
That was Hitler
That was Hitler and
to me."
That was Hitler and the
That was Hitler and the idiot.
And
And they
And they signed
And they signed the
And they signed the peace
And they signed the peace truck,
And they signed the peace truck, you
know.
know. Yeah.
And they signed the peace truck, you
know. Yeah. Sign
know. Yeah. Sign the
And they signed the peace truck, you
know. Yeah. Sign the peace
know. Yeah. Sign the peace peace
And they signed the peace truck, you
know. Yeah. Sign the peace peace in
know. Yeah. Sign the peace peace in our
time.
time. You're
time. You're right.
time. You're right. The
time. You're right. The minute
time. You're right. The minute he
time. You're right. The minute he turned
around,
around, Hitler
time. You're right. The minute he turned
around, Hitler thought,
around, Hitler thought, "What
time. You're right. The minute he turned
around, Hitler thought, "What a
around, Hitler thought, "What a stupid
idiot."
That's
That's a
idiot."
That's a fact.
That's a fact. That's
idiot."
That's a fact. That's a
That's a fact. That's a fact.
idiot."
That's a fact. That's a fact. What
That's a fact. That's a fact. What a
stupid
stupid idiot.
Come
Come on.
stupid idiot.
Come on. Dragon
Come on. Dragon says
stupid idiot.
Come on. Dragon says anybody
Come on. Dragon says anybody that
stupid idiot.
Come on. Dragon says anybody that thinks
I'm
I'm going
I'm going to
I'm going to keep
I'm going to keep a
I'm going to keep a contract
I'm going to keep a contract is
I'm going to keep a contract is really
got
got to
I'm going to keep a contract is really
got to be
got to be dumb.
See,
See, you're
See, you're responsible
See, you're responsible for
See, you're responsible for your
dumbness.
People
People go
People go out
People go out around,
People go out around, oh,
People go out around, oh, they're
People go out around, oh, they're so
innocent,
innocent, they
People go out around, oh, they're so
innocent, they put
innocent, they put blame
People go out around, oh, they're so
innocent, they put blame out
innocent, they put blame out there.
People go out around, oh, they're so
innocent, they put blame out there. You
know,
know, you're
know, you're currently
know, you're currently responsible
know, you're currently responsible for
your
your stupidity.
Own
Own that.
Own that. Own
Own that. Own that
Own that. Own that stupidity.
That's
That's right.
Own that. Own that stupidity.
That's right. That
That's right. That way,
Own that. Own that stupidity.
That's right. That way, you
That's right. That way, you won't
Own that. Own that stupidity.
That's right. That way, you won't be
blindsided.
You
You live
blindsided.
You live in
You live in a
blindsided.
You live in a world
You live in a world where
blindsided.
You live in a world where people
calibrate
calibrate here.
The
The rise
calibrate here.
The rise of
The rise of dinosaurs
calibrate here.
The rise of dinosaurs of
The rise of dinosaurs of 60s,
calibrate here.
The rise of dinosaurs of 60s, first
birds,
birds, first
birds, first mammals.
Life
Life is
birds, first mammals.
Life is up
Life is up to
birds, first mammals.
Life is up to 68.
Primals,
Primals, the
Primals, the last
Primals, the last of
Primals, the last of the
Primals, the last of the dinosaurs,
Primals, the last of the dinosaurs, 84.
Rapid
Rapid development
Primals, the last of the dinosaurs, 84.
Rapid development of
Rapid development of modern
Primals, the last of the dinosaurs, 84.
Rapid development of modern animals.
112.
Here
Here you
112.
Here you see
Here you see the
112.
Here you see the do
Here you see the do domestic
112.
Here you see the do domestic animals
Here you see the do domestic animals and
rise
rise of
rise of dominance
rise of dominance of
rise of dominance of man
rise of dominance of man is
rise of dominance of man is in
rise of dominance of man is in the
rise of dominance of man is in the last
eyelid
eyelid flick
rise of dominance of man is in the last
eyelid flick of
eyelid flick of time.
rise of dominance of man is in the last
eyelid flick of time. Let's
eyelid flick of time. Let's move
rise of dominance of man is in the last
eyelid flick of time. Let's move on.
That's
That's how
That's how the
That's how the ego
That's how the ego arose.
That's how the ego arose. The
That's how the ego arose. The ego
That's how the ego arose. The ego then
is
is the
That's how the ego arose. The ego then
is the instinct
is the instinct of
That's how the ego arose. The ego then
is the instinct of self-preservation
is the instinct of self-preservation and
survival
survival and
survival and it's
survival and it's based
survival and it's based on
survival and it's based on me
survival and it's based on me and
getting
getting this
survival and it's based on me and
getting this and
getting this and that's
survival and it's based on me and
getting this and that's called
egoentricity.
Okay.
Okay. How
egoentricity.
Okay. How how
Okay. How how does
egoentricity.
Okay. How how does it
Okay. How how does it arise
egoentricity.
Okay. How how does it arise in
Okay. How how does it arise in the
animal
animal kingdom?
animal kingdom? We
animal kingdom? We said
animal kingdom? We said to
animal kingdom? We said to start
animal kingdom? We said to start out
animal kingdom? We said to start out at
one,
one, the
animal kingdom? We said to start out at
one, the bacteria,
one, the bacteria, protozoa,
animal kingdom? We said to start out at
one, the bacteria, protozoa, arachnids,
fish.
fish. Here's
fish. Here's our
fish. Here's our friend,
fish. Here's our friend, the
fish. Here's our friend, the komodo
dragon,
reptiles,
reptiles, predatory
reptiles, predatory mammals.
reptiles, predatory mammals. Now,
reptiles, predatory mammals. Now, you
see
see from
reptiles, predatory mammals. Now, you
see from the
see from the spiritual
reptiles, predatory mammals. Now, you
see from the spiritual humanistic
viewpoint,
viewpoint, we
viewpoint, we think
viewpoint, we think that
viewpoint, we think that these
viewpoint, we think that these are
viewpoint, we think that these are pred
we
we call
viewpoint, we think that these are pred
we call them
we call them predatory
viewpoint, we think that these are pred
we call them predatory because
we call them predatory because they
viewpoint, we think that these are pred
we call them predatory because they in
order
order to
order to get
order to get their
order to get their lunch
order to get their lunch to
order to get their lunch to stand
order to get their lunch to stand still,
they
they have
order to get their lunch to stand still,
they have to
they have to crunch
order to get their lunch to stand still,
they have to crunch it.
If
If you
If you were
If you were a
If you were a lion,
If you were a lion, every
If you were a lion, every time
If you were a lion, every time you
If you were a lion, every time you go
If you were a lion, every time you go to
eat
eat lunch,
If you were a lion, every time you go to
eat lunch, it
eat lunch, it runs
If you were a lion, every time you go to
eat lunch, it runs across
eat lunch, it runs across the
If you were a lion, every time you go to
eat lunch, it runs across the field.
Are
Are you
Are you a
Are you a whole
Are you a whole still
Are you a whole still on
Are you a whole still on it?
It
It It
Are you a whole still on it?
It It does
It It does that
Are you a whole still on it?
It It does that in
It It does that in order
Are you a whole still on it?
It It does that in order to
It It does that in order to have
Are you a whole still on it?
It It does that in order to have its
lunch.
lunch. It
lunch. It does
lunch. It does not
lunch. It does not wish
lunch. It does not wish to
lunch. It does not wish to kill.
It
It does
lunch. It does not wish to kill.
It does not
It does not wish
lunch. It does not wish to kill.
It does not wish to
It does not wish to kill.
lunch. It does not wish to kill.
It does not wish to kill. That
It does not wish to kill. That is
correct.
correct. Does
correct. Does not
correct. Does not wish
correct. Does not wish to
correct. Does not wish to kill.
correct. Does not wish to kill. Has
correct. Does not wish to kill. Has no
intention.
intention. Has
correct. Does not wish to kill. Has no
intention. Has no
intention. Has no conception
correct. Does not wish to kill. Has no
intention. Has no conception of
intention. Has no conception of killing.
It
It eats
It eats its
It eats its lunch.
It eats its lunch. This
It eats its lunch. This warm
cheeseburger
cheeseburger is
It eats its lunch. This warm
cheeseburger is running.
cheeseburger is running. did
It eats its lunch. This warm
cheeseburger is running. did it
cheeseburger is running. did it and
It eats its lunch. This warm
cheeseburger is running. did it and it
stands
stands still.
stands still. Now
stands still. Now you
stands still. Now you can
stands still. Now you can eat
stands still. Now you can eat the
stands still. Now you can eat the thing.
If
If your
stands still. Now you can eat the thing.
If your cheeseburger
If your cheeseburger ran
stands still. Now you can eat the thing.
If your cheeseburger ran away
If your cheeseburger ran away from
stands still. Now you can eat the thing.
If your cheeseburger ran away from you
all
all the
all the time,
all the time, you
all the time, you figure
all the time, you figure the
all the time, you figure the bastard.
We
We don't
all the time, you figure the bastard.
We don't have
We don't have to
all the time, you figure the bastard.
We don't have to chase
We don't have to chase our
all the time, you figure the bastard.
We don't have to chase our cheeseburger.
Somebody
Somebody else
Somebody else chased
Somebody else chased it.
>> Then
>> Then you
Somebody else chased it.
>> Then you got
>> Then you got the
Somebody else chased it.
>> Then you got the snakes,
>> Then you got the snakes, the
Somebody else chased it.
>> Then you got the snakes, the alligators.
Here
Here you
Here you got
Here you got dinosaurs.
the
the instincts
Here you got dinosaurs.
the instincts of
the instincts of a
Here you got dinosaurs.
the instincts of a dinosaur.
Uh,
Uh, whales
Uh, whales and
Uh, whales and dolphins,
Uh, whales and dolphins, migratory
birds,
birds, rodents,
Uh, whales and dolphins, migratory
birds, rodents, rhinoceros,
doves,
doves, grizzly
doves, grizzly bear,
doves, grizzly bear, polar
doves, grizzly bear, polar bear,
doves, grizzly bear, polar bear, water
buffalo,
jackals,
jackals, and
jackals, and toxins,
jackals, and toxins, wolves.
jackals, and toxins, wolves. We're
jackals, and toxins, wolves. We're still
below
below 200.
jackals, and toxins, wolves. We're still
below 200. You
below 200. You see,
jackals, and toxins, wolves. We're still
below 200. You see, hippopotamus
actually
actually kills
actually kills more
actually kills more people
actually kills more people than
actually kills more people than any
other
other wild
actually kills more people than any
other wild animal.
other wild animal. Uh,
actually kills more people than any
other wild animal. Uh, and
other wild animal. Uh, and then
actually kills more people than any
other wild animal. Uh, and then suddenly
at
at 200,
at 200, just
at 200, just on
at 200, just on the
at 200, just on the scale
at 200, just on the scale of
consciousness,
consciousness, we
at 200, just on the scale of
consciousness, we saw
consciousness, we saw a
at 200, just on the scale of
consciousness, we saw a change
consciousness, we saw a change of
quality.
quality. At
quality. At 200
quality. At 200 there's
quality. At 200 there's a
quality. At 200 there's a change
quality. At 200 there's a change of
quality
from
from rapacious
from rapacious and
from rapacious and injurious
from rapacious and injurious to
from rapacious and injurious to others
to
to consider.
from rapacious and injurious to others
to consider. You
to consider. You see
from rapacious and injurious to others
to consider. You see a
to consider. You see a shift
from rapacious and injurious to others
to consider. You see a shift to
to consider. You see a shift to the
benign.
benign. You
benign. You see
benign. You see exactly
benign. You see exactly the
benign. You see exactly the same
benign. You see exactly the same shift
of
of consciousness
benign. You see exactly the same shift
of consciousness in
of consciousness in the
benign. You see exactly the same shift
of consciousness in the animal
of consciousness in the animal kingdom.
You
You go
You go from
You go from the
You go from the rapacious
You go from the rapacious it
You go from the rapacious it lives
You go from the rapacious it lives by
the
the death
You go from the rapacious it lives by
the death of
the death of others
You go from the rapacious it lives by
the death of others to
the death of others to the
You go from the rapacious it lives by
the death of others to the peaceful
herbivore.
At
At 200
herbivore.
At 200 you
At 200 you see
herbivore.
At 200 you see the
At 200 you see the sheep,
herbivore.
At 200 you see the sheep, the
At 200 you see the sheep, the deer,
dairy
dairy cow,
dairy cow, range
dairy cow, range cattle,
dairy cow, range cattle, elephants,
dairy cow, range cattle, elephants, the
farm
farm horse.
You
You see
You see a
You see a shift
You see a shift from
You see a shift from below
You see a shift from below 200
You see a shift from below 200 is
dangerous
dangerous and
You see a shift from below 200 is
dangerous and rapacious,
not
not aligned
not aligned with
not aligned with integrity.
not aligned with integrity. Over
not aligned with integrity. Over 200
not aligned with integrity. Over 200 now
becomes
becomes peaceful.
not aligned with integrity. Over 200 now
becomes peaceful. And
becomes peaceful. And this
not aligned with integrity. Over 200 now
becomes peaceful. And this is
becomes peaceful. And this is when
not aligned with integrity. Over 200 now
becomes peaceful. And this is when you
grew
grew up
grew up in
grew up in the
grew up in the Midwest.
I
I grew
grew up in the Midwest.
I grew up
I grew up in
grew up in the Midwest.
I grew up in the
I grew up in the Midwest
at
at the
at the beginning
at the beginning of
at the beginning of the
at the beginning of the last
at the beginning of the last century
at the beginning of the last century and
during
during the
at the beginning of the last century and
during the depression
there
there were
there were two
there were two kinds
there were two kinds of
there were two kinds of people
there were two kinds of people in
there were two kinds of people in the
world.
world. They
there were two kinds of people in the
world. They were
world. They were honest,
there were two kinds of people in the
world. They were honest, integrous,
hardworking,
hardworking, thrifty
hardworking, thrifty people
hardworking, thrifty people who
hardworking, thrifty people who were
polite
polite and
hardworking, thrifty people who were
polite and considerate
polite and considerate of
hardworking, thrifty people who were
polite and considerate of others.
polite and considerate of others. And
then
then there
then there were
then there were criminals.
Nothing
Nothing in
then there were criminals.
Nothing in between.
Nothing in between. There
then there were criminals.
Nothing in between. There was
Nothing in between. There was babyface
Nelson,
Nelson, Machine
Nelson, Machine Gun
Nelson, Machine Gun Kelly,
Nelson, Machine Gun Kelly, Gun
Dillinger.
And
And then
And then there
And then there were
And then there were normal
And then there were normal folks.
And then there were normal folks. That's
all
all there
And then there were normal folks. That's
all there was.
Oh,
Oh, what
Oh, what a
Oh, what a shot.
See
See cats
Oh, what a shot.
See cats at
See cats at 240.
Oh, what a shot.
See cats at 240. The
See cats at 240. The thing
Oh, what a shot.
See cats at 240. The thing about
See cats at 240. The thing about uh
domestic
domestic animals
domestic animals is
domestic animals is when
domestic animals is when they're
domestic animals is when they're around
humans,
humans, their
domestic animals is when they're around
humans, their calibrated
humans, their calibrated level
domestic animals is when they're around
humans, their calibrated level of
consciousness
consciousness jumps
consciousness jumps another
consciousness jumps another five
consciousness jumps another five point.
You
You buy
consciousness jumps another five point.
You buy a
You buy a horse,
consciousness jumps another five point.
You buy a horse, he
You buy a horse, he calibrates
consciousness jumps another five point.
You buy a horse, he calibrates at
where's
where's horse?
where's horse? Horse
where's horse? Horse is
where's horse? Horse is a
where's horse? Horse is a 240,
where's horse? Horse is a 240, but
where's horse? Horse is a 240, but when
you
you train
where's horse? Horse is a 240, but when
you train the
you train the horse,
where's horse? Horse is a 240, but when
you train the horse, he
you train the horse, he now
where's horse? Horse is a 240, but when
you train the horse, he now becomes
you train the horse, he now becomes 245.
Same
Same with
Same with a
Same with a dog
Same with a dog or
Same with a dog or a
Same with a dog or a cat.
Same with a dog or a cat. They're
adopted
adopted by
Same with a dog or a cat. They're
adopted by a
adopted by a human.
Same with a dog or a cat. They're
adopted by a human. their
adopted by a human. their consciousness
runs
runs up
runs up another
runs up another five
runs up another five points.
Um,
Um, so
runs up another five points.
Um, so the
Um, so the dog
runs up another five points.
Um, so the dog actually
Um, so the dog actually is
runs up another five points.
Um, so the dog actually is at
Um, so the dog actually is at 245.
runs up another five points.
Um, so the dog actually is at 245. The
family
family dog
family dog is
family dog is at
family dog is at 250.
family dog is at 250. Get
family dog is at 250. Get monkeys,
family dog is at 250. Get monkeys, you
get
get real gorillas.
family dog is at 250. Get monkeys, you
get real gorillas. Now
get real gorillas. Now we
family dog is at 250. Get monkeys, you
get real gorillas. Now we come
get real gorillas. Now we come to
family dog is at 250. Get monkeys, you
get real gorillas. Now we come to some
exceptions
exceptions and
exceptions and they're
exceptions and they're quite
interesting.
interesting. You
exceptions and they're quite
interesting. You get
interesting. You get Alex
exceptions and they're quite
interesting. You get Alex the
interesting. You get Alex the African
gray
gray parrot
gray parrot who's
gray parrot who's on
gray parrot who's on the
gray parrot who's on the internet
trained
trained at
gray parrot who's on the internet
trained at the
trained at the University
gray parrot who's on the internet
trained at the University of
trained at the University of Arizona
gray parrot who's on the internet
trained at the University of Arizona in
Tucson
Tucson by
Tucson by I
Tucson by I think
Tucson by I think by
Tucson by I think by Dr.
Tucson by I think by Dr. Pepperdine.
Alex
Alex knows
Tucson by I think by Dr. Pepperdine.
Alex knows and
Alex knows and I
Tucson by I think by Dr. Pepperdine.
Alex knows and I forget
Alex knows and I forget 600
Tucson by I think by Dr. Pepperdine.
Alex knows and I forget 600 words.
Alex knows and I forget 600 words. Alex
can
can actually
can actually think
can actually think Alex
can actually think Alex can
can actually think Alex can go
can actually think Alex can go puts
together
together subject
can actually think Alex can go puts
together subject and
together subject and predicate.
Subject
Subject and
Subject and predicate
just
just as
Subject and predicate
just as Koko
just as Koko does.
Subject and predicate
just as Koko does. The
just as Koko does. The argument
Subject and predicate
just as Koko does. The argument is
just as Koko does. The argument is can
they
they think?
they think? Well,
they think? Well, we
they think? Well, we don't
they think? Well, we don't know
they think? Well, we don't know if
they think? Well, we don't know if they
can
can think.
they think? Well, we don't know if they
can think. We
can think. We presume
they think? Well, we don't know if they
can think. We presume they
can think. We presume they can
they think? Well, we don't know if they
can think. We presume they can or
can think. We presume they can or they
can't
can't depending
can't depending on
can't depending on your
can't depending on your argument.
can't depending on your argument. If
can't depending on your argument. If we
calibrate
calibrate them,
can't depending on your argument. If we
calibrate them, you
calibrate them, you find
can't depending on your argument. If we
calibrate them, you find Alex
calibrate them, you find Alex calibrates
at
at 401.
Coco
Coco calibrates
at 401.
Coco calibrates at
Coco calibrates at 405.
So
So if
So if we
So if we just
So if we just use
So if we just use calibration.
So if we just use calibration. Yes,
So if we just use calibration. Yes, Koko
does
does think.
Think
Think he
Think he knows
Think he knows the
Think he knows the difference
Think he knows the difference between
Think he knows the difference between me
and
and you.
Koko
Koko knows
Koko knows subjective
knows
knows predicate
Koko knows subjective
knows predicate and
knows predicate and verb.
Koko knows subjective
knows predicate and verb. Can
knows predicate and verb. Can put
together
together the
together the struct
together the struct basic
together the struct basic structure
together the struct basic structure of
together the struct basic structure of a
sentence
and
and we
and we trained
and we trained him
and we trained him to
and we trained him to what
and we trained him to what we
and we trained him to what we try
and we trained him to what we try to
transcend.
transcend. We
and we trained him to what we try to
transcend. We train
transcend. We train him
and we trained him to what we try to
transcend. We train him to
transcend. We train him to do
and we trained him to what we try to
transcend. We train him to do which
transcend. We train him to do which is
dualistic
dualistic thinking.
Me
Me get
dualistic thinking.
Me get that.
Me get that. Oh
dualistic thinking.
Me get that. Oh the
Me get that. Oh the subject
dualistic thinking.
Me get that. Oh the subject predicate
verb.
verb. Wow.
verb. Wow. That's
verb. Wow. That's called
verb. Wow. That's called thinkingness.
Okay.
Songb
Songb bird
Songb bird song
Songb bird song is
Songb bird song is sort
Songb bird song is sort of
Songb bird song is sort of unique.
Songb bird song is sort of unique. It
calibrates
calibrates at
Songb bird song is sort of unique. It
calibrates at 500.
The
The cat's
The cat's purr
The cat's purr and
The cat's purr and the
The cat's purr and the dogs
The cat's purr and the dogs the
The cat's purr and the dogs the cat's
purr
purr mysteriously
The cat's purr and the dogs the cat's
purr mysteriously calibrates
purr mysteriously calibrates at
The cat's purr and the dogs the cat's
purr mysteriously calibrates at 500.
purr mysteriously calibrates at 500. The
dog's
dog's wagging
dog's wagging tail
dog's wagging tail mysteriously
calibrates
calibrates at
dog's wagging tail mysteriously
calibrates at 500,
calibrates at 500, which
dog's wagging tail mysteriously
calibrates at 500, which is
calibrates at 500, which is the
dog's wagging tail mysteriously
calibrates at 500, which is the level
calibrates at 500, which is the level of
love.
Oh,
Oh, how
love.
Oh, how does
Oh, how does that
love.
Oh, how does that be?
Oh, how does that be? Something
peculiar.
peculiar. here
peculiar. here in
peculiar. here in evolution
that
that we
peculiar. here in evolution
that we have
that we have a
peculiar. here in evolution
that we have a new
that we have a new Alex
peculiar. here in evolution
that we have a new Alex at
that we have a new Alex at home.
peculiar. here in evolution
that we have a new Alex at home. We
that we have a new Alex at home. We have
a
a new
a new train
a new train for
a new train for my
a new train for my birthday.
a new train for my birthday. I
a new train for my birthday. I got
a new train for my birthday. I got a
train
train for
a new train for my birthday. I got a
train for Father's
train for Father's Day
a new train for my birthday. I got a
train for Father's Day for
train for Father's Day for some
a new train for my birthday. I got a
train for Father's Day for some event
some
some recent
some recent event.
some recent event. Anyway,
some recent event. Anyway, somebody
gives
gives us
some recent event. Anyway, somebody
gives us a
gives us a present
some recent event. Anyway, somebody
gives us a present an
gives us a present an African
some recent event. Anyway, somebody
gives us a present an African gray
carrot
carrot who
carrot who we
carrot who we named
carrot who we named broccoli.
We
We haven't
carrot who we named broccoli.
We haven't had
We haven't had broccoli
carrot who we named broccoli.
We haven't had broccoli in
We haven't had broccoli in more
carrot who we named broccoli.
We haven't had broccoli in more than
We haven't had broccoli in more than a
week
week or
week or so.
week or so. Broccoli
week or so. Broccoli calibrates
week or so. Broccoli calibrates at
week or so. Broccoli calibrates at 385.
Poor
Poor broccoli
week or so. Broccoli calibrates at 385.
Poor broccoli needs
Poor broccoli needs help
week or so. Broccoli calibrates at 385.
Poor broccoli needs help and
Poor broccoli needs help and love.
week or so. Broccoli calibrates at 385.
Poor broccoli needs help and love. So,
we're
we're going
we're going to
we're going to try
we're going to try and
we're going to try and help
we're going to try and help broccoli
evolve.
And
And we
And we say,
And we say, "Now
And we say, "Now listen,
And we say, "Now listen, Alex
And we say, "Now listen, Alex can
And we say, "Now listen, Alex can do
that.
that. How
And we say, "Now listen, Alex can do
that. How about
that. How about you?
Alex
Alex can
Alex can do
Alex can do that.
Alex can do that. Alex
Alex can do that. Alex can
Alex can do that. Alex can spell
the
the dog."
Alex can do that. Alex can spell
the dog." So
the dog." So the
Alex can do that. Alex can spell
the dog." So the dog's
the dog." So the dog's wagging
Alex can do that. Alex can spell
the dog." So the dog's wagging tail,
unconditional
unconditional love,
and
and we
unconditional love,
and we were
and we were up
unconditional love,
and we were up in
and we were up in in
unconditional love,
and we were up in in the
and we were up in in the country.
unconditional love,
and we were up in in the country. This
dog
dog came
dog came over,
dog came over, complete
dog came over, complete stranger,
completely
completely trusting
dog came over, complete stranger,
completely trusting and
completely trusting and loving.
dog came over, complete stranger,
completely trusting and loving. He
completely trusting and loving. He said,
"Wow,
"Wow, that's
"Wow, that's unconditional
"Wow, that's unconditional love."
"Wow, that's unconditional love." We
calibrated
calibrated his
"Wow, that's unconditional love." We
calibrated his wagon
calibrated his wagon tail
"Wow, that's unconditional love." We
calibrated his wagon tail 500.
calibrated his wagon tail 500. Wow,
that's
that's very
that's very interesting.
that's very interesting. You
that's very interesting. You saw
that's very interesting. You saw on
yesterday's
yesterday's newspaper,
that's very interesting. You saw on
yesterday's newspaper, the
yesterday's newspaper, the front
that's very interesting. You saw on
yesterday's newspaper, the front page,
the
the mad
the mad killer,
>> we
>> we had
the mad killer,
>> we had 6,000
>> we had 6,000 rounds
the mad killer,
>> we had 6,000 rounds of
>> we had 6,000 rounds of ammunition.
Everybody
Everybody know
Everybody know that
Everybody know that story?
Everybody know that story? Anybody
Everybody know that story? Anybody not
know
know it?
Everybody know that story? Anybody not
know it? On
know it? On the
Everybody know that story? Anybody not
know it? On the front
know it? On the front page
Everybody know that story? Anybody not
know it? On the front page is
know it? On the front page is bigger.
Got
Got the
Got the picture
Got the picture in
Got the picture in anyway.
Got the picture in anyway. Yeah,
Got the picture in anyway. Yeah, all
kinds
kinds of
Got the picture in anyway. Yeah, all
kinds of rifles,
kinds of rifles, guns,
Got the picture in anyway. Yeah, all
kinds of rifles, guns, shotguns,
apparently
apparently mentally
apparently mentally ill.
apparently mentally ill. He
apparently mentally ill. He was
apparently mentally ill. He was going
apparently mentally ill. He was going to
kill
kill as
apparently mentally ill. He was going to
kill as many
kill as many people
apparently mentally ill. He was going to
kill as many people as
kill as many people as possible.
apparently mentally ill. He was going to
kill as many people as possible. He
kill as many people as possible. He had
6,000
6,000 rounds
6,000 rounds of
6,000 rounds of infant
6,000 rounds of infant of
6,000 rounds of infant of uh
6,000 rounds of infant of uh uh
ammunition.
And
And the
And the pictures
And the pictures on
And the pictures on yesterday's
And the pictures on yesterday's shows
his
his dog
And the pictures on yesterday's shows
his dog and
his dog and he's
And the pictures on yesterday's shows
his dog and he's got
his dog and he's got a
And the pictures on yesterday's shows
his dog and he's got a one
his dog and he's got a one of
And the pictures on yesterday's shows
his dog and he's got a one of those
round
round things.
>> Frisbee.
>> Frisbee. There's
>> Frisbee. There's the
>> Frisbee. There's the dog.
>> Frisbee. There's the dog. Anyway,
>> Frisbee. There's the dog. Anyway, this
guy's
guy's about
>> Frisbee. There's the dog. Anyway, this
guy's about to
guy's about to mow
>> Frisbee. There's the dog. Anyway, this
guy's about to mow down
guy's about to mow down people.
>> Frisbee. There's the dog. Anyway, this
guy's about to mow down people. The
guy's about to mow down people. The dog
comes
comes up
comes up to
comes up to him
comes up to him and
comes up to him and look
comes up to him and look at
comes up to him and look at the
comes up to him and look at the power
comes up to him and look at the power of
the
the dog's
comes up to him and look at the power of
the dog's heart.
the dog's heart. The
comes up to him and look at the power of
the dog's heart. The dog's
the dog's heart. The dog's heart
comes up to him and look at the power of
the dog's heart. The dog's heart totally
changed
changed this
changed this man.
changed this man. And
changed this man. And instead
changed this man. And instead of
massacring
massacring a
changed this man. And instead of
massacring a bunch
massacring a bunch of
changed this man. And instead of
massacring a bunch of people
massacring a bunch of people and
changed this man. And instead of
massacring a bunch of people and then
committing
committing suicide,
committing suicide, the
committing suicide, the dog
committing suicide, the dog came
committing suicide, the dog came up
committing suicide, the dog came up to
him
him and
committing suicide, the dog came up to
him and he
him and he gave
committing suicide, the dog came up to
him and he gave up
him and he gave up and
committing suicide, the dog came up to
him and he gave up and totally
surrendered
surrendered to
surrendered to the
surrendered to the whole
surrendered to the whole thing.
surrendered to the whole thing. And
surrendered to the whole thing. And I
mean,
mean, miraculous,
miraculous.
miraculous. So
miraculous. So what
miraculous. So what happened
miraculous. So what happened was
miraculous. So what happened was the
dog's
dog's 500
miraculous. So what happened was the
dog's 500 energy
dog's 500 energy interacted
miraculous. So what happened was the
dog's 500 energy interacted with
dog's 500 energy interacted with the
miraculous. So what happened was the
dog's 500 energy interacted with the man
and
and in
and in the
and in the presence
and in the presence of
and in the presence of 500
and in the presence of 500 energy
and in the presence of 500 energy he
suddenly
suddenly became
and in the presence of 500 energy he
suddenly became insane
suddenly became insane again.
and in the presence of 500 energy he
suddenly became insane again. What
suddenly became insane again. What am
and in the presence of 500 energy he
suddenly became insane again. What am I
doing?
He's
He's now
doing?
He's now getting
He's now getting professional
doing?
He's now getting professional help.
He's now getting professional help. But
I
I thought
I thought that
I thought that was
I thought that was very
I thought that was very interesting.
I thought that was very interesting. It
was
was it
I thought that was very interesting. It
was it was
was it was really
I thought that was very interesting. It
was it was really a
was it was really a demonstration
I thought that was very interesting. It
was it was really a demonstration of
was it was really a demonstration of the
500.
500. We
500. We never
500. We never asked
500. We never asked any
500. We never asked any question
500. We never asked any question about
this.
It
It was
It was due
It was due to
It was due to the
It was due to the dog's
It was due to the dog's 500
It was due to the dog's 500 energy
It was due to the dog's 500 energy that
the
the man
It was due to the dog's 500 energy that
the man changed
the man changed his
It was due to the dog's 500 energy that
the man changed his whole
the man changed his whole idea.
It was due to the dog's 500 energy that
the man changed his whole idea. He
the man changed his whole idea. He just
Yes.
Yes. The
Yes. The interaction.
Yes. The interaction. Suddenly
Yes. The interaction. Suddenly he
Yes. The interaction. Suddenly he had
Yes. The interaction. Suddenly he had a
500 energy
500 energy and
Yes. The interaction. Suddenly he had a
500 energy and he
500 energy and he says,
Yes. The interaction. Suddenly he had a
500 energy and he says, "Good
500 energy and he says, "Good God,
Yes. The interaction. Suddenly he had a
500 energy and he says, "Good God, run
my
my 200."
Isn't
Isn't that
my 200."
Isn't that wonderful?
Isn't that wonderful? What
my 200."
Isn't that wonderful? What a
Isn't that wonderful? What a story.
Yesterday's
Yesterday's newspapers
and
and there's
Yesterday's newspapers
and there's the
and there's the dog
Yesterday's newspapers
and there's the dog and
and there's the dog and his
Yesterday's newspapers
and there's the dog and his whatever
and there's the dog and his whatever it
is
is he
is he runs
is he runs and
is he runs and plays
is he runs and plays with.
is he runs and plays with. Let's
is he runs and plays with. Let's go
is he runs and plays with. Let's go to
the
the next
is he runs and plays with. Let's go to
the next thing.
Oh,
Oh, there's
Oh, there's a
Oh, there's a horse.
Move
Move on
Oh, there's a horse.
Move on to
Move on to the
Oh, there's a horse.
Move on to the next
Move on to the next one.
Oh, there's a horse.
Move on to the next one. I
Move on to the next one. I had
Oh, there's a horse.
Move on to the next one. I had a
Move on to the next one. I had a bad
karma
karma with
karma with horses
karma with horses and
karma with horses and I
karma with horses and I finally
karma with horses and I finally got
karma with horses and I finally got over
it
it and
karma with horses and I finally got over
it and I
it and I remembered
karma with horses and I finally got over
it and I remembered what
it and I remembered what it
karma with horses and I finally got over
it and I remembered what it was
it and I remembered what it was in
karma with horses and I finally got over
it and I remembered what it was in the
what
what lifetime
what lifetime I
what lifetime I prayed
what lifetime I prayed for
what lifetime I prayed for forgiveness
and
and I
what lifetime I prayed for forgiveness
and I asked
and I asked the
what lifetime I prayed for forgiveness
and I asked the horses
and I asked the horses for
what lifetime I prayed for forgiveness
and I asked the horses for forgiveness
and
and uh
and uh then
and uh then I
and uh then I forgot
and uh then I forgot about
and uh then I forgot about it
and uh then I forgot about it couple
years
years later
and uh then I forgot about it couple
years later that
years later that was
and uh then I forgot about it couple
years later that was the
years later that was the next
and uh then I forgot about it couple
years later that was the next horse
years later that was the next horse I
ran
ran into
it
it was
ran into
it was where
it was where I
ran into
it was where I was
it was where I was a
ran into
it was where I was a director
it was where I was a director there
ran into
it was where I was a director there and
said
said we
said we got
said we got a
said we got a new
said we got a new horse
boy
boy horses
said we got a new horse
boy horses and
boy horses and I
said we got a new horse
boy horses and I ordered
boy horses and I ordered this
said we got a new horse
boy horses and I ordered this horse
boy horses and I ordered this horse and
the
the horse
the horse loved
the horse loved me
the horse loved me and
the horse loved me and kissed
the horse loved me and kissed me
somebody
somebody took
the horse loved me and kissed me
somebody took a
somebody took a character
the horse loved me and kissed me
somebody took a character then.
right.
right. So
right. So the
right. So the spiritual
right. So the spiritual foundation
right. So the spiritual foundation then
these
these are
right. So the spiritual foundation then
these are the
these are the virtues.
right. So the spiritual foundation then
these are the virtues. You
these are the virtues. You learn
right. So the spiritual foundation then
these are the virtues. You learn them
these are the virtues. You learn them in
the
the boy
the boy scouts,
the boy scouts, the
the boy scouts, the girl
the boy scouts, the girl scouts.
You
You learn
the boy scouts, the girl scouts.
You learn them
You learn them in
the boy scouts, the girl scouts.
You learn them in a
You learn them in a traditional
the boy scouts, the girl scouts.
You learn them in a traditional culture.
These
These are
These are what
These are what we
These are what we considered
These are what we considered normal
people.
people. This
These are what we considered normal
people. This is
people. This is the
These are what we considered normal
people. This is the way
people. This is the way I
These are what we considered normal
people. This is the way I thought
everybody
everybody was.
everybody was. I
everybody was. I thought
everybody was. I thought everybody
everybody was. I thought everybody was
this
this way.
everybody was. I thought everybody was
this way. Nice,
this way. Nice, polite,
everybody was. I thought everybody was
this way. Nice, polite, diplomatic.
Everybody
Everybody was
Everybody was sold
Everybody was sold the
Everybody was sold the earth.
Everybody was sold the earth. Everybody
was
was glad
Everybody was sold the earth. Everybody
was glad and
was glad and happy
Everybody was sold the earth. Everybody
was glad and happy to
was glad and happy to see
Everybody was sold the earth. Everybody
was glad and happy to see you.
was glad and happy to see you. Everybody
was
was supportive.
was supportive. Keep
was supportive. Keep in
was supportive. Keep in there.
was supportive. Keep in there. Keep
trying.
trying. Everybody
was supportive. Keep in there. Keep
trying. Everybody searched
trying. Everybody searched for
was supportive. Keep in there. Keep
trying. Everybody searched for Everybody
had
had a
had a sense
had a sense of
had a sense of humor.
had a sense of humor. Everybody
had a sense of humor. Everybody was
faithful
faithful unless
had a sense of humor. Everybody was
faithful unless they
faithful unless they had
had a sense of humor. Everybody was
faithful unless they had a
faithful unless they had a weak
had a sense of humor. Everybody was
faithful unless they had a weak moment,
but
but they
but they felt
but they felt guilty
but they felt guilty about
but they felt guilty about it,
but they felt guilty about it, you
but they felt guilty about it, you know.
Everybody
Everybody was
but they felt guilty about it, you know.
Everybody was reasonably
Everybody was reasonably neat
but they felt guilty about it, you know.
Everybody was reasonably neat and
orderly.
orderly. You
orderly. You didn't
orderly. You didn't live
orderly. You didn't live like
orderly. You didn't live like a
orderly. You didn't live like a slob.
Everybody
Everybody was
orderly. You didn't live like a slob.
Everybody was dependable.
Everybody was dependable. If
orderly. You didn't live like a slob.
Everybody was dependable. If you
Everybody was dependable. If you said,
"Return
"Return this
"Return this book
"Return this book to
"Return this book to the
"Return this book to the library."
"Return this book to the library." You
know,
know, they
"Return this book to the library." You
know, they would.
know, they would. Everybody
"Return this book to the library." You
know, they would. Everybody tried
know, they would. Everybody tried to
keep
keep control
keep control of
keep control of their
keep control of their emotions.
keep control of their emotions. You
didn't
didn't just
keep control of their emotions. You
didn't just blow
didn't just blow your
keep control of their emotions. You
didn't just blow your emotions
didn't just blow your emotions all
keep control of their emotions. You
didn't just blow your emotions all over
the
the world
the world for
the world for other
the world for other people
the world for other people to
the world for other people to try
the world for other people to try to
handle.
handle. Everybody
the world for other people to try to
handle. Everybody tried
handle. Everybody tried to
the world for other people to try to
handle. Everybody tried to be
handle. Everybody tried to be kind,
warm,
warm, moral.
warm, moral. But
warm, moral. But these
warm, moral. But these are
warm, moral. But these are the
warm, moral. But these are the basics.
200s
200s and
warm, moral. But these are the basics.
200s and 300s
200s and 300s above
warm, moral. But these are the basics.
200s and 300s above 200.
200s and 300s above 200. This
warm, moral. But these are the basics.
200s and 300s above 200. This is
200s and 300s above 200. This is the
salt
salt of
salt of the
salt of the earth.
This
This is
salt of the earth.
This is what
This is what you
salt of the earth.
This is what you get
This is what you get out
salt of the earth.
This is what you get out of
This is what you get out of a
salt of the earth.
This is what you get out of a Chinese
fortune
fortune cookie.
Chinese
Chinese fortune
fortune cookie.
Chinese fortune cookies.
Chinese fortune cookies. The
fortune cookie.
Chinese fortune cookies. The messages
Chinese fortune cookies. The messages in
them
them calibrated
them calibrated at
them calibrated at 3:45.
If
If you
them calibrated at 3:45.
If you do
If you do nothing
them calibrated at 3:45.
If you do nothing but
If you do nothing but live
them calibrated at 3:45.
If you do nothing but live the
If you do nothing but live the life
them calibrated at 3:45.
If you do nothing but live the life of
If you do nothing but live the life of a
fortune
fortune cookie.
I
I first
fortune cookie.
I first noticed
I first noticed this
fortune cookie.
I first noticed this one.
I first noticed this one. I
fortune cookie.
I first noticed this one. I open
I first noticed this one. I open one
time
time and
time and it
time and it said
time and it said uh
time and it said uh one
time and it said uh one one
time and it said uh one one warm
time and it said uh one one warm smile
can
can change
time and it said uh one one warm smile
can change your
can change your life
time and it said uh one one warm smile
can change your life forever.
can change your life forever. I
time and it said uh one one warm smile
can change your life forever. I thought
wow
wow that's
wow that's really
wow that's really true.
wow that's really true. That
wow that's really true. That that's
wow that's really true. That that's a
fact.
fact. Just
wow that's really true. That that's a
fact. Just one
fact. Just one pleasant
wow that's really true. That that's a
fact. Just one pleasant change
fact. Just one pleasant change your
wow that's really true. That that's a
fact. Just one pleasant change your life
forever.
forever. That
forever. That calibrates
forever. That calibrates at
forever. That calibrates at 3:45.
So,
So, a
forever. That calibrates at 3:45.
So, a fortune
So, a fortune cookie
forever. That calibrates at 3:45.
So, a fortune cookie life
So, a fortune cookie life elevates
forever. That calibrates at 3:45.
So, a fortune cookie life elevates you
around
around 340
around 340 and
around 340 and you
around 340 and you will
around 340 and you will be
around 340 and you will be in
around 340 and you will be in better
condition
condition than
around 340 and you will be in better
condition than about
condition than about 90%
around 340 and you will be in better
condition than about 90% of
condition than about 90% of the
around 340 and you will be in better
condition than about 90% of the world.
90%
90% of
90% of the
90% of the world
90% of the world doesn't
90% of the world doesn't live
90% of the world doesn't live up
90% of the world doesn't live up to
90% of the world doesn't live up to a
fortune
fortune cookie.
It's
It's funny,
but
but when
It's funny,
but when you
but when you get
It's funny,
but when you get the
but when you get the seriousness
It's funny,
but when you get the seriousness of
that,
that, it's
that, it's serious.
that, it's serious. Hey,
that, it's serious. Hey, let's
that, it's serious. Hey, let's move
that, it's serious. Hey, let's move on.
Prefrontal
Prefrontal cortex
that, it's serious. Hey, let's move on.
Prefrontal cortex was
Prefrontal cortex was added
that, it's serious. Hey, let's move on.
Prefrontal cortex was added during
Prefrontal cortex was added during human
evolution.
evolution. The
evolution. The old
evolution. The old animal
evolution. The old animal brain
evolution. The old animal brain was
evolution. The old animal brain was not
removed
removed and
evolution. The old animal brain was not
removed and replaced
removed and replaced by
evolution. The old animal brain was not
removed and replaced by the
removed and replaced by the prefrontal
cortex
cortex was
cortex was added
cortex was added on
cortex was added on to
cortex was added on to the
cortex was added on to the animal.
You
You used
cortex was added on to the animal.
You used to
You used to have
cortex was added on to the animal.
You used to have an
You used to have an animal
cortex was added on to the animal.
You used to have an animal with
You used to have an animal with just
teeth
teeth and
teeth and claws.
teeth and claws. Now
teeth and claws. Now you
teeth and claws. Now you got
teeth and claws. Now you got an
teeth and claws. Now you got an animal
with
with teeth
teeth and claws. Now you got an animal
with teeth and
with teeth and claws
teeth and claws. Now you got an animal
with teeth and claws and
with teeth and claws and speech
teeth and claws. Now you got an animal
with teeth and claws and speech and
thought.
thought. Really,
thought. Really, really
thought. Really, really dangerous.
You
You got
thought. Really, really dangerous.
You got a
You got a child
thought. Really, really dangerous.
You got a child with
You got a child with a
thought. Really, really dangerous.
You got a child with a loaded
You got a child with a loaded gun.
thought. Really, really dangerous.
You got a child with a loaded gun. A
child
child with
child with a
child with a loaded
child with a loaded gun.
You
You got
child with a loaded gun.
You got an
You got an animal
child with a loaded gun.
You got an animal that
You got an animal that can
child with a loaded gun.
You got an animal that can now
You got an animal that can now use
thought
thought to
thought to kill
thought to kill people.
Now
Now you
thought to kill people.
Now you got
Now you got a
thought to kill people.
Now you got a dangerous
Now you got a dangerous animal
thought to kill people.
Now you got a dangerous animal because
the
the emotional
the emotional center
the emotional center then
the emotional center then goes
the emotional center then goes here
the emotional center then goes here and
you
you store
the emotional center then goes here and
you store in
you store in hippocampus
the emotional center then goes here and
you store in hippocampus your
you store in hippocampus your memory.
That
That event,
weren't
weren't the
That event,
weren't the people
weren't the people in
That event,
weren't the people in New
weren't the people in New York
That event,
weren't the people in New York horrible?
Yes,
Yes, I
Yes, I thought
Yes, I thought they
Yes, I thought they were
Yes, I thought they were rude
Yes, I thought they were rude and
Yes, I thought they were rude and nasty.
Cow
Cow driver
Yes, I thought they were rude and nasty.
Cow driver would
Cow driver would steal
Yes, I thought they were rude and nasty.
Cow driver would steal your
Cow driver would steal your blind.
Horrible
Horrible people.
Horrible people. So
Horrible people. So here
Horrible people. So here is
Horrible people. So here is the
Horrible people. So here is the memory
of
of a
Horrible people. So here is the memory
of a left
of a left brain
Horrible people. So here is the memory
of a left brain animal
of a left brain animal in
Horrible people. So here is the memory
of a left brain animal in New
of a left brain animal in New York
Horrible people. So here is the memory
of a left brain animal in New York City.
Above
Above 200
Above 200 now
Above 200 now condundalini
Above 200 now condundalini energy
Above 200 now condundalini energy begins
to
to flow
Above 200 now condundalini energy begins
to flow changes
to flow changes the
Above 200 now condundalini energy begins
to flow changes the brain.
So
So below
So below 200
So below 200 you
So below 200 you see
So below 200 you see you
So below 200 you see you have
So below 200 you see you have left
So below 200 you see you have left brain
dominance.
It's
It's a
It's a linear
It's a linear world
It's a linear world of
It's a linear world of stress,
adrenaline,
adrenaline, fight
It's a linear world of stress,
adrenaline, fight or
adrenaline, fight or flight.
It's a linear world of stress,
adrenaline, fight or flight. Cellier's
alarm
alarm reaction
alarm reaction can
alarm reaction can in
alarm reaction can in fight
alarm reaction can in fight or
alarm reaction can in fight or flight
suppresses
suppresses the
alarm reaction can in fight or flight
suppresses the thymus
suppresses the thymus gland
alarm reaction can in fight or flight
suppresses the thymus gland decreases
immunity
immunity because
immunity because it
immunity because it decreases
immunity because it decreases the
immunity because it decreases the number
of
of circulating
immunity because it decreases the number
of circulating killer
of circulating killer cells.
Every
Every time
the
the stress
Every time
the stress response
the stress response occurs,
Every time
the stress response occurs, you
the stress response occurs, you depress
the
the thymus
the thymus and
the thymus and you
the thymus and you blow
the thymus and you blow the
the thymus and you blow the acupuncture
meridian.
meridian. Same
the thymus and you blow the acupuncture
meridian. Same kind
meridian. Same kind of
the thymus and you blow the acupuncture
meridian. Same kind of negative
meridian. Same kind of negative thought
blows
blows the
blows the same
blows the same kind
blows the same kind of
blows the same kind of meridian
blows the same kind of meridian over
blows the same kind of meridian over and
over
over and
blows the same kind of meridian over and
over and over
over and over again.
blows the same kind of meridian over and
over and over again. impairs
over and over again. impairs the
blows the same kind of meridian over and
over and over again. impairs the body
organ.
organ. Eventually,
organ. Eventually, it
organ. Eventually, it becomes
organ. Eventually, it becomes diseased.
So,
So, you
organ. Eventually, it becomes diseased.
So, you slowly
So, you slowly kill
organ. Eventually, it becomes diseased.
So, you slowly kill yourself
So, you slowly kill yourself with
negativity,
negative
negative kinesiologic
negativity,
negative kinesiologic response.
negative kinesiologic response. You've
got
got a
got a stress
got a stress to
got a stress to the
got a stress to the neurotransmitters
got a stress to the neurotransmitters in
the
the brain,
got a stress to the neurotransmitters in
the brain, depression
the brain, depression of
got a stress to the neurotransmitters in
the brain, depression of serotonin.
A
A high
A high to
A high to the
A high to the to
A high to the to most
A high to the to most of
A high to the to most of these
A high to the to most of these people
A high to the to most of these people is
adrenaline.
adrenaline. Track
A high to the to most of these people is
adrenaline. Track to
adrenaline. Track to the
A high to the to most of these people is
adrenaline. Track to the emotions
adrenaline. Track to the emotions is
twice
twice as
twice as fast
twice as fast as
twice as fast as through
twice as fast as through the
twice as fast as through the cerebral
cortex
cortex to
twice as fast as through the cerebral
cortex to the
cortex to the emotions.
twice as fast as through the cerebral
cortex to the emotions. That's
cortex to the emotions. That's the
twice as fast as through the cerebral
cortex to the emotions. That's the left
brain
brain world
brain world below
brain world below 200.
brain world below 200. 85%
brain world below 200. 85% of
brain world below 200. 85% of the
brain world below 200. 85% of the people
on
on the
brain world below 200. 85% of the people
on the planet
on the planet live
brain world below 200. 85% of the people
on the planet live there.
In
In North
In North America,
In North America, 50%
In North America, 50% of
In North America, 50% of the
In North America, 50% of the people
In North America, 50% of the people live
primarily
primarily in
In North America, 50% of the people live
primarily in left
primarily in left brain.
hatred,
hatred, anger,
hatred, anger, fear,
hatred, anger, fear, greed,
envy,
envy, competition.
They
They don't
They don't think
They don't think they
They don't think they think
They don't think they think terms
They don't think they think terms of
comp
comp cooperation.
They don't think they think terms of
comp cooperation. They
comp cooperation. They think
They don't think they think terms of
comp cooperation. They think in
comp cooperation. They think in terms
They don't think they think terms of
comp cooperation. They think in terms of
competition.
They
They don't
competition.
They don't think
They don't think how
competition.
They don't think how can
They don't think how can you
competition.
They don't think how can you and
They don't think how can you and I
competition.
They don't think how can you and I two
auto
auto dealers
auto dealers share
auto dealers share and
auto dealers share and be
auto dealers share and be together.
auto dealers share and be together. Both
of
of us
auto dealers share and be together. Both
of us increase.
of us increase. No,
auto dealers share and be together. Both
of us increase. No, they
of us increase. No, they figure
auto dealers share and be together. Both
of us increase. No, they figure how
of us increase. No, they figure how I
can
can sell
can sell more
can sell more than
can sell more than he
can sell more than he and
can sell more than he and push
can sell more than he and push him
can sell more than he and push him out
of
of the
can sell more than he and push him out
of the neighborhood.
of the neighborhood. Huh?
can sell more than he and push him out
of the neighborhood. Huh? If
of the neighborhood. Huh? If they
can sell more than he and push him out
of the neighborhood. Huh? If they join
both,
both, they
both, they become
both, they become the
both, they become the new
both, they become the new auto
both, they become the new auto center
both, they become the new auto center of
the
the world.
both, they become the new auto center of
the world. They
the world. They pull.
both, they become the new auto center of
the world. They pull. So
the world. They pull. So if
both, they become the new auto center of
the world. They pull. So if they
the world. They pull. So if they join
forces
forces they
forces they become
forces they become the
forces they become the glittering
forces they become the glittering center
where
where everybody
forces they become the glittering center
where everybody goes.
where everybody goes. If
forces they become the glittering center
where everybody goes. If they
where everybody goes. If they compete
they
they both
they both lose.
they both lose. Okay.
they both lose. Okay. All
they both lose. Okay. All right.
they both lose. Okay. All right. So
above
above 200
they both lose. Okay. All right. So
above 200 now
the
the penalty
the penalty the
the penalty the energy
the penalty the energy then
the penalty the energy then begins
the penalty the energy then begins to
change.
change. You
the penalty the energy then begins to
change. You go
change. You go you
the penalty the energy then begins to
change. You go you start
change. You go you start processing
things
things right
things right brain.
What
What happens
things right brain.
What happens now
What happens now is
things right brain.
What happens now is the
What happens now is the fast
things right brain.
What happens now is the fast track
What happens now is the fast track goes
through
through the
through the cerebral
through the cerebral cortex
through the cerebral cortex to
through the cerebral cortex to the
emotion
emotion and
through the cerebral cortex to the
emotion and more
emotion and more importantly
through the cerebral cortex to the
emotion and more importantly it
emotion and more importantly it goes
through
through the
through the newly
through the newly emerged
through the newly emerged etheric
through the newly emerged etheric brain.
The
The science
through the newly emerged etheric brain.
The science is
The science is always
through the newly emerged etheric brain.
The science is always looking
The science is always looking for
consciousness
consciousness in
consciousness in neuronal
consciousness in neuronal functioning
and
and patterning
consciousness in neuronal functioning
and patterning and
and patterning and I
consciousness in neuronal functioning
and patterning and I got
and patterning and I got news
consciousness in neuronal functioning
and patterning and I got news for
and patterning and I got news for you.
It
It ain't
It ain't there.
Reason
Reason you
It ain't there.
Reason you can't
Reason you can't find
It ain't there.
Reason you can't find it
Reason you can't find it is
It ain't there.
Reason you can't find it is because
Reason you can't find it is because it
isn't
isn't there.
isn't there. Now
isn't there. Now consciousness
isn't there. Now consciousness has
isn't there. Now consciousness has to
isn't there. Now consciousness has to do
with
with the
isn't there. Now consciousness has to do
with the athetheric
with the athetheric brain.
isn't there. Now consciousness has to do
with the athetheric brain. The
with the athetheric brain. The atheric
brain
brain is
brain is is
brain is is only
brain is is only energy.
brain is is only energy. It
brain is is only energy. It is
brain is is only energy. It is not
protoplasmic.
It's
It's like
It's like a
It's like a direct
It's like a direct imitation
It's like a direct imitation of
It's like a direct imitation of the
brain
brain but
It's like a direct imitation of the
brain but it's
brain but it's strictly
It's like a direct imitation of the
brain but it's strictly energy
brain but it's strictly energy energy.
It
It does
It does not
It does not exist
It does not exist in
It does not exist in protoplasm.
It does not exist in protoplasm. Anybody
been
been on
It does not exist in protoplasm. Anybody
been on a
been on a body
It does not exist in protoplasm. Anybody
been on a body here?
been on a body here? Yeah.
It does not exist in protoplasm. Anybody
been on a body here? Yeah. The
been on a body here? Yeah. The physical
body
body didn't
body didn't go
body didn't go with
body didn't go with it.
body didn't go with it. Right.
And
And wherever
body didn't go with it. Right.
And wherever you
And wherever you were
body didn't go with it. Right.
And wherever you were in
And wherever you were in time
body didn't go with it. Right.
And wherever you were in time or
And wherever you were in time or space,
the
the sense
the sense of
the sense of eye
the sense of eye was
the sense of eye was the
the sense of eye was the same.
the sense of eye was the same. You,
the sense of eye was the same. You, you
know,
know, all
the sense of eye was the same. You, you
know, all the
know, all the senses
the sense of eye was the same. You, you
know, all the senses worked,
know, all the senses worked, the
the sense of eye was the same. You, you
know, all the senses worked, the body's
laying
laying over
laying over there
laying over there maybe
laying over there maybe with
laying over there maybe with bullet
holes
holes in
laying over there maybe with bullet
holes in it
holes in it or
laying over there maybe with bullet
holes in it or what.
holes in it or what. And
laying over there maybe with bullet
holes in it or what. And here
holes in it or what. And here you
laying over there maybe with bullet
holes in it or what. And here you are.
You
You can
You can think,
You can think, feel,
You can think, feel, sense,
You can think, feel, sense, see.
The
The capacity
You can think, feel, sense, see.
The capacity then
The capacity then of
You can think, feel, sense, see.
The capacity then of the
The capacity then of the brain
You can think, feel, sense, see.
The capacity then of the brain is
The capacity then of the brain is not
dependent
dependent on
dependent on the
dependent on the protoplasmic
dependent on the protoplasmic brain.
dependent on the protoplasmic brain. Uh
that's
that's why
dependent on the protoplasmic brain. Uh
that's why the
that's why the research
dependent on the protoplasmic brain. Uh
that's why the research devoted
that's why the research devoted to
dependent on the protoplasmic brain. Uh
that's why the research devoted to it
calibrates
calibrates about
calibrates about 135
So
So the
calibrates about 135
So the condolini
So the condolini energy
calibrates about 135
So the condolini energy now
So the condolini energy now changes
everything.
The
The fast
everything.
The fast track
The fast track through
everything.
The fast track through the
The fast track through the phalamus
through
through the
through the cerebral
through the cerebral cortex
through the cerebral cortex and
through the cerebral cortex and the
third
third brain.
through the cerebral cortex and the
third brain. The
third brain. The fastest
through the cerebral cortex and the
third brain. The fastest track
third brain. The fastest track is
through the cerebral cortex and the
third brain. The fastest track is the
prefrontal
prefrontal cortex
prefrontal cortex or
prefrontal cortex or the
prefrontal cortex or the third
prefrontal cortex or the third brain
prefrontal cortex or the third brain to
the
the amydala.
prefrontal cortex or the third brain to
the amydala. And
the amydala. And now
prefrontal cortex or the third brain to
the amydala. And now the
the amydala. And now the emotion
prefrontal cortex or the third brain to
the amydala. And now the emotion is
stored
stored in
stored in hippocampus
stored in hippocampus but
stored in hippocampus but a
stored in hippocampus but a completely
different
different emotion
stored in hippocampus but a completely
different emotion memory.
Two
Two people
Two people have
Two people have a
Two people have a trip
Two people have a trip to
Two people have a trip to New
Two people have a trip to New York
Two people have a trip to New York City.
One
One says
Two people have a trip to New York City.
One says weren't
One says weren't they
Two people have a trip to New York City.
One says weren't they awful?
One says weren't they awful? Aren't
Two people have a trip to New York City.
One says weren't they awful? Aren't they
greedy?
greedy? Aren't
greedy? Aren't they
greedy? Aren't they rude?
greedy? Aren't they rude? The
greedy? Aren't they rude? The other
person
person says,
greedy? Aren't they rude? The other
person says, "Boy,
person says, "Boy, it
greedy? Aren't they rude? The other
person says, "Boy, it was
person says, "Boy, it was marvelous.
Everybody's
Everybody's friendly.
Everybody's friendly. Everybody's
Everybody's friendly. Everybody's happy.
Is
Is one
Everybody's friendly. Everybody's happy.
Is one on
Is one on the
Everybody's friendly. Everybody's happy.
Is one on the line
Is one on the line and
Everybody's friendly. Everybody's happy.
Is one on the line and the
Is one on the line and the other
Everybody's friendly. Everybody's happy.
Is one on the line and the other one
not?"
not?" No,
not?" No, that
not?" No, that was
not?" No, that was this
not?" No, that was this one's
experience.
experience. Because
not?" No, that was this one's
experience. Because with
experience. Because with right
not?" No, that was this one's
experience. Because with right brain
dominance,
dominance, you're
dominance, you're dealing
dominance, you're dealing with
dominance, you're dealing with the
field.
field. It's
dominance, you're dealing with the
field. It's nonlinear.
field. It's nonlinear. You're
dominance, you're dealing with the
field. It's nonlinear. You're not
dealing
dealing with
dealing with the
dealing with the content.
dealing with the content. You're
dealing with the content. You're dealing
with
with the
dealing with the content. You're dealing
with the overall
with the overall feel.
You
You live
You live in
You live in a
You live in a state
You live in a state of
You live in a state of peace
You live in a state of peace because
you're
you're putting
You live in a state of peace because
you're putting out
you're putting out endorphins
You live in a state of peace because
you're putting out endorphins instead
you're putting out endorphins instead of
adrenaline.
adrenaline. You
adrenaline. You have
adrenaline. You have positive
adrenaline. You have positive emotions.
This
This supports
adrenaline. You have positive emotions.
This supports the
This supports the thymus
adrenaline. You have positive emotions.
This supports the thymus gland.
Increases
Increases the
Increases the number
Increases the number of
Increases the number of circulating
killer
killer cells
Increases the number of circulating
killer cells in
killer cells in degree
Increases the number of circulating
killer cells in degree in
killer cells in degree in increases
immunity
immunity to
immunity to all
immunity to all diseases.
immunity to all diseases. Potentiates
healing,
healing, balances
immunity to all diseases. Potentiates
healing, balances the
healing, balances the acupuncture
system,
system, and
system, and you
system, and you get
system, and you get a
system, and you get a positive
kinesiologic
kinesiologic response.
system, and you get a positive
kinesiologic response. That
kinesiologic response. That which
system, and you get a positive
kinesiologic response. That which is
above
above 200
above 200 makes
above 200 makes your
above 200 makes your arm
above 200 makes your arm go
above 200 makes your arm go strong,
below
below 200
above 200 makes your arm go strong,
below 200 makes
below 200 makes you
above 200 makes your arm go strong,
below 200 makes you go
below 200 makes you go weak.
People
People ask
People ask me
People ask me why
People ask me why that
People ask me why that is.
People ask me why that is. I
People ask me why that is. I couldn't
tell
tell you.
People ask me why that is. I couldn't
tell you. Who
tell you. Who cares?
Next
Next slide.
So
So here
Next slide.
So here we
So here we have
Next slide.
So here we have we
So here we have we said
Next slide.
So here we have we said the
So here we have we said the functions
Next slide.
So here we have we said the functions of
the
the lower
the lower mind
the lower mind it
the lower mind it calibrated
the lower mind it calibrated at
the lower mind it calibrated at 155
compared
compared with
the lower mind it calibrated at 155
compared with functions
compared with functions of
the lower mind it calibrated at 155
compared with functions of higher
compared with functions of higher mind
calibrating
calibrating at
calibrating at 275.
calibrating at 275. You
calibrating at 275. You see
calibrating at 275. You see there
calibrating at 275. You see there are
two
two different
calibrating at 275. You see there are
two different worlds
two different worlds these
calibrating at 275. You see there are
two different worlds these people
two different worlds these people live
in.
in. One
in. One is
in. One is concerned
in. One is concerned with
in. One is concerned with the
in. One is concerned with the details.
One
One wants
in. One is concerned with the details.
One wants to
One wants to know
in. One is concerned with the details.
One wants to know the
One wants to know the what's
in. One is concerned with the details.
One wants to know the what's the
One wants to know the what's the general
feel
feel of
feel of the
feel of the overall
feel of the overall thing.
feel of the overall thing. You
feel of the overall thing. You see
feel of the overall thing. You see one
is
is concrete
feel of the overall thing. You see one
is concrete and
is concrete and literal
feel of the overall thing. You see one
is concrete and literal the
is concrete and literal the other
feel of the overall thing. You see one
is concrete and literal the other is
abstract.
The
The more
abstract.
The more invol
The more invol evolve
abstract.
The more invol evolve the
The more invol evolve the more
contemplative
contemplative we
contemplative we become.
People
People want
contemplative we become.
People want to
People want to know
contemplative we become.
People want to know what
People want to know what is
contemplative we become.
People want to know what is how
People want to know what is how do
contemplative we become.
People want to know what is how do you
elevate
elevate your
elevate your level
elevate your level consciousness.
elevate your level consciousness. You
come
come into
elevate your level consciousness. You
come into the
come into the field
elevate your level consciousness. You
come into the field of
come into the field of that
elevate your level consciousness. You
come into the field of that which
come into the field of that which to
which
which you
which you aspire.
You
You meditate
which you aspire.
You meditate but
You meditate but you
which you aspire.
You meditate but you do
You meditate but you do it
which you aspire.
You meditate but you do it like
You meditate but you do it like I
suggested
and
you
you let
you let go
you let go things
you let go things as
you let go things as they
you let go things as they arise.
you let go things as they arise. You
live
live a
you let go things as they arise. You
live a contemplative
live a contemplative lifestyle.
you let go things as they arise. You
live a contemplative lifestyle. I
live a contemplative lifestyle. I think
contemplation
contemplation as
contemplation as a
contemplation as a lifestyle
contemplation as a lifestyle is
contemplation as a lifestyle is more
effective
effective than
contemplation as a lifestyle is more
effective than periodic
effective than periodic meditation.
Periodic
Periodic meditation
gets
gets separated
Periodic meditation
gets separated out
gets separated out from
Periodic meditation
gets separated out from the
gets separated out from the rest
Periodic meditation
gets separated out from the rest of
life.
life. Pretty
life. Pretty soon
life. Pretty soon you're
life. Pretty soon you're too
life. Pretty soon you're too busy
life. Pretty soon you're too busy and
you
you skip
life. Pretty soon you're too busy and
you skip it.
you skip it. Contemplation
is
is a
is a habit,
is a habit, a
is a habit, a way
is a habit, a way of
is a habit, a way of being
is a habit, a way of being in
is a habit, a way of being in the
is a habit, a way of being in the world
in
in which
is a habit, a way of being in the world
in which you're
in which you're picking
is a habit, a way of being in the world
in which you're picking up
in which you're picking up the
is a habit, a way of being in the world
in which you're picking up the totality
of
of the
of the field.
of the field. The
of the field. The totality
of the field. The totality of
of the field. The totality of the
of the field. The totality of the field
when
when you
of the field. The totality of the field
when you need
when you need to
of the field. The totality of the field
when you need to know
when you need to know what's
of the field. The totality of the field
when you need to know what's in
when you need to know what's in the
field
field arises
field arises spontaneously.
You
You live
field arises spontaneously.
You live more
You live more in
field arises spontaneously.
You live more in the
You live more in the totality
field arises spontaneously.
You live more in the totality of
You live more in the totality of the
field
in
in which
field
in which you
in which you can
field
in which you can pick
in which you can pick up
field
in which you can pick up intention
in which you can pick up intention and
all.
all. So
all. So you
all. So you live
all. So you live in
all. So you live in a
all. So you live in a more
all. So you live in a more abstract
symbolic.
symbolic. You're
all. So you live in a more abstract
symbolic. You're looking
symbolic. You're looking at
significance.
You're
You're look,
significance.
You're look, you're
You're look, you're a
significance.
You're look, you're a little
You're look, you're a little more
detached.
detached. You're
detached. You're looking
detached. You're looking at
detached. You're looking at what
detached. You're looking at what is
detached. You're looking at what is the
meaning
meaning of
detached. You're looking at what is the
meaning of all
meaning of all this?
detached. You're looking at what is the
meaning of all this? What
meaning of all this? What is
detached. You're looking at what is the
meaning of all this? What is the
meaning of all this? What is the meaning
of
of what
of what is
of what is the
of what is the meaning
of what is the meaning of
of what is the meaning of that
of what is the meaning of that dog
changing
changing that
of what is the meaning of that dog
changing that guy's
changing that guy's mind
of what is the meaning of that dog
changing that guy's mind who's
changing that guy's mind who's about
of what is the meaning of that dog
changing that guy's mind who's about to
blow
blow up
blow up all
blow up all kinds
blow up all kinds of
blow up all kinds of people,
blow up all kinds of people, kill
blow up all kinds of people, kill all
kinds
kinds of
blow up all kinds of people, kill all
kinds of people?
kinds of people? The
blow up all kinds of people, kill all
kinds of people? The dog
kinds of people? The dog interacts
blow up all kinds of people, kill all
kinds of people? The dog interacts with
him
him and
him and instantly
him and instantly he's
him and instantly he's changed,
you
you know.
him and instantly he's changed,
you know. So,
you know. So, the
him and instantly he's changed,
you know. So, the contemplative
you know. So, the contemplative mind
says,
says, "Whoa,
it's
it's not
says, "Whoa,
it's not just
it's not just a
says, "Whoa,
it's not just a curious
it's not just a curious incident.
There's
There's something
There's something this
There's something this is
There's something this is something
There's something this is something that
is
is implied
There's something this is something that
is implied here,
is implied here, something
There's something this is something that
is implied here, something we
is implied here, something we can
There's something this is something that
is implied here, something we can find
out.
out. So
out. So the
out. So the more
out. So the more advanced
out. So the more advanced mind
out. So the more advanced mind is
interested
interested in
out. So the more advanced mind is
interested in general
interested in general essences,
meanings.
meanings. It's
meanings. It's interested
meanings. It's interested in
meanings. It's interested in ethics,
meanings. It's interested in ethics, the
principles.
It's
It's interested
It's interested in
It's interested in how
It's interested in how each
It's interested in how each thing
contributes
contributes to
It's interested in how each thing
contributes to the
contributes to the overall
It's interested in how each thing
contributes to the overall growth.
contributes to the overall growth. Tends
to
to be
to be reflected.
to be reflected. Sees
to be reflected. Sees itself
to be reflected. Sees itself as
evolving.
evolving. You
to be reflected. Sees itself as
evolving. You see
evolving. You see yourself
to be reflected. Sees itself as
evolving. You see yourself in
evolving. You see yourself in life
to be reflected. Sees itself as
evolving. You see yourself in life as
evolving. You see yourself in life as in
the
the process
the process of
the process of becoming.
the process of becoming. Becoming.
Therefore,
Therefore, what
the process of becoming. Becoming.
Therefore, what you
Therefore, what you hold
the process of becoming. Becoming.
Therefore, what you hold in
Therefore, what you hold in mind
the process of becoming. Becoming.
Therefore, what you hold in mind tends
to
to materialize.
to materialize. The
How
How you
to materialize. The
How you hold
How you hold yourself
to materialize. The
How you hold yourself as
what
what you
what you really
what you really think
what you really think you
what you really think you are
what you really think you are tends
what you really think you are tends to
materialize
materialize because
what you really think you are tends to
materialize because you
materialize because you tend
what you really think you are tends to
materialize because you tend to
materialize because you tend to be
what you really think you are tends to
materialize because you tend to be that
here
here people
here people live
here people live more
here people live more concretely
here people live more concretely and
they
they look
here people live more concretely and
they look at
they look at everything
here people live more concretely and
they look at everything from
they look at everything from a
here people live more concretely and
they look at everything from a personal
viewpoint.
How
How does
viewpoint.
How does it
How does it affect
viewpoint.
How does it affect me?
How does it affect me? Uh
viewpoint.
How does it affect me? Uh instead
How does it affect me? Uh instead of
contemplating
contemplating they
contemplating they are
contemplating they are very
contemplating they are very specific.
They
They get
contemplating they are very specific.
They get into
They get into particulars.
uh
uh they
uh they look
uh they look at
uh they look at morals
uh they look at morals rather
uh they look at morals rather than
ethics.
ethics. Uh
uh they look at morals rather than
ethics. Uh you
ethics. Uh you know
uh they look at morals rather than
ethics. Uh you know rules
ethics. Uh you know rules of
uh they look at morals rather than
ethics. Uh you know rules of right
ethics. Uh you know rules of right and
wrong
wrong rather
wrong rather than
wrong rather than the
wrong rather than the overall
wrong rather than the overall ethics
which
which may
wrong rather than the overall ethics
which may well
which may well be
wrong rather than the overall ethics
which may well be situational.
which may well be situational. What's
ethical
ethical in
ethical in one
ethical in one situation
ethical in one situation is
ethical in one situation is not
ethical in one situation is not in
another.
another. So
ethical in one situation is not in
another. So we'll
another. So we'll move
ethical in one situation is not in
another. So we'll move to
another. So we'll move to the
ethical in one situation is not in
another. So we'll move to the next.
Um
this
this is
Um
this is just
this is just more
Um
this is just more lower
this is just more lower and
Um
this is just more lower and upper
this is just more lower and upper mind
which
which is
which is all
which is all in
which is all in the
which is all in the next
which is all in the next book.
So
So we'll
which is all in the next book.
So we'll skip
So we'll skip it.
Great
Great books
Great books of
Great books of the
Great books of the western
Great books of the western world.
Great books of the western world. I
Great books of the western world. I said
this
this is
Great books of the western world. I said
this is how
this is how I
Great books of the western world. I said
this is how I spent
this is how I spent my
Great books of the western world. I said
this is how I spent my childhood.
this is how I spent my childhood. Uh
Socrates
Socrates is
Socrates is not
Socrates is not on
Socrates is not on here.
Socrates is not on here. He
Socrates is not on here. He didn't
Socrates is not on here. He didn't write
any
any books.
Socrates is not on here. He didn't write
any books. He's
any books. He's at
Socrates is not on here. He didn't write
any books. He's at 540.
But
But uh
But uh these
But uh these are
But uh these are my
But uh these are my friends.
But uh these are my friends. Aristotle
at
at 498.
Later
Later on
Later on I
Later on I took
Later on I took the
Later on I took the oath
Later on I took the oath of
Later on I took the oath of apocates
that's
that's 485.
Um
Um so
Um so these
Um so these are
Um so these are the
Um so these are the books.
Um so these are the books. This
Um so these are the books. This is
Um so these are the books. This is the
man's
man's greatest
Um so these are the books. This is the
man's greatest thinking
man's greatest thinking uh
Um so these are the books. This is the
man's greatest thinking uh throughout
time
time from
time from early
time from early ancient
time from early ancient Greece.
time from early ancient Greece. As
time from early ancient Greece. As you
see
see it's
time from early ancient Greece. As you
see it's owned
see it's owned in
time from early ancient Greece. As you
see it's owned in the
see it's owned in the 400s.
time from early ancient Greece. As you
see it's owned in the 400s. So
see it's owned in the 400s. So every
vision,
vision, honesty,
vision, honesty, intellectual
vision, honesty, intellectual integrity
calibrates
calibrates 450,
vision, honesty, intellectual integrity
calibrates 450, 460
calibrates 450, 460 around
vision, honesty, intellectual integrity
calibrates 450, 460 around in
calibrates 450, 460 around in there.
vision, honesty, intellectual integrity
calibrates 450, 460 around in there. So
you
you see
you see most
you see most of
you see most of them
you see most of them are
you see most of them are hanging
you see most of them are hanging out
around
around 450,
you see most of them are hanging out
around 450, 460.
around 450, 460. Platinus
you see most of them are hanging out
around 450, 460. Platinus Augustine
around 450, 460. Platinus Augustine over
500,
500, Dante
500, Dante at
500, Dante at 505.
And
And here
500, Dante at 505.
And here you
And here you see
500, Dante at 505.
And here you see how
And here you see how the
500, Dante at 505.
And here you see how the constitutions
of
of uh
of uh um
of uh um democracies
of uh um democracies evolved.
of uh um democracies evolved. It
of uh um democracies evolved. It was
from
from ancient
of uh um democracies evolved. It was
from ancient Greece
from ancient Greece refined
of uh um democracies evolved. It was
from ancient Greece refined over
from ancient Greece refined over the
centuries
centuries by
centuries by the
centuries by the greatest
centuries by the greatest minds
centuries by the greatest minds that
ever
ever lived.
centuries by the greatest minds that
ever lived. Therefore,
ever lived. Therefore, a
centuries by the greatest minds that
ever lived. Therefore, a constitutional
democracy
democracy is
democracy is something
democracy is something to
democracy is something to be
democracy is something to be uh
democracy is something to be uh have
respect
respect for
democracy is something to be uh have
respect for because
respect for because it
democracy is something to be uh have
respect for because it grew
respect for because it grew out
democracy is something to be uh have
respect for because it grew out of
respect for because it grew out of the
greatest
greatest minds
greatest minds in
greatest minds in history.
greatest minds in history. And
greatest minds in history. And here
greatest minds in history. And here you
see
see Newton
greatest minds in history. And here you
see Newton at
see Newton at 499
greatest minds in history. And here you
see Newton at 499 who
see Newton at 499 who discovered
greatest minds in history. And here you
see Newton at 499 who discovered the
differential
differential calculus.
Uh
and
and here
and here are
and here are the
and here are the greatest
and here are the greatest minds
and here are the greatest minds to
and here are the greatest minds to ever
live.
live. see
and here are the greatest minds to ever
live. see all
live. see all in
and here are the greatest minds to ever
live. see all in the
live. see all in the mid
and here are the greatest minds to ever
live. see all in the mid 400s
live. see all in the mid 400s with
and here are the greatest minds to ever
live. see all in the mid 400s with the
exception
exception of
the
the whole
exception of
the whole thing
the whole thing ends
exception of
the whole thing ends with
the whole thing ends with Freud
exception of
the whole thing ends with Freud Freud's
greatest
greatest you
greatest you know
greatest you know discovered
greatest you know discovered the
importance
importance of
greatest you know discovered the
importance of the
importance of the unconscious
greatest you know discovered the
importance of the unconscious mind
importance of the unconscious mind so
greatest you know discovered the
importance of the unconscious mind so in
the
the great
the great books
the great books of
the great books of the
the great books of the western
the great books of the western world
the great books of the western world put
together
together by
the great books of the western world put
together by the
together by the university
the great books of the western world put
together by the university of
together by the university of Chicago
under
under mortal
under mortal mortar
under mortal mortar Adler
under mortal mortar Adler back
under mortal mortar Adler back in
under mortal mortar Adler back in the
50s
50s um
under mortal mortar Adler back in the
50s um and
50s um and I
under mortal mortar Adler back in the
50s um and I happen
50s um and I happen to
under mortal mortar Adler back in the
50s um and I happen to come
50s um and I happen to come in
under mortal mortar Adler back in the
50s um and I happen to come in come
50s um and I happen to come in come into
a
a whole
a whole collection
a whole collection of
a whole collection of the
a whole collection of the entire
a whole collection of the entire works
uh
uh it
a whole collection of the entire works
uh it ends
uh it ends up
a whole collection of the entire works
uh it ends up at
uh it ends up at Freud
a whole collection of the entire works
uh it ends up at Freud at
uh it ends up at Freud at $4.99
Um,
everybody
everybody here
Um,
everybody here is
everybody here is in
Um,
everybody here is in the
everybody here is in the mid
Um,
everybody here is in the mid 400s
everybody here is in the mid 400s and
up.
up. The
up. The greatest
up. The greatest minds
up. The greatest minds that
up. The greatest minds that ever
up. The greatest minds that ever lived
with
with the
up. The greatest minds that ever lived
with the exception
with the exception of
up. The greatest minds that ever lived
with the exception of marks
at
at 130.
at 130. The
at 130. The color
at 130. The color graded
at 130. The color graded levels
at 130. The color graded levels of
at 130. The color graded levels of the
kind
kind of
at 130. The color graded levels of the
kind of books
kind of books if
at 130. The color graded levels of the
kind of books if you
kind of books if you remove
at 130. The color graded levels of the
kind of books if you remove marks
kind of books if you remove marks jump
another
another 10
another 10 points.
another 10 points. Uh,
another 10 points. Uh, so
another 10 points. Uh, so Markx
another 10 points. Uh, so Markx had
another 10 points. Uh, so Markx had an
unresolved
unresolved medical
another 10 points. Uh, so Markx had an
unresolved medical complex
unresolved medical complex and
another 10 points. Uh, so Markx had an
unresolved medical complex and his
trouble
trouble was
trouble was with
trouble was with Hegel.
Don't
Don't forget
trouble was with Hegel.
Don't forget I
Don't forget I did
trouble was with Hegel.
Don't forget I did psychoanalysis
Don't forget I did psychoanalysis and
trouble was with Hegel.
Don't forget I did psychoanalysis and I
was
was a
was a psychoanalysis.
was a psychoanalysis. Nothing
was a psychoanalysis. Nothing escapes
was a psychoanalysis. Nothing escapes my
eye,
eye, I
was a psychoanalysis. Nothing escapes my
eye, I tell
eye, I tell you.
was a psychoanalysis. Nothing escapes my
eye, I tell you. Well,
eye, I tell you. Well, Marx
was a psychoanalysis. Nothing escapes my
eye, I tell you. Well, Marx is
unresolved
unresolved complex.
unresolved complex. He
unresolved complex. He just
unresolved complex. He just rebelled
against
against Hegel
unresolved complex. He just rebelled
against Hegel and
against Hegel and threw
unresolved complex. He just rebelled
against Hegel and threw it
against Hegel and threw it out
unresolved complex. He just rebelled
against Hegel and threw it out and
against Hegel and threw it out and came
out
out as
out as an
out as an adolescent.
out as an adolescent. So
out as an adolescent. So 130
out as an adolescent. So 130 is
out as an adolescent. So 130 is really
adolescent.
What's
What's difficult
What's difficult about
What's difficult about it
What's difficult about it is
What's difficult about it is that
What's difficult about it is that it
sees
sees everything
What's difficult about it is that it
sees everything in
sees everything in terms
What's difficult about it is that it
sees everything in terms of
sees everything in terms of a
What's difficult about it is that it
sees everything in terms of a dualistic
projection
projection of
projection of perpetrator
projection of perpetrator victims.
This
This is
projection of perpetrator victims.
This is the
This is the downside
projection of perpetrator victims.
This is the downside of
This is the downside of a
projection of perpetrator victims.
This is the downside of a modern
This is the downside of a modern society
and
and the
and the projection
and the projection onto
and the projection onto the
and the projection onto the world
and the projection onto the world of
perpetrator
perpetrator victim.
Which
Which is
Which is the
Which is the perpetrator
Which is the perpetrator and
Which is the perpetrator and which
Which is the perpetrator and which is
the
the victim
Which is the perpetrator and which is
the victim depends
the victim depends on
Which is the perpetrator and which is
the victim depends on your
the victim depends on your political
positionality.
One
One person's
positionality.
One person's perpetrator
One person's perpetrator is
positionality.
One person's perpetrator is another
person's
person's victim.
person's victim. Yep.
The
The projection
person's victim. Yep.
The projection of
The projection of perpetrator
person's victim. Yep.
The projection of perpetrator victim
then
then is
then is the
then is the crux
then is the crux of
then is the crux of what
then is the crux of what ills
then is the crux of what ills modern
society
society and
then is the crux of what ills modern
society and why
society and why it's
then is the crux of what ills modern
society and why it's so
society and why it's so contentious.
Why
Why it's
Why it's so
Why it's so contentious.
Why it's so contentious. The
Why it's so contentious. The world
Why it's so contentious. The world I
grew
grew up
Why it's so contentious. The world I
grew up in
grew up in wasn't
Why it's so contentious. The world I
grew up in wasn't wasn't
grew up in wasn't wasn't that
contentious.
uh
uh it
contentious.
uh it was
uh it was not
contentious.
uh it was not a
uh it was not a popular
contentious.
uh it was not a popular philosophy.
Uh
Uh everybody
Uh everybody was
Uh everybody was responsible
Uh everybody was responsible personally
responsible.
responsible. So
Uh everybody was responsible personally
responsible. So we
responsible. So we didn't
Uh everybody was responsible personally
responsible. So we didn't think
responsible. So we didn't think in
Uh everybody was responsible personally
responsible. So we didn't think in terms
of
of perpetrator
of perpetrator victim
of perpetrator victim because
of perpetrator victim because that
focuses
focuses everything
of perpetrator victim because that
focuses everything on
focuses everything on blame.
Our
Our world
Our world is
Our world is one
Our world is one in
Our world is one in which
uh
uh there's
Our world is one in which
uh there's in
uh there's in intense
Our world is one in which
uh there's in intense competition
uh there's in intense competition for
blame
blame and
blame and intense
blame and intense competition
blame and intense competition to
blame and intense competition to avoid
blame
blame and
blame and intense competition to avoid
blame and to
blame and to put
blame and intense competition to avoid
blame and to put it
blame and to put it on
blame and intense competition to avoid
blame and to put it on somebody
blame and to put it on somebody else.
We're
We're more
We're more interested
We're more interested in
We're more interested in blame
We're more interested in blame than
anything
anything else.
More
More interested
More interested in
More interested in blame
More interested in blame than
More interested in blame than survival.
We're
We're more
More interested in blame than survival.
We're more interested
We're more interested in
More interested in blame than survival.
We're more interested in blame
We're more interested in blame than
honesty,
honesty, truth,
honesty, truth, profit
honesty, truth, profit or
honesty, truth, profit or anything.
Everybody
Everybody lives
honesty, truth, profit or anything.
Everybody lives in
Everybody lives in terror
honesty, truth, profit or anything.
Everybody lives in terror of
Everybody lives in terror of blame.
terror
terror that
terror that they
terror that they will
terror that they will be
terror that they will be the
terror that they will be the target
terror that they will be the target of
blame
blame at
terror that they will be the target of
blame at the
blame at the same
terror that they will be the target of
blame at the same time
blame at the same time surreptitiously
projecting
projecting it
projecting it out
projecting it out there.
It's
It's a
projecting it out there.
It's a world
It's a world run
projecting it out there.
It's a world run and
It's a world run and ruled
projecting it out there.
It's a world run and ruled right
It's a world run and ruled right now
projecting it out there.
It's a world run and ruled right now by
blame.
First
First you
blame.
First you blame
First you blame it,
blame.
First you blame it, then
First you blame it, then you
blame.
First you blame it, then you sue
First you blame it, then you sue it,
then
then you
then you attack
then you attack it,
then you attack it, then
then you attack it, then you
then you attack it, then you bomb
then you attack it, then you bomb it.
So,
all
all right,
all right, we'll
all right, we'll move
all right, we'll move on.
Anyway,
Anyway, that's
all right, we'll move on.
Anyway, that's what
Anyway, that's what I
all right, we'll move on.
Anyway, that's what I get
Anyway, that's what I get to
all right, we'll move on.
Anyway, that's what I get to tell
Anyway, that's what I get to tell you
about
about philosophy.
Truth
Truth cannot
about philosophy.
Truth cannot be
Truth cannot be understood
about philosophy.
Truth cannot be understood unless
Truth cannot be understood unless it
about philosophy.
Truth cannot be understood unless it is
placed
placed in
placed in context.
placed in context. So
placed in context. So you
placed in context. So you saw
placed in context. So you saw the
placed in context. So you saw the great
minds
minds of
placed in context. So you saw the great
minds of the
minds of the world
placed in context. So you saw the great
minds of the world that
minds of the world that have
placed in context. So you saw the great
minds of the world that have all
minds of the world that have all ever
existed.
existed. That's
existed. That's only
existed. That's only the
existed. That's only the western
existed. That's only the western world,
the
the eastern
existed. That's only the western world,
the eastern world,
the eastern world, we
existed. That's only the western world,
the eastern world, we can
the eastern world, we can put
existed. That's only the western world,
the eastern world, we can put together
the eastern world, we can put together a
similar
similar one.
similar one. Nobody
similar one. Nobody in
similar one. Nobody in all
similar one. Nobody in all that
similar one. Nobody in all that time
similar one. Nobody in all that time and
all
all those
similar one. Nobody in all that time and
all those great
all those great minds
similar one. Nobody in all that time and
all those great minds was
all those great minds was able
similar one. Nobody in all that time and
all those great minds was able to
all those great minds was able to arrive
at
at a
at a definition
at a definition of
at a definition of truth.
The
The greatest
at a definition of truth.
The greatest minds
The greatest minds of
at a definition of truth.
The greatest minds of history
The greatest minds of history put
together
together collectively
together collectively could
together collectively could not
together collectively could not arrive
at
at what
together collectively could not arrive
at what is
at what is truth.
Well,
Well, in
Well, in as
Well, in as much
Well, in as much as
Well, in as much as blame
Well, in as much as blame depends
Well, in as much as blame depends on
truth.
truth. How
Well, in as much as blame depends on
truth. How can
truth. How can you
Well, in as much as blame depends on
truth. How can you get
truth. How can you get away
Well, in as much as blame depends on
truth. How can you get away with
truth. How can you get away with blame
if
if you
if you don't
if you don't even
if you don't even know
if you don't even know what
if you don't even know what the
if you don't even know what the truth
is?
Why
Why can't
Why can't anybody
Why can't anybody ever
Why can't anybody ever have
Why can't anybody ever have a
Why can't anybody ever have a truth?
Because
truth
truth is
truth is a
truth is a statement
truth is a statement that
truth is a statement that is
truth is a statement that is content
restricted
restricted in
truth is a statement that is content
restricted in form.
restricted in form. The
truth is a statement that is content
restricted in form. The Newtonian
paradigm
paradigm of
paradigm of form.
paradigm of form. However,
paradigm of form. However, you
paradigm of form. However, you cannot
get
get away
paradigm of form. However, you cannot
get away with
get away with that
paradigm of form. However, you cannot
get away with that unless
get away with that unless you
paradigm of form. However, you cannot
get away with that unless you state
get away with that unless you state what
the
the field
the field is.
the field is. Oh,
the field is. Oh, now
the field is. Oh, now you
the field is. Oh, now you get
the field is. Oh, now you get a
the field is. Oh, now you get a little
closer
closer to
the field is. Oh, now you get a little
closer to what
closer to what is
the field is. Oh, now you get a little
closer to what is truth.
closer to what is truth. Somebody
the field is. Oh, now you get a little
closer to what is truth. Somebody says
so
so and
so and so
so and so makes
so and so makes a
so and so makes a statement
so and so makes a statement that
so and so makes a statement that is
so and so makes a statement that is true
and
and purposely
so and so makes a statement that is true
and purposely leaves
and purposely leaves out
so and so makes a statement that is true
and purposely leaves out the
and purposely leaves out the context
so and so makes a statement that is true
and purposely leaves out the context in
which
which that's
which that's true.
which that's true. That's
which that's true. That's the
surreptitious
surreptitious lie.
which that's true. That's the
surreptitious lie. The
surreptitious lie. The surreptitious
line
line per
line per said
line per said is
line per said is you
line per said is you quote
line per said is you quote this
line per said is you quote this verbatim
and
and you
line per said is you quote this verbatim
and you forget
and you forget to
line per said is you quote this verbatim
and you forget to state
and you forget to state yes
line per said is you quote this verbatim
and you forget to state yes but
and you forget to state yes but under
what
what conditions?
Under
Under one
what conditions?
Under one condition
Under one condition this
what conditions?
Under one condition this is
Under one condition this is a
what conditions?
Under one condition this is a lie.
Under one condition this is a lie. Under
another
another condition,
another condition, it's
another condition, it's the
another condition, it's the truth.
One
One condition,
another condition, it's the truth.
One condition, you're
One condition, you're a
another condition, it's the truth.
One condition, you're a hero.
One condition, you're a hero. Another
condition
condition you'll
condition you'll be
condition you'll be executed.
So
So therefore,
condition you'll be executed.
So therefore, truth
So therefore, truth cannot
condition you'll be executed.
So therefore, truth cannot be
So therefore, truth cannot be stated
condition you'll be executed.
So therefore, truth cannot be stated or
understood
understood unless
understood unless placed
understood unless placed within
understood unless placed within a
context.
A
A favorite
context.
A favorite one
A favorite one politically
context.
A favorite one politically is
A favorite one politically is reject
something
something in
something in current
something in current society
something in current society backward
something in current society backward in
time
time and
something in current society backward in
time and make
time and make it
something in current society backward in
time and make it wrong
time and make it wrong or
something in current society backward in
time and make it wrong or take
time and make it wrong or take it
something in current society backward in
time and make it wrong or take it out
time and make it wrong or take it out of
time
time and
time and put
time and put it
time and put it in
time and put it in today's
time and put it in today's world
time and put it in today's world and
make
make it
time and put it in today's world and
make it wrong.
make it wrong. Of
time and put it in today's world and
make it wrong. Of course,
make it wrong. Of course, it'd
time and put it in today's world and
make it wrong. Of course, it'd be
make it wrong. Of course, it'd be wrong
in
in today's
in today's world.
in today's world. stupid.
In
In the
in today's world. stupid.
In the world
In the world in
in today's world. stupid.
In the world in which
In the world in which it
in today's world. stupid.
In the world in which it would
In the world in which it would occurs,
it
it was
it was the
it was the way
it was the way life
it was the way life was.
Playing
Playing games
it was the way life was.
Playing games with
Playing games with time
it was the way life was.
Playing games with time paradigms,
projecting
projecting them
projecting them forward
projecting them forward and
projecting them forward and backward
projecting them forward and backward to
reinforce
reinforce some
projecting them forward and backward to
reinforce some political
reinforce some political position.
projecting them forward and backward to
reinforce some political position. Yeah.
Here's
Here's a
Here's a statement
Here's a statement that's
Here's a statement that's limited
Here's a statement that's limited to
form.
form. Newtonian
Here's a statement that's limited to
form. Newtonian paradigm
is
is only
is only true
is only true within
is only true within a
is only true within a certain
is only true within a certain context.
Now
Now that
is only true within a certain context.
Now that context
Now that context is
is only true within a certain context.
Now that context is both
Now that context is both linear
is only true within a certain context.
Now that context is both linear and
nonlinear,
nonlinear, both
nonlinear, both stated
nonlinear, both stated and
nonlinear, both stated and unstated.
The
The neatest
nonlinear, both stated and unstated.
The neatest trick
The neatest trick of
nonlinear, both stated and unstated.
The neatest trick of rhetoric
The neatest trick of rhetoric is
nonlinear, both stated and unstated.
The neatest trick of rhetoric is to
The neatest trick of rhetoric is to hint
at
at it
at it but
at it but leave
at it but leave it
at it but leave it unstated.
It's
It's both
at it but leave it unstated.
It's both linear
It's both linear and
at it but leave it unstated.
It's both linear and nonlinear.
The
The approximate
The approximate field
The approximate field of
The approximate field of that
The approximate field of that is
prevailing
prevailing public
The approximate field of that is
prevailing public opinion,
prevailing public opinion, prevailing
emotionality,
emotionality, the
emotionality, the weather,
emotionality, the weather, the
emotionality, the weather, the financial
condition
condition of
emotionality, the weather, the financial
condition of the
condition of the country,
emotionality, the weather, the financial
condition of the country, international
politics,
stated
stated or
politics,
stated or unstated
stated or unstated religious
preferences.
You
You can
preferences.
You can see
You can see what
preferences.
You can see what is
You can see what is the
preferences.
You can see what is the truth
You can see what is the truth now
becomes
becomes very
becomes very really
becomes very really quite
becomes very really quite complicated.
Made
Made by
becomes very really quite complicated.
Made by who?
Made by who? Under
becomes very really quite complicated.
Made by who? Under what
Made by who? Under what conditions,
under
under what
under what prevailing
under what prevailing circumstances?
And
And you
under what prevailing circumstances?
And you still
And you still don't
under what prevailing circumstances?
And you still don't have
And you still don't have the
under what prevailing circumstances?
And you still don't have the truth
because
because you
because you still
because you still haven't
because you still haven't related
because you still haven't related it
because you still haven't related it to
the
the absolute.
So
So you
So you have
So you have content
So you have content within
So you have content within approximate
field
field within
So you have content within approximate
field within an
field within an infinite
So you have content within approximate
field within an infinite nonlinear
field within an infinite nonlinear field
consciousness
consciousness it
consciousness it is
consciousness it is self
the
the absolute
Hegel's
Hegel's absolute
Hegel's absolute which
Hegel's absolute which marks
Hegel's absolute which marks hated
Hegel's absolute which marks hated and
rebelled
rebelled against
Hegel's absolute which marks hated and
rebelled against adolesence
rebelled against adolesence hate
Hegel's absolute which marks hated and
rebelled against adolesence hate the
idea
idea that
idea that there
idea that there is
idea that there is any
idea that there is any absolute
idea that there is any absolute anything
truth
truth or
idea that there is any absolute anything
truth or anything
all
all right
all right so
all right so if
all right so if we
all right so if we get
all right so if we get over
all right so if we get over our
adolesence
adolesence we
all right so if we get over our
adolesence we realize
there
there is
there is an
there is an absolute
there is an absolute reality
by
by which
there is an absolute reality
by which everything
by which everything else
there is an absolute reality
by which everything else is
by which everything else is relative
there is an absolute reality
by which everything else is relative and
measurable.
measurable. That's
measurable. That's what
measurable. That's what we
measurable. That's what we do
measurable. That's what we do with
kinesiology.
Compared
Compared to
an
an infinite
Compared to
an infinite field
an infinite field compared
Compared to
an infinite field compared to
an infinite field compared to this
field,
field, what
field, what does
field, what does this
field, what does this calibrate
field, what does this calibrate compared
to
to this
field, what does this calibrate compared
to this field
to this field here
in
in and
in and of
in and of itself
in and of itself as
in and of itself as compared
in and of itself as compared to
in and of itself as compared to the
absolute
If
If within
If within the
If within the human
If within the human domain
consciousness
consciousness is
If within the human domain
consciousness is measurable
consciousness is measurable up
If within the human domain
consciousness is measurable up to
consciousness is measurable up to 1,000
as
as compared
as compared to
as compared to that
as compared to that what
as compared to that what does
as compared to that what does this
calibrate?
calibrate? So
as compared to that what does this
calibrate? So you're
calibrate? So you're always
as compared to that what does this
calibrate? So you're always comparing
calibrate? So you're always comparing it
with
with a
with a standard
absolute.
That's
That's the
That's the way
That's the way we
That's the way we do
That's the way we do thermometers,
right?
right? It's
That's the way we do thermometers,
right? It's compare
right? It's compare it
That's the way we do thermometers,
right? It's compare it to
right? It's compare it to the
That's the way we do thermometers,
right? It's compare it to the absolute.
You
You have
You have to
You have to have
You have to have an
You have to have an absolute
You have to have an absolute by
You have to have an absolute by which
You have to have an absolute by which to
compare
compare it.
You have to have an absolute by which to
compare it. Otherwise,
compare it. Otherwise, you're
You have to have an absolute by which to
compare it. Otherwise, you're dealing
compare it. Otherwise, you're dealing in
a
a problematic
hermeneutics
of
of relevant
of relevant relativistic
of relevant relativistic mmology.
You
You don't
of relevant relativistic mmology.
You don't want
You don't want to
of relevant relativistic mmology.
You don't want to do
You don't want to do that,
of relevant relativistic mmology.
You don't want to do that, do
You don't want to do that, do you?
You
You want
You want to
You want to mess
You want to mess around
You want to mess around with
You want to mess around with problematic
hermeneutics,
disturb
disturb your
disturb your relativistic
disturb your relativistic epistology.
That's
That's what
disturb your relativistic epistology.
That's what you're
That's what you're doing,
disturb your relativistic epistology.
That's what you're doing, folks.
That's
That's what
That's what you're
That's what you're doing.
Don't
Don't say
That's what you're doing.
Don't say I
Don't say I didn't
That's what you're doing.
Don't say I didn't warn
Don't say I didn't warn you.
Sounds
Sounds comical.
And
And as
And as a
And as a consequence
And as a consequence of
And as a consequence of what
And as a consequence of what I
And as a consequence of what I just
said,
said, in
And as a consequence of what I just
said, in my
said, in my lifetime,
100 million
100 million people
100 million people have
100 million people have died.
100 million
100 million people
100 million people have died.
100 million people have
100 million people have laid
100 million people have died.
100 million people have laid down
100 million people have laid down their
life
life for
life for the
life for the lie.
And
And how
life for the lie.
And how is
And how is the
life for the lie.
And how is the lie
And how is the lie sold?
By
By twisting
By twisting truth
By twisting truth around.
Ables
Ables was
By twisting truth around.
Ables was the
Ables was the world's
By twisting truth around.
Ables was the world's master.
Make
Make anything
Make anything sound
Make anything sound like
Make anything sound like truth
Make anything sound like truth repeated
often
often enough?
You
You can
You can get
You can get anybody
You can get anybody to
You can get anybody to believe
You can get anybody to believe anything.
We're
We're all
You can get anybody to believe anything.
We're all now
We're all now say,
You can get anybody to believe anything.
We're all now say, "Oh,
We're all now say, "Oh, that
You can get anybody to believe anything.
We're all now say, "Oh, that couldn't
happen
happen to
happen to us."
happen to us." It's
happen to us." It's happening
happen to us." It's happening to
happen to us." It's happening to you
every
every time
happen to us." It's happening to you
every time you
every time you read
happen to us." It's happening to you
every time you read the
every time you read the newspaper,
happen to us." It's happening to you
every time you read the newspaper, every
time
time you
time you go
time you go to
time you go to the
time you go to the movie,
time you go to the movie, every
time you go to the movie, every time
time you go to the movie, every time you
listen
listen to
time you go to the movie, every time you
listen to a
listen to a commentator.
As
As compared
As compared to
As compared to the
As compared to the absolute,
As compared to the absolute, what
As compared to the absolute, what does
that
that calibrate?
A
A lot
A lot of
A lot of times
A lot of times you
A lot of times you say,
A lot of times you say, "Oh,
A lot of times you say, "Oh, he's
A lot of times you say, "Oh, he's an
honest
honest guy.
A lot of times you say, "Oh, he's an
honest guy. He
honest guy. He find
A lot of times you say, "Oh, he's an
honest guy. He find it
honest guy. He find it calibrates
A lot of times you say, "Oh, he's an
honest guy. He find it calibrates at
180."
180." Oh,
180." Oh, what
180." Oh, what you
180." Oh, what you really
180." Oh, what you really meant
180." Oh, what you really meant is
180." Oh, what you really meant is he's
persuasive.
persuasive. Oh,
180." Oh, what you really meant is he's
persuasive. Oh, that's
persuasive. Oh, that's different.
Persuasive
Persuasive is
Persuasive is one
Persuasive is one thing.
Persuasive is one thing. Integrous
Persuasive is one thing. Integrous truth
is
is another.
Persuasive is one thing. Integrous truth
is another. Okay,
is another. Okay, move
Persuasive is one thing. Integrous truth
is another. Okay, move on
is another. Okay, move on to
Persuasive is one thing. Integrous truth
is another. Okay, move on to the
is another. Okay, move on to the next.
Mankind
Mankind has
Mankind has never
Mankind has never had
Mankind has never had a
Mankind has never had a capacity
Mankind has never had a capacity to
Mankind has never had a capacity to know
truth.
truth. Never.
This
This is
This is just
This is just a
This is just a a
This is just a a stating
This is just a a stating it
This is just a a stating it in
This is just a a stating it in words.
All
All this
This is just a a stating it in words.
All this will
All this will be
This is just a a stating it in words.
All this will be out
All this will be out in
This is just a a stating it in words.
All this will be out in the
All this will be out in the next
This is just a a stating it in words.
All this will be out in the next book.
And
And you
And you have
And you have the
And you have the content.
And you have the content. You
And you have the content. You have
And you have the content. You have the
proximate
proximate field
And you have the content. You have the
proximate field which
proximate field which can
And you have the content. You have the
proximate field which can be
proximate field which can be you
And you have the content. You have the
proximate field which can be you know
proximate field which can be you know a
thing
thing is
thing is true
thing is true or
thing is true or is
thing is true or is true
thing is true or is true or
thing is true or is true or not
thing is true or is true or not true
depending
depending on
thing is true or is true or not true
depending on popularity.
depending on popularity. You
thing is true or is true or not true
depending on popularity. You know
depending on popularity. You know it's
popular
popular to
popular to hate
popular to hate so
popular to hate so and
popular to hate so and so
popular to hate so and so or
popular to hate so and so or it's
popular to hate so and so or it's not
popular
popular to
popular to hate so and so or it's not
popular to hate
popular to hate so
popular to hate so and so or it's not
popular to hate so and
popular to hate so and so.
popular to hate so and so or it's not
popular to hate so and so. It
popular to hate so and so. It comes
popular to hate so and so or it's not
popular to hate so and so. It comes and
goes
goes fads
goes fads of
goes fads of preferences.
The
The way
goes fads of preferences.
The way the
The way the media
goes fads of preferences.
The way the media present
The way the media present you
goes fads of preferences.
The way the media present you see
The way the media present you see the
way
way the
way the media
way the media present
way the media present it
way the media present it is
way the media present it is by
way the media present it is by selective
attention
attention so-called
way the media present it is by selective
attention so-called reality
attention so-called reality TV
way the media present it is by selective
attention so-called reality TV is
attention so-called reality TV is not
becoming
becoming reality
becoming reality movie
becoming reality movie which
becoming reality movie which you
becoming reality movie which you can't
tell
tell truth
becoming reality movie which you can't
tell truth and
tell truth and falsehood
becoming reality movie which you can't
tell truth and falsehood because
tell truth and falsehood because if
becoming reality movie which you can't
tell truth and falsehood because if I
selectively
selectively take
selectively take which
selectively take which angle
selectively take which angle of
selectively take which angle of your
face
face under
selectively take which angle of your
face under what
face under what expression
selectively take which angle of your
face under what expression under
face under what expression under what
circumstances
circumstances I
circumstances I get
circumstances I get one
circumstances I get one person
circumstances I get one person if
circumstances I get one person if I
circumstances I get one person if I take
the
the camera
circumstances I get one person if I take
the camera and
the camera and I
circumstances I get one person if I take
the camera and I only
the camera and I only take
circumstances I get one person if I take
the camera and I only take pictures
the camera and I only take pictures of
you
you that
you that are
you that are smiling
you that are smiling and
you that are smiling and nice
you that are smiling and nice about
you that are smiling and nice about to
get
get your
you that are smiling and nice about to
get your wife
get your wife hugging
you that are smiling and nice about to
get your wife hugging your
get your wife hugging your dog
you that are smiling and nice about to
get your wife hugging your dog you
get your wife hugging your dog you look
like
like a
like a different
I
I choose
like a different
I choose to
I choose to project
that
that to
that to you
that to you now
that to you now change
that to you now change how
that to you now change how you
that to you now change how you see
that to you now change how you see me,
right?
right? I
that to you now change how you see me,
right? I can
right? I can either
that to you now change how you see me,
right? I can either be
right? I can either be a
that to you now change how you see me,
right? I can either be a devil
right? I can either be a devil or
that to you now change how you see me,
right? I can either be a devil or an
angel.
That's
That's be
angel.
That's be called
That's be called selective
angel.
That's be called selective observation.
By
By selective
By selective observation,
I
I can
By selective observation,
I can make
I can make anyone
By selective observation,
I can make anyone appear
I can make anyone appear like
By selective observation,
I can make anyone appear like an
I can make anyone appear like an angel
or
or a
or a devil.
Person
Person is
or a devil.
Person is the
Person is the same
or a devil.
Person is the same untouched.
Person is the same untouched. I
or a devil.
Person is the same untouched. I can
Person is the same untouched. I can only
know
know what
know what the
know what the person
know what the person is
know what the person is if
know what the person is if I
know what the person is if I calibrate
their
their conscious
know what the person is if I calibrate
their conscious level
their conscious level of
know what the person is if I calibrate
their conscious level of consciousness.
Move
Move on.
Move on. So
Move on. So the
Move on. So the media
Move on. So the media are
Move on. So the media are moving
Move on. So the media are moving into
Move on. So the media are moving into a
substitute
substitute for
Move on. So the media are moving into a
substitute for reality
and
and we
and we select
and we select which
and we select which selection
and we select which selection will
and we select which selection will now
determine
determine how
and we select which selection will now
determine how you
determine how you will
and we select which selection will now
determine how you will see
determine how you will see and
experience
experience that
experience that person.
experience that person. Once
experience that person. Once you
experience that person. Once you see
experience that person. Once you see the
person
person this
experience that person. Once you see the
person this way
person this way through
experience that person. Once you see the
person this way through that
person this way through that kind
experience that person. Once you see the
person this way through that kind of
selectivity,
selectivity, you'll
selectivity, you'll now
selectivity, you'll now emotionally
react
react to
selectivity, you'll now emotionally
react to them
react to them differently.
selectivity, you'll now emotionally
react to them differently. You've
react to them differently. You've become
a
a different
a different person
a different person and
a different person and you've
a different person and you've become
programmed
programmed without
a different person and you've become
programmed without knowing
programmed without knowing you're
a different person and you've become
programmed without knowing you're being
programmed.
You
You think
programmed.
You think you're
You think you're smarter.
programmed.
You think you're smarter. You're
You think you're smarter. You're not.
Why?
Why? Because
Why? Because the
Why? Because the mind,
Why? Because the mind, the
Why? Because the mind, the intelligence
cannot
cannot tell
Why? Because the mind, the intelligence
cannot tell true
cannot tell true and
Why? Because the mind, the intelligence
cannot tell true and false.
It
It only
It only knows
It only knows perception.
Gables
Gables knew
It only knows perception.
Gables knew that.
Watched
Watched the
Watched the childhood
children
children brought
Watched the childhood
children brought up
children brought up a
Watched the childhood
children brought up a journey.
children brought up a journey. They
Watched the childhood
children brought up a journey. They all
went
went to
went to camp.
went to camp. Camp
went to camp. Camp campfire
went to camp. Camp campfire songs.
Sickle.
Sickle. They
went to camp. Camp campfire songs.
Sickle. They love
Sickle. They love their
went to camp. Camp campfire songs.
Sickle. They love their fatherland.
The
The innocent
The innocent heart
The innocent heart of
The innocent heart of the
The innocent heart of the child.
The innocent heart of the child. All
The innocent heart of the child. All you
have
have to
The innocent heart of the child. All you
have to do
have to do is
The innocent heart of the child. All you
have to do is call
have to do is call your
The innocent heart of the child. All you
have to do is call your country
fatherland
fatherland or
fatherland or motherland.
fatherland or motherland. That's
fatherland or motherland. That's all
fatherland or motherland. That's all you
got
got to
fatherland or motherland. That's all you
got to do.
Oh,
Oh, for
Oh, for the
Oh, for the motherland.
Oh, for the motherland. Oh,
Oh, for the motherland. Oh, for
Oh, for the motherland. Oh, for the
fatherland.
All
All you
All you got
All you got to
All you got to do
All you got to do is
All you got to do is call
All you got to do is call it
All you got to do is call it motherland
or
or fatherland.
All you got to do is call it motherland
or fatherland. And
or fatherland. And I
All you got to do is call it motherland
or fatherland. And I can
or fatherland. And I can get
All you got to do is call it motherland
or fatherland. And I can get anybody
or fatherland. And I can get anybody out
there
there to
there to do
there to do anything.
Give
Give me
there to do anything.
Give me a
Give me a kid
there to do anything.
Give me a kid when
Give me a kid when he's
there to do anything.
Give me a kid when he's young.
Give me a kid when he's young. Give
there to do anything.
Give me a kid when he's young. Give me
motherland,
motherland, fatherland.
motherland, fatherland. I'll
motherland, fatherland. I'll turn
motherland, fatherland. I'll turn out
any
any kid
motherland, fatherland. I'll turn out
any kid you
any kid you want.
Easy.
Easy. Why?
Easy. Why? Because
Easy. Why? Because the
Easy. Why? Because the human
Easy. Why? Because the human mind,
Easy. Why? Because the human mind, I
need
need it
Easy. Why? Because the human mind, I
need it cannot
need it cannot protect
Easy. Why? Because the human mind, I
need it cannot protect itself.
need it cannot protect itself. It
Easy. Why? Because the human mind, I
need it cannot protect itself. It cannot
tell
tell truth
tell truth and
tell truth and falsetter.
tell truth and falsetter. That's
tell truth and falsetter. That's the
structure
structure of
tell truth and falsetter. That's the
structure of the
structure of the ego.
Therefore,
Therefore, spiritual
Therefore, spiritual evolution
Therefore, spiritual evolution means
that
that we
Therefore, spiritual evolution means
that we learn
that we learn to
Therefore, spiritual evolution means
that we learn to transcend
that we learn to transcend the
Therefore, spiritual evolution means
that we learn to transcend the ego.
Oh,
this
this is
Oh,
this is the
this is the Lou,
Oh,
this is the Lou, which
this is the Lou, which calibrates
Oh,
this is the Lou, which calibrates at
500.
500. Anybody's
500. Anybody's been
500. Anybody's been there
500. Anybody's been there recently
remembers
remembers this
500. Anybody's been there recently
remembers this ice
remembers this ice cube
500. Anybody's been there recently
remembers this ice cube in
remembers this ice cube in metal
calibrates
calibrates at
calibrates at 180.
calibrates at 180. We'll
calibrates at 180. We'll move
calibrates at 180. We'll move on
calibrates at 180. We'll move on from
there.
We'll
We'll move
We'll move on
We'll move on from
We'll move on from there.
All right.
All right. So
the
the direct
the direct application
the direct application of
the direct application of of
the direct application of of course
the direct application of of course is
to
to realize
the direct application of of course is
to realize that
to realize that the
the direct application of of course is
to realize that the ego
to realize that the ego is
the direct application of of course is
to realize that the ego is the
to realize that the ego is the evolution
is
is the
is the consequence
is the consequence of
is the consequence of evolution.
It's
It's trained.
is the consequence of evolution.
It's trained. It's
It's trained. It's trained.
is the consequence of evolution.
It's trained. It's trained. Then
my
my ego's
my ego's name
my ego's name is
my ego's name is ego.
Ego.
Ego
Ego does
Ego does what
Ego does what ego
Ego does what ego is
Ego does what ego is supposed
Ego does what ego is supposed to
Ego does what ego is supposed to do.
Ego does what ego is supposed to do. If
you
you cut
Ego does what ego is supposed to do. If
you cut in
you cut in front
Ego does what ego is supposed to do. If
you cut in front of
you cut in front of them
Ego does what ego is supposed to do. If
you cut in front of them in
you cut in front of them in traffic,
Ego does what ego is supposed to do. If
you cut in front of them in traffic, he
hates
hates you.
hates you. You
hates you. You hate
hates you. You hate them,
hates you. You hate them, don't
hates you. You hate them, don't you?
Yes.
Yes. I
hates you. You hate them, don't you?
Yes. I like
Yes. I like to
hates you. You hate them, don't you?
Yes. I like to kill
Yes. I like to kill them.
hates you. You hate them, don't you?
Yes. I like to kill them. They
Yes. I like to kill them. They deserve
to
to die
to die if
to die if they
to die if they cut
to die if they cut in
to die if they cut in front
to die if they cut in front of
to die if they cut in front of you.
It's
It's important
to die if they cut in front of you.
It's important to
It's important to be
to die if they cut in front of you.
It's important to be first.
It's important to be first. Right.
to die if they cut in front of you.
It's important to be first. Right. It's
important
important to
important to be
important to be right.
important to be right. Yes.
If
If they
important to be right. Yes.
If they don't
If they don't think
important to be right. Yes.
If they don't think like
If they don't think like we
important to be right. Yes.
If they don't think like we think,
If they don't think like we think, we
hate
hate them,
hate them, right?
hate them, right? In
hate them, right? In fact,
hate them, right? In fact, they
hate them, right? In fact, they deserve
to
to die.
hate them, right? In fact, they deserve
to die. Correct?
>> Your
>> Your ego
>> Your ego is
>> Your ego is the
>> Your ego is the same
>> Your ego is the same as
>> Your ego is the same as everybody
>> Your ego is the same as everybody else's
ego.
ego. So
>> Your ego is the same as everybody else's
ego. So when
ego. So when you
>> Your ego is the same as everybody else's
ego. So when you get
ego. So when you get to
>> Your ego is the same as everybody else's
ego. So when you get to train
ego. So when you get to train them,
>> Your ego is the same as everybody else's
ego. So when you get to train them, you
get
get to
get to adopt
get to adopt them.
get to adopt them. Instead
get to adopt them. Instead of
get to adopt them. Instead of resisting
them
them and
get to adopt them. Instead of resisting
them and denying
them and denying them,
get to adopt them. Instead of resisting
them and denying them, seeing
them and denying them, seeing as
get to adopt them. Instead of resisting
them and denying them, seeing as your
enemy,
enemy, realize
enemy, realize that
enemy, realize that it's
enemy, realize that it's the
enemy, realize that it's the the
enemy, realize that it's the the old
animal
animal brain
enemy, realize that it's the the old
animal brain within
animal brain within you.
enemy, realize that it's the the old
animal brain within you. It's
animal brain within you. It's the
enemy, realize that it's the the old
animal brain within you. It's the left
brain
brain dominance.
brain dominance. And
brain dominance. And ego
brain dominance. And ego is
brain dominance. And ego is doing
brain dominance. And ego is doing what
he's
he's supposed
brain dominance. And ego is doing what
he's supposed to
he's supposed to do.
to
to survive.
to survive. He's
to survive. He's supposed
to survive. He's supposed to
to survive. He's supposed to be
to survive. He's supposed to be greedy.
The
The amoeba
to survive. He's supposed to be greedy.
The amoeba is
The amoeba is supposed
to survive. He's supposed to be greedy.
The amoeba is supposed to
The amoeba is supposed to get
to survive. He's supposed to be greedy.
The amoeba is supposed to get every
molecule
molecule out
molecule out there
molecule out there to
molecule out there to get.
molecule out there to get. Good
molecule out there to get. Good amibo.
Good
Good amigo.
All right.
All right. So,
All right. So, instead
All right. So, instead of
All right. So, instead of denying
All right. So, instead of denying it,
instead
instead of
All right. So, instead of denying it,
instead of denying
instead of denying it,
All right. So, instead of denying it,
instead of denying it, making
instead of denying it, making your
enemy,
enemy, you
enemy, you adopt
enemy, you adopt the
enemy, you adopt the animal
enemy, you adopt the animal part
enemy, you adopt the animal part of
enemy, you adopt the animal part of you
as
as your
enemy, you adopt the animal part of you
as your pet.
Give
Give it
Give it a
Give it a name.
Suki,
Popsy,
kiddo,
kiddo, whatever.
Popsy,
kiddo, whatever. You
kiddo, whatever. You like
Popsy,
kiddo, whatever. You like kiddo?
kiddo, whatever. You like kiddo? He
likes
likes kiddo.
likes kiddo. Okay.
likes kiddo. Okay. All
likes kiddo. Okay. All right.
I
I know
likes kiddo. Okay. All right.
I know what
I know what the
likes kiddo. Okay. All right.
I know what the ego's
I know what the ego's up
likes kiddo. Okay. All right.
I know what the ego's up to.
I know what the ego's up to. So
likes kiddo. Okay. All right.
I know what the ego's up to. So if
I know what the ego's up to. So if you
you
you can
you can beat
you can beat the
you can beat the ego
you can beat the ego very
you can beat the ego very easily.
you can beat the ego very easily. The
minute
minute you
you can beat the ego very easily. The
minute you get
minute you get a
you can beat the ego very easily. The
minute you get a raise,
minute you get a raise, you
you can beat the ego very easily. The
minute you get a raise, you say,
minute you get a raise, you say, "Okay,
ego.
ego. Let's
ego. Let's hear
ego. Let's hear from
ego. Let's hear from Fry.
ego. Let's hear from Fry. Let's
ego. Let's hear from Fry. Let's hear
you.
It's
It's here
It's here for
It's here for vanity.
It's here for vanity. You
It's here for vanity. You know
It's here for vanity. You know what
It's here for vanity. You know what the
ego
ego is
It's here for vanity. You know what the
ego is going
ego is going to
It's here for vanity. You know what the
ego is going to do.
ego is going to do. When
It's here for vanity. You know what the
ego is going to do. When you
ego is going to do. When you stop
denying
denying it
denying it and
denying it and stop
denying it and stop opposing
denying it and stop opposing it,
denying it and stop opposing it, you
know
know what
denying it and stop opposing it, you
know what it's
know what it's going
denying it and stop opposing it, you
know what it's going to
know what it's going to do.
denying it and stop opposing it, you
know what it's going to do. You
know what it's going to do. You you
outguess
outguess it.
outguess it. And
outguess it. And by
outguess it. And by outguing
outguess it. And by outguing it,
outguess it. And by outguing it, you
dethrown
dethrown it
outguess it. And by outguing it, you
dethrown it because
dethrown it because you
outguess it. And by outguing it, you
dethrown it because you already
dethrown it because you already know
what
what it's
what it's going
what it's going to
what it's going to do.
And
And so
instead
instead of
instead of fighting
instead of fighting the
instead of fighting the ego
instead of fighting the ego with
instead of fighting the ego with guilt
and
and sin,
I
I say
I say the
I say the downside
I say the downside the
I say the downside the sin
I say the downside the sin and
I say the downside the sin and Gothic
form
form of
I say the downside the sin and Gothic
form of Christianity
form of Christianity tend
I say the downside the sin and Gothic
form of Christianity tend to
form of Christianity tend to put
I say the downside the sin and Gothic
form of Christianity tend to put it
form of Christianity tend to put it as
an
an enemy
and
and enlightenment
an enemy
and enlightenment was
and enlightenment was rare.
an enemy
and enlightenment was rare. When
and enlightenment was rare. When you
look
look at
look at the
look at the history
look at the history of
look at the history of Europe,
look at the history of Europe, the
look at the history of Europe, the great
Christian
Christian epics,
look at the history of Europe, the great
Christian epics, you
Christian epics, you see
look at the history of Europe, the great
Christian epics, you see endless
Christian epics, you see endless wars.
The
The whole
The whole history
The whole history of
The whole history of Europe
The whole history of Europe war
Protestant
Protestant against
The whole history of Europe war
Protestant against Catholic
Protestant against Catholic beheading
kings.
kings. Some
kings. Some kings
kings. Some kings beheaded
kings. Some kings beheaded their
kings. Some kings beheaded their wives
who
who then
kings. Some kings beheaded their wives
who then beheaded
who then beheaded their
kings. Some kings beheaded their wives
who then beheaded their children
who then beheaded their children who
then
then had
then had their
then had their grandfather
then had their grandfather beheaded
then had their grandfather beheaded who
beheaded
beheaded I
then had their grandfather beheaded who
beheaded I mean
beheaded I mean it's
then had their grandfather beheaded who
beheaded I mean it's unreal
beheaded I mean it's unreal if
then had their grandfather beheaded who
beheaded I mean it's unreal if you
beheaded I mean it's unreal if you watch
the
the History
the History Channel.
I
I don't
the History Channel.
I don't know
I don't know they
the History Channel.
I don't know they got
I don't know they got a
the History Channel.
I don't know they got a ruling
I don't know they got a ruling done.
They're
They're so
They're so busy
They're so busy beheading
They're so busy beheading each
They're so busy beheading each other
They're so busy beheading each other and
imprisoning
imprisoning each
They're so busy beheading each other and
imprisoning each other.
imprisoning each other. You
They're so busy beheading each other and
imprisoning each other. You I
imprisoning each other. You I mean
They're so busy beheading each other and
imprisoning each other. You I mean it's
catastrophic.
>> Okay.
All right.
All right. Now
All right. Now this
All right. Now this is
All right. Now this is a
All right. Now this is a generic
of
of great
All right. Now this is a generic
of great usefulness.
Probably
Probably the
Probably the most
Probably the most pragmatically
Probably the most pragmatically useful
thing
thing for
Probably the most pragmatically useful
thing for uh
thing for uh people
Probably the most pragmatically useful
thing for uh people in
thing for uh people in general.
Probably the most pragmatically useful
thing for uh people in general. Here's
the
the calibrated
the calibrated levels
the calibrated levels of
the calibrated levels of consciousness.
And
And this
the calibrated levels of consciousness.
And this is
And this is called
the calibrated levels of consciousness.
And this is called us.
And this is called us. And
the calibrated levels of consciousness.
And this is called us. And then
And this is called us. And then you
the calibrated levels of consciousness.
And this is called us. And then you put
the
the rest
the rest of
the rest of the
the rest of the map
the rest of the map over
the rest of the map over here.
the rest of the map over here. That's
called
called them.
the rest of the map over here. That's
called them. You
called them. You can
the rest of the map over here. That's
called them. You can use
called them. You can use this
the rest of the map over here. That's
called them. You can use this in
business.
business. This
business. This is
business. This is our
business. This is our company.
business. This is our company. This
business. This is our company. This is
our
our country.
business. This is our company. This is
our country. This
our country. This is
business. This is our company. This is
our country. This is our
our country. This is our county.
business. This is our company. This is
our country. This is our county. This
our country. This is our county. This is
our
our church.
our church. Whatever
our church. Whatever you
our church. Whatever you want
our church. Whatever you want us
our church. Whatever you want us to
our church. Whatever you want us to be.
Okay.
Okay. Move
our church. Whatever you want us to be.
Okay. Move to
Okay. Move to the
our church. Whatever you want us to be.
Okay. Move to the next
Okay. Move to the next one.
Okay,
Okay, this
Okay, this is
Okay, this is us
Okay, this is us and
Okay, this is us and this
Okay, this is us and this is
Okay, this is us and this is them.
Okay, this is us and this is them. All
right,
right, I'm
Okay, this is us and this is them. All
right, I'm going
right, I'm going to
Okay, this is us and this is them. All
right, I'm going to use
right, I'm going to use that
Okay, this is us and this is them. All
right, I'm going to use that in
politics.
Here's
Here's America
politics.
Here's America at
Here's America at 421,
politics.
Here's America at 421, Canada
Here's America at 421, Canada 423.
You
You know,
You know, areaite
You know, areaite North
You know, areaite North America,
educated,
educated, and
we
we presume
we presume everybody's
we presume everybody's like
we presume everybody's like us.
Therefore,
Therefore, we
we presume everybody's like us.
Therefore, we speak
Therefore, we speak to
we presume everybody's like us.
Therefore, we speak to people
Therefore, we speak to people who
we presume everybody's like us.
Therefore, we speak to people who are
here
here as
here as though
here as though they
here as though they were
here as though they were up
here as though they were up here
here as though they were up here and
they
they look
here as though they were up here and
they look at
they look at us
here as though they were up here and
they look at us blankly.
they look at us blankly. They
here as though they were up here and
they look at us blankly. They say,
"Don't
"Don't you
"Don't you want
"Don't you want democracy?"
"Don't you want democracy?" They
"Don't you want democracy?" They go,
"Huh?"
Democracy.
Democracy. What?
Democracy. What? What
Democracy. What? What are
Democracy. What? What are you
Democracy. What? What are you What
at
at 75?
Democracy. What? What are you What
at 75? Why
at 75? Why would
Democracy. What? What are you What
at 75? Why would you
at 75? Why would you be
Democracy. What? What are you What
at 75? Why would you be interested
at 75? Why would you be interested in
democracy?
75 doesn't
75 doesn't know
democracy?
75 doesn't know if
75 doesn't know if it's
democracy?
75 doesn't know if it's going
75 doesn't know if it's going to
democracy?
75 doesn't know if it's going to stay
alive
alive till
alive till dinner
alive till dinner time.
alive till dinner time. All right.
alive till dinner time. All right. So,
if
if we
alive till dinner time. All right. So,
if we put
if we put the
alive till dinner time. All right. So,
if we put the them
if we put the them here,
alive till dinner time. All right. So,
if we put the them here, now
if we put the them here, now we
alive till dinner time. All right. So,
if we put the them here, now we see
if we put the them here, now we see what
international
international diplomacy
international diplomacy is
international diplomacy is like.
You
You get
international diplomacy is like.
You get where
You get where is
international diplomacy is like.
You get where is us?
You get where is us? Then
international diplomacy is like.
You get where is us? Then you
You get where is us? Then you get
international diplomacy is like.
You get where is us? Then you get where
is
is them.
is them. This
is them. This is
is them. This is the
is them. This is the country
is them. This is the country you're
dealing
dealing with.
is them. This is the country you're
dealing with. Now
dealing with. Now there's
is them. This is the country you're
dealing with. Now there's three
dealing with. Now there's three things
you
you need
you need to
you need to know
you need to know about
you need to know about the
you need to know about the country
you're
you're dealing
you need to know about the country
you're dealing with
you're dealing with or
you need to know about the country
you're dealing with or the
you're dealing with or the culture.
Let's
Let's say
Let's say countries
Let's say countries cuz
Let's say countries cuz they're
Let's say countries cuz they're easy
Let's say countries cuz they're easy in
today's
today's news.
You
You need
You need to
You need to know
You need to know the
You need to know the calibrated
You need to know the calibrated level
You need to know the calibrated level of
consciousness
consciousness of
You need to know the calibrated level of
consciousness of the
consciousness of the ruler,
You need to know the calibrated level of
consciousness of the ruler, the
consciousness of the ruler, the king,
the
the president.
the president. You
the president. You have
the president. You have to
the president. You have to know
the president. You have to know that
the president. You have to know that of
the
the government.
the president. You have to know that of
the government. And
the government. And you
the president. You have to know that of
the government. And you have
the government. And you have to
the president. You have to know that of
the government. And you have to know
the government. And you have to know the
people.
people. Three
people. Three different
people. Three different things
people. Three different things very
often
often widely
people. Three different things very
often widely disparit.
I
I can
I can think
I can think of
I can think of a
I can think of a couple
I can think of a couple countries
I can think of a couple countries are
off
off the
I can think of a couple countries are
off the top
off the top of
I can think of a couple countries are
off the top of my
off the top of my head.
I can think of a couple countries are
off the top of my head. The
off the top of my head. The rulers
I can think of a couple countries are
off the top of my head. The rulers are
at
at about
at about 450.
at about 450. Very,
at about 450. Very, very
at about 450. Very, very integrous.
at about 450. Very, very integrous. The
people
people are
at about 450. Very, very integrous. The
people are in
people are in the
at about 450. Very, very integrous. The
people are in the 300s.
Anytime
Anytime you
Anytime you go
Anytime you go vacation
Anytime you go vacation there,
Anytime you go vacation there, everybody
tell
tell you
Anytime you go vacation there, everybody
tell you the
tell you the people
Anytime you go vacation there, everybody
tell you the people are
tell you the people are wonderful.
Anytime you go vacation there, everybody
tell you the people are wonderful. And
the
the government
the government is
the government is rotten
the government is rotten through
the government is rotten through and
through.
Without
Without thinking
Without thinking too
Without thinking too hard,
Without thinking too hard, you
Without thinking too hard, you can
probably
probably think
Without thinking too hard, you can
probably think of
probably think of a
Without thinking too hard, you can
probably think of a few
probably think of a few governments.
Without thinking too hard, you can
probably think of a few governments. The
people
people are
people are great.
people are great. The
people are great. The president
people are great. The president is
great.
great. And
people are great. The president is
great. And the
great. And the government
people are great. The president is
great. And the government is
great. And the government is just
people are great. The president is
great. And the government is just poor,
right?
You
You got
right?
You got to
You got to know
right?
You got to know who
You got to know who you're
right?
You got to know who you're dealing
You got to know who you're dealing with.
Then
Then other
Then other countries
Then other countries are
Then other countries are dissimilar.
Uh
Uh so
Then other countries are dissimilar.
Uh so for
Uh so for effective
Then other countries are dissimilar.
Uh so for effective communication,
you
you have
you have to
you have to go
you have to go to
you have to go to where
you have to go to where they
you have to go to where they are.
As
As a
you have to go to where they are.
As a psychiatrist,
As a psychiatrist, a
you have to go to where they are.
As a psychiatrist, a psychoanalyst,
As a psychiatrist, a psychoanalyst, as
you have to go to where they are.
As a psychiatrist, a psychoanalyst, as a
physician,
physician, when
physician, when somebody
physician, when somebody walks
physician, when somebody walks into
physician, when somebody walks into the
office,
office, I
physician, when somebody walks into the
office, I don't
office, I don't expect
physician, when somebody walks into the
office, I don't expect them
office, I don't expect them to
physician, when somebody walks into the
office, I don't expect them to start
from
from where
from where I'm
from where I'm at.
from where I'm at. My
from where I'm at. My job
from where I'm at. My job is
from where I'm at. My job is to
from where I'm at. My job is to find
from where I'm at. My job is to find out
where
where they're
from where I'm at. My job is to find out
where they're at.
where they're at. How
from where I'm at. My job is to find out
where they're at. How do
where they're at. How do they
from where I'm at. My job is to find out
where they're at. How do they see
where they're at. How do they see the
world?
world? What
world? What are
world? What are their
world? What are their values?
I
I don't
world? What are their values?
I don't try
I don't try and
world? What are their values?
I don't try and sell
I don't try and sell them
world? What are their values?
I don't try and sell them how
I don't try and sell them how I
world? What are their values?
I don't try and sell them how I see
I don't try and sell them how I see it.
That's
That's not
That's not what
That's not what they're
That's not what they're there
That's not what they're there for.
That's not what they're there for. My
job
job is
That's not what they're there for. My
job is to
job is to find
That's not what they're there for. My
job is to find out
job is to find out who
That's not what they're there for. My
job is to find out who they
job is to find out who they are.
That's not what they're there for. My
job is to find out who they are. Who
they
they are.
they are. All right.
they are. All right. So,
they are. All right. So, if
they are. All right. So, if I'm
they are. All right. So, if I'm dealing
diplomatically
diplomatically with
they are. All right. So, if I'm dealing
diplomatically with a
diplomatically with a country,
they are. All right. So, if I'm dealing
diplomatically with a country, I
diplomatically with a country, I want
they are. All right. So, if I'm dealing
diplomatically with a country, I want to
know
know I
know I can't
know I can't I
know I can't I don't
know I can't I don't want
know I can't I don't want to
know I can't I don't want to even
know I can't I don't want to even talk
to
to them
know I can't I don't want to even talk
to them until
to them until I
know I can't I don't want to even talk
to them until I know
to them until I know those
know I can't I don't want to even talk
to them until I know those three
to them until I know those three things.
I
I know
I know the
I know the calibration
I know the calibration of
I know the calibration of the
I know the calibration of the presidents
of
of living
I know the calibration of the presidents
of living countries
of living countries in
I know the calibration of the presidents
of living countries in the
of living countries in the world,
calibrations
calibrations of
calibrations of their
calibrations of their governments,
calibrations
calibrations of
calibrations of their governments,
calibrations of their
calibrations of their people.
calibrations of their governments,
calibrations of their people. So
calibrations of their people. So then
you
you know
you know who
you know who you're
you know who you're talking
you know who you're talking about.
I
I heard
you know who you're talking about.
I heard an
I heard an interviewer
you know who you're talking about.
I heard an interviewer speaking
I heard an interviewer speaking to
you know who you're talking about.
I heard an interviewer speaking to the
former
former president
former president of
former president of China.
former president of China. He's
former president of China. He's talking
to
to President
former president of China. He's talking
to President Jang.
to President Jang. I
former president of China. He's talking
to President Jang. I think
to President Jang. I think his
former president of China. He's talking
to President Jang. I think his name
to President Jang. I think his name was
He's
He's talking
He's talking to
He's talking to the
He's talking to the leader
He's talking to the leader of
He's talking to the leader of the
biggest
biggest country
He's talking to the leader of the
biggest country in
biggest country in the
He's talking to the leader of the
biggest country in the world.
biggest country in the world. The
biggest
biggest country
biggest country in
biggest country in the
biggest country in the world.
Jane
Jane calibrated
biggest country in the world.
Jane calibrated over
Jane calibrated over 450.
People
People calibrated
People calibrated high
People calibrated high 307.
Anyway,
Anyway, I
People calibrated high 307.
Anyway, I thought
Anyway, I thought he
People calibrated high 307.
Anyway, I thought he was
Anyway, I thought he was being
People calibrated high 307.
Anyway, I thought he was being addressed
disrespectfully.
He
He was
disrespectfully.
He was being
He was being like
disrespectfully.
He was being like chiding
He was being like chiding for
disrespectfully.
He was being like chiding for having
uh
uh civil
uh civil inequalities.
Huh.
Huh. So
uh civil inequalities.
Huh. So the
Huh. So the president
uh civil inequalities.
Huh. So the president retorted,
Huh. So the president retorted, "Well,
you
you seem
you seem to
you seem to have
you seem to have a
you seem to have a few
you seem to have a few problems
you seem to have a few problems in
you seem to have a few problems in your
own
own country,
you seem to have a few problems in your
own country, divorce,
own country, divorce, crime,
you seem to have a few problems in your
own country, divorce, crime, drugs,
own country, divorce, crime, drugs, etc.
3%
3% of
3% of your
3% of your population
3% of your population is
3% of your population is prison."
3% of your population is prison." Okay.
No,
No, he
3% of your population is prison." Okay.
No, he he
No, he he handled
3% of your population is prison." Okay.
No, he he handled it
No, he he handled it with
3% of your population is prison." Okay.
No, he he handled it with area
No, he he handled it with area vision,
but
but many
but many people
but many people that
but many people that are
but many people that are not
but many people that are not that
but many people that are not that high
would
would have
but many people that are not that high
would have taken
would have taken umbrage,
but many people that are not that high
would have taken umbrage, gotten
would have taken umbrage, gotten a
resentment,
resentment, become
resentment, become angry.
resentment, become angry. All right?
resentment, become angry. All right? So,
we
we have
resentment, become angry. All right? So,
we have to
we have to respect
resentment, become angry. All right? So,
we have to respect who
we have to respect who these
resentment, become angry. All right? So,
we have to respect who these people
we have to respect who these people are,
who
who their
who their leaders
who their leaders are,
what
what their
who their leaders are,
what their overall
what their overall cultural
value
value is,
and
and then
value is,
and then we
and then we treat
value is,
and then we treat them
and then we treat them with
value is,
and then we treat them with respect.
Here
Here you're
Here you're talking
Here you're talking about
Here you're talking about people
Here you're talking about people that
are
are interested
Here you're talking about people that
are interested in
are interested in survival.
You
You want
You want them
You want them to
You want them to vote
You want them to vote for
You want them to vote for democracy.
You want them to vote for democracy. I
mean,
mean, don't
You want them to vote for democracy. I
mean, don't be
mean, don't be meaningless.
You're
You're unlikely
You're unlikely going
You're unlikely going to
You're unlikely going to make
You're unlikely going to make it
You're unlikely going to make it through
the
the next
You're unlikely going to make it through
the next 40
the next 40 80
You're unlikely going to make it through
the next 40 80 hours
the next 40 80 hours for
You're unlikely going to make it through
the next 40 80 hours for lack
the next 40 80 hours for lack of
You're unlikely going to make it through
the next 40 80 hours for lack of water,
food,
food, medical
food, medical care,
food, medical care, ravaged
food, medical care, ravaged by
food, medical care, ravaged by AIDS,
neighboring
neighboring tribes
food, medical care, ravaged by AIDS,
neighboring tribes chopping
neighboring tribes chopping up
food, medical care, ravaged by AIDS,
neighboring tribes chopping up members
of
of your
of your family
of your family in
of your family in small
of your family in small pieces.
of your family in small pieces. Huh?
You're
You're talking
of your family in small pieces. Huh?
You're talking about
You're talking about militancy
of your family in small pieces. Huh?
You're talking about militancy in
You're talking about militancy in which
winning
winning and
winning and being
winning and being right
winning and being right is
winning and being right is more
important
important than
winning and being right is more
important than anything
important than anything stupid
winning and being right is more
important than anything stupid like
democracy.
democracy. I'm
democracy. I'm dumb.
democracy. I'm dumb. Democracy
democracy. I'm dumb. Democracy vote
democracy. I'm dumb. Democracy vote for
people.
people. What
democracy. I'm dumb. Democracy vote for
people. What do
people. What do you
democracy. I'm dumb. Democracy vote for
people. What do you mean
people. What do you mean vote
democracy. I'm dumb. Democracy vote for
people. What do you mean vote for
people?
people? They
people? They haven't
people? They haven't got
people? They haven't got enough
people? They haven't got enough brains
to
to vote
people? They haven't got enough brains
to vote for
to vote for people
people? They haven't got enough brains
to vote for people for
to vote for people for anybody.
people? They haven't got enough brains
to vote for people for anybody. You
understand
understand the
understand the different
understand the different world
understand the different world views.
This
This could
understand the different world views.
This could be
This could be your
understand the different world views.
This could be your company
This could be your company and
understand the different world views.
This could be your company and this
This could be your company and this is
your
your target
your target market.
Here's
Here's your
your target market.
Here's your product.
Here's your product. Here's
your target market.
Here's your product. Here's your
Here's your product. Here's your target
market.
market. I
market. I watch
market. I watch advertising.
market. I watch advertising. I
market. I watch advertising. I love
advertising.
advertising. I
market. I watch advertising. I love
advertising. I like
advertising. I like to
market. I watch advertising. I love
advertising. I like to watch
advertising. I like to watch it
market. I watch advertising. I love
advertising. I like to watch it come
advertising. I like to watch it come on
TV
TV and
TV and a
TV and a lot
TV and a lot of
TV and a lot of times
TV and a lot of times we
TV and a lot of times we love
TV and a lot of times we love to
calibrate
calibrate it.
Here's
Here's a
Here's a company
Here's a company spending
Here's a company spending multi-millions
of
of dollars
Here's a company spending multi-millions
of dollars on
of dollars on an
Here's a company spending multi-millions
of dollars on an ad
of dollars on an ad that
Here's a company spending multi-millions
of dollars on an ad that calibrates
about
about 145.
The
The net
about 145.
The net effect
The net effect is
about 145.
The net effect is you
The net effect is you dislike
about 145.
The net effect is you dislike their
product
product the
product the instant
product the instant you
product the instant you see
product the instant you see that
commercial.
There
There is
There is a
There is a psychiatric
There is a psychiatric medication
There is a psychiatric medication and
there's
there's a
There is a psychiatric medication and
there's a full
there's a full page
There is a psychiatric medication and
there's a full page ad
there's a full page ad that
There is a psychiatric medication and
there's a full page ad that comes
there's a full page ad that comes out
There is a psychiatric medication and
there's a full page ad that comes out in
every
every psychiatric
every psychiatric newspaper.
every psychiatric newspaper. It's
every psychiatric newspaper. It's got
this
this horrible
every psychiatric newspaper. It's got
this horrible looking
this horrible looking woman.
every psychiatric newspaper. It's got
this horrible looking woman. It's
this horrible looking woman. It's got
the
the name
the name of
the name of their
the name of their product.
the name of their product. She
calibrates
calibrates at
the name of their product. She
calibrates at about
calibrates at about 130.
the name of their product. She
calibrates at about 130. As
calibrates at about 130. As a
consequence,
consequence, I
consequence, I have
consequence, I have never
consequence, I have never prescribed
consequence, I have never prescribed it.
They
They have
consequence, I have never prescribed it.
They have created
They have created a
consequence, I have never prescribed it.
They have created a negative
conditioning
conditioning to
conditioning to their
conditioning to their product
conditioning to their product and
conditioning to their product and their
product
product name.
conditioning to their product and their
product name. So,
product name. So, you
conditioning to their product and their
product name. So, you can
product name. So, you can see
conditioning to their product and their
product name. So, you can see calibrated
levels
levels of
levels of consciousness
levels of consciousness in
levels of consciousness in the
levels of consciousness in the field
levels of consciousness in the field of
advertising
uh
uh and
uh and many
uh and many other
uh and many other demonstrations
uh and many other demonstrations other
than
than just
uh and many other demonstrations other
than just uh
than just uh moving
uh and many other demonstrations other
than just uh moving on
than just uh moving on the
uh and many other demonstrations other
than just uh moving on the light.
than just uh moving on the light. So
uh and many other demonstrations other
than just uh moving on the light. So I
consider
consider this
consider this a
consider this a a
consider this a a very
consider this a a very useful
consider this a a very useful uh
consider this a a very useful uh field
with
with multiple
consider this a a very useful uh field
with multiple applications.
with multiple applications. There
consider this a a very useful uh field
with multiple applications. There is
with multiple applications. There is no
science
science of
science of diplomatic
science of diplomatic religions.
No
No science
science of diplomatic religions.
No science of
No science of truth
in
in history.
in history. The
in history. The of
in history. The of the
in history. The of the world
in history. The of the world certainly
demonstrates
demonstrates that
in history. The of the world certainly
demonstrates that fact.
Barely
Barely recover
Barely recover from
Barely recover from one
Barely recover from one war
Barely recover from one war and
Barely recover from one war and you're
into
into the
Barely recover from one war and you're
into the next.
into the next. One
Barely recover from one war and you're
into the next. One catastrophe
into the next. One catastrophe the
Barely recover from one war and you're
into the next. One catastrophe the next
horizon.
horizon. The
horizon. The solutions
horizon. The solutions to
horizon. The solutions to things
horizon. The solutions to things cannot
be
be found
horizon. The solutions to things cannot
be found through
be found through appearance
horizon. The solutions to things cannot
be found through appearance but
be found through appearance but only
through
through essence.
through essence. You
through essence. You don't
through essence. You don't know
through essence. You don't know the
essence
essence unless
through essence. You don't know the
essence unless you
essence unless you calibrate
through essence. You don't know the
essence unless you calibrate to
essence unless you calibrate to know
through essence. You don't know the
essence unless you calibrate to know the
truth
truth of
truth of it
truth of it because
truth of it because illusion
truth of it because illusion looks
truth of it because illusion looks like
truth
truth and
truth of it because illusion looks like
truth and unless
truth and unless the
truth of it because illusion looks like
truth and unless the third
truth and unless the third eye
truth of it because illusion looks like
truth and unless the third eye of
truth and unless the third eye of the
Buddha
Buddha body
Buddha body is
Buddha body is open
Buddha body is open which
Buddha body is open which is
Buddha body is open which is very
Buddha body is open which is very late
in
in spiritual
Buddha body is open which is very late
in spiritual illusion
in spiritual illusion until
Buddha body is open which is very late
in spiritual illusion until the
in spiritual illusion until the third
eye
eye of
eye of the
eye of the Buddha
eye of the Buddha body
eye of the Buddha body opens
eye of the Buddha body opens up
eye of the Buddha body opens up and
eye of the Buddha body opens up and you
have
have discernment
eye of the Buddha body opens up and you
have discernment you
have discernment you can't
eye of the Buddha body opens up and you
have discernment you can't tell
have discernment you can't tell truth
from
from falsehood.
from falsehood. Okay.
from falsehood. Okay. The
from falsehood. Okay. The thought
from falsehood. Okay. The thought that
you
you can
from falsehood. Okay. The thought that
you can tell
you can tell truth
from falsehood. Okay. The thought that
you can tell truth from
you can tell truth from falsehood
from falsehood. Okay. The thought that
you can tell truth from falsehood is
already
already a
already a falsehood.
Therefore,
Therefore, the
already a falsehood.
Therefore, the way
Therefore, the way to
already a falsehood.
Therefore, the way to spiritual
advancement,
advancement, enlightenment
advancement, enlightenment is
advancement, enlightenment is through
humility.
humility. Humility.
advancement, enlightenment is through
humility. Humility. We
humility. Humility. We pray
advancement, enlightenment is through
humility. Humility. We pray to
humility. Humility. We pray to God
advancement, enlightenment is through
humility. Humility. We pray to God uh
humility. Humility. We pray to God uh to
lead
lead us
lead us to
lead us to the
lead us to the truth
lead us to the truth and
lead us to the truth and reveal
lead us to the truth and reveal to
lead us to the truth and reveal to us
the
the truth.
lead us to the truth and reveal to us
the truth. Uh
the truth. Uh because
lead us to the truth and reveal to us
the truth. Uh because in
the truth. Uh because in and
lead us to the truth and reveal to us
the truth. Uh because in and of
the truth. Uh because in and of ourself,
we
we we
we we realize
we we realize that
we we realize that we
we we realize that we don't
we we realize that we don't know
we we realize that we don't know what
we we realize that we don't know what it
is.
is. Okay,
we we realize that we don't know what it
is. Okay, let's
is. Okay, let's see
we we realize that we don't know what it
is. Okay, let's see the
is. Okay, let's see the next
we we realize that we don't know what it
is. Okay, let's see the next slide.
is. Okay, let's see the next slide. And
whether
whether we're
whether we're done
whether we're done or
whether we're done or not,
uh
uh we'll
whether we're done or not,
uh we'll move
uh we'll move on
whether we're done or not,
uh we'll move on from
uh we'll move on from there.
We'll
We'll move
We'll move on
We'll move on from
We'll move on from there.
Oh,
Oh, this
We'll move on from there.
Oh, this is
Oh, this is the
We'll move on from there.
Oh, this is the list
Oh, this is the list of
We'll move on from there.
Oh, this is the list of 200
Oh, this is the list of 200 movies
We'll move on from there.
Oh, this is the list of 200 movies which
we
we don't
we don't have
we don't have time
we don't have time for.
we don't have time for. So,
we don't have time for. So, we're
we don't have time for. So, we're going
to
to move
we don't have time for. So, we're going
to move on
to move on from
we don't have time for. So, we're going
to move on from movies.
>> But
>> But that's
>> But that's going
>> But that's going to
>> But that's going to be
>> But that's going to be in
>> But that's going to be in the
>> But that's going to be in the next
>> But that's going to be in the next book.
Next
Next book.
Oh,
Oh, it
Oh, it says
Oh, it says see
Oh, it says see all
Oh, it says see all Mr.
Oh, it says see all Mr. Green
Oh, it says see all Mr. Green cannot
200 the
200 the next
Oh, it says see all Mr. Green cannot
200 the next book,
200 the next book, baby.
20%
20% discount.
20% discount. Any
20% discount. Any member
20% discount. Any member visits
20% discount. Any member visits a
coupon.
Actually,
Actually, we
Actually, we weren't
Actually, we weren't going
Actually, we weren't going to
Actually, we weren't going to do
Actually, we weren't going to do that
movies
movies and
Actually, we weren't going to do that
movies and the
movies and the two
Actually, we weren't going to do that
movies and the two of
movies and the two of us
Actually, we weren't going to do that
movies and the two of us one
movies and the two of us one weekend
Actually, we weren't going to do that
movies and the two of us one weekend we
were
were by
were by oursel.
were by oursel. I
were by oursel. I said,
were by oursel. I said, "You
were by oursel. I said, "You want
were by oursel. I said, "You want to
were by oursel. I said, "You want to go
for
for it?"
were by oursel. I said, "You want to go
for it?" She
for it?" She says,
were by oursel. I said, "You want to go
for it?" She says, "Let's
for it?" She says, "Let's go
were by oursel. I said, "You want to go
for it?" She says, "Let's go for
for it?" She says, "Let's go for it."
She
She grated
She grated her
She grated her teeth
She grated her teeth and
She grated her teeth and we
She grated her teeth and we did
She grated her teeth and we did all
She grated her teeth and we did all 200
by
by hero
She grated her teeth and we did all 200
by hero stand
by hero stand up
for
for this
for this book.
for this book. We
for this book. We did
for this book. We did 7,000
for this book. We did 7,000 do
for this book. We did 7,000 do that
7,000
7,000 times.
for this book. We did 7,000 do that
7,000 times. So
7,000 times. So her
for this book. We did 7,000 do that
7,000 times. So her dedication
7,000 times. So her dedication and
for this book. We did 7,000 do that
7,000 times. So her dedication and her
devotion
devotion to
devotion to the
devotion to the work
devotion to the work is
devotion to the work is really
tremendous.
Uh
Uh and
Uh and this
Uh and this is
Uh and this is just
Uh and this is just to
Uh and this is just to conclude
Uh and this is just to conclude um
Uh and this is just to conclude um that
things
things um
Uh and this is just to conclude um that
things um it's
things um it's sort
Uh and this is just to conclude um that
things um it's sort of
things um it's sort of like
Uh and this is just to conclude um that
things um it's sort of like the
things um it's sort of like the broken
window
window principle.
window principle. Instead
window principle. Instead of
window principle. Instead of blame
window principle. Instead of blame and
looking
looking outside
window principle. Instead of blame and
looking outside of
looking outside of yourself,
window principle. Instead of blame and
looking outside of yourself, we
looking outside of yourself, we see
window principle. Instead of blame and
looking outside of yourself, we see that
it
it each
it each thing
it each thing that
everything
everything that
it each thing that
everything that radiates
everything that radiates a
it each thing that
everything that radiates a level
everything that radiates a level of
consciousness
consciousness is
consciousness is associated
consciousness is associated with
consciousness is associated with other
phenomena
phenomena but
consciousness is associated with other
phenomena but not
phenomena but not on
consciousness is associated with other
phenomena but not on the
phenomena but not on the basis
consciousness is associated with other
phenomena but not on the basis of
causality
causality more
causality more like
causality more like attraction.
causality more like attraction. It's
like
like magnetic
causality more like attraction. It's
like magnetic power.
like magnetic power. You
causality more like attraction. It's
like magnetic power. You see
like magnetic power. You see below
below
below conscious
below conscious you
below conscious you know
below conscious you know over
consciousness
consciousness level
below conscious you know over
consciousness level 600
consciousness level 600 the
below conscious you know over
consciousness level 600 the rate
consciousness level 600 the rate of
unemployment
unemployment zero
unemployment zero poverty
unemployment zero poverty zero
unemployment zero poverty zero happiness
100%
100% rate
unemployment zero poverty zero happiness
100% rate of
100% rate of criminality
unemployment zero poverty zero happiness
100% rate of criminality zero
500 to
500 to 600
500 to 600 unemployment
500 to 600 unemployment zero
500 to 600 unemployment zero poverty
zero
zero happiness
500 to 600 unemployment zero poverty
zero happiness 90%
zero happiness 90% 2%
500 to 600 unemployment zero poverty
zero happiness 90% 2% must
zero happiness 90% 2% must have
500 to 600 unemployment zero poverty
zero happiness 90% 2% must have a
problem
problem there
problem there 0.5%
problem there 0.5% criminality
all
all right
problem there 0.5% criminality
all right as
all right as you
problem there 0.5% criminality
all right as you keep
all right as you keep coming
problem there 0.5% criminality
all right as you keep coming down
all right as you keep coming down 400
problem there 0.5% criminality
all right as you keep coming down 400 00
to
to 500.
to 500. Now
to 500. Now the
to 500. Now the rate
to 500. Now the rate of
to 500. Now the rate of unemployment
to 500. Now the rate of unemployment is
2%.
2%. Rate
to 500. Now the rate of unemployment is
2%. Rate of
2%. Rate of poverty
to 500. Now the rate of unemployment is
2%. Rate of poverty still
2%. Rate of poverty still 0.5.
70%
70% say
70% say your
70% say your life
70% say your life is
70% say your life is happy.
70% say your life is happy. 2%
apparently
apparently succumb
70% say your life is happy. 2%
apparently succumb to
apparently succumb to probably
temptation.
temptation. Huh.
temptation. Huh. Handling
temptation. Huh. Handling the
temptation. Huh. Handling the company's
books.
Being
Being the
Being the treasurer
Being the treasurer and
Being the treasurer and the
Being the treasurer and the auditor
Being the treasurer and the auditor all
at
at the
Being the treasurer and the auditor all
at the same
at the same time.
7%
7% are
7% are probably
7% are probably collecting
7% are probably collecting unemployment
insurance.
insurance. Rate
7% are probably collecting unemployment
insurance. Rate of
insurance. Rate of poverty
7% are probably collecting unemployment
insurance. Rate of poverty is
insurance. Rate of poverty is 1%
probably
probably bad
probably bad investments.
probably bad investments. 50%
probably bad investments. 50% are
probably bad investments. 50% are only
saying
saying that
probably bad investments. 50% are only
saying that life
saying that life is
probably bad investments. 50% are only
saying that life is okay.
saying that life is okay. 5%
probably bad investments. 50% are only
saying that life is okay. 5% are
saying that life is okay. 5% are falling
for
for criminality,
for criminality, illegality.
200 to
200 to 300,
for criminality, illegality.
200 to 300, you
200 to 300, you see
for criminality, illegality.
200 to 300, you see the
200 to 300, you see the rate
for criminality, illegality.
200 to 300, you see the rate of
unemployment
unemployment now
unemployment now is
unemployment now is 8%.
unemployment now is 8%. Poverty
unemployment now is 8%. Poverty 1.5,
unemployment now is 8%. Poverty 1.5, 40%
okay
okay 9%
unemployment now is 8%. Poverty 1.5, 40%
okay 9% succumb
okay 9% succumb to
unemployment now is 8%. Poverty 1.5, 40%
okay 9% succumb to illegality.
>> Now
>> Now when
>> Now when we
>> Now when we get
>> Now when we get below
>> Now when we get below 200,
>> Now when we get below 200, you
>> Now when we get below 200, you see
>> Now when we get below 200, you see a
dramatic
dramatic change.
>> Now when we get below 200, you see a
dramatic change. You
dramatic change. You see
>> Now when we get below 200, you see a
dramatic change. You see all
dramatic change. You see all the
>> Now when we get below 200, you see a
dramatic change. You see all the changes
in
in the
in the animal
in the animal world
in the animal world the
in the animal world the low
consciousness
consciousness level
in the animal world the low
consciousness level 200
consciousness level 200 you
in the animal world the low
consciousness level 200 you suddenly
consciousness level 200 you suddenly see
the
the rate
the rate of
the rate of unemployment
the rate of unemployment jump
the rate of unemployment jump to
the rate of unemployment jump to 50%.
Here
Here it
the rate of unemployment jump to 50%.
Here it was
Here it was 8%
the rate of unemployment jump to 50%.
Here it was 8% you
Here it was 8% you jump
the rate of unemployment jump to 50%.
Here it was 8% you jump to
Here it was 8% you jump to 50.
the rate of unemployment jump to 50%.
Here it was 8% you jump to 50. Poverty
suddenly
suddenly jumps
suddenly jumps to
suddenly jumps to 22.
suddenly jumps to 22. Happiness
suddenly jumps to 22. Happiness is
suddenly jumps to 22. Happiness is okay.
Happiness
Happiness life
suddenly jumps to 22. Happiness is okay.
Happiness life is
Happiness life is only
suddenly jumps to 22. Happiness is okay.
Happiness life is only okay
Happiness life is only okay only
suddenly jumps to 22. Happiness is okay.
Happiness life is only okay only 15%.
50%
50% have
50% have already
50% have already engaged
50% have already engaged in
50% have already engaged in criminal
behaviors
behaviors of
50% have already engaged in criminal
behaviors of one
behaviors of one kind
50% have already engaged in criminal
behaviors of one kind or
behaviors of one kind or another.
Below
Below consciousness
Below consciousness level
Below consciousness level 100.
Below consciousness level 100. You
Below consciousness level 100. You see
75%
75% unemployment
Below consciousness level 100. You see
75% unemployment 40%
75% unemployment 40% rate
Below consciousness level 100. You see
75% unemployment 40% rate of
75% unemployment 40% rate of poverty
only
only 2%
only 2% think
only 2% think life
only 2% think life is
only 2% think life is happy
only 2% think life is happy 91%
only 2% think life is happy 91% are
already
already into
only 2% think life is happy 91% are
already into criminality
already into criminality as
only 2% think life is happy 91% are
already into criminality as a
already into criminality as a lifestyle
lifestyle
less
less than
lifestyle
less than 50
less than 50 consciousness
lifestyle
less than 50 consciousness level
less than 50 consciousness level way
lifestyle
less than 50 consciousness level way at
the
the bottom
the bottom unemployment
the bottom unemployment 97%
poverty
poverty 65%
the
the rest
the rest have
the rest have relatives
0%
0% say
the rest have relatives
0% say life
0% say life is
the rest have relatives
0% say life is happy
0% say life is happy and
the rest have relatives
0% say life is happy and criminality
0% say life is happy and criminality has
reached
reached 98%.
Okay,
Okay, that's
reached 98%.
Okay, that's the
Okay, that's the end
reached 98%.
Okay, that's the end of
Okay, that's the end of the
reached 98%.
Okay, that's the end of the stand.
That's
That's the
That's the end
That's the end of
That's the end of the
That's the end of the slides.
>> Just
>> Just one
That's the end of the slides.
>> Just one more.
>> Uh
>> Uh that's
>> Uh that's the
>> Uh that's the end
>> Uh that's the end of
>> Uh that's the end of that
>> Uh that's the end of that one.
>> Uh that's the end of that one. Move
>> Uh that's the end of that one. Move on.
Let's
Let's move
>> Uh that's the end of that one. Move on.
Let's move on.
>> All right,
>> All right, we
>> All right, we did
>> All right, we did them
>> All right, we did them all.
>> All right, we did them all. Boy.
>> All right, we did them all. Boy. Oh
>> All right, we did them all. Boy. Oh boy.
Thank
Thank you,
>> All right, we did them all. Boy. Oh boy.
Thank you, Lord.
Here's
Here's the
Here's the last
Here's the last slide
Here's the last slide is
Here's the last slide is really
Here's the last slide is really um
Here's the last slide is really um to
demonstrate
demonstrate you
Here's the last slide is really um to
demonstrate you know
demonstrate you know in
Here's the last slide is really um to
demonstrate you know in many
demonstrate you know in many areas
Here's the last slide is really um to
demonstrate you know in many areas of
life
life that
life that that
life that that which
life that that which befalls
life that that which befalls you
life that that which befalls you tends
to
to be
life that that which befalls you tends
to be the
to be the consequence
life that that which befalls you tends
to be the consequence of
to be the consequence of that
life that that which befalls you tends
to be the consequence of that which
to be the consequence of that which you
are.
are. Consequently
are. Consequently there's
are. Consequently there's no
are. Consequently there's no point
are. Consequently there's no point of
chasing
chasing and
are. Consequently there's no point of
chasing and seeking
chasing and seeking success.
Be
Be all
Be all that
Be all that you
Be all that you can
Be all that you can be.
Be all that you can be. Be
Be all that you can be. Be what
Be all that you can be. Be what you
Be all that you can be. Be what you are
to
to the
Be all that you can be. Be what you are
to the max.
to the max. And
Be all that you can be. Be what you are
to the max. And success
to the max. And success people
Be all that you can be. Be what you are
to the max. And success people are
pulled
pulled to
pulled to you
pulled to you like
pulled to you like a
pulled to you like a maggot.
pulled to you like a maggot. If
pulled to you like a maggot. If you're
the
the most
pulled to you like a maggot. If you're
the most charming
the most charming waiter,
pulled to you like a maggot. If you're
the most charming waiter, everybody
wants
wants Eduardo.
wants Eduardo. The
wants Eduardo. The tips
wants Eduardo. The tips increase
wants Eduardo. The tips increase to
Eduardo.
Eduardo. I
wants Eduardo. The tips increase to
Eduardo. I mean,
Eduardo. I mean, you
wants Eduardo. The tips increase to
Eduardo. I mean, you understand?
Eduardo. I mean, you understand? Just
being
being who
being who you
being who you are
being who you are automatically
being who you are automatically folds
being who you are automatically folds to
you.
you. There's
being who you are automatically folds to
you. There's no
you. There's no point
being who you are automatically folds to
you. There's no point of
you. There's no point of chasing
being who you are automatically folds to
you. There's no point of chasing it
you. There's no point of chasing it or
seeking
seeking it
seeking it because
seeking it because by
seeking it because by becoming
seeking it because by becoming that
which
which you
seeking it because by becoming that
which you can
which you can be
seeking it because by becoming that
which you can be to
which you can be to the
seeking it because by becoming that
which you can be to the fullest
which you can be to the fullest extent
you
you can
you can be
you can be that
you can be that one
you can be that one automatically
you can be that one automatically draws
to
to oneself
you can be that one automatically draws
to oneself the
to oneself the consequence
you can be that one automatically draws
to oneself the consequence of
to oneself the consequence of the
you can be that one automatically draws
to oneself the consequence of the field.
Huh.
So
So that's
Huh.
So that's the
So that's the end
Huh.
So that's the end of
So that's the end of the
Huh.
So that's the end of the talkingness
because
because the
because the talkingness
because the talkingness is
because the talkingness is probably
because the talkingness is probably just
going
going to
because the talkingness is probably just
going to run
going to run out.
because the talkingness is probably just
going to run out. I
going to run out. I don't
because the talkingness is probably just
going to run out. I don't have
going to run out. I don't have anything
to
to do
to do with
to do with the
to do with the talkinginess.
to do with the talkinginess. I
to do with the talkinginess. I hear
to do with the talkinginess. I hear it
the
the same
to do with the talkinginess. I hear it
the same time
the same time you
to do with the talkinginess. I hear it
the same time you hear
the same time you hear it.
I
I don't
I don't know.
I don't know. Mine
I don't know. Mine went
I don't know. Mine went away
I don't know. Mine went away 35
I don't know. Mine went away 35 years
ago.
Speaking
Speaking this
Speaking this everything
Speaking this everything is
Speaking this everything is happening
spontaneously
spontaneously of
Speaking this everything is happening
spontaneously of its
spontaneously of its own.
Speaking this everything is happening
spontaneously of its own. The
spontaneously of its own. The same
Speaking this everything is happening
spontaneously of its own. The same thing
is
is happening
is happening within
is happening within yourself.
It's
It's just
is happening within yourself.
It's just the
It's just the illusion
is happening within yourself.
It's just the illusion that
It's just the illusion that there
is happening within yourself.
It's just the illusion that there is
It's just the illusion that there is a
you
you causing
you causing that.
you causing that. Everything
you causing that. Everything is
happening
happening like
you causing that. Everything is
happening like that.
happening like that. You
you causing that. Everything is
happening like that. You see
happening like that. You see what
you causing that. Everything is
happening like that. You see what it
did?
did? You
did? You saw
did? You saw that.
It
It did
did? You saw that.
It did it
It did it again.
Things
Things just
Things just happen
Things just happen spontaneously
because
because of
Things just happen spontaneously
because of the
because of the consequence
Things just happen spontaneously
because of the consequence of
because of the consequence of the
Things just happen spontaneously
because of the consequence of the field.
And
And to
And to live
And to live in
And to live in the
And to live in the field
And to live in the field then
And to live in the field then is
And to live in the field then is to
And to live in the field then is to live
the
the spiritual
And to live in the field then is to live
the spiritual life.
the spiritual life. To
And to live in the field then is to live
the spiritual life. To realize
the spiritual life. To realize that
And to live in the field then is to live
the spiritual life. To realize that one
is
is the
is the context
is the context and
is the context and what
is the context and what you
is the context and what you think
is the context and what you think of
is the context and what you think of as
yourself.
yourself. the
is the context and what you think of as
yourself. the content.
yourself. the content. So
is the context and what you think of as
yourself. the content. So now
yourself. the content. So now we'll
is the context and what you think of as
yourself. the content. So now we'll take
a
a break
a break and
a break and then
a break and then after
a break and then after that
a break and then after that what
a break and then after that what happens
before
before we
a break and then after that what happens
before we go
before we go to
a break and then after that what happens
before we go to break.