have Nico chant and we'll conclude with personal interviews anybody who wants to
talk to us can we'll give you an individual answer we've got to meet
everybody get to sign anything you want signed just two other things I wanted to
finish off the intellectual history of mankind you see the really decisive
intellectual discussion ended in 350 BC all the rhetoric that you see out about
politics and all it's a good time to review Socrates Plato and and the
greatest thinking throughout mankind I happen to have a set of the great books
of the Western world it was published in the 30s University of Chicago a world
collection of scholars there is currently a world collection of scholars
that supports the study a true liberal education is to know the great books of
the Western world and they suggest you do it over a 10-year period
you
I had a misspent youth as I have told before the spiritual experiences began
at age very early age three and age three out of nothingness out of
nothingness out of the oblivion of nothingness suddenly there was a
crashing stunning confrontation with existence I was not pleased not only did
you come back into existence but a body went with it
On top of that stunning fate, the minute there was the awareness of existence, all this happened
non-verbally.
A three-year-old doesn't know such words as existence.
No sooner was there the stunning awareness of existence than instantly there was the
fear of non-existence.
If I had come into existence, then it could have been that I would not have come into
existence and the initial confrontation, the initial duality, polarity was existence versus
non-existence, whether the infinite reality is void, voidness or allness.
Having come out of the pathway of negation, each lifetime would end, I would end up in
the void because that which you hold in mind is what you experience and if you think the
void is the ultimate reality, that's what you experience is void.
However, if void were the ultimate reality, you could stay there.
It's not the ultimate reality.
Allness is the ultimate reality.
So out of nothingness, one comes back in to correct it.
That doesn't correct itself to consciousness level 850, transcend the duality of divinity
as allness or nothingness.
It comes out of a mistranslation of the teaching of the Buddha, no-thingness, emptiness means
devoid of form, devoid of form, devoid of form.
There would be no knowingness of the devoid of form.
Of that which is without form, other than consciousness, because without consciousness,
what would be knowing the void?
Anyway, the best thinking throughout all of time, which people would like to disregard
in certain, in present society, the best thinkingness of all time.
So democracy is built on the best thinkingness of all time and evolved through the French
philosophers.
It calibrates around 450, 460.
It's the best thinkingness.
460 is excellence, intellectual excellence.
One has mastered the physical domain at 460.
So you see Thomas Aquinas, 460, Aristotle, 498, St. Augustine, 503, you see Chaucer,
480.
And then there's Dantès, 455.
And Dante, I haven't had a chance to research Dante, how he knew what hell was like, because
his description of hell was unbelievably accurate.
So I don't know how he knew that, but he's at 505, which is rather unusual.
You see Engels is at 200, Dostoevsky, 465.
Descartes is 470.
Descartes I refer to in my own writings, because he discerned res interna, from res externa,
the subjective from the ostensibly objective.
Spiritual work is shifting from perceiving thinking reality as something out there, to
realizing that it is only subjectivity that says there's something out there, and the
irreducible reality is radical subjectivity.
That's a very familiar idea.
Absolutely.
It's only because I say it is that it has any chance to be is, is.
Otherwise, isn't this, you see, is a concept.
Isn't this is a concept.
All right, so Descartes played an extremely important part.
Darwin's theory of evolution we already handled this morning
because at 450 it looks like a dualistic Newtonian paradigm
and that is also the limitation of theology
which sees God as first cause.
You know, first cause.
There is no such thing as first cause.
Let's see.
That's a fact.
There ain't no such thing as first cause.
That which always existed can only have a first cause.
Plus, it's trying to project the Newtonian paradigm of cause
to the infinite, nonlinear,
which there is no such thing as cause and effect in the nonlinear.
Alwaysness has no beginning, so there's no first cause.
To be explained because nothing is causing anything.
Everything is what it is and it unfolds out of divinity.
So, anyway, that's beyond these people here.
And then we have Euclid.
We've got all the great names, Faraday, the great names of history.
You'll see there's a reason we're going to go over this.
Freud, you see, stops at 499.
Freud was limited to the scientific paradigm.
And I, at one time, was exactly the same place Freud was.
My analysts and myself and Freud, we were all atheists.
We all thought religion was foxhole religion.
You have a fear of dying, now you get God.
See, so we all rejected that.
All right, so that was a false God that we rejected.
And the mistake was in assuming,
because you've disproven the reality of a false God,
that doesn't mean that a true God doesn't exist.
So that was the...
where they were thinking that it stopped.
You see Galileo at 485.
You see Hegel at 425.
I've had to...
For this book, I've had to review all the great philosophers over time.
And it's really been fun.
It's like going back to childhood.
As I said, other kids were out playing stickball.
And I was sitting there reading Plato and Socrates
and the aphorisms of Marcus Aurelius.
Uh...
Little did I realize...
that some 70 years later,
that would be what I'd be writing about.
What I've been writing about the last couple of months
is what I was reading when I was 12 years old.
The dialogues of Plato.
Oh, God.
So, anyway.
You see, Gaiety, where they all are.
The great names of history.
Hippocrates, the father of medicine, 485.
You know, Homer, the Iliad.
William James, the great philosopher Kant.
Kepler, the great astronomer, Kepler.
And Machiavelli.
And then, in the middle of all these incredible people,
you've got Milton, you've got Newton, 499.
You've got Plato at 485.
Plotinus jumps the whole thing.
When you read Plotinus, it's really a spiritual.
It's very spiritual.
You have Sophocles at 485.
So, you've got the great names of history.
Collectively, the greatest minds that ever lived.
Let's recalibrate the books of the greatest ones.
We have permission to do this.
Resist before the sun.
All right?
Collectively, the great books of the Western world
calibrate over, as they are on the board,
calibrate over 460, 465, 470, 475, 470, 475.
Okay, if we remove Karl Marx,
the great books of the Western world
will calibrate over 470.
475, 480, 485, 490.
Wow.
Oh, we have to take Marx out of there.
We got a new world, yeah.
Yeah, he got in there at 130.
The difficulty with Marx is
that it set up, you know, and gave energy,
political energy,
to the dualistic concept of perpetrator and victim.
And perpetrator and victim is a poisonous...
Perpetrator and victim,
let's do perpetrator and victim.
The projection of perpetrator and victim
calibrates over 200.
Calibrates over 130, 135.
135.
You see how perpetrator and victim
is so pervasive in our society
as a sociological, political,
philosophic theory.
It's them, society out there,
causing each thing to be what it is
instead of seeing each thing is,
what it is because it's radiating forth
into physicality, its own energy.
That which calibrates at 120
will live in and create an environment
that is concordant with that.
Each thing is being what it is
because of its own karmic momentum
and the potentiality coming into actuality.
Nothing is being caused
by anything outside of itself.
Everything is being what it is.
By virtue of what it is.
Not by virtue of something else.
You see how serious an error that is
in the election.
Everything is what it is
by virtue of what it is.
Otherwise, there's no karmic responsibility,
would there be?
We're all victims of something.
We're all victims of history.
We're all victims of evolution.
We're all victims of the weather.
We're all victims of having a physical body.
We're all victims of being human.
I'm a victim of getting older.
Little people are victims of childhood.
You want to play the victim game,
ad nauseum.
Then everything is the victim of everything else
and therefore nothing is responsible
for its own actions.
Everything is somebody's fault out there.
That justifies vilification,
which justifies,
which justifies hatred.
So if by their fruits you shall know them,
that distortion of reality
has a very serious fallout
in my lifetime.
It's caused.
Think how many people died
in the various revolutions,
you know.
World War I, 10 million died
due to the distortions
of truth.
World War II, millions more.
Chairman Mayo's experiment,
experiment, experiment,
experiment, cost the lives
of 30 million people who died
of starvation.
30 million people died of starvation
due to that distortion.
The vilification of that
which is integrous.
Millions more die.
So to be unaware of
serious distortion
then brings about death
and destruction.
That's why we say peace is the automatic
consequence of truth.
War is the automatic consequence
of falsehood.
Whether it's cultural war, physical war,
or any other kind of war.
Alright.
So that's what we can learn from
the great books of the Western world.
The intellectual basis of
democracy then
is
many centuries old.
It's been refined,
thought about, argued
by the best minds
in all of history.
For thousands of years.
If somebody has a better
idea, I'd like to hear it.
The best
minds throughout history
have evolved as
the structure of the world
that we live in.
We live in the highest calibrated country in the world.
Highest calibrated country
in the world.
So, to have
respect then for that which is
integrous, calibrated level
460, 470, 480,
that is integrity.
That is integrity.
So we reverence integrity in all of its forms.
In the snow today
is beauty,
and incredible music,
and people who devote their lives
to God and to service to others.
We respect beauty because
it is the revelation of divinity.
Eventually, we go
beyond form itself.
We are no longer dependent
on the aesthetics of form.
We go beyond the
aesthetics of form.
And then one sees
from everything
radiates divinity
and everything is equally beautiful.
You discover that
first in weeds, I think.
You're going by a weed
and suddenly,
look at this weed.
It's an incredible piece of sculpture.
Show me any human sculpture
that reaches the perfection.
You see the weed standing there
and its structure is absolutely
perfect and balanced.
And then you see
the divinity of all that exists.
Now, we're going to go to a practical
application of all of this,
if you think it's just for your spiritual enlightenment.
Or fill up the afternoon.
Let's see.
What's the practicality?
Well, this is sort of a jump on the book
that I'm finishing up now.
You see, every country you can calibrate
the energy level of the people
the government and the leader.
And they can be quite divergent.
You can have a very
integrous people, the people of China.
You can have a seriously pathologic leader.
You can have
loving, wonderful people
and their bureaucracy is rotten.
The people are great.
The bureaucracy is horrible.
There are certain countries you don't drive your own car in.
Because everybody knows.
The slightest thing that happens, they're going to put you in jail
and blackmail your family back home
for 10,000 to get you out of jail.
So we don't drive our car there.
We leave it at the border.
So the leader's integrous.
The people are integrous.
But the bureaucracy is rotten.
After the fall of Russian communism,
same thing happened.
The gangsters took over, bureaucracy.
Certain countries in the world,
the people are wonderful.
Some of them have great leaders.
But the self-feeding bureaucracy
is so rotten through and through
that you don't get integrity.
So you get three different numbers.
So diplomacy, when it fails,
costs the lives of millions.
We went back to World War I.
We went back to World War II.
You see how each one was due to a failure
of understanding other people.
We antagonized the rest of the world
by coming on superior
and smugly superior.
Try to sell them our way of life.
What's the error?
Well, it isn't exactly what I wanted.
There's another one,
but I guess that other one is in the book.
Here we have what I call the raw scale
with universal applicability.
Here is, this is called us.
Oops, us.
This is called us
and this is called them.
Or you can turn it around.
This can be us and that can be them.
For convenience, this is us
and that's them.
Alright, let's take it into international diplomacy
and see how we could have prevented
all the wars that have happened
so far in recent history.
We start out, we draw a line.
I've got lines all drawn.
You start out with where are you.
You're at, this is USA, 421.
Now who do you want to deal with?
Who do you want to deal with?
You want to deal with a culture
that is at 225.
You try to sell them your program
of 421
when they're only at 221
and it's going to fall on its butt.
You're not talking the same language.
You try to sell 421
to a country that is at 125.
to 125,
which is poverty and craving.
They care about everybody having a vote.
I mean, it's an idiotic idea.
Most people are too dumb to vote.
There's all countries
where nobody went as far as third grade.
Everybody's illiterate.
Their problem is food.
Oh.
Then you deal with countries that are run by
regimes that are run by rage.
Alright, so you begin
to see the
usefulness of this as a tool.
The ones I have at home all have
little dotted lines with an arrow.
So you have a dotted line.
You have your dotted line come down
and the arrow goes to whatever
you're dealing with.
This could be your company
and this is your customer base
that you're heading for.
This could be your advertisement.
What is the group you're heading for?
So we've been calibrating advertisements.
Frankly, a lot of them make you go weak.
How they sell whatever they're selling
because every time
there's one pharmaceutical
it's got the most horrible looking woman on the front.
When you calibrate her, she's 130.
Every time I open a psychiatric magazine
there's this ugly looking woman
calibrating at 130 and I hate their product.
I hate their product.
It's awful.
So you say
where are we and where are they?
And now
you don't make these gross
miscalculations.
There was
Adolf Hitler at the time
they signed the non-aggression pact.
What's his name?
Comes back to 110 Downing Street
peace in our time.
No sooner did he sign this pact with Hitler
and I'll tell you what Hitler was thinking.
Hitler was thinking
what a stupid ass.
He was thinking
I mean really.
Anybody who ever grew up in Chicago
knows better than that.
The non-aggression pact with
yeah right.
The minute your back is turned
gotcha.
It's to get you to drop your defense.
The feint.
So the non-aggression pact
the inability
to see through it.
That's why I
try to bring up naivete
the downside
because spiritual
people with spiritual naivete
are famous for the blindness
of their downside.
Oh everybody's good and sweet
and if we just believe in their goodness and sweetness
that's when the truck hits you.
Why? Because that which is against
where you're at
is looking for an opening
and your blindness is their opening.
10 million people died
due to that opening.
So we're not just talking about theory.
Not talking about theory.
If we're just good to them
they'll be good to us.
I'll tell you what's gonna happen if you're good to them.
And gloat over your
stupidity.
So to be spiritual doesn't mean to be dumb.
Doesn't mean to walk around
the world this way.
How did that happen?
Try opening this eye.
The Buddha
and Jesus Christ and Krishna
didn't say it doesn't exist.
He said don't go there.
Don't have anything to do with them.
Avoid it. Do not oppose it.
Do not go to war with it.
But don't deny it either.
Avoid anything that makes you go weak
with kinesiology.
That's what he said.
Make sure I don't go weak. Don't go there.
Alright so
in the book we calibrate the levels
of a number of countries
and now you see
what you're dealing with
because
here's a country
at a level here
it's dealing with a country here
you cannot go across this way.
You understand?
You cannot come on.
What was his name?
The guy that got us into World War II.
Chamberlain.
You see Chamberlain is coming from
sort of a
I think he's about 180.
He's around in there.
But look what he's dealing with here.
And he's saying
I'm going to trust you.
Look what this guy is.
You can't trust anything below 200
except that it's going to eat you, kill you
or sell you short.
Alright so if he knew beforehand
I'm going to meet with a guy
who calibrates here.
Right?
What a different story history would have been.
So
you can use this in relationships.
Where am I?
Who am I talking to?
Where am I? What am I studying?
Where's my business?
Where's my customer base?
I'm the university
where are my students?
I'm the professor, where is everybody?
So to talk meaningfully then
most people that are very
deviated from truth, far from truth
are off into sophistry
rationalization
and rhetoric.
We think
because they're sort of puffed up with pride about it
that democracy because it's so superior
and wonderful everybody should just go
gaga over it.
Why should they go gaga over that
which they don't even understand and don't even
value?
That's how we antagonize the world to ourself.
It isn't
the truth of what you are
but how you present that.
I see the president do the same thing.
He's thinking that
the truthfulness of the content
should hold the field.
No. Aristotle said
aside from
sophistry there is rhetoric.
What's useful about
rhetoric is the realization that
you have to anticipate where your audience
is at, not just where you're at.
If you want to know
my opinion of Bush's downside
he knows where he's at
but he doesn't present himself.
He doesn't contextualize himself.
So to me most politicians
are not adept at
how to contextualize
where they're coming from.
One simple sentence would
take them out of the
conflict they're into.
One simple sentence that would recontextualize
so they spend all their time defending
themselves on the level of content
and they contextualize
themselves with just one or two facts
the whole field changes.
You don't have to defend yourself.
Truth doesn't need to defend itself.
So
the importance of contextualization
is crucial to survival.
Survival of our world.
So it's not just a philosophic position.
In your own spiritual evolution
it's necessary to be able to discern
truth from falsehood.
To avoid getting polarized
in positionalities.
So what you do is you align
yourself with the highest truth
that you are able to recognize
and live your life
in accordance.
You try to give up positionalities
because there's only
different ways of looking at
the same phenomena.
The same phenomena.
They appear differently
from two different perspectives.
That doesn't mean they're two different realities
of life.
So the difficulty with life
in the present world
is that appearance is not essence.
Appearance is not essence.
That which one is innately
is not what it appears
to be out there.
That's one of the great values
of calibrating levels of consciousness
and that's why we did
maybe a thousand for this book
because not everybody is able
to do kinesiology and very often
what we try to do then
is to calibrate the things
of ordinary life.
Spiritual teachers,
religions,
various belief systems,
various things in our culture,
various architectural styles,
the media,
movies, books,
writers, art.
We tried to cover the entire
panorama of human life
and recontextualize it
throughout history.
It's an experience
in all of its complexities
throughout all of time.
No wonder I'm tired out.
God, I wonder
why I was pooped the other day.
Trying to calibrate
the Encyclopedia Britannica.
And of course each thing
leads to something interesting
and new.
Suddenly in the middle
of eating a fork full
of scrambled eggs
you suddenly get,
oh yeah,
valor.
Valor is different than curious.
Yeah, you get what valor means.
You got a whole couple more paragraphs.
You can see how the book goes on forever.
Because one thing leads to another.
Alright, so we wanted to
have an announcement
and then we're going to
have questions and answers
and take a break.
But I think we tried to cover
everything that is necessary to know.
It's not necessary to know anything.
I think we said it today.
No thinking.
I pledge no thinking, Doctor.
Hail to the truth.
And I choose instead to be
that which I am.
I choose to be a prayer
and by my existence
do I bless thee.
While they're setting up
we're going to have Nico do a chant.
Lotus Sutra.
Lotus Sutra in Sanskrit.
And he's going to do it
just by himself.
And while he's doing that
anybody that has to do anything else
can do it.
Nico.
I would suggest just relax into this.
This requires no thinking on your part.
And close your eyes if you like.
So, now we're going to have a chat with you.
Hello, everybody.
My name is Michael here.
I'm here to see Lord Jesus.
And I want to thank you
for your Friendship and for the
support you've shown me over the years.
And to make sure you have the
best possible time in your lives.
So, as you only have one thing to do
I would suggest that we make a
Bible study.
I think this is great to do.
Thank you.
Thank you, Nico.
Consciousness, that annoying time between naps.
There you go.
Hi.
Thanks very much for everything today.
Yeah.
Page 304 of your book, you talk about a personal meeting with a sage,
and you're the only one I know, so I came here,
and I don't know how it works,
but it seems like everything...
everything else is thinkingness,
so if you can flare what's going on over there this way.
Let me embrace you, sir, formally.
All right.
You've been formally embraced.
Excellent.
That's why I came.
I know what you mean.
That's all it takes.
The energy's there for...
And then I had a subjective experience recently with meditation
I wanted to ask you about.
I closed my eyes,
and I did your very simple...
I did my very simple thing of looking at the Fahs genes,
looking past them,
and I've waited it out.
Usually I don't get anything for a while,
and I just sit there for 25 or 30 minutes,
and I sat there about that long,
and then there was this ground that materialized.
It was like a sort of a deep space photo,
something like that,
and I had the sense when I was looking at it
that I was seeing only maybe, you know,
90 degree angle of it or a certain view.
Like I was definitely outside the picture,
and then I tried to rotate it
because you know,
because you're always talking about
be the context, be the field,
be the whole, everything of what you're seeing.
So I tried to rotate it 360,
and then suddenly my sense of self,
except for a very thin and persistent pinprick of consciousness
like deep in my head,
was like in this field,
and there was no body,
there was nothing at all there
except the very nagging sensation in my head.
And I'm wondering what's going on there,
like,
what level I'm at.
I didn't feel bliss.
I felt like,
I actually felt like I was led to this point,
and I kind of looked back at myself,
and I got the distinct sensation that nothing was there,
like what I consider to be me.
I was looking back,
and it was like deep space, too.
You became space, huh?
I don't know.
Well, you see,
the identification with the content dissolves,
and you begin to identify with the field,
and that's why I say spiritual work is really the way you are in the world,
the way you contextualize yourself,
the way you see yourself.
You begin to see yourself impersonally.
You begin to realize that life is impersonal.
It's subjective,
but even the subjective is a quality
that is not a personal possession.
Everything is happening of itself,
everything is happening of its own,
and you stop personalizing it as an I and a that, huh?
So what you're doing is going into a type of meditation
where you begin to disidentify with the content,
and you become at one with the field.
You see that you're the field, not the content of the field.
That meditative awareness then begins to translate
into,
into contemplation.
So you can experience it intensely in meditation,
but it's the translation into contemplation.
That's why I recommend contemplation more than meditation.
Meditation is very informational.
You discover various things,
but then as you open your eyes and walk around,
the samadhi leaves,
and you're left with what is your
prevailing level of consciousness.
Contemplation is a way of being in the world.
It's a supplication to God at all times,
to be that which is the expression of divinity
as this form,
but then the form only becomes an expression of divinity,
and it takes the person out of it.
So contemplativeness is a way of life, huh?
So the meditative experience was going from identifying with me,
the I,
the person itself as content,
and experiencing yourself more as context.
Yeah?
I mean very good.
Thanks for your help.
I'm looking forward to your new book.
I'm looking for it too myself.
You can imagine how cheerful society is about having the truth revealed about everything.
I mean that's what they say.
Tell the truth,
then leave town several experiences in my life and I shared them with friends
and my husband but I have not been able to talk about them with anyone who could
really give me a more concrete answer about so many years ago probably eight I
was working in the library high school library and it was my habit to go there
I was meditating about four hours a day at the time for about three months and
I'd been meditator for about 25 years anyway but I would go and read the
Upanishads for about 15 minutes before the students would come so I had this
quiet time well it got so as I was reading them I was having this
incredible joy and I understood them not that I could write a comment but I
understood them on a very wonderful level
and
I
and they gave me so much joy, and I couldn't wait to get in there at lunchtime
before the students would come and read my panachat.
I don't know which one I was on, whether, and I agreed with everything it said, wholeheartedly.
And in the middle of my reading, there was this experience.
It was like a veil had opened up.
Everything disappeared.
The library was gone, everything, and I was in this blackness, such a space.
And there were planets and stars coming at me.
That's what I interpreted, that they were light, but I felt I was in the middle of the universe.
And at first, there was me, but I had completely disappeared.
So I said, how's all this here in my heart?
I said it.
And from the right side of...
From the left side of me, it said, all this was made by you, for you, and because of you.
So I said, oh.
And we're in this note today.
So I accepted that, and then there was this, it just kept going on,
and the planets and the stars kept coming faster and faster at me,
as though I was going toward them and they were coming toward me.
And I was in space.
How did I get in the middle of the universe?
I was in a library.
So finally, I felt this incredible loneliness.
It was pit, lonely.
You mean, I'm the only one in the universe?
So we're heading for the void, you understand?
Yes, sir.
And then I became more lonely and perhaps frightened.
And I said, where's God?
Because I wanted to see God, but he wasn't there.
And with that thought, at the time I was thinking, where's God?
This kind of abyss opened up underneath me, at the same time as, and the veil closed.
Yes.
And I feel like I blew up.
You didn't blow anything.
For months after that, I lived in a lot of bliss.
I had no ambition.
My desires were all gone.
I was just happy.
I'd laugh at rocks.
There was no fear.
Everything was friendly.
Yes.
And it faded.
It's gone.
So?
What I want to know.
What's the question?
Did I blow up?
Did I not go through?
Did I lose my courage?
No, no, no.
See, where you were.
Is it really gone forever?
Where you were was the void.
I'll tell you how you know when you're in the void.
The difference between nothingness and allness is the element of reality.
Is in.
In the allness of divinity, the presence of love is overwhelming.
It melts everything with its infinite grace, its infinite power.
There's no feeling of loneliness.
So the loneliness means you're in the void.
Yeah, it was the universe of nothingness.
It's where the pathway of negation will take you.
There are certain teachings that teach you to negate love.
Well, love is one of the qualities of divinity.
And it's a serious error.
The presence of God.
Anybody who's had a near-death experience?
How many people here have had a near-death experience?
All right.
One of the most telling qualities is you're melted by the exquisiteness of the presence of a love beyond which you've ever even imagined.
So you explored the void to see how far it would go.
And you found out that it leads to nothingness.
Loneliness.
Yeah.
But you were in a high place to be checking out the void.
I'm sorry, sir.
You were in a very good, you know, advanced stage because of the years of meditation.
You understand?
So through the meditation, you were going through the pathway of negation.
Not this, not that, not this.
So the next step is to realize that divinity is allness, not nothingness.
Right?
Okay.
You see, to understand God, you see, it's through the misunderstanding of love.
From the ego's viewpoint, love is an attachment.
And if you're going through the pathway of negation, which is let go of attachments and aversions,
you would then begin to see love as an attachment and something that would be standing in your way of enlightenment.
That's emotional attachment on a dualistic basis.
Love is a quality of divinity.
See?
So if you negate the reality of love, you will end up in the void.
The totality of divinity includes love, but not dualistic love, a love of a me for a love of a you.
And if you leave me, I'll kill you.
And I'll own you and possess you.
Let's see what's the shortcut for you.
Shortcut.
What is the shortcut?
I still meditate about the power of the day.
Yeah, I want you to pray to the love of God.
Pray to the love of God.
See?
The pathway of devotional non-duality is non-duality without devotion can lead you into the pathway of negation and bring you to the void.
But it's the devotion to it that takes you into the divinity of the presence.
The presence is also without form, but it includes the quality of love which just wipes you out.
It wipes you out in that state.
And the divinity is love and the completeness of love.
So the difference between the two is the void will take you to a feeling of loss.
The infinite state brings you to a state of completion.
In the state of completion, there's nothing you need.
So that's how you can tell a true spiritual teacher from a false one, which is one of the lessons of today.
A true teacher needs nothing because a true teacher already is all there is.
If you offer him power, he'd say,
What would I do with it?
I got a closet full.
It would be a drag, wouldn't it?
Control over others, power over others, influence over others.
I mean, who would want it?
All right.
So the fact that it left you incomplete, but the void is a very high space to get into.
It shows a lot of work on your part, more than this lifetime to get that far.
Well, is it coming back?
I mean, my life after...
Unless God hates you, yeah.
You pissed me off, girl.
I guess because it faded, because I lived for three months.
It's a stunning space to be in.
It's a very, very stunning space.
To the naive person, they think this is it.
Because it has all the qualities of a finale, there's a finality to it.
There's something about it that is the ultimate.
It is.
It's the ultimate void.
That's not necessarily where I want to go.
No, it's not where you want to go.
You want to go to allness rather than nothingness.
Right, right, right.
At age three, I looked at that at age three.
Huh?
At age three, that was the confrontation.
Allness versus nothingness.
Existence versus non-existence.
So devotion would be the...
Yeah, pray to the love of God.
Pray to the love of God, yeah.
Which is where I started when I was a teenager.
All right.
Just hanging with love.
Just hanging with the love of God, see?
You've done enough of the not this and not that.
I did a lot of that.
You already know you're not this and not that.
I did that a lot.
You're all that is, so now just be inclusive.
All right?
Yes, sir.
So divinity is exquisitely beautiful.
It's exquisite beauty.
It's exquisite gentleness.
And it's loving to the point that you feel like you could melt in it
and die this moment and you would be complete.
Yes, yes, yes.
You know you're there.
When if you're suddenly expired, it would be perfect.
Yes, yes, yes, yes.
Why?
Because you're already complete.
There's nothing more you want.
Right, exactly.
You got it.
Wow.
Thank you for answering.
It's very simple.
Well, it wasn't because for like eight years I feel like I've been...
No.
It's a very stunning space to be in.
The void is a very stunning space.
I felt like I've been in trouble.
Yeah, you were suffering from void shock for a number of years.
Yeah.
Now, that's a...
You think it's a joke.
It is.
It's stunning.
And it leaves you shocked.
That's my husband.
He was with me through this whole thing.
Well, you feel shocked like you have somehow failed.
Yes, I did.
Yeah.
Right.
I felt like I blew it.
You feel like you blew it.
Yeah.
Because the space is very, very impressive.
Yes.
Okay?
God is space.
And it was like...
It's very impressive.
Being part of our space.
It's beyond form.
Beyond time.
Beyond location.
Beyond personal identity.
So, I shouldn't read the punishments anymore?
I love reading them.
I mean, they give my heart joy.
You just do what I tell you.
Okay.
I will.
I'll start.
Where's my teddy bear?
Your teddy bear?
I need my teddy bear.
Okay.
She scared me.
I need my teddy bear.
Well, you see, you meditate on the purr of a kitty and a dog's wagging tail, and it'll
take you from nothingness to happiness.
It'll take you from nothingness to almas.
Okay.
Well, I have a question about God and consciousness.
And here's your teddy bear.
Oh, teddy.
I was frightened.
That lady frightened me.
We're okay, teddy.
We're okay.
Are God and consciousness the same thing?
Or what is their relation?
Consciousness...
I'm trying to write and talk to you at the same time.
Experientially, out of the unmanifest arises the manifest.
Out of the manifest arises the manifest.
Out of the manifest arises consciousness, which is not different than the energy of life.
The light energy of consciousness, life, when it interacts with material matter, spawns
living, biologic life as we know it throughout evolution.
Consciousness is without form.
However, it's within the subjective experiential.
Yeah.
So that would be God manifest to the degree...
That is, God as divinity is subjectively experiential as self with a capital S, huh?
Totally unmanifest.
There would be no capacity for knowing this.
I don't know.
Where's my right arm?
Right arm.
Oh, she's hiding behind me.
Yeah.
That which was just expressed was correct.
Thank you.
I'd never said that before.
Would you repeat it, please?
I can't.
Total consciousness.
Divinity is infinite potentiality, omnipotent.
Omnipotent, omniscient, omnipresent.
That's a potentiality.
It's the God, the Godhead.
Out of the Godhead manifests God as creator.
But that's only an actualization of a potential.
The unmanifest is not bound to become manifest, but out of its potentiality becomes manifest
as the universe.
Within the universe, then, is born the capacity for consciousness and awareness.
The manifestation of God as consciousness, then, is one of the manifestations of divinity,
which we share with God.
Okay?
Okay.
The presence of God within us is knowable by virtue of consciousness itself.
Without the expression of God as consciousness, you would not even know that you exist.
To be aware that you are is already an expression of divinity as consciousness is experienced
in the subjective.
To say, to be aware that you are, to know that you are, to say it is taking you out
of it already.
Yes.
It's knowing.
Knowing it.
Yeah.
Rather than believing, it's knowing.
See, because even to use an intransitive verb like am-ness is already a step down from
reality.
If you calibrate the statement I am, it's less than the ultimate reality.
That which is is beyond all categories, such as beingness, existence.
Am-ness is an intransitive verb, but it's a denigration of the level of the true state.
Thank you.
Thank you for asking me such a fun question.
Did I sign them all?
Thank you.
There are some Lollapaloozas in the audience, huh?
They don't ask you dumb things.
I don't know what it is.
Yes, we are.
Hi.
I would just like to thank you for all your sharing.
Thank you for your sharing.
Yes, ma'am.
And your giving.
You're the most generous teacher I've ever known.
There's nobody there to be generous.
Yes, ma'am.
Thank you.
But nobody there to be generous.
Its just a condition.
If I an anything to do it, I'll be stingy.
Wake up.
Where's the bear?
Where's the king?
He's listening in.
He's eavesdropping.
He thinks that's a microphone dumbbell.
That's the wrong end.
Oh, this way.
Well.
You see-
I can't.
A sense of humor is necessary to existence.
Without a sense of humor, you can't really get along spiritually, I don't think so.
Because humor is the capacity to go outside yourself and laugh at yourself.
You laugh at yourself, you're forgiving yourself.
You're including yourself in and letting it be okay.
So the humor of human life is a way of healing.
You can laugh at yourself well, you see, because everything's ridiculous.
Life is a theater of the absurd.
If you read the daily headlines, you realize it.
Today's madness, you say, I really don't believe this.
Get some guy on TV, you say, I can't believe this is happening.
Theater of the absurd.
So it's comical.
Some spiritual teacher that used to teach me.
I don't know who it is.
It's a serious error to take life seriously.
I think taking life seriously is comical.
So you have to get serious about taking life as being comical.
Yes, Farrah, yeah, golly, whiz.
Yes.
Well, I don't have a story, I don't have a question, and if you knew me two years
ago, you'd know.
You would know what a miracle that is.
Oh, great.
Great.
So you've been through some kind of wondrous transformation, I can see, huh?
No, I can't even speak, see, that's what happened.
It's wonderful.
Oh, God.
It's not explicable.
It's a condition.
It's a condition that prevails.
That's why nobody goes through it takes credit for it.
Nobody becomes egoistic about it.
Nobody becomes egoistic or prideful because it is not of the personal self.
One is the recipient of the benefit of it.
Yeah, I see.
It's terrific.
Yes, sir?
She's referring him up, so if she wants...
Oh, that's fine.
Nobody has to come up.
I'd be happy to sign their books incognito.
Okay, Ben Lawden.
He tried to get my autograph on a book.
Now it's not me.
autograph on a book you saw it okay thank you first of all for being my
spiritual teacher for the last year I've been coming about a year now oh thank
you also from Wisconsin oh wow I've got a question about CEOs you kind of opened
your session this morning talking about female CEOs in my experience I teach
CEOs and write books for them and I would agree the problem is that 99.9% of
the CEOs are men and probably will be for some time I've heard you talk about
CEOs with a great deal of empathy but you've also said they calibrate as a
group in the 190s is that right that particular group of corporations was
right before Enron was but that was before the big fallout okay before the
big fallout not a big corporation so I won't even say what they are calibrated
at 195 around there
mm-hmm now some of them have been taken over and big corporations that were
non-integrated are now over 200 so a lot of them are now over 200 and going
through a reconstruction no I think the average I have 100 greatest corporations
in the world we have permission to do with the CEOs in fortune 500 resist
collective consciousness of the CEO
Johnson the Fortune 500 are over 200
resists 199... scream one hundred
Jesus there are 1.99 well they were worse than that
I've got to do something for corporate America here bleed out the camera on this
one please they were at about 194 195 they were at about 194 they're up to about
199 okay
so
what's happening is because the overall field is 207 it's surfacing everything that is less than
integris every day the headline is that something that we once got away with is now being uh focused
so it's a shift of the culture in which the culture is realizing that integrity shows up on
the bottom line yeah it is going through that integrity every day's headline is about the
integrity of some politician some congressman some businessman some corporation right ninth
circuit court of appeals whatever the question is the integrity of judicial bodies even the supreme
court are they being integrous or are they giving some of us some kind of political bias readout you
know so the integrity of everything
is on the line right now so society where i grew up integrity wasn't on the line
you know you're a democrat voted for roosevelt or you're republican who voted for somebody where it
was eisenhower or somebody uh but integrity wasn't it wasn't the question nobody questioned
roosevelt's integrity or eisenhower's integrity nobody questioned their integrity uh it was
you know whether they were more one party or the other party but their integrity was not in question
well just here's my my question i guess
you better test that with your wife my question is this and i know that ceos in my 30 plus years
of teaching them are probably more open than i've ever seen them before they're getting better and
better and they're more under pressure but i was struck by the the difference between less than 200
and more than 200 in your lecture this afternoon and i know ceos are forming corporate governments
committees they've got the legislation
there's a lot of things that's
happening but my question is
this I'm just finishing up a book called
the CEO challenge
and I'm trying to recontextualize
the whole field of management thanks to your
teachings and I'm
trying to write it for CEOs
and my question is what is
a message that I can
help give that might help this along
a little bit well you see they're under
brutal pressure yes
brutal pressure on the bottom line
and the stockholders want profits
so they're under
brutal pressure unless you're made of steel
I don't know how these guys withstand it see
I don't know how they take it
under brutal pressure
by the way I just had a 20 year
client who got fired
as a CEO after
five years and I talked to him
the other day he said I am so relieved to be
out of that job oh it's a terrible
job he said I can't tell you how happy
I am to be out of that job
it's a very tough job
because you're being pushed to the
edge of non-integrity all the time
yes yes you're really under
fire a slight move in
this direction moving the
stock look at what you all make
and when you got stock options
the move of a
dollar you just made a fortune
I don't know how they do it
is there a message is there
how can I raise their level of consciousness
CEO is a tough
assignment
because on an ethical
viewpoint you are
you have the responsibility
of stewardship
the stewardship
so you have a responsibility
big style
they need
compassion
they need support of everybody in the organization
they need the love
and compassion it's a heck of a job
a very difficult job
I wouldn't want to be CEO of anything frankly
me either
okay thank you very much
it's a whole subject in itself
you know
and one I'm quite interested in too
I'm quite interested in
the difficulty of the businessman
having to show a profit
and the same time remain
integrity
that's right
thank you very much
in the book I was saying about
how people hate success
you see
they really hate it when you're not doing anything
with a vengeance and especially they hit big companies but one of the you want me
to sign something going broke you know the the vilification of capital well
capital as I said this morning is that money in the bank it's a bright idea in
the head from that bright idea in the head multi-billion spawned forth and the
vilification of corporations people forget that most of these the wealth of
these corporations was accumulated over hundreds of years you compare your
lifetime inner earnings and you say compared to that corporation look how
much there they've been in business over 200 years well you put away money at 4%
for 200 years the company the corporations outlive all of us Ford was
established in 1903 Brock where is Brock Brock hey I don't know where he is
anyway Brock got me a list of corporations
you know I don't know where he is anyway Brock got me a list of corporations
many of the giant corporations actually started in the 1700s well 250 years later
so the corporation is huge and powerful not because it's voracious but because
it's been integrally busy for 250 years so that recontextualize is it you want
me to sign something please I don't know where you sign this what is in here your
lunch
I'm going to sign here I don't know if it's gonna start out on there yeah Thank
You
music
写
you
thank you
me
I don't know what you mean by psychic. You mean esoteric?
Yeah.
You mean consciousness?
You mean mind?
Yeah.
Experimenting like what?
Well, I practiced. I started practicing my psychic nature by seeing that if I was capable
of seeing that which is unseen, non-linear, and I started to practice with friends and
people with names, just using the third eye. I read a couple of books, Edgar Cayce and
others, and I found that...
You mean psychism?
Yeah.
Yeah, okay.
I found that actually it was a function of practice and silence, but I found that I could
see people's names, dead people, live people.
People I had no knowledge of.
Mm-hmm.
And incidentally, when this happened, whenever this happened, the other person said, well,
you know, fine, can you see my grandmother's name who died 27 years ago?
Mm-hmm.
And I would take a look at it, and I would literally see her and ask her for permission
to know her name.
Yeah, yeah.
She would give it to me.
Okay.
And this person would right away be sort of...
Yeah.
Sort of astonished or amazed, and then quickly covered up...
Uh-huh.
...as if nothing had happened at all.
So the reason I'm bringing all this up, and this happened, this went on for about six
or nine months...
Mm-hmm.
...is today you mentioned, you were talking about kundalini energy...
...and potentiality...
Mm-hmm.
...and how we had no, we in effect had no power over whether or not we were going to
experience this movement of kundalini energy.
That's true.
So what you're talking about is psychic ability...
Mm-hmm.
...and it can be practiced and learned.
It's been practiced since the days of Mesopotamia.
And so those are psychic abilities.
They occur spontaneously.
They occur spontaneously as a consequence of the kundalini energy.
They can be pursued for their own ends, which is, so the ancient spiritual teachings are
to avoid the cities, S-I-D-D-H-I-S, to avoid pursuit of the cities, and to avoid considering
them to be personal.
That is you performing that, because it is not you performing that.
It is the kundalini energy doing what it does of its own nature, having nothing to do with
you personally.
Mm-hmm.
So there are two different things.
One is kundalini energy...
Mm-hmm.
...which does what the world would consider possible.
...which the world would consider paranormal of its own.
Then there is psychism, which is a pursued skill.
Two different things.
Oh.
So what was I experiencing?
You were pursuing the skill.
Okay.
Mm-hmm.
There's nothing wrong with it.
Okay.
Yeah.
Just practicing.
It's just an altered state of consciousness.
Yeah.
Like learning distant viewing, you know, or out-of-body projection, you know.
I went to Monroe Institute and learned how to go in and out when I want, you know.
What was...
I want to share what I found out.
It's really interesting.
At the same time, I had a lot of dreams and many prophetic dreams.
Mm-hmm.
And in one particular week back in 84, two major airliners went down, one in Japan and
one in Dallas.
Mm-hmm.
And this was like on a Monday, and I had this dream.
And it was so powerful, I called my father who was a pilot.
Mm-hmm.
And I said, I just want to tell you about this dream I'm having.
And, you know, it was about sitting in the rear of the plane in a safe place and so forth.
He said, well, that's interesting.
But the two planes went down, and on Friday, I called him back because I had all this doubt.
Did this really occur?
Did I really have this dream?
Mm-hmm.
And I recognized later that it's like this is the ego covering up anything other than
linear reality.
Mm-hmm.
And I had to literally go to him on Friday and say, did I have this conversation with
you on Monday?
Mm-hmm.
Did I not talk about these dreams?
And he said, yes, you did.
You know, he confirmed it to me.
Yes.
But in my mind, to me, it was the ego covering up, you know, anything that's not within
its realm.
Is that right?
Yeah.
I don't know about that interpretation.
Mm-hmm.
You see, we live in a world of infinite potentiality, any one of which, combined with intention,
combined with karma, plus favorable circumstances, may materialize.
It's one of 10 million options that could materialize.
Sooner or later, one of them's going to materialize.
They materialize.
Yes.
Yeah.
Lincoln saw his own death.
You know, it happens very often.
What'd you say?
Abraham Lincoln saw his own assassination in a dream, et cetera, you know?
Yeah.
Okay.
I was just curious about what you thought about the idea of the ego covering all this
up.
I don't know what you mean by that.
Well, the same thing happened when I came up with a name, and the person across the
table from me was quite shocked by it.
Yeah.
But then suddenly covered up and said, oh, well, yeah, that's my great-grandmother's
name who died 27 years ago, and we never met, who I haven't thought about in 22 years.
Yeah.
What's the question?
I don't get it.
Well, is this the ego covering up this astonishment, this surprise?
Why did they cover this up?
Well, just a statistical likelihood.
Oh.
That's why people are impressed with psychic powers.
Yeah.
I see your grandmother reading the tea leaves.
Okay.
My grandmother used to read the tea leaves.
She did.
Yeah.
Appreciate it.
I see your grandmother reading the tea leaves.
Yes, indeed.
Yeah.
I have a few burning questions for you.
If I tell a lie, what is the energetic repercussion of that in the hologram?
What happens to the person that I'm lying to?
What happens to me?
How does it affect all that is?
When an untruth has happened?
You're never going to affect all that is, you know, because you're an infinitesimal
part of what all that is.
But if everybody does it, then the consciousness level of mankind goes up or down.
Actually, everybody knows unconsciously when they're being lied to.
Yes, yeah, closer.
I want you to be on the other side.
What?
You need to be where you're with me.
Anyway, everybody...
Yeah.
That's great.
This side or this side.
Anyway, everybody knows unconsciously when they're being lied to or just...
Wow.
All right.
So that shows you something interesting.
Because when I calibrated the advertising industry as an industry, it was below 200.
First of all, think how much more, you know, how much more powerful an advertisement would
be.
I used to have hyperacidity, and I take the purple pill, and now my stomach feels fine.
But she's an actress, so she's lying.
Well, I don't think it's somebody who had terrible hyperacidity.
They took the purple pill, and now they feel great.
One would be convincing unconsciously, and the other you know is crap.
Uh-oh.
I used strong language.
I'm sorry.
The other is...
Advertisements would be powerful if they were real.
And if they...
You know, we were calibrating, I think I'm gonna, at the last minute, put in maybe half
a page of advertisements, you know, like the MSN Butterfly.
I mean, he's so stupid looking, how he would sell anything.
That is the dumbest commercial I've ever seen.
On the other hand, Whiskas is hilarious.
Whiskas shows his little, you know, cat and shows this big stag, you know, and then the
kitty stares down the stag and starts to chase the stag, and the stag runs off.
You calibrate that, it's over 500.
What were you gonna ask me?
Well, you know how...
Well, the fact that our thoughts, every one of our thoughts ripples through the universe.
Yes, it does.
Ripples through the hologram.
Yeah, yeah.
So my thought would be that a lie would have some kind of a repercussion for the
hologram.
Well, what about a white lie?
No, no, no.
Right, the different levels of lies.
Exactly.
You could text someone.
Well...
You know, because there's...
Jesus Christ.
Well, you know, you could text someone.
Well, you know, because there's...
Jesus is asking a couple different questions.
Okay.
See, below 200 is force, it's not power.
So an itty-bitty lie at energy field 180, its impact on all of life is insignificant.
Somebody who lies at level 520 is gonna have some serious karmic consequences.
Right.
Yeah.
I mean, in certain realms, murder is nothing.
I mean, you kill 10 or 12 people,
so what does that make you, a big shot?
You get in there with the big boys to kill 10 million,
now you're playing with the big dealers.
The big dealers, 10 million here, 20 million there.
Here, Mayo, 30 million die of starvation
due to Marxist BS, due to totalitarianism.
People want to sell us that paradigm of reality?
No, thank you.
Well, I've also noticed there are different kinds of lying,
like the sin of omission.
We know the intention behind it, right.
You just reveal it all.
There's two intentions.
One is to hurt other people.
That is a different karma than to protect yourself.
Sometimes we lie just to cover ourself.
That's not really injuring anybody.
That's lowering our own internal integrity.
Then sometimes we lie to injure somebody else.
To bear false witness is a rather grave karmic consequence.
It's to bear false witness against your neighbor.
That's why I don't like to hear the severe polemics of political extremes,
because to falsely accuse somebody else
is, you know, violating one of the commandments.
It's not to bear false witness against yourself.
It's to bear false witness against your neighbor,
even if he's running, you know, on the other party.
It's still a grave error, see.
You don't have to vilify chocolate to be the champion of vanilla,
and I wish the politics would learn that.
So if one is of a more high consciousness, like, say, 500,
and you tell a little white lie,
what we call a white lie to protect yourself...
You can't get away with white lies as you move on up.
So even an exaggeration would be considered...
Well, white lies are...
Why are you worrying about that?
Are you going to try and sell me a used car, or what?
What else?
You're going to try and sell me a used car.
Well, that discussion of integrity
and the implications of it in business, you know,
came up over the weekend with the visitor.
I had me discuss the impact of that in business.
Well, that was one of my burning questions.
Another one is...
Oh.
Go ahead.
When I have the desire to pray for another person,
how do I do that without being in a positionality or thoughts
or in some way judging their experience or their life
because I'm wanting to pray for, you know...
You want to change them, really.
Probably.
You're trying to change their spiritual destiny.
I want to help them, send them energy, whatever you want to call it.
Yeah, right.
You're going to undo their negative karma, or what?
Well, I guess I'm wondering, how do I connect with another being with prayer?
Why do you want to connect with them?
Maybe I'm stuck in the new age.
I don't want to connect with any dead people. Do you?
No, no, no. Not dead people. Live people.
Oh, live people.
Yeah, like I want to pray for somebody who is...
Oh, I got you.
...having problems in their life or, you know...
Well, if you stay to the highest good, then you're doing well.
You see, because what you see as disaster is frankly to their highest good.
Yeah. I do have that caveat in my prayer.
I say to the highest good...
Then you're okay.
Okay.
See, because the person's highest good, you can see they're speeding rapidly towards the bottom in disaster.
And that's just what their higher self is holding for them.
If you try to prevent the disaster, you just, you know, delayed their salvation.
Because it was only by hitting bottom that they are going to rise to the top.
So, therefore, trying to change it out there, you know, is being quite naive.
Because, like you said, your perception may not be what it's about at all.
Just like we applaud people's success, and that success is, you know, what's going to take them to the bottom.
We see that happen all the time to celebrities and various people.
Is it still worthwhile to pray for them then?
I don't know. That's what your motive is, you know.
Otherwise, you wouldn't be asking the question.
You're trying to change people, influence them, control things.
You're messing around with other people's karma and stuff.
On the other side is the gooderism, and on the other side is genuine spiritual commitment.
So you have to find out where you are and all that.
It feels like I have a high motivation of just sending them energy of help and caring.
Did they ask you to do that?
No.
Okay, thank you.
That's a big one going down.
There's different answers at different levels.
But I get you're about to transcend that level.
Otherwise, you wouldn't be asking me the question.
Probably.
If you're trying to influence other people.
Yeah.
But you're already getting that intuitively.
That's why you're asking me.
Yeah.
Let them worry about it.
Let their own karma and their own be what it is.
Okay.
Your intention to be loving towards them, of course, is great.
And the last question I wanted to ask you is, okay, it's beyond the third dimension that we're in right now.
Third dimension?
Is that just a new age thing?
I was in the 9th or 10th generation.
Are you still back in the third?
Go ahead, sweetheart.
I'm just kidding along with you.
I know.
Yeah.
The past, present, and future at some point becomes one.
We're not in time anymore, right?
Yeah.
At some point.
So from that place, I'm assuming it's all the past, present, and future become one somewhere in the future.
One somewhere in the field of consciousness itself.
No, they don't become one.
But they are one.
They don't become anything.
Well, this is in reference to the fact that calibrating...
See, they're not three separate things that then become one.
Right.
They're three separate things to begin with.
In other words, just no time.
There's no past, present, or future.
In the space that we're talking about.
But with the tool of kinesiology, we are only to calibrate present statements.
What is?
Yes.
So past, present, and future are all one beyond here anyway, though.
I don't know.
It's too much to think about.
I don't know what you mean.
I guess I'm trying to ask why we can't calibrate the future if the future is the same...
Because it has no existence.
It has no reality.
Yeah, I know that based on your information.
But if the future is the same as the present and the past...
You're confusing it intellectually.
You're playing with it conceptually.
It isn't a conceptual thing.
It's obvious that the future has no reality because otherwise there would be no evolution
of consciousness.
There would be no spiritual merit.
Because the universe is waiting for you to collapse the wave function.
Through the Heisenberg principle, intention itself, consciousness itself already takes
potentiality into actuality.
The minute you look at a thing, it's already changed.
You cannot see the same thing twice because you're looking at it has already changed it.
So, therefore, no future could possibly be known because it depends on an infinite number
of decisions and choices.
So that's why you can't predict future events.
What's going to happen in the year 5083 is all in your head.
Nobody can predict what's going to happen in the year 5083.
Not possible.
Because the future is only a potentiality.
Free choice means that you are where you are within the infinite field by virtue of choice.
You choose this.
If the fate was of all of the universe was already set, predetermination, there would
be no point to life anyway.
So predestination is just an intellectual concept.
You got it.
It's not the same as karma.
No, they're not the same.
You got it.
Because divinity, once you understand the nature of divinity, you realize that predestination
and divinity are not compatible.
Divinity cannot be divinity and still be the source of predestination unless you project
forward into the future and now the present becomes the past.
You see what I'm saying?
I don't know what that meant, but it sounded good.
Thank you.
That should shut her up, I guess.
Yeah, you get into intellectual constructs.
It's a good question.
I mean, she's got a lot of good questions.
Hi.
Yeah.
A question about resistance.
Is it best to resist nothing or is there nothing to resist?
That's a conundrum.
How could you resist nothing?
There'd be nothing to resist.
What do you mean by resisting nothing?
You mean don't resist anything, not nothing.
So don't resist anything that comes up.
Yeah, true.
All right.
The other way is to resist everything all the time.
Yeah.
Thank you, Dr. Hawkins.
Well, my main question would be that I tried the kinesiology testing.
Yes.
She tried kinesiology.
But I would like to know how would I get more consistent answers or more
consistency?
Yeah.
I would like to know how would I get more consistent answers or more clear answers.
I don't know.
It depends on what the basic problem is.
We'd have to do like a short individual workshop with you.
As I mentioned this morning, the capacity to do it, first of all, not everybody has
it.
Secondly, it's limited to probably 10% of the population anyway.
The intentionality, the intention behind the question has to be integrous.
I would always say in the name of the highest good, you can't have any personal interest.
You can't have any personal interest in the outcome.
And the background in the setting has to be appropriate.
And you may need special training.
It's not the easiest thing in the world for some people.
Some people it becomes very easy and other people it's quite difficult.
Susie teaches it to a lot of people and she usually finds out what's wrong.
Sometimes they're holding the arm too straight.
I would say a lot of people resist the arm going weak.
It's a very transitory weakness.
And the ape in us thinks it's falling out of a tree.
So you get it, especially in macho guys.
The minute the arm goes weak, they're unconsciously falling out of a tree and their ape comes
up with strength, see?
And they get high answers for everything, you know?
My dog calibrates over 1,000, 2,000, 3,000.
We get letters all the time.
My dog calibrates over 900, I think.
Wow.
Yeah.
So it's a technique.
It has to be learned.
Sometimes there's a kinesiologist.
A lot of times a holistic practitioner.
And there's actually a kinesiologist that you can see for a private consult.
Do you ever read Dr. Diamond's book?
So you need education.
Your Body Doesn't Lie by Dr. Diamond is a classic in the field.
So you just need more education.
Also, have you heard of a contemplative outreach, Father Thomas Keating?
Yes.
Centering prayer.
We spoke up there.
We were with Father Keating a few months ago.
Yeah.
He's a big guy.
He's over six foot tall.
Yes.
Look up there.
I'm high, brother.
Yes.
Yeah.
We spoke at the St. Benedict's Monastery up there.
Met with monks.
And we did a public thing.
Yes.
We did a public thing in the city hall there in Aspen.
It's a beautiful monastery.
Yeah.
Beautiful place.
So centering prayer and contemplative outreach.
Yes.
He's the champion of centering prayer.
Which got him into a little trouble with the church itself, too.
But he handled it.
The classic religion distrusts the mystic.
And I represent the mystic.
So when I spoke to the monks, they didn't say anything.
I don't know if they were praying silently inside.
The worry is that without ecclesiastic guidance, a person could go wrong.
And that it sees authority as protective of the naive soul that could wander off into
wide avenues.
There's a certain reality to that.
So I don't discredit it.
Certain reality.
Because we get a lot of bizarre letters out there.
Where people do get derailed.
Yeah.
I know Father Keating.
Thank you.
I enjoyed him, too.
In fact, we had dinner with him, didn't we?
Aye.
Even for someone like yourself, how susceptible is kinesiology to the Luciferic?
Luciferic means, too, is the temptation of power.
I remember when the Luciferic came.
Non-verbally, as a knowingness, power for its own sake was what it was about.
I don't know what that's got to do with kinesiology.
Of getting, having a Luciferic influence give you the wrong answer.
Well, that would be the intentionality of the person using it.
The person who seeks to use it for gain, for power.
Usually, the misuse of it is to verify positionality.
People want you to calibrate something they've already got a really screeching positionality
about.
You know?
To verify that their candidate is better than this candidate's.
Or this spiritual teacher is better than that spiritual teacher.
They have a vested interest.
So, I'd say Luciferic use is a vested interest.
A vested interest.
Something to gain by it.
Instead of a tool, it's something to gain by.
But even if you have positive intentions of the Luciferic energy trying to get in there
and giving you wrong answers?
That's the whole point of being Integrist.
So, because both are over 200 and the question is Integrist, the Luciferic does not prevail.
Here you say, in the name of the highest good.
See, the Luciferic has a vested interest in one answer or the other.
The Luciferic is certainly not interested in one answer or the other.
It's certainly not interested in what is the highest good.
It's not interested in the stockholder.
It's interested in exercising its stock options.
But it's not interested in the welfare of the stockholder.
So, yes, I understand what you're saying from a hypothetical viewpoint.
And I looked at myself quite a bit.
Can I have a hug?
Huh?
You can have a hug.
I'm going to put some devious burp behind me.
Now, that's a very good question.
Very good question.
It shows he's not asleep.
No, you see he's not into denial.
He realizes that there's things out there that are antithetical to spirituality
and purity and integrity, you know?
And it comes looking for your chinks.
Yes, it does look for your chinks.
Huh?
Yeah.
All right.
Um.
My question is regarding the idea of the soul moving up through evolution
like a cork in the ocean.
Yes.
Now, it's, I mean, personally, I feel I can see it in the world.
And you mention in your book that suddenly a soul, for one reason or another,
will put down a heavy foot and start backpedaling.
Yes.
What is the divine quality that would motivate a soul to suddenly want to U-turn?
To suddenly what?
Do a U-turn instead of continuing to evolve towards a higher power.
Yeah.
And suddenly make decisions that lower...
Well, because there's traps all along the way.
That which hates integrity is out to get you.
You realize that the tremendous gain that huge parts of the population get from non-integrity,
you try and get Israel and Palestine to quit their war, they're going to assassinate you
the minute you look like you're serious about peace.
Because their whole game is war.
Why should they like what you have to present?
Well, you know, I don't know.
I don't know.
Why should they look favorably on 540?
Why would the 540 then suddenly make decisions that lowers it's consciousness down to 190?
Oh, why do people fall...
Yes.
...Because, um...
There's temptations at each level.
There's temptations.
When you say, I am so-and-so, you instantly bring up the idea that you're a genius.
You kill your enemy.
say I am so-and-so you instantly bring up the test of whether that what you
just said is a fact or not the energies that that lose by virtue of your
integrity are out to bring it down and it's commonly called temptation in
proverbs in proverbs it's well spoken in proverbs that the alluring creature who
whispers into your ear be aware of the alluring creature who whispers in your
ear to forsake the wisdom of ones the collective wisdom of one's father's they
see to turn from wisdom to the seduction so integrity is seduced all the time if
your consciousness gets seriously a threat through non-integral forces they
come out
in great numbers
and you get hit by psychic
attacks right and left
looking for what's out
and what shocker of one archetype
that you're unconscious
where can they bring up fear
where can they bring up greed
where can they bring up gain
is there not a danger then to
alright, more questions
we're just going to sign books
alright
is that good enough for now?
yes
it brings forth a test at every level
we'll just sign books
we'll just sign books, come on
and if anybody's got a question that's brief
we'll do it while we keep talking
calibration level of the audience
the audience went up over 8 points
10 points
11 points
12 points, 14 points
15 points
the audience went up
the consciousness level of the collective audience
went up 14 points
today's lecture
14 points
thank you for asking me
and you, I hope you enjoyed it
thanks a lot for the
Wisconsin and the Maryland
yeah, it was fun
yeah, I missed the wonderful chocolate
in Milwaukee, you had the best bakery
German bakery