I knew I was gone all the time.
Here
we are in Toronto. Wonderful, beautiful
city.
Don't remember ever having been here
before.
Anyway, visited Magna Falls, calibrated
the energy of uh Toronto
at the request.
America's at 421, Toronto's at 423.
various cities at different levels.
Toronto
is a very good city. Beautiful. All
right.
So, we came today to together to review
uh uh the impact of the work and what
we've learned from it as it applies to
human consciousness as it applies to
everyone in the audience.
So we're going to do today is um
discover how things come to be and then
a group like this.
The problem is going to be how to
transcend the intellect
the world of duality. And so we're going
to trace the evolution of the ego from
the beginning of time up to the present
time. And once you understand the nature
of the ego,
it's much easier to transcend it.
The traditional way has been to oppose
the ego and declare it as evil and sin.
Uh see it as the downside of life,
something to be conquered,
something to feel guilty about,
frightened of, angry about.
Instead, we're going to see how it
evolves
and we're going to adopt our ego, love
it, and transcend it. Dissolve it,
which is easier than the sack cloth of
ashes. Go on your knees from here to the
pyramid back again or something.
Okay. Say, would Jesus have a
microphone?
If everybody asks you would Jesus do
this or Jesus do that
make it in this world.
>> He said me instead.
>> Yes.
So we begin with the ending of the
lectures. will begin in the end and then
move backwards to the beginning. Saves a
lot of time that way.
A group like this, the difficulty this
is a very areaike group. Uh this group
is probably over 423 424.
Yeah, this is a this these groups uh
like this are
you know educated and intelligent and
so the the mind and the ego which is
what brings us into the awareness the
spiritual truth and gives us the the
motivation to study it uh then becomes
the limitation. So, it is the canoe and
uh at the other side of the creek, how
do you let go of the canoe?
How to transcend the canoe? So, a group
like this, we're still dragging our
canoe.
It got us this far and now how do we get
rid of it? So, they were going to figure
out how to transcend your canoe and so
you'd be free on the other side.
The big difficulty with an educated
group like this is we're stuck in the
world of causality. We're stuck in the
Newtonian paradigm of reality.
The ego is dualistic.
It believes in a this that causes a
that.
The pathway I teach is called devotional
nonduality.
Devotional nonduality. How to transcend
the v thisness and the thatness, the
dualistic
ego which confuses perception with
essence. It thinks that it's the cause
of things. Therefore, you're subject to
guilt, anxiety, fear.
If there's a this causing a that, then
there must be a this within here causing
a that.
And that reinforces the illusion of the
reality of the ego. And therefore, we're
going to figure out today we'll we'll
illustrate clearly how to transcend it.
So we'll start at the end of the lecture
of how things actually come into
manifestation.
Each and everything
becomes what it is
as the actualization of a potential,
not as a result of any external cause
within the invisible domain, the
unmanifest.
There be there is the potentiality.
Potentiality
within an infinite powerful field
becomes an actuality.
Each thing
becomes the expression of that which it
is
solely on its own
not due to anything else out there.
The flower has the potentiality. The
seed has potentiality.
You put that seed in an infinite a field
of infinite power.
Its potentiality becomes an actuality
when conditions are appropriate.
It only awaits appropriate conditions.
You can picture how life comes about
then. The infinite divinity, the
infinite field of consciousness
is the unmanifest which becomes manifest
knowable experience as infinite field of
consciousness.
The infinite field of consciousness is
like a giant electromagnetic like a
giant electrostatic field.
Electromagnetic electrostatic field of
infinite power and infinite dimension
which includes all that is
out of the unmanifest arises the
manifest which first presents
as the infinite field of consciousness
of infinite power.
to go into states of enlightenment. One
of the staggering things is the
recognition, the realization
of the degree of power. The power is so
incredible that it's beyond all
imagination.
Its absoluteness is absolute.
When dealing with the infinite,
you're dealing with the absolute. The
absolute
The absolute which is also exquisitly
gentle.
The presence is like
infinite power beyond all comprehension
at the same time exquisitly soft.
It melts what was left of the personal
self.
Therefore, things happen.
Happen is
the way we observe things. We say they
happen.
What we mean is we just notice it.
We just notice it because it's a
continuity. The fact that you notice it
doesn't cause it happening.
It's just that you noticed it.
Each and everything then within a power
infinite an infinite power electro
magnetic field. Each of us is like a
little iron filing.
We karmically evolve over vast eons of
time. Today we'll look at how it arises
vast of time to become that way
throughout we are. So you could picture
yourself like a little molecule or a
little iron filing.
And what you look like depends on all
the decisions
and things you've done throughout an
infinite number of lifetimes.
As a consequence of this, you look like
this or like this or however. So,
however you're going to be in this giant
field depends on your configuration.
You see, nothing is arbitrary. The
justice of God is continuous
absolute ongoing.
One doesn't have to worry about judgment
day being later. Judgment day is right
now. Every moment is judgment day. Every
moment like an iron fing you are exactly
at the perfect place within this giant
electromagnetic field.
Consequently, if you leave the body, if
you leave the body,
world gets emotional about that.
When you leave the body, it's fantastic.
You're free of it. Oh, there's a lane
down there and you are exactly in the
perfect place.
Where else could you be except
where you are and where you are depends
on what you have become. So all happens
autonomously as a consequence of that
which it is.
Everything that comes into
manifestation,
it has a potential potential with a
within a infinite power in a field of
infinite power then actualizes.
Potentuality becomes actuality.
Each thing arises of its own as a
consequence
and with the intrinsic design.
To understand the design, it's useful to
look at Sheldre's
Sheldrake
discovered
that what he calls formative causation.
The design of things prior to the emerg
their emergence within the world.
The design occurs in a field of
consciousness.
A very powerful and interesting concept.
We can see it in the construction of the
Empire State Building.
The man sitting at his desk with his
feet up there smoking a cigar and he
says, "Wow, what if we built the tallest
building in the world?"
Tallest building in the world. In his
mind, he sees this thing going up like
that. He gets enthused. He starts to
talk it up. Bank anchors get interested.
Union is bid for the job. Won't walk
Indians are the only ones who could
climb all the way up there anyway.
Steel company's bid. You see how the
whole thing the banks underwrite it. But
it was just a vision in his mind. And
now the whole thing manifests.
And in the middle of the depression,
Empire State Building went up in exactly
one year. One year. God's building the
world of time all came out of nowhere
wasn't caused by anything.
There isn't any building causer machine
that produced it out of nothingness.
So
the other thing to know is that
everything arises out of nothing
especially thoughts. As you meditate,
you realize, you see, if you're stuck in
causality, the Newtonian paradigm, you
think one thought is causing another
thought,
an infinite series of thoughts. And
people are frustrated with meditation
and say, "I can't get my thoughts to
stop." With close observation, you'll
see that each thought is rising out of
nothing.
It arises out of nothing. The next stop
arises out of nothing. They're not like
bills sequentially going from A to Z.
Each one arises independently.
It could arise A and then B and then C.
But they all arose from nothing.
The B does not arise from the A. The B
arises from nothing. The sea arises from
nothing. Each thing
thoughts emerge like flying fish out of
the sea.
The sea is the nothingness, the
potentiality, capacity, the think
consciousness itself. Here comes a
flying fish. Here comes another one and
another one. Here comes another one.
Flop all over the deck.
I was into the South Pacific and they
would fly all over. Now this line, this
fish here does not cause this fish here
to come up. You understand? So the
observer could say, well, the first one
up is A. This is fish A. This is fish B.
This is the seat the seat that came up
like ABC but the ABC is in your mind
ABC in the world.
So
main
observation
there is rest kajans
rest internal that is the world of
thinkingness the mind and then there is
rest external the world as it is nature
the world as it is without ugly thoughts
about it
and it's a griev mistake the two to
think that rit intern represents That's
for sex externa. What you think about
the world is one thing. What the world
is is something else. Very often you're
not related at all.
More often than not,
you have no relationship at all.
Appearance is not essence. Occurrence is
not essence.
Therefore, one of the classic
spiritual
tools has been humility.
The awareness that the mind alone unaded
up in and of itself is unable to discern
reality.
That was the most major stunning
discovery of all the work we did. The
mind in and of itself by virtue of its
construction is dualistic construction.
The ego by virtue of how it's
constructed is incapable of telling
truth from falsehood.
So much for pontification.
I see people on TV their faces red with
emotion waving their hands and fists and
stuff.
And when you calibrate what they're
talking about, it calibrates like 120.
Completely the opposite of the truth.
That doesn't prevent people from
believing it. So
throughout time it said that life is
impossible without the help of an
advanced spiritual teacher. Why?
Because
the mind in and of itself is unable to
discern reality. Cannot tell. Therefore,
the great teachers throughout all time
arose,
arrived, developed, evolved, popped out
of
initiality and to act to actuality.
Um
to make people aware of what is what is
truth. You call that truth spiritual.
That's sort of labeling me. What if we
didn't use the word religion or
spiritual? Well, what if we just said
that's truth?
Anything wrong with that? It would solve
all kinds of rivalries, wouldn't it?
Everybody could give up war because it's
always based on some
philosophic religious premise.
What if we just said the only thing
that's true about truth is truth and we
don't care who said it.
I don't care who said it. George Peabody
not to kiss his butt because he said
truth. I mean what is that?
Some guy knew the truth.
You know the truth is so rare in the
history of mankind that we have called
them avatars.
man in and of himself uninfant know what
is the truth and the occasional
individual who
manifested that then is so rare that we
re rever them throughout history
man had no way to know truth and false
except by the authority of an
enlightened being the great avatars
great saviors of mankind alone knew the
truth
It recurred throughout time. The great
sages of ancient India thousands of
years before Christ, before Buddha
stated the same truth. So we see that
the same truth is rediscovered,
re-realized,
repronounced,
spoken of again over and over throughout
time, usually with long time lapses. But
the truth is always the same. No matter
what culture, no matter what era,
whether it was 7,000 BC,
whether it was the time of the Buddha
500 BC, whether it was Christ
Zoraster,
the truth has always been the same. Each
one who's discovered it spontaneously,
autonomously
have declared it to be exactly the same.
There's no difference. No difference
to a group like this which is destined
to enlightenment or else they wouldn't
be here.
People in this room are distant for
enlightenment.
>> People in this room are distant for
enlightenment. Otherwise, they wouldn't
be here.
If you're into golf, you'd be out on the
golf course.
Who would be at a lecture like this
unless they people were in you know
distant that was their destiny. Okay
to make the road easier then we'll try
to describe how the ego evolved what its
nature is and therefore how to transcend
it because
it is perception that stands in the way
of the realization of truth.
Each thing then comes into existence by
virtue of its potentiality becoming an
actuality
under appropriate conditions.
That gets rid of blame.
There's nothing out there causing
anything to be any other than what it
is. Nothing's causing it.
Everything is happening
is the actualization of its potentiality
within a field of infinite power.
That explanation, let's see,
that explanation calibrates over 800,
850,
840. It's good enough for today.
toonian causality calibrates about 460.
All right. So what we're describing is
how it actually comes about a deal
closer to the truth.
We witness potentiality becoming
actuality because the conditions are
appropriate
and it happens because of the infinite
power of the field.
There was a seed alongside the road in
uh Arizona
that you started to all of a sudden this
century plant started to come up.
There's nothing there. nothing but dirt.
In fact, that seed laid there 150 years.
We calibrated it.
150 years this seed lay there and
suddenly out of nowhere the conditions
are appropriate and this incredible
century plant shoots up and within one
seating becomes this glorious and
fantastic and magnificent display.
Seemingly out of nowhere after waiting
150 years, 150 years. You say, well, it
rained a lot of times in 150 years,
but currently not the right combination
to trigger the whole phenomena.
Therefore, you can't always tell from
local conditions what's causal. As you
look around at this plant every year,
there's no conditions there to
potentiate its growth. Why 150 years out
of seeming nothingness does this plant
suddenly arise?
All right. So I thought today we'll
cover the basics and we'll also describe
somewhat how these awarenesses came
about
and we'll take a break in the morning
and we'll have lunch we'll take another
break in the afternoon and then we'll
have personal questions and answers. All
right. So let's let's see we do have
slides. Let's start with the calibrated
levels of consciousness which are
becoming
pretty rather widespread within the
world relatively well known. We have a
pointer here.
We had a great one which we I left in my
suitcase.
Therefore, God must want me to have this
one. Right.
work.
Actually, I made this is supposed to
have a flag on it. I saw it off the flag
thing, took the flag off, and now I have
a point.
>> Theiology is a strange phenomenon.
physiology
the the abs the only absolute in the
universe then is an infinite field of
consciousness which is the absolute
philosopher Hegel in the beginning of
the 1800s
one of his principles was that of the
absolute
absolute there is an absolute
by which all else can be to which all
else can be compared
an absolute reality, not an absolute
hypothesis, but an absolute existent
reality by which and against which
everything else can be deferred. That
was never discovered before and it was
only a philosophic proposition even in
the 1800s.
But that's exactly what we're relying
on.
The field of consciousness then is like
a giant electrostatic field. You
remember the days of electro
electrostatic uh speakers where was that
back in the 70s? You used to get these
big jumps and it was so the
electrostatic speaker is really just a
charged membrane that's it's one charged
positive or negative I forget which
doesn't difference
one or the other.
and you bring up electrons of of an
opposite charge. So the electrostatic
field is really a potential. It doesn't
do anything. It just is. Then when you
bring up a certain charge, it
automatically responds
complete and totally opposite to the
charge but to the exact degree.
82 billion electrons here result in 82
billion posetrons. So that on opposite
sides of the membrane you'll always have
complete balance.
The field of consciousness itself then
has only it doesn't do anything. It just
is
it registers everything that happens
for everything that happens. So it's
like a giant electro electrostatic
field.
Every thought, everything that happens
in the universe, every human being,
every living thing
uh radiates energy. And this energy
radiation, every thought that you have,
every movement, every decision,
it has a consequence.
And the consequence is registered within
the field of consciousness. The field of
consciousness is not a flat fl
electromagnetic
electrostatic speaker but it is
everywhere present at all times
everywhere equally present.
All that happens all that's ever said
thought felt all that's ever existed
is automatically recorded in this field
forever.
Every thought you've ever had is
recorded forever.
Scripture says every hair on your head
should be counted. That is a fact.
It's usually held up as a threat. Every
hair I'm hear is going to be counted.
Every kind thought you have is also
thought recorded.
Happily, positive thoughts are so much
more powerful than negative thoughts.
Frankly, you can have negative thoughts
all day long. Have one happy, loving
thought, it wipes it all out.
Positive thoughts are so infinitely more
powerful than negative thoughts. But
negative thoughts by their sheer
multiplicity have an effect in the
world.
When I first saw kinesiology, it was Dr.
John Diamond and
New York City. It was one of those iffy
sort of things and I went because people
of you know pretty good awareness
recommended it. So when I went to see uh
John Diamond, he was demonstrating
kinesiology the way it's used in
clinical medicine, holistic health and
holistic medicine.
You know, you hold a turnup next to your
solar plexus and it makes your arm go
weak. I'm sure they come here for a week
at Colorado.
My grandmother was from Ireland.
Colorado's birthday turnips on.
So the only difference was the audience
saw it as a local phenomena. They saw it
as the turnup now makes your arm go
weak.
So we found that in the presence of that
which is positive your arm goes strong.
In the presence of that which is false
or negative your arm goes weak. That
which supports life makes the arm go
strong. That which is unimicable to
life. False being one of them makes the
arm go weak. And this is an impersonal
reaction of the field of consciousness
itself. It's impersonal. It doesn't care
what you think at all.
So Susie and I have done it so many
times, millions of times, hundred for
this current book that we're putting
out. We did 7,000 calibrations.
7,000 times the world couldn't care
less. The physi the arm just goes weak
in the presence of falsehood and it goes
strong in the presence of that which is
positive. So you might say it's sort of
a quality of life. It's almost like
protoplasm. It's impersonal like a
protoplasmic response.
Protoplasm knows like an amoeba knows
that which is good for it. The amoeba
goes opens towards that which is
lifegiving and it retracts and closes up
and withdraws from that which is
life-threatening to it. It's an
automatic consequence. It's not
personal. First difficulty people
usually have is they think it's
personal. However, we get the same
exactly the same answers if we verbalize
them or we don't verbalize them.
In fact, when it's a very important
calibration, I'll say what I'm holding
in mind calibrates over 200, 300, 340,
420, 2020.
Let's do one. We won't tell audience
what it is. I'm holding in mind
calibrates over 420, 421. Okay. Now, I'm
going to hold something else in mind.
When I'm holding mine, calibrates over
422.
I'm holding mine calibrates over 423.
Okay.
She doesn't know what I'm holding in
mind.
So, how does it happen? If if she
doesn't know what I'm holding in mind,
how can her arm respond with yes or no?
It's because it's happening within the
field of consciousness itself.
The thought form I'm holding interacts
with her electrostatic field.
When she goes weak, the acupuncture
system is temporarily out of commission
and that's the kinesiologic response.
The field of consciousness then
recognizes truth. It goes strong in the
presence of truth. It doesn't go weak in
the presence of false. So it just
doesn't respond.
Therefore, the kinesiologic response is
not yes versus no. It's
True versus not true.
That's an important duality to trans
transcend.
It's not yes versus no. A thing is
either true or not true.
Therefore, in reality, there is no such
thing as falsehood because that would be
non-truth and non-truth has no
existence.
So, that which exists make your arm go
strong.
That which is false and has no existence
has no charge. In the presence of
nothingness, the arm goes weak. So it's
not yes versus no.
It's true versus the absence of truth.
There is no opposite to truth. It's
either present or absent. We'll get to
that on a slide. Like there's no
opposite to light.
Darkness is merely its opposite, but
it's not it is merely its absence. I'm
sorry. It's absence, not its absence,
not its opposite. All right. So, we
talked today about the calibrated levels
of consciousness and this is how they
evolved and we calibrated them on a
scale of one to a thousand. He said
the numbers are so huge as
power goes up the numbers become log so
huge you have to use logarithms to
handle them. On a logarithmic scale, we
found that you could calibrate all of
life that's ever existed on this planet
on a scale of 1 to 10,000.
Beginning with number with one, bacteria
are the first conscious living entities
on the planet. The bacteria caliber is
one and the great avatars. Jesus Christ,
Buddha, Krishna,
they're great avatars. We're the highest
level of consciousness that's ever
walked the planet.
and that was 1,000. So we discovered you
could calibrate the energy of anything
and everything that ever existed on a
scale of 1 to a,000.
And in doing so, we'd also made the
discovery that everything that
calibrates 200 or below makes you go
weak. That which is false, fellacious.
We find that these are the numbers down
here less than 200.
200 and up makes you go strong. 200 and
up makes you go strong. So it's a simple
test of true versus not true.
Mankind has never had capacity in all of
its history
to be able to tell truth from falsehood.
All the philosophic systems You look at
the huge libraries fully zillions of
books. Not a one of them can even tell a
truth from falsehood.
How we survived it all.
You can't tell truth from falsehood.
You pull the arm on the machine. I know
you're going to lose.
You're not going to be convinced of it
till they take your money. So you do
that over and over again.
see if maybe next time it'll be
different
except they've got the odds set the
same.
I quit slot machines in grade school. My
dad says and I'm at the American Legion
for fundraising. He said there's 6040.
Yeah. It said 6040. I says, "You mean
you're guaranteed to lose 60% of your
money?" He says, "Yes." That's what I'm
playing
6040. All right. So then we discovered
that if you if you you can calibrate
everything on the planet including all
of human mankind we found that the
evolution of consciousness was
over a period of time slowly evolved and
we'll do a chart on that at the time of
the birth of Buddha the calibrated level
of consciousness of mankind was at 90
at the time of the birth of Jesus
Christ, the calibrated level of
consciousness of mankind was 100.
It slowly evolved over the centuries
during the six 1500s, time of the black
plague on up through the 1800s, it
stayed at 190.
It stayed there until the late 1980s,
uh 87 around in there. And then at the
time of the harmonic concordance, not
caused by it, but at the same time, it
jumped to 205. The most dramatic event
in all of history. The most powerful
event that has ever happened in all of
history is when the collective
consciousness of mankind went from 190
to 205.
Silent, unspoken, unnoticed.
People
expect the second coming of Christ to
bearded
fellow who goes on television. I guess
tell you back
to me. The coming of second coming
Christ was the dominance of truth.
Christ consciousness now dominates the
planet
after 2,000 years.
consciousness level is now over 200.
Therefore, the energy sent forth by the
great avatar.
We think a thousand years is a long
time. It is not. In only 2,000 years
now, it dominates
the consciousness of mankind is now. It
was went over to 205.
Then last year in San Francisco was uh
at the end of a conference like we're
having today
on October 14th there was this another
great harmonic accordance
and at 5:15 consciousness level of
mankind was 205. The collective
consciousness of all of mankind was at
205.
And then
with people around the world we all
prayed. at home chanting
and at 5:35
conscious the level of mankind is where
it is today. 207
a whole different world at 207 than it
is at 190.
At 190 not integrity gets by is the way
it is. That's why Dennis is done. You
slip a few bucks. You teach a little.
Just don't take too much. No,
no boy network
worked at 190 was way life two five
don't work. Uh-oh.
You see the great corporations falling.
And therefore in the old world before
consciousness level was 205. Success
was what it was about. Success, money,
stature, big name, big house, big car.
Now at 205 and now 207
the new signature is integrity.
Big corporations fall right and left.
The old boy network just doesn't work
out. Little tip here, little tip there.
Whoa. At 207, you get yelled on the
carpet for that. Now we live in a world
in which integrity is the predominant
quality.
And if we fault anybody on any level in
society, it's for lack of integrity. You
can be wrong if you're integrous about
being wrong.
Make sure you're honest about being
wrong. Nothing wrong with being wrong.
Well, you're sure about it.
And if you're not sure about it, say
look at it's the best guess. the the
best guess you got. You should take it
left, Emma. She says, "No, we should
make it right." Our best guess we do
with kinesiology. Should we turn left or
right? Oh, wait. Left.
Can't get lost in the woods anymore.
Should we turn left or we turn right?
There you go.
All right. So, we we discovered that
these things were correlated with human
emotions
and
conditions. The way they view God, they
view way people view God. the way they
view themselves.
We label these levels. We gave them the
log of the number and these are the
predominant emotions. And this is the
process going on.
The process going on in consciousness.
You see the egotism we call that
inflated. Uh they're prideful people. Uh
they're demanding and arrogant.
And uh they really don't care much about
God at all unless it's useful to back up
their positionality in which case they
become very they talk a lot about God.
God is favorable to their position. They
talk a lot about
God just becomes a uh another tool of
pridefulness.
Level 200 is critical. Level 200. Um,
you now have the capacity to take
responsibility.
Responsibility.
Seeing yourself that it's who you've
become that is responsible for the
phenomena around you. The minute you do
that in the 12step groups, that's the
first step. You stopped lying about
things. You started to tell the truth.
You took responsibility.
As a consequence of that, your life
became transformed
because the minute you take
responsibility for yourself, you shoot
above 200. These people are a negative
attractor fields, they tend to attract
negative things to them.
Each one of these levels of
consciousness then attracts to it and is
aligned with it with what we call an
attractor energy field. That's a term
for nonlinear dynamics. Nonattra's
an attractor field. When you see a swarm
of birds, you know, swooping like this
or the fish under the sea and like a big
rolling donut.
People think, well, each bird is
following the other bird. You know, like
airplanes, you know, he's lining up with
this bird. He's lining up with this
bird. He's lining up with this bird. No,
these birds are not lining up with other
birds. The fish in the sea are not
lining up with other fish. They couldn't
care less what the fish are. Each one
individually, like a little homing
pigeon in his head, is aligned with an
infinite attractor field. So, what you
see under the water is the way that
attractive energy field looks. Each one
individually independent of those next
to them is aligned with that attractor
field. The same thing happens
unconsciously
in humans.
There's an attractor field here of
pridefulness. It attracts people from
all different walks of life. And you
look at what they're saying, they're all
saying exactly the same thing. They
didn't hear it from each other. It's
comes from that which they are. The way
they see the world leads to these kinds
of remarks. Above 200 people have a
different attitude altogether.
They now become trusting, optimistic,
forgiving, live in a different uh world
altogether.
They become willing and they be they
move into acceptance and they become a
reasonable people reasonable reasonable
and logical. Therefore, what should he
like? Toronto should be a reasonable,
intelligent place to live. 423. As I
said, America cowboy is 421. Toronto is
a 423.
Should be a little easier this side of
the border than the other side of the
border.
Two points there.
We expect people that we expect people
because this is who we are. This is who
we are. We expect other people to be
that way which has a serious downside to
it as we'll see later when we get to
international relationships. The fact
that we are this way does not mean that
other people are that way and that the
tools that to us are meaningful to other
people may appear ridiculous.
Love to us is a is a value to people
down here. I want you to realize that
love is a weakness.
Love is a weakness. Despicable weakness
to get you assassinated.
So what we consider the virtues from the
others from below become their opposite.
To be fair, reliable, loving, forgiving,
merciful is a sign of weakness.
As we move up to consciousness, we move
up to the levels of unconditional love,
joyfulness, peace, and the more advanced
levels of consciousness which are
statistically rare. Statistically rare.
Let's move to the next level.
Everybody's familiar with that map of
consciousness,
I think. Yes.
Anybody who hasn't heard of it?
Anybody who wasn't redpar versus horse,
raise your hands.
I failed. Lord,
now you haven't heard that. That's why
you're here. No, that's why you're here.
And because you've already all right, we
calibrated the the levels of
consciousness because they became so
huge. They were logarithmic
and I did the relative difference in
strength.
As we said, negative thoughts are so
relatively weak
uh that you can think them all day long
and have one really powerful loving
thought and you pretty much overbalance
the negativity. So this is done by a
physicist
engineer who
demon graph field of consciousness and
here we are and they did them in
microwatts. So here is the levels of
power in microwatts and you'll see
uh at 200 you suddenly go up 400 at 500
which is the level of love. Sleepy rises
and from 600 on it really goes into
infinity.
Okay, let's have the next one. Really
goes into infinity. How does mankind lay
out and see?
Uh 75% 85%.
85% of mankind kelp or it's below
consciousness level 200.
So here's consciousness level 200.
People that are in tender calibrated 200
from 200 up, they constitute 15% of the
world's population.
You see, you're in the minority.
You're in the minority.
15 against 85 in the world.
In Canada, the United States, it's more
like 50/50.
In Canada, the United States, people
above 200 are about 50% of the
population and at least 50% below, but
that's unusual. The rest of the world,
it's more like 85% of the population
count rates below.
You see the significance of that for
many activities including politics etc.
You have to realize who you're talking
to. If 85% of the world is nonattakers
and not interested in love, equality,
fairness, you can see how far those
concepts go. Below consciousness level
200, people are interested in gain,
benefit, getting ahead. Understand?
All right. You know that if you're a
door to door salesman, I learned that
when they sold Electrolux
vacuum cleaners door to door.
The fact that it's the greatest machine
in the world doesn't mean anything to
them.
They take it out and they vacuum him up
the mess in there and she says, "Boy,
that does a good job. Now you're
talking."
All right. So, you see the implication.
You see the implications.
85% of the world is below
uh interior. Okay. Let's go to the next
one. Let's take the supposed opposites
of heat and cold. People say, "Well,
heat's the opposite of cold." That's a
manner of speech, but it is not a
reality. There's only one variable, only
one variable. The presence or the
absence of heat.
If there's lots of heat up here, lots of
heat, then there's less heat, then
there's less heat, then there's less
heat, then there's less heat. You see,
there's only one variable, the presence
or absence of heat.
There is not a second hypothetical
entity called cold coldness.
We don't have an excess of coldness here
and a deficiency of it up here. You see
heat is either present or not present.
There are not two opposite heat versus
cold. This is a really major
understanding. Once you transcend the
obstacles, the duality of the opposites,
you're into a state of oneness of mind.
You can do the same thing with anything
in the world. We can say if you want it,
then you say it has value. If you don't
want it, the only thing that changes
whether you want it or not.
There isn't anything that's precious
versus something that's worthless.
It's just whether you want it or not. If
you're out in the woods, a little string
may be fantastic. The greatest discovery
you made all week.
>> Look, piece of string you can do with a
piece of string.
So, how much you want it then? We say
it's precious. It's it's a it's a plus.
We can say, "Oh, well, I got lots of
string. I can say it's ugly string. Get
rid of it. It's repulsive."
Nothing has changed in the world at all.
You understand? No reality has changed.
To you it looks like opposites, good
versus evil,
etc.,
good versus bad.
Truth versus non-truth is the only thing
that's changed is your desiringness of
it. There aren't two choices out there.
Those are projections from your own
mind. Okay,
let's do another one and then we'll
pretty much have the basic idea then.
Here we have desiraability again. We say
if it's wonderful it's heavenly. It's
okay, sort of okay, sort of bad. Then we
start using negative language. Uh and
nothing has really changed at all except
our point of observation.
How we observed it is how we describe
it. So what we're talking about then are
worlds of perception. This is how things
are perceived. How things are perceived
is not how they are.
We're doing a book uh out shortly. 7,000
calibrations.
Many of them I said, Susie, do you think
we should really tell the world this?
I can't tell you. And I still remember
I know how the world sees it, but I know
what it is intrinsically.
So, can they handle it or not?
I don't know if people going into the
truth shock all over the country.
We're going to have cases of truth
shock. People just are shocked when they
realize the truth is something. Also,
they get angry. They realize they've
been had.
Now, we take light versus dark. So, this
will really bring it to a conclusion.
There are not two variables called one
called light the other called dark.
Light is either energy of light is
either present or not not present.
It's present or to diminishing degrees.
There is not an opposite of light called
dark.
There's only one variable.
That kind of languaging is you know
useful pragmatic. pragmatic. We we know
what it means. But for spiritual work,
you have to go beyond just the
convenience, linguistic conveniences
and to begin to see the reality.
Truth is present or absent.
Light is either present or absent. He is
either present or absent. There's only
one variable and in the end we'll see
it's really just truth. spirit is either
present or not present. Okay.
One of the greatest difficulties in
spiritual work is so-called uh
transcending the opposites.
People do a lot of meditating. Look at
these things from a meditative
viewpoint. When do we have to breathe?
>> 10:30.
>> 15 minutes.
>> Oh boy. I've got the hole
put in this to get it all across
or we can just like
now you got it in your aura. Okay.
My responsibility
if you feel that which I am
by your breathing then you're
feeling
All right.
People going to meditation, they say the
difficulty with meditation is I my mind
just won't stop. Won't stop. It just
goes all the time. That's because they
don't know what their mind is.
Looking in the wrong potato. The
potatoes are not in this bin or they're
in this bin. Oh, okay.
People meditate uh hopefully they read
books and
hope that by meditation they will reach
the density of consciousness much
forever which they do also which they
do. The difficulty is the mind doesn't
you know seems to like it's not talking
because they think that talkingness is
their mind. That isn't your mind.
That's why what you tried doesn't work.
That isn't your mind at all anyway.
That isn't your mind. That's the
loudspeaker. That's not the radio.
That's the speaker trying to silence the
speaker. No, the sound is coming from
the radio itself. The speaker is just
the noise maker.
In reality, the mind is 99% of the mind
is silent. The mind is silent.
be in heaven. I gave the analogy of the
sea out of which come flying fish.
Flying fish are the thoughts. The mind
is the sea.
Each one of your thoughts is coming out
of nothingness. Coming out of absolute
silence.
We have a black white board. No, we
don't. Okay. Well, nope. Enlightened
some other. Okay.
Can't get light without a whiteboard.
All right. Uh, but I'll sneak around it.
Any people here have read mistransations
of the Buddha say it said that the
Buddha said
the the infinite reality can be glimpsed
can be glimpsed between two thoughts.
That mis
um misinterpretation has gone down for
centuries.
You don't
Witness the infinite between two
thoughts.
You witness them just prior to the
thought. That makes a huge difference.
Thoughts are going A B C D E F G like
this. So people try to look between A
and B, B and C. They try to catch a
space of silence between two thoughts. I
think if I watch harder, if I watch
harder, if I really concentrate and
watch hard in between A and B, I'll see
infinite reality.
Anybody ever see the infinite reality
between two thoughts here? Please raise
your hand.
Nobody's ever raised your hand. No,
because it's not there.
That would explain why for 2,000 years
that meditative technique has not
worked.
The Buddhas of Paladine said, "Dave,
I felt guilty about this this m this
translation for 2,000 years. I take
responsibility for it and it's your job
to shut your mouth
in return for which you straighten out a
few things for me
which I'm quite grateful."
No,
the mind is this blank space out of
which like a flying fish comes an A,
comes a B, comes a C. Okay, so the
infinite space you're looking for is
just prior to the emergence of the fine
fish out of the sea.
If you watch your mind, you'll see.
Get away from the Newtonian idea
causality.
That's the trap.
You think they're like billiard bolts.
A causes B. If you can just get between
here's A coming B. You quit trying to
kick stop. Here's A on this side, B on
this side. You hold up, but B comes up
anyway. You ever do that? You struggle
in meditation
trying to stop the next thought from
coming up
and and the reason you can't do it is
you're you're holding it up like this.
There's a B. You're holding C there
trying to make keep it from hitting D.
Suddenly D appears. You say how the hell
get there?
I was watching. I was watching.
It doesn't come A B C D. D came up from
there. Sucker. Oh,
now somebody told us. Thank you. Thank
you, Buddha. I have repay my debt, too.
I did what I said I would do.
Yes. What you got to watch is the ocean.
If you watch this flying fish,
he's not causing that flying fish to
come out of the sea. You watch him all
day. This guy's going to come out
anyway. This guy's a clown.
Every first in meditation,
including some spiritual teachers, God
bless him, are running around trying to
catch the flying fish. Quick, I'm up
quick.
You can't stop the mind by catching the
flying fish.
Okay?
You don't have to. Why? Because the
identification that which you're seeking
is the sea itself,
the silent matrix. that exists prior to
all thoughts.
99% of your mind is silent right this
moment.
You think it's busy because you're
focused on the 1%.
99% of the mind is silent at all times,
including right now.
98% of mine is sad. 99%.
98.5 Oh, went up. One and a half. Wow.
Hearing is going on in 1% of your mind.
And the secret behind it is that you are
hypnotized by it.
You are hypnotized by the 1% that is
talking. Therefore, you're ignoring the
99% that is not.
You're fascinated with the flying fish
to the degree you don't even notice the
ocean
and then somebody points it out to you.
People meditate trying to stop the
flying fish emerging from the ocean. You
can't do it more. The best you can do is
valitional for using force thought
stoppage. You can volitionally fiercely
fight the fight. But the minute you stop
fiercely fighting it, the thoughts
resume again. So
realize that you're in a hypnotic state.
When TV first came on, I used to watch
people.
They would watch the program, then the
commercial would go on, then the program
go on, commercial, but their
concentration didn't change at all.
There' be the story of Lone Ranger, then
we come the Wedies, then we come to the
Lone Ranger again, then come to Wedies
again. They were like an hypnotic
trance. You could walk into the living
room like this. People were just glued
to the TV set,
whether it was sweeties or the Lone
Ranger was all the same. Nando or crispy
crunchies with milk and sugar. They were
just like entranced with the field.
You still see it today. All kinds of
phenomena are happening everywhere in
the world in there in a trans state.
All right?
Just to know that you are hypnotized in
a hypnotic state of only 1% of your mind
already frees you up considerably. Oh,
it's not the mind. No, it's your
hypnotic attraction to the mind. So
let's go to the hypnotic. Let's go to
this one. Why are we so fascinated with
the mind? Because it's extremely clever.
The ego's only interest is in survival.
Its only interest is in survival. It
doesn't want you to know anything about
it secrets whatsoever. No,
it's very inventive.
It knows how to politicize everything.
Adnauseium.
Nothing in today's world that doesn't
get politicized,
genderized,
create made into an issue.
You know,
should pianist be that long or this
long.
Everything is contentious.
You can't live a peaceful life in
today's world because everything gets
politicized. politicized.
Everything gets moralized.
Everything gets idealized,
hypothesized.
It shouldn't be that way. It shouldn't
be that way. The world of blame. You see
the world of blame
hypothesizes. Then we romanticize how it
should be. We criticize how it is or
hasn't been. We emotionalize. Isn't that
terrible? We dramatize it. It
catastrophizes it. A slippery slope.
Virtues. We're all going
the slippery slope. Oh my god. The
hypothetical. We all live in terror of
the hypothetical.
We're victimized by the catastrophe of
the hypothetical which is dramatized and
emotionalized in between being
criticized and romanticized.
We rationalize it all, fantasize about
it, intellectualize about it, mentalize,
glamorize it, demonize it, prize it,
theorize,
and
we're so eyesed we can't even see what
the reality is anymore.
We're in between. We're getting eyes all
the time. Every paper is a
politicalization, a dramatization,
intellectualization, a theorization.
And this is what our mind does.
Your mind is the daily tribute.
What's the what's today's hypothesis,
Jack? Well, those songs they keep doing
that boy, they're going to be in
trouble.
And if they keep that up, wow, we're all
going down the tube. No country,
economy, the world.
Oh, wow.
So this is how the world this is how the
mind keeps us in a hypnotic state.
Then it gets itself published in the
paper just in case you didn't notice it.
So that we're all it's regimented. So
the 1% you and 1% me we all walk in line
you know.
So we got group think group think
group think.
Well, you have to take a position about
matters. Uh, don't you know what if you
don't take any position about matters? I
don't care which way it goes. You can't
not care.
Can't not care who wins the game.
The good guys are the bad guys. So, I
don't know who the good guys, the bad
guys are. That's why I can't play this
game. This today's good guys are today's
bad guys. I don't know what the hell
across the border another country, the
good guys, the bad guys. Depends on
which paper you read. Front page, you
read the editorials. It's all different.
>> Whoa.
Keep up with the world. I don't know why
I stuck in here, man. Just
dumb
here this time. It's Dumbo.
Dumbo. A chance to leave. No. All right,
let's move on to the next one.
Move on to the next exciting uh Oh, wow.
Um
you see you you can become extremely
spiritually advanced without uh leaving
the world of reason, logic and science.
We're prideful about our intellect. A
lot of people say spirituality,
religion, that's all very
loud stuff.
It's presumed that you have to leave the
world with rationality, logic, reason.
Huh?
You sit around with flowers and hymns,
pretty dresses, plant tulips, stuff,
pray for dead people
or an incense.
I mean, real guys don't really go for
that too much. You know what I mean?
That's why I often speak to the men in
the audience because nobody gives a rap
about them.
Sometimes the ladies say your language
sometimes gets a little strong. I said,
"Well, there's guys in the audience too,
you know.
We're 50% of the population."
Okay.
So, the way you can still be reasonable,
logical, not lose respect of your
intellectual friends is you tell your
what is the Victorian paradigm reality
and you move on to quantum reality,
quantum mechanics. Then we're going to
move on to nonlinear dynamics and then
we're going to make a paradigm jump at
consciousness level and to cons the new
consciousness the science of
consciousness.
So while they're saying, you know, you
leave them way behind in the dust,
they're not interrupting nonlinear
dynamics in a year or two.
the physics of consciousness itself and
say well you'll catch up three or four
books on
first of all the ignoramous you have to
teach him the difference between
Newtonian probably didn't remember what
Newtonian is world of cause and effect
and the world we discovered through
quantum mechanics sub particle
submicroscopic reality which has
completely different laws completely
different laws we don't live the world
in that world we live in The subjective
world, the subjective world we live in
is more influenced by quantum mechanics
and nonlinear dynamics than it is by
externals. My mind isn't changed much by
the texture of this carpet here at all.
Doesn't really affect subjectively where
I live.
No, where I live is not measurable.
So the world of logic then is orderly
and logical.
We discovered that the world in reality
is really disorderly. It's
creative. It's free. This world is
limited, deterministic,
reductionistic. This is the reductionist
mechanistic reductionist lives here in
solitary confinement.
Nothing as real as you can measure any
way. Oh, I feel sad for them. Lo, please
help them.
They live in a coded world.
>> Uh everything is seen as separate,
discreet. Everything is seen as a
consequence of cause. Animistic that
means separated from everything else.
It's the world of force. Everything is
seen as being caused by something out
there. If that's true, nobody's
responsible for anything because there's
always something out there you can blame
on.
See, you know, you always see that when
you apply it to education, everybody
gets an F.
All right. Everything is cause,
provable, measurable, sequential.
Everything is settled. There's no point
in looking at it. Everything is
temporal. You can get it all on a
computer. It's computational because
it's limited. It's permanent. And of
course, there's a very restricted view
of reality.
When you go to quantum mechanics, which
is nothing but the mathematics of that
which we know already, in reality, we
know that things are not predictable.
All of a sudden, bang.
80,000 generations of black beetles.
Somebody throws an albino. Wow. Where'd
that come from?
Disorderly, illogical, unpredictable,
free, creative, imaginative.
Everything is diffused, intermingled.
Everything's intermingled in the field
of consciousness. That's why what I'm
holding in my mind causes a kinesiologic
response. And she doesn't even know
consciously what's in my mind. It's
because we're intermingled.
We're sharing a common field.
Things are diffuse. Things are not
limited. They're potential.
They're reactive, responsible,
responsive, comprehensible. Things here
are measurable here. You can't measure
them, but you can observe them. You can
observe them. When you try and measure
them, they change. So, you can't measure
anything because measuring it already
changes it.
So, you have to keep measuring things
constantly. Spend your whole life just
measuring things. Every time you measure
it, it changes. So, now you got to
measure again. You can see you can never
catch up with reality because it's
changing faster than you can measure it.
This is subject to the shading equations
which are both time dependent and time
independent. Later on we have a slide
that'll show you that everything is
really stocastic chaotic unlimited
infinite possibility and the fact is
that it's altered by observation. You
know the infinite potentiality that
you can't tell what anything is really
going to do from moment to moment.
You can't tell anything is going to do
from moment to moment.
Right?
The speaker might just suddenly go nuts
in front of you.
Walk around like a crazy thing.
So, what in the world is going on with
him,
Roger? He was being very nice. All of a
sudden, he's being crazy. I don't know
what it is.
Well, it's because here you're limited.
Here you're unlimited. You're not
limited.
No, you don't have to talk like a
squeaky old college professor.
Just be crazy anytime you want to be.
So the infinite reality is one of
infinite freedom
at any one moment to fulfill any
potentiality
being boring and pedestrian.
I can become very pedestrian and boring
at a moment's notice.
I want to discuss Hegel's basic premises
this afternoon
and then we'll go on to their reput
reputation
by the problematic
uh hermeneutics
of the uh distorted
uh relativistic epistemology.
box.
So, some of you have heard from
and I want each of you to bring a large
notebook because we're going to cover
the entire history of human
philosophy from the beginning of time,
including the great books of the Western
world. Oh, that'll be a thriller.
We said everything
is just being what it is, fulfilling its
own potentiality.
Consequently,
everything is happening spontaneously.
The secret of the enlightened state is
that there's nobody here talking to you
at all.
It happens of its own.
The potentiality becomes the actuality
under favorable conditions such as an
audience. Then the speakingness speaks
of its own.
There's no person
speaking as a dualistic concept. There's
a a this causing a that.
That's why I saw kinesiology from a
different paradigm
than the rest of the people because I
had already been through
um
spiritual experiences which began at an
early time. People ask me to
recapitulate my own spiritual evolution
which is somewhat tradition I guess
spiritual teachers
um
to put it against some kind of
comprehensible context.
Um
this life began out of nothing.
out of nothing
which was a fantasy.
Seemed like nothing.
Prior to age three, there was nothing
oblivion
out of oblivion
which was the residual of lifetimes of a
hinana Buddhist. I followed the pathway
of negation. Anonymous is the
translation of the Buddha is that the
ultimate reality is nothingness. No, no,
it's no thingness. It's not void as a
nothingness.
If it was a nothingness, I would have
stayed there.
This lifetime there was nothing.
Complete void nothingness
until age three. at age street.
Suddenly, shockingly,
like having lived forever in a dark
closet, somebody turned on three glass.
Suddenly, there was a shocking discovery
of existence
that I existed.
Three-year-old has no vocabulary. This
was not mentalization. It was a stunning
awareness of existence that I existed.
I was not pleased.
was bad enough that you exist,
but a body went with it.
In this little cart, you know, 3 years
old was this little body that went with
it. You exist plus you exist as a
physicality.
Oh god. So
after that shock
instantly the awareness of existence
brought up the fear of non-existence.
The knowingness was that if I had come
into existence potentiality could have
been to have not come into existence.
The minute I
minute there was the awareness of
existence. There was the fear of
non-existence.
The duality is the ultimate reality.
Allness or nothingness.
Duality is one of the last gateways you
pass. Calibrates about 850. So at age
three presented with a conundrum
that took most of his lifetime or good
part of the lifetime
transcend. So that was unusual enough.
And then the difficulty was of staying
identified with the physicality. I'd be
sitting in class in grade school and the
sense of a personal self would disappear
all
this nothingness. Everything else and I
would get scared and I would say you're
Dave. You're you're 88 you're sitting in
third grade. This is spelling class. I
mean I try to hang on to what the world
called reality.
it would slip away. And um
in age 12, I had the longest paper out
in Wisconsin,
18 miles every day below zero.
One night came below zero lizard pitch
black. There was no electricity. We live
way on the sticks. Electricity was only
on one side of the highway. So in the
pitch act with no electricity
timbal
the wind blew the papers out of the back
of my bicycle and I started to cry with
frustration trying to chase the pickers
across the icy snow
and finally gave up. So I dug my way
into a snowbank in Wisconsin. By the end
of January the snow was about 12 ft
high. I dug a hole in this through the
crust of the snow, climbed into this
little space out of the wind. Main thing
was to get up
and almost instantly an exquisite
presence,
which is not really possible to talk
about.
There was an ex exquisite presence like
the very essence of love itself which
melted away any thinkingness,
place, time.
It was beyond all time, location
and it was forever.
That which I am
existed prior to all universes
and will be and all universes
have gone.
That is a fact existed.
That is a fact.
That which I am existed for all
universes and will be after all
universes have disappeared. Beyond all
time, beyond all place, beyond all
conditionality.
Yeah.
In exquisite state.
I don't know whether breathing continued
or not. It sort of wouldn't be
interesting.
Every time that sleep occurs,
you don't need to eat, drink, think,
feel, nothing.
And whether the body continues or not is
irrelevant.
Whether it does or not depends on karmic
propensities and conditions. If the
conditions are favorable, the body
resumes because somebody comes along and
feeds it.
And since you eat
it's Thursday, you haven't eaten since
Tuesday. So, okay.
Anyway, in that particular state which
goes on beyond time, the experience of
infinity is infinite.
The foreverness of the existence of the
infinite all presence of God is forever.
Anyway,
something was shaking my foot with my
father and the 29 Model 8 Ford. He
followed the my tracks. I showed up for
dinner. So, he discovered that the
body's there
and I didn't need to breathe or be with
the body ever again. I looked at my
father and I realized he believes in
death. He thinks death is reality.
Therefore, if I didn't breathe again, he
would be stuck with a lifetime of guilt.
If he'd allowed his son to die in a
blizzard,
he would have been struck with a
lifetime of guilt.
So, because I love my father, I
became
the energy of the body again.
I'm sick.
You see because death is not a
possibility.
Death is not a possibility.
There's the law of conservation of
matter, law of conservation of energy.
And why mankind has never discovered the
law of the conservation of life is
beyond me. It's the most stunningly
obvious thing there is. Life can change
form, but you cannot kill it.
You cannot kill it.
It just goes out of body and comes back
in another form. If you hit a moth or a
fly, it doesn't even notice it.
>> You know, they don't they don't even
notice it.
That's a fact. Doesn't even notice it.
Goes red one clock in his ether atheic
body rematerializes in another body.
Oh, you're worrying about the fact that
it died. It's having a good time. You
know,
I was a strict Buddhist for many years.
Each like you had to practice, you know,
in New York, biggest in the country.
And uh so there would be flies would get
in the middle of the room. You know when
you got a fan going down to get in the
middle of the room air conditioner. I
wait till the patient leaves and behind
the drapes I had a butterfly net. As
soon as the patient leave I take out the
butterfly net capture these flies and
put them out the window and put it back
behind the drapes to see the next
patient.
Monu flies.
I believe that I thought you could kill
life. Well can't kill life.
Can't kill life. Not possible.
When you draw a body, you just say there
it is laying there and life goes right
on.
So this life was sort of different in
many ways. Later on, other uh events uh
other events I can't remember what they
were. I was going to tell you about
them, but I don't remember what they
were.
Other
states that the world calls
enlightenment would recur spontaneously
in one actually prior to one. Oh, I was
an atheist also an atheist for 20 years.
Oh yes, I was very religious as a kid
scrupulosity
episcopal.
I was a boy uh
acolyte the bishop. I was a boy soprano
sang in the cathedral
panelas
the full orchestra
full organ
all the p pageantry
full cathedral
stained glass windows sun coming through
the stained glass windows and this
obligato upon us angelica is coming out
of this voice oh
like a voice somewhere
from somewhere
And with that was scrupulosity,
fear of sin. The Gothic downside of
Christianity
gets fixated on sin. So it isn't that
you live for goodness, it's that you
live in fear of sin. So at least at 12,
you do. So
testosterone surging through your veins.
The nemesis of sin. Well, sin was
explained to me that was like a black
spot on your soul. Uh-oh. Uh, here's
this invisible soul. You think of a
simple thought, you got a black spot,
you know, like
and God can see this. Whoa. I must have
dreaded that.
Saturday afternoon, I'd go to high
Episcopal was very much like Catholic.
So, you went to confession on Saturday
afternoon as late as possible.
Confessions were over, I think, at 4:30.
got going at 4:20.
Then you had to live very carefully from
4:30 after confession to God absolution.
You did all the rosary deals
until I would go to the earliest mass on
Sunday. So the shortest time for sin to
happen
from 4:30 Saturday afternoon till 7:00
a.m. Sunday was dreadful time.
You walked carefully. You watched your
thoughts.
One Sunday morning, we're going to
church. 29 Model A Ford at the top down.
We always get to church and I've been
sinless spotless up to this point. It's
now about 18 minutes to 7.
And as we round the corner,
there's a 30 foot long billboard of a
Jansen swimming suit ad.
30 foot long.
Oh Lord, forgive me for the wickedness
of my thoughts.
Oh Lord, forgive me for the lust of my
thoughts. Forgive me for Oh my god, it
was torture. No,
I didn't dare tell my folks why I wasn't
going to go to communion that morning.
I had to fake it. I got a spot on my
soul. And you got to go to communion
with a spinal soul. Oh my god.
I was respiring. I get up to communion
real.
I was afraid.
I felt like it was striking.
Went to communion with a spot on your
soul. So you live in the dread of
religion. It was not a source of joy.
Not like unity church. Let me tell you
it was the downside. Yeah.
Anyway, eventually I became
intellectual. Studied all the great
books of the western world. Not all good
ones. Aristotle Socrates. Socrates is my
hero. I was a little skinny ecamorph
with thick glasses. And I read Socrates
while other people had stick ball.
He rzled and did other disgusting
physically aggressive things.
Sweaty and greasy. Good.
Aristotle, Socrates, they were my
friends. Socrates is my hero. Socrates
was a hero and he's still a hero.
Socrates went to death rather than
violate truth rather than violate the
truth of God. He accepted death when he
could have chickened out and capped out
the deal. Said rather than violate
where did he get that religion? Because
Christianity wasn't born yet. Buddhism
had gotten to Greece.
So now Socrates got it cal 540
unconditional love.
So he was a hero.
Anyway, then I got into intellectualism
became an atheist and then I was a
sincere atheist for 20 years
and I went to a Jesuit university
various things
and uh became got straight A in
theology.
going to argue it. You better know a lot
about it.
>> You have to do have a beer and argue
theology,
metaphysics. It was a wonderful life. I
was an art atheist.
But then the exingencies of life. I was
in World War II.
And uh the thing that happened after
that snowbank experience curiosity
curiously uh was a complete boss of fear
of death. Never had fear of death since.
Somebody says that'll kill you. So I say
so
I mean here's this mine right next to
the ship ready to go off any second. We
got these boat hooks. The only thing
we're concerned about is that this thing
shouldn't hit the boat.
The fact they could blow up and kill you
wasn't even in her mind. You don't let
it hit the boat. You know what I mean?
Oh god.
So there we are. I was an atheist and uh
eventually I needed to I was preoccupied
with the core essence truth itself all
this entire lifestyle since age three. I
got into a search within myself. I've
been into psychoanalysis. I was
psychoanaly
neoian otherwise
psycho analyst my greatgrandfather's
sign for it
he was the analyst for Abraham Carter
Abraham Carter was the analyst line of
obviously was my training analyst for I
saw him every day for four years we were
both atheists
we were in agreement about that religion
was a foxhole fear you know foxhole
religion you know right to I now you got
religion who always
anyway the preoccupation with truth
became an obsession of his lifetime
I had to find what is the core and the
essence of truth you know Socrates was a
big help
but there was a driveness to discover
the basic source of the sense of I
realized it came from from a sense of
who I am.
And therefore, one time I drove into the
depths of the psyche. I guess you would
call it the fian hid searching for the
source of the source of the sense
itself.
And to get there, I descended through
the depths of hell. It led me somehow
into hell.
Dante is correct about hell. How he knew
about it, I don't know.
D curious. Calgary is very high. I've
never researched the life of Donnie
about over 500. You lose some heard the
truth.
As you go into hell, you go into agony.
That which people consider is hell.
These only the jacks for opening people,
crutching them to death, burning oil.
And then beyond that, it gets serious.
Death's just agony in torture and
horror. Beyond that there is a spiritual
agony.
The physicality is irrelevant. You leave
the world of form. And just as the
highest levels of consciousness are
formless, you go beyond form. And
there's a knowingness as you descend
beyond form.
Abandon hope. All ye are here. How did
know that? It's almost like you. It's
annoyingness and then you go and then
you find out what hell is.
It's forever.
Forever hopeless agony for which there
is no recourse and no hope ever. And
then you go into eternity.
Now eternity of
forever of agony and hopelessness. It's
one thing to be in it for days, weeks,
and months. It's another thing to
realize that it forever is opening up
front
beyond all imagination.
I do not recommend hell under any
circumstances.
It is more horrific than anyone can ever
describe or imagine.
Spiritual agony cut off from all hope
for
at the in the pit of that out of silence
and some voice within said if there is a
god I asked him to help me and then
oblivion
I don't know how long the oblivion
lasted but when it disappeared all
things had been transformed
all things The divinity of all that
exists shines forth.
The mind had become silent, disappeared
forever,
disappeared forever, gone.
Instead, just the knowingness and the
awareness of the presence of all that
exists here. You see that
creation and evolution are one and the
same thing. What you witness as you
think as a happening is nothing but the
process
of creation.
What we see think is evolution is the
way creation looks sequentially.
We think sequest that's rest sequence is
rest internes
in here. There's no sequence in the
world.
sequence is serial witnessing because I
witnesses serially I say oh it's
happening serially no you're witnessing
serially
creation and evolution are one in the
same thing
done manifest becomes manifest as the
totality of all that exists
and we see it unfolding sequentially
not due to causality
It like rises out of the sea to your
vision like this. You say, "Oh, it's
happening that way." Not happening that
way.
Creation and evolution are one and the
same thing.
Different point of observation
without mentation. You would just accept
this isness.
The minute you mentalize, you start to
think in terms of causality.
and you start thinking of the billiard
balls and goth becomes billiard ball a
it starts the ball rolling it's very
naive
very naive
I knew that when I was still an atheist
the arguments for the existence of god
the point is in earth are very weak
indeed you can't find any primary
primary cause there is no primary Cause
cause exists within the Newtonian
dimension with this causing it. That
reality is the unmanifest becoming
manifest as conditions written doesn't
require a cause. You don't have to find
a primary cause. There is no primary
cause
in any sequence. There is no primary
cause. It's all imaginary hypothetical
ought to be that way, could be that way,
sounds good that way. Except it's
nonsense. There is no primary cause.
It's all the potentiality becoming
reactuality.
It's beyond pause. Pause calibrates
around 450.
Creation
calibrates infinite and above.
What is the cause of that which is
infinite? And see what a nonsensical
question it is.
All right. So let's go on with the
lectures.
Let's go on with the uh titles or the
whatif boss
whatever they are.
Yes. Well the the the other scale goes
up to 600 because that includes 99.9% of
the people on the planet because to go
beyond this is is unusual statistically
unusual.
probably in the wrong wrong place for it
to happen. But to those that happens,
that's what we call it.
600 and up then is a different paradigm
and it's non-duality.
Transcend duality into non-duality.
If you're from the viewpoint of
non-duality, causality sounds like an
absurdity.
Within duality, it sounds like a
necessity. Beyond 600, it sounds stupid.
Go.
You see potentiality becoming an
actuality. I mean
it's simple, right?
Very simple.
The minute somebody points it out to
you, you get it.
So these levels and 600 these these are
extremely rare. Uh this is Narada
Maharaj. Uh
the great sages of India usually come
around at 700. Um higher than that is
very rare indeed in ancient India maybe.
Um and the avatars calibrate at level
1,00
why do they stop at 1,000? Because
that's the capacity of the human nervous
system. In fact from the nervous system
is going to give you trouble from the
mid 500s up. I'll tell you
uh
about the mid 500 you start feeling this
energy running up your spine up your
back.
exquisite, delicious, like the essence
of
it's like the essence of the presence in
the snowpack. An exquisite meltingness
like the very essence of divinity of
lovingness itself begins to flow
deliciously up your back. Boom. When you
close your eyes, you like disappear into
it. People say, "Why are you closing
your eyes all the time?"
where I'm blissful, where I hear it's
blissful where you are is a pain in the
neck.
This and that, arguing with this and
that. Oh, I got money blurs.
>> I mean, where I am has no relationship
to that at all. Peace be.
And as the as you get into the higher
500s, then this energy is flowing up.
You can feel it flowing into your brain.
We're going to later see that it has a
profound effect on brain physiology.
Totally changes your brain physiology.
Also, above level 200, you begin
developing an atheric brain. Below 200,
you're stuck with an animal brain.
Primarily processes things to the left
brain like an animal. 200 and above now
spiritual energy begins to flow. It
creates for the first time an evolution
of the brain.
the brain, individual karma, not just
group karma. Blow it to 100, you're
talking about group karma, the same as
animals.
People that are come in and off the
planet aligned with an attractor field
over 200. Now you've got individual
karmic responsibility, answerability,
and mirror as well. This energy begins
to flow up exquisitly into your brain.
Feel it in your brain.
If you think to the left of your brain,
it flows into the left of your brain. If
you move your attention to the right of
the brain, it flows into the right of
your pl brain. It's very explicit.
There's reluctance to be in the world or
with people.
And the effect you have uh on people is
quite different. Also, this energy
sometimes does things all you know it's
all by itself. Not had nothing to do
with your personal self. Sometimes this
energy flows out through the heart. It
would flow out. You're driving along the
highway. You would feel it going down
the highway.
And I'd say, "Well, God, no. Now what?"
It would go down the highway, around the
bend. You get around the bend, there's
an automobile accident. The car, the
wheels of the car are still spinning.
This energy is pouring into the car. you
get that the people in there are praying
and somehow you're like an antenna of
some kind of demonic energy or
something. I guess you're the nearest
handy antenna. So it goes out into the
into the car.
Then a little while later all of a
sudden it stops. So in my mind I'm
thinking should I stop God? No. No
you're not needed cuz who's going to
stop person. You don't need a person
here. The energy was what
shown forth around the another couple
miles is coming down I 10 in Arizona.
Couple of miles down this starts again
again. He's going around some quarter
mile down road. And whenever it would do
this did it in Chicago one time to stop
a gang fight. It would do these things
all on his own. And I say think, "Well,
God, now