box here to bring the coffee. Where's the coffee? Well, I better go find it. Hello Sweethearts.
Hello Sweethearts. Hello Sweethearts. Did you bring a guest? Hi, how do you do? Hi,
hello Sweetheart. Yeah, do I get a hug? No, no, honey, I can't do anything. Morning, David.
Yes. What a pleasure to meet you. Yes. Good morning, Doctor. Yes, indeed, hi. Wow. Good
morning. Yeah, good morning Sweetheart, I'll see you in a while. There's walls here and
everything. We saw you in Austin last week. Oh, how wonderful, yes. I love to see you.
Thank you for being there. That was a wonderful group. Yes, indeed, uh-huh. Good morning.
Yes. Hi. How you doing? Hi. Hello, hello. Hello, Sweetheart. Yeah, hello. I flew across
country just to do this. Thank you. Hey, there you go, there you go. It was so wonderful
to see you. Hi. Good to see you.
Hi. Ah, look at the little people here, the big people. The little ones and the big ones.
Hi. Hi. Hi. That's a comfortable jacket. Hey. Hi. Hi. Yeah, well, we gotta hurry up
and say hello to everybody, huh? How you doing? Nice to meet you. Hi. Hi. Thank you very
much. Good morning.
Oh, yeah. Excuse me. Well, hello.
Yeah, if you aren't careful, they knock you over. They knock you over.
David, this is my boss's mother, Arlene. Hi. Hi. Arlene, you were the, what, president
of a hospital? Yes. What a pleasure. She was the president of a hospital. Oh, there's
a job for you. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi. Hi.
Hi.
Oh, there's a job for you.
Yeah, I enjoyed it. Thank you for putting into language experiences that have not been
able to be put into words. Thank you for that.
Ah, there we are. Hi. These old regulars are my favorite, sir. Yeah, hi.
Good morning, Dr. Hoffman. It's a pleasure to be with you again.
Yes, good. Hi.
Hi there, Shawn.
Hi.
Hello, sweethearts.
Hey.
Hi.
Hello.
Thanks from all of us for today.
Good morning.
God bless you.
It's a pleasure to see you again.
Hi.
God bless you.
It's a pleasure to see you again.
We'll go around this way.
Yeah, that'd be easier.
Okay.
Hi.
Here's one that is a big guy.
That is a big guy.
One of the big guys.
Hi.
Don't argue with the big guys.
He's another big guy.
Hi.
Hello.
Good to see you again.
Yeah.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
Hi.
How are you?
Good to see you again.
Hi.
I like it.
Excuse me.
Hi.
Hello.
I'm going to catapult right past all these people here.
Yeah.
The music stops, so it must be time to start.
God is prompt, so we try to be prompt.
It's 9 o'clock, God's here, so it's good to see you all again.
Last week we were in Austin, so if you're from Austin and you're here today, say hello
to them.
We start out, we have an interpreter here also.
I can't hear what she's saying, but she knows.
The rate my hearing is going, I'll be needing her soon.
So I'm buttering her up.
I say what more than any other word in the language.
What?
Now I have this African parrot that makes my what's even worse.
She said Merry Christmas this morning, so that's her message to the group.
We've been following the advance of her consciousness, you know, and she's learning all kinds of
language.
And now she says, ho, ho, ho, Merry Christmas.
When Jesus returns, she'd be all ready for us.
So, as you know, we always start out with the end of the lecture first and work back
to the beginning.
The realization, there's only a few things you really need to know.
There's only a couple of things.
If you know just a few things.
If you know the things very well, that's all you need.
To merely hear them already begins the process.
Just before the world disappears altogether, you notice that everything is happening spontaneously.
The most important thing to know is that everything is happening in and of its own.
Nothing is being caused by anything.
All phenomena.
All phenomena are the automatic consequence of the field.
The field is one of infinite, invisible, omnipotent power.
All encompassing.
Like a giant electromagnetic field.
No beginning, no ending.
Either spatially or in time.
Forever and always present.
This field is infinitely powerful.
The human mind cannot conceive of the infinite.
Except as a concept.
Its presence is exquisitely gentle and exquisitely powerful.
The field is so powerful that potentiality is activated by the field to become an actuality.
All things happen by virtue of the infinite power of the field.
What the world considers evolution.
Is the witnessing of creation which is continuous.
The unmanifest.
Beyond the linear.
Becomes manifest by divine providence.
As the totality of creation.
And this happens effortlessly.
Within the field then.
Potentiality is actualized by intention.
Therefore.
Each thing comes forth.
Manifesting its karmic inheritance.
You might say its karma is its innate potential.
And when conditions are appropriate.
Then the potentiality becomes an actuality.
In and of itself.
As a consequence of the infinite power of the field.
The field is so powerful that if you continuously hold the thought.
It will become a happening.
Yeah.
Otherwise no one will become enlightened.
Therefore.
One's intention is all powerful.
See the ego is very clever.
And as the thing begins to.
As the potentiality begins to manifest.
It takes credit for it.
Person goes and takes a pair of scissors.
And cuts the stem into an apple.
And he thinks he made the apple.
And he thinks he made the apple drop to the ground.
That's how all things are happening like gravity.
There's no.
Inner.
Separate personal self.
Making anything happen.
It holds an intention.
And now.
When the conditions are appropriate.
The potential manifests.
There was.
I used to drive over Mingus Maung.
Three times a week.
As you drive around a certain curve.
There was nothing.
No flowers there.
All of a sudden.
In the late spring.
What do they call those plants that grow up like that.
Within a couple of months.
Huh.
Century plant.
Okay.
Here is this first from nothing.
Within a couple of months was this incredible century plant.
Taller than I am.
Stunningly beautiful.
Before there wasn't anything there.
So we asked with kinesiology.
You know.
How long had the seed.
Been in the ground.
That grew into that century plant.
And the answer was a hundred and fifty years.
The seed was laying in the dirt.
A hundred and fifty years.
And then.
It's calming potential.
Being there.
When the local conditions were appropriate.
Just the right moisture.
The right sequence of barometric pressure.
Temperature.
Sunshine.
When all was just right.
There was nothing.
Nothing.
the mind in one ten thousandths of a second quickly claims that it was the
author of the action see what it did you don't keep it under control it might do
it again was there a decider there who decided to do that that's a very hard
illusion to break the difference between being enlightened and not enlightened
is merely to see that if you're strictly completely and radically honest
radically beyond the capacity of most people to be honest much less radically
honest to be radically honest means to somehow be able to beat that one
ten-thousandths of a second to completely surrender that all things
happen by divine providence by the will of God and for no other reason the only
opponent to that understanding of the divine providence is the one who is
understanding is the ego and the ego's job is to claim to be God and it does it
well it claims that it is the originator you see it will claim that it was the
originator of that happening the ego is a liar to understand the liar then frees
you from its coils so one thing we do is try to understand the ego
and that is how we can invent and connect with the devil given the
power of the divine truth in ways that have not really been discovered or
described before and that's our contribution was discovering of the
usefulness of kinesiology now we do not lecture on
kinesiology and I don't even believe in it you can't believe in kinesiology
because it calibrates to 600 which is the line between the linear and the non linear
most the time I don't believe it either so you don't have to you're going to have to
to believe it but you just use it like you do a screwdriver or pliers it's a
very practical tool but with kinesiology we've been able to discern really in
libraries of encyclopedias of information and knowledge an incredible
amount of information to which mankind has never had access therefore I have a
certain reverence for the gift because in witnessing kinesiology it was taught
by dr. John diamond it was thought by the people who still were dominated by
duality to be a local phenomena but in this lifetime there had already been
what the world would call advanced states and therefore I didn't live in
the same limitation and when I saw kinesiology
what I saw was the response of an infinite field of power the infinite
field of power was then registering in the person's consciousness and traveling
down through the acupuncture system and the basic premise of this infinite field
is that it instantly recognizes truth the infinite field of consciousness
registers all that ever happens or has happened
time every thought every feeling every movement every action is recorded
forever there isn't such thing as privacy you haven't got any privacy at
all and you never did everything radiates out an energy this could be read
thousands of years later therefore the discovery was so mind-boggling that I
walked around
for five years wondering what to do with it you have access to all the
information that exists now or ever within one second takes that long to
discover any secret in the universe so you can see why I walked around for five
years thinking what to do with this first of all it's best not to tell
anybody yes so it is an incredible gift it's an incredible gift mankind has
suffered untold agonies for centuries and centuries for a lack of the
knowledge of the difference between truth and falsehood to not know that
there's any truth and
falsehood condemns mankind in this war's poverty savagery's sickness agony
suffering and death the affliction that is one has been one of ignorance all the
great avatars buddha christ krishna all say there is only one sin only one
problem and that is ignorance ignorance but man had no way of discerning truth
and falsehood
you
can find it anywhere except God is God is sent and the such thing we起來
to be the acknowledge and acknowledge it and if the Buddha step back and
annihilate answer of 50 was in fact a promotion each of us has a cooking
ation lining and just all you have to do isgruppe this area which began you
and we can儘 appear their lord better so it will 어제 do that or disagree
phase two is you will all act according to the grace of the teacher we take in
of consciousness and we simply hate or be uncertain that the you will I will not
accept if you are not devoid of this principle yet even the words of the great spiritual teachers words the great spiritual teachers now we have at hand a gift which to
and it jumped to 205.
Therefore, mankind throughout the centuries
has been dominated collectively by a consciousness
that was below truth, non-integrous.
So we see a civilization in history
which grew with an overall collective consciousness level of 190.
Suddenly in the late 1980s, around 87,
at about the time of the harmonic concordance,
but not caused by it, it jumped to 205.
People speak of the second coming of Christ,
and they think it's going to be somebody
who suddenly gets born in Brooklyn and appears on television.
That's a rather naive understanding.
The Christ, then, is a conscious awareness.
Therefore, when the consciousness level of mankind went over 200,
that, to me, was the return of the consciousness of the Christ
which now...
dominates mankind.
The collective level again went up last November,
from 205 to 207.
Therefore, we now live in a different world.
And as you can see by the daily newspaper,
truth often brings...
People think truth is going to bring peace.
People call themselves spiritual,
picture that it's all flowers and hymns,
and saintly smiles.
Christ said,
I came with a sword, a sword of truth, right?
Because when consciousness level is 190,
you have a world in which,
slipping you a few bucks,
you can even buy the UN,
42 billion dollars,
you can buy the UN Security Council.
What happens when consciousness level reaches 205?
That's no longer okay.
When it reaches 207, it's very much not okay.
Very much not okay.
It used to be, success was fame, fortune, money, wealth, fancy cars, Cadillacs, a yacht.
And now the new success is integrity.
Anybody can have those things.
Back east where I lived, everybody had them.
Everybody was a multimillionaire.
Because I belonged to, everybody was a millionaire.
Everybody had a yacht.
Everybody.
Everybody had six Cadillacs and servants.
Did me a thing.
Most of them inherited it.
That's the best way to do it, folks.
No, I wouldn't say that.
Because if you inherit it, it really isn't yours.
It's really not what you did.
And you're all sort of apologetic for it.
So you play polo or something, you know.
Go to the right school and all.
No, 207 then, there's quite a push.
There's a push for integrity.
So what you see is unrest in society, contention, conflict, social discord, because the energies
below 200 now are in a world which calibrates at 207.
So pure rhetoric alone will not cut the ice anymore.
It's got to be backed up by some facts.
Okay.
A new paradigm then of social acceptance.
So social acceptance, integrity.
I could have saved Martha, trip to jail, easy.
Martha, go to a 12 step meeting.
10th step is when we were wrong, we promptly admitted it.
All she had to do is say, well, look, if your stockbroker said he's thinking that something's
bottoming out, wouldn't you sell it?
Well, I would too.
So I'd fine her, you know, $50,000 and end the story.
Big deal.
So, but no, she's really in prison for lack of integrity.
And that's the thing.
She's a person.
That's really, she was convicted of lack of integrity.
When you lie to a federal jury, you know, that's why she's in jail.
Not for money.
Not for wealth.
Not for fame.
You see at 207, you go to prison for lack of integrity.
Wow.
It's a new paradigm.
Hmm, in the old days, you could have bought off everybody, and she wouldn't be here.
Now, it's not so easy to buy everybody off.
So you see now a strange interface between the old culture.
Uh.
. .
at 190, and then interacting with the culture at 205 and 207, right?
So it's like you, you know.
All right, so the advance of truth doesn't necessarily bring tranquil waters.
In fact, it may disturb things for a period of time.
And people who have gotten involved in intense spiritual work,
before they get there, they think it's going to be hearts and flowers
and we're all going to sing hymns.
We'll dance around the maypole and have peace marches, peace vigils,
and that will bring about peace.
No, you find that it's quite the contrary, that you now have a new paradigm
and reflected in this new paradigm is the downside of the old,
and so you have a conflict, a conflict going on.
We'll have peace, all right, but it may take a few thousand years, that's all.
No point to being impatient.
To merely know that all things are happening in and of their own
with no external cause, because the difficulty in a group such as is here today
is a group like this is stuck in the Newtonian paradigm of reality.
The Newtonian paradigm is that there is a this causing a that.
It's dualistic.
It's also the very source of thinking that there is a separate individuality
and a separate individual eye, a separate personal eye.
There's no separate personal eye talking here, going.
The field, the field, the presence, because of the audience,
speaks back to itself as it speaks, and I don't have anything to do with it.
Nothing to do with what is being said, nothing.
Nothing.
That happened.
Many years ago, when the personal self, the infinite presence is so powerful
that it really extinguishes anything that is not itself.
And the personal self became disappeared and the mind became silent.
The side, the mind right now is still silent.
I listened to the mind, said nothing at all.
Neither does yours, but you think it does, and that's the difference.
So, we'll start out where to make that jump, you see, and then we'll go back to the lecture.
The mind thinks there is a you, and this you is causing this sequence of events, sequential causality.
I saw through that in theology class.
I went to a Jesuit university.
The arguments for the presence of God is that there must be a great big capital A back here.
Which in itself is fallacious.
It's an idiotic thing, and at the time I was an atheist, and it's a stupid remark.
Anyway, a sequence arises from that which is not of the sequence, not of the sequence, not of the sequence.
So, the average person thinks there is a personal me, and it is causing these thoughts or actions in a chain reaction.
Causality is.
This causing of that.
Therefore, there must be an entity causing all that.
That's a presumption.
The mind can't understand infinity, so it presumes that in the sequence of events there would be a prime cause of God.
God must have a prime cause of something.
That which always has been obviously needs no cause.
Beyond cause.
This is where the thoughts are, and this is where there is a teaching, a mistranslation of the teaching of the Buddha.
That the infinite reality, enlightenment, is seeing between two thoughts.
In the seeming nothingness and void.
Now, many of us spent years and years cross-legged, breathing in strange places, wearing sandals, incense, the whole.
Looking for the space between A, B, and C.
Did anybody here ever find it?
No.
Maybe somebody says yes.
You know, you're a liar.
Because it cannot be found between the thoughts.
That's a mistranslation of the Buddha.
But, endless lifetimes have been spent.
Nico and I are experts at it.
We spent lifetimes as Hinayana monks.
Pathway of negation, not this, not that.
Anyway, between.
You cannot catch the infinite space between thoughts.
Because the mind is what's looking for the space between two thoughts.
And the mind cannot catch something that happens in less than one ten-thousandth of a second.
The mind is limited to one ten-thousandth of a second.
So, the mind is unable.
What's today's lecture's name?
Observing and witnessing.
The mind, as we will see later, can't move fast enough to catch it between two thoughts.
It's got to be faster than one ten-thousandth of a second to do it.
And it can't.
The mind cannot move faster than one ten-thousandth of a second.
In fact, when a rabbit runs across the road, you put the brake on.
If you're quick and honest, you'll see that it happened.
And then, the personal self congratulates itself that I stepped on the brake.
Now, it already braked.
And then the I, in one ten-thousandth of a second, claims authorship.
That's the difference between enlightenment and non-enlightenment.
It's in that one ten-thousandth of a second.
I had the good fortune when I was very young that I caught the ego doing that.
I caught it.
It had already saved the rabbit's life and braked.
And then I caught the ego.
I caught it claiming credit.
But I knew it had already happened.
At the moment it said, I, the phenomena had already occurred.
So, that was fortuitous.
At that young age, I didn't understand.
I didn't understand the implication of that.
All right.
So, if you cannot find the infinite reality between the thoughts,
then where is the infinite reality?
And here is where it is here.
Beneath all the thinkingness is silence, void, silence.
The source of thinkingness, then, is an infinite silence and infinite peace.
And if you go in there, it's hard to lecture.
So, I'm not going to go in there now.
Because you feel weak and you begin to weep and you want to leave the world as soon as you can.
Stay out of there.
So, anyway, it's the infinite silent field out of which your consciousness and your thinkingness is arising.
So, your thoughts are not arising this way.
Each one is being individually created sequentially.
See there?
Oops.
Each one is being independently sequentially.
So, instead of like billiard balls, thoughts are really like flying fish.
I remember World War II, we were in something or other sea.
And I don't remember what sea it was.
Anyway, flying fish are flying out and landing on the deck.
So, a flying fish arises here.
All of a sudden, over here, another flying fish comes up.
Over here, another one.
Another one comes up.
Each one is coming up separately individually.
Of its own nature.
Spontaneously emerging of its own nature.
Because its nature, as a flying fish, is to do that.
Nobody is forcing it to do it.
Nobody is causing it to do it.
The nature of the flying fish is it gets a kick out of doing that.
Now, you'll see how sick and weird the human mind is.
This fish comes up here.
And some idiot who's always a professor at some university.
They're always a professor.
Will tell you that the fish are triangulating.
There's always this incredible mathematics.
You got to go through all the formulas and crap.
Demonstrates the triangulation of fish.
That's what your mind does.
So, your mind is the idiot scientist.
The idiot professor.
So, standing in your way is not ignorance.
No.
It's the idiot professor.
The fish doesn't.
The fish just is what it is.
See?
Each one of us just is what we are.
We're not caused by anything at all.
There's no cause for anything.
Creation is the unfolding of the unmanifest becoming manifest.
The infinite potentiality becoming manifest.
This is by virtue of the incredible power of the field.
That explains and now we understand how karma works.
Therefore, each one of us are karmic inheritance.
Which is sort of like a software program.
We're all born with a software program.
The brain is your hardware.
It's genetically engineered.
You've got nothing to do with that.
But you're born with consciousness.
So, you're born with this software programming.
Software.
That's your karmic inheritance.
That defines who you are.
Your calibrated level.
Everybody has a calibrated level of consciousness at the moment they're born.
The moment you're born, you already have a calibratable level of consciousness.
Without karma, how would you explain such a phenomena?
This now plays.
So, the hardware of the brain plays any software you put on it.
So, the karma is your software.
The karmic inheritance.
All the decisions made through great eons of time.
Now, because of the software, you might say you're like an iron filing.
Every spiritual decision then tends to change the configuration.
Let's say you've got a little karmic body.
It looks like caramel taffy or something.
All the decisions you've made have positioned it to be the way it is.
Now, in an infinite power, in an infinite field, like an electromagnetic field,
this little iron filing is positioned as a consequence of the power of the field.
The field is so infinitely powerful that as a little iron filing,
you automatically go to where you fit in the field.
As a consequence of that which you are,
in the power of the field determines all phenomena.
When and where you're born, how long you live.
And we discovered also through karmic research, through kinesiologic research,
you have a calibrated level of consciousness at birth.
People who are born are calibrated at 40.
60, 80, 200, 300, 400.
Also, at the moment of birth, the time of death is already preset.
Is that fatalism?
No.
You can call it whatever you like.
The fact is you enter already with a certain level of potential,
consciousness potential.
And your exit is already prearranged.
So you don't have to worry about dying.
It's all handled.
You know, the scary thing about this world is not...
The scary thing is how do you get out of here?
They keep closing all the doors, curing all these illnesses, safety features.
I mean, you can't get out of this place.
We're trapped. How are you going to get out of this place, you know?
Getting here is easy. Getting out of here, how are you going to get out?
Okay.
You have to get an exit permit from the government.
So that's not predestination, which is something else altogether.
But
your time is limited and the time of leaving is already preset.
It's sort of like getting a...
What do you call a computer disc now with a movie on it?
DVD? What do you call them?
DVD, yes. All right.
When you buy a DVD, the end of the sturdy is already in the tape
or the disc, what do you call it?
The end of the sturdy is already there.
The fact that it hasn't unrolled yet doesn't mean it's not there.
So it's like you're born with this computer disc CDD thing in your head.
This karmic CDB? What is it?
DVD.
Huh? DVD. DVD.
You're born with a karmic DVD.
However, you can play it on your computer and you can change the story as it goes.
But when the end of the disc arrives, that's the end of the disc, folks.
And if you listen to what we say in the lectures,
you will be very, very happy about it.
You can go now, you go.
Thank you, Lord.
It's okay to leave.
You know, I had a huge psychiatric practice for many years
and even after retirement, they didn't have anybody to go to the nursing homes
and various places.
So in the county, I used to do that.
30,000 miles a year, running around doing nursing homes and all.
Every nursing home always has an old crone strapped in a wheelchair.
She's got all these tubes, pipes hanging down there,
all these devices, machines, computerized stuff,
and she's always going,
Help! Help! Help! Help! Help!
They say, Doctor, Doctor, can't you do something?
She keeps, Help! Help! Help!
Help! Help! Help!
I know what she wants, but it's illegal.
Help me get out of here.
They won't let me out of here.
You cannot leave this world without Medicare permission.
Medicare breaks. It's not permissible.
Pull all these tubes and things out.
That's what she wants.
She keeps trying to pull the tube out, you know, because she wants to leave.
So what do they do? They strap her arm down. Literally.
Tie down their arm so you can't croak.
And get the hell out of here.
Before things get worse.
All right, so you come in with this karmic program,
you know, your software.
You've got already a calibratable level of consciousness at the moment of birth.
The level of consciousness will determine what kinds of choices and options
you will have to make decisions about.
Also, everyone is born under the most karmically optimal conditions
for their evolution and growth.
That was a major discovery.
Let's see if that's a fact.
Everybody knows Susan, but I want to make sure everybody knows Susan.
Without whom, we wouldn't know anything.
Okay, so the moment of...
What did we ask?
The moment of death is only a percent?
Right. No, it was karmic potential.
Oh, yes. Everyone's...
The circumstances of your birth
are perfectly aligned with your karmic potential
to potentiate your evolution and growth.
We have permission to ask, that will learn.
And the answer to that is true.
Resist. True.
That gets rid of self-pity, folks.
Poor me.
The competition for being a victim in the poor me
is so severe in society.
I mean, if you get to be more awful and pathetic than somebody else,
they just...
They're so full of envy and hatred.
They just hate you.
My condition is worse than your condition.
Being the martyr, the victim of injustice,
is the keynote to American society today.
All right.
So realizing that whatever the circumstances of your birth were,
hardship, illnesses, death of parents,
sexual predation, anything,
is part of one's karmic inheritance.
Karma has its upside.
It also has the necessity for the undoing
of things, the undoing of things.
So if we accept the less pleasant things about our life
and get that it's an undoing, an undoing,
and therefore to be grateful for it,
somehow, when you reach a certain level of consciousness,
then you remember.
You remember what the events were in previous life,
in a prior life, what the world would call a prior life.
It's all one life, but prior incarnation.
That which is infinite in dimension can only have a beginning and an ending.
So your consciousness has always been.
The field out of which your consciousness arises
has always been.
And because it has always been,
it will always be.
Death is not a possibility.
Too bad.
Not the people that dashes your final hopes, huh?
No, you have to accept responsibility.
Death is just, you know,
it's long for a cop-out, a cop-out.
No, you can't cop-out with physical death.
And if you didn't undo it all,
you come back again until you undo it all.
So, therefore, the vicissitudes of life
we can look at from wisdom and say,
I don't know what it's serving right now,
but obviously it is serving something,
either individually or collectively,
because people also have collective karma.
Yeah? Collective karma.
10,000 people kill 50,000 innocent civilians.
Now, how do you undo that?
How do the Vikings undo butchering
tens of thousands of innocent civilians?
Little babies in their crib.
How do you undo that?
If you want to get to heaven,
you're going to have to undo it.
So, you need an opportunity to undo it.
So, karma prepares the infinite possibility.
Therefore, we all inherit now,
by virtue of this life,
therefore, is a gift,
because through this life,
we can undo that which was negative and a deterrent,
and we can align ourself with that which is integrous.
The only difficulty is that the world has never known
truth and falsehood and what is integrous.
That's difficult, isn't it?
You have to live a life without a compass.
You only have the say-so of tradition and religion.
You know, traditional religion told you which way is truth.
So, we need the...
What do you want to call it? Number one.
Number one or number uno.
What do you call that thing? Slide.
Slide.
Slide. Ta-dum!
They've become relatively well-known.
The map of consciousness.
These are the levels of man throughout all of time,
as recorded throughout all of time.
Different wording and different cultures,
but they always boil down to exactly the same thing.
Exactly the same thing.
And we call these the levels of consciousness.
You can calibrate their relative energy.
And...
Um...
In doing this, the numbers became so large,
I had to switch to logarithmic.
Logarithmic.
So, each of these numbers are 10 to that power.
This is 10 times 10 times 10.
250 times.
10 times 10 times 10 times 10.
You do that 250 times.
You see that's a pretty big number.
So, it wouldn't fit on the blackboard.
So, we went to logarithmic.
We discovered that anything that ever existed, now or ever,
it can be calibrated on a scale of one to a thousand.
We said, what's the highest consciousness
that's ever walked this world?
And we got the great avatars.
Jesus Christ, Buddha, Krishna, Zoroaster.
Is the infinite...
That is the top potential.
The reasons for it are not important.
But, frankly, it's because of the nature
of protoplasm and the central nervous system
can only handle up to a power.
See, because you're talking logarithmically now,
as frequencies, energies go up,
the frequency gets higher and higher.
The human nervous system, frankly,
has great difficulty handling anything
over maybe 750.
From 750 up, you really should be in a different dimension.
From one to a thousand, we discovered then
that we could calibrate the consciousness level
of anything on earth.
Everything, now or ever.
And we discovered, as I said, the kinesiologic test.
When I saw Diamond do it, I realized it was...
Consciousness is like a giant electrostatic field.
Remember on the electrostatic speakers?
It was a membrane, electrostatically charged membrane.
Now, when you bring a charge up to it,
it reacts with an equal and opposite reaction.
If you bring up...
Those of you who know physics will laugh at this.
Let's say we bring up 32 frequencies.
Three protons and 32 neutrons,
or what do you call them?
Negatrons.
Electrons.
And protons.
Whatever they are.
Whatever the field holds,
an equal and opposite reaction shows up.
So, in the presence of truth then,
consciousness recognizes...
The difference between truth and falsehood,
and it recognizes the electrostatic charge,
you might say.
The higher truth goes up,
the higher and more powerful its charge.
So, when we calibrate something,
I hold it silently in mind.
People say, you're suggesting...
Don't forget, kinesiology has been examined,
you know, for decades by thousands of people.
So, every argument you can think of
has already been looked at by thousands of people.
I don't influence what she's thinking
because I don't tell her what I'm thinking.
We only verbalize it when we have an audience.
If I want to know something,
I don't want to spend the time and energy
talking about it.
Once in a while she'll say, what was that?
What was that?
Okay.
There's one I haven't had a chance to ask yet.
I have permission to ask that.
Okay.
What I'm thinking calibrates over 200 resistances.
300.
250.
260.
What I'm holding in mind is a phenomenon.
250.
260.
Telepathy.
We never did calibrate telepathy.
It says 250.
So, obviously, she didn't know what I was thinking
because I've had it on my disk for a couple of months.
Someday I'll ask.
Telepathy.
We never did ask it.
A lot of people have experienced it on various levels.
People who go for silent weekends
very often
become very adept at it.
I went on a...
I think it was only a four or five day silent retreat,
and within 24 hours
everybody was telepathic.
You wouldn't even think butter.
You would sit down
and somebody would just hand you butter
like they knew it.
Some of our staff have recently been
on silent weekends
and they say it's sort of magical and mystical.
So you discover that telepathic capacity.
It's not that you're consciously thinking a thing,
but what you're holding in mind
even non-verbally
is somehow knowable by other people.
Anyway, 250, that's interesting.
So this is the way we do it.
I don't want to influence her in any way.
She's so sophisticated
and skilled at this over the years
that it doesn't influence her.
But just to make sure,
I had no idea what was going to come up
about telepathy myself.
So we discovered
you can calibrate everything
on a scale of consciousness
that goes from one to a thousand.
The critical level,
and I forgot my pointer today,
I always take it where I don't need it
and forget it where I need it.
We found that
everything that is true
calibrates 200 and up,
and below 200.
So then we,
because having been a psychiatrist,
psychoanalyst, etc.,
we naturally calibrated these things
according to the
classical levels
of human consciousness.
Each level then
has its own way of
understanding or perceiving God,
including atheists.
Atheists can be predicted.
Their view of themself,
a person's opinion of myself.
We give this level
a name
that's common and familiar
so everybody knows
what grief is,
everybody knows what shame is.
Here we have the emotion
that goes with it, emotion.
Here you see
every day's headlines.
Every night's news broadcast.
You can calibrate
everything that happens on the news.
And this is the process
going on in consciousness
on the far right.
This plus knowing how to do kinesiology
can give you an answer
to anything.
Right now,
mankind in a way has
the most incredible gift
it's ever received.
First of all, the revelation
of the great teachers in history.
The gift of how to tell truth from falsehood.
This world,
and this is hard to get,
does not know truth from falsehood.
This world does not know
truth from falsehood,
nor does it have any test or capacity
to differentiate the two.
Convincingness has nothing to do with it.
The most convincing, persuasive
politicians in history
have led mankind
to death by the tens of millions
in my lifetime,
tens of millions
died as a result of the
rhetorical,
oratorical excellence of Adolf Hitler,
Stalin,
Milosevic,
the fallacy of Marxism,
etc.
The human mind
so, by the tens of millions
people salute
and worship falsehood.
Salute and worship
leaders who calibrate at 50.
Give up their lives
for leaders who calibrate at 50
worse than
Machine Gun Kelly.
Worse than Machine Gun Kelly.
Lower than Machine Gun Kelly.
People give up their lives
for them.
Donate all their properties.
Sacrifice their children.
Send their sons off to war.
To fight for illusion.
So really this is
one of the greatest gifts mankind
has ever really received.
It's only dawned on me more and more recently.
What an incredible
it's probably the most
valuable
gift we own right now.
Just think what you could do
if you could know truth from
falsehood about anything,
anytime.
How would it make your life different?
The only requirement
to get an honest answer
is that you have to
yourself be aligned
and committed to integrity
and truth. That eliminates
85%
of the world's population.
Therefore, what we're talking about
today is accessible
to only 15% of the world's
population. It calibrates
over 200. If the purpose
of asking the question is personal
selfishness, then the answer
is unreliable.
When you ask for something, people say
can I use kinesiology about my
business? Yes.
So long as you ask only in the name of
the highest good. Anything
in reference to your personal life.
You can say it is in
the highest good. The highest good
meaning for the world,
for society, for your employees,
for your employees and their families.
For the good and welfare
after all, everyone
who has any kind of money is now
the steward of that money.
So you now have like a moral responsibility.
The minute you have money, you have in a way
a certain moral responsibility
to be a responsible steward for that money.
The taxpayers have worked
hard for that money.
We expect our public
officials to
be considerate of that. We've all
busted our chops for that
money.
So if
the intention of the question is
integrous and you yourself calibrate over
200, then the reliability
should be excellent and it's like riding
a bicycle, you just need a little experience
with it. So you can say
it's in the name of the highest
good that my company
by this other little corporation
that we expand,
we triple the size of our restaurant.
The way to go broke in the restaurant
world is to be very successful and then
double it, double the size of the restaurant.
Have you ever seen
a little thriving Chinese restaurant,
you know, there's steam all over,
Italian restaurant, you know,
you can see the chef there with the spaghetti
and there's a waiting line out there
so they're gonna double and triple it.
Okay, so they close for six
weeks, reopen,
and it goes bankrupt.
In Sedona it happens all the time.
I don't know, 15, 20 of them I can think of.
The energy of this change.
So, if I were him
I would say in the name of the highest good
that I double the size of this restaurant
and you're probably gonna know. Why?
Because it's the ambiance that's pulling the people
and if you double it and make it luxurious
you've lost what they're there for.
You know, I can remember
in the Gaslight
District, you know, a very
popular tavern, you know, very
popular, everybody goes there.
And it's very cool and hip, you know,
to hang out there near the gas
gasworks. So somebody
buys it and decides they're gonna clean it up.
They close the
place for six weeks,
clean it all up, and now nobody goes there.
Because the energy
is all there. I remember the Electric Circus
back east in New York.
The Electric Circus was one of the first psychedelic
nightclubs.
And rock music, it was very avant-garde.
And the cool and the hip went there.
And there was a waiting line outside.
So they closed it, and of course
after a couple of years, Andy
Warhol, the whole group used to hang out there.
So they closed it and expanded it.
And what had been
really sorta funky
was now like a white
alabaster and curved walls.
Really weird.
People went
back there, the acoustics were horrible
because it bounced off these curved walls.
And it went flat broke. Nobody went
there anymore. But when it was all jammed
up and funky looking,
it was
where everybody went, you know.
So the thing
to do then is you can pose anything
that you would consider personal,
but pose it in a way that is not
just like you're gonna vote.
The way to vote is
not, I'm always amazed when I hear people
come on television, they say,
they're gonna vote for so-and-so because he's gonna
vote for higher wages for truck drivers.
You know, the guy's a truck driver.
I never hear anybody say, I'm gonna vote for so-and-so
because I think it's the best for the country.
You know, you could say,
which would
serve the best interest of
mankind or the country
instead of just me? I mean, it seems
to me you would vote for whoever you think is gonna be
the best for the country.
And last night on TV, they were saying,
you know, the guy makes pickles and he's gonna vote for
whoever pays more to pickle
makers than packers or something.
I mean, it's so completely
self-interested. I don't believe
this that people think in such a petty way.
You know, only me, me, me.
But that's the ego,
egocentricity, and
it looks to gain.
You see, it's always looking, it's demanding
and it looks to gain.
And, alright,
so that's, we could spend a whole
lecture on this, and we used to spend a whole lecture
on just going over the
scale of consciousness and the
incredible implications.
In the United States of
America,
well, let's go to the next slide. We'll get
there. Anyway, let's go to the next slide.
Well, we'll go to that after a while.
In the
world, then, 15%
of the world's population
calibrates over 200.
15%.
If you drop yourself off in the world
with a parachute, the chances
are, 85%,
that the people around you will be
non-integrists. As you'll see
later, you're safer with Coco,
the gorilla,
than you are
in the United States.
Now, only 49%
of the people calibrate
below 200.
In the United States, which calibrates overall at
421, 51%
of the people calibrate over 200
and are integrists.
So that's a very interesting development.
We, on the scale of
consciousness, we went up to 600
because
there are only a half a dozen people on the planet
at any time, at this time,
that calibrate over 600. So, it's not
too useful.
We do use it in
calibrating spiritual teachers throughout
history. They're the only ones that go over 600.
Nisargadatta Maharaj,
various people like that, up to a thousand.
So,
up to 600 is really all
of it. At 600,
the linear dissolves
into the non-linear.
And 50% of the
time, when people hit level 600,
they leave. They leave
just because.
Because,
well,
they leave and
they just topple over.
At that level, everything, you don't
need anything.
And everybody around you thinks you need something, but
that's because they want to keep the body going,
which is their problem.
So, they feed it and make sure you wash it
and all kinds of strange things.
So, 600 and up, you're at the mercy
of the people around you.
Remember Ramana Maharshi,
Ramana Maharshi was
just an ordinary
religious, ordinarily religious
person, not unduly.
And then, in teenage
somewhere, I forget what age,
he suddenly went into a different state
and he fell down and died.
He felt himself die.
And he did die.
And what
survived was his consciousness, which
remained silent for several
years. Anyway, he
was bitten by all kinds
of insects, hadn't eaten in weeks, and
some spiritually advanced
people discovered his condition
and saw to it that he ate
and various things like that. And he did
not even speak for two years.
Which is probably a good
idea.
These are the subjective
states. So, we calibrated them even though
they're unusual. Historically, they're
cited all the time.
Teachers of enlightenment, avatars,
uh,
avatars in 1985.
So, these are the
depictions of
divinity, Brahma,
uh,
and then archangels,
who you gotta be careful of.
Archangels calibrate about 50,000 and up.
And I've told the story
of my own personal evolution.
In the pits of hell,
in the pits of hell,
in the very bottom of hell,
of absolute blackness and forever despair,
a voice arose
within that said,
if there is a God,
I ask him for help.
And then silence
and oblivion.
And then the explosion
of the wondrous state
which revealed divinity
as creation itself.
Not only as source, but as creation.
And
then the mind was like
shock silent in awe.
It is still silent in awe.
So, you gotta be careful
of archangels,
because I always pictured
that it was a cruising archangel, see?
And here's this idiot in the depths of hell,
says, I ask him if there is a God.
And he just glances over like,
hmm, bang.
Archangel, 50,000 and up.
Well, you're talking about
a logarithmic scale.
You can imagine what 50,000 is.
10 times 10 times 10, 50,000 times
the power is so infinite,
it's incomprehensible.
The power there is absolute.
It's because of the
absoluteness of the power
that
the unmanifest
becomes manifest.
The creation,
which is merely a thought,
then begins to unfold.
Creation and evolution are one and the same thing.
Because the way creation
presents itself
seems sequential
and evolutionary.
What's not evolutionary
what's evolutionary
is the witness.
What is sequential is the witnessing.
Because you witness evolution
and it seems to be sequential,
you think evolution is sequential.
It's a total oneness.
It is neither sequential
nor does it even occur within time,
which is the programming
which the mind projects on the phenomena.
Okay, let's go away from that.
The calibrated levels of consciousness,
this is their equivalent
in microwatts.
So as you see,
below level,
consciousness level 200,
the power is limited,
very limited.
And then as your consciousness advances,
your power becomes extraordinary.
Okay, so we'll move on.
That's the equivalent in microwatts.
85% of the world lives
below consciousness level 200.
So the great volume
of humanity then
is below
level 200.
Why do you get
that this is not a celestial realm?
Yes, Walmart has
vaults. I agree.
Government officials
are human. Yeah.
True.
This is not a celestial realm
where no such phenomena occur.
Alright.
Why doesn't mankind self-destruct?
It's because of the exponential power.
The 15%
have so much power
that they totally counterbalance
95%.
The power, the 15%.
So the kindly, loving, forgiving
thoughts that you have,
you're not conscious of it.
But that is counterbalancing
980 people
thinking of suicide
who suddenly at the last moment
think, oh,
maybe I'll give it another try.
It's because of the presence
of the infinite power
of this field.
And as a consequence
of what they are,
what they have become,
counterbalances.
Now what they do,
people think, well, we'll have a peace parade.
No. It's what you have become
that is the power
that counterbalances.
What you do is relatively
irrelevant.
What you do is only a consequence
of what you have become anyway.
What you have become.
So consciousness is like a light bulb
and the higher the level of consciousness,
the more intense the light
that it shines out.
The more intense the light that it shines out.
So what's the next one?
Oh, we got there already.
What happened to the evolution
of consciousness over time?
The time graph.
I thought that was supposed to be next.
We can live without it.
Oh, yes.
Well, we got a little bit out of step.
This was sent by a man named,
it's easy to remember his name.
An engineering student.
This suddenly appeared in the mail.
Just as the previous graph.
His name is Daniel Lyons.
Isn't that an easy one to remember?
I always think of Daniel
and the lion's den.
This guy's name is Daniel Lyons.
Which is an adorable name.
And he sent this to us.
He's a mathematician,
an engineering student.
This is how much
evolutionary time
has elapsed.
And you see the
calibrated level of consciousness.
It's only in the last flick of time
that the calibrated
level of consciousness
is now up to
207 or so.
It took this much
evolutionary time,
eons and eons,
before it even moved off the carpet.
It barely got off the carpet
after eons and eons
of time.
Now it's
beginning to rise.
People say, what do you think is the future of mankind?
I say, all I can do is look at this graph
and from this graph it looks like
the consciousness of mankind
is about to catapult ahead.
In fact, learning kinesiology
and how to tell truth from falsehood
and all that we lecture about
is a consequence of this.
It's a consequence of the evolution of consciousness
that we're now able to tell truth from falsehood
and do so in a second
about anything, anywhere in time.
Or history.
So long as the question is
integrous and the people asking it are integrous.
So here's where we are
and you could
pretty much predict.
The nature of consciousness itself
is to evolve.
So now we'll move to the next slide.
Okay.
Now we gotta go backwards to evolutionary time.
I got those backwards.
Yeah, okay, that's right.
It's my fault
because I changed all these charts
yesterday and
Betty was trying to keep up with it.
How does this start here?
Oh yes.
I have all kinds of pointers
and of course they're all home.
So I'll be the pointer.
The beginning of time.
The beginning of the evolution of consciousness.
How did consciousness evolve?
This is critical
to understand from a spiritual
viewpoint. I'll tell you why.
The ego.
Oh, look at that. Right out of the mystical
wonderment of the universe.
How did I do that, huh?
Intention manifests
when the conditions are appropriate.
You see,
how he and I and the pointer and the audience
are all one concordance.
It's all one concordance
and of course this evolves
when it's needed.
This is crucial to understand.
It's not academic at all.
Self-hatred, guilt, all this stuff
that comes about from egocentricity.
Hating yourself,
shame, guilt, all that.
It's all a response
to our perceptions,
spiritually evolved people,
our perception of the ego.
Once you understand the
evolution of the ego and its core,
the essence of it, you stop feeling guilty
about it. Now you can
transcend it.
The first signs of life, the unmanifest
becomes manifest.
So the universe evolves
as a physicality.
What is to become planet Earth
is liquid lava,
no, just energy flying around
which condenses itself
because E equals MC squared
to the potential
for
what do you call
our galaxy and then
a little glob of it spins out
of these hot gases and it condenses
to lava. And over the
eons this then cools
off enough to develop a crust
on it that could sustain
life. The interaction
of consciousness,
the interaction of the
infinite power of the unmanifest
when it interacts
with matter is that it can
spawn the emergence of life.
So the source of life
is consciousness.
The source of life is
non-physical. The source
of life is
the impact of consciousness
on material when
conditions are
appropriate for this.
That takes care of the mechanistic reductionist.
Life does not
arise from non-life.
You see the imbecility of such
a proposition. That's what's
called mixing paradigms.
Mixing levels of abstraction.
Violating the Kantian
categories. It's
dumb.
Life has completely
different qualities from non-life.
The mundane mechanical
chemical
cannot create something of a
totally different level of
being, existence, paradigm.
It's a violation even within
the Newtonian world of
logic. What happened to, oh my
god, I said
something wrong, didn't I?
Did I say somebody
was feeling blue or what happened?
Well, without
that, folks,
we had a good prognosis for a
while, but I've got the
transparency with me if the worst
comes to worst.
She can play with that. We'll get it back then.
Oh my.
I mean, the computer world, I stay away
from it as far as I can.
It's a trap. Once it gets you by
the ankle, you can't get
loose on it.
Alright, so the evolution of
life then. Somewhere back in
infinite time.
Unmanifest as
the power of
consciousness itself, the infinite field of
consciousness, interacted
with material matter
and activated
the energy of life.
Now, life as it first
appeared on this crusty
planet
did not emerge
under favorable conditions.
As you can see, if you landed
on Mars, your survival
would be dependent on
getting energy.
So life is born
without the source of energy
within it, it has to get it.
So the first organism that arose
was the bacteria.
Bacteria calibrate as one.
That moved on to
protozoa, calibrate
as three. Then on into
the insect world.
But you can see the basic quality of life
is that
the organism has to go
outside of itself for the energy.
And our
bad karma as humans
is that we're not born green.
If we're
we need chlorophyll instead of skin.
When I get back there to the other side
I'm gonna tell them too.
Next time you do it,
boss, how about making us green, okay?
If you're green,
you don't need a job, you don't need money,
you don't have to go to work.
You just walk around being who you are.
Happily,
your green energy
creates energy.
Now, in the animal world
unfortunately,
you have to get.
So the core of the ego
is self-interest.
The core of the ego
is get.
And you see the appeal to the voters
today is based on the same
get. It's a solar plexus
energy. Why?
Because the organism
is born, it does not
have within itself
the capacity to create energy.
So the animal kingdom
has to get it from somewhere.
And the easiest way is
to eat it.
So we're born to eat.
Without eating you die.
So if you were green
you wouldn't have to eat.
You see what a break that would be?
Let's all go together.
Next time we'll come back green
in a different place.
You don't have to go to work.
You don't have to save up money.
What good would money be?
So the core of the ego then
consciousness level below 200
is get. Selfishness.
Self-centeredness.
And that is
oh goody.
That is the core
of your animal.
Inside of you is an animal.
And here's how the animal grew.
Look at time.
Remember that thing about time?
It did nothing forever.
And I just recently jumped up.
So these ages are so old
I can't pronounce all these words.
Trillions and quadrillions
of rock ages
and things.
Bacteria at one.
In vertebrates.
Then you get scorpions, snails,
fish, amphibians,
reptiles.
Finally you get up to the dinosaurs.
Dinosaurs calibrate at 60.
That's pretty good.
World leaders in every day's headlines.
I'm going to hold somebody in line.
He calibrates over 60.
Thank you.
It's been loud, huh?
Why does he calibrate lower than a dinosaur?
Because the dinosaur
is innocent.
It eats the living
because it has to
for its own survival.
So the dinosaur's intention
is innocent.
The dinosaur's intention
is merely to eat.
And something below 60 then
would have to be a pretty negative intention.
Alright, that's just an
accidental thing.
Here we have the reptiles.
And here we have the
higher dinosaurs.
Here we have modern mammals.
And the rise and dominance
of man. So here you see
how consciousness
evolved protoplasmically
as needing.
Needful.
Therefore you don't have to feel guilty.
That your ego
is greedy.
Of course it's greedy.
If it wasn't greedy you wouldn't be here.
We owe our survival to the animal within us.
And I call the
animal in me ego.
Ego.
Now we know that ego hates anybody
who cuts in on traffic
and that they should die.
He knows that the voters
who are going to vote wrongly
deserve what they get
because they're wrong.
Therefore
to win it's okay to lie.
It's okay to lie to win.
Because he thinks survival
depends on winning and getting and gaining
and have power over others.
Why anybody would
want power over others is totally beyond me.
To control other people, force them to think
the way you think.
And when the temptation came
because it was of an extremely high
space beyond mind and
thinkingness and mentalization
there was really nothing left
other than the source of life itself.
And there came to me
so that I understood
what came to Jesus Christ.
There comes to you in the silence
a knowingness.
There's a knowingness.
It's a silent transmission.
It's like what? Telepathic I guess.
Telepathic.
Now that you know that you
have transcended karma
now that you know you're not answering
the answer bolt.
That there is no God who will
punish you.
There is no consequences for all actions.
All power is yours.
Own it.
And that was
I saw what Christ said there
because there aren't too many people
at that high pass.
And he turned it down.
And a few others I saw were there
turned it down.
And happily I saw
who would want power over others.
And so I turned it down.
Own it.
And all power is yours.
Own it and all power is yours.
Because there is no payment.
You're even beyond love.
Even beyond love.
So you would not even be constrained
by love.
You could put all the poor widows
out of your apartment house
and double the rent.
And if they starved to death
because you no longer have love for others
you're beyond love.
Beyond love is an error
because love is one of the attributes
of God.
And a teaching that
negates love as
only a manipulation
or wanting other people's approval
is a very serious
very serious error.
180 serious error.
Love is one of the qualities of divinity.
So when you look at yourself
you can say
what do I want with power over others?
What a drag it would be wouldn't it?
Wouldn't it be a drag?
That power over others
control how they think
and what they believe and all that.
So anyway
we see the rise and dominance of man
and we see
and we saw from that previous chart
that it's only about now.
Okay so move on to the next slide.
What say?
She thinks for me, thank God.
Let's go back, let's go to the next one.
Okay and
very interestingly
this is one of my favorite slides
and after you've seen this slide
and comprehend it
it will eliminate guilt forever.
Guilt, shame,
hatred
you get rid of it all now forever.
Because once you understand
the core of the narcissist
is the ego that you were born with.
You were born with an animal brain
that's your hardware.
Karmically you come in with software
but that software now has to play on this hardware.
You're stuck with biologic hardware of an animal folks.
Oh.
We own our animal.
The way we disappeared is
we stopped making an enemy of them
and we say yeah I've got an animal nature.
So here we see the protozoa.
We see
oh I've got a pointer now.
And look
this is really fun.
You see how they all come up here?
Crustaceans, insects,
grasshoppers. Here's grasshoppers.
They're not too smart, huh?
But they're still around.
Reptiles,
snakes, alligators.
I don't know. I don't understand people
who play with alligators.
It's just macho that you can grab an alligator
get your picture taken.
I'd like to see them grab a dinosaur though.
Let's see you do that one.
Or a Komodo dragon.
And we see whales
and dolphins,
migratory birds, birds of prey,
rhinoceros,
songbirds, doves.
And polar bear,
water buffalo. Water buffalo are
very dangerous. Water buffalo
will be staying there and then just suddenly for no reason
he'll charge you.
But he's not as dangerous as the hippopotamus.
And I always tell people about the hippopotamus.
Kills more humans than any other
wild animal. Do not hang
out with hippopotamus if you get nothing else
out of this lecture.
You see these idiots in canoes
are hanging out with hippopotamus.
Finally he says
Four people plus a canoe
go down his goal.
Just do not hang out.
You see there's people that haven't even gotten
that far. Do not hang out
with hippopotamus.
Do not lay down on the railroad track.
You know what I mean?
Now you see the emergence of the grazers.
And much to our surprise when we calibrated these
we saw suddenly we had
gone over consciousness level 200.
That's the critical level
in the human. And wow.
Here it is. The critical level
characteristic difference between
animals below 200 and animals
over 200. Below
200 they live at the price of the life
of others. They have
to eat and kill
in order to live. And now
at 200 suddenly you become benign.
Just like the human dimension.
Below 200 people are dangerous.
They're not safe till
they're 200 and over.
And the animal kingdom, you see the same
phenomena. Isn't that curious?
Consciousness level 200
then differentiates. That
which is dangerous
and that which is benign.
So the animal once it reaches
200 becomes a grazer.
It eats grass. It doesn't kill
anybody. It doesn't tear them to pieces.
And
you see they'll defend themselves
like an elephant. You get up
to cats at 240. Family
cat 245. So when
you adopt a pet
just their being around you
advances their consciousness 5
sometimes even 10 points.
Family dog you see.
Monkeys, gorillas, chimpanzees.
And here's
an African Grey.
Alex. Alex
is Broccoli's
ideal.
You keep listening
pretty soon you'll be smart as Alex.
You'll be smart
as Alex.
Our Grey is named Broccoli.
So we've been calibrating Broccoli every couple of months.
Coco. We all know
Coco. Coco is
really quite benign.
You're safer with Coco
a gorilla than most
of the people on the planet.
Coco is at 405.
Then we see the
wonderment of these two pets.
We see that the cat's purr
calibrates at
500 and the dog's wagging tail
calibrates at 500.
500 is love.
So the dog's wagging tail
the cat's purr
is reflecting the
energy of love.
And I'll just tell the last story when we were in Toronto
and then we'll take a break.
And when we were in Toronto
on the front page of the paper
the day we gave the lecture
was the story of a dog named Elvis.
And Elvis, there was a man in the park
who had
6,000 rounds of ammo
and high powered rifles
and he was like the famous
killers that hit the newsreel
gonna mow down everybody, kill everybody
and then kill himself.
He would not give up his weapons.
All of a sudden
Elvis, this dog
ran across with a
frisbee in his mouth
and jumped up and wanted this
guy to play.
And this guy suddenly came to his senses
suddenly said, what the hell am I doing?
And dropped his
rifle and surrendered to the
officials and I guess he's now in treatment.
But see Elvis came up
with an energy fuel to 500
so his wagging tail
his 500
hit this man's dementia
and the man became sane.
Amazing.
The healing power of love which we know
experientially
in therapeutics.
We know that people who have dogs and cats
or pets and love them
live longer, have lower blood pressure
have fewer heart attacks, etc.
It doesn't mean that you can't get out of here
but they'll
they'll make the way
waiting time more pleasant.
Sitting on the park bench
waiting to leave.
You can have your kitty purring in your lap
and when you leave.
When it's time to leave the planet
all I want is the cat and the kitty
and the surrounding
being surrounded by love.
Love tends to bring
love to oneself. So loving people
I think tend to have loving pets.
So we're going to take a break for how long?
Fifteen minutes.
Okay. Thank you so much.
Where's the sound person?
Okay. Sound person.
Sound person.
Where's the sound person?
We know that a fifteen minute break
always takes half an hour.
That's why we give you fifteen minutes.
If we gave you half an hour
it would take forty-five.
Now in all the excitement here
I forgot what today's lecture was about.
But now I remember.
Today's lecture is called
We said the human mind
cannot move faster than
one ten-thousandth of a second.
Therefore, how are you going to
discover
this field here?
When
in early life, teenage or whatever it was
I caught the
mind claiming credit
for saving the life of the rabbit.
It wasn't the mind that did that.
It was the field.
The field.
That's where the first mind arises.
The witness observer.
People want to know how to become enlightened.
I tell them.
Stop identifying with content
and identify with the field.
Because meditation is something that
tends to be somewhat artificial.
It's not what you do in everyday life.
A lot of people go someplace
and pay money to learn it
and spend three weeks learning it.
And you're very enthused about meditation.
So you do it.
I did it myself for an hour in the morning
and night for many years.
And then what happens is
your life gets to be too busy.
And so now you do it for half an hour
and then you skip Monday morning
and then Thursday night you forget it.
And within six months you've given up meditation.
Then you go to a retreat
and you do it again for a week.
So it's not something that you are.
It's something
in addition
compartmentalized.
I think I'll go and meditate now.
It means you've got to leave everything.
Get off the TV.
Tell the dog
go lay down.
You've got to go to some special place.
Get a special mat.
Special perfume, incense,
all kinds of images of divine figures.
You go into this state.
Yeah.
And then when you
stand up and walk around
back.
You're right back to where you were.
Consciousness is advanced by
identifying with the field.
Not with the content of the field
but with the field itself.
That's the witness observer.
See.
The mind is literal and linear
and it's good for
figuring out what all the controls are
in the car, you know.
We have a new Chevy
and it's got 100 controls.
100 controls.
At my age that's a nightmare.
Where's the on
or off?
Great.
I'm going to go see these
and then see these playing when I'm driving.
I would have run over the rabbit.
You know what I mean?
When you drive
you trust the field, don't you?
You don't just trust what you're looking at
because this car is just coming in
from this side.
When you drive
you tend to spread your consciousness
and your awareness to the field.
Or you better or you wouldn't be here today.
No.
You're aware of the totality.
You're aware of your creative lifestyle
than this one
in which
you become aligned with the field
rather than the content of the field.
And we'll get to a diagram about that later.
You get to be the field.
Why?
Because the field and the observer
do not move within time.
The mind has to move from
the particular to the particular
to the particular.
It's confined to the linear
so the mind goes from this word
to this picture in the paper
to this TV thing.
So the mind can only move
can't move any faster than
one tenth of a second.
Flicks from this to this.
The field doesn't move
from anything to anything.
If you become
one with the field
the field automatically
notices
that the brake went on before.
The mind took credit.
It was the witness observing
that discerned that.
So the witness observer
is faster than
one tenth of a second
because it is not on and off.
It doesn't move from this to that.
It's the totality
of the field.
It's the field that sees all three fish
arise out of the sea at once.
If I look at this fish
and then this fish
you can't do it, right?
If you're one with the field
you see all three fish
simultaneously of their own.
It's very obvious.
You don't have to attend lectures
to remind you what a flying fish knows.
It just is what it is.
It doesn't think
oh I decided to leap out of the sea.
It's nature
did that for it.
So the witness observer
and we'll get to a diagram
that explains that
is the field.
So I tend to emphasize contemplation
as a spiritual style.
To be aware of the totality
of the field.
The current political thing is
it isn't what this one says
and what this one says.
That's what they all focus on.
It's more the intention of the field.
What's the intention of the field?
What's the intention of the people involved?
What's the overall field
that they're creating?
Then you try to decide
which field is the best
for the country.
I saw a TV
being interviewed saying
they're going to do what's best
for the country.
They're going to do what's best
for us truck drivers
or us plumbers
or us whatever
instead of the field.
When you ask what
in the name of the highest good
so you would ask
if you want to find out how to vote
in the name of the highest good
I would be best serving the highest good
appeals to you.
We'll go back to the slides.
We got as far as the dog's wagging tail
and Elvis.
We're going to go on to the next one.
You see the animal now
you're born with
that's your physiology.
Then on top of this animal brain
evolves the prefrontal cortex.
The prefrontal cortex
does not replace
the animal brain.
It's an add-on.
Now you have the great
difficulty of being a human being.
If I was St. Peter
I'd say where have you been? Planet Earth?
Have you been a human being? Yes. Pass.
Why?
Because you're stuck with an animal brain
and a prefrontal cortex
with spiritual awareness,
honesty, integrity, answerability
and such things.
Now you've got
a setup for conflict.
How to resolve the conflict then
traditionally has been done
the down side, the gothic side
of traditional religion
has been sin and guilt and penance, etc.
Ash cloth,
sackcloth and ashes.
Consequently
few people have become enlightened in history.
It's an extreme rarity.
Because
God is not at the bottom of the chart
of the Calvary of the level of consciousness.
God is at the top.
Joy, happiness, forgiveness
So
the first thing we learn is that
God is not at the bottom of the chart
God is at the top of the chart.
Joy, forgiveness
love.
What to do with the down side then?
If you
vilify it, you set up a duality
in which the ego
becomes your enemy. Your animal nature
now becomes your enemy.
And you have to do penance and say the rosary.
Because it gets angry
and it's the
selfish, etc.
The way to eliminate a thing is to not
resist it and to adopt it.
You adopt it.
My ego's name is
Ego.
And I accept
that ego is what it is
because it's my animal inheritance.
Instead of vilifying it
I said of course you're selfish.
Of course you want to win.
Of course people in traffic deserve to die.
And the
people who vote wrongly, we know who they are.
Deserve what they get,
don't they?
So you just
assume that the ego is that way
and that everybody's ego is that way.
So you finally have a prefrontal
cortex. So as
consciousness evolves,
it evolves from
the emotions of
the negative emotions
then it evolves to more positive
emotions.
At the very bottom it's pure animal emotion.
And then it evolves
from negative emotions, shame,
guilt, hatred, etc.
to positive emotions.
Enthusiasm, commitment, reliability,
the traditional
virtues of traditional America.
And eventually the
prefrontal cortex evolves to the point
where it can think.
Most people think they can think but that's
an illusion. They're not thinking.
They think they're thinking.
You can't really
think until you get to consciousness level
400, which excludes
most voters.
Logic and
reason arose late
in the game.
It really hasn't made much
progress since about
350 BC.
In 350 BC, Aristotle,
Plato, Socrates
pretty much, of course later refined
Kant and others.
But pretty much it was said
the logic, the difference between rhetoric and
logic, and the
paradigm of reality that
dominates our current society.
American society calibrates at 421.
400 is the level
of the intellect,
reason, the prefrontal cortex,
education, college.
So America calibrates higher than any country
in the world right now at 421.
So we celebrate
inventiveness, creativeness,
intelligence,
going to college, learning,
reading, becoming educated,
staying up with current events,
being informed.
So we emphasize
intelligence.
And out of it has come a great society.
A great society.
Capacity to reason and to think.
So let's, this is
the world I grew up in. In childhood
other people were playing stickball and
wrestling and all kinds of things.
And football and
all kinds of dangerous games.
They didn't allow me on the football field.
The coach said, I don't want you on the football field
because your bones are just going to
get crunched. And so he wouldn't
approve me for anything.
The worst day for me was field day
when there was no classes and
everybody climbed ropes and did somersaults
and other nightmarish things.
Because I was into the great books
of the western world.
Which were assembled by
Mortimer Adler at the University of Chicago
in the 50s.
These are the greatest thinkers the world has ever seen.
These are the people that set up the paradigm
of America as it stands today.
The Constitution
of the United States, which calibrates
at 710, the highest of any
in the world. 710.
710. Extremely brilliant.
What's so terrific about the
United States Constitution?
It says,
equality arises
by virtue of the
divinity of our creator.
The Americans political
rights arise out of
the fact that out of the creator
arose the rights of man.
Not by the vote.
Not by secularism.
Not by one army winning over another.
But by virtue of the
divinity of our source.
That is what gives us
freedom of religion
and freedom from religion.
710.
Constitution of the United States.
People that want to meddle with it,
when you calibrate them,
are usually less than 200.
Change the Constitution of the United States,
you calibrate that energy of that person,
you usually find it's less than 200.
Because the sheer arrogance of it
is enough to put you below 200.
Anyway,
here you've got the greatest minds.
So, while everybody else is playing stickball
and other violent games,
sticking their fingers in each other's
eyes and things,
I was sitting
with a big book in front of me,
and I wore very thick glasses,
I had trifocals and all.
So here's this skinny ectomorph,
you know, a bookworm,
and the mesomorphs
are out there whacking into each other.
I could never really get the pleasure of that.
What is the pleasure of wrestling?
This guy's eyeballs are
in your point.
What is the kick out of that?
You know what I'm saying?
I was fascinated with Aristotle
and Plato and
the aphorisms of Marcus Aurelius
and things like that.
So you see here's in the 400s
Thomas Aquinas and
Marcus Aurelius,
Sir Francis Bacon, Berkeley,
all the great names of history.
Chaucer,
Darwin at 450.
So here you see the Newtonian paradigm.
Where's Sir Isaac Newton?
I think he's on here too, isn't he?
You see the
idea of causality.
Now the problem with the human mind,
and I can't tell truth from falsehood,
was delineated quite clearly
by Descartes.
The problem with the human mind
is its dualistic nature.
It thinks
that what res interna,
res cogitans,
it thinks
that what it thinks
is what is out there.
It confuses res interna
with res externa.
The reality of thinkingness
with the reality of nature
is what the universe is.
If you follow what I'm saying
you will see that
the concept of causality
is res interna,
res cogitans.
It's a thinkingness.
That there is a this causing a that
is a dualistic perception
on the part of the mind.
It now projects it
into the world
and thinks causality is out there.
In thinking that, for one thing,
when it comes to causality
it's violating a very
basic principle of logic itself.
Because a thing follows another
it doesn't mean
it's caused by that which preceded it.
That's the great illusion
which science itself falls into.
So science
is limited to the paradigm
of about 450 to 460
even quantum mechanics.
To go beyond duality
you then have to go into a different paradigm,
a different paradigm.
Within the Newtonian paradigm
of causality.
If you're stuck with causality
to a spiritual student
you're then stuck with the thought
that there is a personal separate I
causing a that.
There's a personal I.
It's answerable, punishable,
limited.
And it causes that.
It decides that.
There's a separate personal self
with a small s
that is separate from the infinite oneness.
If you constantly
identify with the field
you will catch, the witness observer
will see that everything is happening
spontaneously.
We saw it happen spontaneously this morning.
This is where things say
things happen spontaneously
as a result of intention.
Audit came out of the audience, didn't it?