to demon to to utilize one's skills you
know for the benefit of all of life
then empowers them empowers them you
become empowered
you know the starting the starting gate
if you uh use a fast stopwatch the
person who's doing it for the sake of
the university,
womanhood, Canada, whatever they're
doing for the flag, uh, will have a
quicker and more power at the start than
the person is trying to who's going to
race in order to win.
A personal the person will win. I want
to win. I want to be the winner. Alino,
he already loses a quarter of a second
right off the bat. And he loses a good
percentage of car. Do whatever you do
for some higher purpose, some higher
gain. Thank you.
>> We calibrated the very interesting in
Scotland there at
the military tattoo in front of uh
>> what's the name of the castle there in
Edinburgh.
>> Edinburgh Castle. Yeah.
>> That was stunning. That was stunning.
And again, it was not what it looked
like it was. It's called military. Then
when you got into it and calibrated, you
find it's got nothing to do with
military at all. It has to do with the
demonstration of excellence.
You hear a 100 bag pipers
playing
at my heart.
Calates about 550.
Thousands of people there all became
silent and wept at once.
>> My bad.
>> No. Got nothing to do with militaryism
at all.
It has to do with valor, integrity,
honor,
uh, love of humanity,
incredible power. Incredible power.
>> It just so happens they made the
association.
>> Mhm.
>> It's the association.
>> Yeah.
>> It's the energy field of uh we calibrate
the energy field of that.
>> It was over 500. So, yeah. Would you
recommend that we calibrate politicians
before we vote for them
>> and then to continue?
>> Don't tell anybody what you get.
>> Yeah. And then continue to monitor them
while they're in power.
>> You Yeah. A person of advanced
consciousness knows wants to know what
to calibrate. Now, it's not necessary
that a person caler is going to be
better.
>> That's the difference that we want to
know.
>> That's the difference.
They're not necessarily going to be
better
>> but it certainly is a foot up.
>> Well, there's other qu all the other
qualities. See,
>> now Aristotle thought there is three
factors in politics. See there's ethos
that is the integrity of the speaker.
There's logos that's the integrity of
the message, the speech, the lecture.
Now then there's pos which is where the
audience is at. All right. The
difficulty with the patrician let's say
the way I view President Bush is
petition
I know within himself is integrous and
the message is integrous as far as he
can ascertain
but getting across the audience is
something else again.
President Roosevelt, you know,
calibrated around 500. So he would get
the whole country to do things that were
very unpleasant, like you have to have
butter ration and gasoline ration
and skirts have to be short and you
can't have uh things of war. And he got
no protest at all. Why? Because he had
fireside chats. So in the evening, we'd
all sit around the radio. Explain why we
can't have butter for everybody, why
meat has to be rationed, why you can't
have gasoline and all this. Does anybody
grumble? No, nobody grumbles. So the
capacity to communicate. So there's more
than being correct. There's more than
having the right information. There's
how you make this available to the
people. So it might be more effective.
somebody who calibrated lower but was
better at um conversation and rhetoric
and connecting with the audience you
know connecting with the audience
communication
so there's more than just a calibrated
level of consciousness
>> is there any connection between this
work and Dr. from Mirto's work where he
actually showed Hitler and Mother
Teresa.
>> I don't even know who he is.
>> I don't like
>> someone else's work. I don't know.
>> I don't know. Somebody else's work. I
don't read anybody else's work.
>> I guess that's my advantage.
>> Why did Teresa calibrate over 700?
I had a question about uh what we
perceive of as as pain and how it relate
to uh various treatment modalities that
are
>> pain
>> what we perceive of as pain. Oh,
>> and
>> uh in various treatment modalities you
like apply kinesiology look for for
causes right um
>> now you're talking about causes the
whole lecture was about there is no
cause
>> this is where where my question lies
if there if there are no causes does
does healing then just occur
spontaneously as well not as as a result
>> it occurs spontaneously
>> of the treatment itself all right so uh
we didn't talk about healing modalities
today we don't think Um the way to
transcend pain is to let go resisting
it. Let's say experientially about the
surgery twice that I see you. You fall
down and you think you've twisted your
ankle.
What you do is you lay there and you let
go resisting whatever the sensations
are. Don't label them as pain. The
minute you think fractured ankle, you've
already got one. You don't have a
fractured ankle. That's a concept. You
don't have pain. That's a concept
experiential. There's a sensation. You
let go resisting it. As I say, the way
you transcend the immediate present, the
immediate presence seems to arise like a
note of music, reaches a crest and then
fades away. If you anticipate it, you
live in anticipation
and you live in the future. If you're a
person who thinks of the past, you're
always hanging on to the pain of the
past. To be present in the immediate
moment is like one point of mind. As the
situation arises, you surrender it to
God or you surrender it to the infinite,
whatever you want to call it. You you're
willing to let go of it as it arises.
Okay? The sensation arises, you don't
label it as pain. That's a that's a name
in your head. There's no such thing as
pain. That's all of rest internal rest
kajans. You let go. You let go resisting
whatever the experience is. The pain
what you call pain will leave the ankle
and it not becomes sused. When you're
doing it correctly, whatever it is
you're letting go, resisting becomes
your whole aura now is filled with this
sensation. As you keep letting go within
minutes, it fades away. You get up and
you walk away. The person who resists it
says, "Oh, I think I have a fractured
ankle." has a fractured ankle now.
and they'll have to go for treatment.
>> However, it's good for business,
>> right?
>> But there are treatments there that that
will potentiate that that healing of of
the pain
>> treatments.
>> Well, I mean, yeah, that will potentiate
healing of it or must
>> there's there's a holistic system of
techniques, so I can't go into them.
There's probably 100 of them out there.
>> Yeah.
>> You go around this audience, you get 50
60 cards from
you hold in mind that which is uh
desired and you let go of resisting and
you add to that prayer. Then depending
on karmic potentiality, karmic
positionalities, not everything is
within your own province. You
understand?
Uh then uh you surrender to whatever the
consequence is. If that doesn't work,
you take the course of miracles.
I believe the course of miracles works
extremely well if you do the workbook.
I believe in the workbook. The textbook
is about 50 points lower
because it demonizes the ego. So it came
from a different source on either side.
But the workbook calibrates at 600. The
textbook calibrates at 550.
And we already demonstrated this morning
why demonizing the ego and getting
polarized with it doesn't strengthen the
ego.
>> Um I have a question for Dr. Hawkins.
>> Yes.
>> So are you familiar with spiral
dynamics?
>> Only fleetingly too complicated.
Is the red and the blue at six and nine
and
>> Yeah, I just saw thought I saw a little
bit of correlation with the uh
>> There is a correlation. Yes, that book
calibrates about 385.
I think it's an excellent book. It's
just too complicated cuz I'm not that
left brain anymore. I don't know where
my left brain is.
>> I know where the ignition is on the car,
the brake.
>> He doesn't drive much.
>> She drives.
No, it's uh I'm sure uh I know Unity
Church uses it and uh I'm on the
steering committee of Unity Church there
in Unity Village and uh we all got a
copy of it and I studied it and I say
it's just too complicated for me. Uh I
get I think one important thing you get
out of it is about understanding of
memes. Me
>> the partly of course Dawkins is also
good the the selfish meme uh to know
that a meme is like a virus. See, and
this little virus, if it happens to be
true, is great. If it happens to be
false, it can undermine a whole uh
society.
That's why I calibrated the truth of
everything because false memes gain as
much momentum as true ones. And if you
repeat them often enough, that's how
giggles got his power over the German
people. He put out their false memes,
gave them great energy. Everybody
parroted them like idiots. That's why I
don't like political extremists because
they parrot memes. They're not subjected
to scrutiny. Everybody presumes they're
true
in and of itself. They have no value
whatsoever.
>> Thank you.
>> Hello. Uh assuming that the human race
consciousness is rising at this point in
history, I'm just wondering how rapidly
you see it rising, for example, where it
might be in 10 years.
>> Well, I told you that
>> the late 80s went from
190 to 205.
It stayed there for 20 years.
October 14th of last year, it went from
205 207.
the time of the birth of the Buddha it
was at 90. At the time of the birth of
Jesus Christ it was 100.
>> So it seems to me it's on a rising curve
like this.
>> Uh what might the calibration have to be
for all sort of hidden malevolent
agendas to be revealed?
>> What what
>> what what calibration would the human
race have to be at for hidden political
agendas to be revealed to the human
race?
What calibration would it have to be for
political agendas to be revealed to
human
>> that are hidden?
>> Well, we calibrate them all the time.
>> The extremists extremists calibrate
quite low. You go, the farther you go
from the center, the lower the
calibrated levels.
The extreme far right and the extreme
far left are far below integrity. Yeah.
>> What he wants to know is I think is how
are they being exposed at this time? Are
they being exposed?
>> Oh. Uh,
frankly,
nobody's exposing except me
in a book. But
there
no extremist cannot be extremely well.
Why? Because they're purposely
distorting truth for personal gain. What
is the personal gain? Narcissism.
You get to be quoted in the press and
sound real cute and you know with it
in the no cool
>> and degenerate all
>> thank you so much for your work Dr.
Hkins um I have a question about the use
of astrology if we're looking at the
fields I'm new to your work I'm very
familiar with astrology and it seems
perhaps be useful to identify some of
the fields of consciousness at any
particular time. just interested if
you're
>> what's the question Dane Rajar for
example do you know are you familiar
with Dane Roger's work Dra
>> the question is is are there fields of
consciousness that can be identifiable
using the tool of astrology
>> I don't know anything about astrology
>> well thank you one more question
>> people say you know see I can take a a
sky full of dots dots.
>> Mhm.
>> I can connect the dots and I have a cat.
That's the sign of the cat.
>> I can make a door.
I can make five star. I can connect
these points to get a circle. This is
the sign of the moon. So, all I see is
the projection. I told you the fish fly
out of the sea. This fish is not causing
this fish to fly out of the sea.
>> Oh, I'm not talking about that type of
astrology though.
>> This fish flies out of the sea. This
fish flies out of the sea. This fish
flies out of the sea. The observer says,
"Look, they're triangulating."
>> Right. Right. No, I understand that. But
um well, the idea
>> I don't want to hear about astrology
today.
>> All right. Thank you very much for your
work on this.
>> I don't lecture on astrology.
>> Um I would like to know if if a person
calibrates at 200, can they go from a
from 200 to a,000 or is that a karmic
setting that you can stay at 200 for
this life?
She must know someone who jumped from
200 to a thousand
>> you're asking me the hypothetical. I'll
tell you there is no answer to the
hypothetical
because the hypothetical has no reality.
>> Okay. So is it karmically saying that
you're to stay at 2,00 or 200 for like
this life?
>> No. Or can you like
>> she's asking can you change
during your life?
>> We've already said you can change your
consciousness level.
>> The whole purpose of the lecture is to
show to show you how to advance your
level of consciousness. Then it depends
on karmic propensities
and integrity and intention
>> you change your level.
>> One pointedness of mind if you persist
in any if you take any integrity
spiritual technique let's say
forgiveness
surrendering things to God. Whatever it
might be, you take the third step in the
12step program.
You can take any one tool. That's all
you need. Then the important thing is to
do that always, all the time, no matter
what.
The reason people don't make progress is
they do it for 5 minutes here. Month
later they do it for an all day seminar
there. 3 weeks later they remember to do
it for 15 minutes.
That won't get you there. It has to be
the way you are in the world. See, your
life becomes like a mudra positionalized
in a certain way. If your
avenue is one of surrender and
forgiveness, then it's continuous always
in all circumstances, no matter what.
That'll get you all the way to the end
because
out of the depths of hell then
everything has to be surrendered to God.
And then came the presence as the
absolute totality of all that exists.
Then out of silence because the mind was
silent came the knowingness that life
itself must be surrendered to God. That
which is experienced as the essence and
the source of this life.
This m must be laid before God also.
It's a nonverbal knowance. There was
nothing left to surrender to God except
life.
At that point,
the surrendering life to God started.
Then came terror.
Then came the agony of death because it
was death. In fact, the only death that
is possible throughout all of time. It's
only possible to die once.
This was death and one felt the agony of
death. Then out of nowhere came the
knowingness.
All fear is illusion. Walk straight
ahead. No matter what.
No matter what. The absoluteness of that
knowingness then came out of the
frequency, the energy field and the
vibration of the guru, the teacher from
which I got it. Walk straight ahead no
matter what. The terror rose absolute
terror in the face of actual death
and the surrender continued and then
ecstatic forever.
Thank you.
>> Hi, Dr. Watkins. Thank you very much for
coming to Toronto, especially
uh in a very difficult time for Toronto.
Will be election on Monday.
>> Hopefully Monday.
>> Oh, good for you. Election day. That's
fine.
>> The person I have a question. The person
with whom you do the calibration depends
on gender and the level of stress.
>> She ask does it depend on gender?
>> Gender level of stress in the moment
when you do the calibration.
>> He does it to me when I'm cooking
dinner.
The reason I'm asking this question,
The reason I'm asking this question is
>> earlier on a presentation you says um
men calibrate high
because of or Jesus Buddha calibrates
high because they were men.
>> No, no, I didn't say that. People ask
how come
>> people ask how come no avatars are
women. They think it's sexist.
>> It's because they project sexism.
>> You say something about the difference
of nervous system.
>> Yes, there is a difference in the
nervous system and woman.
>> The nervous system has to be very heavy.
>> Are you going to keep talking or are you
asking question?
>> Yeah. What is the question? Can you
elaborate what would be the difference
between men brain and women brain?
>> I said didn't say anything about brain.
I said nervous system.
>> Nervous system.
>> I said nervous system.
>> Yes.
>> You understand?
>> In the days see I I grew up when I grew
up 50% of the country was rural
agricultural.
Therefore, men with their heavier frame,
heavier muscles and testosterone did the
field work.
Women worked just as hard and just as
valuably doing the inside work. Men were
not better than women. Women were not
better than they just did what they were
suitable for. A guy cannot be out there
fixing the tractor
in 120°ree weather with a sweep running
all off of him.
You see? and also looking after three
children. So, I mean, you know, one's
not better than the other. See, it's
just one is suitable for certain things.
You don't see me running in the
Olympics. See, I'm not equipped. So,
karmically, I'm not equipped to run in
the Olympics. I would bet some more.
If I was slated to become an avatar,
I would have probably special help from
the celestial realm.
And in knowing this how to increase the
capacity of the central nervous system
because as the energy field goes over
during the condolini flow it's
exquisite. That's the 500s. Yes. And
600s is bliss and 700 is great. But you
go beyond that and all of a sudden you
start experiencing excruciating pains.
If you hold the slightest negativity, if
you hold the slightest passing
negativity, it's like agony. You have to
search within the collective unconscious
to see in what chakra of which archetype
something is being held that is contrary
to the absolute truth.
>> And in those evolutionary periods, I'll
tell you,
>> it was the spiritual night that gave me
the hardest time.
Thank you.
>> The spiritual knight
devoted to truth and wanted to kill for
truth. Son of a gun. Remember that guy?
>> Dr. Hawkins, can you supplement your
previous advice to that we could improve
our lives uh by through contemplation?
Can you expand on that a little bit?
>> Contemplation is a way of being in the
world. It's a way of positioning
yourself easily,
experiencing
see oneself as the field instead of the
subject of the field. to see oneself
more detached than personally. You might
say
some people when they walk into a room
are instantly fiddling with all the
details. Other people get what is the
overall ambiance of that room. Okay. A
good decorator tries to create a certain
feel. When you walk into that room, you
get a certain feel. He's looking at the
feel. Then the details get arranged
according to the context.
Other people do it the other way. Isn't
this a cute doily? Isn't this a cute
frog? Isn't this something?
See, so it's a different way of coming
about what it is you're trying to
create.
So being more contemplative
uh means more aware of
I suggest that one's life becomes a
prayer. Your life becomes like a mudra.
Mudra as a sacred position of the hands.
Your life becomes thus.
>> Your the way you position your existence
visa be God is thusly.
The universe responds and with answers
because you're standing there
surrendering to God and open to God as a
as your way of being in the world,
not as a verbal manipulation.
Everybody's trying to verbally
manipulate God. Oh God, please I need a
red Cadillac because the blue one's
diamond
that much power. If you come from the
stewardship of that which you are,
the totality of that which you've become
and you give it to God as a tool. It's
like the 11th step in 12step program
where you ask for God's will for you.
That is a way of being in the world.
Supplication, openness
and attracts, it attracts
you might say higher beings. It attracts
the celestial realm to like
hold for you that which then becomes
your knowingness.
Oh, I can see what I really need to be
doing. That doesn't come out of thought
or specifics or form. That comes out of
finessing it out of the field.
So like the prayer from mudra finess out
of the field that which you're seeking.
>> Does that answer you?
>> Very well. Thank you very much.
>> Hi. Wonder if you can help me resolve
paradox. Um, I taught myself how to do
kinesiology testing and using that and
with some other help, I went from 250 to
539.
What I can't tell is if I'm being
spoofed or if I'm spoofing myself
because the problem is is that as I
progress, I've received an awful lot of
what I believe described as elimination.
Things that are completely out of any
context I've ever had. Yet, the test is
true.
I don't know. I never say anything about
myself. So, I can tell you.
>> Well, this isn't always about myself.
This is actually part of this is about
you because I touch that I'm supposed to
give away always in the forest.
>> I don't know what it is you're
calibrating.
>> Um, well, I just I what I was trying to
do is I was trying to drive my
consciousness using statistical process
control. In other words, how do I push
my consciousness?
>> I don't I wouldn't push it.
Well, my wife is ill.
>> Let's say becoming more love
>> is totally different than trying to push
your consciousness.
>> Well, I'm in as far as the ruthless
examination of the self. That's what I
question.
You're missing what spiritual work is
all about.
Spiritual work has got nothing to do
with galler consciousness.
Rich work is becoming unconditionally
loving, unconditionally forgiving,
seeing sacredness of all of life. If you
do that, you won't worry about
calibrations because you realize that
you are that
>> sounds like I have a challenge with
spiritual life
>> you just described earlier.
>> Yeah, you don't have to rate yourself.
>> Okay, let worry about that.
>> You be as loving as you can. as you try
to be as long as you can, you'll find
yourself automatically being being
judgmental. You know what I'm saying?
And then you ask God to let you see that
differently. Therefore, that's the value
of the course of miracles. The value of
the course of miracles is that you're
acknowledging the humility and the
limitation of your capacity to know.
You're asking God, "This looks to me
like so and so, and I asked the Holy
Spirit to recontextualize it." The
miracle is merely asking God to
recontextualize it.
>> I asked the Holy Spirit to
recontextualize it so I can see it in
truth. When you see in the truth, you
see there's nothing to forgive.
But uh because
perception takes it out of the karmic uh
context of the past etc. So it looks
awful in the present, but then you say,
"Well, I I you see that one thing comes
out of another."
You say, "My problem is I'm angry all
the time." You think your problem is
anger? Your problem is not anger.
Your your problem is what is the source
of the anger? Oh, and you look at the
source of the anger. Why am I angry all
the time? And you discover it's egotism
and pride. Oh, I'm so puffed up with
egotism and pride and the need for
everybody to see me as perfect and
wonderful. If anybody says anything less
than that, I'm angry. So, you see, your
problem is not anger. It's frag, right?
Then you ask, well, where does the pride
come from?
So, you see, as you begin to deconstruct
the ego, you only have to be truthful
about one brick. Once you pull out this
one brick, the next brick falls and the
next brick falls. You see, you're angry
because you're jealous because you feel
inadequate because so you start
unraveling. So it's like pulling the
yarn on a sweater.
Crumb is not anger. Your problem is
egotism.
>> Egotism.
What is the basis of the egotism?
Because I'm always rating myself.
You project that onto God, God's going
to rate you too. And you're worried
about. So you can see how one thing
leads into another. So that's sort of
how spiritual work evolved you know that
um
the awareness of one defect and the
surrender of it then pulls up the source
of that defect of character and you just
keep evolving like that from instant to
instant.
The trick is to spiritual work. You want
to know how do you make rapid spiritual
progress? You find one simple spiritual
tool and do it all the time. No matter
what,
even faced with certain death.
Even faced with absolute death.
>> I appreciate that. I had a sense that I
had fallen into some trap. So, thank you
very Take a simple tool forgiveness
to see the sacredness of all of life.
Be loving towards all of life.
When you see the beauty and the
sacredness of all of life, it sort of
knocks you out for a while.
You start to walk by a weed and you see,
my god, you see the incredible
look at a weed.
>> That's that's happening.
>> All you have to do is look at a weed.
You see
>> it's incredible. Magnificent. The
magnificent perfection of the sculpture.
Incredible. Just knocked you out. Can't
go to work today.
I didn't get quite that far.
What happened? Keep going. You're
laughing at your day with him. You say,
"I don't think I can go to work today,
God."
>> Actually, I haven't worked in two years.
>> No, I think the curse of miracles two
years.
>> All right. Good.
>> You got the You got it. You got it.
Big gut worried about the calibration.
Got nothing else to do.
>> Just be
>> even prior to being and uh which being
>> could you please explain uh your vision
of suicide?
>> Of what?
>> Suicide.
>> What about it?
>> Your vision of suicide.
>> I haven't really studied it. I remember
that the lady who wrote the famous book
on death and dying,
the German psychiatrist I think it was.
>> Anyway, I I can remember she did some
research on that. She found that the
people who committed suicide ended up in
as good a places as other people.
We're talking so many times in
Christianity and everything that you
spoke today about dying in yourself even
physically. So that means something
similar like that
>> or surrendering
totally
>> talking about the ego not
>> that but coming close to total
surrendering and sometimes does get
confusing
>> or just being tired of trying so many
things and methods.
>> She's like ego physical body.
>> They're two different things all
together. Physical dying is nothing at
all.
The world carries on about it, makes a
big deal out of it. It's disgusting.
A body you get and the whole world is
moaning and caring on and there you are
perfectly alive. Why they still
be so dumb?
It's cuz they love to whale and make a
big deal out of something.
>> Anybody here any experience?
Anybody here go out of body?
>> Yeah. No big deal, right?
>> Well, you got to tell the truth.
>> One minute you're here, one minute
you're there. So going out of body is
one thing. Near-death experience is
another.
But you see instantly
one time when I was young, I went to the
to learn how to go astrojected will.
happened spontaneously
>> and then I learned, oh, you could learn
to do that. Well, some people do it all
the time. Susie goes out of body once.
Anyway, I heard there was a way you
could learn it. So, I went there. Sure
enough, went out of body. In fact, I
went back in the body one time upside
down.
I went into the body. I docked that way.
I'm looking out the back of my soul at
the floor back.
That's the fact I'm actually looking at
the back of my skull at the door.
If I'm in my body this way, how can I be
looking at the floor? So, I had to come
out this way.
I was at the mineral institute.
But anyway, if someone finds too much
energy willing to do something great and
improve life and things don't turn that
way
and decide I mean usually people say
suicide comes from people who are with
low level of energy. I I heard so many
people who were very high
through their life proving themsel in
many levels creativity and love and
everything and after all they couldn't
continue
>> well I don't understand the question
people make long story ask the question
what is the question is suicide
>> how do people at high levels end up
committing suicide
What? What people at high levels?
>> I don't know.
>> People at high levels commit suicide.
>> How do you know they're high levels?
>> You mean high levels in society? Rich
people? What do you mean?
>> Did you calibrate them to know that they
were high level?
>> What do you mean by
>> people with a lot of capacity
capacity? a lot of, you know, artistic
ability that
>> Oh, yeah. Well, they're not related.
>> You can be bipolar and the genius of a
architect and then go into bipolar
depression and commit suicide.
>> Sus is bipolar plus drugs.
Put the two together. You could take
your lithium, you go into depression,
you get into meth and you drive your
motorcycle into the wall.
It's called psychosis
psychosis or psychotic severe
depression.
>> Can I ask two questions?
>> If you want to
>> I tell you my understanding is you I I
said that you know at the moment you
come into the world
you already have a calibrate level
consciousness. You also have an expected
date of departure. Now, if you commit
suicide,
I'm just guessing. Uh, you'll have to go
on the other side and you can't leave
that till you're completely dead. Just
Okay.
>> Okay.
>> Um, you mentioned that potentiality
becomes actuality and then that
actuality is the potentiality for the
next actuality. What's the difference
between that and cause and effect
and and karma? Where does karma fade?
You see
cause and effect are mentations.
You have to first get that.
You understand that they're mentions.
You know what's the dance of Shiva?
>> You know the dance of Shiva?
>> No. The whole
>> the whole
>> So the answer is that
is this construction or is this
destruction?
It's neither one. If I desire it, it's
constructive. If I do not desire it,
it's destructive.
In and of itself, rest external
is what it is. Neither constructive nor
destructive. Now ask the question again.
Okay. The question was uh potentiality
becomes actuality and that actuality is
the potentiality for the next actuality.
>> Yes.
>> So what's the difference between that
and cause and effect?
>> Because the word potentiality
manifesting as actuality is different
than causality.
See causality imputes an external source
as a doer.
Therefore,
the implication for spirituality is so
long as you believe in duality, so long
as you think there's a cause
and an effect, you will then presume
that there's an individual separate eye
separate from the one. Therefore, this
arm is flashing out here because there's
a separate eye that makes it. As you
see, there is no separate eye. It
happens spontaneously as a consequence
of the potentiality of the field.
You know, I caused it to do that. I saw
it at the same time you did. Come back
here.
>> So, so where this car thing
>> potentiality would be you have to you
understand shell.
You know Sheldrake?
>> No.
>> I would study Sheldrake
>> because Sheldrake
puts it forth in a way that would make
sense to you. Within the field of
consciousness, there's the field called
morphic, you know, morphic.
>> That's what
>> anyway morphic resonance.
If you study evolution, if you look at
if you watch deep sea photography, you
know, deep sea photography like on
History Channel, Discovery Channel, I
don't know what it is in Canada, but
anyway, there's incredibly beautiful
photography in great depth. There you
see the magnificence and incredible
beauty of these creatures. Here's this
thing. It floats like a gom or a thread
and it's sparkling with its own
selfcreated electricity. And it's got
this magical phosphorescent
radiance. It goes like this. It changes
form
and it becomes that form becomes that
form and then it slinks and pretends
it's starts to eat up that and pulls
back and then that which it wasn't no
longer was. Is that
incredible
to witnessing?
The aesthetics is incredible. But when
you get the essence of what's going on,
you see the genius of divinity. Yeah.
Expressing itself
in the form of creation.
Even to watch an octopus, it's
magnificent genius.
THAT'S GREAT.
FREEDOM THE freedom of creation
>> and the infinite potentiality. You see
the divinity of the creatures below the
sea.
>> So what does
>> you can't find god get deep sea
photography
videos you watch them for a couple of
months and do nothing else.
I'm just going to be karma figures in
that karma.
>> How karma figures
>> karma.
>> Okay.
>> The second question was if if I'm
>> karma is only a word.
Okay.
>> The evolution of a thing
>> karma could be positioned in time,
>> right?
>> That the karmic propensity to this is
this. The karmic propensity to this is
this karmic propensity. But this will
only happen
within a context that would allow it and
bring it to a fulfillment.
Otherwise, there would be no
possibility.
Great. Thank you. That's good. Uh the
second question is Oh, that was enough.
>> Yeah.
>> Next.
>> We're running out of time. That's why we
only we can only stick to one question,
please, because we're running out of
time.
>> Would you
>> would you explain how those living in a
state of group karma don't have
individual karma?
>> Explain it. If they belong 200,
>> why don't they have individual crime?
>> I don't know. I thought
>> because I can ask you. You see
below 200 is behaving and being an
animal. As I said, the animal evolves
over millennia of time. Then you get a
prefrontal cortex plastered on, but
you're still an animal.
You hate, you greed, you kill, you
murder.
You're just an animal.
Now you're a thinking animal. Okay. So
that means you're a smart animal, but
you're still basically an animal.
>> The mind has only become a tool of the
animal.
Yeah.
Now the animal has grew consciousness.
All animals are really one animal.
Native native
Native Americans knew that.
The natives know that the spirit of the
tiger rules the jungle.
Is that imaginary? No. There is an
attractive field of tigerness
and every tiger is a manifestation of
that attractive field.
I first noticed that the orange all
orange kitties are the same.
They have different names, different
slight memories of this lifetime. But
then in essence, every orange kitty is
the same as every other orange kitty.
Okay, let me have your arms. There's
only one orange kitty in reality.
>> I'm moving along. Thank you.
There's only one orange kitty.
that orange kitty manifest as millions
of physicalities of orange kittiness.
But there's really only one one way of
being one way of experiencing
contextualizing subjectively
experiencing life that is possible for
orange skitties. But there's really only
one orange skitty.
They don't need an individual
consciousness. What would they need it
for? Because karmic mirror is
consequence of having an individual
consciousness.
The group then evolves. So
Within the visible domain, you see no
evolution. There is no connecting
species at all. There's Neanderthal man
at 75. There's homo rectus at 85. Let's
say
I forget all people right now.
Neanderthal man at 75.
Hidleberg man. You see, but one does not
become the other. Neanderthal man comes
off at 75. that he disappears. He
doesn't evolve. You don't find halfway
between Neanderthal and Homois. He
disappears. Then Homo rectus comes out.
They may be concordant time wise
overlap, but there's no connected links.
You don't see something that's half
zebra, half horse. It comes out zebra
horse comes out giraffe. You don't see
giraffes with, you know, sort of long
necks and then longer necks and then
longer necks. No,
there is no connection. So where does
evolution take place?
Children's formative causation is the
explanation.
The intelligence. So the attractor field
is aware of all the experience of all
the orange kitties. It's the compository
of all knowingness of all orange
kittiness.
Intelligence knows this. Intelligence
puts together the experience of the
individuals and has a collective
uh information bank.
How does intelligence understand how to
make electricity?
A billion years ago at the bottom of the
sea were phosphorus and going things
that could create electricity.
Ancient Greece they used to give shock
treatment. people that are depressed.
Electric eels give you a real kick
on the electric eel. Learn how to make
electricity.
All right. So, intelligence is intrinsic
to creation.
The most impressive thing to me about
creation
is the incredible aesthetics.
The incredible you ever look at a tiger
aesthetics are just incredible.
Beyond the
you look at the face of any animal, the
aesthetics are just a knockoff, you
know. Plus the brilliance with which how
does this fish get to make electricity
and and hold a lure up here at the same
time? I mean, you know, you'd have to
have an IQ of, you know, sizable amount
as a as a human to figure out how you
going to create electricity, you know, a
couple thousand feet down at that
temperature.
creates survival and matingness and all
out of this and then it also knows when
when to turn its light off when it's
safe to turn it on when it's safe to I
mean the brilliance the intelligence
if you just watch uh nature films all
the time you'll discover the nature of
God
>> yes
>> yes um my mathematics is not so However,
I look around and I see just about 20%
of the crowd here are men. Why aren't
they here? um worldwide I observe that
women are stepping out more and uh I'm
just wondering um if something
magnanimous is about to happen to be
manifested through women because women
are co-creators
and um without um being blasphemous
Jesus came via a woman
and all the great thinkers have come via
a woman so I'm just wondering that all
these great thinkers, where did this
wisdom come from?
>> Great thinkers.
>> Yeah.
>> And women,
>> where did the wisdom come from? Jesus
came of a woman. He had no father
>> as we know it.
>> I don't know. It's a pretty convoluted
question. I don't know what you're
asking.
>> I'm just saying here it's only about 20%
of men are here. Is it because they are
more involved involved that they think
they don't have to be here
>> or is it some party?
>> Some of us are dressed as women,
right?
>> I don't know. Dermographics of
spirituality. I couldn't
>> that's an independent study. I've never
studied demographics.
Thank you.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah, that's the demographics. I don't
know. It's probably it's probably as
>> going on the cover of GQ magazine.
Uh,
>> would you write this to Elizabeth? No,
not here.
>> I can't write that. I got my signature.
That's it. You want me to write a story?
You got to hire somebody.
>> He signed Elizabeth. Okay.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Go ahead.
>> Good afternoon, Dr. Hawkins. in um
the September election in 2002 on the
way to God through the heart. You at one
point commented and calibrated that uh
you can't evolve out of the astral.
>> You can evolve what from the astral from
the astral plane.
I didn't say that.
>> Well, I think you did.
>> Okay. What What is the question?
>> Astral plane. You you were talking about
don't go near the astral because
>> Oh, avoid the astral.
>> Avoid the astral.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> And you calibrated with Susan the um
that you can't evolve from the astral
plane. And yet on the other hand, you
said that
>> within the astral plane. No,
>> you can't evolve in the within it.
>> Ah, that's what I thought. But you can
leave.
>> Yeah. If you're interested in spiritual
advancement, you don't want to become
hooked into the astral realm. That's why
I tell people, you know, not to go for
psychic readings and stuff like that
because you can get iguled into the
astral domain and its purpose is to
control you. Control over you.
>> Thank you. That's doesn't tell you how
to become lucrative.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah. Okay.
Good.
>> Okay. Um you spoke about countries and
how the leader could calibrate very high
>> about in countries you could have a
leader who calibrated very high.
>> Well in the country I said yes you have
to understand the leader you have to
understand the government you have to
understand the people. Yeah. What I was
wondering is if this couldn't be true of
an organization and is true organization
>> and uh why wouldn't if let's say the the
mass of the organization the employees
were mostly integrous and the leader was
why wouldn't the management be don't
they raise it up the positive is
stronger than the negative
>> no they could be different you know
yesterday's uh Toronto paper had a very
excellent in the business section all
about what you're just asking
Yeah,
>> Anthony's business section of the
Toronto Globe something had quite a good
coverage of um
how CEOs set up the next one to be
failures by setting a field and the
field is inable to their survival etc.
It was quite an ariodite discussion of
uh integrity and business ethics and
blame in business.
I thought it was a very interesting
paper
place of be a bl business
and integrity
management styles
I thought I think it was yesterday's
paper pretty good I think one with a dog
on the front had a pretty good excellent
uh section on business I thought pretty
>> um by the way is this going to be
available by tape or by video this
lecture.
>> No.
>> No. Okay. Um
>> it's just archival.
>> Okay. Um
when we have our individual
consciousness, obviously we have to make
choices and so on. There's some sort of
a summary of like what's really
important to consider for making
choices, important choices especially
in order to advance spiritually and so
on so forth.
What's the value of calibrating the
level of consciousness of many things in
the world?
Jesus said to avoid anything makes you
go weak with with ideology.
>> That's it.
>> Thank you.
>> He said to avoid sin. He says don't
don't become positionalized against sin.
Just don't go there.
Avoid it. Withdraw from it.
>> Evil. Evil. Um, this is about sex,
specifically orgasms. Is that or can it
be or is it a spiritual experience or is
that what my ego wants?
>> Oh, I never asked it. I know sexuality
calibrates at 250. Hooray.
Food calibrates at 200.
>> Less food calibrates about 215.
>> Sex calibrates at 250. I work.
>> The big I never checked it out.
>> It feels like a thousand.
It wasn't the big O. None of us to be
here. Folks,
our love all our life to the big O.
>> You're going to do it in
You're going to do it in chest tubes.
Ups down.
Yes.
>> How does one make a statement in
chinesiology and be sure that the answer
is not being influenced?
>> That's a good question. How does one
make a statement in chiology and make
sure that the their answer isn't being
infin
>> I don't know
>> how do I know that it's not my
>> two people have to calibrate over 200
their intention has to be over 200
there's also ways if this is true that
many other things would be true so
there's ways of cross crossoraborating
that we've come up with very extremely
important things frankly
um and Yes, we did a lot of cross
cooperation.
>> Thank you.
>> Just to make sure that we were
calibrated correctly.
>> Thank you so much.
>> We got some things that are planned on
the planet now. We check every day to
see if that's going to be if that's the
same now or not.
>> Monitor them.
>> Dr. Dr. Hawkins, I would like uh I guess
clarification on my understanding of
your calibrated scale of consciousness.
It's a logarithmic scale to the base 10,
which from what I recall means every
point um of difference would be an order
of magnitude.
Um so
that would mean today's lecture stated
that um the level of of consciousness
was 12 points. The audience.
>> The audience those 12 points which to my
understanding of it then would mean 12
or one with 12 zeros after it or one
trillion times greater than before. Is
that
>> I don't understand bought by the facts.
That's where I'm at.
We would divide up into three teams and
then this team would research this
project this
and then after half an hour an hour we'd
all meet together and discuss what we we
discovered and then we would do it
together as a group. See you know you
could take a project is there human life
on other planets.
What percentage of planets in the
universe contains human life on
equivalent level to what we are? See,
you can find all kinds of fantastic
sources of study.
You may not always like what you find
out.
>> Interesting. Uh the last question is
very quickly. Um I was really amazed by
what uh your story on how meditation
increased possibly increased the 2% um
in the entire world. And my question to
you is um would you lead us in perhaps a
meditation today to try to do a little
bit of that as well?
>> No.
>> Here's what I want you to do for the
world.
See the sacredness of your own
existence.
Share that sacredness with everyone.
see the sacredness in them.
Be that to the world to the fullest
extent that you can because that
radiates out into the world. You see,
because as you recognize the sacredness
of yourself and the sacredness of life,
they recognize the sacredness of life in
them. The next person they look at, they
recognize the sacredness of life.
Reverence for the sacredness of life
then is the way to be in the world. So
that your life itself is a meditation.
Otherwise people go off here meditate
cross-legged play music do the incense
and the all that stuff and the flowers.
So why
you have to be be that which you are to
the fullest extent. So your gift to the
world is to be
to the fullest extent that which you
are.
That's a class act.
What's a class act? What's class?
Class is being what you are to the
fullest extent that you can be that
satchel.
Satchel calibrates the word 500
just unconditional love just being
totally that which he is. And you see
how that blesses the world and radiates
out to the world. So that's what we can
do for the world. I think people who
like to do formal meditation and such uh
is fine.
I don't I don't think that it lives. I
don't think I don't think it like like
lives. Okay.
As I say to the dormant,
thank you. He goes, "Thank you."
Yeah.
I validated to him the worth of his own
experience. It happens in every airport.
these kids from some country or other
really around them. And then you turn to
them, you say, "Wow, that really made a
difference in my life." They go, "Boom."
And the $5 on top of it just means that
what you said is the truth. Put my money
where my mouth is, too.
You see, what you do is you're
constantly validating people's value to
themselves by that which you are. So you
become the reflection back to the world
of the truth of that which it is. And
that's the way to meditate.
>> Yeah.
>> To me because it spreads. That's the way
to meditate. Okay.
>> You're not meditating for yourself.
You're meditating out of the joy of
sharing truth that which you are. Huh.
>> Okay.
>> So time's almost there.
>> Our time's up.
>> Oh no. Wait. Can't see you. Four more
people.
>> Okay. We'll finish you off. Huh?
>> 5 minutes.
>> Okay, we have 5 minutes. My clock's 5
minutes.
>> Okay, go ahead.
>> Mine's a little slow.
>> In the countries that calibrate
generally below 200, if people from
whether it's North America or others
that are above individuals who are above
200 go to those places, is there like
especially for a length of time,
could there be a drop in their own uh
level of consciousness? I'm thinking
specifically of Iraq, the American
soldiers going over there and the um
problems that happened say for example
in the prison. Now the soldiers that
that did that would that be something
that they never would have done if they
were
say in in a country above 200? A long
question.
>> All right. Iraq is the lunch saying if
you go and visit there or
>> would you go be hello to No.
>> As as the the soldiers who went over.
>> No.
>> No. You become you say the same. You say
that which you are.
>> It would be a circumstance like any
other circumstance. Nothing special.
because you could be tempted to drop in
consciousness more by let's say a chance
to uh short trade your company stock
than uh Iraq. So in other words,
temptation is always around.
The interesting thing about the
military, we didn't have time today to
do the the various wars, is that very
often the military is more integrous
than either the country or the leader.
very often that the military people are
terrorists and it's the leaders that
sell them out. We saw that in World War
II. We saw Hitler allow whole armies to
be slaughtered rather than surrender
some non-integrous leaders but integrous
military.
Non integrity is more likely to be at
the top than at the bottom.
You find the military, they're usually
clean kids who will die for their
country and will follow on a big orders
right to death. What do you want of them
human being?
And would the leaders be willing to do
that? I doubt it.
And you got to catch them and you got to
put them on trial.
No, you won't find any real military
guys there.
I never met any in service.
Every guy on that ship would have died
for everybody else on that ship.
We all would have died for each other.
Funny, after the world was over, after
the war was over,
cuz my age, I'm talking about World War
II. Other people think
about what other words after World War
II. So, I was on a mind sweeper and you
know, we were on hazardous duty. So, we
didn't get blown up when we came back.
So anyway, 50 years later, I never heard
from another guy on the ship. There's
only 18 of us. Average age probably
about 19.
CEO was executive officer was 22.
Anyway, there we are. Asia, etc. Yeah.
50 years later, I never heard from these
guys. 50 years later, the phone rings
and the guy says, "Is this shorty?"
I started to cry. I recognize the voice.
>> So, four or five of us discovered each
other. Each one that would call the
other one, everybody would break up and
cry.
I said, "This is ridiculous." He said,
"I haven't talked in 50 years and I'm
crying." He says, "It happens with every
one of us. Every one of us
in
you see the heart of warrior
is love of a level at 510.
The leaders weren't 510.
But the heart of the men to each other
was over 500. 505
510 is the allegiance of one warrior to
his brother for whom he's willing to
die.
That integrity takes him right over 200.
See, so you come out of a low karmic
background. Now this like you're a
warrior
and it's your karmic opportunity to
shoot over 200. Huh? You either become a
coward or you die for your brothers. So
you see illusion and perception are two
different things.
At 510 you see the commitment
the willingness to give up like itself
for love of your brother.
So you can decry war but it's the karmic
opportunity for millions to cross over
the threshold from below 200 to above.
So illusion and essence are two
different things you know
there's a commitment that transcends all
time
and on the other side the warriors meet
each other. You see in this lifetime the
second war is over
the former enemies are embracing each
other. See that warriors each one
salutes the other one. The minute the
arms is assigned they're not buddies.
They celebrate each other's holidays.
The Japanese and the Americans kamicazi
pilots and the American pilots celebrate
together. You see them understand that
that's forgiveness. You know that's the
level of the heart. So what looks like
negativity can be the road to salvation
because the capacity to forgive the
kamakazi crowd who was out to shoot you
down. The minute the war is over respect
his integrity and his honor.
I'm trying to take
some of the murder off war and show you
what it is. rotten and horrible.
Also magnificent.
Hello. Um, is the field of potentiality
itself the divine? And if so, is there
such a thing as evil? Can it be
manifested out of the divine?
some of those types of questions.
>> Repeat it one more time.
>> Is the field of potentiality the divine?
I guess to be
>> I don't know what the question means.
>> Is where we emanate from God itself is
that potentiality is that God itself
>> is that what itself? God itself
where we in where we in
where we come from is that God itself.
>> It's not a proper question that could be
answered.
>> Just ask a question. Don't try and put
uh all the flowery words in. Just ask a
question.
are is everything that we witness in
this world is it created by us or is it
all created from God from the divine
he's asking about form what you're
witnessing is form the infinite
potentiality divinity you feel the
consciousness itself not is nonlinear
it's beyond form it has the potential it
is present and it is present within form
But it does not form itself.
The unmanifest obviously has the
potentiality to become manifest.
Correct. As existence.
Then how does it arrive in form?
What gives it form?
>> I don't know. Were you standing there?
>> Your own consciousness, your own
thinkingness,
>> our own my own witness.
>> What gave your voice the question? You
did. Yeah. So the potentiality to speak
then you decided by your own intention
what to speak. Yeah. Simple.
Thank you.
>> Yes.
Without meaning any disrespect, um Dr.
Hawkins, are you open to the possibility
that in some of your concepts you might
be not um stating the things as
accurate?
>> What you saying?
>> I
say what?
>> I can't hear what you're saying.
>> What?
>> Are you a humble person?
>> Are you a humble person? No,
>> just one quick another question.
>> I'm not a person at all.
>> Have you ever calibrated crop circles?
>> Crop?
>> Crop circles?
>> No.
>> They're human in origin.
>> A
crop circle.
>> Hello.
I'm just wondering if you're familiar
with Rubert Shelvik's recent research on
the sense of being stared at and if you
have any comments.
>> The what now?
>> The sense of being stared at.
>> The sense of being stared at
>> children's new.
>> What about children?
>> It's a new research that he's doing on
the sense of being stared at.
>> Have you?
>> I'm not familiar with that film.
>> I'm sorry. We haven't
>> Yeah. No, his original stuff back in 81,
you know, was very good. When you
calcate
>> wondering, um, will humanity achieve
world peace in the next 50 years?
>> Future,
>> will we achieve world peace in the next
50 years?
>> Unlikely.
You can you celebrate that?
>> You're talking about the hypothetical. I
told you there's no answer to the
hypothetical.
If you look at the history of mankind,
in the history of civilization, peace
has prevailed 7% of the time. War has
prevailed 93% of the time. Now you ask
me to predict what is the likelihood of
peace in the near future. You're a dumb
question.
To be what we are to the fullest
capacity to be that is doing more for
world peace than anything else on the
planet.
To be the ultimate capacity of your own
potentiality
that is being a Christ to the world.
Understand
there's nothing you have to read in a
book by the Christ. I mean that level of
perfection of consciousness not the
person up historic figure that
potentiality within yourself
to fulfill that that is what's what
you're doing for a world peace you know
for which we all thank you.
Heat.