So you see, the oneness of the evolution then, up through the animal kingdom, up through
the levels of the 200s, up through that which doesn't have within it enough energy, it has
to go out and eat others because it lacks energy, not because it's wicked or because
it's bad, because it doesn't have within itself.
Therefore, as we sacrifice our personal lives for the welfare of others, as we in this room
do so for the sake of the world, then by that intention do we sanctify the world, sanctify
human life.
It's by our intention that human life becomes sanctified, all that's personified in the
life of Jesus Christ.
The message radiates out 2,000 years later.
So as we support that energy now, then we are serving life right this moment, right
this moment.
We are, all of us, collectively serving the welfare of all of human life.
Huh?
Let us see if that's a fact.
That's a fact, O Lord Jesus, that's a fact.
You don't have to ask, what can I do, do me a favor, don't do anything.
Stop doing things, please.
Just be the fulfillment of the potentiality.
This is the fulfillment of the potentiality which you have karmically inherited, or you
would never be in a room like this, because a room like this is full of people destined
for enlightenment.
Everyone that is in this room is destined for enlightenment.
That's a fact, O Lord.
Resist.
It is a fact, O Lord.
Otherwise, why else would you be here?
Why else would you be here, if this was...
Hey.
People destined to become tennis players are at a class on tennis this afternoon.
People destined to become enlightened are in a class on being enlightened.
What else would you expect?
Everyone here then has to own that within themself that you all innately have elected
by your own free will to be that which upholds all of life in its expression in its humanity
by your very being here.
This very moment we are upholding.
We are a part of that 15% that's upholding the other 85% just by the virtue of our commitment
to truth, to learn about truth, to my sharing with you what I've learned about truth and
what I hope will be useful to the world and in today's world, its application to world
peace and bringing about peace.
How to express that?
That intelligence, how to express that intelligence in our international diplomacy.
So spirituality is just not a Sunday morning thing.
It's a way of being in the world.
It's a way of being in the world that by its sheer intention tends to bring forth truth
and integrity in others because non-integrity when it's confronted by integrity tends to
cringe.
It pulls back from the light.
So just being what you are tends to suppress non-integrity.
Being what you are radiates out an energy field and light.
The collective consciousness of mankind keeps evolving and it's going to continue further.
You saw on that curve how it's going like this and how it's going like that.
Hmm.
Consciousness level of mankind is rapidly moving.
So this group here is in the forefront of that graph.
We're right there where it's at.
This is about as far as consciousness has evolved up to this point which you're hearing today.
Frankly.
Consciousness has evolved any further than this point in a way that can be communicated.
Yeah?
In a way that can be communicated.
Certain information is transformational.
It has within itself a transformational power.
So we share with you information which in and of itself, in and of itself with no effort
on your part.
Please put in no effort at all.
No effort.
To just be with the information is already transformative.
Thereby, your life becomes a prayer.
So you become a blessing to the world by the nature of your own existence.
And so prayerfully, we'll stop for the day for the lecture.
We're going to take a little longer time for questions and answers later.
So we'll take a break, and then we'll do questions and answers
and try to fulfill what is being unanswered in your mind.
I'm very Christian, so I'm very Christian.
Okay, so our collective intention is impacting the world.
I can hear it. It's ringing. It's shaking.
Yeah.
Yes, we're going to do Nico's chant.
And then we're going to have the questions and answers.
Now we have to change microphones.
Those of you who have not been here before are not aware that Nico does the Lotus Sutra.
Chant it in Sanskrit. It's magical. Calibrates over 700.
Nico chanting the Lotus Sutra in Sanskrit is a rare opportunity,
which we've all earned through karmic merit.
Karmic merit.
Karmic merit. Take over.
Mm-hmm.
The last of you want to be?
Okay, we're going to start the questions and answers.
The great people with questions on this side of the room,
the people with just one book signed on that side of the room.
This question I wrote down because I wanted to get it right.
Uh-oh.
Because I've been thinking about it for some time now.
It's a question about karma.
Yeah.
You have written that choice...
That choice supersedes karma, and that at a consciousness level...
It doesn't supersede. It determines it. Yeah, yeah.
Okay. And that at a consciousness level of 600 or higher, you transcend personal karma.
My question is, is it possible, say after going through the course of miracles or something like that,
to choose not to be subject to karma below the level of 600?
What would be choosing?
The ego.
And if the ego persists...
You said it, the karma.
Over 600, it's irrelevant.
Divinity is all that exists, you know?
Okay.
Thank you.
Oh.
As a contribution to the good and welfare...
Uh-oh.
He wants a hug now.
By golly.
Oh.
Thank you.
So, yes.
Oh, dear.
Hmm.
That's funny.
It's funny.
Yeah.
It's just wonderful being here in your presence.
I feel that you've...
There you have to talk.
Right in there.
Is it this one she speaks into?
Yes.
What is this one doing here?
That's the satellite room.
Oh, the satellite room.
Okay.
It's really...
You're really a blessing.
Mm-hmm.
Thank you so much for your presence.
And this was really...
It was really wonderful.
I'm glad you enjoyed it.
I have a question about non-resistance.
We've had...
A friend of mine and I have had some really good luck
following your idea of if you have an acute injury
that you let go of the resistance to the pain
and you say more and more.
And it's been really good.
It works really, really well.
And so what we...
What I'm wanting to ask you is
how do you take that to some chronic type of illness
like ringing of the ears or something like that?
The same thing applies.
You let go resisting it
because that intensifies your focus and concentration on it
which tends to magnify the experience.
You become the field in which it's happening
and let go resisting it.
And what happens is it becomes forgotten.
You can't...
If you recall it, you'll re-experience it, say.
But you'll find that most things,
if you don't pay attention to them,
they're not within the focus of consciousness.
And even though they're still there,
they don't bother you.
If I focus, you know, on the site of the amputation,
I can feel the pain of it
because the pain of it never really physically disappears.
As far as the source of suffering, it disappears
because...
you just ignore it.
So you begin by ignoring it
and letting go of wanting to change it.
And also there's certain karmic undoingness going on with it.
You understand?
I wondered if that might not be the case.
I think so.
I've recalled in front of this group
or similar groups, you know,
very specific recall of exactly what the karmic indebtedness was
that accounted for the excruciating experience
that I went through at one time.
And I remember extremely well what it was.
Yeah.
So if that's the case, if it's a karmic undoing,
then we should just go with that karmic undoing.
And that's also a way of non-resisting it,
of letting go of the resistance.
Yes, that would be a way of intellectually contextualizing it.
Just saying.
That I don't know what this serves,
but for thee, O Lord, do I accept it and surrender to thy will.
Mm-hmm.
And just go with it.
For however long it goes,
because that's your karmic undoing.
That's it.
Okay.
I've also heard you say that
if you want to disappear something,
accept it totally.
So if you go ahead and say,
well, this is karmic undoing,
and then you focus on becoming one with the field,
like you said,
and focus on the higher spiritual qualities.
Well, the first thing you do is,
you stop labeling it, you know,
indigestion, asthma, or whatever you're calling it.
You don't give it any name,
because you're not experiencing asthma.
You're not experiencing arthritis.
So what you do is let go of calling it anything.
Then you're only left with sensation.
Generally, if you let go of resisting a local pain,
stop calling it pain,
you realize that it's only sensation.
Then you let go of trying,
that your mind is localizing it.
If you constantly let go of resisting it,
the sensation will become general.
You can tell it's gone into your aura.
And now the pain or the nausea or whatever it is
that you're letting go of resisting
becomes general instead of specific.
And you just keep surrendering to it,
and it becomes like diffuse in your whole aura
rather than localized to your ankle.
You just do that as a process.
And just continue to do that.
Mm-hmm.
You got a choice?
Well, I suppose I could...
It's like being born ugly.
I mean, what can you do about it?
I suppose I could resist and resist,
but that wouldn't be very wise.
Any other techniques you'd like to share with us?
That'll do for now.
Okay.
Now, we were in Chicago.
We were on a radio program with a guy
who's called sort of a local shock jock.
And I really enjoyed him.
He was really fun.
But it was a crew of three or four of us.
It's a very well-known program in Chicago.
I forget the name of it.
Man for a cow.
Huh?
Cow.
Man cow.
Yeah, man cow.
And then he carries on a conversation with callers in.
Very fast mind, you know.
I got a big kick out of him.
But one of his crew standing around,
we all have to stand up.
You don't get to sit down.
You stand up.
Mm-hmm.
One of his crew,
uh, is just plain stupid.
And he'll tell you,
I'm just, you know,
I can't help it.
I just am stupid.
And then he'll say something.
And by God, it is,
it is really stupid.
And it just breaks up everybody.
Now, this stupid guy just accepts that he's stupid.
He doesn't battle it.
And, you know,
he probably makes more than you and I
and all of us put together, you know.
Just being stupid, you know.
He just says,
he says really dumb things, you know.
Like, I want a hamburger or something.
Yeah.
You know, like, in the middle of a question like that,
you say, I want a hamburger, you know.
That's a dumb thing to say
when a person's asking you a question, you know.
But, uh, so totally accepting that you're stupid
and ugly can be very beneficial.
I got it.
Thank you so much.
You see, what you, what you accept about yourself,
what am I supposed to do with this?
Nothing.
Oh, what you accept about yourself,
nobody can hit you there, understand?
Sensitive people are people who have not accepted
their downside, and they're defensive.
Therefore, they're vulnerable all over the place.
If you accept, if you sit down, I advise the people,
sit down and list every single possible defect
that you have or could be perceived as having,
and let, and it's okay with me.
It's okay with me.
Once it's okay with you,
what could be said to you that would upset you?
You've already accepted that.
So you've completely disarmed the other side
by accepting your downside.
You're short and skinny,
and you're never gonna make the team.
That's right.
You're not tall enough to make the swimming team.
You're too frail to be out there on the court.
You just ain't never gonna be an athlete.
I guess that's a fact.
Okay.
I've just never been very good at it.
Thank you very much.
Four eyes.
One time we were, after, after,
I've been four eyes too.
After A Course in Miracles,
after A Course in Miracles meeting,
you know, Lower East Side in New York.
Famous Jewish restaurant.
Dinner goes on for about three hours.
They stagger out of there.
And on the corner is this bag lady.
And here are these black plastic bags
full of New York City garbage sitting on the curb.
And this, right out of a movie,
bag lady is poking around through these things, see?
So we all stand around and ask for a miracle,
and we all bless her and send her her love.
Our love.
All of a sudden, her head comes out of these pile
of black plastic bags, you know?
And she looks at me and she says,
what are you looking at, four eyes?
Oh yeah, okay.
Okay, thank you so much.
Oh, can I have a hug?
A hug. I don't know.
Yes, maybe you can have a hug.
You don't knock the flowers over.
Could I get Sharon Raine to go to the bookstore, please?
Sharon Raine.
Yeah.
Yes, okay.
All right.
What are all these here?
They have to sign.
Did I sign them yet?
No.
Oh, glad somebody keeps track of it.
Yes, okay.
Look at this one, all beat up.
Holy catfish.
Yes.
Is unconditional love a realistic intention for?
An average American?
Certainly.
Is unconditional love a realistic intention?
Yes.
Why wouldn't it be, huh?
All you have to do is let go of your reservations about it,
judgmentalism and all that.
You see, unconditional love is a way of being.
It's not something you do.
Love is, you know, love at 500 is between a this and a that,
a me and a you, you and your cat, you and your dog, whatever.
Yeah.
At 540, it becomes a way of being in the world.
It's just the way you are in the world.
There's a lovingness towards all of life and all of its expressions,
and a sense of humor about everything,
and also the capacity to see the beauty of all things.
It's a way of being in the world, see?
It's not something you do.
Because it's a way of being, therefore, it's not something that requires effort.
You don't have to try to be unconditionally loving.
You just become that.
You become that.
The flowers are glad to see you arrive, because you're not going to pick them unnecessarily.
You revere all the beauty and all its innate incredible perfection.
You have to be careful, because you won't be able to function.
I mean, it's just if you let the energy of the beauty radiate for it,
then the questions and answers come to a stop,
because you become one with that field, because beauty is innate to divinity, you know, except
for some people.
Because they're ugly.
All right, we'll move along.
Okay.
Could I possibly have a hug?
You can have a hug if you don't knock the flowers over.
Yes, indeed.
Yes.
Dr. Hawkins, would you comment on the relationship between love and passion?
What's the difference between consciousness and schizophrenia?
They're not really related.
Consciousness is an overall nonlinear field.
Schizophrenia is a disorganization of content, see?
The linear content follows certain laws, and when it gets fractured, we call it schizophrenia.
Schizophrenia is the loss of the capacity.
You can't differentiate between the categories, as described by Immanuel Kant.
There are various levels of abstraction, and when you confuse the material with the intellectual,
when you lose the differentiation of levels of abstraction, then you're no longer following
the order of logic, subject and predicate and verb, you know, and therefore you're not
constrained by...
by integrity, by the integrity of logic, see?
So you fall below 400, you're no longer logical.
Hi.
Dr. Hawkins, you've commented before on the level of consciousness of humanity at
the time of birth of Christ.
Yes.
And also the Buddha.
How about Krishna and the Bhagavad Gita, that whole Indian history?
Could you comment on that particular period?
Yes.
Well, the Bhagavad Gita calibrates 900 or over.
The great Aryan sages, you see, 7 to 10,000 B.C., the pre-Indian culture, the Aryan, already
birthed great spiritual genius, 900, 950 was the great sages, and out of the great sages
arose the Gitas.
Yes.
And the ancient Hindu teachings.
So it was already old, already old.
Spiritual enlightenment was already known, you know, prior to the birth of Buddha or
Christ.
It didn't reach this side of the world because there was no communication with this side
of the world.
It was completely isolated from this side of the world.
So it was like reborn in the form of Jesus Christ, reborn in Buddha.
The time of the birth of Buddha, the consciousness level of mankind was...
It was at 90.
At the time of the birth of Jesus Christ, it was at 100.
And how about like at the time of Krishna?
I haven't done all that.
Anyway, it evolved.
And the great Aryan sages of 7 to 10,000 B.C. had already experienced the enlightened condition.
And their writings are still way up there.
Yes.
Thank you very much.
Krishna is coming back.
Yes.
That's correct.
I mean, when I read what Krishna said in the Bhagavad Gita, that's exactly the truth.
Those who worship me by whatever name are dear to me, and I will take them unto myself.
That's the truth.
Yeah.
Thank you.
I have a question about art.
If...
I don't know what Michelangelo calibrated at, but would his art that came through him
be able to calibrate higher than...
Yeah.
I don't think so.
Usually, the production is that of the radiance of the author.
Writers, the writings of spiritual teachers usually calibrate about just exactly what
the teacher's at.
So you're telling me what you calibrate at then, without saying it, by what your books
calibrate at.
About Michelangelo, yes.
Well, I...
You know what?
I was just...
I wasn't even...
I was asking...
I'm an artist, and that's why I was asking that.
But then it just clicked like, whoa.
Yeah, Michelangelo.
It looks...
It calibrated really high.
Thank you.
We calibrated Michelangelo.
And, you know, he's way up there.
Yeah.
Thank you.
I miss you, Midna.
See?
You see, they personalize, they personalize it.
It's impersonal.
The presence.
The presence, then, you learn.
I mean, I...
I...
You know?
The presence then utilizes the machinery, which is this body and this languaging and
all.
The presence utilizes the machinery to express itself in a form comprehensible to the audience.
That's all.
It's impersonal.
Yeah?
You were talking today about non-doing and non-effort, which is exactly opposite
how I'm living my life, really.
Non-what?
Non-doing and non-effort.
Oh, yes, yes, yes.
That's an interstate.
You can be busy as all get out on the outer.
Yeah, I know, I know.
Busy as can be.
Well, it actually brings me to confronting a paradigm that I struggle with, which is,
is it possible for mankind to live on this planet without having to work, having to do
the paradigm that we see out there?
Because it's certainly been my fantasy to live on this planet.
To be able to just be, and not have to...
When you're a spirit, yes.
Well, I thought, well, maybe it's a certain consciousness level.
If you get to be a certain consciousness level, then can you truly just trust that the universe
will provide everything for you, including the money, including the house, where you
don't have to work a job?
Yeah.
She needs to find a job in a spiritual community or something.
If you stop resisting hunger, you don't have to work.
When your material motivation disappears, there has to be some other motivation, or
you come to a stop.
You do.
You come to a stop.
And then the world can worry about you.
and if you topple over, you topple over, so...
I feel like the spin of all that we have to do in this life
is so distracting, and it's driving me crazy.
Distracting from what?
Of what I want to just be.
Well, what you are already is.
I know.
This is a losing conversation.
So it's not mankind's birthright to trust in the universe,
and a very radical trust I'm talking about.
You're talking about the celestial realm.
You're not talking about the physical realm.
No, I'm talking physical realm.
In the physical realm?
If I was in radical trust, I mean really radical trust,
like I know the universe.
Then what?
If you just...
Because I've done it.
So what happens?
That I don't have to try to create my physical self.
You don't have to.
If you're willing to sacrifice it,
something will come along,
and it will propagate the activity of the body,
or it won't.
And it's irrelevant.
You want it to be irrelevant, but still make it happen.
Yeah.
Whether you eat or not is the world's worry.
I have no interest in it.
Okay, can I ask you,
one more thing?
I suffer kind of from a deep love of astrology.
You suffer from what?
A deep love of astrology.
Oh, I thought a deep bad case of it.
I'm sorry.
I feel like I've been...
loved astrology for lifetimes.
I love the planets.
I love the stars.
I love the way they...
Yeah, you're stuck with the stars, yeah.
Go ahead.
I love the way they've guided me,
and...
Yeah, how come you got...
I don't think I have any questions today.
Well, I read your books,
and it put the seed of doubt, of course,
about the astral realms within me,
and I'm having difficulty...
I have difficulty making the break
between that paradigm
and, I guess, just releasing it.
That astrology dominates your life?
Astrological influences?
I think so.
Like Saturn's going over your back,
right, when Saturn is having lunch?
Yeah, and I feel like I give away my power,
but at the same time, I feel...
Yes, you're giving away your power
to the immaterial, to the non-material,
to the physical.
The physical has no intention.
Tell me how a whirling dirt ball
can have intention about your life,
love life.
Because I've seen...
It's not conscious.
It's dirt.
It's a dirt ball.
You don't see the planets.
Consciousness?
They're not...
You want me to ask?
Yeah.
Okay.
The physicality of a planet
has consciousness to resist.
You're projecting its power.
The only power it has
is what you project to it.
If you believe that this star
or this constellation
does what it does,
what happens if you disconnect
your belief from it?
Then it's just a whirling dirt ball.
Why don't you put your faith in God?
Well, I thought it was...
No, that's not God.
It's the material, physical universe.
You're giving it the power,
first of all, of causality.
We lectured about it today.
There is no this that can cause a that.
It's your intention
that a this should align with a that.
Just like we said,
consciousness of mankind evolved
at the time of the harmonic concordance.
So that which is all enveloping,
including the physical universe,
is all in accord with each other.
It's all in accord with each other
because it's all part of the one whole.
So the likelihood of something here
happening in conformity
with this being here
is because they're both coming out
of the same oneness,
not because of this is causing a that.
You're separating it into a duality.
The universe is a unity.
So there would be the concordance
of that which is perhaps favorable
at the same time,
of the phenomena,
not because this is causing that.
Understand?
So the only mistake you're making is causality.
There is still likely a concordance,
if for no other reason
than the power you give it
out of your own belief system.
So to exit a paradigm,
do you just exit?
You transcend it.
You don't have to say it's wrong.
I'm recontextualizing it for you.
That the universe is part of the oneness
of the will of God,
and it's beyond causality.
It's beyond causality.
If I look at a hologram, see?
If I look at a hologram,
as I walk around the hologram,
it looks, what does it look like?
If I photograph it and speed it up,
it looks like there's a this causing a that.
There's no this causing any that.
The only thing that's moved
is my point of observation.
So it doesn't make any difference
whether it's these flowers
or an infinite world of plants
or a planet swirling about each other.
It's still the same holographic phenomena,
see, in which everything is part of the whole, see?
Otherwise, you're trying to separate
this part of the hologram
from this part of the hologram
and saying this is cause and this is effect.
That's all in your head.
Because I can switch it around and say no.
It's the other way around.
All I have to do is turn time backwards.
Did Jesus teach that you get to heaven through astrology?
Answer me.
Did he?
No.
Did the Buddha teach that?
Did Krishna teach that?
No.
Who taught it?
Some divine being?
Okay.
I understand what she's saying,
but you'll get caught up in an interest
and put a lot of time and energy into it,
and I don't have a vested interest in it.
It's not that it's wrong,
it's just that it's not contextualized correctly
as part of the overall whole,
you know what I'm saying?
Mm-hmm.
On a lighter note,
this is a present for your cat.
You were calibrating cats
for cat food last time,
and this is what I feed my cats,
and I don't think you've ever heard
of this particular cat food.
Oh, good.
You might like to calibrate it.
It's called dead mice.
A bag of dead mice.
Oh, nice.
Oh, great.
Yeah.
Oh, isn't that nice?
You'll have to try it.
Oh, this cat food calibrates over 200.
Oh, thank God.
My cat has good karma.
You know, if you bless food,
it jumps in calibration 10 to 15 points.
Therefore, if you love your pet,
what you do is you feed your kitty
or your doggy or whatever,
you bless this food
for the sake of thy love, oh Lord,
because the dog's wagging tail is 500,
the kitty's purr is 500,
so you're just thanking God for their love.
I thank you for their love.
You bless their food,
and they're calibrated
to the level of the kitty food jumps.
I was getting some pretty high numbers
on this food,
and you said that most...
I said it's over 200, yeah.
Right.
Most cat food, you said,
didn't calibrate much.
Well, no.
There's some big-selling brands
whose names I don't want to mention
in today's litiginous world.
Calibrates below 200.
But I know my cat pointed it out
because she wouldn't eat it,
or you wouldn't eat it.
And I was hoping to get a hug as well.
I don't have a dollar on me.
She doesn't.
That's right.
Did you give me kitty food?
It's around the flowers.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Thank you for the kitty food, dear.
Thank you for the kitty food.
Yeah, I know she'll love that.
Thank you.
We love it.
Let me thank you for the kitty food.
That's good.
I thank you, my kitty food.
Thank you.
We all thank you.
In the name of the great kitty.
In the name of the great kitty,
we do thank you.
I have no question to ask.
I ask you for a hug.
Oh, yes, a hug.
I won't kick it over.
No, they want freebies.
Thank you, sweetheart.
Thank you.
This mic is working okay, huh?
Yes.
All right.
Yes, indeed.
I had the same question.
You're into astrology, too?
Thanks.
I once caught Venus in my backyard, dude, and you know what was Saturn, by God.
I reported it to the police, too.
I'm sorry.
Now, I have a question I didn't have before.
No.
When I first read your book, at the end, about the author, I wept, and the reason
being that you were talking about the energy flows that you had from your body, which I
have experienced from mine at times, and it just brought tears to my eyes.
That's the Kundalini energy.
See, when we spoke, we didn't use that term today.
I realize that's an omission of my part.
Because over 200, what happens is the kundalini energy begins to flow.
I wish it had a better name.
Spiritual energy, spiritual energy begins to flow.
And that's what shifts you over to the processing a different thing.
And it's the kundalini energy that actualizes the formation of the etheric brain.
The etheric brain is a consequence of the kundalini energy.
So an animal does not have an etheric brain.
Although maybe cats and dogs do.
I never asked.
I've had experiences where I felt it come all the way through my body, out my arm, out my hand.
And one time I was sitting across from a lady and my hand was on her thigh and I went into her.
And I lifted my hand.
She actually levitated.
And I grumbled.
And I went to a parapsychology department at a university after that happened to ask them what possibly had happened.
And all they said to me, well, we heard of this before.
Just look at it as a love-giving experience.
Kundalini energy, yes.
But to me what they were doing was just copying out.
It was not an answer.
The kundalini energy, we didn't talk about that today, results in the so-called SIDDHAS.
S-I-D-D-H-A-S.
Paranormal Phenomena.
Distance viewing, clairaudience, clairvoyance, psychometry, you could grab this.
I know who owned it, where it came from.
I saw all of it's been spoken in the front of this thing.
All those things are spontaneous.
The capacity to heal things, heal sicknesses, heal beings, the miraculous, all that is a consequence of that energy.
It does it of its own.
Well, I know I didn't do anything.
No, it does it of its own.
I don't know if that's true.
It'll go next door and heal some crippled lady and she'll get up and walk away.
It's a big surprise, you know, it's a surprise.
Second question, please.
So it does all those things of its own, yeah?
Okay.
Knock on my microphone, you'll hear from my lawyer right into my teeth.
See, I can't talk that way anymore.
He's a perpetrator and I'm a victim.
You see that.
I got witnesses.
What?
Dr. Hawkins, thank you.
Thank you for the gift that you are to the world.
My question is, would you help me recontextualize the lower astral, the luciferic, the satanic?
Yes.
Yeah, the energies of the negative energies over the centuries.
Lucifer, you see, the luciferic is like about 190.
It's in our society.
It's secular.
It wants to take God out of everything.
Why?
Because Lucifer did not want to acknowledge.
The sovereignty of God.
So, therefore, it's a competition for power and prestige.
It was the luciferic that came to me as I went through the final pass.
The luciferic came to me as a knowingness.
Now that you realize that you're beyond all answerability or consequence, beyond all karma,
all power is yours, own it.
It's a temptation.
It's a temptation then, which comes.
So, the luciferic has to do with pride and power, prestige, and it distorts reason and logic via the distortions of the hermeneutics of relativistic epistemology.
That's where it invades the classroom.
It sounds very comical.
But, you know, the professorships of the universities have gone down, down, down right now.
The professors of six of the world's, United States greatest universities calibrate below 200.
And a lot of the professors calibrate higher than the student body.
So, the sacrificing of truth, you know, for relativism.
What is the problem with relativism?
It denies the reality of the absolute.
It's the Mad Hatter's Tea Party.
It says, a thing only means what I mean it to mean.
That denies, you see, the reality of the absolute.
It says that I'm God.
How I see it and how I define it is how it is.
So, then, therefore, you can ridicule science and reason and logic and ethics and tradition.
And now anything goes.
All morality and ethics are then hated constraints.
Against freedom.
Freedom of what?
Freedom of the id.
Freud's id.
Which seeks no accountability, answerability, or responsibility.
So, we see a society in which responsibility is now projected onto some supposedly evil external cause.
Making the Marxian dialectic error even more severe.
It is.
To begin with.
All right.
So, you see a downgrading of society.
So, it means that the way I see it is superior to truth.
And that my way of seeing it is superior to all the greatest minds that have ever lived.
And that I am really superior to divinity.
That's a great game to play.
Good luck.
The Lucifer.
That's the Lucifer.
The Satanic is represented by...
Torture, pain, and dynamiting busloads of children.
I was hoping to find some way of finding humor in it.
It's hard to find humor in 300 kids being blown up.
Perhaps the humor is in the absurdity.
The absurdity.
Because you're blowing up all these innocent children for God.
That's what makes it...
So, it's really more the ridiculous.
More the absurd.
And it would be sad if it weren't so destructive.
Yep.
Thank you.
That's what the enemy is.
The enemy right now is that energy field which comes out of Wahhabism.
Wahhabism.
The tradition that I grew up in, and I'll be brief.
Yeah.
Okay.
It is that the astral, the Satanic was so demonized, to put it that way,
that people were afraid of it.
Well, we call it demonic, yes.
Yeah.
If the energies get low enough, we call them demonic.
Right.
You know, because they become homicidal.
Thank you.
Lower astral realms.
Yes.
Dollar for a hug.
And I'll come to you.
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
There are many domains, many realms.
Just like...
We didn't get into heaven today.
But...
We'll just say it to make sure that...
Because I don't want to...
The girl could not have said it.
If you stop breathing, you go...
Oh, I didn't say.
Now I got to come back again to teach you what I didn't say.
So I...
There are multiple heavens.
There isn't just one heaven.
It's a whole celestial realm.
Many religions are the sole pipeline to that region of heaven.
So when they claim exclusivity to heaven,
they are exclusive to that portion of heaven.
Which is that neighborhood.
So if you got to have 30 wives in order to get into heaven,
their hunk of heaven, that's so.
People only have one wife, you don't get admitted there.
So there are multiple heavens suitable for each set of belief system.
And the intentionality.
Don't forget Krishna said,
all who are devoted to me are dear to me.
So if you think God is in a pumpkin and you worship the pumpkin,
then there's...
You go to pumpkin heaven.
I just want to thank you.
I feel so inspired when I hear you talk.
And I wish I could just be your apostle or something
and follow you around everywhere.
But my question is about the negative emotional states
below consciousness level 200.
Yes.
I've heard those referred to as illusory or non-real or even non-existent.
Well, they're based on misperception, yes.
They seem justified because that's how you're perceiving it.
On the other hand, you're perceiving it that way
because that's what your level of consciousness is.
So the two reinforce each other.
But if they're non-existent,
how can they still have an energy associated with it?
Well, because perception determines what has no energy.
Those levels have energy.
Each one has a justified level and energy, yes.
If they have energy, then how can like imagination or something have energy?
If it's illusory, it's not real.
Like fear is not real.
Well, not real in what sense depends on what you mean by real.
Real with a small R, real with a big R.
There's real with a big R in which none of this applies.
Is that why when you're over 600, nothing, test goes weak anymore?
Not being weak.
When you're above consciousness level 600, you don't go weak anymore with kinesiology?
No, nothing makes you go weak.
So those negative emotional states,
you realize that they are fallacious.
Perception.
You realize they are perception, yes.
But that perception creates its own reality within its own energy field.
Hatred is hatred and it does have its own energy field.
But you see that the basis of the hatred is illusion.
We gave you a way out of hatred today forever.
Socrates, when he said that every man chooses only the good,
right away you got, oh, that's the tool, the understanding I needed.
Now I can forgive everyone.
They choose only the good.
They blow up a whole lot of children because that to them is the good.
Okay.
I'm getting them.
I'm signing this.
It's a quarter after four.
I don't know how many people are here.
Don't worry about it.
I'll worry about it.
Thank you.
Let God worry about it.
God's problem, not my problem.
I don't run this universe.
I'm telling you.
Okay.
No, I'm glad you reminded me.
I'm telling you.
Dr. Hawkins.
Mm-hmm.
Today you mentioned that there are a number of mantras that calibrate in the 700s.
And it's also my understanding that for the past 2,000, 3,000 years and up until today,
that the majority of enlightened beings have come from the Eastern religions, primarily Buddhism,
which seems to have a predominant practice of using mantras.
And it's not due to the mantras.
The mantra is an expression of the intention.
And the reason Buddhism is so effective is because it looks for divinity within.
See, in the Western world, God is pictured and held by belief systems to be transcendent,
out there, somewhere ahead in time or behind in time.
Created the universe, disappeared.
Now you're going to meet the big man over there.
See?
So God is pictured as transcendent.
In the Eastern understanding, Hindu and Aryan, East Indian and Buddhic, the God is imminent.
So it is the imminent God within as the Self, with a capital S, as the source of existence.
And that which one experiences in the divine state is the unmanifest becoming manifest as your existence.
The source of joy is the awareness of the source of your existence, which is ever-present.
When I say thee, O Lord, I'm speaking to that which is already present,
not something in the future or something in the past.
Thank you very much.
It was discovered when you let go of the barriers, when you let go of duality,
the reality shines forth as self-realization.
It does so spontaneously of its own.
Not because you caused it, but because when the clouds are removed, the sun shines forth.
But you didn't cause the sun to shine forth.
Dr. Hawkins, I just wanted to thank you.
I do have a question, but I first wanted to thank you.
You were the one that, and Lou and Shelly helped me out of this call group.
And you gave me some suggestions last time I spoke to join an Al-Anon group, which I did.
Right.
And things are moving along.
And I'm learning to let go and let God.
And just feeling the flow of God just working through me.
You took my advice?
Yes.
No, I am going to leave the world.
Everybody has it. Few people take it.
So do I get $20 in?
No, you get a dollar for taking my advice.
So, my question is, it deals with undoing karma.
And I know you mentioned, you talked about it briefly in another question.
Besides becoming the field and maybe surrendering our will to God,
is there specific things, like if we would ask, God, is there karma that I can get rid of?
And what could I do to precipitate that?
Or does it just come about?
Well, it shows up of its own.
Okay.
You don't have to hustle it up.
Although spiritual work often results in your life becoming chaotic for a while.
Because spiritual work then begins removing the karmic layers and you move rapidly.
Okay. Great.
Sometimes people think their life is getting worse.
It's not getting worse.
It's just that they're moving it ahead faster.
Moving it up.
And people go into beatific states and then it doesn't last.
And they feel very sad about that.
It's because they've transcended their karma for up to now.
And then the next layer of what needs to be undone becomes undone.
But the flashes of beauty and inner light are presaging.
They tell you that you're in the right direction.
Just keep going.
And when you undo that next bunch of negative karma, it comes back again.
So it's recurrent.
Got it.
Thank you very much.
Can I have a hug, too?
You can have a hug.
Anybody who takes my advice deserves a hug.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
Yeah.
I had a question about this old book that I found.
It's called The Life and Teachings of the Great Masters of the Far East.
Yeah, it's a famous book.
And I was just wondering, my question was, have you ever read it?
Handle or calibrate it?
No, no, no.
I'm very familiar with it, though.
Mm-hmm.
OK.
Yeah.
Yep.
OK.
That was all I had.
Yeah.
The book calibrates over 500 verses.
550, 560, 580, 575, 560, 565, 560.
Can I raise the 560?
Yes.
Good evening, Dr. Hawkins.
Thank you for the wonderful enlightenment that you've given us.
Thank you.
I messed up.
Do you think I got a hand?
This is my first time, my first exposure.
Where are you, arm?
Where are your...
I had my first exposure to yourي
Yes.
300, no.
You've recovered, though, you've recovered from it pretty well.
Oh.
They call me the Bill O'Reilly of spirituality, you know.
my husband and I and soon after we had him we realized that there were things
that were not just right with him so when he started school we were having
problems and eventually he's now 37 he has been diagnosed as bipolar borderline
and we have stuck by him and we will continue to do that but I was wondering
if there was it's been very draining on us and yet we don't want to abandon what
we started I mean we were told by a pediatrician way in the beginning that
we could probably give him up because he was suspecting something might be wrong
with him because of his biological mother yes and we decided that we would
not do that so that was our decision to keep him and we bonded and of course I
bonded with him within five minutes when they gave him to me
you're welcome
and we're still suffering he's 37 he's he finally left the United States he's
living in New Zealand now but still very very dependent on us because he's never
been able to work he's very brilliant but he doesn't have any judgmental with
him to control his or to regulate his daily activities and he's chronically
disabled yes yeah so I was wondering I mean I know that was kind of a far-out
question but
is there anything that can be done on a miraculous or a spiritual level I mean
we've tried my husband and I you know we've we've done a lot of reading we've
done a lot of growing in the last 37 years well you then you'd let go on to change him no we
don't want to change him we can't all right so what is the problem the problem
is how do we I mean we've gotten to the point where we are so exhausted now you
must be resisting that otherwise you're not exhausted you're exhausted from what
exhausted from what?
To accept what is, then let go, wind it, change it.
That's the prayer you need.
We can't. We realize that there's nothing we can do.
No, that's an intellectual. You haven't accepted it.
Acceptance, it's neither this nor that.
It just is that way.
My kitty is orange.
I just accept it's orange.
I don't want to make it black. I don't want to make it gray.
I don't grieve the fact that it's orange.
I just let it be what it is.
So you let your son be what it is, like a kitty cat.
But don't give me any buts.
Just do what I tell you.
Take the first step in it.
Okay.
I told you that.
Take the first step in it.
It's all step groups have that.
First step, you admit that your power was sober.
Stop trying to change it.
The context for my question is that I have
a spiritual healing practice where I work with people
to help them.
They experience or become aware of the presence of God.
And on a few occasions, it seems that I have helped someone
who is more spiritually advanced than myself
to go to higher levels than they've ever attained before.
Yet there's a traditional belief that a master can't take a student
beyond his own level.
Who said you're a master?
Well, but is it possible for me or for anyone
to help someone go beyond their own level?
Of course.
You can give a person a book.
And they become enlightened as a result of applying it.
So you're only a stepping stone, you know?
A stepping stone.
It's the intention of the other person, for instance.
The intention of the other person
will activate a single sentence.
And all you needed was that one sentence to shoot through.
But it's their intention that activates that sentence.
You don't do it.
You're a facilitator.
Yeah.
You carry the message, but not the person.
Right.
I know it's not.
It's up to them.
You give them the message.
It could be 10 years.
One morning they wake up and they say, oh, Zowie.
Man chooses only the good.
Wow.
When I'm working.
I said that today, didn't I?
No.
Socrates told me that a long time ago.
Socrates.
When I'm working with them, I'm praying that they receive a healing and a teaching.
And they often later come back and say, you know, after I left, it occurred to me that.
And I think, okay, that's the teaching.
And I know it didn't come through me.
Yeah.
So you put in your ore.
And that's all you can do, you know.
Thank you.
The rest is up to the other person and their acceptance and their karma, et cetera.
One thing is the truth.
The other thing is acceptance.
Yes.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
I have a question about your.
You made a comment earlier this year in one of your videos that I saw about your orange
kitty.
You said it was the only one in the universe.
Oh, yeah.
And my question is, is there just one human being in the universe?
Now, it's there over 200.
Over 200, you have individual karma.
You have an etheric brain.
You have responsibility for your choices and your actions.
And the animal kingdom has one central consciousness that radiates out in multiple bodies so that
you meet one orange kitty, you've met them all in a way, you know.
Thank you.
Can I have a hug?
Yeah.
What?
You got an orange kitty in there?
You got kitty food?
Thank you very much.
Thank you.
Mm-hmm.
Boy, I'm making big money today.
My question, Dr. Hawkins, is would eating raw food benefit the body and nervous system
for the Kundalini energy to come up through?
Would it prepare it better?
What?
If eating raw food would prepare the body…
I don't think so.
No.
I don't think it has anything to do with it.
Mm-hmm.
It doesn't have anything to do with it.
Oh.
Because it's non-linear, non-physical.
It's a non-linear, non-physical energy.
Therefore, I don't think physical manipulations have any influence on it.
On whether the energy comes up easily or…
I don't think so.
…whatever.
I see.
Because when it's ready to come up, it comes up by itself.
Uh-huh.
And when it's not ready, you know, I don't believe in trying to promote it artificially,
because then it's not real, it's not you.
Yeah.
I see.
It comes about automatically.
As you become more loving towards all of life and all of the expressions, then it begins
to flow automatically of its own.
I see.
Mm-hmm.
I understand.
Okay.
Well, thank you so much for answering that.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
And I would like to have a hug, please.
Thank you so much.
We have to be out of here at 5 in the morning.
Half hour, we've got…
Okay, don't worry about it.
We'll make it.
That was my mother, by the way.
I know we'll make it.
We'll always make it.
Yeah.
Mm-hmm.
Do you guys always calibrate the group consciousness before and after?
Have you done that?
Or do you stop doing that?
We usually do it, you know.
Oh.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
Would you be interested in doing that today?
Well, let's see what the consciousness level of the audience did today.
The consciousness…
We have permission to ask that.
Of the group here, the consciousness level of the group, from the beginning to the end
of the lecture, it went up over 8 points, 9 points, 10 points, 11 points, about 10, 11
points.
Okay.
That wasn't my question.
It just occurred to me on the way up here.
Yeah.
No, that's because…
Now he's got another question.
He spent a dollar already.
Yeah.
Go ahead.
So this is studying someone who has quit eating.
And I've been a student of that subject for quite some time.
What subject?
Well, some people call it breatharianism, but there are people that are spontaneously
not eating in China.
Oh, breatharians.
Yes, yes, yes.
And they give them a whole different label, and they don't even know the term.
But I'm wondering, you know, because a lot of these people that are doing this happen
to be spiritual-oriented.
I don't know if there's a connection between the two, but here's my question, because I'm
trying to pull together some material on the subject of health, and I'm going to make
a brief mention of breatharianism.
And I want to know whether you have to have a certain calibrated level of consciousness
in order for that to happen.
And I'm not necessarily connecting it with spirituality.
I just want to know.
It seems like, based on paying attention to your research, that it has to be at least
200.
Is there something...
There aren't too many breatharians around.
Well, like I said, NASA's got one, and they're studying them for the obvious reason.
Is it possible for you to find out if...
Are you tired of eating?
What is your problem?
You can stop eating any time you want.
Oh, I can?
Okay.
All right.
Is there a calibrated level of consciousness that you have to reach?
I never calibrated it.
No.
I never did research it.
Oh, okay.
I think we asked about one.
Let me hold in mind something.
The one I'm holding in mind is genuine.
There is a genuine one in Germany.
That's the only one I know about.
Woman.
Okay.
So is it possible to ask if there's a calibrated level of consciousness in order to...
I don't know.
I don't have time to research it.
Okay.
That would be too much time.
I have more than one question.
Okay.
And could you see whether this book is integrous or not just by the Kinesian?
No.
All right.
Thank you much.
We're tough.
Yeah.
Stop eating.
That's easy.
Stop breathing.
Try that one.
That way you transcend the body quickly.
Quit eating.
It takes a while.
Quit breathing.
Instant karma.
Okay.
Thank you.
Instant karma.
Yes, we are.
Dr. Hawkins.
Yeah.
Are you familiar with Thomas Hora that wrote Beyond a Dream?
No.
I was learning to...
The number of authors I'm not familiar with are multitudinous.
Could you calibrate?
What is that?
Beyond...
Thomas Hora?
Beyond a Dream?
No.
How about Joel Goldsmith?
We only calibrated people that calibrated 460 and over.
Yeah.
Joel Goldsmith was over 460, yes.
Forty-five, I think.
He was, still.
Mm-hmm.
The only other thing I'd mention is, on a personal level, it seems like...
I don't know if I'm getting old or silly or what, but, I tear up so easily.
Tear up?
Tear up.
Yes.
Is this a symptom of me becoming more spiritual, or just a silly old lady?
Nope.
.
I don't know, we'd have to research it individually.
You tear up with what? Joy or sadness?
Well, no, anything that moves me.
Yeah, no, that's just, that's very common.
If you do spiritual work, you find yourself crying all the time.
Oh, good.
There's a certain level in which the slightest sign of love or tenderness or something, you just weep.
And when you go through it, it's sort of tough.
You're in an airport waiting for a plane.
And you see this wife look at her husband, and you can just see the love.
And you just break out in tears about it.
Oh, well, that's comforting because my grown children just tease me.
They say, are you going to cry now?
In monasteries, it's, you know, well-known.
And people often cry for several years.
They hit a certain level of love, and they cry sometimes for a couple years.
Oh, that's incredible.
I'm going to cry for a couple years.
Invest in Kleenex and be with it.
Yeah, well, at least we're not going in the right direction.
Yes, beauty makes you weep, beautiful music.
The most common experience of it is beautiful music.
You know, you hear the introduction to Lohengrin or Tannhäuser.
And as you hear the music mount, Jesus, God, it just wipes you off.
You know, anything of great beauty just wipes you out.
So be prepared to be wiped out pretty often.
Or avoid the beautiful.
Except that everything in the world considers ugly.
You see it's innate beauty, so you can't escape it either.
Okay, you know, that's the phase you go through.
Thank you, doctor.
May I have a hug?
Mm-hmm.
If you don't cry about it.
No problem.
Yes, sweetheart.
It's a beautiful state you're in.
Love it.
Wait, don't sit down.
I'll save you the time of sitting down.
Thank you, sir.
Uh-huh.
Dr. Oggins, thank you very much for your work.
And I wanted to ask you if you might illustrate the kinesthological method for me.
You didn't see it today?
I saw you do it with her, but I don't know how to do it myself.
You can't do it yourself.
You got to have a partner the way I do it.
There is a way of doing it by yourself.
When were you?
I don't know.
It's that reliable.
Mm-hmm.
Can I try it with you?
No.
Because nothing makes me go weak.
You see, I hold in mind.
I don't tell her what I'm thinking.
Okay.
What I'm holding in mind calibrates over 900 resists, 950 resists, 975 resists, 980
resists, 990 resists.
Okay.
What I'm holding in mind calibrates over 900 resists, 950 resists, 975 resists, 980
resists, 990 resists, 980 resists, 980 resists, 980 resists, 980 resists, 980 resists, 980 resists,
990 resists, 980 resists, 980 resists, 980 resists.
What I'm holding in mind calibrates over 1000 resists.
Now, I didn't tell her what I was holding in mind.
So truth makes the body go strong quickly.
But it's a very fast response.
So if you hold something in mind and you press down with two fingers, the person resists
to the same degree as you.
Okay.
that you're pressing down.
The reaction is very quick, see?
So you can't hold a thing in mind and press down,
I mean, wait a minute, and then press down.
Because it'll create a doubt in your mind
if you verbalize it, I suggest you do it non-verbally.
Otherwise, you may come back later with a doubt,
well, it's because of what I said, the person heard me, see?
Don't tell them what you're holding in mind.
I can hold a famous painting in mind,
and I say, now, what I'm, let's see,
there was recently a rediscovery of a great painter,
about a year or two ago, what was that great painting
that he rediscovered, one of the greatest masters
of all time, and the argument was
whether it was legitimate or not.
So Van Gogh, maybe?
No.
It started with an R, wasn't it?
One of the greatest, like Titian or something like that.
Anyway, the question was whether it was legitimate or not,
so just for curiosity, yeah, we asked,
is it legitimate or not, and it is, it is, mm-hmm.
Trying to think of the name of the artist,
one of the greatest names in art.
It was Ramiro, I think it was Ramiro.
I don't remember now.
Anyway, it's worth multi-millions of dollars,
so to be able to tell whether it's false or not false.
At home, I have a Picasso that makes you go weak.
We hung it in the bathroom.
It's a fake Picasso.
This is my own question.
I'd just like a hug, please.
Oh, uh-oh.
I'm going to go anywhere.
Oh, I'm getting away easy today, no chowky talk.
I'll just hug you here.
So yes, who was that great artist?
Oh, god.
What was it called?
One of the greatest.
Was it a Vermeer?
I think it was Vermeer, yes.
Let me just ask again.
What I'm holding in mind calibrates over 700, 750, 780.
That Vermeer calibrated around 750.
The world's greatest art experts have a great deal
of difficulty deciding whether a piece of art is legitimate
or not.
We can tell in a second.
My question is, from a spiritual perspective
and in the long run, does it really
matter who wins the upcoming presidential election?
In the long, in the greater context, no.
In the greater context, no.
Why?
Because it's the unfolding of the collective karma
of mankind in its expression in the United States
at this particular time and under these circumstances.
Let me just ask a question myself.
OK, the intention of the person I'm holding in mind is over 200.
The intention of the person I'm holding in mind is over 200.
The intention of both.
Both contestants is integrous.
They both intend.
They both have integrous intention.
So I'm worried about a person's intention, see?
If a person's intention is integrous,
then I'll lend them my car, if it's not at all, I'd say.
I once lent my car to somebody, and I didn't calibrate him.
I had to go get it myself several weeks later.
I was sitting in his driveway with the key in it out of gas.
Hi, doctor.
Uh.
Question from the last lecture I went to in this one
is that in order to raise consciousness,
you would embrace the field.
And one of the best ways to do that
is to pick something that's truly sacred.
Love, beauty, forgiveness, really embrace that.
Could you elaborate a little bit more on that,
and then maybe how you can really get into that in light
of maybe some of our occupations, daily challenges,
things like that?
To be one with the field, then, is
like being with the current moment in a generality
rather than a specificity.
Like, say, the upcoming election.
What are you concerned about?
I'm concerned about whether the people are integrous, right?
Now we ask.
You could then ask.
What is for the highest good of the country?
Then what is for the highest good of mankind, et cetera?
Your alignment with integrity then tends to bring it to you.
To see the sacredness of all that exists is a revelation.
It's not something you can will or program.
It reveals itself spontaneously.
You're walking through the woods,
and suddenly you see the stunning perfection of one
thing standing out in the woods.
You wonder, God.
It's God revealing the divinity which
is present in all of creation.
And it's a revelation when you remove the obstacles to it.
And the obstacles are dualistic perception.
So the reason we talk about nonlinear reality
is because it's the fastest pathway.
If I stop and say the flowers are beautiful or not beautiful,
and I have to name every flower, I'm really missing what they are.
What are they?
They're obviously somebody's intention to create beauty
and to uplift the audience, to uplift.
Whoever put this together did so in the name of beauty, you see?
So you see the intention of the flowers and their arrangement
and their being here is, in a way, worshipful of beauty,
expression of the worship.
Mm-hmm.
Of beauty.
So you begin to see the beauty of all that exists.
It's a matter of just becoming aware and sensitive to it.
All things that exist are intrinsically beautiful.
And I'd like a hug.
Mm-hmm.
So much.
You walk through an alley, and all of a sudden,
the alley and everything in it, all the garbage cans,
strike you as an impressionistic painting.
Incredible.
It's like a stage set.
Next time you see something the world calls ugly,
look at it as a stage set.
Everything is a stage set.
You walk through the alley, there's the tin can,
there's the kitty climbing on the tin can,
there's the little rats scurrying all around.
I mean, it's a perfect stage set.
Don't you see it?
The theatrics of the presents itself.
And when you see through our artistic eyes,
you'll see the intrinsic beauty of the garbage can.
I love old garbage cans.
I mean, they just, whoa, they're so droopy.
And this little rat runs up the side,
and you run down the other side.
I mean, it's like the theater.
Theater, it's like theater.
You see all of existence like theater.
I mean, the politicians getting out there and .
It's like fantastic theater, you know what I mean?
The ones that were up a couple of months ago
shaving their fists.
It's hysterical, you know what I mean?
All the fish shaking.
You calibrate them, 135, you know what I mean?
Hello, Dr. Hawkins.
Thank you very much for your presence.
I'm very grateful.
I want to ask you something about the
anatta and individual karma, the anatta doctrine of no mind.
And I think that I'm having problems with this
because our language in subject predicate fashion
is naturally dualistic and the semantic difficulty.
But who actually changes the program in that DVD
that has an end during his life in our life's journey?
If there is no actual I that has a substantial essence,
how can we affect our own spiritual advancement?
How do we become?
Who has?
Who has free will?
Who is it that no individual I is needed?
How is it?
You know, how does karma?
This is a composition you're reading me.
You're not asking me a question.
No, I'm just trying to qualify all these things.
I'm going to give you a D on the presentation so far.
No, how?
Yeah, I want you to cut to the quick of it.
How do we have individual karma if it happens at 200
and we have a, you know, an etheric brain?
Yeah, you have a collective karma up to 200,
such as the animals do.
And then when you transcend consciousness level 200,
you, for the first time, come into spiritual reality
and spiritual power.
From that point on, you have an individual consciousness,
individual consciousness.
Up to that time, you share the collective.
You share the collective.
See, one forgiving thought can take you right out
of that field, one forgiving thought.
It all takes.
So, you actually remembered your karma as a tiger?
Or was that a joke?
The tigerness, I subjectively intuit.
I don't remember being a tiger.
But many lifetimes, you do remember.
And because they were highly significant
from a spiritual viewpoint and beyond a certain level,
you consciously remember them in excruciating detail,
unfortunately.
Yeah.
You remember them, yeah.
If the individual I does not exist as a substantial essence,
how do we not remember a lot of different?
You're getting into a lot of languaging now.
You're just kind of.
No, I understand.
This is my problem.
What are you really asking?
You know, I was raised Roman Catholic.
And I studied philosophy.
And my problem is the no mind and who reincarnates.
You're mixing levels.
You're not making any sense.
Right, that's what I figured.
It's apples and oranges, right?
Yeah.
OK, thank you very much.
Can I have a hug?
What reincarnates.
What reincarnates is that which thinks it has a mind.
That which is nonlinear doesn't reincarnate,
because it never incarnated.
Thank you.
I wish we had more time to answer him thoroughly.
Well, it would take longer to decipher and translate it
into language.
Because this one goes to the satellite room
and this one is here.
So we have to speak to both of them.
I forgot the satellite room.
I didn't even remember when I say a lot of the people.
Wow.
Guilt.
Guilt?
Well, tell them to come in here and say hello to you.
All right.
Well, yeah.
Sorry.
I'm a facilitator.
So I'm naturally grabbing the mic.
Can you tell me what the relationship is
between a sudden change in our level of consciousness
and the rate of divorces that are happening
or breakup of relationships, specifically
long-term relationships?
Do I think there's a relationship
between the collective consciousness level and the level
of your own consciousness?
Thank you.
Break up of relationships? Is that what you're asking?
Yes, the increase of our conscious level.
I never asked the question. I never researched it.
Does it have anything to do with the indigo children?
No.
Okay, thank you. May I have a hug?
People may stay together because they're evolved or because they're not evolved.
Or one or the other, or more evolved than the others.
Too dumb to know about it, right?
Or too smart to change my mind.
I had two questions.
One, would you take a picture with me?
Sure.
And the other, something that I would call a discrepancy,
but I'm sure there's an explanation.
You had two calibrations for Descartes.
One in Power vs. Force, $4.99.
No, no, Descartes is not $4.99.
Thank you.
Descartes is around $4.60.
Descartes is around $4.60, yeah.
Descartes is around $4.60, I think.
$4.60, yeah.
No, Einstein is $4.99.
Descartes is, no, Descartes is differentiated between res interna and res externa.
So that would be around $4.50, $4.55.
Look at this.
He's two of me.
Let me shake your hand, sir.
He's not tall.
I'm a midget that explains it.
They called me shorty, so it's not that he's tall, it's that I'm short, yes.
Hi.
It's my first time to see you, and I just finished Power vs. Force.
So my question is on kinesiology for beginners.
Do we just keep continuing to practice to be able to really do it as effectively as you're doing it?
Well, don't forget we have a lot of practice.
Yeah.
You can tell, you can, there's a lot of people you can study with on the Internet.
There's people who do kinesiology, teach kinesiology all over the country.
In fact, there are always keeps a list of them, and when we speak around, we often meet teachers of it.
It's very, very simple.
It's based somewhat on a sensitivity.
For instance, I can ask a question, and she'll already feel the energy of the answer run down her,
her arm, before the muscles react.
I've gotten so sensitive that I can experience the energy that is running down her arm.
And I already got the answer before her arm does one thing or the other.
But we've been doing it together for.
For instance, if I ask if Descartes over 460, I already feel the positive energy out.
Descartes are on 460.
So it's clear that this is the basis of knowing the truth to the false for all of those that don't have this, or for me,
we just continue to practice.
You're saying there are people.
Do you have anybody that you recommend for teaching?
There are teachers all over the country and and most chiropractors know how to do it.
Most holistic practitioners of medicine know how to do it.
There are study groups that study this work here all over the country that do it routinely.
Well, we just started a study group on this in Denver.
So we're just beginning, though.
Oh, we're trying to fine tune our skills.
So.
Oh, right.
OK.
Going and doing something like.
Well, we intend to do a teaching video on kinesiology, but we're bored with kinesiology.
So we never did do it.
But if kinesiology is the basis for us to know truth, then we would need to learn it to be able to.
It's a way to verify truth.
Right. Yeah.
But you see what's happened to her arm.
She used to be useful, but she's not anymore.
OK, great.
Yeah, as I say, it's like writing a bicycle.
You'll know why after the new book comes out, if you want.
Anyway.
OK.
When you get where it's at, you've got it, you know, and it's just sort of getting the space of it.
And if you're around people that know how to do it or do it all the time, you sort of pick it up intuitively from them, you know.
OK.
Yep.
Thank you.
And can I have a hug, too?
Yes.
So you can't have a vested interest in the answer.
You have to ask a question in the name of the highest good.
For instance, you know.
Between the two contestants for the presidency, I'm only interested in whether they have integrity or not.
If one of them makes your arm go weak, then that would not be for the highest good of the country.
It's got nothing to do with who they are, you know.
I mean, they all went to Ivy League colleges, you know.
Thank you.
You're welcome.
Yes, yes.
First of all, Lily Tomlin's bag lady tests, reality.
It's nothing more than a collective hunch.
Lily Tomlin, I love her, yes.
Me, too.
You know, to humor is one of the pathways to God.
And I thought it would be too comical to write a book about it, so.
Why?
Because forgiveness, you see, is innate to humor.
And if you calibrate, we, in fact, for the book we did, we calibrated all the most best-known humorists, the
most recent times.
They're all around 480 or so, very erudite.
All the best-known humorists calibrate, you know, 460, 475, 480.
And there's something disarming about it.
I think humor is one of the best ways of learning and teaching, and one of the best ways to
experience yourself, because if you take yourself humorously, nobody can get you there.
Once you realize you're stupid and ugly, it's...
You're way ahead of them.
What can they say?
My question is on a personal note.
What is blocking me from manifesting my full abilities as a manual therapist?
As a what?
Manual therapist.
I'm a physical therapist.
What's blocking your talents?
Nothing's blocking your talents.
Why do you think something's blocking your talents?
Classes that I take, advanced classwork, I'm often able to manifest picking up restrictions
and doing the techniques, but in my own clinic, I'm lacking.
I feel lacking.
I don't know.
That's a personal, investigative matter we'd have to go into, I don't know why.
Because you may have to do self-confidence or your role, how you picture your role, expectations
of yourself and others.
I don't know.
It would be a complicated question.
We'd have to look at it, you know, take five, ten minutes of asking multiple questions to
try and find out what section it's coming from.
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you.
You've tried prayer?
I have.
I do.
Yes.
Prayer for what?
To be an instrument.
Yeah, but that's not what you're blocked about.
You're blocked about what's standing in your way.
So what you really ask the Holy Spirit is for a miracle of understanding about what
you're holding in mind.
Okay?
What you really want is the understanding, the awareness.
And then all of a sudden you're, and then forget it.
You're driving down the highway and all of a sudden you're like, I don't know.
Okay.
You're going to get to the house and ah, got what it is.
Came out of nowhere.
See?
Thank you.
It comes out of nowhere, like a flying fish.
I don't know what happened to nowhere.
It went someplace.
Yeah.
I forgot what I was going to ask.
If Jesus, did Jesus calibrate at a thousand throughout his entire physical lifetime?
And if so, did he, why was he attacked so viciously?
Why was he what?
Attacked.
Attacked so viciously.
If he calibrated at a thousand.
That didn't exempt you from what you're here for.
He made a commitment, came down from heaven with no previous physical incarnation as a
human.
He served the Lord by giving up physicality.
Right?
So he provided a service to mankind.
He served the truth, yes, for the sake of all of mankind.
From that level, you think giving up your physical body is a great sacrifice?
Thank you.
What is the violet flame I see when I focus on an object?
We can't hear you.
I'm sorry.
The violet flame.
Violet flame.
What is it?
I don't know what that refers to.
The Pentecostal flame you're talking about?
A fire, a violet fire.
When I focus on things, I see a violet fire.
Probably a healing energy.
I don't know.
Okay.
We'd have to research it specifically.
I thought you knew everything.
Dang it.
Well, it's just like the last lady said.
You know, everyone has their unique little thing.
You have to kind of, you have to kind of, you have to kind of, you have to kind of,
you have to kind of, you have to kind of, you have to kind of, you have to kind of, you
have to kind of, you have to kind of, you have to kind of, you have to ask several questions.
Yeah, we're going to have to check it out, you know, individually.
Okay.
Thank you.
We've only got four minutes, and four people left.
Mm-hm.
Hi.
My experience of myself and a lot of other people I know is that at certain times we're
capable of acting very loving and very forgiving to other people in our relationships.
Please.
other times we're still capable of having intense anger, rage, and all sorts of negative emotions.
Does any of that have any bearing on one's overall consciousness level?
The fluctuating moods and emotions don't change it.
What changes it is the spiritual will.
Your calibrated level of consciousness and your karma is dependent upon the spiritual will.
So your spiritual will may be aligned in a certain way
and you've got some karmic whatchamacallits coming up.
One of the karmic propensities you have is that of humanness.
You've got this protoplasmic brain and its machinery.
So you transcend each of those things and handle each one as the best you can as it unwinds.
Your life is like a CD and the story is unwinding.
Okay?
And you handle each thing as it comes up.
Okay. Do you have any questions for me?
That's a joke. Thank you.
I knew I was puzzled about something.
I didn't know that my puzzlement shows so badly.
No, it's because I would like to spend half an hour answering each question.
And I'm always frustrated because there's a lot more that can be said.
I'll be brief. I won't be half an hour.
I didn't have a question until you started answering questions.
And it created one.
You spoke of the energy with the weird name.
Yes.
I work for an agency that works with difficult to manage children.
Some of them are the worst of the worst.
Some of them are sexual predators.
And I had an experience with one of these where he was at a dark place, a low place.
And there were a couple of times when I felt him drawing energy from me.
And then as he came out of that and started to go into the abuse cycle,
and we were worried that he was going to, well, they call it make a bad choice, but offend.
I made a connection with him, which I took to be very negative.
It was very scary.
And I was able to feel what he felt as a predator.
And I had been taught that it was like a wolf on the hunt, but it wasn't that at all.
It was a pulling from right here.
And it scared me.
I mean, it really was very scary.
And I felt very defiled.
I felt like I had to be cleansed after that.
And I'm wondering now if perhaps it was a backwash of that or a backwash of energy, of that energy.
Why would, I don't understand.
The reason Jesus Christ said to avoid evil is for that reason.
You make a practice of hanging out and trying to help evil.
Yeah.
Do you want to play with evil?
No.
You see what happened.
That's what Jesus Christ said, avoid it.
But how do you help?
Did Jesus Christ tell you to try and help evil?
What did he teach?
He said to avoid evil because you're not equipped to handle it.
Is that why it scared me so?
I wasn't expecting it.
You're asking me a question.
I don't want a recitation.
I'm sorry.
Exorcists themselves are hit by those kind of energies.
It's the risk you take when you work with people of that particular level.
Unless you're extremely well guarded, extremely well guarded, it will sense a vulnerability,
whichever chakra it might be, because you don't know your karmic inheritance from past lifetimes,
what you did to others and what you still owe.
So it's really playing with fire.
Yeah.
Now you got it.
Thank you.
Okay.
Yeah.
You survived this far.
Put it on your head.
Dr. Hawkins, just one last question.
Okay.
Thank you so much.
Okay, sweetheart.
Yeah.
Thank you so much.
I hate to sound so tough with people.
But occasionally you have to.
You have to.
That's a hard question.
Because otherwise people will be in walking around in circles.
Yeah.
Loolooland, Lala Land.
Okay, are we done now?
No, there's one more question.
What?
Oh, here's a question.
Walking up to your walking question.
Yes.
Dr. Hawkins, who are the great Masters on the planet right now,
which calibrate between seven hundred and one thousand?
If you're karmically blessed or equipped,
on to them and they yeah and you run into the experience of such a being see that comes about
through karmic inheritance and you can't name them oh you don't want to name them they get enough
mail as it is if you love them you know you would keep them anonymous i keep them anonymous
i don't have a request to hug you but if you will stand i would like to greet you in the indian way
we acknowledge our teachers by treating their
personage as sacred so if you will strand may i what should i do she wants to stand up
stand up oh thank you very much god bless you i realized the divinity i realized that's the
sacredness and the ancientness of this gesture thank you all right so i thank you all for your
presence i give thanks for that for i am
you
i am truly blessed by your presence amen
oh god
yeah my pen where they oh that's not a pen that's a pointer
i have such a collections of pointers and i keep leaving them in my baggage my luggage and
everywhere what good do they do me when they're home