He's got two handshakes, I saw him do it.
There's a couple of our favorites there.
I've got to say, your book has changed my life drastically.
I've got to be here today.
Thank you.
Good to see you.
Hi.
I have a fortune cookie for your collection.
Oh, thank you.
My fortune cookie collection.
We have a fortune cookie message for today.
Oh, a fortune cookie?
Of course.
Thank you.
Good morning, good morning.
Yeah, yeah.
Let's see, what about the side room?
There's people there too.
I'm going to come upstairs and say hello to all of them.
When we get a break.
Did we miss anybody?
Good morning.
We don't want to miss anybody.
Okay, I've got to run, run, run, run, run, run.
Run, rabbit, run.
Do you want help with the stairs?
Can you read this?
You will never regret the present.
You live to its fullest.
Okay.
Well, we'll see if this is true.
What do you have to do to get the music to stop?
I have a new fortune cookie just given to me.
You will never regret the present if you live it to the fullest.
.
Calibrated at 345, which is better than 90% of the world's literature, huh?
A fortune cookie life is a good life.
345 is a good energy.
It's one of enthusiasm and goodwill and things that are no longer fashionable,
but for spiritual people is certainly the beginning and the essence of it all.
We always start the lecture with the same thing.
To a crowd like this, the intellect is the main problem.
Being cruel to your neighbors, lying routinely,
cheating your employer is not usually a problem in a group like this.
Area addition is why people are here, because they have learned.
So the intellect, which then is how we learn about spiritual truth
and it's where we get attracted,
it then eventually becomes the barrier.
And so the lectures have been considerably oriented towards
how to transcend the intellect.
How to transcend the intellect.
There's a humming noise. What's the humming noise?
That machine. Oh.
Okay. Well, modern life.
You put up with hums and buzzes and .
When I first moved away from the big city,
I couldn't even stand the sound of a refrigerator.
I literally unplugged the refrigerator
and lived in absolute silence.
So how to transcend the limitations of the ego.
So today we're talking about positionality,
positionality and how to transcend positionality.
So the fastest way is to understand,
to jump the whole paradigm of the intellect
and see how it is that things come in,
how it is that things happen in the first place.
Because we know that the Newtonian paradigm of reality,
of causality, the explanation of causality
sounds appealing, but it only calibrates around 450,
which is not exactly astronomical.
That means respectably intelligent and it's plausible.
So causality violates, however,
the principle of post hoc ergo propter hoc.
Just because one thing follows another
doesn't mean that that which preceded it is its cause.
That is, of course, the downside of modern society.
So science, the world of the intellect,
calibration levels 450, 460,
of course, have been the great blessing to society.
It's rather recent and evolutionary,
the intellect predominantly has only been really dominant
for, oh, 2,000 years or so,
which is just barely yesterday.
So it still hasn't sunk in.
So large parts of the world calibrate, you know,
not only below the 400s, they calibrate below the 200s.
85% of the world's population calibrates below 200.
And here in an audience like this,
is worrying about how to get through the 400s.
So it is a somewhat select group.
So through the intellect, then,
we hear about spiritual reality,
and now our problem is how to transcend the intellect,
how to experience reality without processing it sequentially
through the left brain and nominalizing everything,
how to transcend the Newtonian paradigm of reality.
And so what we've been doing is giving the lectures backwards,
and we find that's very effective.
We start with the ending of how things actually come about,
and then the intellect figures out subsequently.
Everything happens of its own, of its own nature.
What you see happening is the consequence of the effect
of that which you are within a given context,
within an infinite context, which we'll cover over the slides.
Everything comes about spontaneously,
spontaneously as a consequence of that which it is.
You can picture everything and everyone
as though they're a magnetic field.
This magnetic field draws to you
that which is of your own level of consciousness.
There's nothing out there causing anything at all.
We see the downside of it in the broken window principle.
The minute there's a broken factory window in a neighborhood,
the energy goes out.
We don't care, we're not responsible,
and the whole neighborhood goes down.
Nothing causes that to happen.
It's just that that energy attracts mice,
cockroach, crime, drugs, prostitution,
homicide, suicide.
And degeneracy of one kind or another.
Nothing is causing that to happen.
The field is attracting it.
So you become an energy field.
As you let go of negativity,
you become, you are that field,
and you draw to yourself
that which is a consequence of the field.
Everything comes about as potentiality becoming actuality.
You have a potential.
You put that in a powerful field,
now the potential actualizes.
Without the field, it's dormant.
The seed lays there, the seed lays there.
Then the rain, the warmth, and the sun comes up,
it comes, it doesn't force the seed to do anything,
but the seed of its own propensity,
because that's its karmic potential,
now responds to favorable conditions,
and it shines forth.
Nothing is causing it to do that.
It's not within the realm of cause.
Phenomena, then, are the consequence
of potentiality becoming actuality
when the conditions are right
because of the infinite power of the field.
All that lives, lives within an infinite
field of infinite power.
The slightest potentiality,
when put into a field of infinite power,
becomes an actuality.
That is the consequence of divinity.
Without divinity, you have to resort
to the Newtonian paradigm of causality
to explain phenomena.
So if you picture divinity,
the infinite field of consciousness,
which is what our research is all about,
there is an absolute non-variable.
That's the field of consciousness.
Like a giant electromagnetic field, then,
everything within this field of infinite power
aligns itself,
according to that which it is.
As you can see, the configuration,
where it happens to be,
and that's the karma of the spirit.
Karmic consequence, then,
is like a little iron filing
or a little molecule.
Every decision,
every action, then,
affects the position
of all these little molecules
and this little iron filing.
Shapes like this, it gets bigger
with good intention and it gets smaller
with bad intention.
And where it is in the field
is the consequence of the infinite power
of the field.
Therefore, the field is not arbitrary
to an ignorant person
that gets pulled this way,
blames it on the field.
God hates me.
God condemns me.
And there you have the Old Testament
of this capricious,
sort of mentally ill,
divinity,
suffering from paranoia,
sensitivity,
jealousy,
power,
position,
and prone to favoritism,
gets even with you.
That's a pretty negative paradigm,
but it dominated society
until the present day.
Actually, that's pretty high caliber
compared to some other spiritual teachings.
Spiritual, in quote,
teachings prevalent on the planet today.
All comes about as a result
of that which it is.
And therefore, the pathway
to the realization of truth
is really the mystical pathway.
It's really the way of non-duality.
Duality will limit you to the 400s,
which is the world of theology,
epistemology, ontology.
The world of science.
Gosh, you don't dare cough
with a microphone on.
I'm knocking my ears out.
That was a jet plane going over.
It was just a cough.
Sorry I said that, Lord.
In case I was wrong, you know.
There is a big, jealous, paranoid God,
and he does hate you, David.
Well, so be it then.
Because we were created with intelligence,
we were created as spirit,
and therefore,
the karma of having been created in itself
gifts us with an intellect
and a spiritual will,
and we then follow that spiritual will
in blind faith
and trust in truth.
So the pathway of truth is what we teach.
Devotional non-duality is
the way to God,
avoiding the intellect
and form of religion, etc.,
to follow through the pristine purity
of consciousness itself
to where it leads us.
Where it leads us.
That takes courage,
and takes fortitude,
takes inspiration,
takes information,
information,
which has traversed that pathway.
And if one falters,
then I suggest the 91st Psalm.
I love the 91st Psalm,
and you only need the one Psalm in your life,
the 91st Psalm.
And the Psalm also says that,
the Lord is one's fortress,
and that his strength is his truth.
So the pathway of truth then does not violate
old spiritual tradition either,
but merely puts it into operation.
Anybody who falters,
I got a couple suggestions
along the way.
When you're depressed,
you get a copy of
the military tattoo,
which was presented in Scotland
once a year,
or you watch Riverdance.
If you're still depressed
after watching Riverdance,
or watching the Edinburgh Castle tattoo,
you do need a psychiatrist.
Because when soul is somehow impaired,
there must be something obstructing it.
Yeah.
So the way to God then is through
the joy of the present.
And what is the joy of the present?
The joy of the present is,
the full experience of the presence
of the source of one's creation.
Consequently,
one needs nothing outside oneself.
There's nothing out there
that is needed.
The world insists that you eat things
and do all that kind of thing,
but that's their problem.
Within yourself,
you really don't need anything at all,
being complete and total.
So that gets rid of wantingness,
desiringness,
greed,
and takes you out of the solar plexus
right away.
Now,
we have a number of new people here,
perhaps,
who have not been to the lectures before.
Is that so?
Oh, wowie, wowie.
And there's more people upstairs.
So,
all right,
we always say something new at every lecture,
and have a new slide,
you know,
that's very instructive.
And we also recapitulate
what's been said.
But every time we recapitulate it,
of course,
you hear it differently,
because
having heard it once before,
you become different than you were.
So the person,
nobody here has ever heard today's lecture before.
That which you are,
at the end of reading Power Versus Force,
is not the same as started reading it,
yes, you know.
So we're all in the process
of evolution of consciousness.
None of us are exactly,
you know,
are what we were before.
Although the material may look familiar,
it's never been really given before,
and I've never said it before,
nor has the person in the chair ever heard it before.
So every moment is,
every moment is startlingly new.
Yeah.
And every moment is excitingly inspirational.
So I have to keep a lid on myself
to not get over-exuberant.
And so we will recapitulate
the slides,
but this time with a difference.
I want to start with the newest slide at the end.
Can we do that with this spotter machine?
We have a spotter machine,
and I also have a new
and wonderful...
Okay, so we'll start with the new slide,
because it demonstrates what we just got through saying.
We calibrated the level of consciousness.
I just finished this book,
which has been agonizing work for two years,
and passed out about 7 o'clock last night.
I said, I think we finished the book,
and then it's the last thing I remember.
But one thing we did,
was we correlated level of consciousness,
because this book had to do with looking at the world,
which was quite interesting,
because back in the 70s when I left the world,
I totally ignored it.
Never read a book,
never watched television,
didn't own a TV,
and I didn't know President Reagan had been shot or anything.
And now to do this book,
I had to recalibrate everything in the world.
So it was a grand tour of the world.
We calibrated every writer, songs, music, movies, philosophies,
places, positions, spiritual teachers,
whoa, everything from the Eiffel Tower
to...
to all the things I've forgotten about,
there's so many.
Anyway, so what we did was we calibrated,
correlated the level of consciousness
with the rate of unemployment,
the rate of poverty,
the rate of happiness,
and the rate of criminality.
As I said, things are not caused externally.
Nobody forces you to throw trash on the street.
Nobody forces you to do that.
That's forced.
No, you choose to do that,
because of that which you are.
So you see, according to the level of consciousness,
a rather astonishing correlation.
At the level of consciousness, the higher levels,
the rate of unemployment is zero,
the rate of poverty is zero,
the rate of happiness is about 100%,
the rate of criminality is almost zero.
I don't know how that guy even got in there.
One of these gurus that takes you for your money,
I guess, got in there.
All right.
So now we see these levels here.
400 to 500.
There you have the world of the intellect.
Rate of unemployment is 2%.
They're probably collecting unemployment insurance,
that's why.
Rate of poverty is 0.5%
due to having made a bad investment, no doubt.
Happiness rate is 70%.
Well, we can't all have 100% of everything, can we?
And the rate of criminality is 2%.
My guess would be white-collar crime.
Yeah.
Probably fall for that.
The temptation of all that money.
So the 2% in the 400s,
let's just see.
That's primarily white-collar crime.
Does everybody know Susan?
Anybody doesn't know Susan?
The right arm.
She's my right arm.
When somebody gets that close to you,
you don't notice them anymore.
I just think she's me.
She is an other.
Oh, yes, it's an other.
The world sees you as separate from me.
All right, so we've probably got white-collar crime there.
The 300s and the 300s,
the rate of unemployment is 7%.
Let's see what percent of these people are just there
because they're collecting unemployment insurance.
Of that percent,
60% are there because...
80%, 90%.
All right, probably 85%
are listed as unemployment
because they're collecting unemployment insurance.
Unemployment...
Unemployment, you know, usually ends
when your unemployment insurance runs out.
Well, you've earned it all these years.
You might as well stay in Florida another week
and see your mother.
When it runs out, you go back to work.
Okay.
So the 300s there, you see,
all this is very low.
Now, when you get to the 200s,
in the 200s,
rate of unemployment is 8%,
and again, probably a good part of that
is just collecting unemployment insurance.
Rate of poverty, 1.5%.
I suspect recently divorce has made a bad investment.
Happiness rate, 40%.
Now you're beginning to see some decline.
Rate of criminality, 9%.
All right, so far, we've been over calibration level 200.
It means over 200 doesn't mean you're a saint.
Doesn't mean you're a saint.
It means you do things that in your eyes
are reasonable, probable, or necessary.
All right, now what happens when we go from below 200?
In the 100s, you see the rate of employment
is now suddenly 50%.
It's not just minimal.
You see a huge jump.
Rate of poverty, 22%.
Huge jump.
Happiness rate drops to 15%.
Rate of criminality now is about 50% of that population.
When you drop below 100,
and we're going to do the scale of consciousness,
next, between 50 and 100,
between 50 and 100,
the rate of unemployment is 75%.
Rate of poverty, 40%.
Happiness is down to 2%.
Everybody's miserable.
The rate of criminality has skyrocketed to 91%,
because criminality is almost the way of life.
You always steal from your employer.
You always pay out your expenses.
You always pick up whatever is not,
and nail down.
When you get below 50,
when you get below 50,
you think,
there aren't any human beings below 50.
Oh, yeah, there are.
They're in today's headlines.
They were in yesterday's headlines.
Below 50.
Unemployment, 97%.
Poverty, 65%.
The rest is supported by the government.
Happiness rate, 0%.
Criminality is a lifestyle, 98%.
It's a lifestyle.
So you see the correlation,
how nothing is causing anything,
but that which you are,
then, manifests itself in the world
in this sort of a style.
There's nothing outside you
causing you to do any of these things.
These are all coming from who you are,
the nature of the decisions,
the way you relate to people,
and your ability to comprehend
spiritual reality, morality, and ethics,
or the lack thereof.
Okay.
So, good.
So we started with the end,
and the last...
So now we can go back to number uno.
We're gonna have questions and answers later,
if anybody has any questions about this.
There's lots of sociologic theories
that calibrate about 180 or 190,
which is always trying to find a blame
or something kind of blame.
Anything that talks about blame,
you know, is fallacious.
What is the field that potentiates
these kind of phenomena?
Oh...
Ego.
We'll get to you later, Bushy.
You know, he wants to be part of the spotlight.
I know you want to be part of the spotlight.
My ego's name is Ego.
Of course he wants to be front and center.
Because that's what he's supposed to do.
He's supposed to want to be front and center.
He's supposed to want to win all the time.
He's supposed to want to be better than you.
He's supposed to hate people
who cut in front of you in traffic.
All right, we'll get to ego later.
So we just want...
You know, we started with,
what are the consequences of understanding
the map of consciousness?
You see, they're quite profound
in every major area of life.
Every major area of life, then,
is affected by a level of consciousness.
So to just recapitulate it, then,
we looked at what life is like from 200 and up.
We see a high rate of happiness,
low rate of unemployment, low rate of crime, etc.
And then we see at consciousness level
a really dramatic change.
I mean, we go from very low numbers
to extremely high numbers.
We could spend the whole lecture just on this,
and when I first devised this script,
devised this scale,
I was giving lectures at a rehab place,
and we did spend...
We'd spend a couple hours on just this scale,
discussing each level, discussing each level,
because recovery from a great many human conditions,
addictions being one of them, alcoholism,
and various others,
then is based on going above level 200,
the first step in the 12-step program,
any one in which you accept responsibility.
The minute you accept responsibility,
you're already on the way over level 200.
Therefore, the difficulty with blame,
trying to blame conditions on external conditions,
is blame you instantly are divesting yourself
of responsibility, making yourself the helpless victim,
and you're instantly below level 200.
Theories below 200 do not help the people below 200
for which the theory is devised in the first place.
No, it gets abused and misused and exploited.
Okay, so, learning to be responsible then,
willing to say,
yes, I'm the one that said that,
and I'll take the consequences for it.
Yes, I'm the one.
Takes you over 200.
What happens over 200 now
is your, you might say, your magnetic charge changes.
Now, you stop pulling rats, mice, cockroaches,
and various bad viruses into your life,
and you start pulling healing energies,
and the people with whom you congregate change dramatically.
Change dramatically.
When I was director of a big rehab place
here in Arizona,
I'd say, how are you doing?
Well, I knew already,
because I knew who they were hanging out with.
Who they were hanging out with
told me exactly where they were at,
whether they'd given up gang colors or whatever.
So you become different,
and now you live a different life.
You hang out with different people.
You think different thoughts.
You have different standards and values.
Frankly, you're quite a bit different than the people,
the people above and below are really quite a bit different,
remarkably different.
And as you get to the lower levels,
extremely difficult
for people above 200 to even comprehend that
and accept it as a reality,
which is today's headlines, of course.
The inability to comprehend that people literally
live in this level down here,
below the level of the Komodo dragon.
My friend, the Komodo dragon,
calibrates around 40.
.
And the big headline makers in today's news
calibrate less than that.
So it's very difficult for people to become realistic
in how to handle those kind of energies,
and the downside of that has shown itself
in the last couple of world wars, etc.,
where the inability of somebody who lives up here
to even comprehend that it's down here.
You sign a peace treaty with Adolf Hitler,
you go back home,
you tell him,
and he says,
you know what,
you're not the only one in our time,
and Hitler thinks you're an idiot.
.
Spirituality is naivete, especially when you get into the 500s.
You think if you're just nice to people, they're going to be very sweet with you.
They will, and then behead you.
The fellow that walked into the Komodo dragon cage, I was going to kick out of him.
I think he was without his shoes or he had sandals on.
He goes to visit this Komodo dragon in his cage.
Oh, God, he got away with it.
All right, so the downside of spirituality is naivete.
It's not really denial.
It's incomprehensible.
You don't take it into consideration because to you it's not a possibility.
Other people live that way around the clock all the time,
and your worst imagination is nothing compared to what they think about all day.
Make up the worst story you can think of.
I'll tell you, that's peanuts.
That's not even jacks for openers.
Okay, so I haven't really.
I emphasize that because it's not a matter of fear.
It's a matter of caution and awareness.
It's a matter of spiritual discernment,
not to go into denial about the fact that this world is a whole panorama.
Fifty percent of the population in the United States calibrates below for 200.
Forty-nine percent exactly.
Currently, 49 percent.
Let's see if that's so or not.
I don't know.
It might have changed since yesterday.
Forty-nine percent is still correct.
Wow.
Okay.
Well, that's better than it was.
So 51 percent of people in the United States are integrists, have crossed this line,
and you speak to them one way.
Those people comprehend what you're saying.
You say, well, that's illegal, unethical, or immoral.
All these people go, oh.
Below 200, they say, so?
I mean, we're supposed to win, ain't we?
Give your life through your teeth.
Buy the votes.
I mean, you're supposed to win.
Bring home the bacon.
All right.
So there are almost two different societies.
You see that?
And on spiritual people, I don't think I've been educated about that.
I don't know.
There's teachers that really tells you how the hell to survive in this world, you know.
They'll tell you to leave it, join a monastery.
Well, there's crooks in the monastery, too.
You come back, and you had 32 grapes.
Now there's 28.
It means being conscious and aware.
It means caution and wisdom rather than denial and naivete.
All right.
So leading people into the 500s and not forewarning them sets them up.
And we see it all the time because I can give you a list of 20 well-known gurus
who all got into the mid-500s.
And then we're shot down, shot down, not prepared for what you're going to attract
because the sharks see that you're walking around in a happy, trusting, bliss state.
And then they head for you.
So a chink in your armor, that of denial, the archetype of the spiritual student.
You start out naivete, the innocent maiden.
So we all learn of spirituality.
We go to the bookshop.
We buy all these wonderful books.
We go ooh and ah.
We burn incense, play hymns, live with flowers and butterflies.
You see it all around Sedona.
This is butterfly land.
If we all just pray for peace, they'll stop shooting us down.
The last thing he said before he was riddled with bullets, you know.
No, spiritual intention is what affects the field.
Your actions, the world.
You know, don't.
They don't have any real effect on the world.
It's your spiritual intention to be loving and forgiving towards all human beings,
to see all of life is sacred, and to not be stupid about it at the same time as what I'm saying today.
I don't know many spiritual teachers that advise you not to be stupid.
Anybody?
Not to be a retarded dumb-bill about it, 49% in America live here, 85% in the world live here.
And in fact, a large percentage of them not only live not here, but actually down here.
The minute you turn your back, they'll cut your throat.
And they think they're serving God by doing it, yeah?
So, never be fooled into complacency and denial or stupidity.
And therefore, time some teachers said that out loud.
All right, so these lower levels, as you can see,
have an inner...
Unhappiness, they have an extreme downside, but if that's what you are,
and that's what you've become, that's good enough.
If the more people you kill, the better, then the more people you kill, the happier you are.
So, it doesn't say they're not happy.
Killed 50 infidels today.
Hey, boy!
End of the class, right?
All right, so it's like a different world, different world.
So, you have to be aware of what world you're living in.
What your reality is, and realize that your reality does not match that of everyone around you, all right?
Jumping above 200 then transforms how you experience,
because now you've moved up the trust, which is its strength.
Trust of what?
Trusting of the truth and love and all these things up here will take you the way you want to go.
Above 200, you see there's one comfortable area called neutrality.
And when you let go, wanting to control things, when you stop wanting to dominate them,
you become pretty independent.
So, here you're happy because you're prideful, here you get a lot of energy out of anger.
These are all emotional states.
You get into real comfort when you've let go of everything in the world,
and you hit a level called neutrality.
Neutrality is okay if it happens, okay if it doesn't.
It works.
It looks to the world like indifference.
Indifference is something different.
That's apathy.
This is apathy.
Detached is not the same as apathetic.
And all spiritual pathways, especially non-dualistic, Buddhic pathways, teach detachment.
So, detachment is a very comfortable field right here called release.
There's a technique that teaches releasing.
And it is a very effective technique in which you just let go of your attachment to things.
And like all spiritual techniques, however, for them to be effective,
it has to be pretty much a lifestyle, a way of being in the world.
So, it's a way of being detached, just like forgiveness is a way of being in the world,
seeing the beauty of everything.
Spiritual progress, then, is pretty much a continuous way of being in the world.
And I compare it to, really, to a mudra.
It's not so much something you do, but it's something that you are.
It's a way of being in the world.
As a spiritual student, it's not necessary to do all kinds of crazy things.
It's only a way of being in the world.
It's like what you have become.
You become, like a mudra, positioned thusly.
Open, you might say, asking by one's position, the will of God,
the input of the higher beings of the universe,
appealing to the celestial dimension,
that here I am is thy servant, O Lord, and O thee do I trust.
That is sort of the background.
That way you sort of float up through the levels of consciousness
instead of having to fight your way.
It's God's problem, right?
Here I am.
I'm like the dandelion seed, Lord, floating in the wind.
I am thine.
To a certain degree, that's true.
To a certain degree, it's fairy-fairy.
Because it's also extremely hard work.
It's hard work.
Each of these then has its downside that we experience as spiritual work.
The willingness to let go, gain and greed, anger, resentment, blame.
And so we struggle with ourself.
And the reason we struggle with it is because that's a positionality
based on our perception.
That's how we see it.
And we see things dualistically,
as either-or.
And that is a consequence of the construction of the ego itself.
The evolution of the ego over great expanses of time
have brought us with a mental structure.
The consequence of that mental structure
is that in and of our own selves,
we're unable to tell truth from falsehood.
The human being is unable, innately,
by the very structure of the ego and his mentalization,
to tell truth from falsehood.
That's a fact.
A dreadful fact.
A horrible fact.
That's a fact, oh Lord, resist.
That's a fact.
The human being, unaided,
consciousness, mind,
is unable to tell truth from falsehood.
I don't know how we survived this long.
Well, it doesn't mean the animal's dumb.
Animals are smart.
Animals have survived.
They weren't animals.
So, like the rest of the animal kingdom,
we have survived.
The inability to tell truth from falsehood.
And that's why the discovery of how to tell truth from falsehood
was so mind-boggling.
I frankly was knocked out for at least five years,
not knowing what to do about it,
because I got the full comprehension
of the significance of that
and its potential impact on human life
and spiritual life in particular.
By design, by design,
karmically, by inheritance,
by evolution,
the human mind is unable to tell truth from falsehood.
If that don't give you humility,
nothing will.
Consequently, the spiritual teachers throughout all of time
have said,
unaided, without the help of a guru or a teacher,
it's impossible to reach the highest truth.
Only, in other words, truth can reveal itself,
can reveal itself.
But without the revelation of that truth,
nobody would even know what direction to look.
Now, we've shared with the world
the way in which everyone can find out for himself
what the truth is.
Someone is not dependent on a teacher.
However, a teacher having been the root
can save you time, so it's practical.
It's practical to have a teacher.
Save you all kinds of time wandering through the desert.
And so, if you have a map,
it really speeds up your expedition.
That's the main value of a teacher to me,
is shares the map, having traced it,
you know, like Marco Polo.
He went all the way to China,
and he came back, and he told you how it was,
and he told you how to get to China.
And, of course, a lot of people thought he was an idiot
or smoking something weird.
People have slanty eyes,
and imagine his story when he got back to Europe,
where he didn't even know that China existed.
So, Marco Polo was an explorer.
So, to me, a spiritual teacher is an explorer,
having been to China,
can tell you the best map, you know,
and that's the value of the spiritual teachings.
So, these are the lower levels,
which we're all familiar with.
They're all labeled.
They all have emotions,
and they calibrate from one to a thousand.
Bacteria calibrate at one,
and the greatest avatars that have ever lived
calibrate at one thousand.
The human nervous system cannot tolerate
anything over a thousand.
In fact, anything from 700 and up
is extremely agonizing.
People say,
how come women are the great avatars,
and now they're women?
From our research,
we got was that the woman's nervous system
cannot handle the voltage.
It's just you've got to have a stronger,
heavier duty body,
and get reborn as a man,
and get fried when you get up over 700.
You don't have to get there through the physical domain,
you know.
You go to the celestial domain
and move from there on up.
So, I agree with the Buddha,
lotus land Buddhism,
that becoming enlightened in this world
is extremely difficult,
and it's best to reach the celestial realms
in Christianity, heaven,
and Buddhism, lotus land.
The gravity here in this domain is so intense.
Therefore, you live a life
the best you can according to spiritual principles,
and when you leave the physical body,
you're attracted to the celestial realms,
and from there you can move on up.
From there you can move on up,
and you don't have to overcome the gravity
of the intense negativity of this world,
because karmically one has earned the right
to move on to a different realm,
different realm.
We call those the celestial realms,
celestial realms.
All right.
So, when you go out of body,
you want to be as loving as possible,
and at 540, of course,
you have unconditional love.
So, the practical goal in this lifetime,
as Jesus said and the Buddha and everybody else,
is to be as loving as you can
at all times towards all people,
and reach for unconditional love.
So, what Jesus Christ said was,
avoid anything that makes you go weak with kinesiology.
That's what he said.
In the worlds of religion,
from here on down is simply sin.
Oh, okay.
How do you avoid sin?
Well, I think the best way to avoid sin
is to know what it is,
to study it,
to be able to recognize it,
to learn techniques to traverse it.
And traditionally, of course, they have been,
through prayer, surrender, meditation,
all the traditional pathways to God.
All right.
So, so much for that for now.
We'll move on to the next thing.
And, of course, you notice,
you did notice that God was at the top of the chart,
and that the other place was at the bottom,
which a lot of people don't have confused.
All right.
Guilt, suffering,
the downside of Gothic Christianity,
you might say,
penance, sackcloth, ashes,
out of guilt, shame, penance,
oh, miserable.
Here it says miserable.
Miserable, evil, hopeless, disappointing, horrible.
Me?
Oh, you know.
And he blames himself for everything.
And does that take him to enlightenment?
It takes him down to needing Prozac.
You know, it takes him down to the bottom.
God is not found at the bottom of self-hatred,
guilt, remorse.
Those ways are helpful for periods.
It doesn't mean that it won't be helpful for a period.
Karmically, you've got something left undone,
and you're not going to be satisfied.
You, you're not going to be satisfied.
You're not pleasing God.
You're pleasing your own karmic demand
until you've done proper penance for that.
So it isn't that it's wrong.
It's that it has undoubtedly a place for certain people,
and that is the only way.
The only way they can karmically undo certain debts.
I myself have gone through it in this lifetime.
Yeah.
And in the middle of the operation,
remembering exactly what the circumstance was
and what I was paying back.
I did that to him,
and now I experience back what I had caused.
So, therefore, it's not that it's useless,
but as a primary pathway to God,
it has a limited application
to only specific karmic situations.
So let's go on to the next slide.
Oh, yes.
And this is below 200 is force.
Above 200 is power.
And the mathematics of it was beyond me.
So what I did was I estimated the power of thought
using kinesiology.
And we got the difference.
The main significant thing was the difference
in power in microwatts between a loving thought
and a negative thought.
It was tremendous.
It was significant because people worry
about their negative thoughts.
However, negative thoughts,
and don't be taking advantage of this either,
are relatively weak.
Weak. Weak.
That was good. Weak. Wow.
Relatively weak.
Loving thoughts are extraordinarily powerful.
I mean, really, in almost a wholly different dimension
they're so powerful.
So you can be nasty all day
and have one loving thought.
People below 200 will use that
as the pathway to hell.
All right.
So anyway, George, what did you do now?
She snuck in on me.
What did you do?
Anyway, what George did was figure it out
in microwatts using mathematics.
I did it with kinesiology.
He did it with mathematics.
And this is the little thing.
This is the level of energy.
And you see up to 200,
and then it begins to exhilarate.
Then 500, you see suddenly it really exhilarates.
At 540, it would exhilarate even more.
And from 600 up, it goes to infinity.
Consciousness level is 600 and up.
Therefore, the more evolved you can be
and the more benign and loving you can be
towards all of mankind,
you're benefiting all of mankind
because you're affecting the field.
Because of your intention.
A very powerful prayer, you know,
by a multitude of people influences the field.
The field then lifts all the ships at sea.
You understand?
Using causality, it takes a lot of energy
to try and lift one battleship, right?
A lot of energy.
Try lifting one battleship.
10,000 men can't do it.
And the collective intention of mankind
raises the level of the sea six inches,
and all the ships at sea are lifted.
What can we do for world peace?
Be the most loving human being you can.
Hold the whole world in your lovingness thoughts
because the power of intention
then affects the overall energy of the field.
That's Wayne Dyer's latest book, Intention.
As I said, the last chapter is free on the Internet.
I read the last chapter.
So, all right, intention then.
We'll get to the quantum mechanics of that.
But, you know, from a mathematical engineering viewpoint,
this is how the calibrated levels of energy come out.
And the distribution of the world's population,
which we talked about before,
the great majority of mankind,
you see the huge quantity of mankind then.
The masses live below consciousness level 200.
As you get up to 250, as you get up to 310,
look how small it gets
when you get up to a Chinese cookie fortune.
Where's my Chinese cookie fortune?
You'll never regret a day
that you've lived to your fullest potential.
So, you see, people joke at it,
but once you're sensitive to wisdom,
you see wisdom where it is.
You see truth where it is
because you're sensitized to truth.
So, at a higher level,
you see wisdom where it is.
At a higher level,
you see the wisdom and the truth of that.
This is at 345, huh?
You can see that a Chinese fortune cookie
contains greater wisdom
than that held by almost all of mankind.
Who thinks the nastier you are,
the quicker you steal it,
the faster you stab them,
the more successful you will be.
The Chinese fortune cookie says
happiness is in the other direction.
All right.
Why doesn't the world disintegrate
and blow itself up
if there's that much negativity?
And it's because the 15%
who calibrated above 200,
these people here,
counterbalance.
Oops.
Counterbalance.
Karen did this graphics.
The 15% cali...
They're white for some reason.
And this is dark.
This must be the good guys
and these are the bad guys, right?
Anyway.
This 15% then counterbalances
the entire 85%.
Right now the consciousness level
of all of mankind
is at 207.
We know it was 75 at Neanderthal man,
about an 80s homo erectus.
At the time of the birth of the Buddha,
the consciousness level of all mankind
collectively was 90.
At the time of the birth of Jesus Christ,
the collective consciousness
of all of mankind was 100.
It then crept up slowly over the centuries
during the 1600s, 1400s,
time of the Black Plague, 1800s.
By the late 1900s, 1987,
around in there,
at the time of the harmonic concordance,
it jumped from 190 to 205.
People picture the second coming of Christ
as a physicality.
I picture it
as consciousness going from falsehood to truth.
Let's see.
The second coming of Christ
revealed itself as the advance of consciousness
above the line to 207, resist.
The second coming of Christ,
in my understanding,
has already happened.
The dominion of truth over falsehood
is what Christ is about, correct?
If he physically reappeared, what would he do?
Be on TV?
You know what I mean?
If you appear in a physicality,
the world gets polarized.
However, if divinity expresses itself
as a rise in the level of the sea,
there's no way you can fight it, can you?
The level of the sea has risen.
So to my understanding,
the physicality in a primitive society was necessary.
You have to have a human being
who looks like so-and-so, lives there,
and is called that,
and says so-and-so.
In a more advanced society,
the difficulty of that accomplishment, to me,
would be almost impractical.
Therefore, one comes back
as a rise in the level of the sea.
Why?
Because as people themselves
become christened with the life energy,
become, I can't think of the right word,
aligned with the teachings of the great avatars,
then the collective spiritual energy lifts the sea.
And the purpose of the great avatars
is accomplished silently
because it has no enemy.
The rising of the sea has no enemy.
A specific entity living in Columbus, Ohio,
six foot three, saying all these crazy things,
would probably not survive long in today's world.
All right.
So, the other thing we talk about,
we talk about non-duality.
The propensity of the mind to divide everything,
and then, by using an arbitrary point of reference,
seeming to create a duality of opposites.
A duality of opposites.
As we saw in the calibrated levels of consciousness,
they are not opposites.
Above 200 is not the opposite of below 200.
Below 200 is the absence of spiritual truth.
200 and up is its presence,
and finally its dominion, its domination.
So, it's important because a group like this
has to transcend the elect to understand
how dualistic perception occurs.
It tends to take an arbitrary thing and say,
this is long and this is short.
As you can see, this has no long and short.
Because I could say,
well, now this is long and this is short.
There's no shortness or longness in this pointer at all.
Gil made this for me for the lectures.
It's really great.
So, as you can see,
it has no short, short or long.
That's all in your mind.
Res interna.
Res cogitans is the world of thinkingness.
Res externa is the world the way it is.
Descartes' famous quote.
Res interna. Res interna.
The reality of inner mind is one thing.
The way the world is is something else.
The fallacy is to presume.
The way you think is the way the world is.
And that's the source of duality altogether.
To assume that this is divided into two parts of unequal length,
just because I think it,
you can see the egotism.
So,
duality then is the egotism of res cogitans,
the thinkingness of the mind,
making the jump, projecting into the world and say,
therefore, the world is that way.
There's nothing more egoistic than the mechanistic reductionist
who says, unless I can weigh it and measure it, it's not real.
That's what you call an inflated egotism.
It's intellectual pomposity.
No such reality is even possible.
Because I think a certain thing doesn't mean that's the way the world is.
So, humility says this is the way it appears to reason,
which leaves what the reality is open for further research.
So, the most common examples are then heat.
The world divides it into hot versus cold.
This ends hot, this is cold.
And you see in reality there are no opposites of hot and cold.
There is a lot of heat, less heat, less heat,
less and less heat.
So, this is important because the kinesiologic test
and all what we talk about truth.
Truth has no opposite.
Like heat, it's present to a variable degree.
This is the avatar's truth, the great spiritual teachers,
and then it comes down.
Here we call it falsehood.
It isn't falsehood.
It's just the absence of heat.
So, these are ways of speaking.
Hot and cold are convenient, you know, convenient operationally.
But in spiritual understanding then it becomes a roadblock
because you get stuck with trying to transcend good and evil and all that.
So, there's only one variable, the presence or the absence of heat.
There is no opposite of truth then.
Truth is present or it's absent.
The kinesiologic test, what we're testing,
we're not getting yes versus no.
We're getting yes or not yes.
Here we have desirability coming out of the solar plexus
in which we project our desires onto the world.
We say, isn't that precious, what you might call a diamond or something?
Isn't it valuable?
Isn't it wonderful?
And then finally, you don't care about diamonds anymore.
And you'd say, you know, they're a pain in the neck.
And then finally, I don't know, you'd say they're repulsive.
Yeah, there's probably some ugly diamonds in the world.
Unpolished diamond, oh, that's ugly.
Goodness, this is desirability.
We say at the top they're heavenly, they're good, very good, sort of okay.
As this diminishes, we say they're horrific.
So, that's the world we're in.
That's the world of today's headlines.
You know, very good, is he very good?
Or is he awful?
We're not talking about the world.
We're talking about how you see the world.
Politics, how you see what's out there is not what's out there.
It's how you are seeing it.
Either the person is a hero or they're horrible.
But you can see it's not out there.
It's how you're seeing it.
The best example, of course, is light.
The presence of light is overwhelming.
And the absence of light we call darkness.
So, they are not opposites.
That's the important thing.
When you deal with truth, it's there to a variable degree.
Humility tells you then that res cogitans, the domain of the mind of thinkingness, is not res externa.
So, when you say, so-and-so out there is so-and-so, you can see the lack of humility.
What you mean is, to me, so-and-so seems so-and-so.
To me, so-and-so looks like so-and-so.
Of course, that depends on how I grew up, my education, my level of consciousness, intellectual erudition, IQ, family, ethnic origin, etc.
Those capacities, then, are increased in certain people in the world.
The capacity to see truth is dependent on so many things.
It would take an all-day lecture to get into all of them.
Neuroanatomy, the way the neurons have, you know, early in life, to be exposed to classical music early in life.
To be exposed to music early in life.
Classical music.
To learn how to play chess.
To learn martial arts.
These are all things that profoundly change.
These are all things that profoundly affect the neuronal connections and will have a high impact on later behaviors.
Later behaviors.
We found with research that exposure to classical music as a child, plus a religious upbringing, and chess is good for one more point, reduces the crime rate totally by 91%.
The crime rate in people who are brought up with classical music, some kind of religious upbringing, it doesn't matter what it is.
They have a 90% less crime rate.
And if you add playing chess, it's even less than that.
91% less crime rate.
So spiritual truth, then, if you're brought up in its presence, or its expression as aesthetics, the love of beauty, affects the neuronal, as you see, because as you grow up you get millions more neurons than you need.
And they're constantly being weeded out.
So if you don't use them, you lose them.
That's a fact.
Exposure to beauty and the love of beauty, the appreciation of beauty in whatever form, arts, dance, music, ballet, opera, whatever, then profoundly affects.
Also, exposure to classical music in early childhood increases mathematical capacity as well.
So therefore, when I grew up they were called long hairs.
We had a minority group called long hairs, yeah.
And we hung out together, and we played chess, listened to classical music, and drank wine in front of the fireplace.
While the rest of the people were doing other things.
Oh, God.
So anyway, it has an effect on your neuronal patterning.
Then, in later life, a 91% reduction in crime.
I mean, it's really pretty profound.
You can see the faith-based programs, which according to our research, decrease the recidivism rate by 35%.
To find some pseudo-political reason to try and remove the faith-based programs, it's the only hope that people with chronic criminality have.
And then it's only 35%.
Remove it, and it drops back to 0%.
The other thing that's very helpful, and I never got what the percentage rate was,
is these people who raise dogs.
What do they call that in prison?
The whole dog program.
The prisoners train dogs to become seeing-eye dogs.
Cell dogs, yeah, yeah.
And some of them, when their term is over, stay in because they still have one cell dog to train.
Let's just see, we never did have time at home to do this.
Cell dogs program, we have permission to ask it in this group, calibrates over 400.
Wow, calibrates over 490, 485.
Cell dogs itself, as a program, calibrates over 485.
It has a positive effect on the recidivism rate.
Reduces it by at least 10%, 20%, 15%, 20%.
Reduces the recidivism rate.
So if you put together a faith-based program and a cell dog program,
then we will recover.
Those who are karmically capable of recovering.
We always forget about karma in the Western world.
In the Eastern world, it's a given.
It's a given part of every formula.
Karma is just automatically understood to be part and parcel of the package.
In the West, it's practically never comprehended, never brought to awareness.
But as you get more evolved, you begin to see.
If you do the Course in Miracles, you see it.
You see that a thing will only go a certain way.
And you see that that is its propensity.
Its propensity is to go that way.
It has its own karmic pattern yet.
It hasn't evolved beyond its own karmic inheritance.
Depends on the mind.
The mind is always very busy.
Everybody complains when they meditate or meditate.
They're unable to get the mind to be silent.
I think you should forget about making the mind silent.
Forget all about that.
You can't make the mind silent.
Except with a bullet through your head.
No, what you do is you look elsewhere.
You look elsewhere.
We might as well do this early because I forgot to do it last time.
And I want to make sure we have it.
And I can drag this all over and I don't know if it will show up on the camera.
But maybe we can't draw it.
Come think of it.
Everybody thinks, they say, look, I sit and first one thought comes along,
then another thought, then another thought.
So what they do is they put their foot down here
and see if they can stop it here so it won't go on to D,
but it goes right on to D.
Toodly, toodly, poo, poo, da, da, da.
Itty, bitty, boo.
Oh.
Ha, ha, ha, ha.
Ha, ha.
The flotsam and jetsam projects by.
Now, the misinterpretation of the Buddha's writings,
and I can confirm this having spoken to the Buddha personally,
the misinterpretation is that the glimpse of eternity is between two thoughts.
How many people here have read that?
Between two thoughts.
How many people have looked between two thoughts?
How many people have glimpsed eternity between two thoughts?
Anywhere it is.
That's a mistranslation.
Mistranslation.
It's not between two thoughts.
It's just because this is the Newtonian idea of causality,
that A is causing B causing C.
So this is the billiard ball theory of thinkingness.
It doesn't happen that way.
It happens like flying fish coming out of the sea.
This flying fish doesn't cause this flying fish.
You understand?
All right.
So the source of thinkingness is each,
here's how it really happens,
is that out of nothingness,
this is nothingness, arises A.
Out of nothingness arises B.
Out of nothingness arises C.
Each one is arising independently.
The reason you can't stop it is because blocking it here,
as you can see, will have no effect in the first place.
Because this is not coming from this.
If it's coming from here,
then you're focusing your attention in the wrong place.
So in that misunderstanding of the teaching of the Buddha,
people focus here,
trying to catch that like in a car.
You're passing the telephone poles,
you're trying to catch in between two telephone poles.
I've been doing this for 34 years,
and I'm still not enlightened.
I guarantee you, do it for another 100 years,
and you won't be enlightened either.
No, what happens after you've done it for 100 years
is God feels sorry for you.
He sends you somebody who says,
Jesus, man, it's down here, not up there.
Oh, after 14 lifetimes, you tell me.
Well, you had a lot of bad karma to work off.
Good karma is earned.
Oh, people hate to hear that.
Potentiality is a gift,
but the actual experience is usually evolutionary.
All right, so you see there's this great reservoir of silence.
This is a silent, formless energy.
Out of the silent, formless energy,
the thought arises,
first as a fuzzy, primordial,
nothing yet, sort of a doggy feeling.
Then it becomes progressively like this, if you watch it.
More dogs.
Then it becomes old Rover.
Then it's old Rover, how he got hit by the bus.
Then how they all cried.
Then how, a long, sad, creepy story comes out of this.
That's called the thinkingness.
That's what people encounter when they try to meditate.
The field of consciousness, then, is silent.
Out of it arises each thought independently.
They seem to have a concordance.
The concordance is in your mind, res interna.
They have no concordance.
You think, well, it's a comprehensible story.
It is to you, because you made it up.
All right.
There's another influence on the field.
There's another influence on the field
that gives this a meaningful coherence,
and that is in Sheldrake's...
Sheldrake's...
What the heck is it called?
Morphogenetic, yeah.
So Sheldrake's morphogenetic field has this here.
You then project this onto the sequence and call it ABC.
The meaningfulness is up here.
There's no meaningfulness down here,
and this is devoid of meaning.
The coherence would be like you have a big fish magnet,
and as the fish come out of the sea,
they're attracted up by this magnet,
but that's only after they've jumped out of the sea.
All right.
Out of nothingness, the mind is silent.
The place to focus, and you can do it all the time.
I'm focusing right there, right now.
There's nothing going on in this mind at all.
I hate to tell you, but there's nothing going on there.
If you focus here, like I'm doing right this minute,
right this minute, this is where I am.
Right in here.
There's nothing going on there.
The field, the field is pulling these thoughts out
because the speakingness is happening of its own.
On the way here, somebody says,
what are you going to talk about today?
I say, how should I know?
I have no comprehension of what is going to happen.
How would I know that?
This is where you watch.
You watch just prior to the thoughts.
Just prior.
Don't get pulled in by the thoughts.
Thoughts are like little magnets.
You focus right here.
Then this thought says,
oh, look at me, I'm so cute.
This thought says, oh my, oh my.
Don't get suckered in by them.
These thoughts, their job is to sucker you in
because if you stop looking there,
you'll become enlightened and their days are over.
An unemployed ego.
By constantly relinquishing them,
surrendering and letting go,
your capacity to do this increases.
Why?
Because these have like a gravity of attraction,
seduction,
and the naive person without spiritual training
easily gets pulled into the story of old Rover,
how he got run over, how we all cried,
that whole melodrama.
The spiritually unsophisticated person then
needs training to detach and ignore
the seduction and the glamour,
the eroticism, whatever this is composed of.
The way you live here in is because
each of these thoughts, as they arise,
does so in a crescendo.
As you watch the thoughts arise,
you'll see they arise, they peak,
and then they fall back into the sea.
If you're trying to control things,
you're living on the front of the wave.
Those people are always living a life of expectancy,
one-upmanship, fear, paranoia, planning.
Like a musical note, it rises to a peak,
the minute you hear it, it's already fading away.
And people who live in the past,
they can't get over old Rover.
There are people that spend their whole life
mourning a loss many years ago.
They're attached to the past.
It's a way of avoiding the reality of the present.
So with spiritual training and technique,
you can diminish the attraction,
the seduction of the fascination of the thinkingness.
You become aware now
that they are coming out of nothing.
All right, so if you focus right here,
focus on the sea and not on the fish.
So you see, you can't be hooked by the attraction
and the novelty of the flying fish.
No, you keep your focus on the sea.
This fish arises, this fish arises, this fish arises.
They're all coming out of the sea independently.
In the sea, nothing's happening.
The sea is still and silent.
This is silent.
There's no knowing what this noise is going to be
till these ears hear it.
I don't know what it's going to say.
Why? Because it happens of its own.
Because instead of coming out
of intentionality and a formula,
the field brings forth,
the field brings forth
that which is innate to the field.
And a field created by a group like this
brings forth automatically
out of the speaker the music
for the information they need.
How would I know what anybody out there needs?
I can only guess that.
So having heard it, I would presume
that the field, which is you folks,
and this folk here,
that the field pulls forth
that which is innate to the field
and concordant with the field.
Would you agree?
We're not talking about golf today.
We're not talking about archery.
We're not talking about swordsmanship.
So probably the field then is pulling forth
spiritual information, which is what the world calls.
All right, so let's look at the nature of the mind,
which disappeared.
The minute we turn your back on the mind,
it disappears on you.
How does it keep you busy?
This is your TV set in your head.
It politicizes, it moralizes, idealizes.
And the hypothetical world,
oh, it loves the hypothetical world.
What if?
Yeah, but what if?
And isn't that a slippery slope?
This is the slippery slope world.
We can't give them a break because what if everybody?
What if everybody?
So we'll have to let them die because if we do so and so,
what if everybody?
So it hypothesizes, it romanticizes, it criticizes.
It makes everything emotional and drama.
There is the sitcom.
There is the ladies' afternoon romance.
It emotionalizes and dramatizes.
Life is full of catastrophes.
They say, oh, so and so died.
So?
What about it?
I got news.
100% of the people now present are going to die.
We're all together here.
We're all going to be together there.
Isn't that good?
Another team hits heaven.
Creative Life Sedona team is here.
We're not going to be victimized.
We're not going to catastrophize it.
When we cross over, we're going to say fantastical.
Look for all our friends.
All right.
So the world just likes to rationalize, fantasize, infantilize, intellectualize,
mentalize, glamorize it, demonize it.
Isn't it awful?
Or prize it?
We must have it and then get into endless theories about it.
All right.
So I just want to tell you where this is.
If you watch right now, it's a fact right now.
Right now, there's nothing going on in your mind whatsoever.
Right now, your mind is silent.
It hears.
It hears these things.
That's all.
But your mind is not doing or saying anything.
It like registers.
So you got this, what do we say?
It's like a sound board that picks up the vibrations of what's happening.
But in and of itself, it's silent.
You can discern that in meditation, one focus, one pointed mind.
Having decreased the glamor and the pull of this or some just regular spiritual work,
you more easily keep your attention right here.
See, this is like a magnet pulling on you.
Huh?
Oh, look at the awful story.
Look at the beautiful naked lady.
Look at the headline.
It wants to pull you out of the silent sea and join its entertainment.
That's how it gets its life.
With spiritual training then, you develop a certain intention.
Okay.
Intention will pull you out of that attraction.
If your intention is to.
If your intention is to experience the reality of the invisible field of consciousness itself,
out of which thinkingness arises, you become increasingly aware.
So it's more like focusing on the peripheral rather than the central vision.
It's like being aware of the totality of this room, the totality of what's going on,
and not getting sucked in by somebody fiddling with their buttons next to you.
I mean.
It's like you walk through the world in a contemplative style,
aware of the totality of the environment,
because the totality includes history, includes evolution.
If you walk around Chartres Cathedral,
if you walk around the Louvre,
even if you walk around Creative Life Center,
if you do it in a contemplative style,
you pick up the energy of its creation, its origination,
you pick up the inner onlogy of the architectural style,
it's almost like you see it in your mind.
Therefore, you're becoming aware more of fields rather than content of fields.
So I just wanted to make sure we covered that.
So we'll jump next and then we'll take a break.
No, we should take a break.
We should take a break and we'll reconvene in 15 minutes.
Is that correct?
We'll see you in 15 minutes.
Okay.
Here we go.
Igo wants everybody to pay attention to him.
He wants to be important.
Good ego.
That's how you overcome your ego,
not by demonizing it, but by adopting it.
Ego is doing what he's supposed to be doing.
Good ego.
We'll get to ego later,
because ego represents our own ego.
Well, all right.
Where were we?
We were at nothingness.
Oh, familiar.
So let's see.
Now we were talking about the different contextualization,
different dynamics.
The ego also keeps us very busy with logic and reason,
and therefore the whole Newtonian paradigm,
which is where most of this group originated,
at least in this lifetime.
Intelligent people, interested,
and a lot of education,
which is orderly and logical and atomistic,
and it's a world of cause.
And in that world, everything's pretty much settled,
because it's temporal, it's limited.
And that's the way the mind looks to us.
You see how it's ranked up, as though it's causal,
and as though it is sequential.
And it's measurable.
We could measure this mind, give it an IQ,
and it's caused by neuronal activity.
I calibrated Francis Crick's recent,
Francis Crick,
the research that led to the discovery
of the nature of the double helix,
calibrated at 440.
He now has a research project with UCLA,
neuronal, trying to prove that neurons
are the seat of consciousness,
and the overall intention is to prove
that after death, man has no soul.
Anyway, that calibrates at 130 or something.
It actually calibrates at 130.
All right, so the application to research is,
I can tell you before the research is done
what the answer's going to be,
and the likelihood of success.
And seeing as multi-millions of dollars,
whole faculties or business corporations,
the best brains, are involved in research,
it's nice to know the answer beforehand.
Instead of, we blew it.
The applications of consciousness research, then,
are enormous.
So we can tell by the research design,
the likelihood of success,
just by its calibration.
130, I can tell, is going to fail.
Now, I don't know how much that research costs,
but you better if you research something else,
like flying fish.
Because flying fish deals a little closer to reality,
in that you cannot predict when a flying fish
will arise out of the sea.
It's disorderly.
It's illogical.
It's unpredictable.
I can sit there and watch that same space,
and no flying fish comes out of it.
In the South Pacific, or wherever I was in World War II,
the flying fish would just come out and flop on the deck.
You don't know where they're coming from.
They're unpredictable.
They're free.
They're progressive.
They're diffuse.
Certain things undoubtedly potentiate it.
The temperature of the sea,
the time of the year, the sunlight.
So you get the...
The influence, then.
So in quantum mechanics now,
you're dealing not with the actually predictable,
but the very likely.
The quantum reality is the likelihood.
It's observable,
but it's not really predictable or measurable.
Things in this Newtonian paradigm are sequential.
A follows B follows C.
Over here, they may be simultaneous.
A, B, C all show up at once.
Three flying fish jump out at once.
They may be simultaneous.
So you see potentiality.
So prayer, then, influences the likelihood.
On a scientific basis,
it increases the likelihood
that more flying fish will arise out of this sea.
You increase the potential, but not by causality.
We'll get to the calibrated...
We'll get to the quantum mechanics later,
the Schrodinger equations, et cetera.
One is time-dependent.
One is time-independent.
So, therefore, you don't know
when a flying fish may come out.
It's somewhat chaotic.
You're dealing with possibility,
and it's altered by observation,
altered by observation.
So this phenomena is altered by intention and observation.
If your intention is to witness here,
to locate yourself as here and not as here,
this increases the likelihood
of the success of that meditation.
Okay?
Next one.
The calibrated level of scale...
We'll have to redo this someday.
It goes up to 600.
The reason is practically nobody at all
ever goes beyond 600.
0.0001% or something.
So we thought it's not very practical.
So enlightenment at 600.
The sense of self as reality at 650.
Then you get to the 700s.
Nisargadatta Maharaj, Ramana Maharshi.
You get to the great teachers.
And there you meet what I met at age three.
Age three, I was confronted with this conundrum.
So this was the paradigm that set...
This set the paradigm of this lifetime.
At age three, out of nothingness,
out of nothingness, out of nothingness at all,
there was suddenly a shocking...
I've never gotten over it, really.
Shocking, striking revelation and realization
that I existed.
Wow.
Disappointing.
Age three, out of oblivion,
suddenly, there's this little body,
which I found with mine,
sitting in a wooden cart.
The mind was still silent, but it knew.
It had knowingness.
It knew.
I'm verbalizing it now,
but at age three, you can't verbalize such a thing.
There was the total awareness of existence.
I was not pleased.
More dreadful was that a physicality
called the body went with it.
Not only did you exist,
but you had this thing with it.
Instantly arose a fear of nonexistence.
The knowingness that if you'd come into existence,
hypothetically at least,
it could have come about
that you would not have come into existence.
On the one hand, displeased with existence.
On the other hand, frightened
that it might not have occurred.
The dilemma was the infinite reality,
existence or nonexistence.
In other languaging, as I came to realize in later life,
was it allness or nothingness?
There is one teaching of the Buddha on misunderstanding.
Let's see if it's a misunderstanding before I even state it.
What I'm holding in mind is a misunderstanding resistance.
Thank you.
I found out at age three
that the Hinayana pathway of negation
will take you to the void of nothingness.
The void of nothingness is profound.
Profound.
It is profound.
The knowingness which is beyond mind
is that this is the infinite.
This is the ultimate.
This is the Buddha nature.
Voidness, that is not the ultimate.
If voidness and nothingness
was the ultimate reality,
there would be no one to know it.
And if it was the ultimate truth,
you'd stay there.
But, obviously, at age three,
I learned it was not the ultimate reality,
nor was nonexistence.
So, the discovery is that
no-thingness means allness.
The ultimate reality is no-thingness.
That's correct.
It's beyond.
It's nonlinear.
It does not contain any thing
nor any form.
Beyond form is the infinite reality
which is allness.
Allness.
Because it is devoid of form,
it is present within all form.
Within all form
is the presence of the existence
of the field of consciousness
which is beyond all form.
The ultimate experiential reality,
subjective enlightenment state,
is that the infinite reality
is the totality,
the allness, the divinity,
which can be experienced
as the unmanifest becoming manifest.
The unmanifest becomes manifest
as creation.
Therefore, creation and evolution
are one and the same thing.
What we witness as life
and what we think is change
and what we think is sequence
is serial observation.
It is the serial witnessing
of the unfolding of creation.
So the unmanifest becomes manifest.
Out of the nothingness,
out of the infinite seeming void,
arises.
The unmanifest becomes manifest
as the totality of creation.
Creation unfolds to witnessing
because witnessing is
within the temporal domain
because you think you go
from here to there
that it's sequential.
What is sequential?
Not what's out there,
that's res externa.
What's sequential is res interna,
res cogitans.
Because you see it sequentially,
you say, oh, it must be happening sequentially.
That's hard to understand intellectually.
The unmanifest becomes manifest
because the infinite power of divinity
makes manifest potentiality.
The infinite power of the manifest
becomes manifest as creation.
That creation we witness sequentially
and we think creation is unfolding.
The unfoldingness is a mentation.
There is no unfoldingness,
there's only isness.
The totality of the allness
is the totality of the isness
of all of creation.
So much for creation versus evolution.
Evolution calibrates at 460
and what we just said is probably
I don't know, 980 or something.
950, 960.
What we just said is over 960,
970, 965.
Yeah, I see why.
Okay, the truth of that is 965
and Newtonian causality
evolution theory is about
450 to 460.
You see potentiality becoming actuality.
So the creation is continuous, consequently.
That's why intention is important
because what you're holding in mind
is the prologue to what will come to be
if you keep doing that.
And we always use the example
of the Empire State Building.
Was a vision in somebody's head.
Then that vision is projected into the world,
pulls to it bankers, money, investors, workmen, etc.
Its creation was a potentiality
which becomes an actuality
by the power of intention.
Everybody at the moment of birth
already has a calibrated level of consciousness.
So that karmic propensity then
evolves over great eons of time.
And we all say to get rid of self-pity.
I know you're going to resent my
getting rid of your self-pity, but
Everyone is karmically born
under exactly perfect circumstances.
The karmic propensity
unfolds then as this lifetime
to the maximum possible karmic benefit.
If that means being born with AIDS in Africa
and dying at age three months,
that's the way it happens.
If it means being born to
rich people, however it is,
whatever you needed to learn
is provided.
I grew up in what the world calls
the depression.
And even a couple of pennies
took a lot of energy.
So apparently learning steely-willed
relentless drive was something
I needed to learn because
when you approach the ultimate end of
the process of meditation and all,
it takes a steely, rock-like will.
And learned on the highways of Wisconsin,
it's ten below zero with no electricity
and a blizzard.
No matter what, you grit your teeth and go.
Susan calls it put your head down.
What do you call it?
Put your head down and go, she'll say.
She learned it in Iowa.
Put your head down and go.
That's steely resolved then.
So it'd be like you birthed yourself
in the circumstances that guaranteed
that you would learn this.
And then it may set you up
for such a dramatic fall.
Bang, you hit bottom.
And now God becomes your savior
and your atheism dies.
What does an atheist need to get over?
It sets you up, boy.
Okay.
Hitting bottom.
Oh, everybody moans about it.
So that means we should stop moaning
about what our karmic inheritance is
and say with the wisdom of divinity,
whatever it may seem to be,
which is perception,
is not reality, which is essence.
The essence of everybody's
circumstances of birth
is absolutely perfect.
Wow.
That's a fact.
Over 950.
All right.
So that's a fact.
So much for self-pity and resentment
and blame.
Well, that's the quickest way over 200.
Give up all blame, resentment,
and out-there-ness as being causal.
Because whatever is in your eye,
you attracted it into your eye, see?
Nobody asked you to stand there.
I was thinking about the lady
who was in the paper in New York.
She's walking down the street
and a flower pot falls off the 23rd floor.
Bang.
Hits just her on the head.
Instant death, huh?
What's the karma of being the only one
in a whole crowd to pull a flower pot
onto the top of your head?
That took some intention, right?
However, all those people,
or the stewardess,
you remember there was a Boeing something over there,
the door opened,
and the one stewardess,
like the hand of God,
picked her up and said,
baby, I want you.
So we bemoan what we witness in the world
because the perception,
it looks like tragedy.
The tragedy is what you project onto it.
And the karmic perfection of it,
you don't understand.
So if you say,
whatever I'm judgmental about
or have a negative view,
if I could see the entire karmic pattern,
then I would understand it.
And if I understood it,
then I would not condemn it.
Then I would not condemn it.
There's only certain ways to jump over 200.
And for instance,
war is traditional, traditional.
From a cowardly, callow youth,
you learn pride, self-respect,
for the good of your countrymen,
for the good of God,
for the good of the king,
you walk into a hail of bullets.
When you walk into a hail of bullets,
for a higher purpose,
man, you skyrocket over 200.
It'll take you right out of 120
and skyrocket you way up there.
And as I've often said,
women did it for centuries with childbirth.
The fatality rate, even in my family,
I look back in the old Bible,
every woman,
you'd see the men were married four times.
Why?
Because all the three wives died in childbirth.
So they self-sacrificed in the name of giving birth,
giving life of nurturance.
So each one has traditionally had his own way to go across.
So instead of bemoaning
and looking at the world perceptually as a negativity,
I don't know what the purposes of these events are,
nor do I need to know,
except that I have faith in the concordance
of the totality of the allness,
that for reasons unknown to me,
this seems to be happening,
at least in the world of perception.
This innocent, quote, innocent person
is going through this.
Right.
It's neither guilt nor innocence.
It's just that this consequence
increases the likelihood of this potentiality.
And now that karma is undone.
How are all the Japanese savage people in Manchuria?
When I grew up,
they killed them by the millions,
innocent civilians,
bayoneting babies to death, etc.
To prove your loyalty to the emperor or whatever,
the Nazi party, whatever.
Done all the time.
How are you going to undo that karma?
Please tell me.
How are you going to undo
the bayoneting of 30 innocent children to death?
Now, you go out of body, you say,
good God almighty.
The undoingness of that.
Therefore, a lot of the things we consider tragedy
are the way back
for them.
That's the way back for them.
How are you going to undo that?
You tell me.
Huh?
Not being born rich, fat, and successful.
No.
Somehow, the guilt of all that.
As I tell you,
I remember one very specific incidence.
There I am,
going through a hernia operation without any anesthesia,
and all of a sudden the agony started.
I got through it by constantly surrendering to it.
And in the middle of that,
I remember,
I remember the exact guy.
And I really did him through in the groin.
And instead of the coup de grace,
I left him to die of his wounds,
days of agony.
Lacked the moral knowingness
to do the coup de grace.
Out of my love for my fellow warfare,
warrior now,
I'd look at him and I'd go,
okay, okay.
Put him out of his,
so that was my obligation.
Warrior to warrior.
Not many laymen understand the warrior.
Those who have been warriors know it very well.
You're obligated,
even if he's on the other side.
Warrior to warrior.
Integrity means that you will express mercy.
The failure, then,
was the cause of the agony in this lifetime.
So I saw the one-to-one payback.
That applies to karmic propensities in general.
So we'll go on.
Also, we've got to finish the last fact.
Is that the exact moment of death,
the exact time of death,
is already karmically set at the moment of birth.
Let's reaffirm that.
That's absolutely true.
100% true.
So worrying about death, then,
is a waste of time.
First of all, you're going to die.
Secondly, you're going to get there no matter what.
And thirdly,
whether you eat a healthy diet or a lousy diet,
it's going to happen the same.
All my vegetarian, non-smoking, health-freak fellow physician colleagues
are all dead.
In fact, most of them died jogging.
Yeah, they really did.
We used to call them the brown paper bag people.
There would be a banquet for the Earth and Molecular Society,
and there would always be at least half a dozen.
They had brown paper bags.
That was organic rice and dried brussel sprouts and shit.
No wonder they died young.
That's true.
That would kill you early, wouldn't it?
All right, so the exact moment of death is precept,
not the means.
The means is up to you.
So if you want to die healthy or you want to die sick,
that's up to you.
Yeah.
That's up to you.