in the
>> Waldorf.
>> Waldorf
>> like Atoria.
>> Um
>> like
>> that's the first thing. Yeah, like salad
like Atoria. And and our our works we're
in our training program um our works uh
we are asked to study Rudolph Steiner.
>> Yes. And I couldn't see the the chart,
but I wasn't sure if his name was on
there. Would you be able to calibrate?
>> He's in the book. Yes, we did. Rudolph
Steiner
>> and is that theosophy?
>> Yes, it is.
>> Yes.
>> And anthroposophy.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Right. No, it it calibrates
quite
>> integrous,
>> does it? Okay. I was curious about that
because
>> Yeah, we did both. We did that and
Steiner separately. Theosophy Calibre.
Yeah, it's in Tiger. Yes.
>> Okay.
>> Y
>> Thank you. And it's in this book?
>> No, it's the new one.
>> Uh no, the new one. I think uh I think
we have theosphere in the new book. The
new book is called uh the crisis of
truth and we calibrate
most everything on the planet
enough of each thing on the planet that
a person
understands what truth is because
nobody's ever been able to define truth.
There's lots of mentation about it
and when the mentation is done, they
don't realize that their mentation was
facious.
>> All right.
>> So, the new one hasn't been published
yet. Your newest one.
>> We're hoping it'll be out by June or
July. I think we're in there.
>> Okay. Thank you very much.
>> Yeah, but I think Steiner's in there.
Theosophies. Theosophies in there.
>> Is integrous. Okay. Thank you. That's
very reassuring and comfortable.
>> Yeah. No, no.
>> Thank you.
>> Steiner is integrous.
Yes. How are you?
>> Hi, my name is Judy and I'm from
Chandler, Arizona.
>> From where?
>> Chandler.
>> Oh, Chandler.
>> Uhhuh.
>> I wanted to know my question is fairly
simple. I think um
>> I wanted to know the wrong you are
already.
the the karma that you come into this
life with
>> can you change it during this lifetime
>> that's what it's all about
>> how
>> how you're changing your karma
>> you know if you see a pattern that's
repeated in your life
>> karmic pattern
>> how can you change
>> calibrated level of consciousness is set
by the spiritual will now thinkingness
and emotionality jiggles around like
this from moment to moment
But spiritual intention is a commitment.
It's a commitment to a certain context
of reality
and it doesn't doesn't fluctuate.
Spiritual intention is an act of the
will. Therefore, it's slow and
deliberate.
Person often thinks for years about
making a major change in their life.
See, from instant to instant, you make
choices.
some choices may be um of karmic
significance and yes that does change
your overall calibration.
>> That was the question.
>> Well, if there's a pattern that's being
repeated,
>> yeah,
>> can you change that pattern from
happening again?
>> Well, that's the purpose of this whole
lifetime. That's why you're here to
change.
>> I never told you why you're here.
And if this pattern is also you're
seeing it in your children, is that
their karma or can
>> Well, yes, there's an intentionality.
So, you come into this lifetime with
proclivities,
likelihoods,
fields that tend energy fields that tend
to favor going in this direction, but
you're not forced to. At every moment,
you have freedom to change your mind.
Now, to change your mind, you have to
evolve somewhat spiritually so that you
see it differently. Now when you see it
differently, you make a different choice
because you see it differently. So that
takes spiritual evolution.
You know the evolution of consciousness
has been going on for millennia. If it
was a quick thing, you know,
the life would only last a few seconds
and the universe would only last a few
seconds. No, it's a very slow and of
course this this world provides optimum
choice.
I call it purgatorial nature because you
can go from the very bottom to the very
highest optimal choice.
This is uh as I said this morning a
staging area. You come in with certain
karmic propensities. You say yes or no
to them and then you leave for other
dimensions. And that if karmically so
inclined, you can reincarnate again and
try it try again.
Over great spans of times, consciousness
itself evolves. You can see on this
planet alone, it started out at one
bacteria billions of years ago. You saw
it go all the way up to the 200s
and you see it transcend through animal
world and you see it evolving through
humanity.
H Highidleberg man you know calibrated
maybe what I forget all the series
Hidleberg man calibrated over 130
Hidleberg man's at about 125
Neanderthone man was at about 75
well 75 is the level of the animal is it
not
>> and how many people on the planet behave
like animals
about 50%
50% are run by their animal nature But
you can't change it during your
lifetime.
>> You have to play.
>> Don't worry about a lifetime. Every
instant.
>> You were free to come up and ask a
question. You said yes to ask a
question. That means you're spiritually
motivated and directed and inspired,
right? Otherwise, why would you want to
know the truth about anything?
>> Mhm.
>> So, you see, every instant you every
instant you're making choices. Should I
sit here? Should I sit there? Should I
do this? Should I say that? Should I be
friendly to this person, not friend of
this person? Should I watch this TV?
Should I turn the radio on? Should I?
You see, every instant you're making
constant scintillating choices. So, it's
like a scintillation and this
scintillating of the endless choices,
you know, move you from one energy field
to another.
>> Thank you.
That's all happening on the level. The
mind's op real operation is is operating
at a extremely high frequency. The
harmonics of the calibrated levels of
consciousness which themselves are
already logarithmic
but the harmonics beyond them and then
harmonics have various octaves. So you
can have like 15 octaves of the harmonic
interacting with 15 octaves of other
harmonics. So you can see the complexity
of the hologram.
Oops.
You can see the complexity of the
hologram. Yeah.
Hologram is an of course an analogy, but
it's a very good analogy. I think very
good analogy.
I wanted to just um
>> talk about intention a little bit more.
Uh the first gal talked about
wantingness versus intention and you
explained wantingness, you know, very
thoroughly. So I'm thinking that
that with just discerning between
wantingness and intention, you have to
be sensitive to if it's coming from the
solar plexus or the heart.
Um,
>> what does intention mean?
>> Yeah,
>> you're asking me about intention. What
do you mean by intention?
>> Well, to try and describe it without
using the terms
of want
or without being
in lack. Um, you know, you mentioned the
that a person's intention it interrupts
the wave, you know, with some of those
quantum mechanics things.
How do you know?
>> Well, we listed integrous intentions.
>> Mhm.
>> And of course, we didn't list all
non-integrous intentions because they
would fill many a book.
That which is friendly, that which is
favorable to life, that which is benign.
And then what does the person pray for?
When a person prays, what are they
praying for?
>> Health, wellbeing,
>> new MercedesBenz.
>> Well,
isn't that what she sang about?
>> Oh, yeah. That song. Yeah.
A new MercedesBenz. Yeah.
>> Spiritual intention then be really takes
you beyond that.
>> Mhm.
>> See because when you get spiritual then
you see the problem is not that you
don't have a new a new car. You see that
your problem is your dissatisfaction
with what you have. So you see the
problem is not out there. The problem is
within me. the problem is within me then
doing anything about out there is not
going to solve it because the problem is
within the me and it's the way I'm
seeing things. So you do the course of
miracles for instance and what it says
is you're asking the Holy Spirit
to redefine to recontextualize
to show it to let you see it differently
and when you see it differently you
realize you don't have a problem it was
only the way you were seeing. So what
people are praying about is a projection
of their own limitation and distortion
of a reality which they they think is a
reality.
>> Dear God, please help me get over this
uh lack. You don't have any lack.
>> So then they pray and they say, "Well,
God doesn't answer my prayers.
You don't have a lack. God's waiting for
you to have a lack and then he'll supply
something.
Soon as you get a lack down there, I'll
take care of you, baby.
You're suffering from illusion. God
can't do anything about your illusion.
>> Read a good go join unity.
>> So there's only one
So there's only one true intention and
that's to
>> be be
part of the field. Be the contacts. Be
>> get you're getting it. The higher the
prayer, the higher the intention.
>> Yeah.
>> And the more things just manifest,
>> right?
>> You know,
>> uh,
as far as actual lack, I don't think
it's ever happened in this lifetime.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, being without money, yes.
Dying in the middle of the desert, yes.
>> So, what do you lack?
>> Nothing.
>> So, you're dying. So, you go. I said,
"All right, I'm ready to go." Truck's on
fire
and just north of the Mexican border,
many, many miles to civilization in the
water and the truck's on fire. I said,
"Well, if I'm going, I'm going." So, I
sat back waiting to go.
Happy to go. Next thing I know, I hear
it's almost like a voice in my head
says, "Pick that cup." I had a little
hot styne cup in the truck, my old 46
or 64 uh
Willis truck. And uh there's a styrene
cup and had about this much coffee in
the bottom
and the smoke is pouring out one of the
windshield dashboard here. I'm in the
middle of the desert, no water. I've
already got heat exhaustion.
Truck's on fire. Smoke is obscuring
everything.
I didn't have the energy to get out and
even lift the hood.
It would have been solid smoke. So, you
couldn't see anything. Anyway, this
knowingness comes into my mind. Says,
take this plastic cup. Now, take a
screwdriver and pound it through the
bottom of the glove compartment. The
glove compartment right there. The lid
was missing. So,
turns out glove compartments in old
trucks are made of heavy cardboard. I
didn't know that. I took take the
screwdriver and ram it through the
bottom. Boom. I went through the bottom
of the screwdriver. Now pour this coffee
through there. Through this hole.
Through this hole in the middle of
everything. Molded smoke. Pour it in
there. I pour it in there.
Electro fire just went out. And all that
mass of crazy wiring. There was a short
the left brain ego. It never could have
tracked it out. The knowingness
said to do that. So like a dumbbell, I
did it. I think
>> you do it.
>> So where's the lack?
The downside is I'm still here.
I didn't say, "Dear God, please keep me
from crying to death here in the middle
of the desert and dying of heat
exhaustion and dehydration." Didn't say
like that.
>> I was happy to go. Every time I've been
happy to go, I don't go.
I know how to get out of here. Resist
going.
Resist going. There you got the secret.
No, I'm not going.
Okay, drag him away.
Thank you, sweetheart. Come.
That's true. You see non-resistance. So,
you know, we could spend quite a bit of
time on what she actually asked, you
know, because uh surrendering means
non-resistance.
So, if you're not resisting,
not having anything to eat, then
something to eat appears. So long as you
resist it, it's the same with pain. If
you fall and
sprain your ankle and you say, "I have a
sprained ankle," and you lay there. Now
you fixate on resisting it. I'll tell
you what's going to happen. You're going
to have a sprained ankle.
You're going to end up in ace band
injury cast. See? Now you let go
resisting it. You just lay back. Stop.
Don't label it pain. Don't label it
sprained ankle. And if you totally and
completely let go resisting it, the pain
will leave your ankle and it will become
diffuse. You'll feel the pain leaves the
ankle and it's now in your entire aura.
pain is everywhere around you. You let
go resisting the pain that's everywhere
around you. You stop calling it pain.
You just experience the experience of
what it is without calling it anything.
As you let go resisting it, it gradually
fades away. Within four or five minutes,
it's gone. You wake up. You stand up and
walk away. And you do not have a sprain
ankle.
You disappear it.
The idea of lack then is to let go.
Resisting the fact that if it's God's
will that you're poor as a church mouse
right now, you say, "That's great.
It's great being poor as a church mouse.
I've been poor as a church mouse. It's
terrific.
What?
>> I just wanted you to sign."
>> Oh, just she only wants me to sign the
book. Okay. Thank you, Spirit.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Oh, all right.
>> Michael Dennis, Gilbert, Arizona.
>> Yeah, Michael.
>> Hi. Um, you previously had u calibrated
Walmart.
>> Yes.
>> And anyways, uh I believe that was
probably under uh Sam Walton's
regime
>> and I' I'd like it if you could
recalibrate Walmart under the re new
regime because I feel it's completely
flip-flopped.
>> Now what about Walmart? It's
>> I personally feel that Walmart if they
continue on the uh
>> you're talking about their personnel
policy, public policy, retail goods,
marketing, supply chain.
>> Where I'm financing
>> where where I'm coming from is I
personally believe they continue on the
path that they're that they're
>> what path I'm trying to define what path
you talking about. They're the biggest
retailer in the world, the most
successful corporation. You're telling
me it's failing?
What I believe personally their impact
could be
>> on what?
>> On on the uh earning potential of the of
the United States employees. They could
reduce their earning potential by 30% if
they continue the the way they're going.
>> The biggest most successful corporation
in the world,
>> right,
>> is destroying the American economy.
>> No, I didn't say.
>> What is it they're destroying? What
they're basically doing is replacing
highpaying jobs with lowpaying jobs by
>> Well, they better be.
>> But I I feel that's
>> Oh, you got a position.
>> No.
>> Yes, you do.
>> Well, yes, I do have a position. Yes,
>> they better be pre replacing high paid
with low paid,
>> right? I But
>> they better do that.
>> But they
>> otherwise I'm going to fire them.
I dispers
>> They're not a benevolence. They're not a
philanthropic society. You're supposed
to make money and provide goods to the
public.
>> Exactly.
>> And then you want them to pay higher
wages.
>> In some marketplaces, I they I feel they
should pay prevailing rates.
>> What's prevailing rate?
>> Prevailing rate is what people are
willing to work for. I work for 35 cents
an hour. So,
>> well, example like when Home Depot went
into uh Prescott They had to reduce
their uh their normal salaries because
it would have been detrimental to other
>> That's the way it is in the world of
commerce,
>> right? Okay. Ex example. They're trying
to
>> mass production put the
home shop workman out of business. The
shoe machinery put the cobbler out of
business. The electric light put the
candle maker out of business.
The computer put the Hello G. Ed call me
Edwood 8364. Gert would say to me,
"She's not home."
We had a party line, five of us on the
hunt. You ring five. Ours was ringing
five. You go through four rings
and then the fifth ring was the ring.
Wasn't for you.
>> No, I it's it's just that I firmly I
firmly believe
>> I got what you're saying. See, you're
witnessing economic change.
>> Economic change is continuous at all
times.
You can't focus on one and say that it's
good or bad.
You can't say that it's good or bad.
I'll tell you why. Because
you know the dance of Shiva. You know
dancing Shiva. Sa nataraja. See Shiva
you know is dancing like so. You know
very famous statue famous worldwide.
And what the dance of Shiva is is that
what you observe is a function of your
point of observation.
She was demonstrating the Heisenberg
principle. He was also demonstrating
the function of the search engine on the
internet that the intention which makes
you select what you select then
determines what you discover. The answer
Shiva is that is destruction.
That which is that what you want
determines whether you see a thing as
constructive or destructive.
If you see the building coming down,
let's say you see a building explode,
you say, "Well, that's destructive."
Yeah, but they paid $420,000 to have
this company explode that com building.
So whether you want it to collapse or
not want it to collapse.
So the dance of Shiva is that the
oscillation of what you think you see in
the world is the centilation of your
point of observation. It is nothing
going on in the world. You see
the cotton gin destroyed all kinds of
things. The printing press destroyed all
kinds of things. I back east I used to
treat
type setters. Then a new kind of type
setting came in done by electronics or
machine or something and the type
setters union put up a big fuss.
But the new
way of setting type was coming in. You
can't set type anymore
with tweezers and set them in the board.
You can't afford it.
So we see economic changes taking
various forms, you see. And it's neither
good nor bad. And to survive in this
world, you have to roll with the changes
because nothing is going to stay the
same. The way Walmart was when Sam was
around was about 380.
The last time I calibrated it was around
365.
>> I agree that you know when Sam was
there, but what I'm referring to is the
direction in a shift that it's taken
since Sam is no longer
>> Yeah, but you're you're not paying
attention to what I'm saying.
You ask me a question, I ignore the
answer. What seems to you to be bad is
your point of vision.
If my point as a consumer is, I like
cheaper prices. I don't want to pay you
higher prices and I can hire somebody
else for 50 cents an hour cheaper. What
am I? I'm not a philanthropist. I'm a
businessman. So if the viewpoint of the
businessman, he's supposed to make a
profit. He's not supposed to be a
humanitarian out there doing welfare,
quasi welfare.
You understand? Yes. That's not his
business,
>> right? Profit's not a bad word.
>> Without profit, nobody' be sitting here.
>> Exactly.
>> Right. Because there would be no company
that would make this carpet, that would
make these clothes, that would make the
what we're living with. So, you see,
it's a point of perception. When you see
change, it looks like things are getting
worse.
And it's only from an attachment to the
way things were.
I have to let it go all the time because
the way things were when I grew up were
beautiful.
I could look down the highway, there
wasn't anybody for miles. There wouldn't
be another car for 10, 15 minutes. There
was only two lanes, you know. Now I got
to listen to all that traffic going by.
Super high where I used to live. Now,
there's giant super highways going by.
I went to a little school, four room
school called the Maple School.
It's it's now an underpass with a clover
and leaf.
I could bewail that.
But what could it what would it do to be
it? See, so there's no point in getting
moralistic about that which is not a
moral world. The world economics is not
the world of morality.
I guess I'm just looking at it for as as
far as presentment, you know, to the
group at all because we're the ones that
make the decision on who's going to grow
and who's not going to grow and and and
it's us consumers that make the
decisions on
>> you have to make you you have to change
world economics.
>> You know, to help Walmart, you would
have to get the Chinese to revalue the
one.
The Chinese revalue the one that'll
change Walmart. That'll change
everything.
>> Yeah. One time.
>> Yeah. Because the good jobs are getting
sucked overseas at such a rate unless we
drop everything down to absolute hard
rock bottom costs. We're not going to
survive. And now you got the European.
The European economy is the same size as
the American now. They're highly
competitive. Plus, you got the Far East.
So it's draining American capital out of
America at a huge rate. That's why the
dollar is falling against the Euro
dollar.
So you have to contextualize it within
the overall economic world economy in
which if Walmart don't cut costs and
that biggest corporation in the cor in
the country in the world goes down, it's
going to take America with it. And
Walmart goes so are you because it
reflects the totality of the human
economy and the way we do business. See,
Walmart is the way we do business. And
if that fails, then we'll go down
against the European economy and the Far
East. Hong Kong will take us right out
of here.
>> I can hire four Chinese for the cost of
you. Why should I hire you?
>> I've lived in China. For two cents a
day, I can hire people.
>> Yeah.
three cents a day, 5 cents a day.
So to have a child in a sweat shop, we
go, isn't that awful? Except without
that child, the whole family starves.
All of us go. So you look at the develop
of the economy. It goes through a
agrarian then it becomes industrialized
when it gets industrialized to women and
children. And so that's evolutionary.
You see a third world country coming out
of a third world
uh agricultural, you know, still working
with uh water buffalo.
And who do you think the fact when the
factory gets there, they're going to
hire? They're going to hire children.
Well, I would what I would do, you see,
if I was Walmart,
is I would use my economic muscle
to hire those children. Then I insist
that they shorten their hours from 12
hours to 10. Then I insist they shorten
it to 8. Then I insist that they add an
hour of school. If you want my contract,
this is what you got to do for the
children. So I'd use my my economic
power to bring the children out of that
level to a higher level.
>> And I say, you can't hire children
unless you give them at least two hours
a day of school if you want my contract.
Well, if I'm a big contractor in Hong
Kong, I want Walmart's contract. I'll
say, "Okay, we'll give the kids two
hours of school." What about then a year
or two later? I want health benefits.
Then a year or two later, you see, so
you can use your economic muscle for the
benefit of mankind, not for
exploitation.
>> And they have that ability and let's
hope they use it.
>> I hope so.
>> Yeah. So we as spiritual people we try
to energize that context that economic
muscle is is a force for good when when
it serves good and it serves it serves
Walmart and it serves the world and it
serves the children serves all of us.
Well, then we'll put that out there and
we'll let him
>> That's what spiritual people we do. You
see,
>> right?
>> And when Black went on TV there to
defend it, you know, Sam was dead and
Walmart was being attacked for that.
I thought they really need somebody to
know how to contextualize that properly.
Properly. Who but economic muscle can
get better working conditions for those
children? Nobody.
>> No point.
>> No. I see. I'll give you a big contract
in return. I want these kids to have
some schooling. I want them to have
medical benefits, you know. And of
course, that's a phase in
industrialization. First the children,
then the women at the sweat shops and
the sewing, you know, the sewing and
then and then the machine takes over
eventually anyway.
Then the machine takes over.
>> We don't want that. We don't want the
matrix.
>> Hey, we we don't even need to think
anymore. The computer will do our
thinking. So, we don't even need the
executive anymore. We put the data in,
the brain power comes out there. So it
isn't just the lower echelon, it's every
echelon that is going through
transition. Middle managers aren't
needed anymore.
>> I understand where you're coming from,
though.
>> I understand completely.
>> Yes.
>> I'm Sam.
>> Hi, Sam. Hi,
Out of the context,
>> how are you?
>> Out of the context of non-duality,
>> a Christ arises or a Buddha arises.
>> Yes.
>> And calibrates at a thousand.
And the teachings of both the Buddha and
the Christ called disciples. Ask those
to follow.
The intention of the Christ and the
Buddha to me seems to be that their
consciousness would arise
would would increase. And you say the
consciousness only moves at a very slow
rate. But yet in the New Testament,
Jesus talked about the disciples staying
in Jerusalem and tearing until they were
endued with power on high.
>> Yes.
>> Could you speak to that as far as the
transformation of personal conscience?
>> All right. What you're asking about is
the function of the avatar. See the
avatar calibrating at a thousand
Jesus Christ descended directly from
heaven, a celestial realm consciously
chose incarnation
and his message was salvation. His
message was
to avoid anything that goes makes you go
weak with kinesiology.
>> I remember that one.
>> Right. He said
and he and he gave by his life example
as he was
uh crucified he said forgive them for
they know not what they do.
That's what we said today. We said the
human mind in and of itself is unable to
know truth. Consequently
responsibility is limited.
The Buddha
taught the way to enlightenment which is
somewhat different. Quite a bit
different actually.
The disciples that followed Jesus Christ
calibrated over 900. I think they
originally calibrate 98 98 980.
The disciples themselves calibrated in
the 900s.
The bones of St. Peter under the altar
in the basilica
of St. Peters in Rome calibrates over
900.
The relics of the Buddha who have been
on
have been on what do you call it
worldwide tour worldwide. Yeah. Relics
of the Buddha. And when they came
through Sedona,
we calibrated them and they were in the
high 900. In the 900s. So the relics of
the Buddha and his and and the great
sages that followed him are in the 900s.
The relics of St. Peter are literally
under the floor of the altar of St.
Peters in Rome and calibrate in the high
900s. Yeah. What was your question?
The question is that you have said that
uh calibration for the average person
within humanity is around 200 215 and
what is the hope of raising our
individual consciousness?
If we set our intention,
>> well, if if this is a staging area, if
this is an island in the middle of the
for the migratory souls to uh land and
refurbish and take off again,
then the reason we're here is to learn
as much as we can about that which is
permanent, meaning spirituality. Because
skills and devices and property and
money are all transitory. You can't
leave here with that.
There's no U-Haul behind the hearse, as
she says. So, you take with you that
which you take with you. What you take
with you is that which you are, that
which you have become.
So
the purpose of being here is to become
all that you can be as aligned with the
truth. And what is the truth? The great
spiritual teachers of all history do
calibrate in the 900s or the thousand.
The rig vida the early vidas the
yupanads calibrate like 850.
the great scriptures, the New Testament,
if you would, if you take out
Revelations and read the lumpsa
translation from the Aramaic,
calibrates, you know, 880. That's enough
to keep everybody going for quite a few
lifetimes.
>> Christ himself had expectations for
other souls that they would do greater
things than he did. Now,
>> that's what he said, but I don't think
he really
>> is that a misration. I don't think um
myself you're actually my opinion
the radiance that replaces the
thinkingness
there is no intention to one's state
one's state is what it is one state it
does seems to do what it is because of
what it is it doesn't have any intention
the sun doesn't have any intention to
shine on you that's just nature it
>> just is
>> all right so enlightenment is merely to
remove the clouds and then the sun
shines forth because that's what the sun
is and does.
The sun doesn't shine in order to make
you happy or give you a nice suntan.
It just is what it is. I fig you know to
me the radiance of the Christ, the
Jesus, Zorashia, Buddha, the great
beings that have walked the earth is by
virtue of what they are that influence
all of mankind. How do they do that?
First of all,
by vibration. The frequency, the
vibration, the harmonics of an advanced
consciousness radiates out into the
human consciousness
forever.
It redefineses reality. It
contextualizes all of life for humanity
for thousands of years. I always get a
kick out of people who want to remove
God and Jesus and Christmas and all this
crap.
I said, ' When do you want to do that?
Next year. Yeah. Oh, okay. Next year.
What year is next year? 2005. 2005.
What? 2005 BC, idiot. D A D. I mean, and
it would dominate in the year of our
Lord that you'd have to change the
calendar, the year. You'd have to
change.
How can you eliminate divinity then when
that is the very source of your own
existence? That's comical. See,
>> you could if you could eliminate
existence, you would disappear in a
puff.
4:30. So, you're going to have to move.
>> All right. What time did we stop?
>> 4:30.
>> Okay. We stop at 4:30.
>> Any more questions? Any more books?
>> Yeah, we have two more. Two more. So,
two more.
>> Let's do it quickly.
Secrets of the universe. Yes. That'll
take us two and a half minutes.
>> Um my question is I wondered if there's
a point in Jesus's life where um where
he arrived at 1,00 or was he born at
that caliber rate? You said he
>> I didn't ask.
>> Well, you had said just before to the
other person that was here that that he
came down from heaven. And so I would
assume that then he came down as at that
calibration.
But I'm I just wanted to confirm that.
>> I never asked based on that. I just
asked what the consciousness was the
radiance of the the Christ and I got a
thousand. You all the great avatars
calibrated a thousand. The human nervous
system won't take anything over a
thousand. In fact, it doesn't like
anything over 700. uh at thousands is
difficult and the Buddhist said he was
racked with agony and pain Jesus Christ
sweat blood
it's no easy matter to handle a thousand
with the human nervous system
>> I guess I'm wondering if if there's
anything that they did since uh we we
sort of can make choices and that will
affect where we stand in our spiritual
life by the choices we make. Did they
also have to make choices or were they
perfect right from the outset?
>> I don't know.
>> The story we have about Buddha is that
he went from an ordinary consciousness
into an enlightened state
just as Wayne Poe any of the great sages
and avatars of the great sages of
history
evolved. So the Buddha says that you can
transcend the ego and then you will
discover the same thing that I
discovered and he tells you how to do
so.
The story of Jesus is that he was
already
in spiritual debate even as a child
which would tell you that his
consciousness was already advanced at an
early age.
Even as a child he was already what in
heavy discussions with the elders in the
temple. Yeah. Isn't that the story?
So I presume it was an early onset of
that level of consciousness.
>> Is there any um any point in our when
we're embarking on a spiritual path? Is
there any point at which uh
uh we we would feel a need to uh
um get involved with uh with the
problems of uh the world that we live
in? Uh or is there is there a danger? Is
there like a temptation to want to
retract?
>> Yeah. Yeah. You can get derailed very
easily. You see what what you know we
said today that to raise the level of
consciousness
to advance your own consciousness is
already serving God and humanity. See
the difference between Mahayana Hinana
Buddhism Hinana is concerned with your
own enlightenment. Mahayana is concerned
with the enlightenment of all mankind.
The answer to that from the hinana
viewpoint is that my enlightenment is
the enlightenment of mankind and does
benefit of all mankind. So
hinana and mahayana disappear and become
the same at a more advanced
understanding.
There is no personal self that's going
to get enlightened through hyana. Nor
could you avoid the fact that your
enlightenment will benefit all of the
world which is the
the greater vehicle. There is no lesser
vehicle and and greater vehicle. Those
are just
later misunderstandings of the teacher
of the Buddha. There's no lesser and
greater. Those are already judgmental
and
and the conceptualization. There's no
lesser and greater.
>> Is there any real enlightenment if it's
not involved with the suffering that's
in our in the world that we live in?
>> The suffering of the world you live in
is your own perception. From another
perception, there isn't any suffering in
the world.
If I tell you to stop suffering, you can
stop suffering in an instant. I've done
it when I fractured my ankle. I just got
through telling you there's no
suffering. You let go resisting,
suffering disappears.
Well, just in our century, there's a 100
million people who have been slaughtered
by other
>> That's right. Sounds awful, don't it?
>> Yeah.
>> Sounds awful.
>> How do you know that it is?
>> You don't.
We presume that that is so. Yeah. We
presume that is so.
>> In other words, there's that there's no
value judgment attached to that. No
value judgment.
The viewpoint of
the viewpoint of Shiva,
the dance of Shiva. It looks this way,
this way. It looks this way, this way.
So that's only a perception and a
moralistic judgment.
From another viewpoint, the death of 10
million people is nothing at all.
They've done it a zillion times already.
So, what's one more time?
It's called the spiritual skeptic.
Okay. Thank you. And my last one. Yeah.
>> Mhm.
>> Hi. Um, my question is in regards to
unconditional love and You guys what?
>> Unconditional love. And you you talk
about
>> what kind of love?
>> Unconditional love.
>> Oh, unconditional love. Yes. Yes.
>> Sorry. Um in respect to the naive side
to it. Um often I find my mind or um
gets caught up in
judging the love of even idiots or as
you as you would you know. But I get
I get caught up in okay why can't why is
someone labeled as idiot if it he's just
following the perfect path.
>> There nothing wrong with being an idiot.
>> No, that's the thing.
>> But we still label
>> the sooner you get to be idiotic. You
know there's called
what's called divine stupidity.
There is a realization that your mind
not only knows nothing, it's not capable
of knowing anything.
It's called the condition of divine
stupidity.
The great unknowingness.
If you are not the mind, then what
difference does it make what the mind
thinks? What do I care what the mind
thinks? If I'm not the mind, what do I
care what it thinks?
But that I think that part of the book
uh was talking about the naive part of
the unconditional love that can be a
little
>> Oh yes. Well okay yes there is a
downside.
>> Yeah the naive. You see when the heart
chakra opens you see everything as love.
You walk around in a world surrounded by
love. Everything is love. Everything
makes you weep. Everything makes you cry
because of the re revealed beauty and
divinity of all that lives.
The downside is you can't see it coming.
So your your naivity you can get
broadsided
rather easily. Not a few spiritual gurus
who calibrated in the 500s crashed into
much lower levels.
The reason I feel compassion for them is
because they were blindsided because at
540 you live in the heavenly realm. But
this is not heaven.
That's why the higher dimensions are
really only safe in the celestial realm.
Anything below 200 doesn't get to the
celestial realm. It goes to lower astral
or middle astral.
That's the wisdom of lotus land
Buddhism. That's the that's the wisdom
of Christian heaven.
When you get to the unguardedness of the
heart chakra,
when are you safe? You're not
well safe. Everything I I say has to be
modified. Actually,
when you see everything as nothing but
love, then
you're easily blindsided.
You're not safe until the third eye of
the Buddha body opens up. That's
discernment. Now you see the wolf under
the sheep's clothing.
Before that all the wolves look innocent
and they know that too. And they come
looking for you. Fame, fortune, money,
followers, garb, incense, holiness, the
whole works. And you see the guru's
fall. Don't
until the third eye of discernment opens
up. You can't tell the difference.
But that's not the lesson of lovingness
anyway.
Therefore, the celestial realms,
everything below 200
doesn't get into that realm. So there
aren't sharks waiting to eat you, eat
your leg off when you're not looking.
So for one thing, spiritual groups tend
to coales together for mutual protection
if nothing else. And when something that
is non-integrous is invading the group,
the group senses it. The group senses
it. The group senses it. So the
community, the spiritual community is
for communication, for communion, for
the oneness. It's also for its own
safeguard. So the sa
Niko and I belong to the same Buddhist
sana. We used to live separate from the
world in a safe and we sanctified
everything with incense and with chance
and we were quite aware of the negative
spiritual entities and we also knew how
to deal with them.
The lack of spiritual discernment. So
that's one reason I did the calibrated
levels of consciousness and the books
that I've published because I know the
mind doesn't know truth from falsehood
and a more spiritually evolved person uh
into a saintliness usually withdraws for
protection of anything else.
And as I say, until the third eye of the
Buddha body opens up, then one sees and
knows
by the essence of things. You look at
it, you got the essence of it already.
You know what it is. I don't have to
read it. Says, "You're going to
calibrate this. I don't need to
calibrate it. I just looked at it and I
can tell you where it's at."
Thank you.
So, I want to thank you all. I want to
thank the church for asking us.
I want to sing my right arm.
I thank you all for being here. It's
been a great joy.
So I sort of pictured that uh the world
is like an island in the middle of the
Pacific and migrating birds from all
over you know rest up and the decisions
they make then decide where they will go
from there and they scatter from there
and go to different places.
So it's um staging area in which the
migratory soul in its evolutionary
flight
uh stops off and thereby
um by its choices free choices. This is
a perfect place for the evolution of
one's
undoing negative karma and choosing
differently this time.
Why? because the the spectrum of choice
in this world is
almost purgatorial from the very worst
to the very highest.
So here is a island in the middle of
time space in which
we land for a time and by virtue of our
decision
determine our ultimate direction
and those who will be flying with us
and those who will not be flying with
us.
So
then we pick up our friends uh along the
way and of course when we travel around
the spiritual circuit we meet all the
friends that
that are now in bodies and u
have stopped off here with us. So I I
think also whole uh large uh numbers of
birds stop in this island.
uh karmically they coming together
by the tens of millions even and um
continue to migrate on because you see
great sweeps of ethnic
you know when we did the calibration of
the various areas of the world.
We saw there was a tendency for people
who calibrated in certain categories to
settle in one hemisphere or the other
and within that hemisphere even to
settle in in specific regions. We see
whole regions one country after another
uh calibrates enormously differently
from people on the other in the other
hemisphere who
so it's just I I thought of it as a
migratory pattern and earth is just a is
a temporary landing place
from which we can change our direction
if we wish you
so
and the other thing we sort of confirmed
which we did in book we're just
finishing
is that everyone where when they're born
under what circumstances
is karmically perfect
absolutely perfect. Everyone's born with
a certain calibrated level consciousness
and
the circumstances of their birth,
where, when, who your family is, what
your destiny is from there.
The initial conditions are karmically
absolutely perfect.
So that sort of
knocks the wind out of
uh playing victim and uh
self-pity
and resentment and uh if everyone's con
if the conditions were karmically
perfect for each one and that's what we
said. Let's see if that's so
what we just said was perfect.
without permission.
You're supposed to ask permission first,
but
so you might say the conditions of your
birth were optimal for the karmic
lessons of this lifetime.
Whether it's
to learn what it's like to be the heir
of multi-billions of dollars and the
oppression of that. See, people don't
think of that as oppression. Let me tell
you, that's oppression.
To be born to born to a famous family
and be worth a hundred million when the
minute you're born
carries worries and responsibilities and
sleepless nights that you wouldn't even
dream of.
uh responsibility in the ethics and
what's your responsibility to the world
and the temptation to be arrogant,
temptation to be callous,
temptation to abuse power and privilege.
So you see the karmic responsibility
inherent to everyone's
circumstances. your birth. You look back
at your own birth and uh
it's hard to see, but if you
look at it from the viewpoint I'm
mentioning, you'll notice it was really
quite perfect.
As a kid, I didn't think so, that's for
sure.
Yeah. Life in the 30s in the Midwest
during the depression was arduous.
Arduous. arduous.
Every day was a 12-hour day of one kind
or another.
Yeah.
But side was the camaraderie of World
War II. America was completely united,
unified, completely at one.
You couldn't have won without Rosie the
Ribbiter.
Everybody played an important part.
Important part.
Kids like myself save scrap metal for
the war effort. You know, there was a
tremendous unity to that generation. It
was really fun. You know,
you know,
more doctors smoke camels than any other
cigarette.
They're good for your T-zone.
And then on television, there were
dancing jello- boxes, you know. And
Sunday, everybody gathered and sat on
the bed and turned on the radio, you
know, radio Filco,
AM radio, and you listen to Jack Benny
and Red Skeleton. And
it was an era that the young people
today uh that never got to experience of
the whole country being united like one
big family
and everybody hitchhiked everywhere. I
had to hitchhike every day 10 miles to
the high school which was in town
because I lived out in the country.
So, you know, 10 below zero, you get on
this highway, there was one car every
15, 20 minutes
and I'd hear a car coming down, you
know, a truck. Whoa. I could hear a
truck coming all the way. And uh so I'd
stick my thumb out, you know, hoping to
see me in the headlights. And the nicest
sound in the world was those those what
do you call them? Compression brakes.
you know, the air brakes, you know, all
of a sudden I'd hear and I could hear he
was feathering the brakes, you know, to
stop on an icy highway with an
18-wheeler. He's got to start about
quarter mile away
and gradually slow down, you know, and
then he'd say, "Hop in, kid." You know,
now I guess it's illegal to pick up
hitchhikers.
In those days, they would have a sign.
It said, "It's illegal to pitch up pick
up hitchhikers."
And uh they would have a sign illegal to
pick up hitchhikers. Come on then, kid.
The mutual trust that everyone had and
uh
crime was extremely rare during the war.
Crime just practically never happened.
There was no no crime uh sub
civilization, sub society,
much less were they glamourage. John
Dillinger was public enemy number one.
told my mother before bed. He escaped
somewhere near Wisconsin and uh yeah, in
fact, he was caught in Wisconsin, right?
The hit line was Don Dillinger on the
loose. Jeez, everybody locked our doors
at night.
Yeah. My father go out and double lock
the garage door so John Dillinger
couldn't steal our car and escape
our 1929 Hudson or whatever the heck it
was.
29 modeling Ford Roadster, you know. So,
I just thought I'd amuse you with a few
little personal vignettes, you know. Uh
but I still hold in mind sort of the
ideal of America as a a unified uh giant
family.
Uh
of friendliness and trust and uh
everybody was pretty integrous and uh we
worked our best for the good of the
country and the war effort and everyone
else.
So the goodwill and the trust that
prevailed
made it what's now called the great
society you know
there you take war you see war which is
supposed to be so awful which it was too
I mean
yeah and uh but the other side of it was
that it brought a great unification of
the country so the counterbalance of the
negativity of the war was almost off set
by the the goodwill of civilization and
uh they brought mother from the
stove to the factory and uh you know
this was an agrarian society
when I grew up 50% of the population
lived on the farm
and the work of men and women were
divided as they would be in a rural
agrarian society
and Nobody thought a woman would go out
and get a job. If she got a job,
everybody would feel sorry for her and
the guy would be would die of shame that
his wife had to work. So it was a
totally different society and they
didn't see women's position as inferior.
On the contrary,
mother was revered and respected and
when a woman entered the room, a man
stood up in respect. That was respect.
She held he held the door open to the
car out of respect for women.
were revered. So, she was the queen of
the domestic scene.
And it wasn't them that were dominant at
all.
George, you're not going to sit at smoke
in that room. How? My
grandfather would take his pipe and hide
it in his hand. And he'd scurry through
the living room like this. And my
grandmother say, "Frank, Frank, the
drapes." And she
I just wanted to give you a picture how
it really was. And uh so the woman of
course did the house work because she
was raising the kids and the guy of
course did the work out in the farm in
the field. It was very heavy duty work
and they both worked 12 hours a day and
then some.
though I say them, you know, they were
equal and uh
trying to depict the woman as inferior
or whatever was sort of a mis mis
mis miscasting it. It's isn't the way it
was.
Mother ruled the household with an iron
hand and uh in the ultimate, you know,
uh if one of them had to make the
decision, the man had to. It was
expected that he would do it. you know
whether a certain
sick animal was enough to be put down or
not.
He'd say, "Yeah, you you have to
decide."
So he got the tough decisions. And
so that to me is what a normal society
is, where everybody's equal no matter
what they're doing. One was not
considered better than the other at all.
They were very equal. No family could
live without the mother. That was for
sure. Four kids in a farm.
Without a mother, you'd never make it.
She worked 12 hours a day canning and
peeling.
And uh
the reverence for life that is revealed
by that kind of a life style, you know,
is what I sort of hold as an ideal for
society. Unification and oneness,
commitment to everybody.
You could go out in the street if you
needed to ride. Stick your thumb out.
You usually got rides like that. First
car or two would stop and get you.
Nobody's left standing out on the street
by themselves. Very interesting kind of
society to live in.
Yeah. And benevolence was left up to the
churches and benevolent societies
and the government wasn't involved in
it. You see, so
religion served a different function.
And it was the backbone of benevolence
and the churches you know
established all the hospitals all around
them and the charity clinics etc.
And in the world I grew up all every
doctor donated a certain amount of time
to the hospital which had a clinic. So
people didn't have money, they went to
the clinic and uh the residents and the
interns took care of them and if you had
a complicated case, you called the
specialist. So when I was in obstetrics,
I delivered maybe 100 kids and uh but if
you got a breach or something difficult
looking twins or a breach or something,
you call the obstatrician. So
the charity patient for nothing had the
most expensive obstitrician in town
attending to her
and uh the society sort of evened out in
a certain fairness and uh
it was free of uh you know distortions
of viewpoint. Nowadays everything is
distorted in viewpoint.
One reason I'm doing the book I'm doing
is because there's no way to tell the
truth about anything in our society
at all and uh so the current book I'm
working on hoping to have it out by June
is called the crisis of truth. Nobody
knows what the truth is about anything
anywhere in our current society.
The typical criminal case it's always
who done it in politics. Nobody knows
who's telling the truth. Can't tell
where the government is telling you the
truth. Can't tell where the testimony is
the truth. People who swear by the Bible
and then lie up and down.
Nobody knows the truth about anything.
It's like a crisis of truth. And if you
watch every night's news, you'll notice
the whole focus is always on what is the
truth of the matter.
You know, our relationship with the
Middle East and al-Qaeda and the whole
thing. What is the truth? So they
finally captured this guy in the spider
hole
and people what truth is he speaking so
far I don't think he's spoken any
likely.
So we have a society
in which nobody knows what the truth is
nor does anybody know how to define what
the truth is
and if they could define it how they
would ascertain it anyway. So it seemed
to me
because that's what the world. So I was
going to write a different book, but I
substituted this one. It seemed I moved
this one up because
crisis of truth. Nobody knows what the
truth is about anything much less God or
spirituality.
And now we have secularization. There's
a movement
based on all kinds of sophistries.
And so the the only real source of truth
is going to be removed altogether
secularized. So the
we'll fall back into sophistry.
I thought the difficulties of sophistry
were solved back about 400 BC
in the Greek civilization. Sophus
uh taught how to shade the truth so as
to accomplish success in the world.
Sophus for a fee would teach students
how to be prominent in public life and
how to shade the truth by nuances.
And that's become of course
uh the common genre of communication
nowadays. Everybody has to shade the
truth with a little innuendo.
And of course the way the media do it is
if they favor one position they see TV
time TV exposure even a split second is
worth a million right. So they you have
the com the camera hesitate just a split
second longer on this picture rather
than this picture and now people are
programmed through this picture. So on
top of all the untruth, you now have the
almost organized programming via the
media and therefore the slant of the
media.
Which news channel calibrates higher
than another, etc. So I thought
I probably should wait until I get some
fatal disease and then publish it. But
I figured that's cowardice
and
I just soon be shot down walking is
laying down. So
naturally you can't tell the truth about
everything. Can you imagine the
devastation to the world if you tell the
truth about everything?
Lord, are you sure?
It is okay for me to publish this book
soon.
Your witness.
We'll only leave a few things out.
There are organizations known for
intimidation by litigation. So, we won't
ref we won't mention them. We'll give
the name of the org and then we'll say
we'll leave the calibration blank and
we'll say due to conditions over which
we have no control. We've been advised
to leave this calibration out of the
book.
The only trouble is I'm sure we get sued
for that because by inference I have
defamed them. You see what I'm saying?
So here we have a free society. You're
allowed to say anything you want.
However, you're probably going to get
sued for it
unless it's a lie.
Because maligning people's character can
be done freely and there's no recourse.
It's free called free speech.
So this is a society of such complex
of complexity now complexity political
and legal balances and nuances that it's
very difficult to
really be who you are.
you have freedom of speech, but you'll
be sued if you exercise it. So,
uh,
so I thought it's a timely time to
publish such a book and, uh,
critical to the world's thinking.
And people say things publicly, they're
so outrageously facious, you wonder how
they got the courage to say them in
public.
Because when you calibrate them, they
come out like 140 or something, you
know, and you say, "How could a person
who's
running for the presidency make a
statement that cal 140 or 150?"
Oh god.
That's what we're going to do. And uh
if it's our last section on the planet,
so be it.
So that'll be fun. That'll be fun to
look forward to that one. Of course, the
books I've done appeal to a very small
audience.
Probably half of 1% of the world is that
much
people who are seriously spiritually
committed are rare as hens.
And you know there's a lot a lot of
people what what percentage of the
population is really uh sue over the
books I've written already just have to
ask this over 1% over 3% over 5% or 10%.
Wow over 8%. 9% whoa 8% I didn't know
that many. All right. The book I'm
writing now would appeal to over 25%,
30%, 25% of the population. So,
what's the matter with the other 75%?
They must be dead upstairs, right?
Well, I've always been obsessed with
what is the truth about things. And
that's why I like to, you know, when I
was a boy, other kids were playing
stickball and baseball and football and
things. And I was reading the great
books of the western world, you know,
the apherisms of uh Marcus Aurelius and
Plato and Socrates and Aristotle.
A misspent youth, eh,
a misspent youth. Yeah.
So now in writing a certain section of
the book, I had to sort of recall some
of the fine points. What was the
argument of between the Sophus and
Socrates
and had that all come down about 4 or
500 BC?
Uh because
here we are a few thousand years later
and people still haven't gotten the
point of it all. You know, it seems like
instead of playing stickball, you should
have been reading yourself.
The more boys should be reading the
epherisms America and Socrates and Plato
and all instead of playing stickball.
That's my advice.
Where will stick ball get you anyway?
All right, I've said enough.
She said I said enough.
Anybody
got any questions? And then we're going
to sign books too, you know. Anybody got
any commentary?
Speak, sir.
>> I Yes, we calibrated all the
presidential candidates. We're not going
to publish them either. Um,
yeah, I'm trying to remember the
calibrations. They're around 440.
Uh, the highest the highest calibrated
colleges are the Big 10 in the Midwest.
Uh, below that is Ivy League,
uh, and Stanford and those like that.
Uh, they're all, you know, 400 and up.
They're none of them are slouches.
Uh but surprisingly the Big 10
calibrated higher than the lowest were
actually Yucula and Berkeley actually.
They were like 395 or just barely over
the border.
And um
as far as prep prep schools go, exit was
like higher than all the universities.
Exit must be a good school to go to.
Where is Exit? I don't know.
Anyway, it's a fashionable prep school.
I think
we go there.
Yes, we did the colleges and
universities and uh
they all seem to be, you know, arerodite
arerodite
as an organization.
What I thought was interesting, the Big
10,
but you would expect the Midwest sort of
a more balanced view of everything. You
know, the mid and midwestern politics
don't take over to such a degree
as they do on either coast. Either
coast.
Any other questions? Then we'll sign
anything.
How do you personally decide which is
more appropriate as far as um
maybe how do you know when it's it's
appropriate to to follow the idea that
that
you are or that each person is um their
own version of God and therefore
creating their own circumstance and
universe and fulfilling their own will
as it's appropriate versus um this
separate
intelligence,
consciousness,
um that that has a will that's
smarter or more
better uh thought out or well planned
than what you could decide for yourself.
How do you know which is
>> I understand the question,
>> Nico? You understand the question? What
you saying?
I'm trying to
hear what
>> are you talking about the will of God?
>> External God or internal God. Well,
she's wondering the difference between
an external God and and an internal God
and how how do you discern what is uh
what is right for you with uh I think
what she's saying with because there's a
lot of churches there's a lot of gods
there's a lot of and so how do you
discern for yourself what's the right
path and what's
>> oh yeah
>> discernment I think is what she's saying
>> well discerning between what you want
and what you what what the drive is for
you versus
the temptations of the 500s are quite a
bit different than the temptations of
the 200s or 300s or whatever other
number
because you pull to yourself different
lessons having to do with love, having
to do with the abuse of love, having to
do with the blindness of love. The
difficulty with being in the 500s is
that the heart is open, but the third
eye of the Buddha body is not open yet.
So, you don't have discernment.
Spiritual evolution, you might say,
takes you out of the base chakra so
you're not run by sex. Takes you past
the spleen so you're not run by hatred.
Takes you past the solar plexus so
you're not driven by craving and desire.
And the purpose of primarily
Christianity and Islam and other
religions
is to get you up to the heart.
From the heart, you don't have to worry
if you die in the heart. Christ says
that you'll you'll end up in the
celestial realms, the heavens.
So Christianity is really designed for
unconditional love. The perfection of
Christianity is unconditional love.
The Buddha taught enlightenment.
Different deal.
Christ taught salvation. Buddha taught
enlightenment. So in the 500s up to a
thousand is one arduous trip
not made by many.
Yeah.
It's driven however by an energy over
which one really has no particular
conscious control.
Many people are content to be at
whatever level they are and they stay
there. Man Harshi
I never caliber him before he became
enlightened but I know karmically he had
done a great deal of spiritual work
already because at age 15 he suddenly
fell down or 16 whatever it was and felt
himself dying.
He was dying. He literally was dying.
The only death you can experience which
is the death of the ego because you
think the eye is the self the real self
and when it dies you think you died. So
he was very surprised to see that the
body was still alive
and we know that he calibrated over 700
hence for it. He never left the side of
the mountain there or what it was
called. And he didn't even speak for
several years, you know. He didn't he he
stayed in a cave or some place. The bugs
were eating him and all and didn't eat
and didn't drink and didn't speak. And
some followers, some spiritually
enlightened students found him and fed
him and um got him to eat and he
physically survived. But he didn't speak
for two years.
And his whole life he never left there.
Well,
because over 600 there is no
the the experience is absolute
perfection.
There isn't an inkling of a doubt that
there's anything beyond what what you
what the state is. The state is total
and complete and universal and beyond
time.
So one would not think it would never
enter one's mind to proceed further.
Sometimes for karmic reasons one
proceeds further without make having
made any int decision whatsoever about
the matter
and um
it proceeds onward from there.
The human nervous system is not made to
go. The human nervous system is
comfortable up to about consciousness
level 700.
Beyond that, it is not comfortable. The
energies are too extreme for it.
It's not
equipped to handle such high energy any
more than one wires for 110 are equipped
to do 20 220. And
I mean that's just my explanation of it.
And one feels um physical symptoms and
anguishes. And
what hap what's hap what happens you
know from this experience is as you move
forward it pulls up anything out of the
collective unconscious
and you've got to clear whatever got
pulled up.
It can be the one I had difficulty with
was um
was spiritual warrior
and
the spiritual warrior would take a
positionality
about some spiritual iniquity.
So I had to meditate and pray on seeing
things differently.
So not to be run by the spiritual
warrior.
So you pull up the different archetypes.
Probably below 700, you don't pull up
the archetypes. I don't know. I've never
asked these questions. Below 700, you
don't pull up the collective archetypes
for clearing. Over 700, you do. That's a
very good question. I never knew that
before. All right. Up to 700, the
reading is comfortable. In fact, it's
blissful
and there's no inclination to
participate in the world.
Uh is you haven't pulled up anything
in the collective.
Oh yes, I see. So from 700 up, you're
clearing it in the collective
unconscious.
All right. So from 700 up, you're
clearing it for everyone. Oh. Uhhuh. I
get it. All right. So because things
that are not personal and never were
personal will come up
and uh
it comes up as an agonizing
uh
an agonizing pain in one's whole aura.
Not localized physically although
physically you get some things too but
well you read in the history of mystics.
Mystics are the only ones that get into
that kind of a trouble.
that that trouble. And you read in the
encyclopedia bratannica it says some
advice to mystics from a famous mystic
of the 16th century was uh you will
spend much time in bed
unable to eat and sick with the with
strange diseases nobody has ever heard
of.
Anyway, they can be uh quite anguishing
and then one once one discovers so
from one's spiritual education and
intuition you pick up what's likely out
in what chakra of what archetype.
It can be the child who's disillusioned
with spiritual truth expected it to be
different.
It can be um
it can be any of the archetypes uh that
pervade in human consciousness
and something can be out in one of them.
So by intense prayer
by intense prayer want to clear it. When
it's cleared
your your energy goes clearer and the
pain stops.
So it can still happen.
I can run across something and all of a
sudden I feel that energy start and I'll
say something's out about something
somewhere
and usually we get what it is and then
verify it with kinesiology and then by
intense prayer clear it check it out
again now it's clear
so perhaps one serves a different
function then at that point I don't know
and I think I've told you that we were
in Korea and uh
and one says, "Why am I afflicted with
this affliction? It's so strange. She
has no diagnosis in this world.
No, nobody knows anything about it." And
Susan reached in the drawer of the in
the hotel room. She recently Jordan and
pulled out the equivalent of the Holy
Bible, but in Korea it was the teachings
of the Buddha
and she flipped open the page and it
said the Buddhist said he was racked
with aches and pains and his bones felt
like they were broken and all. Instantly
I felt okay. I said, "Oh,
no, you're not alone." is very helpful.
See, so sharing our spiritual experience
with each other, you never know who
benefits from it. See,
and I remember going through surgery
without anesthesia. And and I thought of
all the soldiers in the Civil War whose
limbs were sought off fully conscious,
maybe a few slugs of whiskey, and
somehow they survived it.
And if they can survive it, I can
survive it.
And Susan said the same thing about
childbirth. In the middle of it, she
pictured all the women throughout
history who've gone through this
experience and had succeeded. And she
she's kind of a person who puts her head
down, heads into the wind.
She just went to it and drove through
it. So that's sharing. See, we get
inspiration from each other. So mankind
serves each other by sharing our own
experiences. You never know what you
share that someday in a crucial
situation the person's going to remember
that by God that makes the difference to
them they did it I can do it you know
what do you all say put your head down
>> the tougher it is the more she puts her
head down decides she's going to go
so that's how we serve each other in a
way by sharing who we are and being as
open as we can with each other
and um sharing uh our reality because in
so doing we benefit everyone without
knowing it without realizing it.
Many people have inspired our life you
know and serve as examples you know we
think of them and if they can do it you
know we can do it. So that's a wonderful
gift we give each other is just the gift
of our own existence. Yeah.
So now we're supposed to Yes.
>> What' you say?
>> Everything.
>> That's a funny question.
>> I never have the slightest idea what's
going to be said. And uh I hear it at
the same time you hear it.
>> I never have the slightest idea what's
going to be said.
I have a general idea of what
material uh we should cover you know
having to do with consciousness
research. Consciousness research is one
thing and inner spiritual experience is
another although the two one came out of
the other. Yes
something regarding sincere earnestness
in this process of investigation that
Ramana spoke about. I see a lot of
people now I think getting down the
languaging of nonuality of not taking
positions also I find in my own
investigation that often I'm sincere I
want to forgive everyone and then found
out through muscle testing that I had
not and found that there was something
in the subconscious could you say more
about the process of getting your stuff
>> yes well we're talking about you know
what guides your spiritual progress you
see you get to a certain point And then
uh you're pulling up karmic uh
consequences from other lifetimes. And
you know, you'll say, "Well, what did I
ever do to deserve this?" Truth is
plenty.
If you don't believe it, do past life
regression. You'll see, boy, you were an
SOB in that lifetime.
and you say, you know, I must have been
a so and so in some lifetime. Well,
that's almost always correct. You were.
Now, you go through it with forgiveness
and a change of mind and you take
responsibility. So, I always pray for
forgiveness for all those that I have
whatever people I think people have done
to me.
Uh I
pray for forgiveness for having done it
to them. So the way to undo negative
karma is first assume that whatever is
happening in your life is the
consequence of what you've done in some
particular lifetime.
And the safe bet is to guess that
you know if everybody is stealing your
your money then you ask for forgiveness
for having stolen people's money because
obviously
the great likelihood is 90%. That you
spend a lot of time burglarizing
and pickpocketing. See,
I was a pickpocket in France. A good
one, too. I tell you, I know the secrets
of pickpocketing.
That was a good pickpocket. France one
left.
Well, I didn't see anything that wrong
with it. They had their money and they
wouldn't miss a few dollars. So it
wasn't crime of violence but it was
petty grand.
So whatever happens in your lifetime if
you make a presumption that it could be
a karmic precedent to it you won't make
any mistake by praying for forgiveness
and forgiving people you know
forgiving people for what you think has
happened to you.