long time since we've been here and this is like a whole home week here and we
were in snow for you we thought that would be nice create a creative life
actually rains the snow and we want to thank them for it yes thank you for the
snow sweetheart we we she said she had a surprise for us and so don't even do
things like that elsewhere in the world you're stuck with the weather here we
just create it whatever suits us what happened to the music anyway the magic
music well and to celebrate today we we heard from a publisher in Russia we're
gonna be in Russian now so like
so we're in Russian we're in Slavovian we're in Slovenian we're in all different
languages so that's very nice and I brought my ego with me
I just wanted to see if it was working well let's see I forgot about what
today's lecture is about does anybody know illuminating thought alright last one yes retry
So I was in the laboratory uh and I remember there was this seminar this guy was so interested in
Community Studies very similar to what Mr. Bogen doesn't like and I mean really knows everything
he's into He knows where his boy gets whatever he has to hide what he has to hide here so so i don't
Oh oh she does this investors an investigation not on my existing circuitry one before we know what a
lot of these protocols go I guess was so Daar ratio where people think i'm not even an artist I'm an instructor
I don't have any thoughts about the lecture today.
Then we'll have to wing it.
Well, since we last were here, we've been all around the country and talked here and there.
And we've discovered that it's better to start the lecture from the end and work back to the front.
So we'll start with the end.
That way you don't have to listen to the rest.
Today has to do with, I believe, transcending thought. Isn't that what it's about?
It has to do with a condition that is already in existence
and how to just become aware that it's already there and that you don't have to do anything about it.
You can save many lifetimes by just getting a simple understanding of how things come about in the world, you see.
And it'll save you all kinds of worry.
Because
a group like this, which calibrates quite high,
the obstruction to enlightenment is really the intellect.
For 85% of the population on the planet today,
the problem is really to cross over 200 to become oriented and to value integrity, truth, and honesty.
And in America now, 51% of the people calibrate over 200.
In 4090,
15% are trudging along.
And we hope to inspire them to move faster.
So in a group like this, which has already decided that they'll give up murder and robbery and
and thievery is a lifestyle,
give up recidivism and live in the world instead of a prison,
um,
the problem is, therefore, the mind.
So, you see, each level on the scale, I've got a new pointer thing, but I don't know where it is here, someplace.
Someplace, it's in my, somewhere, anyway.
Anyway, we, we, oh, there it is.
It's so new, I don't even know I have it.
Look at there.
Ta-da!
Let's see now.
The world, uh, you know, the world over time, you know.
To understand the ego is to not be at the effect of it.
We see that it's a development that occurred over great eons of time.
And we have a slide on the eons of time.
Over great millennia, then life appeared at consciousness level one, as bacteria,
uh,
Algae and viruses don't have any consciousness.
Don't ask me why. Apparently they don't think about anything at all.
It isn't until you get to a bacteria that you start to worry.
Bacteria, Calvary said, won. We'll get to that slide later.
And then, great millennia, on through the animal kingdom, on up through the Komodo dragon,
and that's level Bin Laden.
Yeah, he calibrates the same.
Up through the reptiles, and then we get to domestic animals,
and finally we get to the capacity over 200 herbivores.
The grass eaters calibrate about 200.
And then you get on to the scale of consciousness.
So we see that
the
consciousness of mankind.
This is Neanderthal man, about 75 here.
Neanderthal man really wasn't man, he was pre-man.
Because Neanderthal didn't evolve into Homo erectus or Homo sapien.
He got off the train there.
Being smart.
He got off. And he disappeared into oblivion and reemerged then later.
Off the evolutionary tree is Homo erectus
and Homo erectus and 600,000 years ago finally Homo sapiens,
Idelta, appeared in Ethiopia.
At about this consciousness level here, you see?
Then it took many, many centuries.
At the time of Buddha, the consciousness level of man was 90.
At the time of Jesus Christ, the consciousness level of mankind was 100.
When you look at the teachings of the ancient masters,
you have to realize to whom they were talking.
To whom they were talking.
Then, over a great millennia of time, it got up to 190.
It stayed at 190, below the level of integrity.
And then recently, in the late 80s, crossed over.
And now, when we were in San Francisco,
right during the session, at the end of the session,
it went from 205 to 207.
That was the time of the last,
you know, harmonic concordance.
And we happened to be talking to a large group in San Francisco,
and we calibrated the level of consciousness at 515.
I think it was supposed to happen from 518 to 530,
San Francisco time.
And in front of a whole audience, and it's on video,
we did the calibrated level of mankind at quarter after five.
And then we all did OM,
and other wondrous things, and prayed.
And by God, at 530,
consciousness level jumped from 205 to 207.
So, we have a new millennia in which we're living.
At 207, non-integrity tends to surface.
You see, at 190, it's just everybody does business that way.
A few bucks under the table,
a little wink here, a little wink there.
The old boy network,
which, as Wall Street has found out,
isn't working out anymore.
The old boy network doesn't work anymore.
And interestingly enough, along with the old boy network,
you see that the women CEOs,
the companies run by women CEOs,
according to Fortune magazine,
were more profitable than the corporations run by men.
Considerably more, in fact.
Like 30% more profitable than the ones run by men.
See?
All right.
So, women are making tremendous executives.
I was saying to myself,
now why is that?
Well, I saw it right away.
Because men come from a different culture,
in which the old boy network,
you do me a favor, I do you a favor.
You know, many years ago,
somebody offered me an insider,
it would get you prosecuted nowadays,
whatever you call it.
Anyway, he ran the company.
So, he said, give me 10,000
and I'll give you 100,000 back in a week.
Oh, I didn't do it,
but probably because I didn't have 10,000.
No, actually, by that time,
integrity, it would create guilt, you know.
So, anyway, in the old boy network,
then, amongst men,
certain deviations from
absolute purity have been part of the culture.
It's not part of the women's culture.
Not part of the women's culture.
And when women first appeared as CEOs,
the guys all thought,
boy, they're really picky uni,
you know what I mean?
Really picky uni people, you know.
Well, they're new at the job,
they'll learn.
No, women don't come from that culture.
They're not from the old boy culture.
So, they toe the line.
And I predict, you know,
in a few generations,
they'll be the old girl culture.
Let me see somebody off your board
and I'll see to it that
things go your way.
But they haven't learned that yet, so.
I just think that's very interesting.
And I find a lot of women don't know that,
so I thought they should know that.
That isn't what we're talking about today, anyway, but.
Spirituality, then,
is actually a way of being in the world.
It's the way you are.
It's not spiritual practices.
It's not specific techniques.
It's not sitting in weird positions
and breathing in strange ways.
It's not getting your aura read.
Your cards told,
your ruins thrown,
your marbles, whatever.
New Ageism won't get you there.
It will get you in latent,
but it will satisfy your curiosity.
It's possible to get involved
and then become uninvolved, unscathed,
but it's unlikely.
Because usually some of it sticks to you.
And I advise people to avoid it.
Why?
Because there's hidden energies,
the likes of which you're unaware of.
People are naive.
So the downside of,
the downside of the human condition
is really not evil.
It's not really even ignorant.
It's naivete.
It doesn't know any better.
And it's attracted by the lure of the unusual,
the unique,
the odd,
the bizarre.
Master Bamba Rumba
giving you instructions from the other side,
et cetera.
God help you.
Yeah.
All right.
So consciousness then evolves up to the point
where integrity now is the rule.
Every single newspaper,
I've read for weeks,
has had the impact of that.
Every single newspaper.
Suddenly something that's been getting away with something
for a long, long time
is suddenly under the spotlight.
It's not a good time
to try to pull fast ones in the business world.
What was it yesterday?
Yesterday the president of Smith & Wesson
gets knocked out.
He really has a criminal record.
And he didn't think it was important
to tell anybody about that.
Of course not.
17 years in prison,
that's not important.
I agree with him.
I agree that he's turned a corner
and has become an okay person.
And I really don't doubt his integrity nowadays.
However,
the fact that he didn't reveal it
put his company at great risk.
He and his company should have known better.
If they don't get a background check on executives
before they get big salaries,
they need to be examined.
So the board of directors is also careless.
Because integrity means
that you also demand integrity,
and it's your style of life.
So that's the new lifestyle.
Every single day there's been
a scandal of dereliction
from the level of integrity,
which did not happen in the old days.
In the old days,
there weren't big scandals,
much less every day,
much less in the headlines,
much less celebrities.
All right.
So today has to do with thought.
It has to do with
transcending thought.
The transcendence of thought
is automatic.
It's not something you have to do,
acquire.
It's not a discipline.
It comes from a way of contextualizing yourself
and contextualizing life
so that you become
that which is thoughtless.
You become that which is thoughtless
by virtue of how you contextualize
the meaning of your life
and the meaning of life altogether.
Why does the mind think at all?
Good question.
The mind really thinks because of anxiety
and because of safety.
It really thinks because of survival.
I don't know what to do with this thing
in the meantime.
Anyway, I guess you hold it.
Okay, thank you.
I never know what the body's doing.
It's saying,
what do I do with this thing?
I don't know what to do with this thing.
I'd have to think about it.
That's why people around are very useful.
You say,
what is that for?
you hit that and you get a spot.
I say,
whoa, that's great.
You see,
you don't really have to know anything at all.
Somebody around knows
and as long as somebody knows,
it's fine.
Once you understand the reality
of your own existence,
thought comes to a slow intermittency
instead of a continuous process
that's torture.
There's really no necessity
to think about anything
once you understand who you are
and what life is.
What does the mind usually do?
It thinks about the future
and it thinks about the past.
It ruminates about the past
and what is the past?
Well, if the ego is determining
your perception now,
it did also in the past.
So you can't remember reality
in the first place.
You can only remember
the ego's perceptions
which are all distorted and BS.
So there's nothing in the past
that's real.
And as much as it's not real,
there's no point in ruminating
and trying to correct it.
I wish I'd said that.
I wish I'd done that.
The way to handle the past
was well expressed by Bill Wilson
who was the founder of AA,
who had an enlightening experience,
was transformed,
a good part of society
and introduced
and made us realize
the healing power
of spiritual concepts.
Bill said,
there's only one thing
you gotta do about the past,
have a decent regret.
Have a decent regret
and live differently.
End of story.
Is that agreeable to everyone?
A decent regret.
Let's say if you were God,
what would you say to a person?
You killed all those people, man,
and you slaughtered all them people.
Are you sorry?
I am.
You're forgiven.
If he's not sorry,
you send him back to light world
and let him live it all over again
until he's sorry.
Then he comes up.
You just stay there until you're sorry.
Isn't that what it's all about?
Once you've realized
that you're sorry
for what happened in the past
and you're gonna accept
a new way of living,
what more is there to life?
Well, there's the future.
Uh-oh.
We just took care of the past.
All your memories of the past
are distorted perceptions
because if you went through the past
in an enlightened state,
you wouldn't remember anything about it
because nothing happens.
Nothing to recall
except projections.
When you see they're all projections,
they lose their lure.
What about the future?
Well, the future has to do with anxiety.
It has to do with planning.
It has to do with anticipated disasters
and misfortunes.
What if we run out of gas
on the highway, et cetera?
What if the world's gonna be hit by a meteor?
There's always somebody
predicting the end of the world.
Think of all the fortunes
that have been made
by various people
predicting the end of the world.
There's always a new book.
It usually comes out
of some mystical thing,
like you count the number of
whiskers in a seal's mustache,
and you multiply that
by the stones in the pyramid.
You divide that
by the number of chapters
of books in the Bible.
You multiply that
by a sacred number,
and you come up with 5082.
All right, man,
we'll give you a new date.
The world is coming to an end
in 5082.
How does that affect your life?
Not at all.
See, all these books
that predict the end of the world
in thousands of years,
I don't know why anybody
wants to buy them.
You're not gonna be here,
so...
They said next week
it'd be worth reading.
In Sedona,
we've got all kinds
of people like that.
There's one guy,
and he has a funny way
of making his hair and all.
And, you know,
every five or ten years,
he's got a new prediction.
So then,
you know,
if I predict
the world's gonna end
in such and such a year,
and it didn't, man,
I'd just fold up my tent.
I'd just say,
oops,
and find something else to do.
No.
These people don't even have that.
Yeah.
You know,
they come back next year,
they got a new prediction
that they counted
the ruins
in the Temple of Karnak wrong,
measured it in sacred geometry,
and came up with 2043.
Oh, okay.
Then they come back.
I always tell these people,
if you're gonna predict
the end of the world,
make it far in the future, man,
so that when they're all gone,
nobody will ever know
you're wrong.
Those who have
a decent regret,
a really heartfelt regret,
are the ones
who have a decent regret.
They're the ones
who have a heartfelt regret
for human error.
You see,
the human is built,
he's fallible.
Therefore,
errors are certain.
If you haven't made
serious errors in your life,
you're a liar.
To say you haven't made
serious errors in your life
is already a serious error.
We've all screwed up mindily,
and,
as Christ said, forgive them for they know not what they do,
and the Buddha said the same thing.
So the one sin of the past from which all human beings suffer
is ignorance, not knowing the full truth.
This is a condition of all of society, and it doesn't make you special.
Oh, Lord, I've sinned.
People make a big drama.
There's a whole trip about ashes and sackcloth and suffering
and self-flagellation and guilt and misery,
and these are people that are looking for God at the bottom of the chart.
Shame, guilt, griefs.
Oh, God, how I have sinned.
Okay, that gets rid of a little guilt.
I mean, I'm not going to put it down,
except after a while you feel guilty that you did that,
but that's beside the point.
I was looking for God down here.
And then I heard a lecture that said he was up here,
and that changed my life.
Oh.
So everything in the past then is washed out.
There's no point to think about the past because there's no reality there.
If you were in a state of reality, as I said, there wouldn't be any past.
All right, so the next thing is fear.
Fear has to do with not realizing that you're safe at all times.
Well, the brain and the mind,
they manufacture conditions and take examples from the past
to try and justify that fear is a rational condition
that you have to think fearfully of the future.
So the future then has to do with control,
trying to control the future.
All this is premised on survival is due to the ego.
And as you get more sophisticated, you realize that,
survival is not a product of the ego.
It's a product of the spirit.
The mind becomes silent automatically with the realization that you are absolutely safe.
And even if you aren't, so what?
So you die.
Dying is a certainty.
So accepting the certainty of death, then what can we do about the future?
You can be devoted.
You can be devoted to all that is sacred.
Be devoted to beauty.
Be devoted to all that is sacred.
You see, the beauty, as we came here this morning, it was stunning.
The only difficulty with beauty is it makes you cry,
and you shouldn't be driving.
As soon as you said, what are you crying about this morning?
He said, I don't know, it's just the snow.
It's just the snow in Sedona, you cry with happiness.
Anyway, first time we've had it all year.
So, to be aware and to be aligned with, to honor divinity and all of its expressions,
to be sensitive to the beauty that exists at every moment in all things.
Therefore, the spiritual pathway through this world is only a way of being.
And you become that.
That's why I'm not crazy about various techniques.
Breathing and sitting in strange ways and contorting your body and sucking your stomach
so it's against your spine and weird things.
It's only necessary to just be who you really are.
That is a divine state.
And when walks through the world on the wings of truth, the divine state reveals itself.
When you realize the truth of your own existence.
So therefore, how you contextualize your life, then, is how you present yourself to the world.
And it's what you are to the world.
The universe responds in like.
When you are thus to the world, the world is thus to thee.
And you walk safely through the hail of bullets.
And if one's meant for you, so.
And if you come out the other side, then there wasn't one meant for you.
So that is the way it goes.
So that is complete surrender, is it not?
The past is eliminated by the realization that a decent regret is all that's necessary.
Let's make sure about that.
.
A decent heartfelt regret does indeed undo the past.
Oh Lord, amen. Resist.
It does indeed undo the past.
In one instant, that's all it takes.
So you can stop ruminating and trying to rewrite the past.
You're lying in bed.
I should have said this, I shouldn't have said that.
I should have bought this stock, I should have bought this stock.
I shouldn't have bought that stock.
I should have.
So the past was a learning program.
And what's the point of that learning?
The point of that learning is for you to have a decent regret about it and let it go.
To stop dragging it around.
I don't want to hear other people's chains dragging.
They come up after a lecture and they want to give me about,
oh, I did this and I did that and then she died and I wasn't there
and my mother-in-law was having her gallbladder out.
Boy, oh boy, I say.
Susie's daughter says, you're the Bill O'Reilly of spirituality.
I just say to the lady, cut it out, man.
Don't drag me along with your sad story.
I don't want to go there.
Those are people who, you see, wallow in the past
because their ego is sucking the juices out of it.
You see, the juices the ego gets out of wallowing in the past,
sackcloth and ashes, all the drama.
It's drama.
Drama.
You're also trying to control God and tell him what to do.
Forgive you because look how you suffer.
That's blackmail.
All the people try to blackmail God with suffering.
You realize how you're trying?
That's a control thing, isn't it?
God is this awful parent and if you just suffer and wallow in guilt,
then he'll forgive you.
You don't have to manipulate God because God is a condition.
Non-manipulable.
Like a giant electrostatic field.
All right.
That's the past.
The future then is surrendering to the will of God completely with no reservation.
And that's a way of being in the world.
A way of being in the world.
And it's letting go, wanting to control the world, control the future.
If you have a negative view of yourself, then you expect the worst in the future
and you begin to plan for the worst.
Because you're extrapolating, you're projecting out there what you think you are.
Don't think what you are at all.
Just be what you are and don't think about it.
How can you just be what you are?
You can do it in one instant.
Be willing to accept what I'm saying to you right now with no reservation.
Isn't that easy?
If I tell you E equals MC squared, I don't want some smartass to get up there
and start to argue with the mathematics of it.
I'm telling you E equals MC squared.
I don't want some smartass to get up there and start to argue with the mathematics of it.
Get it?
Jesus Christ, that's so simple.
I mean, everybody can see it.
It's just matter.
It's just energy, condensed energy.
I mean, you don't have to even go to school to figure that one out.
Once somebody explains it to you.
So we accept things on faith.
We accept things on faith.
To completely surrender one's will to God, then,
means whatever happens in the future happens in the future.
Don't worry about the mind going silent and leaving us stranded.
I get letters from like that all the time.
I'm meditating and my mind stops, and that scares me because how will I survive?
Well, maybe you won't.
I don't know what she wants to survive for.
She's all the way home.
Why not just be there?
What about the kids?
Let God worry about the kids.
Let the world worry about the kids.
Yes, this week one came that way.
We said, let God worry about the kids.
If you bliss out, you bliss out.
Somebody blisses out, you sit them down.
You put a tin cup next to them, and people walk by.
Your mother-in-law comes and gets the cups.
Empties it every hour.
Children are okay.
Don't worry about it.
So we let go of wanting to change the past, and we let go of wanting to control the future.
And that's done at a profound depth.
One realizes that you are safe, not because it says so in a book, but because you realize that.
As I stand here, you don't see any past hanging off of me.
You see any past anywhere?
I don't see any past.
When is a karmic product at this moment?
That which stands here is where evolution is at this moment.
Okay.
The present is the finish of the past.
With spiritual realization, which you come by through contemplation, it's really a contemplative matter.
As you walk about, you say, who am I to myself anyway?
Who am I to the world?
What am I to life?
What is my relationship to life?
When you reverence all that is beautiful, when you reverence all that is divine by virtue of its existence,
then you walk about in a different state.
Out of that state arises a conviction of safety.
The mind will start up periodically when it needs to tell you something.
Not because it's coming from the mind, but because it's coming from the spirit.
If you need to know something, the spirit will see to it that you remember to take your vitamins.
The ego doesn't.
It takes credit for it.
But it's really the spirit acting through your wife.
Who sees to it that you eat and all those things?
She has a big thing about eating, I don't know, every few days I suppose.
Because people are concerned about the body.
If you're not concerned about the body, other people worry about it.
If you need to eat something, somebody will tell you that.
So you don't have to think about when will I eat next or what am I going to eat next
because it's all handled.
It's all handled by the nature of life.
So I want everybody here to feel profoundly safe.
You're safe from your past.
Is there anybody here who lacks a decent regret for the past?
I'll help them.
Anybody?
Anybody who doesn't have a decent regret for the past?
We just confirmed that that's all you need.
You don't have to invoke God's mercy, right?
You don't have to invoke the mercy of an electrostatic condenser.
When you put a charge, it crackles.
When there's no charge, it doesn't crackle.
You don't say, oh dear electrostatic condenser, give me the presence of thy presence.
The past is over.
So you only have to look at the future.
The future you surrender to God
so you don't have to worry about that.
That leaves you in the present, whatever that is.
Does anybody have any thoughts about the present?
You have to make one up, don't you?
You don't really have any thoughts about the present.
Alright, so if you give up wallowing in the past
and trying to rewrite history and make yourself look better,
cleaner, brighter, and smarter,
and if you don't have to worry about your survival in the future,
and nothing's going on in the present as you can see,
don't worry.
Then there's nothing for the mind to think about.
The mind becomes silent.
Actually, the mind doesn't have to become silent.
The mind is silent.
What are you doing there?
Shading the screen.
Oh, I see what you're doing.
I thought you were sending me mysterious signals or something.
Don't think about it.
Well, you see, when you have to think,
all of a sudden a thought comes out.
It says,
it's a thought of curiosity.
What is she doing with that car there?
So I don't have to worry that I won't think about things
when I should think about things.
You understand?
You surrender your thoughts to God
because they aren't worth anything anyway
other than E equals MC squared,
and you don't know what that means anyway.
All I'm saying is we take certain things on faith.
We take certain things on faith.
That somebody who has been there
will tell you how it is,
and you just say,
oh, the big mistake is to argue with them.
Marco Polo went to China, he came back,
and I'm sure a lot of people thought he was making up stories,
but that was their problem.
I've been to China,
just the way he said it was.
The Chinese are very Chinese-y.
That's all I can say.
Things are, so.
Faith and confidence, then,
in wisdom.
So what we're talking about is faith and confidence in wisdom.
And we'll talk about what wisdom is,
how it expresses itself
in spiritual teachings.
Yeah.
Where were we?
We were talking about not thinking,
which leads us in the middle of nowhere, doesn't it?
Where do we go from here?
How many people are here for the first time?
Oh, my gracious me, oh, my, oh, my.
Well, then we'll have to hurry up.
Okay.
On with the slides.
We're working on a new book,
and, uh,
well, it's gonna be something.
Just trying to decide on a title.
Wow.
Wow, how about that?
Okay.
So the map of consciousness is all over the Internet.
I don't know how to work the Internet, but people do.
And they give me all these things.
So we're all over the Internet,
all different languages.
So whatever we're talking about seems to have
some general recognition of its essential truth
and its usefulness.
Mankind has never had any means
of discerning truth from falsehood.
Even now,
the capacity to discern truth from falsehood
is limited to a small percentage of the population.
The kinesiologic technique,
which itself calibrates at 600,
and therefore is not explicable in logical terms,
it is only useful
if, for people whose own consciousness
calibrates 200 or over.
So that eliminates about 85,
80% of the world, 85% of the world.
So, and then the question itself
has to be integrous as far as motive.
So two people who are integrous
ask an integrous question,
and the way they get a correct answer
is because they're dedicated to truth
rather than looking for a position.
A positionality or a gain.
Many people usually don't get the right answers
because of the intention behind it,
which is rather glaringly obvious very often.
The way to get the correct answer is
to say in the name of the highest truth,
in the name of the highest truth,
I ask, O Lord, is
this or that or the other thing.
So then you make a statement,
and you ask the person to quickly resist,
and as we said
before, the acupuncture system
is very, very rapid.
So if I hold something in mind
and press down her arm,
it's a flash down.
She's strong right for a moment,
but if I keep pushing,
that moment is over.
So some people wait too long.
So when we demonstrate it,
you see how quickly we do it.
We say we just want to confirm
the validity of this,
that what we just said is true.
I don't have to tell her what I'm holding in mind.
I can say to her,
what I'm holding in mind is true.
All right, let's do it now.
What I'm holding in mind now is true.
What I'm holding now in mind is true.
She doesn't know what I was holding in mind.
She doesn't know if I'm holding a hippopotamus,
a zebra.
No way of knowing.
It's quick and easy.
Some people are adept at it, others are not.
It's like riding a bicycle.
Some people are good at it.
They get on the first time.
It's like riding a horse.
I tried riding a horse for years.
I got thrown about 20 times.
Horses and I didn't get along until just recently.
Recently, horses and I kissed and made up a course.
This horse actually was loving.
I said, whoa, a loving horse?
One reason I didn't like them,
they never seemed to be loving.
But this horse was actually affectionate.
I said, holy cats.
We took it.
We have a picture of it.
This horse actually gave me a kiss.
In that instant, horses and myself,
now I have a lovely relationship.
I haven't ridden one since.
My orthopedist doesn't recommend it.
One more fall, Doc, and you've had it.
Let's go on to number two.
We're going to quickly run through the slides
for those who haven't been here before.
Spiritual work.
I'm putting this in my right-hand pocket.
You're all witness.
This is my thingy.
It's like a mudra.
It isn't what you do.
It isn't some performance.
It's the way you are.
The way you are.
Your life is a presentation to divinity,
to be the best that you can be
at the moment that you are what you are.
Your life then is like a mudra.
Your life is like a sacred gift to the world and to God
that you are being all that you can be at any given moment.
The sacredness of all of life then
allows you to see the sacredness of your own.
That commitment to contextualize that that's why you're here,
to be all that you can be at any moment,
to realize the divinity of all things,
to see the beauty of all creation,
to leave judgment up to God,
liberates you from thinking this,
the disease called thinking this.
All right, let's go to the next.
This was a contribution from Mr. Selinsky
whose name has been chopped off the bottom.
He translated the consciousness levels.
You remember I said they had to become logarithmic
because the numbers are so huge, logarithmic.
It's a logarithmic scale.
And we tried to give comparative in microwatts,
you know, just because people are used to such things.
We're really talking about a nonlinear domain,
but to make it more comprehensible,
we tried to relate it in comparative figures
to like the electromagnetic spectrum.
Now, in the things we write and all,
people tend to become literal.
They tend to miss the forest for the trees.
Don't focus on the trees.
The things that we're trying to illustrate
is so you get the gist of it.
The gist of it.
All right, so what he did was he translated...
He's very good at mathematics.
I am not very good at mathematics.
I don't like mathematics, even.
I hate mathematics.
All right, because it's so pedestrian.
You're limited to trudging through the linear world.
I mean, it's...
When you're used to living free like a bird
in the nonlinear world,
it's a drag to have to figure everything out.
You know what I mean?
Anyway, he correlated it in microwatts
using more advanced mathematics.
The answers we got were using kinesiology,
which would make any dyed-in-the-wool scientist shudder.
That's where I figure out certain things.
I say, how much do I owe the government?
Kinesiology.
That's the right figure.
I've got employees that never give me a charge card.
I say, how much do we owe you?
Then we get the right amount.
I write them a check.
Everybody's happy.
No problem.
All right, so what he found was
when he really...
The mathematics are not on here.
I don't know what happened to them.
They fall off the bottom here.
But the mathematics is quite advanced.
So he calibrated them,
and you see the levels of consciousness
sort of form a...
Look how they go from 100 to 200.
And then suddenly...
So you see them and suddenly at 500,
you see it shoot up like this,
and then at 600, it reaches almost infinity.
Okay, we'll go on to the next one.
I don't know what that means,
but I thought it looked earlier.
Here's where most of mankind is in the dark.
Here's his consciousness level.
Where are we at?
207, did I say?
207.
So you see the percentage of mankind over here
that is above 207
is actually quite minimal.
And the great mass of mankind
is behind us in the learning curve.
Instead of good and evil,
in terms of learning curve.
So 15% of mankind is above consciousness level 200.
Next slide.
And Karen in our office made these graphics.
You get that the 15% is counterbalancing the 85%.
Their creativity, their power, their productivity.
This is the power that counterbalances the world
because the power of integrity
is far greater than that of non-integrity.
Also, now you understand the power of capitalism.
And the answer to Karl Marx,
this is not exploiting this.
This is holding it up.
One brilliant idea creates more capital
than all the banks in the world are holding.
Thomas Edison, one thought.
Think of the giant economic productivity
of one brilliant thought.
Capital exists in the mind and not in the bank.
One brilliant thought followed up by Antigris.
The rest of it is just automatic.
So this is the 15% that holds up the 85%.
Okay, what's next?
We got a new thing here called PowerPoint.
It's a mysterious new electronic gadget.
We used to flip these transparencies around.
I don't see even the transparency flipper anymore.
We're on our own.
This is called the PowerPoint thing.
And we're going to get into silent mind.
You see, you have to understand how the ego works.
And one way it works is by duality.
And it sees everything as opposites.
It doesn't see things as comparisons.
It sees them as opposites.
You see?
So in politics, if people would say,
you know, this is the way I see it
and the way I would go,
and why I would go that way,
you know, politics would be Antigris.
Instead, they think, instead of doing that,
they just hate this one.
Or this one hates this one.
I would say, you don't have to hate vanilla
because you like chocolate better.
You have to just tell people why chocolate is better than vanilla,
but you don't have to hate vanilla.
All right, so here we have
people think of heat, hot and cold
as opposites, opposites.
So the mind thinks dualistically.
It sets up a positionality
and then divides everything
into dualistic pairs, polarities.
This against that.
Not this and that, but this against that.
So actually we see there's only one variable.
We see with heat, where's my pointer thing?
I got to really get used to working this thing.
You see this thing here?
All right, there's only one variable.
There isn't hot versus cold.
There's only heat, the presence of heat
and the absence of heat.
There's not two opposites of hot and absence of hot.
There's no such thing.
The kinesiologic response then
is like electricity going down a wire.
There is no opposite to on.
When you turn off electricity,
no offness runs down the wire.
It's either there or it ain't.
It's a presence or the absence of a quality.
And here we have desirability.
If you desire something, it's precious.
If you don't desire it, you think it's awful.
Okay, now PowerPoint.
Oh, this is another example.
You don't have good versus evil.
You've got desirability.
And the most obvious one to see is light.
There's only one quality of light.
It's either present or it diminishes and it's absent.
The same with truth.
Truth either prevails
or it becomes muddied and becomes absent.
All right.
So that takes care of duality.
That is to take care of it for everybody.
We said in previous lectures
that one can realize
the real way to become silent
is to become
the potentiality of that which you are
and accept what I tell you,
that you're perfectly safe.
The past doesn't mean diddly.
The future isn't here.
And in the present, nothing's going on.
So there's another way
and that is by reflection, inner reflection.
By inner reflection,
one will begin to realize
that the mind is silent at all times.
If the mind were not silent,
you wouldn't know that you were thinking anything
because it's against the background of silence
that you think you experience a thought.
The mind itself then is the field
in which thought occurs.
It's the silence,
the backdrop of silence.
And we'll explain thoughts a little bit later,
but thoughts,
just prior to a thought,
is where you'll notice the silence.
This silence can be noticed
no matter what you're doing.
As I'm talking right now,
the mind is really in a field of silence
so that I'm listening to what's being said.
I haven't the slightest idea.
People say,
what are you going to talk about?
How would I know what I'm going to talk about?
Tell us what you're going to talk about.
They want three paragraphs
sent to their church
to announce what you're going to talk about.
How would I know what they're going to talk about?
I can make a presumption,
so I send them some wild thing.
I don't want to tell them the truth
that I have the slightest idea.
I hear it at the same time you do.
Sometimes it's funny.
I get a kick out of it when it's funny.
And sometimes it's a crack up.
Just the funniest thought comes out of nowhere
and it just cracks me up.
People say you laugh at your own jokes.
They're not my jokes.
I don't know where they come from.
They crack me up.
If they were my joke,
they wouldn't crack me up.
No, they're not my joke.
That's real so funny.
At all times,
even though you're thinking
or think you're thinking,
the mind is actually silent.
98% of the mind is silent
even when you think you're thinking.
You think it's all your mind is thinking.
No, it's about 1 or 2%.
1.85 to 3.6%.
I like how obsessive,
make obsessive-impulsive happy.
I thought you said 1.8.
No, no, it's 1.92.
It's an itty-bitty part of your mind
is what's thinking.
It's about this much of your mind here is thinking.
The rest of it is entertainment.
All right, so if only 1 or 2% of your mind is thinking,
then how does it have so much,
seem to have so much power over you?
It doesn't have any power.
You give it the power in the secret.
I'll give you the secret of what the power is.
It's called hypnosis.
Hypnosis.
I tell you.
Watch my fingers.
Sleep.
Peace.
Wake up.
Okay.
This 1% keeps you seduced.
It traps you.
It's a lure.
It's good to be paranoid about your mind.
It's up to no good.
So long as it's got you boom-boggled,
it survives.
When it stops having you entranced
in its hypnotic condition, lure,
it stops.
So its days are numbered.
The mind knows its days are numbered.
The ego knows its days are numbered.
Consequently, it's frantic to keep you going
with a new worry, a new anxiety,
a new guilt.
And how does it do it?
It izes everything.
It izes everything, I call it,
and it seduces you through guilt,
excitement, promise, lascivious images.
That sounds good.
Lascivious images.
Oh.
MTV.
There you go.
When it's got nothing else to do,
you'll see your mind will resort
to one of the things on the bullet board.
It'll politicize everything.
It'll moralize.
Isn't that awful?
It'll idealize how things should be.
It's going to hypothesize and rewrite history.
It's going to romanticize things.
And one of its favorite entertainments
is to criticize.
Wasn't that awful?
And here's drama.
Dramatizes, emotionalizes things.
Emotionalizes.
People love to get on TV and blubber.
Blubber.
They do that.
They emotionalize.
They dramatize.
And they do that by catastrophizing.
Catastrophizing.
Then you theorize how it should be.
And you rationalize.
And then you fantasize.
You infantilize.
Intellectualize.
You mentalize everything.
You idealize it.
And you glamorize the whole process
and say, I'm thinking.
Don't bother me.
I'm thinking.
We glamorize things.
Exaggerate them because we prize them.
We like to victimize and demonize things.
So the wise give up izing.
The mind keeps going.
It's got you hypnotized.
So just to know,
98% of your mind is silent.
There's only 1 or 2%.
It has no power over you
except the hypnotic fascination
that you project to it.
So we glamorize.
You know, Alice Bailey's book on glamor
is probably the best one out of that whole series
or one of the greatest.
And it was described by some spiritual teacher
in the celestial realm.
The energy of glamor.
It doesn't exist in the thing itself.
It's something we project onto it.
So we glamorize and exaggerate
the importance of our mind.
Make it a wonderful, wonderful thing.
Our thoughts are really precious.
Precious.
Precious thoughts.
Okay, let's go on to the next.
All right.
The mind has different styles
depending on what level of consciousness
you're talking about.
In a group like this,
the Newtonian paradigm is the big barrier.
Few people escape to level 500.
What do we say?
Point, no.
4%.
4% of the population
ever transcend to level 500.
4%, huh.
And to level 540, unconditional love,
0.4%.
So why is it so few people
transcend the barrier of the intellect at 500?
As we've said,
Einstein calibrated 499.
Sir Isaac Newton, 499.
The great scientific geniuses of all time, 499.
Great books of the Western world
run around the 460s, around there.
So, 499.
So the intellect now, first of all,
brings people up from the bottom.
So each level of consciousness, then,
is an improvement over the other.
Therefore, there's no point of demonizing it
because if you don't have enough energy to hate,
you're going to lay down there and die.
You're going to be in apathy
because the first rule of the ego is survival.
And so the levels of consciousness, then,
you transcend one.
So each one is not bad.
It's not bad in itself.
Each one is an improvement over the one below it.
Unless you can get angry,
you're going to be in apathy.
Apathy.
That's why what's going on in Haiti right now
is good.
Why?
Because angriness and rebellion
is an improvement over abject dying of poverty and AIDS
and just laying there listlessly
without enough energy to even feed yourself,
which is what happens at the bottom.
So angriness is a way up over something.
Then, once you get beyond that,
you don't need angriness anymore
and you give it up for courage.
And you give up courage for valor.
And you give up all those things.
So each level serves its purpose biologically,
you might say,
and disappears when you've transcended it.
What's happening up there?
Holy...
My God.
Wow.
That's the Newtonian mind expressing itself.
Okay, I hear you.
The Newtonian mind, then,
is a tremendous advance.
Tremendous advance.
To be able to think logically,
to know the rules of logic.
See,
rationality is really a dialectic.
Dialectic.
In which bringing the question
gets you voted out
of the debating team
because that's a violation
of the dialectic
of logic.
The undistributed, middle,
all those kind of things.
So logic has certain rules
which are similar to mathematics.
And people fall below
intellectual integrity.
So intellectual integrity
really begins in the 400s, 410,
and then around 460,
you see that's really
intellectual integrity.
So I know people prefer to hate George Bush,
but I know they hate to hear it,
but he does calibrate at 460
so he follows what
in his world is logic.
Logic.
It says here, by the oath of office,
I should do this, he does that.
That's his duty.
Other people see their mission differently.
But people in the mid-400s
consider their world
to be logical, scientific,
provable,
based on evidence, etc.
And so the Newtonian
paradigm of reality
is orderly and logical
it sees things as separate.
Spiritually,
the downside it is
of Newtonian is it divides
the world into a dualistic
of this causing of that.
So long as you think there's a this causing of that,
you'll be stuck in duality
and you will think there's a separate
ego within yourself, separate from God,
of this causing of that.
We'll have to transcend
that this morning, too.
Quantum mechanics is then an advance
from the Newtonian paradigm
still within the linear world
in which you see
that things are not happening in an orderly fashion.
They're unpredictable.
What you're dealing with really is
likelihoods, but not certainties.
The Newtonian paradigm
promises certainty.
And within certain limitations
it does bring you to certainty.
However,
the world we live in
is not ruled by Newtonian
paradigm.
We live in a biologically real
earthly world
in which subjectivity
is actually the
most prominent factor.
It is subjectivity that gives
Newtonian
the Newtonian paradigm
its credence.
In and of itself it has no credence,
but subjectively we value it
as highly useful.
Quantum mechanics,
we go beyond that. We see that
in the world of biology,
in the world in which we exist,
subjectivity of our own existence.
Then, things are really quite
disorderly, unpredictable.
They're not bound.
And the most important
thing is the Heisenberg principle.
The discovery that
things change just by sheer observation.
The effect of consciousness.
That's where
Einstein bucked.
Einstein did not want to accept that
he said, I prefer to think there's
an independent universe out there
that exists independently of human consciousness.
And so he refuted it.
So he stayed at 499.
Alright, so
quantum mechanics says that
you can't
predict the next thing
that will happen with certainty.
If there's one digit off
in the 26th decimal point
and you run that through your computer
enough times, bang, you'll get a response
that's way out there.
As people break their backs
high diving discover 13 jumps
killed on the 14th.
Right in Sedona.
I've told this story before.
Two guys that used to be off
what you would call a drive there
back of the Pizza Hut.
And if you had a rattlesnake in your yard
he'd call them up.
They would come over for nothing.
They would get the rattlesnakes.
And they did this for years.
And one of the guys
got bitten 19 times.
19 times.
And the 20th time killed him.
20th time.
So out of all of them
you presume I must now be immune.
No.
He wasn't immune.
Yep.
That's why I tell people
to avoid extreme sports unless you're ready to go.
You're ready to go.
Enough high dives
and just as you go off
the diving board
you suddenly remember
you forgot your mother's
you forgot a Mother's Day card
and that split 1 50th of a second
breaks your back.
So I just don't
I'm not too hot on extreme sports
because I understand quantum mechanics.
Quantum mechanics says
if you do it often enough
sooner or later it will get you.
And of course we know the many sports stars
who push the envelope
and they rack up.
It's the fact that they have driven
400 races
successfully
that the 401th kills them.
It's because of the success
of the 400
that the 401 kills them.
So that's enough
of the grim side of quantum mechanics
let's go to something happier.
These are the enlightening
the scale only goes up to 600
and then we calibrated
the higher levels.
See because to many people
God is an imagination
that somebody thought up somewhere
and it's a big oppressor.
The way God is presented
he is an oppressor from many points
of the presentation.
Instead of the liberator
he is the great oppressor
the great feared God of judgment day.
So we just wanted to calibrate
reality
the verifiability
of spiritual realities
so with kinesiology
then we got
the enlightenment happens at 600
and beyond here
the numbers of people
are small
but their impact is very often large.
Consciousness in mankind
goes up to a thousand
and the reason it doesn't go beyond a thousand
is because the human nervous system
is not equipped for it.
Up to about 700 it's blissful
kundalini energy flows
and it's exquisite
exquisite
takes you right out of the world
and from there on up
from there on up for some reason
consciousness may continue
usually it does not
most people over 600
will leave the body
right then
you don't need to stay there
like a near death experience
you don't have to re-own the body
about 50% won't survive at all
they just let it topple over
but if surrounding conditions
make sure you eat and all that kind of stuff
the body will survive
then it stays where it is
Ramana Maharishi, Nisargadatta Maharaj
all those are calibrated in 700
so up to about here
the condition is
exquisite
and then sometimes it continues on up
and then it is not exquisite
it is extraordinarily painful at times
excruciatingly painful
and the Buddha said that
Christ striped blood
and from there on up
the human nervous system is just not equipped
to handle energies
over 700
and to go over that level
causes a great deal of
suffering, inner suffering
anyway, gradually the nerves do begin
to develop
greater capacity
they pull in more protein molecules
and they actually do modify
but it takes some years
it takes some years
and the techniques advance
so it is better to not worry about that
here in this realm
it is better to go to some heavenly realm
and do that
so then just for fun
we asked what is an archangel
we got 50,000 and up
50,000 and up, yeah
and I was in the pits of hell
and I asked
if there is a God
I prayed to him for help
I was in the pits of hell
eternal hell
the pits of hell are eternal
experientially eternal
eternal with no hope
the certainty of no hope
is so profound
you will never
leave this state ever
and you get what ever means
and then dread
takes on a dimension
you didn't know it could take
and out of that
the voice within said
if there is a God I ask him for help
and then out of that
oblivion
and then out of oblivion and nothingness
suddenly the infinite presence
I don't know
why I got into that anyway
that heaven and hell
are then experiential
while still in a physical body
people worry about it later
it's experiential right here right now
by virtue of one's own decisions
let's move on to the next one
oh yes
Archangel
that's what started that
I always think some cruising Archangel
some Archangel cruising by
heard this little
flippy thought
if there is a God I ask him for help
and he went hmm
and went on
knocked me out of the world for 30 years
30 years I never said anything
I was silent within
I left the world and came out here
hmm
never mentioned anything until 1995
it just is such a shock
it's just like pow
the power of it hits you
and the mind is knocked silent
so the silence of the mind is the automatic consequence
of a automatic consequence
of a level of consciousness
which transcends thinkingness
in that state
there is nothing to think
there is no person to think
there is no somebody to think
because somebody-ness is left
there is no person to think
there is no this to think about
or that
so thinkingness is not
part of that state
through witnessing then
we begin to see
the mind looks at form
it registers form
it recognizes it
and some spiritual teachers say
identify with this here the watcher
the observer and the witness
instead of being part of the content of the mind
merely witness it
we'll move to the next exciting slide
we'll move to the next
exciting slide
what
the maps
oh yeah we'll do everything
this is our home team here
did the maps come up next
oh yes well this is quite
you know we predicted Haiti
a couple of years ago
we said here's North America
the calibrated levels
of consciousness
I think there's group karma
there's group karma
you belong to a group
by virtue of your level of consciousness
because you're ascribed to that
then that group comes on the planet
tends to be in certain areas on the planet
does what it does
either improves its karmic potential
or makes it worse
then we tend to come back again
in karmic groups
let's see if that's so
in the name of the highest good
we have to be a person
there is like group karma
what we're seeing
right in Haiti now
is like group karma
all the great tragedies on mankind
here you've got the western hemisphere
you see Greenland
345, America
Canada 410, 420
Central America in the 300s
you're not going to get any trouble
from the whole western hemisphere here
they're in the high 200s, they're all over 200
right in the middle of it
you've got to turn this thing on here
there
we said wow like a big boil
on your leg
here's trouble
you've got a 55 in the middle of the 300s
and the 400s
we said that a year or two ago
55 then
so this is some karmic group
that comes on this way
and they've got to evolve beyond it
what can we do to help Haiti
well I think
you know
to try and inspire
through beauty, through excellence
through demonstrating compassion
etc.
we're going to send troops there
I don't know what our troops are going to do in Haiti
but they're going to go there I guess
it's really strange
we let Mexicans cross the border
but you don't let Haitians cross the border
if they're trying to swim to safety
why do we put them back
I don't know, we do that with Cuba
there's the peculiarities of politics
which I understand
and I don't really want to understand them
not bad enough as it is
anyway so we have our preferences
and our favorites
and that's human nature
so right in the middle of all these numbers
you've got a 55
and they stand out so strongly
you know that's got to be some kind of a karmic group
and there's certain things about their culture
that would make 55
you would understand why it's 55
I've been there
and there's certain things about their culture
that would pretty much guarantee that
ok let's go to the next one
exciting trip around the world
we calibrate all the
countries in the world
all the continents
and we learn a great deal
here's Australia at 410
here you've got 405
here you've got India at 355
you've got China at 305
you know China is evolving
China is really coming out of the
Marxian collapse
and the mayoism
the collective farms
the downside of
Karl Marx calibrated at 130
so the downside of Marxism is
is starvation
and revolution and disaster
and in the great books of the rest of the world
Marx stands out
they're all in the 400s
and Marx is at 130
so if by their fruits you shall know them
I wouldn't say too much for
Marxism as a lifestyle
anyway we see that China is evolving
they have increasing property rights
civil rights
etc
religion and spirituality is still not
welcomed there
because it's sort of a threat to the
strict secularism
to get the book Power Versus Force
published in China
I was told you've got to clean God out of the whole thing
and divinity
and just express it as energy consciousness
energy
replace God with higher energy
and you can get posed in China
as long as you've got God in there
so they've got a way of
censoring things
yeah but still
China has come up a long way
now it has a new
premiere
there was a group we were at in California
some years ago
of course the miracles group
and we decided the group would take on China
take on China as a
group project
since then China has come up
so I don't want to thank anybody
who's here from California for that miracles group
if it wasn't for you folks
China would still be down
below 200
so the new premiere of China
is moving ahead
so you get very interesting theory
here you have Mongolia up here
great expanses
here's where the trouble is
we said North Africa
North Africa is where the trouble is
it's basically a large karmic group
you've got two countries
one at 190 and one at 192
constantly warring at each other
but they've been doing that for
a couple thousand years
so I don't know if they're going to
decide to stop or not
but anyway they get too much out of it
the whole country is built on
built on the structure
of strife and conflict
and hatred
and we blow up a busload of children
and they bomb our school
and the police
and they send a rocket
so that's a whole lifestyle
if they wanted to stop it
they would
people tell you one thing
but if that was so
it would be so
so it's not so
and we get to this
they calibrate it 190 and 185
which is below the level of integrity
so whatever they say is not so
it serves that positionality
so it's very interesting to them
see here's Uganda
I don't know where the UN is
where all these things are happening
and people want to turn our country over at 421
to the UN which calibrates about 195
it doesn't make any sense to me at all
I mean where are they with Haiti
where are they with Uganda
I don't know what they do
they pass out parcels of food
so they're like an extension to me of the Red Cross
and they do a lot of good
but I wouldn't turn the rule of our country over to them
alright so here you've got Africa
and here you've got Europe
and here you've got Uganda
you see you're around 50 or so
the slaughtering of people there
so
you see the calibrated levels then
show a distribution somehow
now Europe has become secularized
where is Europe here
what happened to Europe
300 is up in here
see America
the constitution of the United States
calibrates around 700
the highest of any country in the world
the government itself calibrates extremely high
you can criticize it
but it's a matter of fact
if you calibrate it's the highest in the world
it is integrity by intent
doesn't mean that it's perfect
doesn't mean that it's saintly
it's not saintly
a government is not supposed to be saintly
it's supposed to protect its people
alright so here we have
what happens with non-integrity
then is
things go downhill
but they only go downhill a little bit
if you stop at saintly
secularism then you're in
usually the high 200s or 300s
that means
it doesn't mean you're not responsible
it's just that you eliminate God
from the equation
you eliminate God from the equation
which is from a certain viewpoint
it's fine with me
I don't care if they do it
God doesn't care about it
so whatever they want to do
alright let's move on to the next country
so here's the western hemisphere again
I don't know why it recurred
well let's go on
we already saw the western hemisphere
here's the other hemisphere
well because I thought these are easier to read
the other was too full of data
you see New Zealand and Australia
would be good places to live
wouldn't they
anything that's 400
all these higher calibrations
if you want to retire
I would retire to a higher calibration
here's where it's 40
it's not a good place to retire
there are the
what do you call those things
gorillas
and the gorillas calibrate
higher than the people there
I would rather sit for breakfast
with a mountain gorilla
than the people who work there
alright we'll move on to the next
so we can't say
anything about it
except that
if we study the world
this is what we find
and North Africa we spend a little extra time on
because you know it's so much in the news
Iraq and all such like
and
a couple of the countries I was talking about
you see are at the top
and you can see they are not devoted to peace
and therefore all this
conversation about it is conversation
and Iraq as a country
was also far
away from peace
Syria has come up since we did this map
if you recalibrate Syria
you'll see it came up
and Gaddafi has somehow gotten religion all of a sudden
for which we're all quite happy
to tell you the truth
Time magazine came out
so let's go to the next one
in the trouble zones
we're in North Africa
where we've experienced them
so we ask now what is the truth
you see because the human mind
can't tell truth from falsehood
the human mind is impressionable
the masters of rhetoric
you know rhetoric political persuasiveness
has been
a formal study
well in the year 350 BC
so for the book I'm doing now
I'm very sharp on it
I had to reread Plato, Aristotle and Socrates
and the refutation
of the argument
the philosophic position of the sophist
and
what could be
saved from all of that
would be some
rhetoric
the good side of rhetoric
is that you present truth in a way
that is palatable to the audience
now
truth is not always palatable
to the audience
in fact truth is often
the last thing people want to hear
so I warn people
I warn people
if you're interested in truth
then you have to pull in
positionalities
the name of the new book
I'm forgetting what it is already
it's going to be truth versus fallacy
truth versus fallacy
you decide something like that
it's always
truth versus fallacy
what happened to the war
oh okay
we were doing World War II
so you can take all the events
of any major thing in history
they say if you haven't learned from history
you have to repeat it
and we see mankind has repeated it
over and over again
so what is the lesson that we should have learned
so that this doesn't keep repeating itself
we learned that
peace is the automatic consequence of truth
the automatic consequence of falsity
it's as simple as that
where truth prevails
peace prevails
because it's an automatic consequence of truth
so peace is not something
you can force on people
or we'll kill you
let's see
because the Iraqi war is still somewhat
emotionalized in people's minds
we should probably stay away from it
and what we do
we'll go back to my earlier life
and see how did people calibrate
and how did a war
the greatest war in history
kill more people than any other war
how could such a thing happen
so we put the calibrations
we just calibrated people
and you see very interesting things
you see Winston Churchill at 510
now Winston Churchill
when he said
in England before World War II
that war is coming and you'd better get yourself
ready for it
they thought
Hitler was a war monger
so they threw him out
and they brought in a gentleman
who said he was going to bring peace in our times
peace in our times
and that was Neville Chamberlain
so
Churchill was a realist
he says I don't like the idea of it
but you know frankly folks
Hitler's going to take over
and we'd better be prepared
he was thrown out as a war monger
and the pacifists who calibrated 145
as exempted by Neville Chamberlain
at 185
became friendly with Hitler
when Erwin Churchill's hand
they signed a peace treaty
anybody who signs a peace treaty
with somebody who calibrates
let's see
by the end of the war
Adolf Hitler calibrated about 145
so here you got somebody
who's in denial
at 185 full of sophistry
all about peace and all that stuff
and you're signing a contract
with this guy here
and so you've got
what you've got is
wishful thinking naivete
oh if we're just nice to them
they'll be nice to us
so damn
he'll be nice to us
he won't torture people
to death so slowly
right
oh so delusion
so that when the chips fell
then
the war started
and they had to pull Winston out
Winston was at 510
wow
well we did
what is the energy of
when we spoke at Oxford
we stopped off in Scotland
and did
the Scottish Tattoo
which is a military musical
extravaganza
put on in front of the palace
once a year
and we heard 100 bagpipes
imagine 100 pipers
walking across
the sound of it just made the hair on the back of your head stand right up
and we said
what is magical
there's something different about the sound of bagpipes
that has nothing to do with music
no
the most dreaded sound
in the history of warfare
is the sound of another army coming towards you
with the background of the sound of bagpipes
more scary
than the screams of the
Viking warriors
more terrifying than any
when you because there's an energy field
at 505
it's not hatred
you better make sure you've
signed your will
is death
you see is not just courage
so the average warrior
transcends fear
we've all walked into a hail of bullets
knowing
because that's how you get over 200
the one in childbirth does the same thing
she knows she's risking her life
most women in history
died in childbirth
so by the act of heroism
for others
for the sacredness of life
she puts her life
on the line
and frankly she used to lose it often
she lost it often
In the family Bible I have at home, the man was often married three or four times,
and many of the children died.
So the man goes over 200 when he's willing to face death for some higher principle,
honor, love of country, to defend the homeland.
505 is something else.
505 is valor.
Valor calibrates 505.
In valor, you're not trying to prove anything.
You don't have to prove that you're not subject to fear anymore.
You proved that long ago at Calibration 11-200.
Now, 505 is being what you are in the face of all that is,
the courage to be exactly who you are.
It's extremely powerful.
So you see Winston at 510 was the,
hmm,
was the spiritual strength of the bulldog.
The bulldog.
Roosevelt very close to him at 500.
President Truman, God bless him, he inherited a terrible problem.
He had to decide about the nuclear bomb.
Nobody envied him.
And that involves triage.
Are you going to kill 200,000 to save the life of 6 or 7 million or not?
Nobody likes to be faced.
Every triage, every physician faces it.
I faced it many a time.
The life of the mother, the life of the child.
So triage then is, was the problem that Truman faced.
And happily, he was at 495, which nobody would have predicted.
I remember my father's description of Truman as being a haberdasher from someplace.
Oh, God help us, he says.
A haberdasher from Missouri or whatever.
God help us.
Well, when called upon,
the energy came up in Truman.
And he did the impossible.
None of us would want his decision.
If he said no, 7 million people would have died.
7 million because you had the moral cowardice not to say yes.
If you say yes, you're going to be vilified in history as having killed 200,000 people.
So you're either going to be attacked one way or the other.
So should it be for the death of 200,000 or the death of 7 million?
Because the estimated death...
The death rate if we invaded Japan was at least 7 million, yeah?
So then we have MacArthur and all these people.
We can see Wernher von Braun, Heisenberg, the U.S. military.
The concept of triage itself is not well understood in America.
It's understood very well in medicine.
Los Alamos, you can see what the intention of all these people were.
Interesting, you see the kamikaze pilot.
You see the kamikaze pilot.
The pilot was already an integrous warrior.
So was the Luftwaffe, integrous warrior.
They didn't do it to prove anything.
They did it out of duty.
Hirohito's right on the edge at 200.
Tojo's at 205.
And Yamamoto had a certain amount of wisdom
because right from the beginning he said,
well, we're going to lose this war.
Yamamoto was not popular because he said,
we're going to lose.
He saw that right from the beginning.
We've awakened the sleeping giant.
Now let's see what else is going on here.
You see Oppenheimer, you know,
then there were double agents in Los Alamos.
You can look at pictures of people and calibrate
and tell who's going to be the double agent
because their consciousness is out.
So they can disguise their appearance
and what they do and what they say,
but they cannot disguise their level of consciousness.
So if you want people to work on a secret project
that puts all of mankind at risk,
you better calibrate their level of consciousness.
A lot of them are going to sell out,
and a certain number of them do.
The Cambridge Five sold out.
Those were the intellectuals coming out of England.
The traders all calibrated 40 or 50.
You see, the League of Nations wasn't doing much better
than the current, what do they call it, UN thing.
The League of Nations didn't do anything to stop World War II
any more than...
the UN's doing much of anything now.
Pacifism, the attack on Pearl Harbor.
Joseph Goebbels is very interesting
because we learn from history.
What Goebbels exploited was the naivete of the human mind.
He knew people can't tell truth from falsehood.
And if you repeat falsehood often enough,
people will believe it.
So that's the position, then, that the human ego gets into.
Because it has a warped view, it repeats it many times
and then becomes conditioned.
We see the London Blitz, Dr. Mengele, the Rosenbergs.
People still worry about the Rosenbergs.
And Lord Ha-Ha, I always got a kick out of calibrating him,
was 50.
Lord Ha-Ha, I forget his real name,
but he was a defector that used to be on radio
with pro-Nazi propaganda.
Okay, so that's World War II.
You see, if you do all the famous wars in history,
you learn incredibly important things.
What's the next one?
Break what?
We're going to take a break.