We'll speak more to the people over here
than we did before. I didn't realize you
couldn't hear.
Anybody has a problem, raise your hand.
Nobody has a problem.
There's a man with a problem. Come up
here where you can speak.
>> Mhm. Can you hear back there now?
>> Better. Okay. Maybe it's the microphone.
I should speak more directly into it or
louder.
>> What? What are they saying?
>> Oh, we should speak louder into the
megaphone.
>> Oh, okay.
Well, today we're going to trace the
evolution of consciousness
and its evolution over great eons of
time, you see,
and then how it manifests in the animal
kingdom and then how that progresses
through the homminids and through the um
evolutionary tree of man. evolutionary
tree of man and how that all comes about
and what that signifies for our current
reality. How many people are here for
the first time?
Oh wow, quite a few. All right. Um and
somebody asked me to speak to tell
something about myself. you know how you
got to be interested in such a thing and
all and got into such kind of research
and the kind of books I did
and so I'll give you a five minute
thumbnail scr stretch stretch scratch
pinch no WHAT
sketch five minute thumbnail sketch you
know
anyway we said the circumstances of
one's birth are karmically perfect
and that we get to see that life moves
from perfection to perfection. Yeah.
Well, okay. So, the what the world calls
this lifetime then was in 1927 in the
Midwest.
My grandfather was Episcopal minister, I
mean, bishop rather, and uh it was
rather
episcalable, very Episcopal, both high
and low at the same time. So,
one Sunday low church, next Sunday high
church.
Anyway, it was a very uh fiscal kind of
a family. They tend to be reserved, you
know, and they they mind their own
business.
which is the best thing you can say
about them. Yeah.
Anyway,
so anyway, uh nothing there was nothing
went on nothing went on and there was no
conscious awareness of existence until
age three.
At age three, suddenly out of
nothingness, out of voidness, out of
voidness arose, sudden awareness of
existence.
Stunning. Stunning. like coming out of
the dark into the dazzling sunlight, a
stunning awareness of existence and I
realized there I existed.
I was not pleased.
The preceding state was the void. I
never checked it with the arm. Let's do
with the arm. The preceding state was
the void. Okay. Out of voidness suddenly
there was consciousness aware of itself
as existence.
The instant there was the awareness of
existence arose simultaneously the fear
of non-existence.
It would seem that if one is it could
have come about then one would not have
come into existence and therefore at age
three I was confronted with the duality
of existence versus non-existence as the
ultimate reality.
which doesn't get solved until you get
to calibration level 850.
So
having nothing else to do and being
bored to death with childhood
and other children, I couldn't wait till
it was over with.
And uh so while their children played,
it seemed terribly boring and they
seemed to be very physically aggressive
and they were dirty little fingernails.
They were all sticking them in each
other's eyes and wrestling and
disgusting sweaty things like that.
So anyway,
I sat in a big chair by myself and read
Plato and Aristotle and Socrates and
Aris plays by Aristophan Aristophanes
and
it was concerned with the philosophy and
existentialism and God knows what signs
of misspent youth and uh
nevertheless life was physically arduous
in the Midwest,
you know, 20 below zero. I had the
biggest paper route in Wisconsin, 18
miles.
And uh 18 miles on bicycle every day out
in the out in the country. They didn't
have electricity on one side of the
highway.
So, uh, one night below zero, uh, fierce
blizzard and it was pitch black and the
papers blew out of my bicycle and blew
across the field
and I was frozen to death and uh, I
started to cry because the newspapers
were flying across the field and I
wouldn't be able to deliver them to the
customers.
So, there were the huge snow banks in
Wisconsin. The plows, you know, the
plows are as high as this room and the
snow piles up as the winter goes on. uh
15 ft high. So there was a crusty
snowbank and I bashed a hole in the
snowbank and I climbed in out of the
wind into the snow into a ko cave I made
just to get out of the furious wind and
uh
very shortly an incredible state came
over the mind stopped thinking
there was an infinite presence of such
exquisite beauty and such infinite are
and um
the presence was not different than that
which I was. I am
before all time, after all time, before
all universes, after all universes.
They which I am existed before all
universes
and will be after all universes have
disappeared.
True. Exist resist. True.
The realization of the infinite self is
the source of existence.
Uh
Sometime later, father uh in his 29
model Ford looking for his lost son in
the blizzard. Poor father
finds a snowbank and and I feel this
shaking on my ankle or something. And I
realized the father the father thinks
that I'm dying that I will if I don't
come back in the body if I don't
reactivate the body, reidentify with the
body, he will grieve and think that I
have died. Plus, I saw he would hold
himself responsible
and spend the rest of his life feeling
guilty.
So
I then resumed the the existence
and uh
then went on with academic career you
know I had a very good academic career
and uh
I forgot what I was going to even talk
about.
I forgot what I was going to talk about.
So anyway, unusual spiritual experiences
began at an early age. Oh, as I say,
yes, I was a scupulous episcipellian. I
was an acolyte of the bishop. I was a
boy soprano.
Sang Pontis Angelicus above a huge choir
in a cathedral incense full choir, full
orchestra. Unbelievable.
this voice floated out over the audience
like an angelic uh energy was going
through me you know I was the witness of
it so henceforth throughout life I've
always been the witness of the phenomena
that the world calls me or you you know
it's more that one is the witness of all
huh
but religiosity was there and with as I
mentioned this morning the downside of
Christianity was still strike strong in
the 30s uh sin and guilt was very big
penance and want saying the rosary, God
knows what,
but I was very devoted and scrupulous
and lived in dread and fear of sinning.
Sin was like on your soul and God could
see this blotch.
So I lived in dread that this black
blotch would appear on the soul screen
and God would see this
blotch there. So anyhow,
one day I was out in the woods by myself
and unasked, not even thinking about the
subject, just
wandering through the beauty of the
woods, all of a sudden came a
revelation. A revelation,
a revelation is a
an unfolding to your conscious awareness
out of nothing.
has no nothing preceding it, nothing
aftering.
Like the realization of the highest.
This came as a re revelation
of the totality of the suffering of all
of mankind throughout all of time.
It was overwhelming. And the
confrontation was beyond time, beyond
space.
The totality of the suffering of all
mankind presented as
a realization.
In that instant I became an atheist.
I said any god that could allow what I
have just realized
I could not worship. And I became a
devout atheist
and I went to Catholic
University, Jesuit University and got
straight A's in theology.
His idiots believe this crap,
but I got A's. The ones who believed it
got C's and I didn't believe it got A's.
That proves they're idiots.
It proves to the existence of of God by
Thomas Aquinus is child's play. You
could demolish that in about
a twominute argument.
First cause
doesn't have to be a first cause. It's a
category of thinking this man. Just jump
beyond that. You realize you don't
require a first cause.
Besides sort of cause causality is an
illusion of the Newtonian paradigm.
So then I went from atheist I became
more sophisticated and became an
agnostic.
Agnostic is an aging atheist.
You can't prove God exists. Well, you
can't prove he doesn't either. So
atheist is stupid. He thinks that God
doesn't exist and he can prove it. Well,
I'd like to hear him prove it. No, you
can't prove God doesn't exist because
the intellect which calibrates in the
400s is not the instrument. Theology
only calibrates in the 460s.
Love doesn't even start till the 500s.
And realization of the presence of
divinity as the oneness, the oneness of
the presence of God doesn't go on any
600. So here's a intellectualization
going on at 450 called theology trying
to prove the existence of God. It's
nonsensical to start with.
There was an intense uh drive to realize
the absolute truth of everything to that
there there was an intuitive knowingness
that there was a core of truth
throughout all of existence
and there was a drivenness to search out
and to discover the truth. exam having
examined theology, atheism, agnosticism,
theism, and religion, there wasn't too
much left.
The I read Zen and got into meditation
and then
in some kind of an intense drivenness
drove through meditation to go through
every single barrier.
And there upon that I descend into the
lower levels of hell.
Dante description of hell is absolutely
brilliantly accurate.
At the highest levels is torture and
death and destruction.
All of which is childless play.
Those are jacks openers. Beyond that
comes despair and then destin
destitution and then hopelessness.
And as you descend into the pits of
hell,
there is actually almost like a sign
there that says, "Abandon all hope ye
who pass this point."
And then you come to hopelessness.
But the hopelessness and the despair,
just like the highest levels, you're
beyond time. It goes on for eons. That
experience in the snowbank went on for
eons.
The experience of the depths of hell
beyond that point now also become
timeless.
You experience
an infinite agony of despair and
hopelessness from which there you know
there is no possible recovery. No
recovery is possible from this level of
hell.
Plus, it goes on for eternity.
You experience what eternity is. And if
you weren't scared crapless before, once
you understand what eternity is,
you turn to cold dread and absolute
despair.
In the depths of hell, the depths of
hell, as I said, are timeless. Go on for
eons.
A voice came forth from this
consciousness and said, "If there is a
God, I ask him for help.
After some period of time,
it's like oblivion took over again and
then
emerged out of oblivion and all
everything had changed.
dramatically that which had been the
self no longer existed. There was no
searcher after truth. There was no
person speaking. The mind was silent.
Instead, the divinity of all existence
radiated forth with a splendor.
The divinity of all that exists is
stunningly and and awesome.
And that prevailed
there where there once had been mind
a condition. It's a state uh a condition
that takes over
and from that henceforth the mind is
silent. So
at that time I had the biggest practice
in United States biggest psychiatric
practice.
I had 50 employees, had 2,000
outpatients, and saw a thousand new
patients a year. We had an advanced
research lab, clinical lab, sir.
And I lived a very elite lifestyle
on the north shore of Long Island and
with a suite of servants and incredible
housing. So,
and I left
Yeah,
I left to go someplace where it was
quiet and get adjusted to the state
because as you see the body moves itself
spontaneously. You see what it did
there? I don't know what it's going to
do. I don't know what the body does
until it does it. And actually, you
don't either,
but you think you do. That's the
difference.
There is nothing causing anything.
Everything happens of its own. There's
no knowing knowingness what's to be said
until one hears it.
Everything happens of its own.
Because the unmanifest becomes manifest.
The potentuality becomes the actuality.
And everything happens spontaneously of
its own. There's nothing thinking behind
the thinker. There's nobody ordering the
doingness
and any illusion like that disappears
into the reality.
So then there was years spend meditation
and per you might say perfecting the
state
and then the state began to move again
and there was the anguishes that would
arise
because beyond a certain level you're
you're not clearing your own karma and
your own psychological problems of your
ego but they start coming up out of the
collective unconscious uncollective
unconscious is and all of a sudden you
feel just horrible all over your whole
aura is a source of like pain pain
and you intuit it what it is that's out
you clear that intensely within yourself
in prayer and then it disappears.
So that's what keeps you busy when
you're not
busy with something else.
So well the first time when I saw
kinesiology people thought it was a
local phenomena. You see the Newtonian
paradigm is local. There's a this
causing a that.
When I saw the kinesiologic response I
recognized right away it's not it's not
a this causing a that. It's
consciousness responding to a stimulus.
Consciousness is like a giant
electrostatic condenser.
The charge of it arises to match and
equal the opposite charge of whatever is
presented to it.
The electrostatic field is still and
unmoving until you present it with the
charge.
That's the field of consciousness itself
infinite infinitely all powerful.
And I saw the one quality consciousness
like an electrostatic field only
recognizes one thing. It recognizes
truth and that's all. If you present it
with falsehood, her arm goes weak.
Not because it's a no, but because it's
a not yes
because it has no reality to it.
That's almost like a protoplasmic
response. The immune body withdraws from
that which is noxious and moves towards
that which is nutritious.
So then when we calibrated I calibrated
the levels of consciousness from one to
a thousand one was the beginning the
lowest possible it turned out to be a
bacteria
1,00 we said what's the highest level of
consciousness ever existed on the planet
came out it was 1,00 and that was the
great avatars Christ Buddha Krishna
Zoras
so on level from one to a thousand next
discovery was that at level 200 a
delineated truth and false. Anything
below 200 make you go weak. Everything
over 200 make you go strong.
I'll answer questions later.
There's probably important things I
forgot to tell you, but I don't remember
what they were.
When you get older, you sort of recall a
moment, but but that moment you've
forgotten the moment I just recalled it
blanked out. Oh, that was a senior
moment, but I forget what it was.
Okay, we'll proceed with it. Yeah, let's
continue.
So the state that
arose back in the some 35 years ago
which I never mentioned to anybody. The
state never mentioned got mentioned to
anybody till 1995 when I wrote the book
called power versus force. No way to
explain it. So it seemed to me that
kinesiology demonstrated
a way of bridging the gap between the
Newtonian
and higher levels of consciousness
which are actually other paradigms.
So the reason science cannot understand
spirituality is it's the wrong
instrument. It's like looking for ghosts
with a geer counter. You're in the wrong
dimension, the wrong realm, the wrong
instrument because the advanced states
of consciousness are radically
subjective.
They are subjective.
All right, this is where we were this
morning. We were talking about how life
evolves
and it begins to appear on the planet.
These people can't hear, you'll have to
take my word for it. that we start we
start with prozzoa at one and I asked
I said sarah what about it she says well
what about viruses she says well a virus
doesn't really do anything it just
reduplicates it DNA so we asked does a
virus have consciousness we'll do it
again we have permission to ask that
here the virus has consciousness resist
the virus doesn't have consciousness
Who are all viruses?
You don't get conscious till you get the
bacteria.
All right.
Bacteria calibrate on this scale at one.
Yep. So consciousness first appears as
consciousness with the bacteria. Before
that it's algae and viruses.
All right. So then you get up to
prozzoa. It's about two. Crustaceians is
three. I can't read that. Insects are
six. Arachnids are seven. Amphibians 17,
fish 20, sharks 24,
vipers 35, and my friend the Komodo
dragon 40.
Represents current political people in
the world. 40.
That's the level of reptilian.
One bite and it's fatal.
One bite.
Okay. Reptiles at 40. Now you come to
the predatory mammals. Hyena.
I always thought there was something
sneaky about a hyena
at 40. The tiger. You see these all live
by the death of others. Snakes at 45,
alligators at 45, dinosaur at 60.
And we move on up until we get these are
all living off of others. The polar
bear, the grizzly bear, the black bear,
the jackal. All right. Now we come up
here and we got to move it to the left.
The wolf at 190 and hippopotamus.
I I never I didn't know what there was
about hippopotamuses. I didn't like much
but they actually kill more people than
any other animal which is surprising. I
always thought the water buffalo did
Havalina at 195 and now suddenly at 200
you see a shift. You see zebra gazelle
you see the herbivorous animal.
So we said the nature of life to survive
it had to be me me. So up to 200 life
lives at the cost of the life of others.
It eat it sees everything as edible and
it lives at the cost of the life of
others which is exactly what happens
with human consciousness below 200. It
exploits your money takes it out of your
retirement account
in run worldcom all those companies
it takes it from you. So it's predatory.
So life is predatorial until you get to
the herbivore.
The herbivore mudes grass and fertilizes
the soil at the same time. Spreads
vegetable seeds and it's as it grazes
and and fertilizes. So it does not live
by the death of others. It eats the
grass but it doesn't kill the grass. The
grass roots. So it becomes benign. So
here you see you go from predacious
to benign. Benign.
All right. 200. The deer at 205, the
bison at 205,
pig 205, elk 210, dairy cow 210, sheep
210, range cattle 210, elephants 235.
I was pitching for the elephants, hoping
they'd come out a little higher, but 235
is all we could get out of it.
Farms at 240. Racehorse is higher. Cats
and cats and dogs are about 240.
Family cat, however, is 245. So once you
adopt an animal, its consciousness jumps
about five points, sometimes even more
than that. So a kitty out there on her
own calibrates at 240, but when she
becomes the family kitty, she jumps to
245. So just to be around humans tends
to elevate consciousness of those they
interact with. Here's a race horse at
245.
And uh I met a retired raceh horse out
at the girls ranch the other day. Did we
calibrate that raceh horse?
>> No, that retired racehorse calibrated
over 245, 250, 255, 250. That racehorse,
there was a racehorse I met. I never got
along with horses for karmic reasons.
First time I connected with a horse was
not long ago. this gorgeous horse was
there smiling friendly at me and and
making nice middle thoughts. And so I
went over and kissed the horse and the
horse kissed me and we fell in love with
each other. We got it on camera.
That's the first horse I got along with.
They've been throwing me my whole life.
Finally, I quit. Your bones are getting
too brittle. You're going to crunch up.
I gave up riding. But I never really
connected with them until that moment we
really connected. Must have been
overcoming some karmic negativity on my
part. I was probably not too nice to
horses is what I guessed and they got
even with me throughout my lifetime.
Take that you
monkeys at 250, the gorilla at 275, the
chimpanzee who shares, you know, 99% of
our genes or something
at 305.
There are some exceptions. the
well-known gray African parrot named
Alex
uh who's been often on television,
trained I think in the University of
Arizona and Tucson by a psychologist
there. I forget the name of the doctor
there. Alex can actually think. What
does 400 mean? It means think. That's
the beginning of intellect. It's been a
big scientific argument about whether
parrots actually think or whether
they've just been trained to mimic
thinking. Our calibration says they do
think. They actually think they can put
together two plus two and and pull out
four. So they're able to conceptualize
401. Koko the trained gorilla is at 405.
Koko, you know, has a a very big
vocabulary. I forget how many 600 words.
She can actually construct sentences,
subject and predicate. She gets the
difference between transitive and
intransitive verbs. That's pretty
advanced conceptualization.
tired a lot of third graders in our
country.
So, Coco, who we've all fallen in love
with over the years, the song bird, now
there's a few exception. The song bird
song calibrates at 500.
Somehow beauty comes through the
songbird and mankind has been entranced
by the sound of the songb bird song
throughout all of time owed to something
or other.
The cat's purr calibrates at 500 as does
the dog's wagging tail.
Isn't that a knockout?
So as a genus then they calibrated 250
but through the heart chakra I still
haven't had time to investigate this.
Why is it that the heart chakra of the
dog or the cat is very advanced far more
than their mental chakra.
200 I mean 500 is the level of love. So
you hear the kitty purring away sitting
on top of the bed at night and somehow
you feel happy. You just feel happy.
hear the kitty purring, you just feel
happy or the dog's tail comes over like
this. This one that we calibrated uh was
the friendliest dog I've ever seen. It
just had to be your friend. And if you
wouldn't be a friend, it would just sit
there and be friendly to you until
finally you gave up and became his
friend.
And what the heart chakra then of the
cat and the dog has meant to mankind has
been of course incredible. Many as
lonely person has not committed suicide
because of their pet.
By the tens of thousands, more likely by
the hundreds of thousands. Over hundreds
of thousands of living persons did not
commit suicide because of the love their
pet exist.
It wasn't for the dog, wasn't for their
kitty, they would have overdosed long
ago.
So they play a big part in our life. I
still haven't tracked out with research
how they got to be that way. How come to
how come the heart chakra and these two
people and these two people say
and and something that's become dear to
mankind? Is it a consequence of our
loving them or it's probably some karmic
the evolution of consciousness
took some turn that we haven't
discovered yet? Okay. It's important to
us and people that are depressed and I
saw in the office I quit practice now,
but I still have some old people that I
see because they're too old to go and
find somebody else.
One was the guy who has the oxygen tank,
you know, and he always asks me for a
light, you know.
So, I've been lighting his cigarettes
for years, you know. I said, "You want
to smoke? Go ahead." He give me a light.
I said, "You sure this thing is not
going to blow up?" He said, "Nah." I
said, "Okay." So, I light it. We don't
blow up. So,
then the nurse told me she once had a
patient that did that and the oxygen
tank blew right through the floor of the
of the
house they were living in. So, last time
I saw him, I said, "No." I said, "That
canister could blow right through the
hole of a hole in the floor.
Neither one of us is concerned about
death, you see. After that near-death
experience, you know, whatever you call
it in the snowbank, the fear of death
totally disappeared,
which was very handy in World War II.
You know, you're right next to a mine
about to blow you up, and the only thing
you're concerned about is it doesn't
boom on the ship. Other people are
worried about blowing up. So, one nice
thing is you don't get startled. A gun
can go off next to you and you don't
even notice it. You know, it's react.
And death is, you know, it's your
problem. So if somebody's going to kill
me, blow me away, I just go.
I don't like loud noise.
You want to kill me? That's your
problem. I don't want to hear about it.
Okay, next one.
That's actually a reality. You see, it
really is the other person's problem.
It's not my problem.
>> What is all this? Oh, the spiritual
foundation.
What's the core of spiritual
spirituality?
First of all, you don't have to call it
spirituality. You can call it decency.
You can call it being civilized.
Whatever you like to call it. But the
beginning of it shows up in the in the
qualities that we call ethics and
morality.
We It turns out to be I don't know. It's
very hard to see this thing here. What
does that say?
>> Oh, you become considerate of others.
Uh, you become what's called decent. You
zip your fly.
You get engaged in hard work.
You begin to sense a certain morality
that is in independent of a specific
belief system. You become helpful.
you tend to become easygoing,
thoughtful,
sort of open, available, dependable.
See these are critical things. We
pointed out how the distribution of
level of consciousness on the planet
that there are whole continents, cold
continents that are practically below
120.
They don't even get that when you hire
them, they're supposed to show up on
time.
Time. Oh.
white man's oppression like reason and
logic.
That's a current political trend right
now to view reason and logic as uh no
male dominance. That's it. Now it's
called male dominance. So it sees reason
and logic as a restraint. A restraint to
what? It's a restraint to the infant in
you. It would like to slobber, take
yours, pee in his pants,
wants to be a little walking id. So you
have a whole political movement that
receives any kind of maturity or sanity
as oppressive. Oppressive and to be
rebelled against which puts you back at
infant again. Puts you back at being
infant then. All right. So you become
accountable, friendly, cordial, and most
important, you begin to consider the
rights of others. The rights of others.
The reason I like to start the lecture,
if it's scheduled at 10:30, I want to be
there at 10:30. It seems very egoistic
to have a whole audience
be on time to something and then you
show up 20 half hour late like, you
know, like you're
a primadonna or something. the concern
for the fact that hundreds of people are
here on time and you should be here on
time. You know, so you re realize
mutuality, a mutuality of agreement.
We call such people sane, fair, ethical.
They also become flexible. They also
become respectable,
respectful. The respect for authority
which is also under siege is under siege
because it confuses authoritarian with
authority. There is true authority.
In fact, every everyone that exists is
the authority of their own existence.
There is no higher authority of the
knowingness of who you are than you
yourself. So you begin to when you
respect others, you respect yourself.
you respect others. So you become
respectful of authority because you
recognize that it is fulfilling a
responsibility and the responsibility is
actually
working in your behalf in the long run.
You become healthy, faithful, sense of
humor. I don't trust people have no
sense of humor. I don't trust them.
They're up to no good.
It's like uh these trials you see and
the guy who's accused of course he
always denies it. Do you ever hear a
killer admit, "Yeah, I killed all 40 of
them." No, he always has to plead not
guilty.
And whenever you where you watch them on
the screen, you will see the fixity of
their face. When a person expresses no
emotion facially, you know they're
controlling it. Well, what is it they're
controlling? Cuz if you're innocent,
you're spontaneous. You're just who you
are. You laugh, you giggle, you s you
cry, you're sad. No, that controlledness
tells you that they're lying.
They're trying to look casual. Look
casual. The harder they try to look
casual and detach, the more you know
they're lying.
Yeah.
If the guy was mean and nasty, I believe
him. No, he's playing cool and detached
like who me?
Who me? That guy. So a sense of humor
tells you that a person is trustable
and people tend to become loyal,
equitable, they develop wisdom and they
respect rationality. So that which
despises rationality
undermines itself and becomes weak,
falls to the bottom of the barrel.
In a barrel full of apples, there's
always somebody at the bottom. There's
always a bottom layer in every barrel.
How does how do they get there? By
violating all these basic principles.
That's how they get there.
Rationality then is what differentiates
man from the animal. Anybody can feel.
So if you're going to let feelings run
your life, then you'd better live in a
cage.
The animal just goes by its feelings.
The exaltation of feelings as a dominant
characteristic to control your life
condemns you to be an animal. It puts
you in the solar plexus, the spleen and
various various other places.
No, it's only when rationality begin it
is distinctly human. Anybody can come
out of their solar plexus. Well, I felt
like doing that. Why didn't you come to
work yesterday? Well, I didn't feel like
getting up.
You didn't feel like getting up? No, I
didn't feel like getting up. What do I
care if you felt like getting up?
They'll get you a court marshal.
Do you know not feeling like getting up
will get you court marshaled?
It's a court marshable offense.
So h responsibility
the person becomes benign. They're not
vicious and threatening. They become
protective of all of life. And we call
that humane.
They're interested in being cordial.
They tend to be happy people, pleasant,
positive, the salt of the earth. Also
modest,
polite, etc. We say, "Well, they're just
nice people." So you're looking at the
200s and the 300s. People who read about
enlightenment decide, I think I'll be
enlightened.
And how do you do that? You take just
one of these and do it all the time with
no exception.
To be kind to all of life. And all of
his expressions without exception. That
means without exception.
You only have to take one tool and it'll
take you the whole way. So you can pick
any one you like.
Respect for life to see the divinity of
all of life.
The easiest one is to begin to be aware
of the sacredness of all of life, the
perfection of all things from moment to
moment.
That's a form of Judaism. I think it's
called hetic in which you focus on
understanding the divinity that exists
the divinity within all that it exists
to be meditatively aware of that it's a
very high form of Judaism it calibrates
the highest
so one doesn't have to read the bagita
one doesn't have to join a zen monastery
one doesn't have doesn't have to become
a syadin
syasan or whatever you call it the one
who denies life in the world
we're going negation the pathway of
negation so this is the pathway of
affirmation
the pathway of negation makes people
think well I must leave you have to
leave the world negation means the
negation of falsity the negation of
falsity
the pathway of negation in and of itself
is a variant of Buddhism and it will
take you to the void of nothingness.
Nothingness.
When the Buddhist said ya meant reality
is the void he meant void of thingness
nonduality beyond
thingness. The void is not the ultimate
reality.
It is stunningly impressive.
It has a finality, a certainty,
a foreverness.
Extremely impressive.
Unless one had heard differently, they
would think that's the end. And that's
where I ended up many a lifetime
Buddhist in the void.
Then there would be no memory of
anything till the next embodiment
because I would go into the void all the
time. This time I came in in the void
that I left last time as believing it
was the ultimate reality. And of course
what it's lacking is the attribute of
God called love.
So in the snowbank I had already
experienced
the absolute reality and its
absoluteness was invincibly
certain
that the presence of God is not only
nonlinear
beyond all time place
but it is the essence of love itself.
the essence of love itself. And it's
that love that wipes out the sense of a
personal self.
In the presence of that infinite love,
it the personal self melts.
It's not attacked or nothing. Okay. I
thought you'd like to know something
about brain function. I know you don't,
but anyway, this is the human brain.
We'll move on. I just wanted to show you
it has a lyic system
and it has an amygdala and it has a
hippocampus.
Those are nice places. Right south of
San Diego, I think.
Next one.
Yeah, the hippoc campus. I love that
word. Hippocampus. You s here comes
hippocampus.
Right south of the hair. Your hippo
campus.
You see is spirituality a fantasy and
imagination. When I was an atheist I
sure I was sure it was a fantasy and
imagination.
No here now here's the brain function.
Uh move to the right. We'll just move
the hippocampus off. We don't need the
hippocampus now. We won't play on the
hippocampus.
Okay. There you got it. All right. All
right. This is the brain function.
The normal brain function. A stimulus
comes in here. It goes to the phalamus
fast. It goes fast to the amygdala which
is emotion.
The impulse go is relayed through the
phalamus rapidly to the amygdala which
is the emotional center.
Belatedly subsequently it's processed
through the prefrontal cortex and also
gets to the amygdala. But the emotion
has happened already.
FU.
God cuts in front of you in traffic. The
FU is out already. Then the spiritual
learning says, "I shouldn't be thinking
that way." Dear God, I'm sorry for using
that name in vain name.
But you did it already. You wait for the
lightning. No lightning.
At least you've learned how to express
yourself. You're not being suppressed.
Your analyst is going to be happy. When
you gave that guy the finger, he said,
"Boy, you're learning how to express
yourself."
This is the pathway through the left
brain. It's the animal pathway. This is
the brain of people who calibrate below
200.
People who calibrate below 200, this is
where they live and this is how their
brain operates.
Now, we'll ask something else
interesting.
We have first ask this in front of this
audience. Those people have an etheric
brain resistance.
People below 200 have an etheric brain
resist.
>> Okay.
Now what happens with spiritual
intention? Spiritual intention
calibrating over 200 totally changes the
tracking
process through the brain. The input
comes in. The fast track goes to the
prefrontal cortex to the emotional
center.
It relays quickly
from the prefrontal cortex to the
amygdala.
It's a different pathway. Even more
importantly, beyond 200, you develop an
atheric brain. The information now goes
through your atheric prefrontal cortex
to your amygdala.
And you see life differently. Anybody
who's done the course of miracles knows
that. You start out seeing all kinds of
awful people in the world. You go to New
York City. You say they're so selfish
and cold. They're awful people. They
cheat you. Cabar are rude. Waitresses
are horrible. Everybody lizard must be
an animal. Then you do the course of
miracles. Say, "How was your trip to New
York?" God, they're the most wonderful
people in the world. Everybody's
friendly. Cabar was helpful. Everybody
turned their hand. Everybody turn
everybody's happy.
Same city, huh?
This is
>> you know has an atheric brain atheric
brain and the atheric brain processes
the own knowingness
and caling the levels of consciousness
you know we're talking about a certain
paradigm we use the logarithmic scale
actually thought spiritual awareness is
beyond that the logarithmic scale goes
up to a thousand
but the reality that It represents
we saw this morning somebody did it in
equivalent in microwatts which I thought
was mathematically wonderfully left
brain and terrific
but actually that's not what it is
either where where it all where
spiritual awareness and all goes on
is our harmonics of the level of
consciousness a thought comes in at a
certain level of consciousness which we
can calibrate with kinesiology
the subjective awareness of of The
actual reality of it is a harmonic.
The harmonic is beyond calculation.
There's nothing no earthly science that
reaches it. And the interface of the
harmonic sets up a dissonance. And then
in that difference, you get the thought.
The defraction between levels of the
harmonics of levels of consciousness is
where the thinkingness
on a subjective level is happening.
Happening.
So, let's put this up because this is
um rather important. Okay, stop. Stop.
Below 200. You're run by your animal.
Left brain dominance. You hate
everybody. They deserve what they get.
It's linear. It's releases constant
stress. Sellier's stress response,
alarm, resistance, and exhaustion.
Canon's fight or flight. So these people
live fight or flight. Watch every
night's news reel. The other side of the
world, it's fight, flight, fight,
flight. That's all it is. Fight and
flight. Fight, fight, and hate.
For relief from fight and flight, they
hate. They get themselves turned up.
Then go out fight and flight some more.
This is going on for
what? 1,400 years. Same fight.
All right. Okay. This causes a stress to
the thymus. So this below 200 your
thymus is always stressed. So you
remember John Diamond's book behavioral
kinesiology, the body doesn't lie.
He documents the thymus thump you go.
That that now profoundly alters the
acupuncture system. It rebalances it. So
that then stimulates the um immune
system to release more killer cells.
People um
who are in stress, there's a suppression
of the thyic regulation of the
acupuncture system and a suppression of
the manufacturer of killer cells.
Therefore, you're more prone to disease.
So this pathway will kill you early.
This pathway will kill you late.
It won't kill you. I know you. No, it
said more killer cells. And I thought,
well, maybe the killer cells kill you.
No, killer cells kill invading bacteria.
Oh. Oh, okay.
Things that make you go weak blow your
acupuncture system. There's many uh
advertisement on television that just
blows you cool. Just blows you right
out. I was saying this morning they
spend millions on advertisements that
make everybody go weak and hate their
product
more disease negative kinesiologic
response.
Okay.
The importance
once you develop a spiritual intention
doesn't mean you've got to become a
Buddha. It just means that you begin to
practice an awareness of spiritual
values and their ultimate reality.
You now have right brain dominance.
You're now dealing not in linear but
nonlinear.
Instead of releasing adrenaline and the
stress hormones,
the peaceful state of mind releases
endorphins.
So, you develop an inner sense of
well-beingness.
It's hard to develop a sense of
well-beingness if you're living in a
light lift brain kill or be killed kind
of a mental set.
This tends to increase immunity, killer
cells healing. It balances the
acupuncture system. It gives you a
positive kinesiologic response.
And you see the information, you
actually see the world differently. You
experience the world differently. You
actually literally see the world
differently.
Spiritual endeavor and intention changes
the brain function and the body's
physiology
and establishes a specific area for
spiritual information
in the cerebral cortex and more
importantly in the cere in the
prefrontal gyrus of the atheric brain.
The atheric brain. Okay, move on next.
What is the etheric brain? It's an
energy brain. When your physical brain
dies, when your physical brain dies and
you leave the body, do you think you
stop thinking? No. How many people here
have been out of the body? Hey, did you
stop thinking?
>> No, you didn't stop thinking. So, what
was thinking? Seeing as you weren't even
there. It happened to me spontaneously.
He looked he was very close to death
laying there in the body.
I had no attraction to him. Glad to be
rid of him. Looked down at Dave. Boy, he
he really looked bad. And I was up here
in the body and I was feeling great. No
physicality. If I thought here, I was
there. If I thought there, I was there.
Dinosaur era, the calibrated level of
life on this planet was approximately
60.
The first birds, diversification of
reptiles.
68. primitive mammals, last of the
dinosaurs, the rise of flowering plants,
the calibrated level of consciousness of
the planet was 84.
Rapid development of modern animals,
insects, I can't read these things.
They're too um far back in time. I can't
even conceptualize them. It rise 112.
Modern animals and plants 212. Rise and
dominance of man. The calibrated level
of life is at 212.
So life itself calibrates a little bit
higher than man because man right now
calibrates at 207.
Okay, thank you. Is that the end of
them? Anyway, I thought that's
interesting. You see the evolutionary
rise in consciousness throughout the
animal kingdom and then you see it uh
let's see, we have to watch the time.
What time we supposed to stop? Huh?
>> 3:00. We're supposed to stop at three.
>> All right. And then we're going to
answer questions and all that. All
right. I just thought you might be
interested in this. We're not going to
present it really fully today, but
perhaps next time in Sedona,
you can see that life evolves from the
lower chakras, the lower chakra, which
is reproduction and survival, the energy
field of life itself.
As you see the evolutionary through the
animal species and just the evolution of
the calibrated levels of life itself on
this planet. It's as though it's rising
up
through the spleen and hatred to the
solar plexus of assertiveness,
aggressiveness,
gettingness, desire, greed. And only
when consciousness level reaches 500 do
you see the opening of the heart chakra.
In only 4% of mankind does the
predominant
energy
illuminate the heart.
Christianity is traditionally the way of
the heart.
Faith, good works, devotion
and Christ came to earth to represent
salvation. Salvation.
The Buddha came to earth to teach of
enlightenment. Two different things.
There is a branch of Buddhism which is
very like Christianity and that it
assumes the negativity of this planet is
so severe that to transcend it is
unlikely
certainly not to reach enlightenment.
But to transcend the fixation in the
lower chakras and get up to the heart,
the heart of Jesus is symbolic.
One then at the point of death is
goes into a heavenly state. The
celestial realms above the lower, middle
and higher astral are the celestial
from which the savior will act as your
will speak on your behalf.
In Buddhism, the same
sort of a pragmatic resolution
that the likelihood of reaching
enlightenment and without very specific
karmic propensity is highly unlikely.
However, it is within one's choice to
choose to be loving. So lotus land
Buddhism of Alakatavar or whatever the
name is the Buddha of of
infinite mercy acts the same as the
Christ and from the celestial land of
celestial land of lotus land Buddhism
from that level which is beyond the
severe negativity of this world you can
then go on further
they both seem like practical
resolutions
The negativity of the world as you can
see is considerable and until the late
1980s the consciousness level of all of
mankind was below 200 at 190.
So the negative influence of the world
was considered to be so dominant
that one could
practically
rise to the heart chakra
and from there
Christ the Buddha's representation as
the Christlike
what's the name of the
Buddha of Lotus Land of Valakas Kavara
what do you remember Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. Right. Yes. So that is the
equivalent of Christ. Yeah.
>> All right.
Beyond as as the energy rises then
feelings solar plexusness is
transcended to thinkingness. You move
from the 300s into the 400s. The 400s is
rationality.
We no longer do what we feel. We we do
what we know is reasonable. We know that
if you don't get up and get there on
time, you're going to get canned. So
reason precludes feeling. The lower
levels of evolution, feeling
predominates.
But now reason and logic begin to rule
decisionm.
So the modern man which began about
600,000 years ago in Ethiopia
began about 600,000 years ago in
Ethiopia. I forget his name. Probably
the source of all of common man came out
of Ethiopia.
He's got a nameus or something. I forget
it. Homo sapien assultus or something.
Anyway, as it evolves then consciousness
evolves the mental bodies the mental
bodies evolve. First is the lower mental
body lower
mind and we can't read it too well. Put
it over on the right and I'll try and
just generalize about it
is reactive. It turns out it learns how
to plan and think and uh it's it's very
uh concerned with specifics specifics.
specifics.
It's far more efficient than just the
animal feelingness because now you can
really think. Okay. And then we we move
that over.
So lower mind, it tends to be literal
and concrete and somewhat pedestrian.
Somewhat pedestrian.
People criticize my book and they'll say
so and so so and so, which is totally
relevant to what the book's all about.
You know what I mean?
>> Yeah. But the person will grasp to some
little thing they understand you know
because they missed the point of the
book because the point of the book has
to do with the essence of abstraction,
meaning, significance, inference,
you know, and so higher mind then
begins to fixate more on the context
than just the content. under what
circumstances and what were the
influences.
It deals with the abstract. It deals
with generalities.
There's a form of contemplation which I
describe in the book in which you become
at one with uh the the the context of
the field. You become at one with the
field and you stop focusing on the
content. You're aware. When you walk
into a room, you get what the whole room
is about. You get what it's about. You
can walk into the library
in Dublin, the book of Kels. The library
is just stunning. Stunning.
Incredible architecture. This mass of
ancient manuscripts so old they're tied
together with ropes two stories high.
White marble statues of all the greatest
minds that have ever lived. I mean, you
just get just knocks you out. I mean,
what it is, what it took to create all
that, to accommodate all that, to bring
it all together.
Incredible. So, what knocks you out is
the field.
Somebody else is busy trying to look in
the corner of one of these books and
read what it says, which of course is
forboten,
but they're interested in the content.
Well, what year did they put this in? I
mean, who cares what year they put it
in?
What year?
Give me a break. It's got nothing to do
with what that library is all about. You
know, it symbolizes the greatest
accomplishments of man throughout all of
time and his devotion to truth and
education and knowledge. And you know,
it's just stunning for what it is. you
know, in the abstract, in the concrete.
It's just a bunch of dusty old books
that probably don't mean much in light
of today's world.
So, you you begin to contextualize
things. You begin to look for their
essence. You look at the essence of
things rather than the content.
And the mind then becomes reflective of
the field. You're interested in the
field. The the field instantly gives you
a reading on the intentionality
of why it's all there.
The field gives you the instant reading
on the intentionality. It happens on a
high level of harmonic, the high
harmonics of
becoming aware of the essence of things
rather than their appearance, which is
the opening of the third eye of the
Buddha body. You begin to be aware of
the essence of all that exists. You
don't have to measure it, weigh it, and
ask it what it's about because you got
it by looking at it.
Yeah. Because you're tuning into the
essence of things. Yeah. Which is his
intentionality and it's karmic
inheritance. Actually,
uh this is more difference between the
lower mind and upper mind. We'll skip
that.
I don't want to know about that today.
It's boring. The trouble with being in
higher mind is you get bored with
details.
Yeah. Oh, this is the Yeah. These are
the greatest minds of all time, the
great books of the Western world, which
I happily ran across a set that wasn't
too outrageous. So, we calibrated all
the greatest minds that ever lived. We
have this in alphabetical order. This is
not the alphabetical one. However, as
you can see, the greatest minds that
have ever lived calibrate around Galileo
was at 485. Most of them run around 460,
450, 425, Hegel 425, Gay 465,
Darwin 450, Marks 130. There you got a
signal. What's wrong with the world?
Out of all the great minds of history,
you find one at 130.
>> 130. Can't tell a perpetrator from a
victim. Can't tell a perpetrator from a
victim.
All right. So projected a duality,
a conflictual duality into that which
has no inner conflictual duality. It's
only a presentation and projection of
one's own paranoia and distortion of
reality. So at 130 but all the trouble
that that 130 has caused and all the
millions of lives all the millions of
lives that that 130 has caused Freud at
499 William James Dusteski
Emanuel Kant
Shakespeare all the great names you can
go to the
great abbey in London and most of them
are buried there
what's the name of the place
>> Westminster. Oh yes, it's Westminster.
I've been there a couple times. I spoke
there in 1970 and went back there in
2003.
But all these jokers are buried in the
poet's corner.
God bless them all.
When we said the man can't tell truth
from falsehood,
the greatest minds of history, here they
are laid out for you. Calibrate around
460. And they can't tell you the diff,
you know, what's true and what's false
either.
>> Until recent times, no man has had no
way of telling. Now, here they are in
alphabetical order in case you want to
look up somebody. These are the ones I
spent my childhood with. Safocles at
465.
Um,
Marcus Aurelius.
All the great names of history. These
were my friends as a kid. As a kid. Go
ahead.
>> Ah, yes. We were speaking about
now we're really getting down to an
explanation understanding
that causality is insufficient
explanation. causality.
Here is a specific uh uh definable,
measurable
within the linear domain
called by people reality.
In here the explanation of why this is
shaped this way is given because this
acts on this and this acts on this and
that's the Newtonian paradigm of
causality. There's a this causing a that
the difficulty of that belief system as
spiritual people that's the great block.
Very few people transcend the 400s. We
said only 4% do because one thing you
have to transcend is duality. There is
no personal eye causing a distinct that.
Nor is that personal eye separate from
the infinite reality. Huh?
What the rule cause causality then is a
very limited view. This is the content.
This is linear and this is the world of
form.
But even this only happens within the
approximate field which is composed
linear and nonlinear through quantum
mechanics, nonlinear dynamics,
randomness, stochastic phenomena begin
to influence this. This is why you can
skydive 14 times in a row very well and
become a pancake on the 15th.
The unpredictable, the nonlinear shoots
out. Oh, they did forget to pack that
parachute, didn't they?
So,
that's the approximate field. It's
knowable, definable. However, it's in
political debate
and intellectual debate, it is unstated.
Truth then, is dependent upon context.
There is no truth independent of
context.
Truth is only true within a certain
In a different context, it's a lie.
What'll get you a badge in one context
will get you executed in another. The
context makes all the difference. So
meaning and significance cannot be
derived from this. Only by this within
this field here, within this field it's
true. In another field, it is not true.
So truth then is dependent on context.
There is no such thing as truth stated
without context. Context is usually
implied
but not specifically stated. This is the
proximate field. It's knowable
discernable. That has to do with
prevailing ethics,
has to do with commercial popularity,
has to do with current political
climate, has to do with finances, has to
do with age, sex, gender. All these
things influence this. Just what gender
you are will make you believe this
rather than this just by sheer gender.
You understand?
Or what country you come from or your
age. You see what I'm saying? All right.
So this is very influential. And now
beyond all of this is the infinite
context.
The complete and infinite nonlinear.
Without this field here, nothing here
can happen.
How would how would potentiality become
actuality
unless within it it had the power of the
creation of existence.
Only this power
in infinite grav of infinite field
comparable to gravity of infinite power
is so powerful that the slightest
potentiality in that field becomes an
actuality.
All it needs is a flick of
intentionality and okay on your part and
now it's a reality.
Until without this field here, no
potentiality could become an actuality.
Why? Because prior to divinity, prior to
God is the Godhead.
It is out of the unmanifest that the
manifest arises.
Out of the unmanifest arises the
manifest
in which the potentiality becomes the
actuality.
Nothing has within it the power nothing
in here has the power of creation.
It's a very weak field. Anything here
can knock this out altogether.
Nothing can knock this field out. It's
beyond time and space. Yeah.
Is that the end?
>> And then we're going to go out and play
for a few minutes and come back.
Um,
we're not going to deal with that. It's
too too much thinkingness there.
He must have gone mad when he did that.
You know, sometimes he gets off into his
mind. You don't know what he's going to
do.
>> Well, he figures Oh, yes.
Here's a a rather interesting one which
we will get into in Sedona.
>> You want to do
>> anyway?
going to do this.
>> Uh no, we'll leave that till next time.
I just want to show the consequence of
going left brain or right brain. The
consequence of spiritual intentionality
is that instead of a barren tree, you
have a tree full of leaves
and abundance.
Abundance is quite a problem.
Abundance
is overwhelming.
When you begin to when you get to a
certain point, everything just begins to
flow to you. Pretty soon, you don't know
where to put it anymore.
The lack of wanting anything.
It's the lack of wanting. So wantingness
is the energy that keeps things away
from you. And if you constantly
surrender your wantingness to God,
pretty soon you don't want anything.
And when you don't want anything, people
load you up.
I remember the day I finally got totally
released on chocolate.
I finally had let go the last desire for
chocolate. I was free of chocolate.
Just then a whole group during the
course of miracles from the east came to
stay in my house. I had a big house at
the time with about six bedrooms which I
lived in alone, my own monastery.
And what do you think they brought in a
sheetcake of a chocolate cake that was
this big? I just got let go of
chocolate. And there it walked in the
door at me and it really made me laugh,
you know.
All right. So, all right. We'll take a
break. So, how long?
la
very
might
break all day. No day. Day
and day
with the go to
I showing
on your right.
I say
she foreign.
You the near
evil.
With the foreign.
Oh
my
god.
Oh,
you're
No.
Oh,
leave me all
the
Oh,
listen to the silence we created.
Thank you.
Well, I will sign books and answer
questions. There we're turned on. Okay.
Yeah, that was the
lotus sutra chanted in sense. Good. And
as it is chanted today,
they say we did it centuries ago
and we're part of a brotherhood. Last
time we were together was 350 years ago.
And uh there's one of the signals of the
mill membership.
We took an oath 350 years ago
and paid the price in this lifetime to
be free of it. Huh.
Now we're dedicated to truth with no
name.
I just got through writing an article
for a
going to be out published in India.
professorship there in India
and I'm adding a chapter of the book
it's dedicated to Dali Lala
and
I said the first thing to know is that
the Buddha was not a Buddhist.
Truth transcends all denominations.
And I always get a kick out of
Christians who consider Buddha
uh to be uh
what is he a heathen? Because he was
born 500 years before Jesus. So how
would he be a Christian? You tell me.
The comedies of religion. Okay. So we'll
take on any questions and uh answer them
to the best of our ability.
Yeah, within a certain paradigm of
reality.
>> Hello.
>> Um, my name is Liz and I'm from Toronto,
Canada. Very grateful to be here.
>> My question is about the difference
between want, want and intention. You
said earlier that to want something is
to repel it from you.
>> Yes.
>> And I I've read two schools of thought.
I'm thinking of Deepak Chopra who talks
about introducing intention into the
field. And I was just browsing in the
bookstore and reading a book by Joan
Gatuso or even Lynn Grabhorn. And they
talk about having an intention, applying
emotion to it, and then detaching and
that will draw it to you. So I'm I'm
very confused.
>> How do you do that?
>> That's my question.
>> Haven't figured that one out yet.
>> Yeah, I know. That's a little
circuitous.
>> Intentionality then
is
definable in terms as high as your level
of conscious and awareness has
traversed at that time. You see in the
name of the highest good. You see to
hold that which is beneficial in the
name of the highest good. Most any you
know intentionality you know
most courses on abundance
are presuming first of all that you
don't have it otherwise you wouldn't be
doing it right which means you want more
than what you got which is already a
statement of lack.
So you start out from a loser position
and the book is all about how to get
from loser position to winner.
The difficulty is the loser position
takes you securiously back to the loser
position.
It's only with the surrendering of
wantingness and being completely content
with whatever is at the moment. As we
said, everything goes from perfection to
perfection.
At this point in life, to not have
anything is perfection.
I walked out of the house with nothing
and wanted nothing.
Just when it's time for breakfast,
somebody says, "You want an apple?"
You walk out onto the street and you
think it'd be nice to have a ride and a
limo pulls over and says, "For hire."
You see,
the way is to let go of the question
because the question is self-defeating.
How can I acquire abundance is already
is already
cancel out any possible answer
to be content with what you have and
realize that it is abundance.
What you have now is abundance. What
people are usually talking about is
monetary.
There is no such thing as shortage of
monetary. There's only spending it
faster than you've got it.
So it's a matter of the speed at which
so you're living beyond your means
otherwise you wouldn't have poverty.
Poverty as a socioeconomic label
and it is whatever you call it.
I've lived in poverty a great deal of my
life and
what the world would call poverty but as
far as I was concerned it was all you
could want.
So
letting go of wantingness itself to let
go wanting
and to just see that you already have
all that you need. Now
a deficiency of what you want indicates
that you're coming from the solar plexus
wanting this.
Why would you want more money? You got
enough to eat, place to sleep. So, what
else do you want?
Amusement,
better car.
I drive a Cadillac.
84.
The car is to get me from here to there
and it does so. So why do I need
something newer and more expensive?
All right. So
wanting this is giving magical ideas to
to more and then feeling a lack. You
know it's an artificial artificial
artificiality of mentation.
If you go from perfection to perfection,
then you can't possibly be suffering
from lack. You're only suffering from
imagination.
The other way you can define it is that
at every moment you are suffering from
lack. There's no moment when you
couldn't have more money, bigger car,
bigger property, more children, more
acreage.
There's no moment at which you would
ever have abundance. So if lack is
possible then abundance is impossible
because the same kind of mentation would
apply.
You see it with the bank robber. Um on
Monday he robs this bank. He got
$38,000. On Wednesday he robbed this
bank, got $62,000. On Friday he robbed
another bank for $18,000. What did he
what did he do? spend it all in the
meantime.
Between Monday and Tuesday, he spent all
$50,000 and Wednesday he's broke and
needs to bring bring in another bank.
You see it in the heads of all the giant
corporations whose heads have just
rolled recently.
You know, he he's managed to chisel the
company out of $50 million. Is that
going to make him happy? If I got 50
million, wouldn't you retire someplace
and take it easy? No. he's going to go
for another 10 million or another 20
million. So he keeps pushing the
envelope. So you see the difficulty with
the solar plexus is wantingness cannot
be satisfied.
You cannot satisfy wantingness because
wantingness is an energy of its own. If
100,000 doesn't satisfy it, now you want
a half a million. That doesn't satisfy
it. Now you want a million. That doesn't
satisfy you not wanting 3 million. So
cravingness is an energy of the solar
plexus and it is not satisfiable.
How many bed partners can you have in
one lifetime?
How many kids can you molest? I've
treated a lot of child molesters.
158.
Oh, judge. How can you be so harsh? You
only got arrested for abusing one boy.
That boy was number 158.
that cravingness is not satisfiable.
Consequently, when you let go of sat of
cravingness,
everything that you have from instant to
instant is complete and total.
There's no instant when one is really
actually lacking anything in life.
And if you die of starvation, that's the
way you set it up. And that's your
karmic responsibility that you set it up
that way.
to prove the world is wrong. See, the
ego to prove it's right would be happy
to kill you. Oh, it doesn't mind at all.
It rather see you dead than admit it's
wrong. No, it's not possible to suffer
from lack unless one is coming from a
solar plexus wantingness.
without wanting this. Life is complete
and total every second.
You think, well, I'm hungry and I don't
want and I want something to eat now and
I don't have it now.
You're not saying that you're lacking
anything to eat. It's just that you're
wanting this to have it now is not
satisfying.
Besides, who said you should have it in
the first place?
Poverty is good enough for you.
You can never be rich unless you can
handle being you can handle poverty. You
can handle poverty then you're always
rich henceforth
from poverty 50 bucks is riches.
I used to check manure for
bought it for 40 bucks, sold it no
bought it for 10 bucks, sold it for 40
bucks.
Drove from Meguireville to Sedona, paid
10 bucks there at the dairy farm, sold
it there for 40, 30 bucks. Do that a
couple times a week. What more do you
need?
As free as a bird.
So joy comes out of the awareness of the
source of your existence.
The source of joy is the awareness of
your existence. This instant.
So this instant is complete and total.
Do I need anything beyond this instant?
No. There isn't anything else the next
instant can offer me that isn't already
present in this instant.
So if life stopped just this instant,
bye.
It's already complete.
To see all that leaves you free of
wantingness
because the wantingness will fixate
on first one thing and then another. And
after you've got lots of money, it'll
want youth. And now you're old. You'll
want beauty and you're ugly.
You want a better tennis game and you
know you're too feeble to hit the wall
anymore. So cravingness is never
satisfied.
Never satisfied. In fact, every time you
satisfy it, it gets stronger.
Look at all the people, Enron and
Worldcom and all those people. They made
money what in the billions or something.
I mean, isn't 5 billion enough for you
woman or H fella?
Isn't 5 billion enough? No. With craving
this, five billion is not enough. 10
billion is not enough. 100 billion is
not enough.
Okay.
>> Your impulse then to have the apple then
is not a state of wantingness. It's a
momentary awareness.
>> I don't know. That's too intellectual.
>> It's it's the old analogy. You ever saw
a U-Haul following a hearse?
>> She said you never see a U-Haul
following a hearse.
The reality is you're complete in total
and have all that you need right this
then.
>> Okay.
>> Thank you.
>> Yep.
>> Just put your feet on the sunny side of
the street and be rich as Rockefeller.
>> Isn't that the way the lyrics go with
that song?
>> Yep.
Put your feet on the sunny side of the
street and you'll be rich as
Rockefeller.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Hi, my name my name is David
Learner. I live in um Scottsdale right
now.
>> Yeah.
>> And I want to clarify something. You
said to me earlier that George Bush
calibrates at
>> You wanted to know what he calibrated. I
told you 460.
>> Yeah, I know. He told me he killed him
face. There's something I don't
understand though I want to clarify and
try try to reconcile in my own mind is
is um even with a strong intellect but
doing actions harmful to humanity. Car
marks was at 130 you said even though he
has a strong intellect. So and I all the
evidence I've been seeing unless I've
been badly misinformed is
>> what have you been studying?
>> David Ike for one.
>> Huh?
>> David Ike and I've been reading a lot of
web pages.
>> Oh you've been reading web pages. What
do these web pages calibrate?
>> Web pages that you're reading calibrate
over 200 resist.
>> Um,
>> the web pages you're reading calibrate
about 130.
>> What about what about David Ike?
>> What does David Ike calibrate at?
>> I don't know.
>> Um,
>> you see, the mind can't tell truth from
falsehood. That's why we calibrate
things. If the mind could tell truth
from falsehood, we wouldn't bother
calibrating because appearance would be
the same as essence. Appearance is one
thing, essence is another.
The world of sophistry is extremely
sophisticated and you're not
sophisticated at sophistry.
The sophist used to charge a fee. I'll
teach you how to become rich and famous
in the world. You want to learn? You got
to learn how to be a sophist. Well, you
already are a sophist. You've been taken
in by sophistry without even knowing it.
Which is what sophistry is for. I get
you in my camp
and you don't see the subtle errors in
my
thinkingness and logicness.
If what you were reading was integrous,
then if what he was reading was
integrous, it would calibrate a word
200. Is this okay? On the internet right
now,
50% of what you read on the internet is
facious. Huh? Over 50% of what you read
on the internet is facious. Over 50% is
already facious.
>> But I'm discriminating about what I
read.
>> No, you're not discriminating because
you wouldn't think the way you're
thinking. Your thinking is already below
200. And your source of information is
below 200. That's why. See, so to
brainwash you is very easy. You know,
you're you're easy one.
I could tell you anything. You'll
believe it if I make it convincing. Does
>> that mean George Bush is doing more good
than Han?
>> You asked me what he calibrated. You
didn't ask me for a moralistic judgment.
I don't set myself up as a moralistic
judge. Okay.
>> He calibrates at 460.
Uh Saddam Hussein calibrated at 130. Bin
Laden calibrates at 70. Now you make out
of that which where what's his reality?
Who you want to embrace?
>> You want to embrace 130 or 460.
>> So what is David Ike calibrate at then?
>> David Ike has been a primary source of
information. Does he what does he
calibrate?
>> I don't know that I have permission to
do that in public. All I can tell you is
the internet. Whatever you're reading,
you should write try reading something
else.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> You see, calibrating levels is is
impersonal. I don't care what I don't
care what what the God calibrates at.
But if by the fruit you shall know them,
the
that which is truth to calibrate over
200. So whatever the source is, I don't
care what his name is. The internet, you
know, is 50% facious. Interestingly
enough, uh the most commonly there
there's a track on there you can get the
most commonly requested words, the 300
most commonly requested words right now
on the internet.
30% are pornographic.
Out of all the requests that go into the
search engines, 30% are pornographic.
Yeah.
That tells you where the mind is. Mind
of who? Probably teenage boys. You know,
12-year-old boys. That's all they think
about.
Thank you
for being on the rally factor.
You were a little bit that way with
>> Well, I was imitating rally.
>> The mind cannot tell truth from
falsehood. It's impressionable. It's
suggestable. It's programmable.
A clever person can program anybody's
mind to believe anything.
Give me 20 minutes with anybody and
they'll walk out believing anything that
we decide they're going to believe.
Because all you have to do is work
figure out how the mechanism of that
person's ego or what he values and co
put it in terms of that which he values
and he'll instantly buy it. You don't
have to sell it to him.
>> Hi, my name is Kelly. I'm from St. Paul,
Minnesota.
>> Minnesota.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah.
>> This is nice and warm. Um, well, I did
have a question in regards to a family
member, my son, who is literally
probably going to starve himself to
death due to ego. But you basically
answered it with the last lady because I
just thought, what can be done? I guess
he's has his own path that that's the
way.
>> Yes.
>> Um,
>> he's anorexic or what are you saying?
>> No, he just hadn't have a job for a year
and now he's out on the streets and
>> Oh, on the streets. Oh, that's a trip.
Love it.
>> It's called Out on the Streets.
Everybody should do Out on the Streets.
I mean, it's cool. Free as a bird. Do
what you want to do. Get rid of mom and
dad. All those restrictions.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. Well, that's I guess you answered
it with the last lady, but my sister has
to take my parents to the airport, so I
have a quick question from her.
>> Yeah.
>> Um you were on that chart that had
here's the animals that um kill and
here's then the ones that don't. What
about humans that then eat uh meat? Um,
I know in the last year I've chosen to
be a vegetarian after feeling I've been
doing better myself. And so what about
the people who are still eating meat and
that caliber calibrate over 200? How
does that
>> what about it?
>> Well, how does that work if they're
still eating or meat that someone else
went and killed and slaughtered and
stuff?
How does that work?
>> It has to do with intentionality. It has
to do with
uh to go back to an original source of
you know spiritual teaching about the
rig vida. The rig vida states that each
evolutionary level sacrifices itself to
the level above it. Yeah. That the
animal sacrifices its life to the human
thereby raises the collective
consciousness of its species over time.
The Rita says that all of us sacrifice
our life for that which is above us. See
the soldier sacrifices his life for the
life of his country and each one
sacrifices their life for a higher
principle. The animal surreners its life
from your position looks like it's being
killed. First of all, death is not
possible. We forgot to mention some of
the basic truths about life.
It is not possible to kill life. Resist.
It is not possible to kill life. All
right? It then manifests forth. First of
all, when an animal dies, it doesn't
notice it.
An animal does not notice that it just
died resist. It goes into its atheric
body and continues life right on. It
then remmanifests within the physical
domain. If you swat a moth, you know, it
doesn't even notice it. It goes right
along flying in its etheric body.
Doesn't even notice.
It's like a dream. So, you watch an
animal. An animal doesn't know the
difference between this world, which we
call real, and it dream world. And the
dream world is chasing a mouse. And then
it finds itself in this reality. It's
like another dream. Then it goes back to
sleep. And now it's chasing another cat.
It doesn't differentiate. doesn't say
this is real and that's not real. It's
all the same.
To those who identify with physicality,
it would look to you like the animal has
died. The animal hasn't died. Death is
not a possibility. There's the law of
conservation of energy. The law of
conservation of matter and the law of
conservation of life. Of all of those,
the law of conservation of life is the
most important and the one totally
unknown to mankind.
It is not possible to kill life. Kill
life. How could you kill life? Life is
the expression of divinity as
consciousness as it interacts with
matter.
It's not possible to kill life.
Yeah.
>> And why did you have the animals under
200 and the animals?
>> That's where they calibrate. I don't I'm
not judgmental. You see, everybody
projects kind of judgmentalism. I'm not
moralistic or judgmental. If you want to
know why the Komodo dragon calibrates, I
don't care what he calibrates. We get
40.
I'm not saying he's a bad animal. He's
probably the best killer on the planet.
Everything is perfection. If you're
going to become a killer, he's the
ultimate perfection of killingness.
One little nip with me and then I just
lay back and wait. Dinner's going to be
ready two, three days.
Everything is the absolute perfection of
that which it is.
Bin Laden is the absolute perfect
expression of that which he is. The
zealous pseudo religious killer. Yeah.
The megalomaniac in religious
sheep's clothing. Yeah. Each person John
Dillinger was the perfect criminal.
Babyface Nelson Machine Gun Kelly. Each
one is perfect.
We see that in the movie. The movie
gives you the
I forget the right word, the projection
of the perfection of that role.
So each thing is perfectly the perfect
expression of that which it is.
John Dillinger is the perfect
bank robber killer.
Babyface Nelson. They're all perfect.
Adolf Hitler was the perfect
megalomaniac dictator who would just
assume decimate all those stupid Germans
who deserve to die because they lost the
war.
That makes sense to another
megalomaniac. I suppose Hitler,
Mallovich, and Stalin talking together
are in total agreement.
They're the perfect expression of
megalomania.
So life is a walking movie. No huh and
full of lessons. And we keep repeating
it over and over again until we get what
is the lesson that appearance is not
essence. You know, and that the human
mind is unable to discern truth from
falsehood.