about in this one you're registering form and the reason you know form is
there because consciousness is making you aware that it's there it's it's
registering and you're entranced with it because you recognize it this is Mickey
Mouse this is Minnie Mouse and this is a bad dog you recognize so learning the
hippocampus comes in there the watcher then you realize I'm not this I'm not
the story of this the recognition is not volitional who am I then you get I'm the
witness of it oh I'm not the content of it because out of awareness now I become
aware that it is awareness of the observer witness which is coming out of
the light of consciousness and then you realize what I just got through saying
that this is the manifest coming out of the unmanifest out of the potentiality
for this phenomena
you
the phenomena within consciousness itself of which because of awareness I
am the observer the witness but I have no control of what's going on over here
that's a product of the universe okay next next thing you you this is sort of
academic I just finished this book and the book includes everything about
everything you think that it's everything about
everything we were talking about karma and getting so we're the purpose the
circumstances of your birth are fantastic here's how we're like big I was
gonna say herds of birds herds of birds in terms of birds we're like big flocks
of earth yeah and karmically I think we come in as a group I mean I think this
whole group is obviously a group you know are we karmically a group a
here well yeah karmically a group so we're like a bunch of whistling swans we
come on the planet together some of us land first some leave first but
generally we come come along together and we'll all be together for many a year
yet in this lifetime and a lot you know we're gonna be together for a long time
why because the fuel brought us all together nothing happens by accident so
if we
reach certain level here's South America we see the average is around 300
America 410 to 421 Greenland up there Caribbean Islands 300 Cuba is doing very
well despite mr. Castro and the people who don't like mr. Castro the people
themselves are around 300 Castro something else again then the people
here you can see if you never understood karma you can certainly get it in Haiti
I mean it is certainly current they've tried 20 different regimes they've all
failed every attempt has failed at 55 then and what is the quality of their
religion their sacrifice of animals and voodoo and various things all right so
obviously these people all live together at a 55 they have a certain karma
obviously right they don't have the karma to be born and
Canada at 415 or Greenland so where we land then has to do with our design you
know if you're a big whistling Swan you're suitable if you're this kind of a
bird a little boring hummingbird he's obviously got a different kerma I do not
want the current hummingbird it's exhausting just to watch let's move on
to the next life I feel sorry for hummingbirds we're going to meet a lot of
people if we're going to meet a lot of people we're going to see the most
people from Puerto Rico and well Carolina and some other nations of the world
so we show up a lot of times and get some serious questions and questions from
you want to talk to me let me know where you are and if you're going to do a
I watch them, and they, and this is just so he can get a moment of the nectar, and I sit
down, I eat a cheeseburger watching them, I think, geez, okay, we saw Australia, and
then you get the islands here, you get China, Manchuria, you see Europe, Scandinavia, the
secular socialist countries are usually around in the 300s, then you see North Africa, 180
to 190, and then you see, as we come down here, you see energy field at 40, 40, all right,
Central Africa, energy field, okay, so we'll move on, you see karmic propensity then, all
right, so we saw this already, I was on the air about Ontario, America's 421, they're
415, I don't know why, why are they at 415, oh, I know, they got rid of God, oh, right,
they got rid of God, let's see, is that the answer I was looking for, resist, okay, when
you go from Constitution United States, which is calibrated to 710, and you go secular,
you're already dropping a certain amount of energy, so this is here easier to see, Madagascar,
here you see where the mountain gorillas live, but the people, the people live, live,
starvation and savage tribal warfare and here you see the headlines of today the
180 to 190 140 to 190 we see that China has become quiescent as a world threat
at 305 at 305 you're not really a world threat you see the rise of reason and
rationalization rationality in calibrating international relationships
in which I devote a whole chapter in the book because of its inference for
diplomatic relationships in world peace to realize what is the level of
consciousness of the populace what is the level consciousness of the
government and what is the consciousness level of the leader then you can begin
to have effective diplomatic relationships it's gone you see we'll
get into that more later if we get to the end of the thing but you can see the
what do we call it here in America
American form of government whatever you call it doesn't appeal to a lot of
people we'll get to that later because it's meaningless and you see the
government's so you have a form of government that calibrates let's say at
410 and you present it to people that calibrated 120 you're going to say yeah
and what's in it for us so our form of government
is only meaningful at a certain level has to be contextualized a certain way
so we'll move on to the next just speaking of karma how the distribution
of levels of consciousness is distributed over the map eastern and
western hemispheres quite a bit of difference and here we have an
explanation of it all what is this Oh World War two yes well we've we applied
for the sake of this book we calibrated everything
moving and not moving in history and current and current life you can analyze
all the factors and we've discovered very simply that peace is the automatic
consequence of truth and war is the automatic consequence of falsehood and
so we can go back and see how did that how is that demonstrated how could we
have diagnosed it so you know trained as a physician then I see the world dealing
with symptoms and not understanding the cause
they've never discovered yet international diplomacy and politics
has not discovered that the cause of pneumonia is a bacterium they still
think it's the miasma of night air now we say as a physician we need a better
diagnosis how can you cure the patient all right here's the diagnosis we get
the circumstances we get all the players we calibrate their levels of
consciousness and now we have some
predictable scientific means to expect a better result so World War two is the
most familiar historically it's not full of current emotional hysteria and we can
probably calmly look at it from an objective viewpoint we find profound if
we just understand one war you all understand all wars so we'll just pick
this one because nobody's having parades about it currently Winston Churchill
calibrates at 510
very few world leaders Gorbachev calibrated at 500 very few world leaders
Gorbachev took down you know monolithic communism without firing one shot pulled
the plug Cold War couldn't do it he did it single end Gorbachev just took it
apart this man with a tinker toy and it fell apart Roosevelt at 499 so these are
the people that held us together through the agony of World War two the London
Blitz
Roosevelt his fireside chats calibrated 500 so see Aristotle pointed out 350 BC
and did this you know Socrates is my hero when I was a kid other people was
Babe Ruth to me Socrates was my hero Socrates calibrates at 540 anyway
Socrates pointed out that there's three things yeah important in politics and
politics is every day every day in a TV now there is ethos there is logos and
then there is pathos one is the integrity of the speaker the next is the
integrity of the information the third is the who is the audience you can be
patrician be calibrated 460 speak the truth as you know it
you can be patrician be calibrated 460 speak the truth as you know it
calibrated 460 and fall on your butt because you did not contextualize it in
a manner and it was meaningful to the populace so therefore them the value of
rhetoric in those days you know Aristotle and Plato doctors defeated
protagonist because because rhetoric does not calibrate at 460 absolute truth
rhetoric is so the app the proper thing that Aristotle did say was out of
that it is significant that the capacity of the audience has to be taken into consideration.
Otherwise, my criticism of Bush is he's partitioned, the logos is there, the ethos is there, but he misses the pathos.
Who got the pathos?
Churchill.
President Roosevelt.
Now, Roosevelt would make a tough decision. No more butter, no more sugar, no more gasoline.
Everybody has to sacrifice everything. It's going to be nitty-gritty survival.
Instead of protesting and having a parade, we're losing our civil rights.
You can imagine trying that in today's world. Ration your gasoline. Yeah, right.
So,
Roosevelt, we all sat around the radio at night, and
fireside chat, he explained it to you. Oh,
like you're a member of his family.
We need the thing, so we can't have butter because we got to have it for so-and-so,
etc. And then you said, okay.
So, all this the protests that I see going on politically is the failure to communicate your message.
It's one thing to know the truth. It's another thing to get people to sit still for it.
President Truman, Eisenhower, so all you see the
integrity of everybody was pretty integrous.
MacArthur had his problems with pride and all, but you know, they won the war. At the same time,
you see
the Heisenberg principle.
So we had the atomic.
Wernher von Braun?
etc. coming in. We had Los Alamos.
At the same time you have the German military, the US military.
The German military was over 200.
Just so the military, you'll often find as
no matter, how horrible war is, you often find the military as discreet.
Out of honor, out of duty, out of surrender to the country, out for the fatherland?
They're in integrity. It's the people in
that are not in Tigris but the warrior the warrior that's why as soon as World
War two ended the people on both sides shook hands you know guy who was out to
kill you before the minute war war is over you're drinking buddies recalling
the war in which they were the kamikaze pilot and you were the target so there's
a certain integrity which does not prevail at the top anyway our US
military was in Tigris general Rommel you see 203 he went to visit his wife's
birthday on the wrong day all right so these are all the integrates people and
then below 200 I'm gonna risk and do with one war and you can see the
application all wars Adolf Hitler by the end the war was 45
Joseph Stalin 90 Mussolini 60 the Third Reich 70 Neville Chamberlain who thought
Hitler was a good guy and was going to keep his word
and
at 185 the Japanese Embassy in the United States was deceptive at 55 and we
see what happens with Los Alamos double agents the League of Nations was
ineffectual then at 185 just as it is now at 195 attack on Pearl Harbor 45
Joseph Gables 60 Nazi treatment for nurse so you see the London Blitz dr.
Mangala the Cambridge five who were turncoats the Rosenberg's turncoats and
Lourdes Hall who just died or got executed or something though was the
anniversary it was execution imagine the world celebrating your execution out
at a 50 he was famous all right yeah at Tokyo Rose all these people got
executed for treason okay so that is just going through one war let's do a
couple more but you get the general principles without being a particular
You can sit home, calibrate the energy of everything, and you will discover very amazing
things of what went on and why it went on.
And then you see that war is the consequence of the degree that the society was ruled by
falsity.
War is the product of falsity.
It's due to the absence of truth.
Peace is the automatic consequence of truth.
What happened to the next war?
Did we lose the next war?
What war is that?
Well, here again, you see a certain integrity of intention, a certain integrity of intention
of less than wonderful resolution.
You see what this group of people is dealing with.
What it's dealing with.
We know that.
The jihad calibrates at 50.
So you're stuck pretty much the same as you were in World War II.
We've got people that calibrate within the field of at least logic and reason.
They're not calibrating as divinity or sainthood, and they're subject to fallacy.
But what you're looking here is intention.
The intention is, the intention's all right.
The intention's all right.
It's not going to deal with it.
Why?
Because these people are coming from the Marquis of Queensberry rules.
These people are coming from the level of the Komodo dragon.
Marquis of Queensberry against a, I found that out, got into one street fight in my
life.
He instantly kicked me in the testicles, and it was over.
9-11 is a kick in the testicles, and I'll tell you.
The Marquis of Queensberry rules.
The Marquis of Queensberry rules are only going to go so far.
I respect all these people.
They all went to college.
They all told the truth, and they knew it, but I don't think it's going to handle it.
Okay, let's go over to the next.
Korean War, you see the intention here was 300, which is not like it is now.
Now the intention is really around 450.
The U.S. position was 300.
I think we were out to defeat communism or something.
North Korea and those are coming from a low level.
All right, so you see the Vietnam War, you see the U.S. was considerably down and in
tension and below 200.
It was one hell of a war, however, PTSD is a fact.
People say, well, they're just falsifying it to collect money, no, it is a fact.
All right, Cold War, U.S. position was intelligent.
And so you see the U.S. media, you see the U.S. intelligence operations, you see the
top level of government, you're talking about the Cold War, I'm not talking about now, as
far back as several decades.
When was the Cold War?
When did it end?
I forget.
I don't remember.
Anyway, during the Cold War, don't forget, other countries have enormous intelligence
operations.
France, even in peacetime, has probably 10 times as many people out there as we do.
Yeah.
U.S. intelligence even during the Cold War was 195, CIA, 185, East Germany, Russian
position, KGB, Saddam Hussein at 95 then, all right.
So in the Gulf War here, you see President Bush, the senior, was at 400, that's, he's
doing his duty.
Don't forget, the President of the United States puts his hand on the Bible to this
day.
All right, he swears an oath to fulfill the obligations of the President of the United
States to protect the people of this country.
So all right, so that would certainly put you up around 400.
Is the Gulf War syndrome a fact?
Yes.
People thought they were trying to collect, but it was a fact.
And you see the level there.
World War I, you get President Woodrow Wilson at 400, and you get the Kaiser at 165.
Was shell shock a fact?
When I was a kid, the guy next door was a veteran, and he had shell shock.
You know what they say, leave him alone, he has shell shock, and he shook like that.
Shell shock, PTSD, these aftermaths of war are real, and overwhelm of the central nervous
system.
We often use Napoleon and Hitler both as examples.
Hitler in his early youth, you know, or young life, he was in the high 400s, middle 400s,
did a lot for Germany.
Then fell for megalomania when he became the head of all the branches of government.
And he dropped to like 170 or something and lost the war.
The same thing happened with Napoleon.
Napoleon was about 440, very brilliant, almost a genius.
When you go to France, it's staggering what Napoleon did for France, the incredible architecture,
the great libraries, museums and all.
And then when he crowned himself, crowned himself emperor.
He dropped down below.
And at the time of the Battle of Waterloo, the Duke of Wellington at that time calibrated
405, and Napoleon had dropped all the way down to 75.
I think he was really at 90 at the, I think 75 was at the end.
I think at the time of the battle he was around 90.
So 90 is no match for 405, okay.
So what all that is saying is that power corrupts absolutely nothing.
That's it.
The power corrupts absolutely.
When Napoleon negated the divinity of God and said, Pope, you know, the popes, the crown
heads of Europe were always, it's done by God through the Pope, crowned the heads of
Europe.
And Napoleon said, I'll crown myself.
Then he dropped from 440 to where he landed.
The negation of the reality of God or the authority of God symbolically, it's got nothing
to do with the Pope or Catholicism.
It's not.
It's just a symbol because that is only symbolic.
This is what we were talking before, how this man seems to manifest out and this was an
early one.
We'll move on.
Quantum mechanics.
Yes.
We mentioned some of the things.
Potentiality.
See, quantum mechanics has to do with the submicroscopic world.
Newtonian mechanics has to do with the physical world.
And then Heisenberg principle came out of the fact.
The observation that merely observing that the power of intention is such that it can
automatically collapse the wave function, the potentiality into a different actuality.
So this is like the mathematics of creation.
God asked me to do this.
Please explain it so that, how did divinity do it?
Yeah.
Schrodinger process.
There's a complicated equations.
Time dependence.
Yes.
Time dependent and time independent.
The Heisenberg process then is by choice, by intention, you've already altered the consequences.
You cannot do the same experiment twice because the second time it's an experiment that has
been witnessed and through the process of witnessing itself, thereby you collapse the
wave function to a new state of the universe.
The state of the universe is a potential.
Through intention it becomes an actual.
You go from the Schrodinger calculations to the Dirac equations.
The Dirac equations via the Heisenberg principle.
And people, I tell them if you're interested, you can find on the internet, the von Neumann
process and Henry Stapp, Henry Stapp, professor of advanced theoretical physics at Berkeley,
has a really good website for those who want to correlate science, consciousness, and spirituality,
which is the reason I put that in there.
Okay.
Now we explain.
What?
Oh, good.
We only got five minutes.
Thank you, Lord.
The author says, don't bring up war, it's too contentious.
It's not.
It's not really contentious.
The only contentious is taking a viewpoint of it.
Once you comprehend the totality of it, you see it's not really contentious.
You see, it's the evolution of consciousness presenting itself in a certain way within
a certain karmic propensity in which mankind works out his own.
It's his own evolution.
Evolution isn't just a gift.
You know, you go from donkey to genius.
You don't just go from donkey to genius in one lifetime.
Is that true?
Anybody think you go from donkey to genius in one lifetime?
Not likely.
No, it's an evolutionary path.
So for lunch, I want to give you evolution to munch on.
Is this the beginning down here?
This doesn't look right.
Yeah.
Is that one there?
Yes.
Okay.
That's a revised chart.
This is a very, we stole this out of an old dictionary, but we give credit to it.
We tried to get permission from the publisher.
He went out of business in 1956, so it's one of my older books, but I don't think the
facts have changed any, because it has to do with archeologic ages.
And you see that.
The first thing, it's very, very common.
And the reason is that we've got to go back and understand the essence of life.
We have to understand the essence of life.
It's so important, you know, to understand the ego, to understand the ego then, and to
facilitate transcending it.
We have to understand its origination.
The energy field of consciousness itself manifested forth in Biblical terms as light.
The universe has molten, this earth was a molten mass flying off.
It then cooled down over billions of years.
After billions and billions of years, the earth has become, it has become very, very,
and billions of years, a crust, the surface was cool enough for a crust to form.
The center of the earth is still molten, still molten lava.
But the crust cooled off, the possibilities, you see,
because potentiality only becomes actuality when conditions prevail.
So you had to have a crust on this earth for life to be able to survive.
Life evolved then.
The first signs of life as algae, viruses.
Viruses are not conscious.
Algae are not conscious.
Chlorophyll, living via chlorophyll, they're not conscious.
The virus replicates its DNA, but it's not conscious.
It doesn't exist.
It doesn't experience that it exists.
However, it doesn't need anything anyway because it's provided.
Chlorophyll, if you go all green, we could just sit in the sun.
Get all the energy.
We don't have to eat.
Don't have to eat, you don't have to work.
You know what I mean?
It's a brick that'd be colored green.
For animal life, bacteria is the first conscious being, calibrates as one.
And what is the characteristic of life?
And this is the secret of the ego, and I'll get you off guilt about it forever.
In order for life to survive, it's got to be self-serving.
Why?
Because it's not born with energy or a source of energy.
It can only survive by getting energy out there.
The amoeba has to encompass something else in order to live.
The bacteria has to get something.
The core of the ego is, its message is, in order to survive, you have to get.
The intellect then expands that.
The more you get, the better.
The squirrel has that idea.
One time I had a whole thing of things, and I put them on the lawn,
and I went crazy, running and digging a hole, putting a nut in it,
and he'd run back and dig another hole, and he was in a panic,
that while he was digging a hole here, somebody might take his nuts.
He just went crazy.
He would fit in today's world very well.
Bacteria, all right.
So the core, the essence of life, the source of life,
and this is the illusion you have to give up.
The last doorway.
The last doorway, what you're giving up is the experience of this
as the core of essence.
The essence of life and truth, because that's the way it has always been.
And that is what you lay down to God at the last.
Then you find that the source of life is the radiance of divinity.
But in the experiential world, it comes from getting this.
The first invertebrates, Susie gave me a trilobite one time
for Father's Day or something.
The trilobite calibrated at six or eight.
Then it evolves, the level of consciousness up to 12,
many marine invertebrates.
Here's the trilobite here.
This is a smart trilobite.
Mine must have been a dumb one.
This guy's up to 12.
How did he get there?
Oh, this is an old dictionary.
That's right.
Okay. First traces of life, scorpions.
Scorpions, I once wrote a book about it,
because I was an etymologist at one time in my life.
And the scorpion crawled out of the sea 400 million years ago.
Scorpion crawled out of the sea, became a land creature,
and calibrates at 17.
Snails, brachiopods, up to 27.
So this is the calibrated level of the totality of all life on the planet.
It's not exactly concordant with other things,
because this is all of life, represents all of life.
So here we have the scorpion, the first amphibians.
Here we have the shell-crushing sharks,
the first reptiles, amphibious,
the rise of the reptiles,
rise of the dinosaurs in the 60s.
The dinosaurs are in the 60s.
A lot of the people we're dealing with politically are 60.
Would you like to sign a treaty and become a,
what do you call our form of government?
What?
Oh, democracy.
Would you like democracy?
Can I eat it?
Can I kill people with it?
Can I be a hero with it?
A little hard to sell it to these people here.
Democracy to a shell-crushing shark.
You people are the leaders of the future.
You get the reality of international diplomacy,
then you get what survival's about,
and you see it isn't truth, it's how you present the truth.
How you present the truth,
it's either going to look good to eat or not.
Because the core of the ego here is to eat.
In other words, the only reason anybody would be interested in
our form of government is what do we get out of it.
You understand?
You got to come from where they are, hungry people.
Give me your gun and vote for this form of government.
Give me a break.
I mean, the naivety of that.
All right.
I try to bring spiritual truth into actually an understanding
is not just an abstract goody-goody.
But it's part of the totality of all of life
and our experience of life.
And therefore your perception of it is quite different
if you have a greater understanding of consciousness and spiritual truth.
Instead of decrying it or vilifying it,
you can say this person must have some karmic reason to go through this.
And we all must be learning something through this experience
because all of humanity jointly learns
and speaks, learns truth jointly.
Here you see the rise of the reptiles, rise of the dinosaurs,
first birds, primitive mammals, the last of the dinosaurs.
That's what they think.
They thought they lived.
All right.
And you see the evolution of animals, modern animals and plants together to the 200.
And finally, mankind in the last flick of an eyelid.
The last flick of an eyelid of evolutionary time
is so brief that it hardly shows up on the chart.
That hardly, approximate duration in millions of years.
You see, we're not even on the chart yet.
The human evolution is so minuscule.
That gives us a different feeling of the evolution of time when we say
the spirit, the soul, karma evolves over great eons of time.
In as much as we got born as humans.
And the human has a physicality.
This is how far back the ego goes.
70% of archeologic time had already transpired
before consciousness level was even at one.
That gives us a certain patience with our own ego and a certain respect for it.
Your ego was born before trilobites.
Let's see if that's a fact.
The ego birthed before trilobites existed.
Wow.
The ego was already on its way in the very beginning of archeologic time.
Oh, so it's sort of a dinosaur-y kind of thing.
Yeah, sort of a primitive kind of a thing.
Right.
What does this primitive kind of thing do?
Well, now we understand.
His name is Ego.
Ego is a human being.
It's buried in the back of the human brain then.
So when man developed the prefrontal cortex,
they didn't remove the old animal brain.
No.
They plastered it on top of this.
Now you got an animal that can think.
You just gave a retarded kid a gun.
Don't get into trouble, Junior.
Don't aim it at anybody.
No, Mom.
Bladdle, bladdle, bladdle.
War is giving the ego a gun.
That's all it is.
All right, so how do I understand that which has been here
since the very beginning of earthly time almost,
not earthly time, but living time,
is I get what it is by understanding how it evolved.
I now, instead of vilifying it,
I see that the ego is doing what it's supposed to do.
Get.
Get more money.
Get more prestige.
Get more cars.
Get more ladies in bed with you.
Whatever.
Get more time on TV.
Be a bigger celebrity.
Get a bigger house.
Get a BMW.
No, you don't do that in the bathroom.
You thought BMW meant the bathroom.
No, that's not the bathroom.
It's a car.
Okay, so you own it instead of negating it.
That's why I approve of the workbook of the Course in Miracles,
but not textbook.
Because textbook deteriorates.
It goes from 600 down to 550.
Why is it?
Because it begins to vilify
and get into a dualistic relationship with the ego thing,
and you can't beat the ego by getting positionalized about it.
You can only dissolve it by owning it.
You're born with the karma within.
The animal only can survive if it gets.
A human being cannot survive without getting.
His body can't survive without getting.
You have to get food.
You see, if we were green, we wouldn't have to be the way we are.
Go sit in the sun?
Oh, no, we have to go for lunch.
Ego, you're hungry, aren't you?
He's hungry.
And what will happen if I don't feed you?
I will die.
Oh, no wonder he's so panicky.
All right, don't do a BM there.
We're just sitting on the table.
Okay.
How long do we have for lunch?
Wow.
Okay.
So, shall we discontinue now and re-continue afterwards?
Appearance is not essence.
The cover is not the book.
Well, we were understanding how the ego developed over time
as a necessity of survival.
Consequently, it's trained to get.
We call that the solar plexus fixation.
When it's dominated by that solar plexus energy,
it cannot be satisfied.
Why?
Because the problem is not wanting that.
It's wanting-ness.
You cannot satisfy wanting-ness by satisfying it.
You only feed it more.
The more money you make, the more money you have to have.
Millions is not enough.
Multi-millions is not enough.
Billions is not enough.
Going to bed with one maid is not enough.
Ten is not enough.
Thirty is not enough.
There are men that have gone to bed with hundreds.
Their only lament is they're too old now.
Say, after 450 women, you haven't satisfied your curiosity yet.
So you cannot satisfy it.
So once the energy gets caught in the solar plexus,
you're stuck below 200 of wanting-ness and craving-ness.
Because you're wanting and craving it,
it looks like you're being deprived.
So you hear the disgruntled people in the world
that are always complaining how they're deprived.
It's because their wanting-ness cannot be satisfied.
It's not satisfy-able.
Not satisfy-able.
So they fault everything in society.
The current favorite target is America
and all of its establishments
because they're coming from,
they feel sensitive and uncomfortable and deprived.
They need a psychiatrist.
They really don't have to change the United States Constitution.
They need a doctor.
So whether it's Wal-Mart or whatever it is.
So, all right.
That comes from a distortion which we'll get into later.
Called the distorted hermeneutics of relativistic epistemology.
Which you have to know to understand society.
Yeah, it's a whole chapter in a book.
Hermeneutics.
Hermeneutics means the meaning.
Meaning, science of meaning.
Relativistic epistemology.
And the secret of understanding it is given by the mad hatter.
Who says things will just mean what I want them to mean.
Oh.
The denial of the absolute.
The denial of logic, reason, etc.
The denial, it's actually the denial of divinity.
It comes out of the narcissistic ego which wants to be God.
And wishes to replace God and become God.
Yeah.
So, anyway.
We'll get to that later this afternoon.
All right.
So we saw how for life to evolve,
it had to be get.
It had to be want.
So wantingness and gettingness is intrinsic to the ego.
And then when you add a prefrontal cortex,
you get the what of the gettingness and the wantingness.
Fame, fortune, more money, etc.
So you can't satisfy him because...
Because what?
He wants all of it.
He wants all the women in the world.
All the money.
All the power.
So he's doing a good job.
When you want something more, you know he's doing a good job.
So you say, you're doing a good job.
They cut in front of you, they deserve to die.
We hate them.
Good.
So you own it.
When you own it and stop resisting it, you dissolve it.
You dissolve it because oppositionalism gives it energy.
So that which is not truth, why give it a reality by resisting it and opposing it?
That is the way of traditional religion.
Traditional religion.
How many enlightened people have occurred on the planet?
Hardly any.
The difficulty is that God is not at the bottom of the chart.
He's at the top of the chart.
Joy, forgiveness, happiness, thankfulness, not at the bottom.
But at the top.
Okay.
Generosity instead of greed.
So we'll move on now.
We've seen how it evolved.
And we've done the animals before.
And we were saying this morning, you know, we never did llamas.
Where's llamas?
We have permission to do llamas.
Llamas is over 200.
202.
205.
210.
215.
Wow.
Llamas are 210.
I don't know.
We didn't do llamas there.
We don't have a dozen of them.
Where's llamas?
I don't see them on there.
Okay.
So anyway, here you see the animal kingdom now.
First we saw it in archeologic time.
Now you see it.
We said bacteria is one.
Protozoa are two.
Crustaceans, insects, arachnids, amphibians, fish, sharks, vipers, komodo dragon, 40.
Reptiles, predatory.
So we say they're predatory.
They have to get energy.
A tiger doesn't have any chlorophyll to get energy from the sun.
He doesn't have batteries.
He can only eat a rabbit.
We say from the human viewpoint he's killing and he's predatory.
But to the lion, he is not predatory.
He is not killing.
And if you ask a kinesiology, does he think he's killing anything, you get no.
To the lion, he's having lunch.
And the lunch won't stand still.
You have to munch it.
You hit it like that.
If your cheeseburger was running down the street.
The animal does not wish the death of its prey.
No, it doesn't wish the death of its prey.
It wishes the life of its own body and it has to eat however it can eat.
So we call them predatory.
That's from our point of observation.
That's a projection of res interna onto res externa.
Res cogitans onto the external world.
Snakes, alligators, dinosaurs.
And I told you, a lot of people on this planet that are in the everyday news.
They're on TV every night, Fox News.
There they are, calibrate less than a dinosaur.
Less than a dinosaur.
Why?
Because these are innocent.
Where those who decapitate others purposely are not innocent.
They're not eating them for survival.
So they calibrate less than a Komodo dragon because of intention.
Then we see the dinosaurs, the whales, dolphins, migratory birds, birds of prey, rodents, rhinoceros.
Oh, he's a mean looking guy.
Songbirds, doves, polar bears, grizzly bears, water buffalo, jackals and foxes.
So these are all what we call predatory, are they not?
And finally, then at consciousness level of 200, we see a dramatic change.
As we did on the graph of energy, on the scale of consciousness.
We see a major shift of quality.
So as energy frequency goes up like a spectrum, like the electromagnetic spectrum.
At a certain level it changes quality.
Water at 32, below 32 is a solid.
32 becomes liquid.
212 becomes gas.
The change of quality then.
So at 200 you see a change of quality.
And the change of quality now becomes familiar to us all.
So what we call the predator, you now see the benign herbivore.
Zebra, gazelle, giraffe, deer, bison.
What did we say llamas was?
210.
210?
Yeah.
Okay, so llamas are in with sheep, elk, dairy cows, range cattle.
Alright, the elephant himself has to eat all day long just to survive.
The farm horse.
You see, if you take an animal and then combine it with a human environment,
he jumps about five points in consciousness.
So the dog jumps five points the minute a family adopts him.
We get up to gorillas at 275, the same as cats.
A cat is 240.
When a family adopts him, he jumps to 245.
And if people have 66 cats, you can imagine where they would be at.
66 times 5, wow.
That human energy is raising the level of consciousness of the cat family.
Now, we'll find out something interesting.
Below conscious, well, we'll save that for later.
Anyway, these people have a group karma.
Their consciousness is aligned with a common attractor field.
There is a attractor field.
There's only one cat in the universe.
And then that cat energy, that awareness, which is where intelligence learns from experience,
occurs, is on the level of consciousness, in that attractor field.
All right, so these animals inherit the karmic consequence of that attractor field,
which we'll learn later is the same with people who calibrate below 200.
Like an animal, they do not have a personal etheric brain, personal karma.
They join in the group karma of that energy field.
So if you're born a mackerel, you see the deep-sea,
pictures of the mackerel, they swirl like a big doughnut in the water.
Hundreds of thousands of them congregate.
They're following one single attractor field.
They are not individual consciousness following each other like pilots in formation.
They are not like pilot formation.
Each one of them is individually aligned with that energy field
and is following that field within himself, each one,
which has certain consequences.
There are certain consequences in human history,
where people below 200 are now led as though they have one mind,
not too intelligent either.
Because to be intelligent, you have to be over 200 and be able to think for yourself.
So you see group think.
You see 70 million people going,
Sighail, Sighail, Sighail, Sighail.
What are they, automatons?
Have they lost the capacity to think, to reason? What?
If you've got the capacity to think or reason,
you get exterminated.
So in every revolution, intellectuals are the first ones to be killed,
because they might object.
Yeah.
No, the way you take over a society is first by distorting logic,
captivating the intellectuals of the academic world.
And so you start from there,
so that when you start coming up with various things,
their objection has already been silenced.
All right, so you see dogs go up five points.
Gorillas, chimpanzees.
Alex is a great parrot at 4.01, and is on the internet.
And I forget, Dr. Pepperdine, I think, is the one, University of Tucson.
You see Coco at 4.05.
And so you see, the question is, can animals think?
400 says yes, they can think.
All the arguments about that.
The songbird song.
So there's three strange exceptions,
and we've never gotten the karmic reasons for this.
The songbird's song calibrates at 500.
The cat's purr calibrates at 500.
See, the cat is up here as a being,
but its purr somehow channels some kind of an other energy.
And the dog's wagging tail calibrates at 500.
Universal love. Universal love. Yeah.
Yeah. Friendly dog just loves everyone.
Friendly kitty, off to pet it, and there's the purr.
So that is strange indeed, is it not?
All right. So we'll go on to the next thing.
I already told you my horse karma.
I had very bad horse karma.
I finally overcame it, and I avoided horses for years.
But I'd overcome it anyway.
So I went over to meet this new horse,
and I never had a kiss from a horse in my life.
He gave me a kiss.
That's a great karmic moment where I ended my negative karma with horses.
I've been thrown 20 times, I think.
Okay. On to the next.
All right. You see, spiritual foundation.
Now, when we talk about the Chinese fortune cookie,
those who are spiritually evolved see the wisdom involved.
See the wisdom involved.
The basic spiritual foundations from 200 and up,
you see, have to do with ethics and morality.
Ethics and morality are under vociferous attack right now.
And what are the basic spiritual things from which we take off?
What you see in front of you is really the Boy Scouts,
the Girl Scouts, the 4-H Club, the Elks.
You see the backbone of what is now called traditional America.
Consideration for others.
And when I grew up in the Midwest in traditional America,
we thought there's only two kinds of people.
There's these kind of people who are decent, honest, friendly, polite,
and then there's criminals.
That's all there was.
There was Babyface Nelson, John Dillinger,
Scarface in Chicago, Capone.
And then there was normal people.
That's what we thought all there was on the planet.
You go to church on Sunday, you don't steal.
If you break any rules, you get stricken with guilt.
You go into a whole big guilt thing.
But we thought everybody was reliable and honest
and did hard work.
Everybody was moral.
Everybody was helpful.
And then there was cranky old guys,
but you know, you made an exception for them.
And everybody was expected to be thoughtful.
You know, they'd leave the toilet seat up or down.
Everybody persisted.
You just didn't give up like a weak nilly about everything.
We were all tolerant.
I don't know, I didn't experience or witness
any racial prejudice at all when I grew up.
I never saw it.
Black people would be loved because they were black.
Chinese people would be loved because they were Chinese.
Everybody was just loved for what they were.
And so there wasn't even any,
that kind of class distinction or whatever.
That was traditional America.
People were dependable.
They were really genuine.
They were who they were.
Everybody was expected to be stable and honorable.
When a woman entered the room, we all stood up in respect.
We were part of honoring femininity.
Everybody was sort of neat.
And we considered this normal.
So normal calibrates at 300.
We assumed, unless declared otherwise,
that everybody was sane, fair, run by ethics,
did what they could to be healthy, a sense of humor.
Some people got left out of that, but we avoided them
because they were going to be dangerous.
He never laughed at anything.
Oh, God, the word went out.
Don't try joking around Uncle Busbo.
He's been seeing a doctor.
Sense of humor, loyal, equitable.
We call this wisdom.
So here you got wisdom at 385.
You don't have to be a rocket scientist
to begin to look to wisdom.
Before you make a decision, you say,
this may be the right thing to do,
this may be the correct thing to do,
but is it wisdom?
In writing this book, I ran across that endlessly.
Is it wise?
Does it serve mankind?
Does it serve my obligation to God to reveal this or not?
And if so, how to contextualize it
so as to be as less upsetting?
All right, so wisdom then was constantly part of the thing.
To be loyal to God and to truth, you see.
At the same time,
ask, yes, but is it wise and rational?
Is it wise?
Is it intelligent?
Does it support life?
Is it intrinsically benign?
Is it really protective of life?
Is it humane to share what you've learned?
All right, so pleasing means a certain ambiance.
It doesn't mean codependency.
Glad, happy, sensible, pleasant, positive.
We call these wisdom.
All right, so what does it mean?
Well, it means to follow the earth at 240.
Relatively modest.
You try to phrase things in a way diplomatically.
Yes, you will have to be beheaded later today, Dave.
However, you can have whatever you like for lunch.
And in those lifetimes, I said to the husband,
don't worry, it's your job.
Don't feel bad about it.
It's okay.
You won't collect the Social Security if it doesn't.
All right.
Be polite.
At the same time, you're not wishy-washy.
You could be faulted for being wishy-washy.
At the same time, you were nice.
You were nice, but not wishy-washy.
So that's the way in which you contextualize the thing.
The way you present it is with consideration for the audience.
And as we said, Aristotle's pathos,
to be aware of the impact of your behaviors
and your statements on others.
And to say, is it wise?
Does it serve the good of mankind?
Does it serve God?
So wisdom then, as you get more spiritually advanced,
becomes a little more complex.
Because from this viewpoint, it might look this way.
From this viewpoint, another way.
And that whole concept of codependency comes in there, you see.
All right.
So we'll move on to the next one.
But we thought everybody was this way.
Anybody grew up in Midwest?
Midwest, wasn't that the way it was?
We thought everybody was that way,
except for John Dillinger and Al Capone.
This is too much of a brain picture.
We'll move on to the next brain.
Yeah.
Well, we said that under 200,
a person does not even have an etheric brain.
And I didn't even know whether to put that in the book.
But under 200, people share a group karma,
the attractor field of that group.
So if, let's say, you're hateful,
and you do that to get your life to hatefulness,
then your consciousness is dominated by the attractor field
to which you have ascribed.
That to which you commit, then.
You are under the dominance of that attractor field.
That attractor field.
That attractor field under 200, then,
expresses itself in brain physiology up here as left brain.
The animal brain, ego's brain is the left brain.
And how is that?
The input from the world,
whether it's television or somebody bumping into you.
I mean, somebody bumped into us at lunch, you know.
And, well, it was an accident.
We both apologized to each other.
I didn't want her to feel upset.
She didn't want us to feel upset.
We were concerned with each other's happiness and welfare, etc.
That's right brain.
Left brain would go into an outrage.
Now, the left brain input,
the fast track is to the thalamus, a relay station.
The fast track is to the emotional centers
and what's called the amygdala, the emotional.
So the fast track is perception.
Perception sees it, fast tracks it
through the animal interpretation of perception
and then stores that memory in the hippocampus.
As I say, I always like hippocampus.
It's somewhere in Mississippi or Missouri.
Hippocampus, Missouri.
Anyway, so the fast track then is left brain, fast track.
Whatever happened to reason and intelligence
in the good book of wisdom you read?
Well, that's in your frontal cortex.
And unfortunately, the frontal cortex in these people is slow.
Slow.
You've already pulled the trigger
and you're like, maybe I should have thought about that.
Oops.
So these people are subject to oops.
And they come back from New York and they say,
boy, isn't that an awful place?
They're all so impolite there and rude.
They're all out to cheat you and all that.
So the left brain person,
consciousness level below 200,
I want you to have some compassion for it
because that's the way the experience is.
That's how they experience the world.
It's not just malevolence.
But that's how they experience the world.
They see it in a distorted way.
They see America as the great Satan, let's say.
Because their brain physiology interprets everything this way.
And they'll say, well, I also read the good book.
Yeah, but the good book is stored over here in the cortex,
which you don't listen to.
You listen to your animal.
First kill them, then remember the good book.
Okay.
So below 200, you have a different physiology,
different brain function,
different karmic mechanism.
It's group, attractor-fueled karma.
The prefrontal cortex, as you see,
is plastered onto this old animal brain.
Here's the animal brain.
And now you just plastered this onto it.
And it's slow.
And people have psychopathic personalities.
Sociopathic personalities.
The actual thickness of the prefrontal cortex
is actually less than normal people.
Congenitally, anatomically unable to be socially responsible.
Hmm.
Impaired.
Therefore, what we see as perpetrator out there
is actually, when you look at it differently, the victim.
The vicious, psychopathic, narcissistic, middle-of-the-maniac
that leads 10 million people to death
is literally also the victim.
The perpetrator, then, is the victim of falsity.
Doesn't have enough evolution of consciousness
to discern truth from falsehood.
Is therefore the victim of propaganda.
And this is how Joseph Goebbels got his power.
He knew this.
You can condition the animal to see things that way.
Yeah.
Consciousness level below 200 is left brain dominance.
This is a linear Newtonian world.
It releases constant stress, adrenaline, fight or flight,
alarm reaction, Selye's alarm reaction,
the release of the canon fight or flight pathway,
adrenaline, cortisone,
and that's how you perforate your ulcer.
Being an alarm reaction all the time.
So during the accident, which came on just an hour ago,
the alarm reaction was about that fast.
And then we looked at each other.
It was like recognizing the energy of the other person.
And we all said,
ah, forget the insurance company, nobody got hurt.
Instant forgiveness, instant so what?
Instant capacity.
Why? Because the etheric brain is functional.
All right, so in this left brain person, who is an animal,
the thymus is under stress.
That's why you have to do the Dr. Diamond's thymic thump.
Because right now, after that,
your acupuncture system got blown out.
Your acupuncture system.
So the ordinary person, left brain, who got rear-ended,
will go into this, blow their acupuncture meridian,
end up with indignation and rage.
Indignation and rage.
All right.
So the left brain person is under thymic stress.
The depression of the thymus results in less circulating
so-called killer cells and immunity.
The killer cells are the good guys, despite their name.
They kill bugs.
They kill germs.
So you lose your immunity.
You're not able to fight off infection.
You catch colds and viruses.
And these people walk into the same crowd as you did.
But out of 100 people here, only three get a cold.
Over here, 72 get a cold.
Quite a difference.
So the immune system, you see, is impaired.
The brain neurotransmitters here, you deplete the serotonin level.
That's why you see a psychiatrist.
He puts you on something to rebuild the serotonin level.
The track to the emotions is twice as fast
as through the cerebral cortex to the emotions.
Right.
That's quite a different world.
49% of America.
85% of the world.
Lives along this track here.
So when you present something to other cultures,
you have to know what is the calibrated level of consciousness
because you want to know, is this side of the brain even working?
Is it even working?
Many of the cultures we've dealt with,
this side of the brain isn't even working yet.
You're telling about the superiority of a governmental system
when these people are living here.
You see why diplomacy very often has failed.
Yeah.
All right.
So this side, the right brain dominance,
now above consciousness level 200,
it now becomes a right brain track predominantly.
The input now is fast through the etheric brain
to the emotional center
because at 200 now, one develops an etheric brain.
Aetheric brain is not protoplasmic.
It exists of pure energy.
People who think they are protoplasm
have a hard time understanding etheric brain.
I said, well, you don't have any problem understanding your radio set.
I mean, you know, invisible energy fields, TV.
The whole world is made up of invisible, non-protoplasmic,
non-measurable, non-physical energy field frequencies and vibrations.
And when it comes to consciousness,
not only the very advanced high frequency vibrations,
but even beyond them, there are octaves beyond them.
So above 200, then, you get the rise of kundalini energy,
what's called kundalini energy.
That is from a little culture called kundalini energy.
I don't favor it because it sounds foreign to Americans.
A spiritual energy then arises
and begins to flow up tracks in the spine.
The east, the hot and the cold, the east and the west tracks,
and they've got fancy Sanskrit names,
which you can live without.
Anyway, the energy flows up the spine,
and as your consciousness gets into the 500s,
maybe around 540, I would guess around 540,
around 4 or 540, let's see, unconditional love, yeah.
It begins to experience it about 540, over 540, at 540.
Yeah, okay, unconditional love then,
because much to your surprise, you know,
not having read anything about it or heard anything about it,
you begin to notice this exquisite sensation
going up your spine, going up your back.
It flows up your back,
and strangely it flows into your brain.
It went on for six years, I think.
This exquisite energy, better than an orgasm, yeah.
Better in quality.
Very close to the experience of the presence of divinity
when I was in a snow bank, age 12 or 14.
The meltingness of the exquisiteness of this field prevails,
and you feel the same,
the same exquisite energy flowing up your back.
If you think about, if you focus your attention
on the left side of your brain, it flows on the left side.
If you focus on the right, it flows on the right side.
It's absolutely exquisite.
This energy, as I've written about in books,
acts on its own.
It has nothing to do with you as a person or volitional.
It may flow out to an automobile wreck
where people are praying,
and it flows to them of its own.
And when it's done its job, it shuts off.
The energy may flow into a person nearby
with some physical problem.
And you witness the miraculous,
the person crippled and psychotic and delusional.
After a few minutes, you hear them quiet down,
the delusions disappear,
and the crippled, supposedly crippled person
gets up and walks away.
And you go, oh, oh.
So the miraculous occurs.
It happens simultaneously of its own.
It has to do with the karmic ripeness of the person.
One day we were in Korea.
We were sitting across from lunch.
And this woman, and I'm not getting why,
they placed her across from me.
In the middle of it, all of a sudden,
she's telling me how she's paralyzed on one side
and paralyzed on this side and another.
And we had similar experiences with others,
nuns and people.
And, oh, I suddenly sort of got what she was looking for.
I thought, oh, God, she's looking for her healing.
Well, that has nothing to do with me.
So I just thought lovingly of her
and, you know, what I could do on a limited basis.
And the energy then either brings about the miraculous
or it does not.
It has nothing to do with you as a person, nothing at all.
It just uses you as an antenna
to radiate the energy elsewhere.
So that's that kundalini energy.
You see, you now have right brain dominance.
This kundalini energy creates this etheric brain.
And the etheric brain is what accumulates
the karmic consequences of all your decisions.
The gift of divinity is free choice,
that only you have the rudder to steer the ship.
And once you set your compass in a certain way,
you bring certain energies and powers in to be supportive.
One thing that happens then is right brain dominance.
It's nonlinear.
It releases endorphins.
You feel peace, positive emotions.
And the thymus gland is supported.
Increase of killer cells, increase of immunity,
rapidity of healing.
Some of the healings that even in this lifetime
were, you know, frankly, miraculous.
It balances the acupuncture system.
And you have a positive kinesiologic response.
The track to the emotions,
then, is slower than that through the etheric cortex.
So, we instantly, like today's experience,
I looked at her, I got exactly where she's at.
She looked at us, got exactly where we're at.
Both of us knew there was nothing but peace on each side.
We instantly knew it.
She didn't have to talk to us or convince us.
One glance, we all knew we were okay.
That's how long it took.
Because we got it right here.
We got what her energy was, what our energy was.
And it all went fine.
The reason I'm telling you this now
is because it was stored in the hippocampus.
It was stored in the hippocampus
as a positive experience.
You see how a person who's paranoid
would think she did it on purpose,
insists he's going to sue her,
claim he's got a whiplash.
You see how, what a different thing, huh?
A whole different energy.
Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh.
There was one on TV, remember?
I think it was San Francisco or someplace.
And you see all the people coming out of the front of the bus,
and then you see all the street people
climbing in the back of the bus
so that they can come out the front
and they take down their name and address.
It was hysterical. It was on television.
Oh, God.
Yeah, we said, we don't need your insurance company.
You don't need our insurance company.
So, you know, we blessed each other.
And we were only concerned that the other one was upset.
I gave her a hug. She gave us a hug.
We were only concerned that the other person
might be upset by this.
I think that's normal, you know.
But other people are not that way.
Other people are not that way.
Other people would see it as an opportunity, you see.
All right, so then the spiritual energy, over 200,
transforms you as an individual,
changes your brain physiology,
changes how you experience life,
changes how people respond to you.
Over 200, New York gets to be a very friendly place.
Everybody knocked their brains out.
They knocked their brains out to be nice to us.
I don't know what more you could expect.
Okay, we stayed at a beautiful hotel.
Guest of a wonderful person.
Saw beautiful things.
Went for a ride in the park.
I mean, what more do you want?
They even had a parade for us.
It was called Israeli Day Parade.
Right down Fifth Avenue.
And that was interesting.
And police, I'd never seen police like that.
We looked out the hotel window.
They had police from Fifth Avenue
all the way down a couple of blocks,
running through into Central Park.
Whoa, what a security operation.
Yeah.
Okay, and it went peacefully.
Nothing else happened.
Because of evolution, you see,
over 200, the mind is different.
People of more advanced consciousness
assume everybody has a mind like yours.
The fact is, they do not.
They do not have a mind like yours.
Why are there so many crazies in the world?
Because you live here and they live there.
Oh, that's how 155 thinks as compared to 275.
So, you see, the lower mind is a different attractor field.
It's a different energy field.
People that are into esoteric information,
such as the Bailey books and all,
are familiar with all these terms
and the esoteric terminology.
But lower mind has a different centralized focus of energy.
It attracts to it then different what attracts to higher mind.
Higher mind has a different attractor field.
So we can talk about the physics of consciousness.
On that plane, lower mind then sees things
in a pretty vicious kind of a paradigm.
You hear these politicians get on
with their veins standing out in their neck
and calling the other one a liar.
It doesn't matter which party they belong to.
It's just they've lost their marbles.
And they shout and scream and vilify.
And you wonder who are they talking to
because they're certainly turning these people off.
Turning them off.
No, they're talking to these people.
Oh, well, if you're talking to these people,
now they make sense.
Now they make sense.
Now, obviously, they're appealing to these people here
because here you're talking from reason.
You're speaking rationally, calmly, with reason,
with proof, with ethics, morality.
You're talking to 275.
Over here, you're talking to 155.
Wow, what a big difference.
And the big difference is not only 100 points,
but here you've crossed over 200
to ethical responsibility.
Here you're under 200.
Two different categories of the citizenry.
And you will hear the politicians screaming
emotionally to these people here
because that's what appeals to these people here.
These people here are turned off by it.
I hear politicians screaming, calling names, invective.
I see the veins in his neck standing out.
I've turned off on the guy already.
I don't care what he's talking about.
It's not the kind of animal I can listen to.
And I say, turn down the TV.
Good God, I'm trying to think.
All right.
Lower mind, then, is concerned with content.
Higher mind is concerned with context.
Context.
In what context?
This one quotes what somebody said.
What they do is purposely misquote it out of context,
so as to make the person look negative.
This person says, yes, but under what context?
I mean, when was it that happened?
Oh, World War II was on.
That does change it quite a bit, doesn't it?
Yes.
All right, so this is concrete.
This is more abstract.
This is specific.
This is more general.
This gets very personalized.
This is more impersonal.
This looks at specifics.
This looks more at the class.
This one is reactive.
This one is detached.
This one says, let's give him a good punch.
This one says, let's think about it.
What's the best move?
What's the best move we could make under these circumstances?
More detached and reflective.
The recall of events of these people at 155
is different than the recall of events of people at 275.
Yeah.
We were talking at lunch about, you know,
the experience of being in the military in World War II.
People above this respect the honor
of the former foe.
People on this side still probably hate him.
All right, so this is reactive and this is detached.
This one says, wait a second, let's think it over.
This one plans for things,
but this one begins to, tries more to create it.
This one looks for definition.
This one tries to get, yeah, but what is the meaning of it?
But this is pedestrian.
This is transcendent.
This is motivated, like by greed or anger or resentment.
This deals more in inspiration.
What is the overall intention of the field?
We're trying to build a company here.
You know what I mean?
We're trying to build a party.
We're trying to create a new environment.
This is involved with morals.
This is involved with ethics.
This is right and wrong.
Ethics is a little more sophisticated
because ethics depends also on the situation.
What's ethical in one situation is unethical in another.
Whether the Patriot Act is passed during time of war
or time of peace makes a big difference.
Time of peace, I'm going to get out there and parade.
Time of war, it's obviously a necessity.
Examples, principles.
Physical and emotional survival,
this one is interested more in intellectual development.
This one is interested in immediate pleasure
and gratification.
This one is more interested in the fulfillment of the potential,
long-term goals over short-term goals.
This one wants to acquire.
This one wants to savor it.
This one wants to think and wants denotation.
This person wants to process it
and see what is the meaning of it.
What is the significance?
This one looks for significance.
This one looks for facts.
I can see the facts on television.
But what is the significance of that?
What does it mean for all of us, mankind?
What does it mean for Americans?
What does it mean for world peace?
What is the meaning of that?
So this side is more like reflective
and lives more in the field.
It's a contemplative lifestyle.
Contemplative people are living more in the overall field.
What's the significance to all of us?
What's the impact going to be?
You know, outsourcing jobs, price of gasoline, etc.
This side just walks about the price of gasoline.
But this side is looking at, yeah,
what is the overall impact going to be
on international monetary valuations, etc.?
What's the long-term,
what does it mean to all of us in humanity?
Okay.
This brings us the rule,
the rule of Western society
in the time of the ancient Greeks
and is interpreted by Christianity, etc.
And as current in our daily experience of law
and construction of the United States government,
comes out of this whole tradition.
This morning we quoted my favorites of childhood,
of Aristotle and Socrates, etc.
They calibrate, so we'll see.
These are the people
who influenced the whole intellectual development of man.
The United States Constitution calibrates at 710.
It's the highest in the world.
It's the highest it has ever been,
higher than any theocracy even.
So if we look at the great books of the Western world,
I had the good fortune to obtain a whole set.
It came out in the 50s.
It was put together by Mortimer Adler
at the University of Chicago.
The scholars of the day.
And there was much argument.
They studied this, chewed it over for years,
and came out with a list of the greatest minds
that have ever lived up until recent times,
up until the last one is Sigmund Freud.
So the last volume is Freud.
Where is Freud?
I remember Freud's at 499.
So the great books of the Western world,
the intellectual tradition
out of which we all drew our education,
our law, our government,
all is the fallout
of this.
From 350 BC down to the present time,
this is what has dominated rational, traditional society.
This is traditional America that I grew up in.
Reason, intellect, ethics, morals, responsibility.
You see how Thomas Aquinas,
I studied Thomas Aquinas.
I went to a Jesuit college.
I went to a state teacher's college,
then a Jesuit college.
Then the University Medical School.
The medical school reflected the impact
because it was a Jesuit medical school.
The ethics of Thomas Aquinas
impacted us all.
So we grew up as physicians
who had an ethical, moral responsibility
to our patient.
Money and all that was secondary.
And if they didn't have the money,
you told them to hell with it.
That's the way it was done
because we had taken an oath.
So that was the impact then,
Thomas Aquinas.
And here we see Aristophanes and Aristotle
at 498.
498 is about as far as you can go.
It's about as far as you can go.
Socrates is not on here
because Socrates didn't write any books.
Of course, he's in Plato.
So Socrates calibrates at 540.
Socrates impressed me
because at a time,
see, this is 350 BC.
So he couldn't get the notion of God
out of Christianity.
He wasn't born yet.
He was far away from the Orient.
He never heard of the Buddha.
He never heard of the Indian gurus
that came out of India.
Without any monotheistic precedence then,
Socrates arrived at a profound commitment
to truth as the pathway to God.
In fact, Socrates,
when he was accused of corrupting the youth
by telling them the truth,
it's a dangerous occupation.
Oh, God bless.
And by telling the truth,
Socrates then put himself
in bad favor with the government
and he was condemned to death.
However, Socrates was given a chance
to recant.
He had by court order
to commit suicide by drinking the hemlock
or he could recant.
He felt it would negate the central meaning
and purpose and thrust of his entire life
to negate truth.
And so rather than violate truth,
he drank the hemlock and died.
540.
What a profound belief.
What a profound investment
at a time when religion was not even dominant,
except the old Greek gods
who don't carry much energy.
Aristotle.
We see Augustine at 503.
So these are almost all
in the high 400s
with a few exceptions.
Augustine jumps over to 503.
You see the great names,
Copernicus, Dante at 505.
He jumps over.
We see Darwin at 450.
Darwin at 450.
So the theories of evolution then
calibrate at 450.
Descartes, who we quoted quite a bit today,
at 470.
Then you see Engels somehow got
in the good guy list here.
He snuck in back door at 200.
He's sort of iffy.
A little bit iffy.
You could push him over either way.
You see the great scientific geniuses of time.
Freud at 499.
I've told the story about Freud before.
Galen at 450.
They're great physicians.
Galileo at 485.
Well, Galileo certainly upset the world
by telling the truth, didn't he?
In fact, it was 400 years
before his excommunication was recalled.
You can call it exactly
swift and speedy justice,
but it did happen.
That's Galileo's karma, probably.
Right?
Probably Galileo's karma
or the field out of which he said it.
But you see,
heresy is not that what you see
heresy is not that what you say
is a violation of the church belief.
That is not the basis for heresy.
Heresy is when ordered by the church
to cease and desist
or to decline what you've said you refused.
So heresy is
denial of the ecclesiastic
authority of the church.
It's not because you said
that the earth goes around the sun
and vice versa.
It's because when ordered
by ecclesiastic authority
to refute his theory,
he refused.
So you see, that is the basis of heresy
is refusal to bow to the authority
of ecclesiastic
bodies,
the pope and the cardinals.
You see, Gaius at 465,
Harvey, you discovered
the circulation of the blood.
And you see Hegel,
who plays a great part in history
in a sort of negative way.
We were talking about him at lunch.
Hegel was the great leading philosopher
in the German philosophy
in the 1800s.
You see, we think this is all textbook stuff
for kids,
but our daily life in great detail
is completely determined
by the output of these minds.
It's all the output of these minds.
So it is of great significance.
Hegel had one of Hegel's
essential to his philosophy,
was his teaching
of the absolute.
Hegel said,
within creation there is that
which is the absolute,
irrefutable, irreducible,
the absolute,
by which everything else
is measurable.
Now that's the core of what we do
with consciousness research.
The infinite field of consciousness
itself is the absolute
by which we compare everything.
So when I ask her by her arm
how many llamas,
I'm saying numerically
as compared to the absolute.
The calibrated levels of consciousness
are relative to the absolute,
which is infinite.
Within our domain,
the highest level of consciousness
historically has been at 1000.
So we can compare it
with the highest it's ever been
or we can compare it with the absolute.
In calibrating levels of consciousness
we compare it with the absolute.
So Hegel's theory was correct.
If you calibrate it,
you'll see that he was correct.
However, Karl Marx was a young
revolutionary and Karl Marx
had an unresolved edible complex.
Apparently,
unresolved relationship with his father
because the father figure Hegel
instead of saying,
wow, what a brilliant mind,
he decided to refute Hegel.
And Marx came up with the theory.
You see all these people
are in the 400s or even up to the 500s.
And you see Marx
bizarrely is at 130.
You wonder how did he get in this?
Marx then defied the absolute
and defied Father Hegel
and hatched an adolescent theory
based on the perpetrator-victim model,
a dualistic model.
You see the absolute is a monism,
is a oneness.
The perpetrator-victim model
is a dualistic split.
Everything Marx looked at then
looked like perpetrator-victim.
If you look at employment,
employee, job,
perpetrator-victim.
If you look at people in bank,
If you look at businessmen,
capitalist, peasant.
So he split everything.
So he didn't see that when
a company moves to town
that it's mutually,
he doesn't see mutuality at all.
How can the company survive
and make money without the workers?
You can't.
It was Thiensville, Wisconsin.
The only thing that made a living there
was the cannery.
Without the cannery,
how would these people pay
for new harnesses for their horses,
get a new tractor?
On the other hand,
the cannery couldn't work
without the workers.
See, and I was a worker there.
We got an extra five cents
for everything over 12 hours.
And a red hot pea cannery,
I tell you.
We had another big track going over.
It was horrendous, you know,
working on these hot warehouses.
They had no windows, no fans.
It was 125, 130,
lifting these heavy boxes.
And so which is the perpetrator
and which is the victim, eh?
Now, if all the workers quit,
the business would collapse.
If the business moved out of town,
the town would go into abject poverty.
So what he didn't get is mutuality.
He didn't get mutuality.
That men and women serve each other.
He didn't get the unity
that the worker and the employer
serve each other.
The student and the teacher serve each other.
You know, he didn't get the oneness of it all.
Which costs 100 million people
their lives in this lifetime.
Because when that's projected
and politicized,
then it becomes a sort of revolutionary.
Then you see the history of Russia,
the history of France,
the history of communist China,
all those things.
When applied to the real world,
the current of the way Marx saw,
projected on the world,
is not the way the real world is at all.
When projected onto the economy of China,
30 million people starved to death in China
as a consequence of Marxism.
Marxist collectivism.
Nobody works on a collectivist farm, man.
You only work on a farm
if you pocket the money from the watermelons.
Otherwise, you're supposed to be just a good guy,
you know,
parading around for some slogan.
And, of course, your energy goes down
at the end of the day.
And 30 million people starved to death
as a consequence of Marxism.
So when people try to resell it
in new clothes in today's society,
I turn a deaf ears.
It's been tried already.
So that is Hegel and Hume,
all these Kant, of course,
the Kantian categories of logic and reason,
Locke.
So Marx at 130 then has had a profound.
So what is the point of this?
The point of this is that fallacy then,
fallacy is the source of war
and truth is the foundation of peace.
That a calibrated level of 130
can take down an entire empire.
You get enough people.
You know what memes are, M-E-M-E-S.
You get that to be a common saying
that everybody begins to adopt as though it's truth.
Oh, the working man, drop your chains.
You have nothing but freedom.
Working men, drop your chains.
Well, first of all, he wasn't in any chains.
He wasn't in any chains.
Unite.
You have nothing but your chains to lose.
Cost then 100 million people.
Not to mention what happened after,
Stalin did after World War II.
Stalin sent another 30 million
off to the gulags to die of various ways.
So we can't exactly close our eyes
to the hermeneutics
of distorted relativistic epistemology.
You heard it here.
The downside of the distortions of logic
by trying to twist the meaning.
It means what I want it to mean.
That denies the absolute.
Okay, in the Bill of Rights
and the Constitution of the United States,
we're guaranteed freedom of speech.
What is speech?
Speech comes out of here.
Does it come out of here?
Does it mean action?
All right, so if you say speech means expression,
everything is expression,
including bombing busloads of children.
Ku Klux Klan, that's expression.
Everything's expression, is it not?
So you see the downside
of distorting meaning, then.
The absolute meaning of a meaning
is the very strength of law.
When you begin to change the meaning of the word,
you've now lost the reliability
and the strength of law.
Law can no longer save you.
You know that law can no longer protect you.
You think it can?
By relativistic epistemology,
I can make anything sound like anything.
So, and the courts are no longer ruled
by law,
then anything can go.
Therefore, the loudest voice
will be the one that carries the vote.
Here we're talking about content.
We said the naive person thinks only of content,
ignores the context.
You can make this wrong
so long as you ignore the context.
This is the proximate field,
the proximate field.
That could be the economic conditions
at the time,
let's say the relationship of men and women,
in which men dominated,
it appeared to society,
to feminists that way,
not to men or to the women they were with
because they had equality.
America was agrarian.
When I was born,
50% of America was agrarian, rural.
In the rural world,
being a mesomorph,
having muscles and testosterone
is what you need.
The woman works like a dog inside
five kids and diapers and God knows what all.
Equal and, you know, equal.
The woman was revered, revered.
We stood up when mother entered.
We did not use vile language.
We did not use vulgar language.
In my home, you could not even say
pew or stink.
Mom, I'm sorry.
All right, so it was equality.
You can distort it and now project it
into today's society,
and you can see how you can do a make wrong
by projecting it backwards in time.
That's called a shift of context.
Is slavery wrong?
It is in today's world.
Was slavery wrong throughout the history of mankind?
No.
Everybody practiced slavery
because it was a part of the cultural evolution
of all societies 100%.
In the days of ancient Rome,
the slaves outnumbered
the free men by ten to one.
Ten to one.
And slaves were the architects.
They were the learned people of the day,
but legally they were slaves, yeah?
All right, so you go backward in time,
you'll find that slavery only got,
came to a legal end, I think, in 1961
as a result of JFK's pressure on that company,
country, 1961.
So it was, to say, is slavery wrong?
In this world, yes.
In the past world, it's the way it was for everyone.
Everyone.
In fact, slavery was an advancement.
In the early, more primitive barbaric days,
when you invaded a country like the Vikings,
you slaughtered everybody.
The Vikings got smart.
They found if you don't slaughter them,
you can sell them.
Instead of bloody death,
you now had a chance at least to live, you know?
All right, so it was discovered in Africa,
it was discovered in Scandinavia.
The Vikings, all of them had slaves,
and slavery was a way of life.
It was where society was at that point in its evolution.
So you can see how making it wrong
by projecting it backward in history.
Was it wrong at the time of the Vikings?
Of course not. Of course not.
The turn-of-the-century opium
was the content of many patent medicines.
It was discovered that a lot of,
especially farm ladies,
got very dependent on this patent medicine.
To feel good,
they just had to have a swig
a couple of times a day.
90% alcohol, the rest tincture of opium,
or the rest opium, rather.
They were slightly stoned.
They were feeling good,
and boy, this medicine works.
Of course it worked.
You felt rotten,
you had some of this Pinkham's egg elixir,
and you felt good.
So what's wrong with that?
How come Harry Anslinger took a negative view of that?
Because it was found out
that it was addicting.
We didn't know it was addicting
for a generation or two.
Now, retrospectively,
you say, well, they were wrong.
But that's retrospective.
At the time, people didn't understand
that that was addictive.
Laudanum, people didn't understand
that cocaine was addictive.
Sigmund Freud got addicted to it.
People didn't know those were addictive.
So you see,
falsification by projection
elsewhere in history
is today's fallacy.
This is true
only within this context here.
To sell medicine
that contains opium
in today's world
would certainly be non-integrous.
In the world of the 1890s,
it was honesty.
When he said, drink this, you'll feel better,
that's the truth. You did.
Smoke this little thing
and you'll feel better. Whatever.
All right.
So that's the context.
Now, you cannot tell truth
without the context.
And what makes any of it work
is the ultimate non-linear infinite context,
and that is the energy field
of consciousness itself.
Within the infinite energy field,
the absolute,
is the relative local conditions
whose meaning and significance
you cannot understand
unless you state the context.
Consequently, man is never known.
We saw the greatest thinkers
of all time.
They arrived at what is truth.
The greatest minds that have ever lived
could not define truth.
And the simple thing that was missing
is this here. Truth is only true
within a specified context.
And even that is not true
unless compared
with the absolute.
Therefore, calibrating levels of consciousness,
as far as I can discern
from a study of everything
like forever,
is the first thing
that has included
the necessary ingredients
to arrive at a science of truth.
A science of truth.
I don't know what time we break for lunch,
or afternoon, what?
Three o'clock, okay.
Okay, so you may think this is irrelevant,
but having heard it, you'll realize
because it'll come to you
all of a sudden with annoyingness,
oh, I get what that means.
I get what that means.
This is something we did when we were in Europe.
We spoke at some place or other.
And this is the Louvre.
The Louvre calibrates,
I forget what, 500 or 700,
500, oh yeah.
All right, the Louvre calibrates,
you know, the Louvre,
it took centuries to build it.
The monarchs, that was the castle,
that was the palace
for the monarchs,
for several monarchs.
It's a stunning experience.
One of the things that sort of knocks you out
is you can wander in and around
and look at the most famous valuable paintings
in the whole world and take photographs of them,
right?
Imagine that.
Taking photographs of all these things,
no charge,
just take as many pictures as you want.
The Mona Lisa does have a glass panel in front of her,
but other than that,
the rest of them seem to be relatively exposed.
They do have a guard in each room.
Having remembered what happened to the Pieta,
I always thought it's rather
either foolhardy or courageous of them
to allow this.
You remember what happened to the Pieta
when a psychotic person attacked it,
because the core of the ego hates God,
is always atheistic,
and all of the relativistic philosophies
which are currently causing
so much contention in America
are all atheistic.
All. 100%.
All right.
Here's the usefulness and practicality
in today's world.
So the book I'm just finishing has to do
with what is truth, defining it,
and how does it affect
the minds that appear throughout history
and throughout society,
throughout the greatest minds that have ever lived.
We calibrated all the most famous names in history.
Charlemagne, whatever.
How does it reflect itself in writers,
in movies, in TV,
in all the expressions of our current society?
So here's a relativistic scale
of great usefulness in many dimensions.
This is just the scale
for practicality up to 600.
This side is called us.
This side is called them.
This can be our company.
This can be our target market.
This can be our club, garden club.
This can be their community.
You can line it however you want.
Okay, we'll go to the next one.