finishing Transcending the Levels of Consciousness. Each of these levels,
people say, well why don't people just move ahead? And it has to do with
ingrained attitudes which arise out of your animal nature, and these come in
pairs. Generally they come in pairs, not in opposites, but in pairs. Each level has
its attraction and its aversion. So in this book I'm finishing, I take each
level of consciousness, describe it, give correlations, etc., and then at the end a
list, and this is one of the lists for instance, that the dualities of attraction
and aversion. So each level has its payoff. If it didn't have a payoff you
wouldn't stay there, and it has its aversions. There's that which you're
attracted and therefore there's that which you fear or regret or don't want to
let go of. The primary
the primary thing that holds people's evolution of consciousness, and frankly
to evolve you only need to know one thing, the one thing, you don't need anything else,
is the juice and the satisfaction you get out of it. Nothing else. It's not the
thing itself, because this capacity to juice something and get, juice it for
gain, animal pleasure, that's what the amoeba does.
You can attach this juicing to anything. So it's nothing out there because there
isn't anything out there. The value of everything that you see out there and
therefore desire is a projection. You glamorize it, make it attractive because
you project that attractiveness. I mean I wouldn't even want it in my house, and you're
willing to kill somebody for it, you know what I mean, or vice versa. You're willing to kill for it,
and I wouldn't have the damn thing around. So obviously value is
something you project out there. Alice Bailey described that in the book called
Glamour, very excellent understanding there from the White Brotherhood.
Specialness is something you project out there, doesn't exist within the thing
itself. Now you're willing to die for it, surrender to it, the glamour of
Adolf Hitler, the fatherland, see Kyle, I mean it's all projected value. The guy
calibrated about, I don't know, 90 or 120 or something, and you think he's the great
fuhrer.
You don't even come up to 200, right. Okay, so this, the attraction is to the
satisfaction. Now this satisfaction the ego feels guilty about, it's a
narcissistic ego satisfaction, so it tries to disguise it. But if you do an
inner honesty, spiritual inventory of yourself, you'll see that any negativity
you're getting is because, any negativity that's bothering you, is
because there is a payoff to it. Therefore what you're attached to is
irrelevant, because you're only addicted to one thing. You're only addicted to one
thing, and what you do is you move that thing around to values, people, positions,
titles, money, wealth, you get a payoff out of it. That's the only reason you hang on to it.
Self-pity, you say nobody want to feel self-pity, oh yeah? You tried doing therapy
with somebody who's stuck in martyrdom, being wronged,
they're right, self-pity, made uncomfortable. Should the whole world
change itself because you feel uncomfortable the way it is? I mean the
egomania of it, you know, the narcissism of it, this is really great, you know. It
makes me uncomfortable. Well that's your problem, isn't it? It's your problem if the
name God over the courthouse gives you a sleepless night, I mean, you know what I
mean? So what? So the narcissistic person seeks to change the world instead of
themselves.
You don't have to change others, you just have to change yourself, and then you experience
others differently.
Alright, so that's responsibility. So the only thing you need to know then, let's
say you're angry and now you feel guilty about anger, and then you started looking
at the anger. The anger is not really the problem, the problem is pride. Oh, why are
you angry? Because your pride has been hurt. And what is it that you fear? You fear shame.
Okay, so you see how
you just can undo it, if you see what is the source of satisfaction? What kind of a
payoff is the ego getting for hanging on? Being the martyr, of course being right. Being
right is being, the competition in today's world is between being right and being martyr.
And you can be a martyr and be right and that makes it a double win. And you do that by
objecting blame, and you're, you know, the Marxist dualism, the Marxist duality, the
duality of being right and being right has its own bond, it has its own bond, and that's
of perpetrator-victim, which is projected onto any situation in the world.
Everywhere is a perpetrator-victim, everywhere.
If you choose to project that out there, yeah.
Now you can assume, being the martyr, oh, poor me, oh, poor me.
Okay, so you can jump the ego's grip on you.
So what's happened is you're addicted to that position.
You're addicted to it.
That position is not you.
You think it's you.
It's not you.
You experience it.
What's addicted to it is the experiencer.
We've spoken of the experiencer in previous lectures, and we'll come back to it later.
It isn't just the ego itself and its whole structure.
The ego presents itself, like the amoeba, through its, like you might call an edge, that's the processor.
The processor is the quality that's incredibly complex in one ten-thousandth of a second.
It evaluates everything from multiple viewpoints, simultaneously, and distills out the experience.
That's called the experiencer.
It's the edge of the ego.
It's like the probe that came out of evolution, that the amoeba has to quickly decide what is edible, not edible, what's good for you, what's poisonous, enemy, quickly.
It has to quickly process.
So it's a processor.
Very complicated.
It's a complex processor.
In one ten-thousandth of a second, it processes enormous, enormous banks of information.
No combination of computers could possibly do it.
It's just far too complex.
Because it includes value, meaning, significance, prioritization.
A computer can't do that.
It doesn't value things higher than one another.
It's got bits of information, and it doesn't reflect projected value.
The computer doesn't, you know, think more highly of this bit of information than it does of this information, but your ego does.
So, to discontinue from the experiencer is the inner way that requires intense discipline, and we cover that pretty much in the book Devotional Non-Duality.
It's a way of being in the world.
It's a way in which one seeks to disidentify with that aspect of the ego, which is not only in a dualistic positionality, but is the leading edge of the experiencer.
So, ultimately, what you're addicted to is experiencing.
Humans are hooked on experiencing.
That's why you keep changing the channel, and then you turn on the music, then you go eat a bite of this and that.
Addicted to experiencing.
Why? Because out of evolution, it was through experiencing that one survived, huh?
The difficulty, then, the feedback, that which you're getting from this experiencer edge of the ego, is the readout of a tape monitor.
The reality, then, is the program out there.
It gets recorded on the tape, and now you're plugged into the tape monitor.
Experientially, what you're getting is the tape monitor.
You are not getting res externa, nature, reality, the world as it is.
You're getting the readout.
You're not even addicted to the world.
You think you are.
You say, oh, I'm so hooked on the world.
No, you're not hooked on the world.
You're hooked on this readout.
You're hooked on the readout that you're getting.
And this experiencer is reading out to you because it's processing based on poor prioritization.
So what you value, then, gets projected out there.
The experiencer aspect of the ego thinks this is important, and it gets attached to it, okay?
And now you get attached to the juice you get out of that perception.
All right.
That's the way the ego keeps itself alive.
You see, the ego has no source of spiritual energy.
It only has animal energy.
Consequently, out of every experience, it has to extract the source.
It's the source of animal existence.
It doesn't have a source of energy within itself.
So therefore, the ego survives by virtue of taking glee at the suffering of others, being right, winning, gaining.
Yeah.
And he deserved it.
Take that, you bastard.
Boom.
Boy, that makes you feel good.
It's done a lot of times, or a lot of lifetimes.
Boy, did he ever get it.
And he deserved it.
He didn't believe in Jesus.
You know what I'm saying?
I told you, that lifetime.
Man, did we do with each other.
He did it for Allah, and I did it for Jesus, and we killed each other, snicker-snack.
Man, he was good, too.
And every lifetime that I've had a challenge like that, we come up for each other.
And got you again, you bastard.
And he gets me at the same time, right through the chest.
Man, we both go out of body, breaking and laughing.
Jesus, did we do this one again?
I thought we did this one.
I can even get you the date of it and the place of it.
It was the Crusades.
Okay.
Okay, we have, what, quarter after?
Yeah.
So, you have an aversion and attraction.
This is based on how you perceive it.
And your perception, then, is the consequence of spiritual energy.
So, aligning yourself with divinity, by whatever means, religion, spirituality,
or just commitment to truth and integrity in a secular way,
therefore, does bring in kundalini energy, which now transforms the appearance,
significance, and meaning of everything.
This kundalini energy, as it begins to flow, becomes quite strong.
It starts at 540.
At 540, which is unconditional love.
So, unconditional love is a practical goal in this world.
And that's what Jesus Christ and other religions really teach,
is try to reach unconditional love is practical goal in this world.
You can learn how to, you can learn that.
If you follow religious teachings, you will reach unconditional love.
That's the level of 12-step groups, by the way, is 540, unconditional love.
540 is reached by 0.4% of the human population, 0.4.
Every reach is 540.
Therefore, expecting the other nations are going to love you if you're nice to them,
the chances are zero.
Why?
Because they would have to be over 500 to even appreciate integrity.
All right. So, anyway, 540 then releases kundalini energy.
The kundalini energy transforms brain physiology, changes how you see and experience life,
changes your value and your goals.
Subjectively, it's experienced as an exquisite sensation.
Even if you've never heard about it, I've never heard about it.
All of a sudden, it's exquisite sweetness flowing up your spine.
Woo.
And it flows into your brain.
Your brain is like having a slow, forever orgasm.
I mean, it's just incredible.
It's better than an orgasm because it's got a quality that is incredible.
It has a quality, not a sensation, it's like.
And then, eventually, this energy begins to perform the miraculous,
the so-called siddhis, s-i-d-d-h-i-s, becomes spontaneous.
You're clairaudient. You're clairvoyant.
You can see auras.
Distance viewing, healings, people come to you and you just hold them in mind.
You see the miraculous appear before you.
There's no person doing that.
This is all phenomena that are consequent to the field.
And a good teacher warns you in advance when you finally reach this level
because it's inevitable, a group like this, everybody's going to reach it.
When these phenomena begin to appear, you have to be aware they are not yours.
Don't claim them as my powers.
That's how you get hooked.
My powers, much less peddle them and sell them.
I'll give you a class on how to, you know, levitate or something.
Ah, get away.
Those things happen spontaneously as a consequence of the power of the kundalini energy.
The world calls them miraculous and goes, ooh-la, ooh-la, ooh-la.
So, you're careful not to parade them around and you try to conceal them
because the world will really tag you around, you know.
The miraculous happens of its own.
There's no performer of miracles.
There are famous gurus out there, don't calibrate all that high,
you know, as miracle workers, you know, they are the miracle, of course, are the miracle.
You are not the source of the miracle.
You're just a dumbbell that hasn't got enough power probably to lift the suitcase.
The power of the miraculous is infinite.
And you witness, we witness, what we witness is the person,
you can see why they're having lunch with you,
then you get the unspoken question, then you see what the problem is,
then somebody says, well, she has this or that, and you say, oh, yes.
And then within yourself you feel the energy.
Now, it's that person's karmic propensity which will decide the consequence.
The field is there and if the karmic propensity is there, the healing occurs.
If it's not, if a person is really spiritually evolved,
like the Course in Miracles, whether a healing occurs or not is irrelevant.
Once you reach that, whether a healing occurs is irrelevant,
whether you live or die is irrelevant, you have completed the Course in Miracles.
Yeah, to precipitate it, you get a person to the point that they lose their fear of death.
You lose their fear of death, you know, and I used to do it with patients.
I said, and then what, and then what, and then this will happen.
So I used to turn to that.
And then what, and then this.
And if you go through all your fears, you will always end up with the same fear at the bottom,
and that is the fear of death, and then I will die.
Then you say to them, so?
Bang, and sometimes you'll see a patient gets it right then.
Yeah, you're right, that's all.
Dying is inevitable anyway.
Being a person is 100% fatal.
Mortality rate for humanness is 100%.
So if it happens now or later, what's the difference?
When you accept the inevitability of the inevitable, it's amazing how your fears disappear.
And you say, all right, so if I lose the job, screw it.
See?
He came in terrified, he's going to lose the job and face the basis of all fears is fear of death.
And if you say, and then what, and then what?
Then I'll be lonely, then they won't hire me, then I'll run out of money, then I'll be homeless,
then I'll starve to death, so then what?
So then I'll die, so?
I remember the first time I said that to a patient, she said, and then what if it doesn't work?
I said, well, then you die.
And she said, oh, because if you're coming from that, the higher space, and you say that, they'll get it.
If you're not coming from a higher space, they would take that as an affront, you know, and frighten them.
So don't tell that to people.
All right, we got exactly where we're at.
All right, so we're doing it different today because Betty and Nico,
have to leave, they have another spiritual event, and so we'll have Nico chant until lunchtime.
And then we'll reconvene this afternoon at what time?
Two o'clock.
Oh, we reconvene then at two o'clock, yes.
All right.
I have two words to say about death.
It's safe.
Relax.
Best use of this time and our time together.
So this year we're finishing up what I would call the didactic first couple of years.
We pretty much covered everything in power versus force, eye of the eye,
our reality and subjectivity, truth versus falsehood,
and then we will complete the transcending laws of consciousness,
and end up on devotional non-duality,
at which point we will all just sit looking happy.
Then next year I thought we will devote more, more, hardly any time,
to lectures or didactic material,
and we'll make it more traditional discussion, question and answer.
You know what I mean? Free discussion.
We've become really a very unique spiritual group,
and as such we'll move more and more into group operation,
where instead of didactic lectures,
we have free open discussions and clarification,
and questions and discussion and answers,
and so forth with the group, yeah?
That's got some name in Sanskrit, I forget what it is.
Satsang?
Huh?
Satsang.
Well anyway, you have to speak Sanskrit to come to the group.
So next year we'll move more into questions and answers and free discussion,
because the group is now aware of all the basic material.
I think the basic material,
we've confirmed this before,
the chances of becoming enlightened are now one thousand times greater than in the past.
One thousand times greater.
By virtue of the information and the evolution of consciousness,
so as in the olden days it was an extreme rarity,
we expect to see it recur more and more often,
and to facilitate that transcending laws of consciousness,
I address, you know,
the levels around 850 and up,
which are very difficult to articulate,
and people say,
why is he talking about that?
Because a group like this,
some of you are going to get there.
And when you hit the void,
it's pretty stunning, you know?
And therefore,
we discuss the downside of the pathway of negation, etc.,
which are really only necessary for very advanced students,
but you're already pretty advanced students,
and we get that now is the time to be more informal
and less didactic and more interactive.
The same material will come up,
but of course in a different context,
and very often a lot of people get more out of that spontaneous emergence
of a subject rather than some kind of a linear presentation.
So what we've done is,
in a very linear way,
we've done it in a non-linear way.
Yeah, that's because you're starting out from ordinary minds, see?
And so you contextualize an ordinary mind
before you move on past ordinary minds.
So I want to start out where the modern mind is.
The modern mind is not into where it was a thousand years ago, you see?
The modern mind has to be addressed.
So,
nothing advanced spiritual mentioned is really addressed to the current mind,
and therefore part of the purpose was to correlate modern mind
with advanced spiritual teaching.
So how to jump that paradigm from the 400s into the 500s,
and then from the 500s on up,
which become progressively non-linear,
and at 600 is quite non-linear.
And at that, when you hit 600, you can leave if you want.
Most do, you know, yeah, over 50%.
When they get to that level, there's no need for the body,
and it just falls over, which is not too interesting.
However, depending on carrying propensities and obligations
that you forgot now because you're back in the body,
but when you leave it, you remember.
So then the world may come along and insist that you eat and poke you,
force you to have a sandwich whether you like it or not, and stuff like that.
You haven't eaten since Tuesday.
This is Friday, don't you think you ought to?
So, all right, we're explaining all those phenomena,
explaining those phenomena,
and how each one of them, as advanced as they can be,
can also be transcended because, sooner or later,
a group like this is dedicated to enlightenment,
will reach the highest states.
Therefore, the time to hear about the highest states is now.
It's going to be too late.
Otherwise, all by yourself in the middle of nowhere,
and no telephone.
So, but the knowingness is encased forever
as a frequency and energy field within the aura.
Amen.
Gloria in excelsis Deo.
Down through the ages forever.
The vibration and that frequency in the aura
that you pick up from the highest truth,
we calibrated the other day,
will persist for at least 25 lifetimes or a thousand years.
So you don't have to worry for a thousand years.
You already know what you need to know.
And at the propitious moment out of silence and nothingness
comes the knowingness.
Because there's no thinkingness, there's no memory.
Everything you've learned is useless because the mind stopped.
And now up comes a confrontation.
And at that point, a knowingness emerges of its own.
Walk straight ahead.
All fear is illusion.
It isn't just the thought.
It's the power of the thought.
The power of the thought comes from somebody who's done it.
That's what gives it the power.
Therefore, the reliance is on the strength
of that truth.
And it better be convincing.
It better be convincing.
So that's the obligation of the teacher.
Now that we're done with him, we'll get on with it.
We were talking about the 500s.
The confusion of love and passionate attachment,
which is in the book.
And passionate attraction, you know,
with all what Hollywood and the world makes of it,
you would think it was really something.
It calibrates at 145.
It's sort of a panting tomcat in a way.
I hate to say it, but it's a desire to make becomes very intense.
Well, you see the biologic evolution of the mammalian species.
If it wasn't for that, we wouldn't be here.
So we're not putting it down.
The only reason we're mentioning it is because there is an error in spiritual teaching.
Also prevalent.
There's one out of Sedona, too,
which which says that love is an attachment.
Watch that one.
That's the one that blew that one girl.
Love is not an attachment.
See, passion.
This this year is an attachment and you're attached to desiring this
glamorization of the desired object out there.
But love is a quality of divinity.
Oh, negate the negate love.
You'll end up in the void.
Yeah.
So the attachment, the possessiveness, the craving.
This is not love.
That's animal nature.
Every you know, you can watch your own pets.
They got it on thing, you know.
So that's what you have to let go of is the attachment to that desiring this.
That specialness, the specialness.
That object becomes very special.
You can't live without it and you must have it, seize it, desire it, possess it.
Now you're jealous of how somebody might flirt with it.
In fact, you'll kill them.
Everybody has done that.
I'm sure you've all killed the former lovers.
If you didn't, what was the matter with you?
I mean,
they deserve to die, don't they?
Poach on my territory.
Cost you.
All right.
So here we made a way to differentiate.
So this is what you're supposed to surrender.
This cravingness, this transitory excess sex hormone.
It's all very love sprained and very physical.
And you can tell it because it gets frantic.
It's like an addiction and a craving.
If you don't get it, you're going to commit suicide or homicide.
You're going to stalk them or something you have to possess.
And
your life, the impact of this energy field that the world calls love is your life is disrupted.
Can't sleep or eat, sort of a temporary madness.
And if you're frustrated, you end up with depression, rage, hatred, blame.
And of course, classically murder and suicide.
Love, which is a quality of 500 and up, is something else.
It's not possessive.
It's not controlling.
It's a spiritual state.
It makes you uplifted.
You feel bonded.
The way you feel about that person is permanent.
It releases endorphins instead of adrenaline.
It brings calm and balance.
Your life is enhanced.
It's more self-fulfilling.
You feel improved as a great well-being as a human being.
You want to be with, you feel grateful to that person and your life is enhanced.
And it comes about really through the right side of the brain.
It's higher mind.
And that's the consequence of the Kundalini energy which pours out at 200.
So that is not to be negated.
If you negate that, you will end up at nothingness.
You know, the pathway of negation, you will end up in the void.
Well, I'm not putting down the void.
It's very, very impressive.
Most impressive thing beyond imagination.
But it's not it.
It seems like it.
It's non-linear.
It's forever non-dimensional.
Has no beginning, no end.
There's nobody there, nothing there.
And it's intensely impressive and wondrous.
Had it not been for having experienced the presence as a teenager,
which was that of an infinite love that was just melting by the sheer force of its infinite power,
there would have been the presumption again that this is it.
Well, if this is it, I wouldn't have gotten hit with it when I was age three.
Nothingness versus, allness versus nothingness.
No, out of that lifetime, you ended up there.
It's not a reality.
So at age three, I get hit with it again.
And the confrontation was, at age three, out of nothing, suddenly there was the awareness of existence.
Existence, not as me, just existence, period.
And I was not happy with it.
I was not at all happy to come out of the void, nothingness into existence.
Instantly, the corollary came up.
If you exist, therefore, it could have happened that you would not have existed.
Aha. Instantly came up the fear of nonexistence.
Aha.
Is the reality existence versus nonexistence?
Is it allness or nothingness?
At age three, I didn't think about it, but I just totally got what the presentation was.
And it took 38 years to resolve it.
Anyway, that's where negation will take you to.
If negation, the void, was real, you couldn't emerge from it, nor would there be anyone to report it.
Got it?
What would be reporting the reality of a void?
Because that which you consider you is also void.
If there's nothingness, then there's nothing to say there's nothingness.
So you see the inner paradox itself.
I understand that.
At age three, I wouldn't know what you're talking about, you know.
I only spoke Sanskrit in those days.
And ancient Greek.
Ancient Greek, yeah.
Okay, we'll go to the next.
So that's the thing to know.
You have now heard it.
Everybody here has got it in their aura.
Everybody here has it in their aura forever.
Amen. Resist.
Nobody here is going to get hung up on the void.
All right.
Oh, we share our experience, strength, and experience, right?
All right, so now we were talking about dualities.
I think the last time we started at the bottom of the scale, didn't we?
We started at, what's at the bottom of the scale of consciousness, isn't it?
Shame? Yeah.
Oh, then we, oh, we're moving ahead out of shame today.
I thought we would hit all these sets of dualities.
I have them at the end of the first chapters in Transcending Levels.
What's holding each one is an attraction and aversion.
There's only one real attraction,
and that is to the payoff of your current position.
And you have to disassemble that current position
and see what it is you're getting out of it.
What are you getting out of being the loser?
Well, you're getting to be the loser.
All right.
What are you getting out of being the victim?
You're getting to be the victim.
The victim has got the biggest payoff in today's society,
other than being right. Being right beats them all.
At the very bottom, actually, we had apathy, I think.
Didn't we have apathy? Or no, and apathy is coming next.
All right, we'll just go with guilt and hate, then.
Without going to apathy, I won't care about guilt and hate.
I've got to arouse myself to get up to guilt and hate.
The attraction, of course, is judgmentalism towards yourself and others.
Judge not, says the Lord. Judge not.
All right, and when we recontextualize divinity
as though it was in a giant electromagnetic field,
and you're a little magnetic filing,
that sort of changes the way in which you experience guilt, see?
You see that the way you've been programmed led you to that,
and therefore, out of what is really an intrinsic innocence,
you chose that because you thought you were choosing the good at the time.
Because the mind is like a computer.
The basic hardware will play any program,
and you realize the mind cannot defend itself against falsehood.
Everybody here, we're all sitting ducks.
It'll play any software that gets programmed.
How long does it take you to get programmed?
You just had it. You just got programmed.
I have to do a slosh. M&M.
You got it.
Fine. Burned into your head is M&M.
The rest of your lifetime.
Forty years from now, you're in the North Pole.
You dig through the snow, and here's a dead Eskimo,
and in his pocket, he's got M&M.
Forty years later, you know what an M&M is.
That's how long it took to program you.
You just got programmed.
So, how can you defend yourself against that?
You can't.
You cannot defend yourself against it.
Consequently,
you're the victim of what your innocence has been programmed by.
Everyone is the victim by which their innocence has been programmed.
That's why fascism, totalitarianism, theocratic, whatever,
seeks the children.
First thing they do is try to program the children.
Get them into the youth movement, you know.
Replace the authority of the parent.
Replace the teaching and the values of the state,
which is what you see in today's society,
which is becoming progressively totalitarian in the name of freedom.
The parent no longer has jurisdiction over their child.
The school does.
By virtue of a program that's been politically put into the school system.
It's not up to you to decide about sexual teachings.
The state has taken over.
You want your five-year-old to know you're all about pedastry and oral sex
and various perversions.
How about S&M, you know what I mean?
You know what I mean?
Well, freedom of speech, you know.
Children should know about S&M, you know what I mean?
At age five or six.
Even now, the ads, you know, you can hear a six-year-old say,
Daddy, why should you call a doctor after three hours?
What is it, four hours or something?
Four hours.
Daddy, why should Daddy call a doctor after four hours?
She's just a toddler.
She's a toddler, for God's sake.
And you're supposed to explain it to her.
I don't want to.
Let somebody else do it.
Well, it's never too soon for them to know.
Which is really pretty dumb.
All right.
Guilt then, you want to punish yourself or others because you've been programmed.
And the other thing about guilt is you're refusing God's mercy.
You're justifying negativity.
You're rejecting your feelings.
It's a rigid, narrow view.
It calls for penance, which is a self-indulgence.
Do you ever think of that?
Do you realize all these demonstrations of penance?
It's not even an egoistic self-indulgence.
Oh, look how guilty I am and how sinful I am.
Oh, give me a break, will you?
What is it, the sin of the century or something?
You forgot your mother-in-law's birthday.
You didn't send her a birthday card.
I mean, how could I have done such a thing?
So, you see, the ego clings to this position.
This position of guilt reinforces it and enjoys its meanness
because now you project it and you have hate.
Hate is then projected onto the world.
So guilt and hate go extremely well together.
Instead of hating yourself, you project it into the world and you hate them.
Therefore, you've got to have a them.
So you've got to have somebody out there that you can blame it on.
So this is the victim.
The perpetrator-victim model, which is a dualistic positionality,
coming out of the distorted hermeneutics of relativistic epistemology.
Distorted hermeneutics of relativistic epistemology.
Okay, there you've got the cue to what ails society today. Very simple.
Distorted understanding of what is true.
Due to distorting meaning by denying that there is an absolute by which meaning can be discerned.
Therefore, all meaning is relativistic and, like Lewis Carroll,
a word means just what I want it to mean and neither more nor less.
Which is about age, what, five?
That's what they teach in the university now, see?
Age five, kindergarten mentation.
A word means just what I want it to mean.
Nothing more or less.
Good, Joey.
You are now going to be a professor.
That's an academic requirement now.
Alright, so that's the attraction.
At the same time there's an aversion.
Surrendering judgment to God.
Why? Because you don't have the capacity to judge.
Aversion is to forgiving yourself and others.
You know, look at all the opportunities people have
to just forgive the other side and forget it.
But they cling to it.
Accept mercy and compassion.
Surrender the secret pleasure you're getting.
There's an aversion to taking responsibility.
And, of course, the reason this comes about is you don't choose essence.
You're going along with linear appearance.
You're refusing to be flexible and see both sides.
And this is not of any service to others.
And you're reluctant to ask God for a miracle and recontextualize it.
Yeah?
It's really, when you ask for a miracle,
you're asking divinity in the form of consciousness
present as the Holy Spirit to recontextualize it,
take you out of the fixation, the perceptual fixation you have.
This is the easy way. This seems like it could be hard.
Hard to change.
Actually, with flexibility,
you'll find that it's easier to do in Rome as the Romans do.
You'll find it's really a lot easier.
It's really hard to maintain a different culture in a different context.
But some people persist anyway.
Cling to the old out of fear of the unknown.
It seems easy, and it's hard or difficult.
So people would rather ignore the negativity
rather than get upset, look at it, or face it.
So this is the attraction, is the comfort of the familiar.
And the aversion is to looking at it, becoming different,
and, of course, to take responsibility and be accountable.
To take responsibility.
That's why I like Bill Cosby.
He's saying, you're not going to get out of where you are
unless you take responsibility.
And, of course, he's getting hit for that.
I don't know for what reason, but it seems to be a sensible teaching, right?
To take responsibility for your action.
That way, you're not just passively,
along yourself, to get run over by society.
When you stop...
So all these things here are only difficult because they're resisted.
When you let go resisting it and look forward to it,
now it doesn't take effort.
It doesn't take effort.
The willingness to see people as innocent,
no matter what they do, becomes easy.
It doesn't upset you to look at or face a failing.
For one thing, as we said, the human mind is programmed
and it is easily misled.
So instead of seeing other people as wrong,
it's more comfortable, you'll find within yourself,
to see them as misled.
They believe this because they were misled.
That's all.
For chronic reasons.
For reasons of the evolution of their consciousness.
Other people are misled.
They're misled by the ambiance of cultures
which are very, very strong and long-standing.
And you would have to be already pretty evolved
to resist being programmed in that culture
in which it reappears all the time.
It's easier, the anticipated pleasure is to just ignore a thing,
rather than get upset and look at it.
The upset is due to resistance.
It's easier to refuse to own it and blame it
than it is to take that responsibility
and be accountable.
And here's the biggest excuse of all,
called, I can't.
I can't really change my ways.
I've been this way all my life.
I was brought up that way.
Excuse after excuse.
Now, if I say to somebody,
could you let go wanting to be that way?
I can't.
And then I hold a loaded gun up to his head.
He says, if you can, I'm going to blow your brains out.
Well, I guess I won't.
Your problem is you won't.
You can.
Facing a loaded gun, you'd be amazed
how fast you're going to make that shift.
The fact that you can make it
when you're facing a loaded gun
means that you are able to.
You're able to.
So it isn't that you can't,
it's that you won't.
Okay.
That changes the whole problem.
It's not to an I can't.
Then I look at why I don't want to.
That brings me up to the fulfillment
of the juice I'm getting out of it
and whether I'm willing to let go of that juice.
Am I willing to let go of the juice of being right?
So you can't get away with the excuse
of I can't.
Because you can say to yourself,
well, I won't fall into I can't.
Everyone says, well, I can't let go of I won't.
I can't let go of I can't.
I mean, you won't let go of I can't.
I can't let go of I want, I can't, I won't.
Oh, yeah.
At the bottom of all these things
is the willingness to surrender it to God
and surrender it to the Holy Spirit,
you know, as a miracle, huh?
So humility then removes a lot of the blocks.
There is a reluctance,
a rigidity due to the reluctance to learn,
to learn and progress.
We would like to hang on to this homeostasis,
seeming stability,
rather than to shift and feel temporarily off balance.
We like comfort.
When you enter the new arena,
you feel unfamiliar.
Therefore, people will stick in very destructive pathways
because just to change it a little,
requires some effort.
This one uses the past as an excuse.
The past justifies being stuck here.
If you grew up the way I did,
if your mother treated you the way you were,
if the Democrats did that to you,
if the Republicans did that to you, etc.
So you see the past is justification to stay stuck.
And what you need to see
is that the present is the change agent,
the change agent is the present.
In one second, you can move from heaven to hell.
Or you can move from hell to heaven.
It happened from the depths of hell.
Agonizing, eternal hell.
Far worse than any hell I've ever heard described.
Hell is far, far, far worse than any description
of the most greatest imagination.
Dreadful beyond all words.
Hmm.
Plus it goes on forever.
Forever. You're in hell forever.
Forever with no possibility of redemption.
Hmm. Eternal.
And then, in one second,
suddenly, the infinite glory of God shines forth
from hell to heaven in a tenth of a second.
Oh, God.
Zen, what is it? Zen teaching.
This means heaven and hell is exactly one inch.
Heaven and hell are very close together.
Why? Because for some people's ego,
it takes the extremes of hell before it will let go.
There's no point of blaming the degree of suffering
that occurs in your life.
Because if that's what it takes to let go,
then that's what it takes.
And the Self, with a capital S, couldn't care less.
Will throw you right over a cliff
if that's what it takes to wake you up.
You don't wake up and you fall through,
but you wake up fast when you hit the bottom.
It's quite a jolt.
So, all right.
So, blaming things on the past is an excuse
because the present is forever a change agent
and the constant asking God for intervention.
In the pits of hell, there was not even mentation.
Like, at the highest level,
it's nonlinear and timeless.
Nonverbal.
Nor is there any, not a single,
nor is there any, not a self there.
In hell, there was a soul.
There was a soul.
Yeah.
But every instant is also what seems like
the worst of the agony
is the open door to transcending it.
So you're never trapped.
You're never actually trapped.
The potentiality is there every second.
Out of that silent agony,
a voice arose from somewhere
within the consciousness field
and it said,
if there is a God, I ask him for help.
And then...
So, it only took 35 years
to recover from the experience
of what happened after that tenth of a second.
Because the mind was struck silent and dumb
and replaced by a presence.
And it's the presence that speaks.
It uses intellect and the mind
as a tool of expression.
But it's the presence that speaks,
utilizing that which is available
to express itself.
So the past, no matter how bad it is,
is no excuse.
Because even from the very pits of hell,
and I've never heard of anybody
who's been lower than that,
even from the very extreme pits of hell,
salvation is an instant away.
Instant away. Yeah.
All right.
So we can't...
We can let go of the past as an excuse
because it's not a permanent thing.
And the whole idea of past, future and present
are all illusions.
There is no past, so...
The other thing is you can say
you don't have the willpower.
And we just said before,
it isn't a matter of willpower, it's willingness.
Now, willpower as conceived of
in ordinary consciousness
is force.
Force yourself to do this.
It's grit your teeth.
It's a white knuckler.
And willpower is about as strong
as your level of consciousness at the time.
Anybody who's tried willpower to overcome anything,
like even chewing gum,
will realize how weak it is.
It's the last stick I'm going to chew, right?
Because willpower is only as strong as
your level of consciousness at that time.
Wherever your calibrated level of consciousness is,
that's the strength of your willpower.
That's the strength of your personal will.
On the other hand, to surrender to God
and to invoke divine will,
we realized that we were powerless
and surrendered to God.
Now you invoke divine will
and divine will calibrates at 850.
Divine will at 850
is capable of the miraculous.
Because at 850, what seems to you impossible
is nothing at all.
At 850, it's a foof.
At 855, it's going to be a life-long struggle.
Even at 220, it's a life-long struggle.
What you by yourself cannot accomplish,
and frankly I'll tell you, you can't,
because you haven't got what it takes.
By surrender to God, then,
you summon forth,
you create the opening for divine will,
which at 850 will overcome anything in this domain,
up to 850.
No will power.
I know you got no will power.
If you had will power,
you wouldn't be calling upon will power.
You would have solved it already.
Isn't that true?
You wouldn't pull up will power.
It would have dissolved already.
So the personal will doesn't have it.
It comes from force.
It's below 200 usually.
And therefore, divine will at 850.
The other thing about will power
is that it's an illusion
because there is not the willingness.
The denial, therefore.
If you need will power to do something,
you realize that you lack the willingness
because if you had had the willingness,
you would have already transcended it
and you wouldn't be requiring will power.
You understand what I'm saying?
Paradoxical.
The person says, well, I've been trying to.
I'm going to.
Which is the denial of doing it.
The denial of doing it.
If you really meant that,
it would be done already, would it not?
I'm going to try.
Remember, S taught that.
Remember, S would never let you get away with a try.
Try was a no-no word in S.
Either do it or shut up.
See, you know?
Because this is a lie.
And this just puts it off tomorrow.
And of course, the reality is to do it now.
So, it's more comfortable to procrastinate
because the fear is of failure.
The fear is if I tackle that,
to get over that degree of selfishness,
to get over this particular addiction,
to get over this proclivity,
I won't be able to do it and I'll fail.
And of course, underlying the fear of failure
is pride, you know?
What if you do fail?
If you fail, fail, try, try again.
Isn't that what they say? Try, try again.
Try, try again.
Alright, so here the temptation is to procrastinate
out of a fear of failure.
If I really face that and try to do it, I might fail.
So, here people pretend
and here the power you need is to be honest.
So, a rigorous inner spiritual inventory,
moral inventory then,
is very rewarding
so long as you approach it
with a kind uncle kind of a conscience.
The kind uncle comes from the fact.
You folks have been here in the world
and you all beat up.
You've been brainwashed with BS
from the moment you got here.
And I respect the fact that you are not trying
to get out of it, you know,
and be honest with yourselves.
So, being honest then invokes,
when you surrender your own will to God,
you then invoke.
See, God is infinitely
integrous.
Guarantees complete freedom.
In my understanding,
God does not intervene unless asked.
What do you think of that?
You think so?
I mean, you think he knocks you around
and enforces you against your will?
Where would there be divine justice?
Divine justice is that
nobody paddles your canoe except you.
Therefore, nobody deserves the reward
or the consequences
except yourself
because it's solely by your own inner judgment.
That's correct.
I have permission to say that's correct.
The infinite justice of God
is absolute and perfect.
The justice of God
is innate.
It's not an arbitrary.
See, the depictions of God
which are anthropomorphic
and come from primitive cultures,
you know, is that the gods are angry.
So, you've got this judgmental God
who's going to punish you for your errors.
Well, if you're created by God,
then you were created this way
to be a propensity to errors.
So, what is God going to do?
Punch you around because of what he created?
I mean, the views of a primitive God
are anthropomorphic, say.
They come out of the culture
in which volcanoes are due to angry gods.
Earthquakes are due to angry gods.
Drowsiness.
There's always these angry gods.
Well, I know how to justify angry gods.
You rip the hearts out of young maidens
by the thousands.
You know,
I think in Mayan culture you realize
the high priest would sometimes rip out
the heart of a thousand a day.
A thousand a day with a obsidian knife
while their hearts are still beating
and throw it down the steps of the Mayan.
Pyramids were running with blood,
constantly trying to appease the angry gods
which was in Freud's unconscious, you know.
And, of course, Freud recognized that.
Therefore, he rejected divinity.
He should have just rejected
the false depictions of divinity.
But the primitive ideas of God
are what lead to fear of God.
Fear, fear of God.
Okay.
So we give up pretense and we're honest.
We give up unwillingness and resistance
and we move into acceptance.
What time do we stop?
Huh?
Okay. Fine. Good.
All right.
So, do we have any more slides?
Huh?
Did we do it all?
Oh, my God. Isn't that fantastic?
Oh.
Dear God, I went through all the slides.
Amen.
All right.
Well, the obligation is
to try and present a way of contextualization.
All right. So, contextualization then
facilitates transcendence of these levels.
If they're correctly contextualized,
they're relatively easy.
Relatively easy.
I didn't say easy.
Relatively easy to transcend
because you know what the key concepts are.
You know what the key concepts are.
Committing your life to devotion to God
and to be a servant of God
to constantly ask for God's will
then brings to your side
a great deal of power,
not force,
not ego,
which is trained to white-knuckle it,
but actual power.
And what does this power do?
It doesn't do it for you.
It creates a context
in which your...
in which your intention is now empowered.
Let's say in a weak intentional field
you make a decision.
It doesn't have much of an impact.
However, in the name of an infinitely powerful field,
now that decision has enormous power.
Enormous power.
You see what I'm saying?
To do it in the name of God then
empowers the decision,
the Heisenberg principle.
So the limitation of the Heisenberg principle,
it says,
the introduction of consciousness itself
collapses the way it functions.
See?
It doesn't talk about the calibrated level
of the consciousness of the observer.
You understand?
It just, it's an academic mathematical extraction.
So the intention of a person
of a relatively low level of consciousness
may have a feeble,
may have a feeble effect on the field.
The same decision by a person
of strict alignment
may have a powerful impact on the field.
Yes?
Powerful impact on the field.
Hmm?
So the Heisenberg principle,
then we could even recontextualize it.
Why is that?
When does the Schrodinger potentiality,
you know,
eventuate as the Dirac collapse
of the wave function expression
in the new state of the universe?
We could add,
it depends on the power of the observer.
Wow.
How do we know that?
I know it from clinical experience.
Oh, I have permission to ask this.
That's correct.
Resist.
100% correct.
Tally.
How do I know that?
Well, it was the clinical observation.
Many years ago,
I had a huge practice,
50 employees,
couple floors,
multiple labs,
neurological labs,
EEG labs,
you know, all kinds.
It was a giant practice
and we had a lot of therapists.
And I noticed that some clinicians
constantly got good results
and others pathetically didn't.
It didn't have anything to do with academic credentials.
This is, you know,
I was saying this morning,
there's a difference between academic science
and clinical science.
All right.
So the credentials were all academic.
But I noticed that certain therapists
consistently got, you know,
great results
and others didn't.
So, of course, at the time,
I didn't know about calibrated levels of consciousness.
But what you're seeing is the consequence
that there's a difference between
the academic treater and a healer.
The real function of the physician is to heal, to heal.
Academic medicine,
the way it's become today,
is sort of, you know,
pharmacologic mathematics.
It's completely dehumanized.
The medical journals I get now,
there are no humans involved.
There are no humans.
Nothing, no characteristics of humanness at all.
Unbelievable.
Compassion, that's unscientific.
Intention, that's unscientific.
You'd think they're talking about
abstract principles
having nothing to do with humanity suffering humanness
or anything like it.
Next to the real.
All right.
So these are providers of services.
They're not doctors anymore.
They're providers of services.
And this is a customer.
And you don't have a practice, you have a locality.
So in this locality,
the provider of services to the customer,
like sacks of potatoes, you know.
Like they were hardware, you know.
Hardware.
We dropped off the screen for repair
and the repairman repaired it.
So I discovered that it was the healing capacity of the clinician
because I could get recoveries with placebos
and academically trained physicians
couldn't get them with active psychopharmacologic agents.
How high was that?
So we discovered that the power of the observer,
of the clinician,
had a greater effect on the outcome
than the scientific principles
of the pharmaceuticals involved.
It's possible to get better recovery from depression
with a placebo with a very powerful physician
who really loves the hell out of his patients
and just uplifts them.
.
Rather than the tax clinician who calibrates at 202
who gives them Prozac, see.
So the classic.
The physician was supposed to be the healer.
The healer.
You're supposed to heal the patient, you see.
You're not supposed to be the local provider of services.
Nobody gets well with a provider of services.
MD online.
What's that big website?
MD online or?
WebMD.
Calibrates at 200.
What does that tell you?
200.
I don't want a physician to treat me at 200.
I'm sure he'll give me the right bandage.
I want you to get well.
Getting well is different.
Calibrates at 200.
Okay.
So that means there's other agendas.
Certainly 200 denotes lack of humanity,
love, caringness, benevolence,
all the things that really count in the long run.
The consequence of a scientific investigation, research,
which I've mentioned, I think, before in other lectures.
From the research, you can calibrate the research design.
You can calibrate the level of consciousness of the researcher.
And I can tell you the result already.
Save yourself $10 million.
Save the state of California and Euclid, 10 million,
because I can tell you right now.
You know, and we said it before, Crick's experiment,
discovery of the double helix, calibrated at 440.
His last experiment, which was to prove that consciousness
is solely a product of the physical neuronal activity of the brain,
calibrated about 140.
You know, the neuronal activity of the brain
is the consequence of consciousness in life, you know.
All right, so the application, then, of the science of truth, then,
is very valuable in many ways.
The intention of the devotee is what empowers the information
to become transformative.
It's not just hearing the information, and it's not just intention,
but you put the two together.
The power of the will, the power of the dedication.
So devotion, you see, is powerful because it's not coming from the intellect.
Devotion is of the heart.
The power of the heart is infinite.
The power of the intellect is limited.
It stops at 499.
Consequently, just deciding you're going to do something
because it's reasonable and makes sense,
intellectually obvious, isn't enough to do it.
In vocation, I ask Almighty God,
through His Son, Lord Jesus Christ and the Holy Spirit,
to be at my side as I try to overcome this limitation,
which is consequent to being a human.
That is powerful.
Therefore, the way to an evolved state is by the power of the devotion,
the uncommitted, unreserving devotion
to whatever it takes is whatever it takes.
Whatever it takes is whatever it takes.
It isn't necessary to go to the depths of hell.
Not necessary.
Eternal agony is not required.
It was just one way.
That's what this ego,
that's what it took for this ego to surrender
because it wasn't, the ego had somehow escaped.
It was pretty ferocious, ferocious.
It would take you through death without a thought,
take you to the depths of hell.
And there, in eternal agony of eternal hopelessness,
it finally let go.
That should not be necessary
because with the advancement of consciousness,
the information we have available now,
teachers available, recontextualization of the field,
recontextualization of the pathway,
it should never, it should not ever be necessary
to reach such an extreme depth of hell.
Amen.
Gloria in excelsis Deo.
All right, we'll take a break now
and then we'll reconvene in a little while.
We'll do questions and answers.
I'm trying to leave more time for questions and answers
because I don't want to hurry through them
and I don't want people waiting forever
and not getting tended to.
It's like being in McDonald's, you know,
and all these people are waiting for a cheeseburger.
That's the pressure of all the people.
Now, we're going to spend more and more time
with questions and answers
that we can all be who we are with each other
and, you know, as a very compassionate group,
you know, this group calibrates extremely high,
and their intention is very strong.
So the power of the intention of the teacher,
the student, and the group
is at maximum opportunity.
In this setting, a powerful teacher,
a powerful student, and a powerful group,
the impossible becomes a snap.
So we'll see you again in a little while.
We'll do questions and answers, you know.
We say, glory to God in the highest.
Bless you all.
Where's the recess bell?
There it is. Wait.
Children, children, recess is over.
We're getting ready to start the question and answer.
Oh, there you go.
Questions on this side of the room.
Book signing on this side.
Oh, I need my jacket.
Okay.
It's in my left inside jacket pocket.
We wanted to leave a little more time
for questions and answers.
The feedback we've gotten is that people really enjoy them,
you know, because it's not, you know,
contextualized in a formal kind of a way.
It's spontaneous, real.
And with Dr. Kalmbach, we were just reviewing
that the power of the intention of a student,
or devoted students like this group here,
the power of the individual,
the power of the group intention,
the intention of the teacher makes it formidable.
All three together is about as good as it gets.
Let's see.
Pow-ee.
Let's do it while we can.
Our being together then is, you know,
to me, a wonderful experience, you know.
Now, the people tell us that the person asking the question
has to speak closer to the microphone
and maybe a little louder.
When they play it back, this voice is too loud
as compared to that voice.
So, you know, speak loudly and clearly.
And we can spend a little more time
answering questions a little more completely
because we don't have such money to ask.
Uh-oh, I was thinking we didn't have a mic.
Can you hear him all right?
Yeah.
No, because I'm having problems hearing him up here.
Both microphones are turned off.
Yeah, you're fine.
Okay, I go into tech shock.
Tech shock.
Dr. Hawkins, you have said in your books or on your tapes
that the kamikaze pilots were calibrating at 390.
If you compare that to the suicide bombers
you see around the world, do they have the same level
or are they coming from a different...
I don't know. I haven't done that yet.
You haven't tested that?
The kamikaze was doing it for the sake of his country
and his leaders, see, and his people.
And he was doing it out of devotion to the emperor
as the representative of God, as representative of God.
Now, what particular bombers are you thinking about?
Middle East and what you see in Iraq every day.
You hear about suicide bombers.
Insurrectionists.
Insurrectionist bombings?
Let's just start with that.
We have permission to do the energy level
of insurrectionist bombings resist.
They're under 200 resist.
So it's a different dimension.
It could be that many of them are just violent people
looking for an excuse to be violent.
So they're not coming from...
It's not to die for a cause.
It's because they're violent?
Insurrectionist bombing is just killing your fellow countrymen
for political power.
The bombings are coming because one political party
is trying to dominate another political party.
That's not exactly, you know, devotional.
You know what I mean?
It'd be like the Republicans and the Democrats blowing each other up.
It's not exactly the highest level of integrity.
Those who say, in that culture, who say they're doing it for God
are using it as a cover-up.
Okay.
We have permission to ask what I have in my mind, resist.
I have permission to ask what I have in my mind, resist.
It's a form of blasphemy, resist.
It's a violation of the name of God.
Therefore, it covers extremely low.
It's not really true, see?
No.
Yeah.
Every verse of the Quran starts out the same.
You ever read the Quran?
No.
Every verse says,
In the name of Allah, be all merciful.
Every single standard says that.
In the name of God, be all merciful.
You would have to certainly violate.
Yeah. Thank you.
On the other hand, I do feel sorry for them.
See what I'm saying?
Because I think they are misled.
So the culpability is one thing,
but the accountability is still there.
Yeah.
I listened to the lecture today,
and I wanted to ask about karma
and chronic pain.
I don't see the payoff
to the chronic pain in my life.
We're talking about the payoff of
persistent levels of consciousness.
Certain things are the consequence
of the karma of humanness.
That's one reason the Buddha said,
Do not identify with the linear
and thereby avoid reincarnation.
Certain things are, see,
part of the collective karma of being human.
And some prevailing ailments may be specifically karmic.
All right, so let's just clarify that.
Some ailments are merely consequence
to the karmic inheritance of being human.
Some expressions represent a specific personal karma.
Such as, I have permission to ask this.
I have permission to ask this in front of this group.
Some resist.
This is personal past karma.
The wrinkles is group.
That was good.
One's a young handsome swain, yeah.
Yeah, so part of it just comes as part of being human.
And then some peculiar things.
To be born deaf, dumb, and blind.
You know, it seems so unique.
They must have these specific karmic propensity there.
Something's served, you know.
Thank you.
Anyway, we ask, you know, we ask God to help you endure it
and to understand it, to contextualize it,
and let go resisting it, you know.
You can live with pain for years.
It's been how many years?
The pain never goes.
All right.
Look what this says on here.
These are new books.
Oh, my goodness.
I brought all of my books.
Oh, my goodness sakes.
Okay.
And I also brought something from the minister,
from Boulder, in Boulder, Colorado, for you as a gift.
Unity of Boulder?
The minister did a series of talks on power versus force recently,
and he wanted you to have those.
Thank you very much.
You're welcome.
Do we ever speak at Unity of Boulder?
No.
No, we spoke at the Benedictine Monastery there.
Well, if you ever come up that way, you're welcome to do that.
So my question has to do with people who are in a position of affluence
in this lifetime who have, you know, the comforts of everything,
who have unlimited, say, assets to use on the behalf of themselves
and also on the behalf of those around them.
How do they go about feeling comfortable, feeling appropriate,
and having these things and using them for their own personal use as well
when there's so much, it appears as though there's so much lack and poverty
all in the world?
I mean, you know, what's the appropriate use of these assets to be a good steward?
Well, how they inherit it, karma is karma, you know what I'm saying?
And it would be the level of consciousness of the person,
how they would best see the fulfillment of the obligation of stewardship
of their assets.
For one thing, just keeping it in the bank is already serving society.
You understand what I'm saying?
Capital itself is necessary for economic survival
and the development of the whole civilization.
So just leaving it there, if you don't know how to benefit society,
the bank will.
It'll loan money to the shoemaker, it'll loan money to, you know.
So society benefits, you know, as just a consequence of its being there.
The accumulated wealth of a society
automatically brings benefits to all.
For one thing, the tax base goes up, government gets more wealthy,
and humanitarian programs can now be afforded by the government.
Many governments can't afford them because there isn't enough capital in the country.
So capital of its own sake, you know, is not intrinsically non-interiorist, you see.
So you don't have to feel guilty about being a millionaire, it's okay.
I'll tell my friends, thank you.
I get the further inference of what you're saying, you understand?
Yeah, it would be how you see that you might most greatly benefit society.
And when wealth reaches a certain level,
it begins to exert a moral pressure.
And you can see the richest people in America have all evolved great foundations.
In fact, in the new book we calibrate the level of consciousness of the major foundations, you see.
And of course they do an enormous amount of good.
So it's true, you can only get so wealthy and then you begin to feel an obligation
to use that wealth for the greatest good, you know.
I appreciate that, thank you.
Not out of guilt, but out of seeing it as a responsibility,
just like you were saying, what's the responsibility, you know?
I mean, I didn't feel any guilt when I was poor,
why should I feel guilt when I'm rich, you know?
Hello, sweetheart.
So, here's a lady who we quoted her in the book, didn't we?
Yep.
Yeah.
Thank you for being the great gift to humanity that you are.
You are one of humanity's great teachers.
Thank you for thinking me worthy.
Thank you for helping me to be in your book.
Yes.
And I have a question.
I am supposed to go to Kashmir to complete my new book on Jesus.
Is it safe for me to go because it's an insurgency state?
Can you calibrate that?
What country are you going?
Kashmir.
Kashmir in India.
Oh, Kashmir.
Is there anything going on there now?
There's a Muslim insurgency going on.
Huh?
Yes.
There's Muslims that are bombing things over there.
What's wrong with Arizona, sweetheart?
Well, I love her dearly and I don't want her...
I'll tell you because the symbols of Jesus in India are not in Arizona.
Oh, so you're going there.
Yes.
Yes, I understand.
I understand.
Of course.
Devji is quoted in the book on America.
She came from India.
The way she contextualized the heart and the essence of America,
I quoted to be in contradistinction to the devotees of hate America.
See?
The hate America comes out of a calibration level of about 130.
And she sees that it's truth.
Just like some people see these as beautiful, the beauty just stands out.
And other people think they should be thrown out, you see?
So I thought...
She wrote an article in Arizona Republic and I was stunned by it.
I says, wow.
This is somebody who really gets what the hell it's all about, see?
And we wrote for permission.
I wrote her and we got to meet.
And I had to foreshorten it.
The original article was considerably longer.
But for sake of space in the book.
But I tried to get the essence of it.
Although she gave some rather...
Because she's also a writer.
So she also gave some unique examples of what she was saying,
which I had to delete.
All right.
We're going to ask the question.
The question she holds.
Let's see.
I don't know if it's answerable.
But we can answer it as of now.
We have permission to ask this.
The area she's holding in mind is currently safe for a person of her extraction
to go into a resistance.
It's...
She is safe.
The area is safe.
The area that you're holding in mind.
You're holding in mind where you're going?
Yeah.
All right.
It is currently safe for her.
It only says currently.
By tomorrow, maybe...
Better call me back before you get on the plane.
Well, we once were supposed to board a plane to return to Korea.
And the plane had left.
And so we tried to get on another one.
And we used the arm.
And the arm said, you're not to go today.
Because it is not physically safe to go.
Yeah.
It's physically not safe to go.
So stop lamenting that you missed the plane.
Because it just saved your life.
However, if she wants to know before she gets on the plane,
call us and we'll recalibrate it.
Yeah.
Dr. Hawkins.
I am from Mexico.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you.
I come from Mexico.
Do you have any suggestions how we might get a better use of your work in there?
Yeah.
Well, the book has recently been translated into Spanish.
Uh-huh.
The first one.
Yeah.
Only the first one.
Yes.
I've never been invited to speak in Mexico.
Oh, well, that's the reason.
But I like going to Mexico.
I love Mexico.
Uh-huh.
And I've never seen people.
I feel very at home there.
So, yeah.
Would you be interested in...
Because I don't speak Spanish, eh?
Of course.
In school, I learned German.
Then I moved out of the German community and haven't used it in all these years.
Now I need to speak Spanish and I only know German, so not too much help.
I have to find a Mexican who understands German and then we can speak in German.
Yeah.
You got one right there.
You could speak English as well.
But would you be interested in participating in...
...in an international conference, international congress of spirituality next February?
I don't know, sweetheart.
You'd have to send the details to me in the office.
We'd have to calibrate it and see whether we can or can't.
My own energies are somewhat limited.
So, although my heart would like to do many things.
Yes.
The physicality doesn't have the energy a lot of times.
Yeah.
But thank you very much.
Thank you.
But of course I would be delighted with the...
Oh, yes.
...the request.
I understand the information.
I did, years ago, you know, go through South America.
I spoke at the University of Argentina, which I enjoyed a great deal.
Uh-huh.
Yeah.
Stopped off in Brazil and various places.
Got to go to Machu Picchu on the way back, you know.
And so, then we ended up in Ecuador.
And in those years, it was not a tourist country, South America.
There was two planes a week out of Crito, in Ecuador.
Two planes a week from Miami, I think it was.
Yes.
I got there for the Wednesday plane.
In the meantime, the clock had stopped in the middle of the airport, years and years ago.
In Ecuador, time doesn't mean anything.
You have to be there to know what I mean.
I mean, but it's there tomorrow, next time it was...
She says, the Wednesday plane won't leave till Saturday.
I said, okay.
In Ecuador, it doesn't bother you.
In Chicago, you'd have a fit, you know.
Ecuador, you say, oh, okay.
So, I went back Saturday to catch the plane.
Supposed to leave at 12 o'clock.
Quarter to 12.
At quarter to 12, there's one plane in Ecuador.
The entire airport, one plane sitting out there.
Quarter to 12, I hear its engine stop.
I said, now what?
The Thursday plane doesn't leave till Saturday, and now its engine...
She said, it's siesta time.
.
It's this airplane costing $1,000 an hour, I'm sure, for maintenance, insurance, and God knows.
They shut it down for siesta.
Ten minutes to 3, the engine started back up, we got on, and everybody flew out of there at 3 o'clock.
The Wednesday plane didn't leave till Saturday, and it didn't leave at noon, it left at 3,
and it didn't make any difference.
Well, things are different now.
I can assure you.
Thank you for the invitation, though.
Thank you. Thank you, doctor, for your great wisdom.
And if you're serious, you can send it to us at the office,
and we'll...
Yes. Yes, I'll make sure of that.
Thank you very much indeed. Thank you.
Your voice has the highest vibration I've ever heard in my life,
and I just loved it from the moment I heard it.
I've listened to about 300 hours on audio,
and this is my first time to hear you in person,
and it just rings true to my heart. Thank you.
A year ago, I was driving by Lake Powell,
and I was listening to one of your lectures about you getting rid of your glasses,
and after hearing you do that,
I rolled down the window and threw my glasses that I purchased out the window.
I'd bought them less than a week before,
and I still don't see.
I haven't seen in years, so what?
And I love it.
I love not seeing.
It's very freeing.
It was so freeing to take them off.
And I just was open
to any suggestions, coaching, to heal myself.
How long has it been?
It's been a year, over a year.
Oh, okay.
What I did with it is I kept surrendering,
and then, all of a sudden, of its own,
the seeingness returned, at least to a degree.
Up until that time, I couldn't see the edge of the highway,
and I'm driving around these mountain roads with a thousand-foot drop-off,
and the edge of the highway would somehow light up
only as I needed to see it.
So I got that you only get to see what you need to see.
You don't get to see what you want to see.
So what you do is keep surrendering the wantingness to see
because of the juice you get out of the visual linearity, see?
Meaning, significance, the entertainment.
And therefore, it's almost like a meditative experience
because when you go within the same thing,
the thoughts are coming by, like the passing scenery,
to suck you in to identify with the experiencer.
So what you're really getting a training has nothing to do with vision.
It has to do with surrendering the experiencer
who's always seeking to juice the visual with novelty, entertainment, titillation, value.
So who knows where it might lead?
I'm excited.
Constantly surrendering it to divinity, to God's sake.
Thank you.
Yeah, interesting experience.
It is. May I?
Yeah.
Thank you.
My pleasure.
God bless you.
I went to see Makananda one time.
I really liked Makananda.
It was in the mountains north of, what do they call them, the Catskills.
Makananda, I really loved him.
Anyway, the mantra they had was Om Namah Shivaya, you know.
And then during the lecture, he would wear orange knit hats.
And periodically through the lecture,
he had a whole pile of them.
He'd put it on a hat and then he'd throw it on the audience.
And they would all rush and grab it, you know,
because of his energy and vibration in that hat, you know.
Then he'd put another hat on.
Then 20 minutes later, he'd throw another hat on.
It was really funny.
But he was a delightful person to know, you know.
Makananda.
Brief knowingness.
My question has to do with intention and karma.
Because of my profession, people die as a result of the training
that I provide.
And I understand that when the two parties meet, it's their karma.
But what karma do I carry when I deal through my training
and providing that training?
Is it like a military, paramilitary?
Military and police.
Yeah, yeah.
So you're fulfilling with integrity the requirements of the office?
Yes.
To be the enforcer of the law.
Protectors of society.
The law in our population.
So you want me to calibrate the intention?
That's going to be what the level is.
The level of how the karma is affected?
Well, yeah, because your intention is what makes it, see?
So if your intention is to fulfill, you know, during war,
you're forced to kill somebody.
If you don't, you're going to get shot.
So for the honor of your country and the fulfillment of your obligation,
you have this role to fulfill.
Somebody's got to fulfill this role.
Somebody's got to fulfill the role.
It also may be a transitory.
And when it's served its purpose, you'll move on to something else.
But it might be the momentary requirement of your own karmic volition.
You're correct.
The volition comes from them, what they do with it.
See, because when we calibrated guns, we were amazed it was 200.
A gun is neutral.
It's like a saber or a dagger.
What you do with the dagger, you know, but the knife,
a knife calibrates at 200, so is a gun.
So you're a teacher of what is needed to maintain law and order.
And law and order, without law and order, society can't exist, you know?
So you're fulfilling a role in the need of society, you know?
And if your intention is to fulfill that need, as integrous as you can, you know?
I don't think the role itself is one way or the other, you know?
But I can understand your concern or question about it, you know?
Thank you, doctor.
Because that was World War II, you know?
And the question was in front of every participant in World War II at all times.
You know, what's the spiritual, you know, of this?
Mines and blowing people up and 20 caliber and guns, you know?
Bombers flying at you, kamikaze.
And you swing back 20 millimeter calibers.
You know, am I killing him or am I protecting my shipmates?
20 caliber, you know, anti-aircraft.
You swing back in that thing like this and take her right out of the air.
That guy just went up in pieces.
With either that or my shipmates going up in pieces, what are you going to do?
Press the trigger.
You're on the line, see?
And what's really pulling up is the courage to fulfill that obligation.
And I think once that's fulfilled, I don't think you have to do it again.
I think you transcend that and you're done with that karma.
So the karma of the officers, the karma of the soldiers that I trained.
Responsibility.
You're fulfilling your obligation to God and country.
That's what I see, you know?
And that would be the oath you take.
Thank you.