song.
We
are
>> Okay, now we have questions and answers.
Uh we discovered uh through experience
that people appreciate hearing the the
the discussions in public. It happened
the first time by accident. The
microphone was on and I was talking to
some people and pretty soon there's a
whole crowd around and
people said, "Let's do that." So, we're
doing it.
Next year, we'll probably
increase the length of the questions and
discussions. will have a less dedactic
presentation
because that's all appeared in books.
You see, I present it as I write it and
much of what I present won't appear in
print for a year or two.
But as it's available in print, then
we'll spend more time in traditional
exchange between
uh everyone and we can answer things in
greater depth and greater length. So
we'll spend more time with questions and
answers and discussion
and uh we may figure out a different way
of doing it other than lining up you
know. Okay. So let's be happy to
proceed.
>> This is what's missing.
>> This is what I put the books on.
>> This is what
>> Yeah. You have to talk to the mic.
>> Yeah. Which mic is the one he talks
into?
>> Both of them.
>> Oh, both of them. Really?
>> Oh, that's nice. Okay,
>> good. Okay. Well, the question is about
the collapse of the waveform and the
particle wave duality
>> and uh over the decades what we've heard
is that uh where the collapse takes
place is in machines or something. But
my version
>> in machines devices like the
specttograph whatever else
>> collapse like
>> oh that's the experiment yes
>> yeah the experiments uh they were trying
to figure it out my own conclusion is
that the collapse takes place in
consciousness
and the question is if that is so is
there any such thing as reality of
particles or is that in a is that a
perception of our
>> that's perception
Because of course subparticle physics
>> is speaking only of potential energies
is really only talking about
potentialities and uh
>> yeah we were talking about
the actualization of potential
and that is sort of an explanation of
the mechanics the mechanics of it
the the potential uh is activated
depends on the power of the field. So
because
consciousness is infinitely powerful,
therefore
creation is the emergence of the
unmanifest into the manifest.
>> Manifest.
>> So that is how creation comes about
because
the field is so powerful any possibility
then becomes an actuality. Yeah. Well,
then matter is really just a illusion of
of consciousness.
>> That is a little difficult to answer
because of the way you phrased it.
>> You said nothing but. It isn't nothing
but because things are
multi-dimensional. See, it's
potentiality in one level. It's a energy
at another. It's empty space, you know,
because uh
an atom is 99.9% empty space, right? One
electron hoing around claims that
territory for itself, but it's really
empty space.
The 99% of the solid world is actually
empty.
>> Okay. Thank you. Yeah.
Dr. Hawkins, thank you first of all for
uh continuing to write and have these
seminars. I think we all appreciate it.
I certainly do. So, thank you both very
much. My question is
should spiritual students do everything
that we can to take some stewardship
over the other species on the planet uh
that are being so negatively harmed by
other humans or should we just leave it
to God?
>> Again it's a projection of perception.
Huh? Uh
uh the Daly Lama.
Uh no, it wasn't the Daly Lama. It was
Mahatma Gandhi. One of them.
It was the skinnier one. I forget which
one.
>> I think I think
I I think sir will know the answer to
this one. Which one said it is not
enough to just pray for yourself. Pray
for yourself but to do everything you
can to be of assistance to life in the
world. You see so what you can do to be
of assistance to life in the world that
depends on your level of consciousness.
At one level of consciousness you give
it beneficial neglect and let it be what
it is. You know at another level you see
suffering and you wish to intervene. I
believe that from the viewpoint of com
compassion
one does all one while one can to
relieve suffering. Huh? On the other
hand suffering is the way to redemption
for the undoingness of negative karma.
The the undoing of the agony you've
caused others. You experience now what
that was like. And therefore the next
time you don't do it. So
it would be where one is in one's karmic
evolution what you feel called upon to
do by the world. I think whatever you
consider to be the most compassionate
would uh be the best. Huh.
>> Thank you.
like eliminating your enemies.
>> Okay, I'm going to pull you up here
quick.
>> The mind is very clever
justify anything. Okay. Uh I would also
like to thank you for the gift of uh
continue your continued teachings and uh
to use your term uh recont
recontextualizing my spirit life. So
thank you very much for that.
>> Um my question I' I've seen uh heard you
or read about um the atheric body. You
also mentioned the Christ or atmic.
>> Yeah. the causal body uh Buddha body um
Christ body atmic body as those are
classic Buddha Christ atic
>> mhm um
>> those are above the physical body they
are energy fields which are taught about
in esoteric psychology esoteric
psychology
energy congregations you might say the
attractor fields of the spirit and
contrad distinction of the attractor
fields of the ego
>> okay
>> so there's lower mind, higher mind,
causal body.
Um, there's people that know more about
it than I do here. I just use it for
general reference. Huh.
>> Okay.
>> Okay. Very good. Thank you.
>> It's a spiritual discernment accompanies
the opening of the third eye of the
Buddha body. So each of these bodies
also has the what's comparable to
uh chakra system
which when you get into really high
realms over the 800 uh is what you're
pulling up from the unconscious all the
time just when you're comfortable you
feel a terrible pain and uh it's some
aspect and instead of looking for it in
your personal life you won't find it
there but you'll find it in the
collective unconscious.
I know when I wrote truth versus
falsehood, I had a lot of trouble with a
spiritual knight.
The spiritual knight came up with
indignation.
Look what they've done to God's truth.
You know what I'm saying? And I had to
quiet the spiritual knight. You know,
the spiritual knight was indignant
because I'd ignored the world for a
long, long time. you know except
the small space of clinical practice but
the world itself I'd ignored so now I
thought well we'll apply this
calibrating of levels of truth to the
world as it appears and see what shows
up and up came the spiritual night
out of the collective indignant
indignant you know so that took some
correction
yeah
>> after One has had the grace of a guru
and the transmission of no mind
and one fully intuitively understands
all the material presented is it
necessary for one to continue the
classes
>> classes
>> um being here now
>> oh you would do it for the purposes of
being with the people you love and care
for.
>> Thank you. I look forward to it because
it's like family week, you know what I
mean?
>> Yeah. Oh, my first time to see you and
hear you was very impressed that you
came around and touched everyone and
said hello. And my question to you is
really about touch. Your thoughts on
those who have suffered trauma
when touch is
compassionate, intentional, and reverent
its value to consciousness.
Was
that a question?
>> I believe it was. I was trying to make
it a question. Um,
>> the value
>> the value of touch.
>> Oh, I never really calibrated the the
the the touch is expressive of the love
I feel uh to make it
experiential on a sensory level. Uh it's
symbolic
whether in innately it has something of
itself I don't know I never asked
>> um do we have we have permission to ask
that here the actual touch uh has some
additional benefit uh oh
here
>> uh a significant again value resist. Oh,
I never knew that.
I just did it intuitively. See, so
I ran out of peacock feathers to hit
people with, so I guess I'll have to get
more squeeze.
No problem. Yes.
>> Um, several times you've mentioned uh
Ramana Maharshi in your lectures and
books. I was wondering um his teaching
of self inquiry
>> if that's the most uh direct path.
>> Yes, I've written about it uh in the
last two books which aren't uh
in printed yet.
Uh self inquiry.
I've not been impressed by the
consequences of it. I get the intention
of it. The difficulty with it is
it starts out with the pronoun who and
then it asks a pronoun. So you're
looking for a who when the answer is a
what.
So I say in the book Ramano Maharshi
taught who am I? And I found it more
fruitful to ask what am I? Let's see.
Because when you get rid of the personal
identification as the pronoun I,
you move to the witness observer and
then the witness observer, what is the
witness observer coming out of? Well,
those are not who's those are whats.
See, witnessing happens spontaneously,
autonomously.
There's no who witnessing and that dawns
on you the witnessing.
So you move from
identification with content to that
which is witnessing
that then you move to the observer
then it dawns on you there isn't any
observer and witness or nor witness that
there is a quality ah you're a quality
you're not a who by what quality are you
conscious or aware and then you see
that's impersonal that that's a quality
of the field. So you're not a who,
you're the field.
So I'm always afraid by asking who that
you're going to be looking for another
pronoun, a different definition of self.
Maybe more sophisticated, but still a
definition. This time you're looking for
a definition of self with a capital S,
which is at least the right direction.
however inferential in his works. You
see the analogy I think he had of the
camera, right? The film.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Of the screen is just
>> Yeah. Yeah. The screen. The film.
>> So that's what's witnessed there on the
TV set. Mhm.
I just think it's more fruitful to ask
what is it that is observing? What is it
that's experiencing?
What is it that's witnessing witnessing?
because I I'm afraid the world word who
uh is constricting
to a pronoun. You're looking for another
pronoun, you know,
>> with the full potential.
>> Yeah. So that's why I appreciate, you
know, what he says what he says.
>> We'll tweak it a little bit.
Well, I I also but I do second his what
he called the fourth state which I
rediscovered
and undiscovered and he already defined
it. You know uh that you won't find the
infinite between thoughts. You find it
in the field out of which all of thought
arises. E so you look to the underlying
field and the underlying field is
silent.
And with observation
and sort of a contemplative lifestyle,
you become one with the silent with the
silence.
So you walk around
not in the state of sleep, not a slate
of dreaming, not an ordinary state, but
in a state in which
you are the infinite silence out of
which all form arises. That's present in
this room right now. So if you look
underneath your thoughts, you'll find
that nothing's going on. It's still and
silent.
>> He learned to live in the fourth state.
>> Yeah.
>> That's what so I value his work because
he gave it a name.
Tia ta Sanskrit ter
is the fourth state of consciousness.
Not sleeping, not dreaming, not awake.
and but um aware conscious but without
form or content.
>> Yeah. Just being
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So young to be so advanced
curiosity.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh Dr. Hawkins, my question sort of
follows on Lindsay's question and that
is
>> is it true what some Adveda teachers say
that personal free will is an illusion
that the only real choice you have is to
move towards that fourth state of
consciousness
>> is to move towards what
>> like the force the fourth state of uh
consciousness
>> fourth fourth
>> fourth or more of a witness
consciousness is the only true choice
that you
Oh, that's sort of a constructive
definition. It's really a little more
complicated than that because in the
same vein, you could say there is no
such thing as karma, which on a certain
level is true. When it's true for you,
it's true for you. But if it ain't,
watch out cuz
you say, "Well, karma is just an
illusion." Okay.
What was the question?
Personal
free will.
>> Oh, personal free will.
>> Yes.
>> All right. Personal free will, of
course, that is the term. All it means
is that you're constantly presented with
options and choices and they're
continuous. So, you're like the prow of
the ship which is constantly making
adjustments. It has to constantly go
here or there. This is the experiencer
who's out there. And the experiencer is
constantly searching, searching,
searching. So that a decision has to be
made all the time. I can eat this. This
is poison. This is a friend. This is a
foe. I can mate with this. It'll reject
me. See what I'm saying? So it's
constantly
searching and it's constantly has to
make a decision.
It has to move in one direction or the
other. See, that's when the ego is
predominant. When it's not predominant,
the ship goes however the wind and the
seas set it. See, and what controls it
is intention. So, a decision of the will
is like setting your karmic compass.
All right? Once you've set your karmic
compass, now it will go this way and
that way with the waves and the wind,
but you're not going to change your
compass. Your compass is set. The only
way to fall in consciousness is to is to
make a bad decision uh by the spiritual
will.
So we talk about in these classes
sometimes but leave me later on and the
book's on completing uh also the
temptations and the traps because that
which goes up can also go down. So you
can make serious errors to fall for
agilation, control over others, money,
glamour, sex, those are the ones that
pull them all down.
They they're on the internet.
So
>> you'd say there are choices then that
personal free will does exist that it's
not
>> otherwise otherwise there'd be no karma.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. No, you're responsible to the
universe for every decision. See,
however, you're responsible. You're
culpable to the degree of your
knowingness at that level.
So you could make what is really not a
spiritual error. But because you believe
it is a sin and you went and did it
anyway, now you got a negative karma. If
you saw it from up here, you'd realize
there was nothing wrong with it.
>> So from a certain state of
consciousness, suddenly like you said,
you're just going with spont sponta
spontaneity
and
kind of off the wheel.
>> Well, the kind of decisions you're
making are based on your spir spiritual
alignment. So if you live a life your
life is a prayer then you dedicate your
life to appreciating the beauty of life
the sacredness of life uh the support of
the happiness of others
and being a servant of life. So to so to
be a servant of God already defines some
what your role is to be. Now through
prayer you may get
you know to go and do something to feed
the hungry
or you may get
allowing them to experience what the
hunger that you cause the others through
your selfishness. See now you know what
it is to be hungry.
So the rich aristocrat, this you know
that ignore the starvation of the
population while they indulge themsel
in massive indulgences
has something to learn what it is to be
hungry and desperate and poor and chased
by the police all at the same time.
So
beheading probably helped that learn
that lesson, but
Probably not.
I consider the urgens of that lifetime.
The beheading didn't make any difference
either.
Anyhow, so yeah, then so they depends on
what your level is. The karma involved
the level of consciousness. So the
options have a certain range. See, a
frog cannot decide to become a bird.
See, so you've only got a limited range
uh due to karmic propensities to begin
with.
Thank you.
>> But you you'll notice that you have to
you're making decisions all the time,
either wittingly or unwittingly. When
you're driving a car, you're making
constant adjustments. Yeah.
>> I mean, your your steering wheel never
just stays still. You soon be off the
road. You're constantly making little
adjustments. So that's what your mind is
doing. Making little adjustments
to smile sweetly, to smile not so
sweetly, to not look too friendly, or to
give them a skull. I mean, you got to
make them make up your mind. It seems
>> they come to you with a hatch, you got
to decide
or give him a quarter or get a job bum.
You know what I mean?
>> You got all kinds of options.
>> Yeah. It just seems like at a certain
point it's not a conscious decision
anymore and it's just like things are
just happening.
>> Well, yes. It goes on automatic.
>> So, uh one of the spiritual practices is
is to watch and be aware.
>> You know, Mr. out of Maharaj you know
reached the layman I think three years
and his dictim was merely to watch the
mind he didn't say do anything with it
don't correct it but watch it that's
what we said today is the Heisenberg
principle if you merely watch a certain
behavior it will automatically diminish
if it's a behavior you you don't like if
it's a behavior you do like watching it
will tend to increase it expect a
miracle is a saying yeah the more you
expect a miracle the more likely it is
you know by the Heisenberg principle
that it's going to precipitate it out of
the field but that again is dependent on
karma.
>> Mhm.
>> Thank you very much.
I too want to thank you for being
available.
And my question is about a daughter of
mine who has really severe depression.
And when you had all the shame,
attractions, and aversions up there, I
realized that every single one of the
attractions has been present and and
kind of defined the depression. And this
is not the first time either that she
and had a major crash and has a
three-year-old
that um has been completely
dysfunctional
um in treatment and will be continuing.
So
>> has severe depression,
>> severe severe
>> intractable
It seems that way.
>> Nonresponsive to antidepressants.
>> Yes.
>> Jock treatment.
>> Had not had jock treatment.
>> Am I curious? Anyway, go ahead.
>> Is there anything
>> that I can do?
>> Well, other than prayer, I don't see
what you can do. She has her own karmic
propensity to run out.
You don't know what the karmic
background is. But out of benevolence,
you do all you can to release suffering.
So you provide all the options by which
then she has to make an inner decision
to come out of it and to to let go of
it. Yeah.
Severe depression is spiritual,
psychological, physical and clinical.
You know, produces neurotransmitters
and when those neurotransmitters get
depleted, the person gets depressed.
Huh? when you build them back up again
generally generally they will come out
of it.
So that has to be done on all those
levels that you spoke of the physical
the spiritual
>> everything is physical mental and
spiritual I believe in approaching all
three simultaneously you know you try
some powerful energy depression like a
fixer very sullen does the depression
that come out of depression on a fixer
and you do counseling you do group
therapy spirituality prayer and do
everything you can physically mentally
and spiritually
and then it's going to run its force
anyway.
>> Okay. And you talked about that
intractable patient that you had, which
means that of course there are some
>> intractable what
>> patient that you had that just did not
respond.
>> There was only one. Yeah.
>> Only one.
>> He had a brain made of lead. I don't
know.
>> Well, I I'm I'm not going to hold that
in consciousness that she's intractable.
But what
>> No, she's not in. something else
something else came up and that is and
in and when this first this crash
happened I thought God you know we need
an exorcist
you know I mean I honestly
>> you thought of everything right
>> I did think of
but what about the idea of possession or
another
energy
>> you try everything when you're desperate
okay
>> people some people get so desperate they
look for a psychiatrist
at death's door they call you.
>> Okay.
>> In two weeks they're out of it. You know
what I mean? They went through five
years of suffering.
I still uh have a a tow hold in
psychiatry. I just published an article
in this month this week's psychiatric
news
on entity presence in childhood and
adolescence. Yeah.
>> Dr. Hawkins. Yeah. Could you explain
more about the aging process or what we
perceive
>> the aging process?
>> Right.
>> Explain what about it.
You get tired wrinkled gray and old and
then you fall over.
No problem.
Like a patient said to me, "What if this
doesn't work?" I said, "Then you die."
No problem.
>> But haven't you said it couldn't come
from a linear process?
>> Huh?
>> From a linear process, doesn't it?
Physicality is linear.
>> Oh, okay.
>> The body arises from the world and it
returns to the world.
>> I was trying to make it nonlinear.
>> Make it what?
>> It's because I was trying to make it
nonlinear.
>> Well, um the the you're talking about
the physical body.
The reality is nonlinear. The minute
you're outside of time,
I mean, I knew that when I was 12.
Suddenly, time stopped. An infinite
presence beyond all description.
Love like no human
can ordinarily experience it. The divine
presence was who I am.
And as who I am, the reality I exist
before all universes and will be after
all universes have disappeared. Let's
see if that's true.
That is a fact. Oh Lord, resist. That is
a fact. That which I am was before all
universes and will be after they have
all disappeared.
That takes care of linear temporality.
Huh.
Now there's periodic reincarnations for
the karmic benefit. Also there's certain
contracts I think that are made that
I've forgotten
out of body now in body now.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you sir. So your reality is
nonlinear
and it won't die. So the you won't die.
The what you think you are. Get rid of
it.
No, it's still fun. It's a toy.
The body is like a karmic windup toy.
It's good for entertainment and fun and
dancing and music and eating donuts.
Might as well juice it for whatever good
you can get out of it when you got it.
Just so don't get attached to it. No,
don't get attached to it and don't
identify with it. No, I think you enjoy
it. You enjoy it like a pet. I mean,
it's a it's a fun thing, you know, and
it's like a toy. It's a fun thing. You
couldn't dance or stand on your head
without it. See?
So, it's a fun thing. Enjoy it while you
got it. just don't believe that that's
who who you are. That's all.
See, because there's the body. How do
you know there's a body? Because you're
aware. Well, what is it that's aware of
the physicality? So, instantly you would
draw from the body. You see, you're not
the body. You're that which experiences
the body. Then you're that which thinks
it's experiencing the body. Then you're
that which is experiencing experience.
And you see you begin to withdraw from
identification with the physicality.
The physicality is limited to this
dimension.
When I dis rediscovered physicality, I
was age three and I was not happy.
I was not happy to have a physicality
and find myself back in the physical
domain.
So
say goodbye to it.
>> Thank you.
>> You drop into the world and you drop out
again.
in and out like a bunch of birds.
We come in as a flock together. We've
gone through this before. This whole
group here, we've all flocked here like
a bunch of swans. We've nested down and
we've flown on. Yeah. We've tend to
swoop in and swoop out pretty much
together.
>> Dr. Hawkins, the saviors such as Christ
and Buddha and even the Holy Spirit have
done and are doing so much for humanity.
I was wondering is there anything that
people may do for them?
>> Do for whom?
>> Christ.
>> The Holy Spirit.
They're not of whom.
It's a quality of divinity expressed as
consciousness.
To be a servant of the Lord then is to
become all that one karmic to fulfill
one's karmic potential to the best of
one's ability.
That pretty much fulfills your
obligation, your gratitude, and the
expression of thanks for your existence.
To be the best long-distance runner you
can be, you put your heart into it and
you take yourself right to the edge and
then you break through the barrier.
Roger Bannister,
you do all that you can pull up with
your heart and devotion. So that's
devotion.
Spiritual commitment to the spiritual
will and devotion are very very powerful
very powerful.
So God doesn't need your help. Holy
Spirit doesn't need your help.
The divinity delights in the fulfillment
of that which you created.
You bring up a dog and teach you tricks
and you see how happy and and gay and
how how it's fulfilled its potential to
learn and be a friend and your pal. That
brings you joy.
>> Thank you.
>> So all of us that is our potential is to
fill
Yeah. To fulfill our karmic potentiality
to the best of our ability to align
yourself with divine intention is a very
powerful act of the will. You've already
done 90% of it. The rest is really up to
the Holy Spirit to unfold to you what
the options are. You know,
>> uh Dr. Hawkins, thank you for uh taking
my question. Appreciate appreciate this
time. Um I have a question about uh
maybe you can share with me about
overcoming a phobia from your clinical
and and and spiritual Yeah.
>> knowledge. Um any advice about that?
I've been living with a phobia for a
long time in my life and
>> yeah right about that uh in the level of
fear which we don't get to. You'll have
to suffer it for a couple more lectures.
Now we get to fear.
Fear is innate to the ego because it
bases survival on it. Then it attaches
fear gets programmed into certain
things. It can be phobic, you can be
afraid of open places, claustrophobia,
agorophobia,
uh a multitude of phobias and u to
recover from them there's a couple of
ways. The spiritual way is to suffer out
the fear. Let go resisting the the fear.
Now fear is a combination of a
physiology plus imagination.
All right? So the imagination you're
probably not going to do much about. But
the fear you can experience out and I've
done it. It may take hours.
Not the not the what you're afraid of
but the experience which is sensory.
What is fear? It's a shaking of the
knees, a whimwaming in the stomach. It's
a trembling of the nerves. It's a
feeling of terror and pending doom. So
what happens, this is a spiritual way of
doing is you let go resisting it. Now
all all feelings uh have a limit.
They're not limitless.
So all the fear since the beginning of
time has compounded and now you have
what in Esther called a big stack. You
got a big stack called fear
and you experience out the fear without
resisting it. This is the way you get
rid of pain too. You surrender to the
fear and allow it to run.
Stop resisting the fear and stop calling
it fear. You can't experience fear.
You can only experience sensation.
Let go resisting the sensation and don't
label it fear.
You can't experience hunger either.
Hunger is a name, a label.
You can only experience
a physicality
as it is arising. So you can let go
resisting
and eventually you'll uh you'll uh drain
it all out. Now at the bottom of the
fears, I call it so what. If your fears
are specific, see
uh you can do the pro process called so
what?
If I don't get this job, I'll be a
failure. And then what?
And then my friends will laugh at me.
And then what?
And then I won't have any money. And
then what? And then I can't pay my
mortgage. And then what? So each And
then what? Could you surrender that to
God? Yeah, you could.
Most people say, "No, I can't." I say,
"I got a 38 caliber
bullet in this revolver, and if you
don't turn, I'm going to blow your
brains out." No. Can you? Yep.
So, it isn't that you can't, it's that
you won't. If I'm going to blow your
brains out, unless you let go of this,
brother, you can let go of it. I don't
have one on me today.
>> You're lucky.
>> All right. For those who are really
brave and courageous, there's the crash
program where you just allow the fears
to rise. Then there's this uh then what
if there's specific I'll get old and
I'll be old and ugly and then nobody
will love me and then I won't you know
and then and then and then and and the
fear always ends up as a fear of death
and then what and then I'll be penniles
and then I'll be homeless and then the
people on the street will attack me and
they'll rob me and I'll be weak and old
and and then I'll get sick and then
what? And then I'll die. So
Once you surrender to physical death,
the whole stack of fear usually
disappears.
There's other ways of doing it. Crash
program, virtual reality in which you
consciously choose
uh a fear situation and recreate it.
Fear of flying, let's say, you know. So
there's various ways you can recreate
uh
and extinguish it
by being with the fear. So there's fear
reduction programs, you know, in which
what you're afraid of, they recreate it
as a virtual reality and you let go
resisting it. Finally, finally it's
gone.
>> Thank you.
Let's say a person has a germ phobia. So
you get the germs and then what? Then
I'll get sick. Yeah. And then what?
>> Kind of nice.
>> Then I'll die. So
the inevitable is inevitable. What you
mean is you don't want to die now
instead of later. So it isn't that you
got to let go of dying. You got to let
go your timing of it.
>> I don't want to go now. I want to go
when I'm old. What if faith says, "No,
you're going this week. I don't want to
go this week." So the child in you, the
infant, insists on having its own way. I
don't want to leave the planet this
week. I got tickets to the ball game
next week.
>> Well, hello.
>> Yeah. Um well somebody get got a little
bit ahead ahead of me about the self
inquiry situation. However I want to add
a little bit about it
>> about what
>> about the self inquiry Roman which by
the way I think it has a little bit of
equivalent when you mention in your one
of your last chapters of the eye about
towards the realization of the self
asking yourself how do how do I know
that I exist?
>> Yeah. So just
biting into that feelingness of
beingness of of being aware that what is
>> the field of it. Yeah.
>> Yes. Just the field. Just the field.
>> The field.
>> Okay. F E L D.
>> Being aware of that feelingness.
>> Mhm.
>> Is that that's like a quality of
divinity? That's like an expression of
divinity within ourselves.
>> Yes. And that's the quality of the
feeling.
>> It's the source of our existence. And
that's it.
>> No, that isn't all there is to it.
No, there's a catch.
>> You're in the right state. Now you got
to find the county, the city, the town,
and the right block.
>> You know, the quality of
experiencing that you experience, the
the quality of subjectivity, radical
subjectivity,
uh reduces it to the awareness of
existence.
And then the what's of existence
uh become irrelevant.
The source of joy is the awareness that
the source of one's existence is is
innate to who you are. Yeah. Therefore,
you don't have to look outside of
yourself for anything to make you happy.
These flowers are not going to make me
happy or make me not unhappy.
However, they're incredibly beautiful.
So you enjoy them because they're
witnessed you know
>> but you just mentioned on this session
that the trees are like ourselves
because they are aware but they're just
only expressed as existence not as a
beingness. So I just
>> I didn't say trees were aware that they
are aware awareness that you are shows
up at calibration level 200 before that
you are but you're not aware that you
are. Okay.
>> So below 200 life experiences life but
it is not aware that it is
>> okay
that's a subtlety
but quite a significant one because
to be aware of your own existence as
beingness as existence as life is a
value. So you you treat others as you
believe you are, therefore a value. So
over 200 other people have a value. You
think, I'm going to do this. Yeah, but
how will the neighbors feel? I'm going
to paint my my house bright red. Well,
how will the neighbors feel about that?
Doesn't occur below 200.
Above 200, you'd say, well, I don't want
to upset the neighborhood. I don't want
people to be unhappy. I don't want
but below 200 you're only interested in
me. Well, I like a black and white and
blue house and if you don't like it it's
my right and I'll call my lawyer and you
know free speech all the rest free
expression I can paint nudes on it if I
want.
>> Okay. So in the end if if I just abide
in just that feelingness of that'll take
care of everything.
That's a simplification,
but you're in the right direction
to sense the context out of which one's
existence arises
and eventually one realizes that that is
closer to your reality. So you you pull
back farther and farther from linear
content to nonlinear context and then
the nonlinear context enlarges and
enlarges and enlarges.
There's still something of the ego left
though despite the fact that's going on.
>> Okay.
>> Yeah. Because when the ego comes up to
die, you'll know it because the call is
to die.
This too must I surrender to thee, oh
Lord. Because the core of the ego is its
belief that it is it is the source of
your life.
So when there's nothing left in the
absolute silence, you're totally alone.
The door stands before you and you know
that the last thing you have to lay down
is your life. Oh,
all do I surrender to thee, oh Lord.
And then you know that it is your life
that you must surrender. It's what you
believe 100% is your life is that core
of the ego.
This too must be surrendered to God
comes as the knowingness because you've
heard it. You've heard it here. It's
imprinted as a vibration in your aura.
Now the n out of the silence the
knowingness comes.
This too
then arises a tremendous fear of death.
You've never died before. This is the
one and only time you can die.
The fear of death arises. Then comes the
knowingness from the teacher somewhere
in the past that exists as a frequency
in your aura
that all fear is illusion. All fear is
illusion and death is not a possibility.
All fear is illusion and death is not a
possibility.
That calibrates at 1,00
you got the message now.
You won't remember it but as the moment
arises
and then you feel the agony of death and
it lasts for a few moments.
The one and only death is possible.
and then suddenly bursts forth.
>> Thank you very much.
>> That's the information you wanted.
>> Yes. Thank you.
>> See, before when you die, you just go
out of body. It's a joke.
You're up here in the air. The body's
down there. Everybody's sobbing and
crying, carrying on.
>> Hi.
>> Hi. I'm delighted to be here and I'm
very grateful for the truth that
continues to flow through you. I have a
question and a gift. Uh I'm a musician
and I'd like to give you this music for
meditation.
>> Yes.
>> As a small gesture to give back to you
some of what
>> Thank you very much. Journey within.
That's a nice title.
>> Thank you.
>> The question I have is a bit of a
paradox. Maybe you can resolve. On the
one hand, time is an illusion.
On the other hand, in the last segment,
>> it's not really an illusion. It's a it's
a it's a track. You know, when you do a
tape, you can a video tape, you can time
track it. It it's the ego time tracks it
before, now and future. You know, it
already time tracks it because it
believes in causality. Therefore, it
believes in change. So, automatically
time tracks it based on sequence.
experience is sequential and it projects
it that the world is sequential. No,
it's your witnessing of it that's
sequential. You see the world now, you
see the world, you see the now. So the
sequence is rest internal, not rest
external.
>> Well, it kind of takes care of the rest
of my question because because on the
one hand it seemed like time is an
illusion. On the other hand, in your
last segment, you said the choices that
we make today are different than the
choices we made before cuz we're not the
same now.
>> Well, yeah. It's not because of time.
It's because of transition. See,
everything is evolving. So, that which
it is now is not what it was when it was
just this. You don't have to call that
time. See, what you're not seeing is
time. What you're seeing is evolution
um unfolding
as emergence.
The word emergence explains it better.
You see out of the cry out of the cocoon
the crysis emerges the butterfly
but the pupa does not become the
butterfly.
The pupa is still only a pupa.
So but this is the emergence of its
potentiality becoming an actuality.
It doesn't occur in time. Time is a
superimposition.
So creation is the emergence. The
unmanifest becoming manifest in which
the infinite potentiality of divinity
comes forth as manifestation.
Then the physicality
is part of the potentiality of
manifestation.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Emergence answers your question.
Emergence.
>> I'm watching it. Yes.
>> Hello.
>> Dr. Hawkins. Why are so many very smart
people calibrate below 200 as opposed to
in the 400s?
>> Because it's one of integrity. So the
intellect can be used to make a ton, you
know, bombs to kill people. The
intellect can be used to make penicellin
to save people. So the intellect is
is equality. Uh and then it's up to the
person how to use that. How to use that.
So you can use it to play chess. You can
use it to make money. You can use it to
uh to be a good doctor, lawyer, merchant
or chief, whatever you want. See? So
what you use with it? So it's like
having a very good athletic body. See?
And uh you can use it
to the best of your ability. You go.
>> Can I have a touch?
>> Yes.
>> Thank you.
>> Thank you for a wonderful lecture.
My question regards prayer.
um
and and when one wants to make a major
decision and um regarding prayer and
decision and some people have suggested
that um you know I just pray for God's
will and you talked about the power of
intention and our will
>> does God have a will as such in the way
that we do
>> and um what you mean
Um
the the best prayer and also the best
way to do kinesiology is to ask what
serves the highest good.
So people are playing, oh I pray that so
and so uh gets well and you ask that
would serve the highest good
may or may not. Why? Because it's not
going to serve her good. Because from
the moment you're born, the time of
leaving here is already preset.
Because the karmic propensities, you
leave here in one form or another. See,
so interference could, you know, not
necessarily be a benefit, you know.
Uh what was the question?
>> Well, the question is does does God have
a will as we such as we have a will.
>> We project an anthropomorphic view of
will. See
>> uh as a partiality.
>> Uh you might say God's will is more
general that than that shines out forth
out of mercy and infinite mercy.
Uh
but within its power, that which is
karmically
destined to potentialize will
potentialize.
So it isn't so much that it's God's will
because you hardly need to remind him
what his duties are.
Most people spend most of their time
advising God what's needed.
Aunt Nellie's gallbladder.
Sister Suzie's asthma.
Yeah. My grandfather's health. It goes
on and on. Advising God what needs to be
done, you know. All right. So, if
divinity is hierarchal, hierarchal,
I see divinity as an infinite power.
Uh and then there's step down
transformers whereby it comes down to
the human domain as I said one glance
from an archangel can fry you. So
even as it is as you advance in
consciousness when you get around 800 or
so you get burning agonies in your body.
So, and compare it to celestial rims.
I'm sure the calibration level 800 or
850 on there is child's play, but
already it's painful within this domain.
So, if you want to go on to a thousand
or over, it's probably best to leave the
body and go to celestial realms where
people don't have protoplasmic nervous
systems, you know. All right. So divine
will then I is you know as a pragmatic
interpretation
would be for each thing to fulfill its
karmic potentiality
in a man in a manner that serves the
highest good which does not exclude
yourself
nor does it exclude others.
So the Holy Spirit the miraculous is
that both are simultaneously possible.
The ego sees that if I win, you lose.
And the Holy Spirit arranges it in such
a way that everybody wins.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Yeah.
>> The angelic forces are God's working
staff
>> staff members.
My question is about the uh Sedona
release technique.
>> The what?
>> Uh Sedona release technique. It's a
>> a form of spiritual growth, I guess. I
was
>> What is it?
>> Sedona.
>> The Sedona method.
>> Oh, this method. Yes. Correct. Yes.
Yeah.
>> And I was wondering if that's been
calibrated. I'd like to know if that's
an integ. Let me let me do Sedona
method.
>> Uh Sedona method is over 480 485. About
480. Yeah,
>> it's very effective. That's a high level
of truth for Eddie.
>> Okay.
>> Very effective.
>> All right.
>> Thank you.
>> The only mistake to not make with that
>> what
>> come back here.
>> The only mistake to make not to make
with this.
>> Okay. Watch very carefully because the
downside of this is severe.
Love is not an attachment.
Don't confuse divine love which is a
quality of divinity with personal love.
So one part of that school is to
surrender and release on love as an
attachment.
You then end up flat
uncaring.
It's confusing divine love. You can't
refute love as a reality because it's a
quality of God.
>> Okay.
>> Personal love is an attachment, a
clingingness. See?
>> Mhm.
>> And
so surrender the attachment,
possessiveness at all. But don't denag
the value of perfection, beauty, love.
That's where he fell.
>> Okay.
>> All right. Done.
Otherwise, it's a good technique.
It It's a good technique. It's a good
technique. Good technique. Don't confuse
personal love and divine love. That's
the error. Otherwise, you end up in the
void.
We didn't get to the void yet, but we
will.
>> Yeah.
>> Um I'm just really pleased to be here.
It's the first time I've come to one of
your lectures as well. Um, my question
has been answered by the man that
approached the issue on fear. So, um,
maybe I'll just avail myself of a little
bit of that touch, healing touch.
>> Thank you.
>> Thanks very much,
>> Dr. Hawkins. It's a pleasure.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Thank you.
My question is um
>> my question is how do you uh suggest to
best transcend the mind and enter the
heart?
>> Well,
what you're asking is how do you get
from the 400s to the 500s?
Okay.
Okay. So to see that mentalization is a
construction.
It's linear. is limited
to not identify with it as who you are.
Huh? To value love as a higher
uh value
to transcend the dominance of the
intellect. 499 is formidable.
Only 4% of the human population
transcends level 500.
Eve and Einstein,
Newton,
great geniuses of time, got stuck at
499.
It's because it's a paradigm jump.
It's jumping from the out there to the
in here to the reality of subjectivity.
Let's say you're an atheist.
What gives it a sense of reality is your
conviction
that that is the truth. Therefore, it's
all things end up as subjective.
The difficulty is making a paradigm
jump.
Paradigm jump
from the out there describable linear
objectiveness
to the in here experiential.
If you love someone, you can't calibrate
it. You can't prove it. There's nothing
you can do about it.
And yet you die for it.
For the for love, for love, you give up
anything.
For love you give up your life.
There's two places in the lifeboat.
You give it
to that that you love.
Thank you.
>> What would you give up your seat in the
light bulb for? That's where you live.
The rest is where you think.
>> Yeah.
>> Dr. Hawin.
>> Uhhuh.
>> Uh I'm a member of a 12step group and uh
recently my sponsor of about seven years
passed away. Yeah.
>> And I was uh I've always suspected he
was had a pretty high level of
consciousness just because of how much
love he gave and everything and and
>> many become saintly.
>> I think he was uh very instrumental in
my pursuing spirituality and so forth.
>> I was just wondering if we if you would
calibrate his level of consciousness at
the time when he passed.
>> I don't want to do that. It's like a
personal invasion. However, I'll tell
you that uh he's at least 540
>> because AA is 540.
>> Yeah.
>> And once you become a sponsor and benign
and loving like that and cherished by
the group, so you could be maybe 450 I
mean 55 56 570.
>> Yeah. Because from 540 up are really the
levels of saintliness
and a person who really has 12step group
you know.
>> Yeah.
>> Somebody shoots up his whole family.
>> Yeah. This was real.
>> Yeah. And you're not allowed to hold a
resentment. There are no justified
resentments.
No justified resentments. Only a saint
can be that way as a reality. Well, you
learn it in aa because either you be
that way or you die.
It's amazing how fast you learn a thing
with a gun. Load a gun to your head.
>> Either get it or you die
>> slow and agonizingly.
So that that's saintly. 540 and up is
saintly. 540 and up is also the level of
u the cities. The miraculous begin to
happen. The inexplicable.
>> Uh
you're 100 miles from nowhere. Nobody
even knows that you're there. And your
car breaks down.
You look in the back, there's no jack.
Suddenly, your best friend from a group
you belong to once upon a time comes out
of nowhere, pulls up alongside and says,
"Hey, can I help you?"
From the viewpoint of logic, the
statistical chance of that is about, you
know, one in 10 million.
It's somebody who doesn't even know
you're there. shows up and just happens
to have a jack, you know, but that
starts to become continuous.
You're driving along and you need a
wrench to fix something or you can't
keep going and right to the side of the
road is a brand new wrench laying there.
Brand new, not used, brand new.
So once you live in that realm, you're
not even surprised. You see, oh, okay.
It's a so what
people in ordinary conscience would have
to tell everybody about this miracle and
this miracle. But when your life becomes
the continuous unfolding of miracles,
there's too many stories to tell. I
mean, you can't tell anybody what's
going on. They wouldn't believe it
anyway.
>> Okay.
>> All right. You're in the right realm,
right?
>> Yeah. We have to move now.
>> Don't worry about the time. I'll watch
it.
>> Yes.
>> Dr. Hawkins, thank you for your
teaching. Um, I'm a relative newcomer to
your teachings, so I had a lot of
questions, but I'll try to keep them to
a two-part one. I'm wondering if um,
babies are born with a high calibration,
>> put it
>> um, I mean, is it possible that babies
are born with a high calibration and
that wounds like shame pull it down?
And what wounds like shame pull pull
them down.
>> So wounds wounds. Yeah. I mean
>> like wounds like shame pull them down.
They're born born with a high
calibration but shame pulls them down.
Is that possible?
>> And then as they're healed their
calibration pops up.
>> You're really asking how variable is it?
>> Oh, it's not going to be uh that very
it's not going to be that vulnerable.
You see because it it changes. Everybody
is born with a calibrated level of
consciousness. That's one of the answers
to karma that how come everybody's born
with a different level of consciousness.
All right? And then that it's going to
this to move and then you have the
options of choice which move it up or
down. You see? Yes. You can alter it.
Mhm.
>> But like is it possible to alter it 100
points? Like can a
>> is it possible to what?
>> To to raise it 100 points of course. Can
you raise it to 300 through healing? And
then
>> the average person in a lifetime
advances consciousness about five points
per lifetime.
>> But it can jump.
>> That's stat statistical average. Yes.
But it could jump extremely high.
>> So my my other question was about the
same time I heard you speak, I heard
about quantum touch, the
>> I don't know that much about it.
>> A healing thing. So I wondered if you
could
>> it's it seems like when I've worked with
people
>> it's over 200 but I don't know where.
Well, what I'm wondering is is breath a
good tool? Breath a good tool for
raising your consciousness?
>> Breathing of the condominium is that a
good tool for brea you know for
breathing one's consciousness. the
breathing techniques that people
>> Oh yes yes yes yes that's that I can't
answer that so easily because it's like
who and when people who try to force the
condundalini energy uh often are damaged
by it because look at it the
condundalini energy flows up through the
chakra system based on the reality of
what you are
so why would you want to force it to
what you are not therefore you risk
what's called condundalini psychosis
this right
>> documented cases where too much
spiritual energy input you're not
prepared to handle it I remember a guy
sitting like an insane insane sound on
the floor raving to me that he is Jesus
Christ
theoretically yes he has a Christ body
but he did not really realize what he
was saying he think I don't believe in
forcing the condolini energy unnaturally
with weird breathing exercises. Some of
them are very bizarre. We saw one on
television the other night. You know,
he's flying up in the air and flopping
on his bottom and flying up in the air
and flopping on his bottom. I mean, you
calibrate that, it doesn't it's like 200
and something. And the only reason it's
200 something is because of his
intention. The exercise itself is
worthless.
You know,
if you if you do probably, you know,
You can induce an altered state of
consciousness, but it's not really who
you are. Spiritual evolution is what you
have become.
>> So when you're in a group or you're
doing something where the consciousness
is 500 or up, does everybody raise?
>> The field tends to Yes, the field tends
to lift everyone.
>> But is it temporary or does it stay
there?
>> As long as you stay aligned with the
field. Okay.
>> Not necessarily your physical presence.
>> Okay.
>> The minute a person in a 12step group
decides he can do it on himself and he
doesn't need the group anymore, he's
drunk.
>> He just lost it.
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> Yeah.
>> Couple of questions.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
Um,
in what way would you say total
surrender to the muscle test
is the same as total surrender to God?
>> In what way would you say what
>> is total surrender to the muscle test?
>> I don't surrender to the muscle test.
No,
>> cha faith and trust in the muscle test.
>> Oh, it's it's just a useful tool.
>> Yeah.
>> It's not divine, you know. It's a it's
contrasting the energy of a thing as
compared to the absolute see and it's
using life energy. It can't be re
replicated in mechanical terms because
protoplasm senses that which is
beneficial to it reaches for it and it
pulls back from that which is
adversarial to it. So it's using a life
energy just as a useful tool. Just a
tool.
>> Yeah.
Yeah, we don't recommend it. We say you
have to learn it. We don't say any of
that. It's just a tool we use to make
sure that our teachings are on the right
path.
>> So, you could also
>> we don't care if you use it or not. It's
not necessary. Just
>> it's just a useful tool.
>> But like an amoeba, you see, you could
use the amoeba test. You could classify
everything in your environment, whether
it makes the amoeba withdraw or whether
the the amoeba reaches forward.
That tells you something about which is
pro-life and that which is anti-life. At
least on the level of amoeba. Now you
can go up through the animal kingdom and
see that which is attractive, that which
is aversive. Pretty soon, if you
calibrate it, you'll have a pattern. You
recreate the map of consciousness.
>> No, I love the muscle test. This is just
evolution. I ask that question because
>> people keep saying it's a distraction.
>> Uh
>> it might be to some people.
>> Yeah. Well, yeah. Some people get caught
in the mechanics of things,
>> right?
>> It's the mechanics of things, you know.
>> So, the other question I got, if
sequence is rest in turn,
>> what?
>> Sequence.
>> Oh, yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. That's the
time tracking. Yeah.
>> Um and the thoughts come up like flying
fish out of the ocean.
They come up randomly. They do not come
up in sequence.
>> Sequence is is a is a mentalization to
superimpose on
>> according to the attractor field that we
are under the influence of.
>> Mhm.
>> So if we made it our intention to be
under the influence of the highest
truth.
>> Yes. The mind stops then.
So the sequence of our thoughts would
then be
>> they stop.
>> They would be not our thoughts.
>> They stop. There are no thoughts.
>> It would be like looking at a black.
>> First you first you say they're my
thoughts. Then you say they're the
thoughts. And then you find that
thinking this is happening because
you're getting a payoff out of it.
Entertainment and value is. And as you
withdraw that and surrender that to God,
the thoughts stop. Eyes blank.
This mind doesn't think unless you ask
it a question and then it turns on like
a TV set
>> but it does it of its own. I don't care
what it does.
>> So the only thing that
>> Why should I care what the mind does?
>> The only thing that puts it in sequence
is the mind.
>> Otherwise they come up randomly
like flying fish.
>> Randomness and sequence are both
mentalizations. Get rid of both of them.
>> Both of them.
It's
>> not either or.
You don't need to know it anyway.
>> That's a present. That'll be a dollar.
>> That's a
>> Yeah. Go ahead.
>> It's great to be here. This is my first
time. Um,
>> I read your book, uh, Power Versus
Force, and I was wondering if you could
explain a little bit more about when you
talked about people that were
calibrating at little higher and higher
levels above 200 that they experienced
the anguish of the soul, as you said in
your book,
>> and I was wondering if you could explain
that a little bit further by what you
meant.
>> What anguish?
>> Well, the term that you used was the
anguish of the soul. Like when people um
are experiencing higher levers levels of
these tractor fields and then come back
out of them.
>> Oh, when you drop. Yeah.
>> Yes.
>> The night of the darkness.
>> Yeah. When people crash. Sure. Because
the euphoria when you're when you're
over above your negative karma. Uh then
you're semi euphoric. Now that may bring
up now because you're powerful enough to
handle it. Now it pulls up the dreaded
that you have not wanted to look at. And
now you pe feel pulled down.
Oh,
why have thou deserted me? My beloved,
meaning Jesus Christ or the God. You
know, all it means is that you've earned
the right to face something even
heavier. You can only go as high as
you've been low.
So, it's always good to know if you feel
down that you can only go as high as you
can go down.
I know. So
>> yeah, you can only go as high as you
can.
>> Thank you very much.
>> Yeah, the the Christian saints, you
know, that's very well known amongst the
mystics.
>> When you say you can go as high as you
can go low, you mean uh relatively each
way. So if you go up 200 one way, you
can you can only drop down
>> well or whatever. But
>> that's just to make you feel better.
>> Okay. Thank Thank you very much.
Okay.
>> You know when you're you're feeling high
and then suddenly some horrible guilt
comes up. Something that you had, you
know, repressed comes up. Now suddenly,
oh my god, where did that come from?
Well, first of all, a stack gets
repressed in Freudian language,
suppressed and repressed. Plus, the
stacks pile up lifetime after lifetime.
So when you experience a loss, it isn't
this loss. It's the stack of losses. It
isn't this person's dying in your life.
It's all of them that have died in their
life. And that's so that stack comes up.
So like the young man who was talking
about fear. The fear that he's
experiencing is a bunch of stacks. So if
you want to sit out the fear and let it
run, it'll run out.
It could take weeks, months, days,
hours, who knows?
But all the fear of all the lifetimes is
is like in a compressed tank. Yeah. Go
ahead.
>> Hello. Um it's been a pleasure to be
here and um I have a question regarding
the angelic power.
The I was raised Rome Catholic back in
Poland and um I always had pictures of
guardian angels and I read I've read
your books. I've read about the 50,000
plus about archangels. Can you tell me
little bit more about angels?
>> Why do you care about angels? Worry
about who you are in the here and now.
>> Yeah.
>> And that's it.
That's
>> it's maidenesque and it's charming to
invoke the angels etc.
>> But you remain who you are. Huh?
>> Absolutely.
>> On the other hand, asking for divinity
in the form of angels, you're really
asking God.
You're really asking God who like a step
down transformer communicates better
with humans at that level we call
angelic. Yeah. But angels are also in
body. The gentleman up here from a
12step group, he was talking about
angelic people. And I've had angels come
stop and help me over and over in this
lifetime. And I remember asking with the
arm, "Was that an angel in a body?"
"Yes."
You think angels are all dead little
spirits flying around with flowers and
wings?
No, the angelic.
I was a million miles to nowhere when a
truck, in fact, I was in my truck and a
truck pulled over next to me. I was on a
terrible interchange. Not that, but I
had a plane to catch. Oh my god. Broken
down in the middle of an interchange. No
phone, no communication. All of a
sudden, a pickup truck stops and say,
"How can I help you?"
He took my tire off. He put it in his
pickup truck. He went to the nearest
exit, went to a station, had it fixed,
clover leaf back, clover leaf back, and
came over.
How do you explain that?
That was an angel. Resist
that completely answers.
There's angels here and now.
>> Yeah. They're not always in the earth.
>> I think they come in and out of body.
They come in and out of body.
>> Um I have no question. I just wanted to
um offer you a hug.
>> Yes. Thank you. No hugs. No hugs.
>> Cuz I've broken vertebrae. Yeah.
>> Thank you.
>> My vertebrae have turned to styrofoam
and therefore no hugs.
>> Okay.
>> However, they're getting stronger by the
day.
>> Pretty soon.
Pretty
pretty soon I'll have calcium toxicity
right over calcium. I
How was your bones? Pretty good.
First of all, thank you for being uh the
lighthouse
because uh it was hard not to know the
way out of hell. It was it was nice to
know the way out of Thank you for
pointing it out for us. I really
appreciate it personally and uh well I
wanted to to comment um when you were
talking about um people below 200 are
not aware of their existence. I uh I
belong to a 12step group and um
>> so what
>> 12step 12step?
>> Oh yes yes yes and um few months after I
started applying the spiritual um
principles to my daily life. I was in a
meeting and uh all of the sudden I was
very aware I I I just all of the sudden
be I become aware of my exist. I was
like, I am
>> there. You got it.
>> You got it.
>> I was like,
>> Po.
I was like raising my hand. Hey, I need
to share this.
>> We are.
>> They don't know what they won't know
what you're talking about.
>> I know. They were questioning my
sobriety.
We're like, I haven't smoked anything. I
swear you look mean
we are. I mean I am look
>> the source of the source of joy is is
innate as one's existence.
>> It's not dependent on anything.
>> Yeah. I was like that.
>> And I have a question. It's not for me.
I would like uh you if you want to say
anything to those because we are just a
very little uh group of uh students that
are they have the the the grace to be
exposed to the presence of the teacher.
Most of the the students are not able to
be exposed to the presence of the
teacher. They're they they can get the
material through tapes, through the
books, but they don't have the the um
the karmic
uh grace to be exposed to the presence
to the teacher. Would you say something
for them?
>> No.
>> Okay.
>> Say
>> when the time arises, the impulse
arises, the opportunity arises. You
know, I spent days with
uh Ramana let's see I spent time with
many of you know Matkananda and Ramish
Balsakar and various people see the
Karmapa various people like that see so
when you're attracted to it somehow the
opportunity arises and you feel
compelled to do that but having
completed that there's no compulsion to
see him again so if Ram is just back in
town I don't feel like I must quickly go
and say but But I remember the encounter
was right at the question level at 850
of whether existence and non-existence
are realities or perceptions.
We started out right there.
So that's funny cuz that's what I was
born with at age three.
>> Suddenly the awareness of existence was
the ultimate reality. existence or
nothingness.
Was the ultimate reality the void the
misunderstanding of the teaching of the
Buddha or was it allness
hit me at age three out of nothingness
that was the dilemma
and here many decades later I'm talking
to Rickar about it and the we open up
with that with each other
one time a person was in a lecture I was
giving and he'd been hopelessly alh
alcoholic. In the middle of the lecture,
his consciousness jumped 150 points. He
became sober, stayed sober.
I didn't know what had gone on with him.
And then 6 weeks later, a couple months
later, a truck pulls up, pickup truck to
the house or little house where I was
living. Backs up, he's got this
incredible table, a slab about this
thick. It was struck by lightning in the
top of Mingus Mountain. He saved it for
50 years. You know, his family, somebody
saved it 50 years. this incredible table
weigh a ton. I still have it. It's right
in the middle of the living room. And in
there in Sanskrit,
he's got written allness and nothingness
in Sanskrit.
I never related such a story at all. You
know, there was nothingness and allness.
There was nothingness and allness at age
three. There was nothing in allness.
when you get hit with the ultimate
realization is nothingness and wholeness
coming up spontaneously with remission
but also so those things are not within
conceptual explanation you know
>> thank you very much and last thing um I
know that broccoli has been rising
her level of consciousness really fast
right why don't you just for the sake of
the conscious iousness of humanness.
Adopt a bunch of us and
we're there.
>> I'm going to excuse myself for a second
in All right. If that happens, Susan
will feed you little pieces of cheese.
I'll be right back.
>> Thank you so much. We love you.
Okay. So, we're we're done. I know.
>> What happens to us? Anything?
>> Yeah, we turn we are cintiggrated.
>> Okay, we're going.
Okie do. Quick question. It hit me at
one year old that our true reality
is a pure happiness and peace and joy.
>> Yes.
>> And
I've been asking myself since
why are we dreaming about being less
than what is the truth?
>> Why you're believing?
>> Why are we dreaming? mean she says um
you know are true uh
>> about being less than what is the truth
of the
>> other words happiness and joy and is
what meant for us
>> I wouldn't say that is dreaming that's
only a style of presentation of spir
is not based on reality which I agree
yeah
>> so why why are we
>> because the evolution of the the ego the
dominion of the ego
which thinks like an animal.
>> Mhm.
>> Thank you.
>> Because the spiritual reality has not
superseded the animal consciousness
completely.
The linear still tends to predominate
and the reality is in the nonlinear
dimension.
Okay. So as you relinquish the belief
in the reality of the linear
then you see that the reality is the
nonlinear and that the only reality the
linear has is the presence of the
nonlinear within it.
>> Thank you.
I couldn't remember if I had my four
point.
>> Okay, we'll move right along.
>> I think I took it. I don't remember.
Yes,
>> thank you for being here and staying
around. I have a question onology.
>> I I work with in the office. I work with
people their beliefs and their
their upsets and and I use your map of
consciousness to see where when they
tell me a story, I say, "Okay, let's see
where your projection is. Where are
you?" And then I'll use your map to get
and then takes them a while to see it's
really their projection, but they are
getting it. But I do have a question
with the muscle testing. I've heard
people and I tried it in the office and
I'm also getting that same answer.
Sometimes they'll ask on a conscious
level, subconscious, body and soul level
and they'll get different answers for
each of those levels.
>> Why do you want to differentiate them?
>> I Well, I just do this is what I usually
do.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay. My question is because I've seen
other kinesiologists do this. I want to
understand if they're getting answers.
What is that about?
>> Sharing too close to my
>> Okay.
>> What is your question?
>> What three levels are you asking about?
>> A conscious level, subconscious, body
and soul.
>> Conscious.
>> Oh yeah. Why do you want to do that
then?
>> Why are you asking those different
levels?
>> Okay. my practice, I don't usually ask
on those different levels. Okay.
>> Okay. But I've seen people do that. Oh,
yeah.
>> And they'll get answers and I
>> You'll get a different
>> I don't know. I never did it that way.
>> When you ask them different questions,
you're going to get different answers.
>> Yeah. Because the impact of the
intention is to bring forth a different
answer. Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. What is your
question? I still don't get what's the
question.
>> But she's seen people use it that way.
Is that a proper way to use it?
>> I don't I never do it that way. No.
Couldn't tell you. And why are they
getting answers?
>> You're when you
>> because they'll get four different
answers.
>> When you ask a question about
kinesiology,
>> it answers one question. So when you
divide it up into four different
questions, you're going to get four
different answers and four different
response.
>> So what you need to ask rather than
dividing it up like that is in the
highest good is this da da which is what
you should do. One question not. Yeah.
And I just came across this a couple
weeks ago and I wanted to get clarity
what it could
>> I wouldn't get into it.
>> Okay.
>> Because it's just
>> it's hard enough to handle the simple.
Most people can't know the simple much
as the complicated,
>> right? Cuz it confused me and it and it
didn't feel right. But I saw this
people, you know, they were getting
answers and I wanted
>> I was going to get answers.
>> Well, it's within their own context, you
know. So within their own context, it's
probably meaningful. You know what I'm
saying?
>> Okay.
>> Mhm.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah. It's like Fahrenheit compared to
centigrade within its own paradigm. It's
meaningful.
>> First of all, always ask if you can ask
the question. Second, then ask, is this
for the greatest good?
>> Oh, yeah. That's
>> the only thing you have to know.
>> Okay. We got to hustle before they're
going to kick us out. We get fined for
every minute. We're over.
>> Yeah.
>> All right. My question is probably a
pretty easy one. Um,
my question has to do with when you're
in a like a sator experience, have you
temporarily transcended the 110,000th of
a second that
uh the experiencer is on?
>> Very likely. So,
>> okay.
>> Mhm.
>> Okay.
>> The only trouble is when you open your
eyes and walk around now, it disappears.
So, that
>> Well, what if you're like walking in the
forest like you said or at a park and
like kind of the birds start moving
slowly?
>> Mhm. But it
it didn't really stay there though like
uh
>> you know it last it last
>> you may stay there sir.
>> Okay.
>> He may stay there.
>> Just be thankful for the experience.
>> Oh yeah.
>> Just being bliss to stay there.
>> Yeah. I understand. Okay. I was just
curious if that's if that's what you
were talking about.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Okay.
>> Yeah. That's it. See the
>> once you have that kind of experience,
you're destined for it. So don't worry
about it. Come on.
>> Yeah, we have to hustle quick quickly.
>> You mentioned that patient you sent to
the Mayo Clinic who had intractable or
or lead brain. Well, I work at the
clinic. I don't think they would have
been able to help him, but
>> no. He had a chronic chronic state of
dysphoria.
>> Yeah.
>> Chronic dis dysphoria.
In his whole life, he had one day in
which he felt happy. One day. and he was
like 80 something, late 70s. One day he
experienced what it is to feel normal.
Never since and never before.
>> There you are.
>> We tried everything on this planet.
We're up against a karmic brick wall. I
think
>> you mentioned that you had nine times
the success of your colleagues as a
physician. Now, how can I how
>> No, I'm saying that yes, the the
experience of recovery
>> with the same chemical,
>> right? Yeah.
>> How can I bring intention into my
practice?
>> Pray for
>> Oh, yes. You bring every spiritual
awareness. You know, the clinic back
east, we had AA groups on the premises.
We gave free B12 shots to all of them.
We had course of miracles groups.
Uh we did everything we could
um you know to bring about a recovery.
So the recovery was also the consequence
of the context. The context of the field
was also was non-judgmental. We
specialize in schizophrenia,
>> right?
>> In those days, they blame schizophrenia
and poor parenting. So, they hit the
whole family with guilt and all the
strife and you know,
>> and we said, "No, it's a genetic defect
of brain neurochemistry."
>> Wow. That alleviated guilt right away.
>> And the cure of it, you know, is to
shift the brain chemistry. So we use
mass action to try and force the
chemical chemical neurotransmitters into
a healthier and falling and I wrote you
know book earth molecular
>> sky right
>> and the idea was to straighten out the
disorder of the brain mole. So we said
that it was a molecular problem.
>> Well, that was the high point of
psychoanalysis. And I myself was a
psychoanalyst and went through classical
psychoan analysis and I'm still a great
enthusiast for the right patient. It's
for neurosis, not for schizophrenia. So
>> they were trying psychoanalytic forian
theory was schizophrenia. Well,
schizophrenia is genetically
biochemical. It's got nothing to do
with, you know, your edible complex.
Mhm.
>> And neurosis has plenty to do with your
complex but not schizophrenia.
>> Yeah.
>> Well, I shall remember that we are
having meditation groups at the Mayo
Clinic, so there's some shift happening.
I can I can see it. So, it's nice. Thank
you so much.
>> I wish I could give you a hug, but never
mind. You charge you charged me a dollar
last year for that.
>> You don't remember it.
>> Thank you.
>> Yeah. Okay, we got to hustle quick
festival.
>> Hey, Doc.
>> Yeah. First of all, I just want to let
you know I love and appreciate you.
>> Thank you.
>> Okay. Good. Good.
>> Um, my question is I have had some
experiences, memories, um, of what I
assume have been past lives.
>> And most of them have been fairly
spiritual, simple lives.
>> And there's this one though that's just
obviously below 200.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Um, and it appears to be the most recent
one that I remember.
And I was just, my wife and I one time
just for fun was doing some muscle
checking and we started to check to see
possibly where some of these things
were. And so I thought, well, I'll just
check and see where I came into the life
and where I went out. And it appeared if
the muscle checking was accurate that
the drop took place outside of body.
Um,
>> so inner planes, huh? Well, it
>> was a big drop, too.
So is that is that a common thing?
>> I don't know that it's common because I
haven't reached that researched that
specifically.
Big drops are certainly very frequent
within the body. So I'm presuming and
when you're out of body it would also be
an option in other realms, you know.
>> Okay.
>> Anyway, you're back and breathing and
happy again.
>> Absolutely.
>> Get in there. Good fight. Bring it.
Yeah.
>> Um, I feel like I'm here on borrowed
time, so I just get to the point. Um,
I abandoned Christianity many years ago
because of a lot of conflicts that I saw
in the factual data that was represented
in the uh Old Testament and the New
Testament.
>> And I've always kept track of the uh
updates in in in with respect to the
life of Christ. And I'm finding that
there's a significant amount of data or
information out there that contradicts
everything that is actually represented
in in those books. Uh you know the
resurrection everything else. Now my
question is isn't it better to
the books he's talking about? I have
permission cal over 200 resist. You're
wasting a lot of time. I know what
you're talking about.
>> Okay. That being the case, um,
>> can I ask you
>> straight to point?
>> That's it. Um,
>> well, I'm curious about a guru up in the
Northwest called Rotha.
>> Can you tell cali Have you ever
calibrated the teacher?
>> I don't want to get into other teachers.
No,
>> you wouldn't.
>> No.
>> Darn. Okay.
We that
>> I I uh I delineated during the lecture
the characteristics of spiritual
integrity and purity. I that covered it,
didn't it?
>> I thought that was great. And
>> so I answered your question. I answered
your question.
>> You did.
>> All right. So don't ask me again.
>> I will. Okay.
Uh but will that list be available in
the book? Your book?
>> Yes. That is published in the book.
Yeah.
>> Oh, great.
>> Yeah,
>> because I didn't write them down and
then I realized we weren't going to get
them. Well, you you get a sense of it,
you know, from what you heard. You've
already got a sense of it.
>> Yes.
>> Nothing to gain.
>> You know what I'm saying?
>> Yeah.
>> Because that which is fully realized is
complete and totally all there is. What
is there to gain?
>> So you watch the downside is somebody's
ego looking to be fed and you get
sensitive and once you pick it up, you
pick it up.
>> Sure.
>> Okay. thing.
>> Yeah, we have to We got three minutes
left.
>> We only have three more.
>> I know. I know. I know.
>> Yeah. Faster. Faster.
>> Well, he signed his face.
>> Yes. Yes. What is this?
>> Sign your face.
>> This is My god. Where'd that come from?
>> This is Science of Mind. This is
Religious Science magazine. And
>> I never saw this.
>> You never saw this.
>> How wonderful. Get us one.
>> I will. I'll get you one. I'll send it
to you soon. Hey, look. There's yours
truly by God on the front of this man.
>> Science and mind. Oh yeah.
>> Yeah. I gave a lecture there few weeks
ago. Reverend Bob Henderson.
>> Wonderful.
>> Yeah. Go ahead.
>> Church.
>> I just came to look into your wonderful
eyes. You're such a gem. And I was
in Walmart just before I came from
Albuquerque. And we have a group there
called Hot for Hawkins.
>> It's a great group and we watch your
tapes and we
>> Yeah. I've been a defender of Walmart.
>> I've been a defender of the vilification
of Walmart. See, you know.
>> Well, well, anyway, I was there.
>> Yeah. And I looked at these things and
you popped into my mind and I knew I had
to bring it to you.
>> Oh,
>> and it's a new toy for you or for your
ego. I don't know which.
>> Isn't that right?
He's a magician. Yay!
>> Thank you, sweetheart.
>> How do you make it stop?
>> I love these toys.
>> That's a great one.
>> Thank you so much for waiting to take my
question. If a person is diagnosed with
an untreatable physical condition that
causes pain and is it better to put your
intention into healing or accepting it?
>> Physical, mental, and spiritual. You do
everything on all level. You do the
course of miracles, you do what you can
physically, psychologically
uh and whether it's going to heal or
not. If you do the course of miracles
correctly, it's irrelevant
>> whether it heals or doesn't heal.
>> It's like you're going to die. You're
going to die. So,
>> what's to be excited?
>> Okay. Thank you.
>> That's really the cutest thing.
>> Unreal.
>> Question. Dr. H. Just wanted to say
thank you very much for your question
today. Thank you.
>> Thank you for thanking me.
>> Okay. You have to get up.
>> That's it.
>> All right. Give it get up and sing your
little glass piece.
>> That's it.
>> Oh, God. What a blessing it is to be
here.
And by that with which is within me do I
bless thee
and love you forever.
We are really one and as I said we've
swooped in
before
in and out and here we are again. Yeah.
So it's my great my great blessing God's
gift to me is all of you. Amen. Thank
you Lord.
Nobody wants to leave.
>> Nobody wants to leave.
>> It's okay to breathe again.
Thank you so much.
Hallelujah.
Hallelu.