Thank you for watching.
The average human being has had more than eight prior human lifetimes, more than ten, more than twelve.
Anyway, a bunch.
You see, the minute you reincarnate, the minute you incarnate, you go into a ninja about it.
But the question I have is, for a group like this, that's come a long way, would the average number be higher?
Does it take a lot of lifetimes?
I don't know.
I don't see why it would be.
But the number is about the same for a group such as this.
Yeah, it's just they make better use of it.
Okay.
Thank you.
We take advantage of it, see.
It's a rare karmic opportunity.
And so we don't want to waste it.
We want to use it to the best advantage for oneself and for all of life.
Thank you.
Okay.
Yeah.
I really don't have a question.
All that I wanted to do is I wanted to acknowledge both you and Susan for the beauty of your lives
and for the gift of truth that you brought through for all of us.
Thank you so much.
Thank you.
Hello.
Hi.
My question is about the dream state while sleeping.
I seem to spend a lot of time dreaming.
And I just don't know what to make of the whole thing.
To ignore it or take up drinking or just forget it or what?
What do you learn anything from it?
Seems to.
They can be quite lucid, almost like living other lives.
Or I don't know.
I don't know if it's imagination or what's going on.
Well, in psychoanalysis, I can tell you the value of dreams from various things.
You know, in psychoanalysis, it was a critical part.
And also in ego analysis in which you associate to it, you know.
And I see Harry Thiebaud.
And Thiebaud was probably the world's expert on the ego and its unconscious representations.
And I'd have a dream about scratching, you know, chicken scratching.
And he'd say, well, how does the ego feel about scratching for a living?
Oh, I said the ego hates it.
So he interpreted everything from the viewpoint of the ego.
The purpose of that was to increase one's understanding of the unconscious ego, which was a rare opportunity.
Unfortunately, he never wrote any.
He finished and never wrote a book about it.
But he wrote some very, Harry Thiebaud wrote some very critical papers, you know, the critical value of surrender.
The value of surrender.
And because of that understanding, he furthered the reach of 12-step movement, you know.
So you can associate to it.
And, you know.
You can ask divinity to reveal to you what you should be learning from the phenomena.
You know, so through prayer, I would say, you know, what, is this of any value?
And is there, you know, something I should be seeing about myself?
Yeah.
Okay.
Well, thank you.
Dr. Hawkins, I'd like to thank you very, very much.
Yes.
I was here in June of last year.
And I was having problems with some lingering character defects.
And at that time, you told me that if I went and worked step three,
Sabbath.
and 11 very extensively it might help and it did thank you very much I took an
opportunity to bring something to you this is out of print it's out of print
it's hard to get anymore yes so I ordered this for you and I wanted to
give it to you thank you thank you oh and I ran it digitized it for you oh
DVD thank you cool and I was wondering if you could tell me the calibrations of
the movie the calibration of what of the movie I don't have a recollection of
movie but I'll look at the image this coverage over 450 500 525 15
so I'm going to leave that out for you okay if you're going to go to the video
520 over 500 lovingness of some kind and the sacredness of life thank you I don't
know what it's about
I don't know what it's about
I pray I spent practically no time watching movies and watch nature channel history channel
history was boring when I was young and now I find it fascinating because just so you can
contextualize it differently you see the evolution of consciousness and its various expressions and
now it's fascinating whereas when it's a kid memorizing dates it was ultra boring
you
when was the war of 1812 geez I don't know I just want to take this opportunity to thank both you
and Susan for everything that y'all have shared and also to ask you is there anything that I or
collectively we could as a group do for either you Susan or the institute oh I tell you we're
we're complete and total yes our life is spent in a sort of joy
you
uh and just our own existence and what we do and your appreciation adds to our
appreciation of the work yes thank you very much thank you for it the gift of your knowledge
I keep telling people I don't need anything and I don't want anything and they keep sending me
things
that's funny
thank you for the privilege of being here today yes what is the straight and
narrow path and what are some of the windy roads that spiritual seekers
caught on or the tourist attractions well we cover that in the two books that
I'm finishing at right finishing two books same time transcending levels and
devotional non-duality the traps along the way are numerous and therefore
I've tried to describe them at each level what was the question what is the
straight now oh straight narrow path yes is to bypass the the seductive allure of
distractions because that which is not aligned with the truth sees the truth as
an enemy and sees you as a spiritual devotee as one of them
therefore
to captivate you with magic and the occult magical powers Unseen entities
etc. the astral circuits so the purpose of
much of that is merely to take you off the pathway the seduction of the allure. so in the writing
by the name Dr. Lamy of Dекторia on the Light of hermanite pictures.
might be slightly later so if you have any questions contact there in the chat room if possible if your computer is no longer active its okay and I hope that so much of the information is Tristan will help you I am much gerneciate your time in the conversation. thank you for your conversation this is Chris different from a celibacy you may do not consult the call folk interviews firement one of you it is not appropriate energy for Lesley that went too long isso way do not create any Sprit with어서 clinical choices let me make这就回事了
what we've done is define the straight and narrow, which is to refuse the
temptations of the ego, see, and its juice, its satisfaction. So that is really the
straight and narrow. To negate the allure and the attraction of the linear. As
people evolve, each level has its attractions, which we've mentioned. Today
we talked about the Trappity, you know, at 850, the void. We talked about the fact
that when you get to be in the mid to higher 500s, you become very
attractive erotically to people. And many, as the Guru has fallen into seduction,
and therefore the people misinterpret spiritual love as personal love. The
seduction of power over others,
controlling other people's lives, wealth and fame, having lots of followers, and all
that stuff. So to negate the juice of the, you see, the way to become a renunciate,
a true renunciate doesn't necessarily have to escape from the world. Instead,
renounces the ego gain and satisfactions and the juice. The true renunciation is
internal.
It can be demonstrated externally as a change of lifestyle. You're saying to the
world when you shave your head and wear sandals and join a retreat center and
and eat nothing but potatoes and turnips that you have, you know, refused the world.
But that's sort of a demonstration. The refusal is the refusal of the
temptation now. See? A true renunciate walks about the earth the same as
everyone.
But renounces vanity, pride, pride of being right, you know. So you renounce the
temptations of the ego. And of course their projections into the world get
renounced. So a true renunciate doesn't have to avoid the world. You can walk and
participate in the world because you've already refused its attractions and its
allures, you know.
Thank you, sir.
Neither attraction nor aversion is what defines freedom.
I didn't really have a question. I just have a lot of gratitude.
Yes.
And I just wanted to hold your hand.
Thank you so much.
Yeah, just one minute.
.
How fortunate it is that somebody wants to hold your hand. Think of all the people.
I started to sing this song but you wouldn't have appreciated it.
.
. . .
That's correct.
By the grace of the teacher, you are correct, yes.
That's traditional, yes.
It's because it's a non-linear frequency in a vibration.
And when you reach advanced states, they're non-linear.
So anything you've read, the mind is silent.
There's nothing you can recall from memory that you were taught.
The mind's a blank.
And yet you're faced with the biggest decision throughout your whole existence.
At that point, a knowingness comes out of nowhere.
To walk straight ahead, all fear is illusion.
It comes as a knowingness.
You don't remember that.
And that's the grace?
It's a knowingness that arises out of the frequency of the vibration
of what you've picked up over some lifetimes.
It could be 20 lifetimes ago.
But somewhere you picked up the frequency and the vibration of that in your aura.
And when it's needed, it comes forth with a knowingness.
Thank you.
You see, that knowingness has to come from absolute conviction.
The conviction has to be absolute.
Absoluteness can only be conveyed by that which has walked through it,
walked through the hail and walked out the other side.
So it can't be gotten out of oblivion.
Because it can only be gotten by that which has survived it.
Yeah.
The value of 12-step groups is the sponsor is one who's walked through it
and come out the other side.
The rest you can read out of a book.
Most people who go to those meetings have already read the book.
The book didn't do it.
But when somebody stands there who's lived through it,
then they have the power.
And from them you get the power.
And therefore, you give it to the same power to the next.
So that's the value of the sponsor, the mentor, you know,
one who's lived it.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Go ahead.
Ha, ha, ha.
I think I'll take my shoes off.
Hi, Dr. Hawkins.
I'm curious, when you bless food or people or anything for that...
Wait, wait, wait.
Oh, I'm sorry.
Okay, start again.
You said something?
Dr. Hawkins, I'm curious, when you bless food or people or anything for that matter,
what technique do you use and how do you suggest that we would bless things and people?
I look at it with love and gratitude.
Gratitude and consciously thank God for the gift.
Yeah.
Oh, you bless it in the name of,
you bless the food in the name of God for gratitude?
Because, you know, blessed food,
the consciousness calibration of the food itself
jumps 15, 20 points.
So before you feed your kitty,
you're supposed to bless the kitty's food.
Okay.
God bless this kitty's food, oh Lord.
Our cat's clairvoyant already, so.
If you keep blessing her food every day,
365 days a year, you can see,
she's starting to walk on water.
Yeah.
And gratitude, you know, itself, bless this, you know,
to be grateful for one's life, you see.
You're the steward of your own life and its assets.
So there's nothing wrong with being rich and powerful at all.
Yeah, as long as you accept it with the humility
that now this is your responsibility
to be the rich king, to be whatever.
You see, one of the most famous successful men
in our society,
the whole society, you know,
gave $26 billion to charity.
$26 billion to charity.
Wow, that's more than the whole output
of some whole country's $26 billion.
So out of gratitude,
he tries to pay back to society
in some way, you know.
Yeah?
Thank you, doctor.
Thank you, Susan.
College dropout at that, $26 billion.
Who was that?
Remember, he dropped out of Harvard.
Oh.
Yeah.
I can't think of names right now, you know, I mean.
The Scottish guy.
No.
The Scottish guy or Microsoft?
The computer fellow.
The Microsoft guy, Bill Gates.
Bill Gates.
Huh?
Bill Gates?
Gates, yeah, yeah, Bill Gates.
Can I hold this?
Yeah.
Bill Gates.
Can I hold your hand?
You may, yes.
When, at the beginning, when you came down
and you were shaking people's hands.
Yes.
And when you came near me, I just started to cry
and I couldn't stop crying.
Yes.
And I was wondering, why was I,
and then you were talking the rest of the time,
I couldn't even hardly listen, all I could do was cry.
And I was wondering what that,
what was going on for me
or what was going on for me.
Well, that's common, yeah.
There's a certain level of consciousness
where you cry all the time.
Monasteries are used to that, convents.
You reach a certain level of lovingness
and you cry all the time.
And I remember going through that stage
and I would see a couple in the airport look at each other,
just a loving glance, and it would just break me up.
The tears would come up.
Well, of some kind of joy, you know, it's like joy, yeah.
The energy.
The energy field of love makes you weep, you know.
I remember in Scotland at the Tattoo, you know,
when they played a certain song, it was incredibly beautiful,
a hundred bagpipes playing at once,
everybody in the audience crying.
The whole audience crying.
18,000 people all crying at once, you know.
Because you hit the heart of humanity, the heart of man.
You access the heart of man, you know, see.
Yeah, and everybody weeps, you know, mm-hmm.
Thank you.
Your books are getting heavier, you know.
She says we should make smaller books so they don't weigh so much.
Hi.
And talking about respect for all creation.
Yeah.
You know, I find myself, you know, thinking about, you know,
myself, I'll find an ant or a spider in the house,
and I walk the little guys outside so they'll be happy,
and I'll be happy.
The other day I saw a carpenter ant come across my wooden house floor.
A what?
Carpenter ant.
Yes.
So this is not an extermination question,
but it does seem that when you're talking about respect for creation,
calling in an exterminator to kill the guys does seem a little unkind.
That's his karma, yeah.
Okay.
So I guess the question would be what does that mean to my karma?
Death is an illusion.
Death is not a possibility.
Life can only change form.
So you change it out of this form here and it'll instantly emerge elsewhere.
The energy field, the energy of life cannot be extinguished through this.
You cannot extinguish life.
So you didn't kill anybody.
I didn't kill anybody.
Okay.
Thank you.
He was bored.
Just think of all the excitement.
He gets reborn in a better house with more crumbs.
Crumbs.
Ants love crumbs.
Is enlightenment a possibility from the inner planes?
Yes.
possible on other planes, then it wouldn't be good fortune to be born a
human. It would be bad fortune, wouldn't it? Yeah. There's no incentive because you're
surrounded with identity, that which is exactly like yourself. You have no option.
How can you reject temptation if you're not surrounded by any?
I just want to give thanks, first of all, for my, on behalf of my daughter because
she now has
a daddy who can answer a lot of questions that I never would have been
able to answer before thank you and I found out about power versus force a
number of years ago just as I entered medical school and power versus force oh
yes yes and I've been using clinical kinesiology in my practice yeah about
March I read for the first time eye of the eye followed by I followed by truth
versus falsehood and since then I've listened to 2004 tapes and 2005 I think
I'm up to date
but it's bad you bet
and
thank you I've been a good student I hope watching in contemplating in the
morning about the field of consciousness and that it's timeless without any it's
nonlinear you then have always calibrated the group here okay
but I'm sitting in my home in
Connecticut listening to the tape that you're calibrating so the question is am
am i part of that calibration when you do it if you're here at the time yeah if
you were your at the time because if if in fact that I'm part of the calibration
than what you said before about no then the question would have to be
contextualized different right oh I saying I say text Celeste differently so
sometimes the reason you get different numbers is you're contextualizing it
differently. So so-and-so is an author calibrated so, so-and-so is a father
calibrated so, so-and-so is a spiritual student calibrated so. So you have to, if you
want accuracy and consistency, you have to contextualize it in the
context of so-and-so. I understand. At the end you were talking about how this
group as a whole is affecting the, uplifting the consciousness, so
really, I guess I'm trying to understand that maybe the tapes themselves, by the fact that...
Well you as a group, yes, I see what you're saying. Yes, no, as a student of a certain teacher you
identify yourself as part of that teacher's group, see. And the teacher has a
responsibility to you, see, so I feel like I have a responsibility to every reader,
every participant, you know, every...
That's excellent. Can I ask one more question?
And the teacher has a responsibility to you, see, so I feel like I have a responsibility to every reader, every participant, and every...
So growing up there was one prayer that I always learned to pray, comes from
Exodus, thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, with all thy soul, and
all that might, alright, it goes on. You know this prayer? Yes. What, do you know what the
calibration, or could you calibrate that for me? Because there's a lot of different parts to it. You want just
this part.
Well, if I have something in mind...
No tricks, what is it you want to tell me?
As a whole, that's all, because it's a long, alright.
I can only do this particular verse.
Okay, just the verse, okay.
Um...
Thou shalt teach,
teach it diligently to thy children.
Huh? Thou shalt teach it diligently to thy children.
Teach what?
To love God with all your heart, all your soul, and all your mind.
Yeah, okay, we have permission to calibrate that. That calibrates over 700, 800, 900, 860, 870, you know,
calibrates high.
Thank you.
Devotion to God is the most high, you know, that's why I like the 91st Psalm, see, for the same reason.
Those who commit themselves to God, then belong to God,
and are under the protection of God, and Krishna said the same thing, so it comes from various sources.
Divinity knows its own, uh-huh.
Divinity knows its own.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Many of the verses in the 91st Psalm, I lived through the reality of them, including stepping over the adder.
Miraculous.
Yeah.
Thank you very much, Dr. Hawkins, for sharing your energy with us.
Yes.
You're a part of many books that I've been reading for the last year that brought me where I am now.
There's a few questions I'd like to ask you today.
The first one is, I know you talked about the vibration.
I vibrate a lot when I'm at State, or even if I go to the bathroom on the shower.
And I've been doing this for a year now, and I'm saying, when is it going to end?
Probably a couple more years, you know.
Yeah, all right, let's see.
What I'm holding in mind is what it is, okay.
And its duration is problematic, yeah.
You know, its duration is problematic.
The flow of the kundalini energy, you know, manifests itself in a variety of ways, you know.
Some people have insomnia, some people go into a high state, paranormal phenomena begin to appear, and it's variable.
They last for a period of time.
They arise in the mid-500s and last for, well, in this case, for years, actually, in various forms.
The shaking itself is something you can just keep.
You keep surrendering to, and it'll go away.
The shaking goes away.
But the miraculous begins to, tends to recur.
And in the beginning, it's a novelty, and after a while, it's the way the world is.
Yeah, I learned to accept it.
And it's the people around me that say, what is he doing?
Well, pay no attention to them, and keep it to yourself.
I never tell anybody any of these things until I wrote about it.
It's something.
I don't want to tell anybody any of this stuff.
And it's a little bit of a mystery.
Yeah, but, you know, like, in a room like this, it'll start happening.
I'll just sit there, and I just, I'll have my eyes open, and I'll just start doing it.
Yeah, that's the way it is.
Yeah, that's right.
That's like that.
Okay.
That's why there's not too many black people in the world.
The second question I would have is, this happens more and more now, and I'd like to know, just to let, I'd let it go anyway, but I'm reading a book, and time would stop.
And it's like I'm watching a TV, but it's not this reality.
So.
You're having visions of it.
Yeah, it's like a movie is playing, and then suddenly I come back to my vision.
That's inner visionary.
Yes, okay.
I just let it go, and that's it?
Yeah, yeah, enjoy the movie.
You don't have to pay a ticket.
But what do I make of it?
Is it something that's going to happen, or what is it like?
No, don't try.
I see what you're trying to do.
It's editorialized about the phenomena that you're witnessing.
Yes.
And experiencing, instead of just witnessing them and experiencing them.
Okay.
You're presuming that you can elaborate about them.
Don't elaborate about them.
It is what it is.
And then you'll transcend it eventually, and then you'll transcend what appears next.
It just is what it is.
Perfect.
Thank you very much, sir.
Thank you.
We're going to get a new kind of microphone that doesn't look like a whisker here.
Hi.
I always thought it would be fun to be a kid and have whiskers.
Wouldn't that be fun, to have whiskers out there?
Pick up the vibration or whatever?
Okay.
My question has to do with doubt.
Disbelief, though I can't figure out how to ask the question.
There have been these experiences.
There's what?
There have been spiritual experiences that, once I wake up, they didn't happen in sleep,
but once I wake up in the morning, I'm just in complete doubt and disbelief.
About what?
About the validity that they occurred.
While you were asleep?
No.
Like the next day.
Like the more time that goes on, the more confused I get,
and the more disbelieving I am in the occurrences.
But if I'm willing to accept the occurrences,
then I fear that I'm tricking myself into believing something that didn't happen.
What do you mean by an occurrence?
For instance?
The most intense energy vibration imaginable that seems to obliterate the body and the mind.
Yes.
Anyway.
Okay.
There's doubt.
Doubt that you're nothing?
The obliteration of linear definition of yourself as linear and limited and circumscribed
is replaced by that which is non-linear and more universal.
Therefore, you merely meditate on that and has God revealed to you the significance of that?
That which you are is more than the linear ego.
It's the infinite non-linear presence which obliterates the identification of self in its customary form.
Mm-hmm.
please speak why are you crying because I'm worried that I'm not crying I'm
recreating stop crying so we can please tell me what it is you want to know stop
the crying okay got no time right now for crying tell me what it is you want
to know I can't no it wasn't it wasn't it was I wasn't asleep it was just sort
of contemplating it the next day there's this focus and then it seems like the
focus and this just massive energy just like merged yeah and then there's just
um
uninform you go from forum to nonform
you got to stop crying now if you want to
talk otherwise you can have to move on
okay stop the crying the power exercise
the power control it's no time for the
child to be coming up as the adult what
are you asking me is there is there a
reality basis for that phenomena my
understanding of the
is that your conception, definition of yourself,
experience of yourself is linear.
It now comes up the alternate of the non-linear.
You're not circumscribed.
The idea of that which you are becomes obliterated
by a non-linear. Is that correct?
Yes.
Then why worry about it?
That's what the lectures are all about.
Dismissed. Case dismissed.
She has a premonition, yeah, a premonition
that the eclipse of the ego
is only a matter of time.
The question is,
I've been doing that thing where you feel pain
and you increase it.
You try to get it to come out more or whatever.
Which gets pretty painful.
But,
lately I've been getting sensations
like tightness in the chest or something
and I'll go into that while I'm meditating
and I'll increase that
and it seems to come up into the throat
and kind of get lodged in the throat.
It isn't necessary to increase it, no.
It's only necessary to not resist it.
And not say anything about it.
Not define it.
It's only experience,
it's just a sensual sensation.
If you stop resisting it,
it will leave a specific area.
You'll know that you've stopped resisting it
because it becomes generalized in your whole aura.
You trip and you feel like you've sprained your ankle.
It's in your ankle.
As you let go of resisting it,
the pain becomes diffuse.
It's like your whole aura experiences it.
And therefore you surrender to whatever that is
without calling it pain.
Or any other label.
And as you do, you finally disappear it.
Then you walk up and stand up and walk away.
Okay.
Well, it seems like when I'm doing it,
I might be doing it wrong,
but it comes up and it comes up into the throat.
Yeah.
And it'll stay there for a little bit
and then I will cough pretty violently.
And then I get a sensation
kind of like I'm getting knocked out.
You know, like I don't feel the body.
I think sometimes the body twitches and stuff.
But I just get really real...
I don't even know if it's...
It's not numb, but it's more like tingly.
And I don't know if I'm really healing.
Yeah.
So is this some energy you're resisting,
in other words, what you're saying?
No, like something...
You're getting it caught in your throat?
Yeah.
Well, like something will come up,
like a tightness in my chest.
Well, you can try breathing the energy
up to the crown chakra.
Try that next.
Yeah, that's what I'm doing.
And it kind of gets stuck here.
And then I'll cough.
You got it in the throat.
I said the crown chakra.
Okay, but when it kind of gets stuck in here
and it's not going to the crown.
You breathe it up to the crown chakra.
Okay, instead of coughing it out.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay, okay.
Can you calibrate me
and contextualize myself as being enlightened?
No.
It's worth a shot.
Thank you.
You see, when you're complete and total,
you have no interest in such a matter.
It's like when all power is yours,
somebody offers you power.
You ask them,
what am I supposed to do with it?
I got closets full of power.
Dr. Hawkins,
I feel like I've made some good progress
since encountering your work,
but...
I still deal with a lot of fear.
What I would...
If I had to label it,
I'd call it fear and anxious-type feelings.
And I've taken anti-anxiety medicine in the past,
but I'm wondering,
could that constitute a resistance
to experiencing the fear and anxiety?
Well, ideally,
you want to get to the bottom of the anxiety, yes?
Have you ever been in psychotherapy, you know?
Not intensely, no.
Just like once a week kind of stuff, you know?
Yeah.
Well, they try and deal, you know,
anxiety means non-specific, you know,
free-flowing anxiety like that,
or anxiety about something particular?
It's more generalized, yeah.
It's free-flowing anxiety?
Yes.
So you're not aware of what the fear is about?
No.
Most of the time, right, yes.
Yeah, most of the time, yeah.
So what is your question about it?
Well, the question was,
I'm trying to practice your teaching of not resisting it.
Yeah, yeah.
And experiencing it.
Oh, I see, okay.
So I'm wondering,
is there a context in which a spiritual seeker
could take anti-anxiety medicine,
being that that is...
having...
having the effect of masking the experience?
Well, I would try to extract as much understanding
as I could out of the anxiety.
Watch your dreams.
Try psychotherapy.
Find an intuitive woman to share it with.
Sometimes they'll intuit it.
Try consciousness calibration,
or have an easy logic research.
There's also everything that's physical, mental, and spiritual.
So there's also nothing wrong.
There's nothing wrong with taking a tranquilizer
if that assists you in functioning, huh?
Okay.
Will that block the awareness?
No, but it may decrease the motivation to find the answer.
However,
if it is some mental conflict or something,
it'll present itself in some other way
in some other time anyhow.
It's not going to disappear even if you tranquilize it, see?
Thank you.
Yep.
Inner research,
research within yourself.
Our day on the couch for a couple of years will help too.
I don't know if there's any psychoanalysts around anymore.
No.
He's about to come to me.
Huh?
Yes?
Thank you.
I have two questions.
The first being,
from your teachings,
I believe I understand that the spirit is eternal
and the bodies wear out.
And I had a partner whose body wore out months ago.
And some people that care for me and that I love
have given me information such as
when I dream of him
or when I think I feel his presence.
If the spirit is eternal,
is it possible that you can communicate?
I mean, not even like have a normal conversation,
but do you believe that since the spirit is eternal
and life doesn't ever extinguish,
that when people's bodies stop moving,
that sometimes they can communicate?
Or is that just spiritual romanticism?
What you're talking about is after death,
is his spirit perhaps trying to sometimes come close to you?
Right.
Or can I feel his presence
and sometimes can I sense him in dreams?
Or is that just spiritual romanticism?
Am I phrasing it correctly?
After death, you're wondering,
does his spirit perhaps sometimes come to contact with you
or try to communicate with you?
Yes.
And not even just communicate,
even just be with, sense the presence.
By that, I mean be with.
Okay.
To make known the presence,
to make known to you the presence, yes?
Yes.
Is that a possibility?
Right.
Oh, yeah.
That's a possibility.
I'm going to ask permission.
I'm going to ask.
We have permission to ask this.
It's a possibility.
Okay.
So not so goofy.
I turned it on this morning.
Cool.
My other question is,
I want to see you intensely.
You want to what?
I want to, when I come to see you,
I want to see you intensely.
I saw you in February,
no, January in the Sedona,
I mean,
I saw you in Phoenix and I saw you a couple of months ago,
and I get a good night's sleep,
and I took special vitamins with a lot of B in them this morning,
and I'm rested and I'm a morning person,
and this has happened every time this year.
I show up and I sit in the audience,
and I want to hear every word you say,
and I sleep.
I sleep up until,
I slept till lunch,
and then I came back and I started hearing you.
And I watch your DVDs.
I've read all your books.
I'm here because I want to be.
What do you think is going on?
You heard it.
Didn't register a conscious kind of thing,
conscious.
You heard it.
You picked up the energy of it anyway.
So, you know, you heard it.
Three times in a row?
Well, you need to know it.
Even though you don't have any memory of it,
the knowingness will come to you.
Yeah.
Okay.
Thank you for being here.
Yeah, yeah.
Thank you.
I'd like to thank Truth or Mist if you'll meet the other
leading innovators,
and of they need to meet us tonight at
de pregnancy กa-orppare up to.
We just have to wait for it.
Uh-huh.
uh-huh.
Hello.
First off, I'd like
to express our gratitude for the efforts of your books.
It's made a huge difference in my life personally,
as well as in the small community I work in,
read power versus force and has made an incredible difference in how we work
inside of our organization great so and I do have a question on top of that
thinking about kinesiology and the way that it works with the calibrated scale
of consciousness I came up with a wondering that was it possible to be
able to use a pendulum in reference people use the pendulum successfully and
they get the same calibration okay that was my question yeah you have this like
program your pendulum yes yeah the 200 and over is truth under 200 you know
relations right yeah people have learned how to various techniques there's you
know standing up straight and if you fall forward that's yes people fall
backwards as no so there's a very intuitive ways that people have done it
throughout time okay you know an ancient way they used to
measure
the way they measure calibrated consciousness in the hood the Hoonah would
would I think using perhaps I forget how they did how they did it I actually can
find that out thinking thinking of what you're asking me to measure the the
width of the aura and the numbers came out almost
exactly the same interesting yeah the numbers expressed in what four meters
inches feet I don't know but anyway I find it in the history of the Hoonah that
they found some means I think they use dowsing yes I'd be telling they would
douse until they got to the edge of a person's aura and then they would
measure it and that would be the level of the person's consciousness would
radiate further and further you know
so there's been various methods you know over the ages you know I suspected
that the pendulum yeah the Hoonah if you look up the history of the Hoonah okay I
think you'll find its origin there okay thank you yeah it was done by the Hoonah
a long time ago great thank you very much yeah they used to a knotted rope
and measured how many something or other
uh-huh
Hawkins yeah dr. Hawkins I just have a question for you my teacher and a
counselor and I work in a community that has is impacted by a lot of issues you
guys speak a little closer also how do how does one move towards being more
spiritual being even when they run into impediments like frustration because you
hear about yourself yeah I am because I do experience a lot of
frustration in trying to change people right trying to not trying to change
because I can't do that so trying to work with people so they can what they
are with a that's sort of a cover-up word no work with work with because I
can what is what is the consequence of you're working with them well the
consequence has been some people have been able to move further ahead in their
lives
yeah
But also, personally, what I've experienced is frustration because sometimes things do
not happen fast enough.
Yeah, the frustration is, you know, your intention.
Just be what you are and allow it to their karma.
Be what you are to them, you know?
Because it isn't just what you say, it's what you become that inspires people.
So you become the epitome of that which you wish for them, you know?
All right.
Thank you very much.
Yeah.
That way it's non-verbal teaching.
Non-verbal teaching, you become the ideal that they incorporate as, in Freudian terminology,
the ego ideal.
You become the hero to them, the teacher who cares, the person who is concerned about their
welfare, you know?
Thank you very much.
Yeah.
Many a teacher is inspired, you know?
Fabulous.
Thank you.
Famous ones, famous teachers, whose classes supposedly hopeless top the academic honors
list eventually.
Hi.
Dr. Hawkins, there are some things I do that create so much energy in my life.
You know?
Yeah.
There's so much energy that I get concerned for my psychological stabilization.
Some things you do create so much energy?
Do.
One is a meditation with the rendition of OM by Robert Gass, and another is come in
here.
Yes.
And I just, the energy is so intense.
Yeah.
And I wonder sometimes if it's beneficial.
You'd be so crazy.
Yeah.
If you'd be certainly.
You'd get a phlogo.
Even if you become enlightened or become destroyed, I don't know whether the other.
Become a blob of photoplasm.
Now the energy is out of the field, you know?
You surrender to the field.
And you do go through transformative phases and stages.
Yeah.
phases where you feel like you're coming off your hinges and strange and
unnatural see but these are normal know that all things are within the infinite
harmony of God nobody can be lost to God no matter how upset or strange people go
through the inner dissociative states but where you're where you're at is is
always within the province of divinity and is known to God so you can never be
lost to God the ego may have to adjust to a different perception of itself but
there's no way being lost to the divinity therefore to love and you could
affirm
affirm repeatedly you know my reality is is that one with divine harmony my
life is controlled by divine harmony everything is in divine order my life is
controlled because the reality of the self of the capital S is the emergence
of divine order see so the only thing that gets upset it
shows that the reality of the self is the emergence of divine order so the only thing that gets upset it shows
that the reality of the self is the emergence of divine order so the only thing that gets upset it shows
shifts and changes is the ego mm-hmm what's stressful to the ego is often the
shifts and changes is the ego mm-hmm what's stressful to the ego is often the delight of the self so I'm all upset I don't know
delight of the self so I'm all upset I don't know
delight of the self so I'm all upset I don't know who I am anymore self says thank
who I am anymore self says thank
who I am anymore self says thank God we're getting somewhere so this
God we're getting somewhere so this
God we're getting somewhere so this it is so if you're not just surrender it to
it is so if you're not just surrender it to
it is so if you're not just surrender it to God don't worry just know at all times
times you cannot get lost to God God's infinite harmony includes all of us and
you go through transition periods where you feel like you're out of balance but
that's because of the advancement of consciousness itself yeah therefore
don't be afraid Dr. Hawkins when I started studying these teachings two
years ago it was like a veil
was lifted but when I'm totally honest with myself I find that I have a lot of
spiritual pride associated with it uh-huh
pride of being a part of this group pride of knowing things that other
people don't know and I know it holds me back and I don't know what to do well
you substitute gratitude for pride instead of pride gratitude huh it would
be like a person achieving sobriety and
AA you know instead of being proud they're grateful they say thank you dear
Lord for the miracle so we substitute gratitude gratitude and because what you
accept with gratitude and humility within yourself you can then pass on if
it's blocked with pride you can't you can't you do anything with it for the
good of anyone see so the gratitude then also gratitude to yourself through its
evolution
and your spirit has brought you to the level of grasping such comprehensive
things you know gratitude is the answer yeah humility is the answer to all of it
actually yeah it's gratitude the basis of humility I've never understood
humility well I know more about humility anybody but I walk in this
I'm a master of humility
now the key on doing this is gratitude and then out of humility you realize
you've been gifted and you give thanks to God for the gift thanks God too we
discovered something in noon today that was like a gift you don't came out of the
blue we didn't earn it we didn't work for it was the work project just suddenly
dawn on us holy snacks we actually changed the calibrations of things in the
world god yeah
Whew. That was, so you're grateful for the knowingness, but with each knowingness goes
an also concomitant responsibility to share it for the welfare of all, you know.
Thank you, sir. Seriously, thank you.
Yeah. Don't feel guilty about the pride. That's a double negative. Thank you, God, for the
pride. So now I know where my Achilles heel is and where to work, you know.
This funny little wiggle thing over my ear. We're going to get a new thing soon. Thank you.
Namaste. Namaste.
Thank you.
With this own little karmic path that I have going here, I feel like I'm at a crossroads.
And I've just given up a very lucrative job because I couldn't stand the conflict and the polarity anymore in the politics.
So I'm wondering if you might give me some advice and a path.
One of them was working for you.
Doing whatever I can do to serve to increase the vibration of our world.
And the other is to express myself in art or photography and bring that joy to the world.
And then a third thing, and I'm sorry, audience, but I prefer you not knowing what I'm talking about here.
But this is something that I'm interested in knowing if it's worth me putting my time and effort to.
So you've gone from what, the business world into the arts?
I'm considering it. I've kind of, I've quit my job in business.
So you were, what kind of a job, business world or what kind of business?
I was an associate director of biostatistics for a pharmaceutical company.
Oh, uh-huh. So.
And now you would rather go into more like the arts, huh?
Something more expressive.
Yeah.
Uh-huh.
Uh, hmm, okay.
So what is the question?
In this lifetime, what I'd like to do is raise the vibration as much as possible.
So raise it, therefore you just want to work on yourself.
Yeah.
Work on yourself. That's what you're doing, to raise the vibration.
On yourself or on all?
On yourself, yeah.
I'm not sure what you mean by your question.
What can you do occupationally to be of the greatest benefit to mankind generally?
Yes. Yes. Yes.
Well, wherever your talents lie, wherever your heart lies, you say to follow your heart, right?
Yes.
Okay. So to follow your heart to which you feel attracted.
That's sensible.
And to practice spiritual principles in all your affairs to the best of your ability.
Yes.
What more can you do?
That would be a lovely life.
You can do that anytime. You can drive a cab and do that.
Yes.
It's fun driving a cab, by the way.
Yeah.
So you want to be free to do that which you're attracted to.
Yes.
Okay. Because of your own talents and gifts.
Do you know what your various gifts and talents are?
I'm sensing they're artistic and it's something I've always suppressed in my life.
And I'm giving it a go right now.
All right. So the artistic side. Okay.
Yeah.
So you're going to explore the artistic side
and dedicate your work in a spiritual context.
Yes.
What more can you do?
That sounds to me sufficient.
Yeah.
Hmm?
That sounds sufficient.
Yes.
Yeah. And that's being a gift to the world.
All right.
And I'm just wondering, is this something I should continue as well?
Right.
I don't know what it means.
Can I whisper it to you?
Huh?
I'm sorry. It should be...
You expect me to be able to read now?
I can't. I can't see.
I'm sorry.
Yeah. Write it.
Vision, visual, acuity.
It diminishes over time, as does auditory.
I'm sorry, sweetie. I didn't mean to put you in a...
If you write it in foot-high letters, I'll probably get it.
I'm not familiar with that, honey. I don't know what that is.
Okay.
I don't know.
Okay. Yeah. Fair enough.
Its intention is to increase the health of people, right?
Yes.
Yeah.
Well, the intention makes it...
The intention is what's important.
I have a sense it's working with the etheric brain.
Huh?
Yes. Oh, I see. With the etheric brain.
Yeah.
You mean spiritual awareness. Yes.
Okay.
Yeah.
It sounds okay.
Leave me your card. If I change my mind, I'll have to...
Okay. All right.
It's a public forum right now.
I understand.
All right.
I'm trying to be sensitive, too. I'm sorry.
Okay. Thank you.
Thanks.
I get your intention overall.
Okay.
I couldn't read it.
What about a unity minister?
I can't hear anything.
A unity minister?
She's...
Have you thought of being a unity minister?
She's upset.
Okay.
Okay. Okay.
Thank you, Dr. Hawkins .
You have made a great difference in my personal life and in my business life, as well.
I have a one and a half question.
It's really almost the same question.
As a flight kinesiologist and chiropractor, which I am, I've been using a lot of your
work for a long time now.
I get the sense especially, recently doing some testing, that sometimes it's more beneficial...
I set a limit of, say, 500.
That's if the treatment or the modality or whatever didn't calibrate that,
I wouldn't use that for the patient.
And in some cases, it seems like they almost get better symptomatic relief,
and I know that's not necessarily a consciousness aspect.
But if I use a lower calibration,
maybe something that's closer to their vibration or calibration.
So then here's where the two questions kind of dovetail,
one in my personal life and also with my patients.
Is it something to strive, maybe it's more realistic,
or to encourage calibrated things, whether it be nutrition or books to read,
that's in a similar level, or something that's...
I think everything is physical, mental, and spiritual.
So you tell them what you feel would be beneficial physically,
energy-wise, maybe through acupuncture or whatever, see?
Intellectually, through reading, et cetera, spiritual practice,
nutrition.
You use everything you can.
Now, what you're really asking is,
if you prescribe something that's far beyond where they're at,
will it have any hold?
Will it have any effect?
I would say so, yes.
Otherwise, mankind is hopeless.
Mankind is endlessly praying to God,
no matter what the level of consciousness, you know?
Now, I think the intention behind it, you know, is sufficient.
So then, in our personal life...
Well, you're trying to tailor it.
I see what you're saying.
If somebody's in the mid-400s,
you should use something that's primarily intellectual
because it'll make sense to them and all.
So they come back?
Well, they may feel more attracted to it.
I give them a couple of things to do, and, you know,
cafeteria style, try it.
So then, in my personal life,
if it's not so much an object of getting rid of the symptom,
should I just strive for whatever is the highest calibration?
And if I have a choice of reading one book or the other,
just go with the highest one always?
I don't know that I can answer that without studying a specific example.
In other words, somebody who calibrates at 250,
is it going to help them to read Wang Po at 850?
That's what you're asking.
Is it going to be meaningful to them?
I suppose you would say as a teacher, as an educator,
or what your position is,
you try to lead them stepwise,
into that which would make kind of sense to them,
so they don't end up mystified, you know?
Right.
Mantras are good,
because you only have to pass kindergarten in order to do them.
Not long and complicated.
Something simple and effective, yeah.
But I get your intention is such
that you will certainly find out
what's going to be the most helpful for this patient,
and you're going to use kinesiology to research that.
Yeah, I used to check out the doses of medications I gave people, you know.
I would guess 50 milligrams is enough,
and then I would check it out with kinesiology,
and I would get, yep, 50 milligrams is right, see.
Use it to cross-check, you know, cross-check.
All right.
Thank you.
Hmm.
Yes.
My question is,
if one commits to a lifestyle of forgiveness towards others
and surrendering all events to God,
regardless of what happens,
will that commitment eventually lead us
to the level we talked about today, serenity?
Oh, of course.
It's the keystone.
Okay.
Thank you.
That's the secret.
Don't tell anybody, though.
One thing to hear it, another thing to do it, eh?
But only forgive those who deserve it, you know what I mean?
The bad guys, they're on their own.
Yeah.
You answered my question with a second.
I'm a good person.
So since Nico is not here, would you do us the honor of leading us in a few long ohms?
You want an ohm today?
Yeah.
Well, actually, some of us were talking about we'd like not only your ohm, but to lead us
all in an ohm.
Okay.
So I think we're going to have to get the ohm.
You're going to have to get the ohm.
Yeah.
Ohm.
Thank you very much.
Dr. Hawkins, I started my journey about 40 years ago, and it seems like you were the
next person, the next teacher.
The next teacher, the next person.
I'm the next teacher.
Yep.
And my husband and I have read your first three books, just finished reading the last
one through twice, and would you mind if he took my picture with you?
She wants her picture taken with you.
Picture?
Pictures are okay.
Yeah.
And I take one of both of you in it.
Oh, I signed it.
Okay.
There you go.
Where are we, honey?
Who's taking a picture?
She's taking both of us with her.
Come on up here.
Who's taking a picture?
He is.
Come here.
I'll take one of both of you.
All right.
We'll do a picture.
Yeah.
Okay.
No, no, no.
Come up here.
Honey, honey, come here.
He's bashful.
Oh, he's bashful.
Okay.
He's mashful.
I'm happy.
And there's five other dwarfs right behind us.
Okay.
You can sign
in to the book.
Thank you.
Could you please speak in a little more detail on the mechanics of intention from two different
perspectives?
One as it involves an individual.
You want clarification on intention?
Does the intention come from the field and then is it energized by the field until the
conditions are corrected?
Well, intention activates the field.
Intention activates the field.
Let's say your intention is to see the beauty, innate beauty and intrinsic sacredness of
all that exists.
That begins to have an effect in the field and the field brings the awareness to you
in a non-linear style, non-linear.
Just the awareness.
It's linear.
You're there.
Mm-hmm.
And then how do the characteristics of intention change from less than 200 as you
shift?
What?
You got to talk closer to the microphone.
Repeat it one more time.
The characteristics of intention, how do they change from below 200 as you move up the scale?
The intention moves, of course, with the consciousness level.
Right.
Yes.
Uh-huh.
Very much so.
And then the fields become more powerful?
Yes.
Logarithmically.
Ok.
Logarithmically, more powerful.
Alright.
To bless all that exists is infinitely more powerful than to dislike it.
You can collapse the function.
There is somebody who has been listening to the lecture.
Thank you.
From potentiality-actuality to the Heisenberg principle of intention.
You collapse the potential into the actual.
It's called collapsing the wave function.
You go from the Schrodinger equation to the Dirac equations via the Heisenberg principle.
And the von Neumann process phases one and two in the middle of it.
I know you all wanted to know that.
Yeah.
I don't have a question, but my friend, I'd like to have a picture taken with you.
The what?
She wants to have a picture taken with you.
Okay, yes.
While you're signing the book, a funny story.
When I was in the plane coming out here, a gentleman was talking to me.
I said, it seems like you come out here a lot.
I said, I do.
And I'm coming out to my friend's at the course house.
I know.
I went to see Dr. Hogan.
She's too close.
She's too close to the mic.
Okay.
Anyway, so I explained a little bit about your work.
And he said, oh, it's religion.
I said, no, it's spirituality.
So I explained a little bit more.
He said, oh, it's a church.
I said, no.
And I explained a little bit more about the map of consciousness.
And I said, and if you really would like to get his book, it's called Power Versus Force.
He said, oh, he's a power speaker.
This guy on the plane was telling her all this stuff.
I said, no, it's spirituality.
He said, no, it's a church.
I said, no, it's a church.
It's a church.
He said, no, it's a church.
of consciousness and I said
and if you really would like to get his book
it's called Power Versus Force
he said oh he's a power speaker
this guy on the plane
was telling her all this
you could explain to him later
I just thought it was cute
he's a power speaker
exactly
we started to run on power
didn't we
now it's power this power that
and then we said thank you very much
because you have changed my life
now my friend has a camera
they want the picture
oh a picture yes
yes indeed
how about with the flowers
that looks very nice
we'll have the flowers between us
there we are
thanks Robert
you bet
yeah
thank you
so now you're a spiritual power speaker
oh a power speaker
oh that's good
you're a spiritual power speaker
spiritual power speaker
how do you do Dr. Hawkins
thank you for seeing me
nice to meet you
I'm in a spiritual conundrum
yeah it's a conundrum
that sounds serious
a conundrum
problems I can handle
I don't know a lot of conundrums
the thing is I've been a nurse
for 24 years
and I work in the operating room
but several years ago
I went into recovery
and I opened a business
and for holistic healing
and I've put a ton of money
into this business
and it doesn't seem like
it's taken off
at all
and so I'm wondering
if I'm supposed to like
stay in the western medicine aspect
just to raise the vibration
or should I continue
how can you put a ton of money in it
well I've put over
$50,000
in it
into the business
and I haven't seen
much
good god
what did you spend it on
computer equipment
made CDs
I've written a book
different types of things like that
so marketing
so what would you call
your occupation right now
I'm going to get over this
I'm a behavior therapist
aside from an operating room
behavioral therapist
so and I just
just can't seem to get the word out
in
well you're
you start small
and do the best you can
and it either succeeds
or it doesn't
yeah I figured that one out
so I just don't know
if I should continue on
or if I should just
pursue something else
about four and a half years
and it doesn't seem to catch on somehow
hasn't seemed to
I'm wondering if maybe I should just write
that's what I don't know
what you're looking for from it
is it something you do
for the satisfaction
in which case
you don't necessarily have to have it grow
you know
yeah well I know I'm supposed to be of service
that's why I'm here
I know I'm supposed to be of service
so
well it'd be like having a part-time practice
instead of a full-time one right
right and that's what I've been doing
all right so you've got a
part-time practice doing that
and then you've got other time
you could do something else
maybe more conventional
you know
and that's what I'm currently doing
and I'm wondering if I should continue
or if I should
work on it
don't know because I can't tell you what the what the value is to you you see
okay all right very good so is it what you really want to do you see if it's
really want what you want to do then it's its own reward see I think should
be its own reward without any particular gain coming to it if anybody reads the
books I've written so much the better but if they don't so I remember the
first year we sold $4,000 worth of books I said this is phenomenal I I borrowed
$25,000 yeah took out a second mortgage for 26,000 wasn't making too much money
delivering manure you know I'm saying
that's what I did well I studied in road you know and I remember the first
year I said my god we sold $4,000 for the books so but that was satisfaction
in itself because the obligation was to write the book the obligation was not
you know to make a success of it or a world-famous
story
or sell a million copies the the obligation was to write down what you
knew could you know is seeming of seeming benefit or significance that was
the end of the obligation after that you could croak and not feel guilty about it
see what I'm saying you're doing it for its own sake and not for some external
gain to come from it so that verifies the worth of what you're doing
not by its success but whether you feel that fulfilling your obligation to the
pee Chen
doctor Hawkins I'm interested in how would you rate your fictivity is a
problem solver and as a healer in your psychiatry practice before them medical
crisis that you had what you practice psychiatry of the years before you had
a medical crisis that yeah yeah sure when you almost died yeah uh how successful were you
how successful was your practice oh i always had a successful practice
before and after you know and when you help people when you help people in their pain
before your crisis did you ever sense there was a greater power helping you
helping you heal that person uh i don't know that's in your time i don't recall that i don't
remember okay that's just curious uh i uh had a good practice before and after you know
of course later on in life i investigated alternate pathways to
healing you know of course the miracles and things like that which and you know freudian
psychoanalysis etc was
my own analyst was an atheist at the time and so was i
and so we were in total agreement about that we have no problem with it
thank you
uh freud was my great-grandfather
my uh my analyst uh my analyst
was analyzed by abraham carden abraham carden
there was a
a
analyzed by Freud. So
Lionel Lovacy, my father,
my grandfather is Cardiner, and my
great-grandfather is Sigmund Freud.
Sequoia and Leckley speaking.
You're incorrigible.
Irrepressible, too.
My spiritual teachers have been
L.C. Bailey and Rudolf Steiner.
Oh, Alice Bailey, yeah, yeah.
And now I'll add you. Rudolf Steiner, yeah.
I'm concerned
about, well,
I've been really focused on politics
since all this mess,
and I'm concerned about the
karmic retributions that
this country will probably suffer.
It's not retribution.
That's the wrong way to phrase it.
That's cause and effect.
That this action causes a retribution.
That's not
within reality.
Everything pulls to it
in accord with that which it is.
And therefore, justice is
automatic and perfect.
Okay.
I try to pray for
leaders of all nations
and send them love and light.
I just lost my little dog just about a month ago.
You lost what?
My little dog.
So I've been mourning that quite a while.
Oh, yes, yes, yes.
Thank you very much.
What?
Okay.
Are you tired yet?
What does that mean, Terry?
Restless?
I don't know what those mean.
Oh.
I don't know.
Good.
I guess that's a good thing.
I'm going to Course in Miracles.
Yeah.
One of the recent lessons was
I'm not speaking.
Was it
you've invented your inner and outer world.
I understand the inner world
because it seems like a fantasy
but your outer world
does that mean by karma and choice
that you've invented it?
What is the quote?
The inner world and the outer world.
Are you pointing to the Course in Miracles?
Well, yes.
It says
do you have a choice?
Do you have a choice?
I don't know what the difference is between the inner and outer world.
I guess they mean the outer world.
And the world of your mind.
Civilization, the way it is.
Well, the world of your mind.
Speaking of the inner world, it's speaking of the world of your mind,
which is an illusion, it's a fantasy.
And then the outer world is the world you visually think you see.
Or that you perceive.
Yes.
So you're talking about Descartes' res interna versus res externa.
Res cogitans versus, yeah, perception versus essence.
Now, the Course in Miracles takes you beyond projecting perception
so that you can comprehend essence.
And that is the miracle.
The miracle is that what is perceived is transformed in time and significance and meaning.
And now you see the essence.
And when you see the essence, that's miraculous
because you realize then,
there is no problem.
Yeah.
The transformation is by the replacement of the linear content by context.
I remember you see a bird of prey eating the sparrow.
And then through the Course in Miracles,
you see that the sparrow,
the spiritual evolution is by serving that which is higher.
Okay.
We all serve that which we sacrifice the lesser for the greater.
Thereby do we earn the karma to become the greater.
Therefore, the animal world serves us.
But to see that is miraculous.
To thee, O Lord, do I surrender.
Because to the animal world, we are the Lord.
To thee, O Lord, do I surrender my beingness.
And the animal spirit thereby becomes transformed
and karmically earns the right to become the human.
Let's see if that's correct.
What I just stated is correct.
That is also the teaching of the Rig Veda.
The Rig Veda.
That all lives to sacrifice itself to that which is the higher.
And by sacrificing itself,
to the higher,
it karmically earns the right to become the higher.
That's the gift to the cattle.
The gift to the sheep.
The gift to the ducks.
So we love the animal kingdom.
Because on some intuitive level,
we know that there is somehow one with us
in some kind of a concordant karmic evolution.
Thank you.
Thank you for asking.
Thank you all.
Thank you.
This is Robert.
I want everybody to know Robert.
He's terrific.
Terrific.
Very significant person.
Yes.
Hello.
I'm wondering if you can explain a little bit more
the mechanism of surrender.
Mechanism?
You talk about it as a shortcut. It makes sense, but it's something that's never been fully explained.
What is to surrender?
It has to do with volition, see?
To let be what it is. This comes out of humility.
I don't know the reason for it, see?
Because you don't know the reason for it doesn't mean that it's wrong.
This applies to everything.
In the world, including war, suicide, death, starvation, plague, volcanic eruptions, tsunamis.
That which is not explicable to human reason, yeah?
The fact that it's not explicable to human reason is indicative of the fact that you aren't God, you see?
So we surrender.
The significance and the meaning of this to Almighty God
is
to Divine Wisdom.
So we substitute Divine Wisdom for
for
an egoistic opinion, you know what I'm saying?
Who's to say that it should not happen?
Are you telling God it should not happen?
Are you telling
the evolution of humanity for three million years out of the emergent hominid
that it shouldn't happen?
Who are you telling by your opinion that it should be different than it is, you see?
And on what basis, what kind of contextualization of reality would allow you to make such a statement, eh?
Who's first?
So...
Okay.
I'm trying to grasp the essence.
So surrender means to let go, surrender one's personal will
to the sovereignty of divinity, see?
To let go of outcomes.
You don't know the reasons why such things happen.
Each thing, you see, is the emergence of a propensity.
The emergence of a propensity.
And some things can only be learned through pain that is of such severity that you hit bottom.
What does it take for mankind to give up war as an option to salute sovereignty?
And to salute solving problems, you know?
Whatever it takes is whatever it takes.
In the self-help groups, they talk about hitting bottom.
There's high bottoms and there's low bottoms.
High bottoms get it right away without having to experience it out.
Low bottoms...
30 million people starve to death based on a certain ideology.
Is that sufficient?
Is that sufficient to shake your faith in that ideology?
I'm sure there are many adherents still today walking this earth
that think Mayo's Little Red Book is the hottest thing going.
You know what I'm saying?
30 million people dying of starvation.
Incredible.
What is this?
That's a Frisbee and you're supposed to sign it.
I'm supposed to sign it?
Yeah.
That is funny.
Thank you.
Oh, no.
I'll sign it.
Oh, sign it here.
Well, we talked about that Frisbee in Toronto, didn't we?
Thank you very much.
The dog chasing the Frisbee.
I gave the dog's name the way it was in the paper.
So somebody emails that his name was something else.
It was Elvis in the paper.
Elvis in the paper, yeah.
Elvis.
Anyway, Elvis calibrated over 500.
Who cares what the dog's name is?
And precipitated a miracle.
Yeah.
So we will go ahead.
Thank you both so much for helping us.
I read Glamour, Alice Bailey's book that you recommended.
And do you recommend her other books?
Just that one.
Okay.
Thank you.
Otherwise I'll have to read all of her books and decide which one to recommend.
That's right.
The projection of the energy field of specialness is what adds glamour and attraction.
And it's Hollywood's, you know, what it lives on.
The energy of glamour.
Yeah.
I love your laugh, first of all.
When you talk about self with a capital S, are you talking about the soul?
Oh, yes.
Okay.
The essence, the source of it, yes.
And then my other question is why do some people remember their past lives while others
do not?
And why is the amnesia important when we're reincarnating?
I don't know.
Okay.
But when you incarnate, you instantly forget previous incarnations.
Why?
Because now you're this body and you're in this present.
You identify with the current perception.
Okay.
And when you're out of body, you're not limited that way.
I think there's an amnesia the minute you incarnate.
There's an amnesia the minute you incarnate.
Yes.
Above level 600 or so, you can begin to recall.
Mm-hmm.
Okay.
And the recall is not of a memory.
The recall is of the subjective experiencing of it.
Okay.
Mm-hmm.
So, what does the body of a blacksmith feels like?
Because to go back into that lifetime, I am like the ultimate mesomorph.
I'm very powerful.
I've got huge biceps.
I know that life and I know what happened to that life.
You see what I mean?
Mm-hmm.
So, don't you remember it like a vivid memory?
It's not.
It's more like a body memory or a...
No.
It's more like you relive it.
Okay.
All right.
And there's hypnotics, very simple past life recall techniques.
It's not a big deal.
You calm yourself down, transport yourself back to asking the question, and you get off
at the 14th floor, and that life begins to rerun experientially like it's happening now.
It's not like a movie where you witness.
It's like the re-experiencing.
Mm-hmm.
And you see the horse's hoofs come up.
And now you remember how you died in that lifetime.
And why you and horses ain't never got along.
My other question is, are we born with our time of death?
I've read that before.
Yes.
Okay.
We've calibrated that many times, and that's so.
Thank you so much.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
Every videotape comes with a story.
Mm-hmm.
Yeah.
Every videotape comes to an end, you know?
Thank you, Dr. Hawkins and Susan, for being here and your staff.
Mm-hmm.
Two months ago at this seminar, you gave us an exercise you called the counting exercise
about eating 60 cookies a day and counting them.
Oh, counting them.
Yeah.
And I loved that exercise.
And you mentioned that I'm up to 80 cookies a day.
I'm up to 80 cookies a day.
So, you mentioned that is a principle of the Heisenberg principle.
The observation begins to change the phenomena, and, well, the best technique for, let's say,
the most successful one was called, I don't know, Tobacco Anonymous or something.
And all they did is have you count the number of cigarettes.
Mm-hmm.
And then everybody in the class eventually quit smoking, you know, just to become conscious,
conscious.
Right.
So, my question is, is it, you're, in the case of the cookies, you're looking at the
cookie, which is a negative.
It's not a negative.
It's not a negative?
No.
The cookie's not negative.
It's just, so where does the wave come in?
What, where, what's collapsing?
Is it, is there a wave between the cookie and me?
The observation.
You had to have the last lecture to understand that.
It has to do with intention, intention.
So, merely observing a phenomena begins to change it.
So, witnessing the phenomena.
How many times do you clear your throat every time you're giving a lecture, right?
Right.
Alright, the more you become aware of that, now you have some control of it.
It's not unconscious.
It's not happening of its own.
It's more aware.
It's more awareness.
Yeah, you become more conscious and aware.
That's it.
Thank you.
You learned that in third grade.
Wrong, wrong, wrong.
You got a 60 on this test.
Hi there.
Thank you for all you've done, first of all, and second of all.
My first question is, on the animal chart of consciousness,
I noticed, and you said, that below the level of 200 are basically carnivores.
Generally, generally, generally.
Right.
And then above the level of 200 are...
Generally.
It's not written in cement.
I don't want to get you into a sense of compulsive literalism or concretism, okay?
No, no.
Songbirds are less than 200, yes.
My question is, then, as humans,
could we raise our level of consciousness
by being more aware of our own consciousness?
By being vegetarian.
By being what?
Vegetarian.
Not eating meat.
Vegetarianism calibrates about 205.
Not, you know, a little sort of disappointing.
I was a vegetarian for, you know, a good 10 years or so.
And, actually, one day I was in a restaurant
and it came to me that I am meat.
I am meat.
You are meat, buddy.
I'm not a vegetarian.
No, I understand.
I was previously.
Yeah, I was for 10 years.
For a while, not 10 years.
Oh, yeah.
But I've been considering it a little more.
I've been reading some Buddhism and...
Well, I think it's very fine to do that.
But not necessary.
It may be for you.
Okay.
And one other...
You're denying all the cattle a chance to evolve into human nature.
That's a new one.
Yeah, you read the Rig Vita and then ask me again next time.
Okay.
The Rig Vita.
R-I-G Vita.
Okay.
Calibrates about 900.
I have one more quick question, if you would.
I noticed you had Plato on your list of...
This would be authors, I believe,
and you rated their consciousness level or something,
of their works.
Yeah.
And...
Right below that was Plotinus.
And I was wondering if you could rate Plotinus as the man,
like with the testing.
Test where he would be as a man as opposed to his works.
Oh.
Plotinus.
That would be different.
That would be different, yes.
Then there's Plotinus as a spiritual teacher,
and there's Plotinus as an author.
Right.
As a spiritually evolved person,
his calibration is higher than his writings.
Okay.
I was just curious if you knew what that was.
Yeah.
I forget now.
I think his writings were 503, but I think Plotinus...
502, 503.
Yeah, around in there.
The author.
Yeah, the author.
Right.
Let's be quick.
Plotinus as an author was about five...
I'm asking about Plotinus as the spiritual teacher.
We have permission to ask this.
Plotinus as an author calibrates around 503, 504.
Plotinus as a realized mystic calibrates over 700, 720.
Oh, okay.
See, many people wrote up to a certain level.
Then you bliss out.
Forget the writing.
Unless you've got a good wife,
you're never going to write anything again.
Thank you very much.
Yes?
Wait, did he sign?
No, yes.
Yes?
Yes.
Again, I'd like to just look into your eyes.
This person would like to join with you and yourself.
Thank you very much.
God bless you, love.
Precious river.
Thank you.
The greatest gift is, though,
to someone who allows you to be yourself.
Someone who allows you to give and to be yourself.
I'd like to thank you both.
Yes.
You for sticking around to help us
and you for getting him here, probably.
I get a feeling you rely on her a lot.
I'm a musician and a composer.
I call her my right arm.
Yeah, I've heard that name.
I can literally, literally, hand finger.
Yes, you're a musician.
I'm a musician and a composer.
And while I'm not interested in knowing my personality,
I'm not interested in knowing my personality.
My personal calibrations,
the music that I compose and my songs,
I've tried with the single.
Yeah, the old ring.
That was pretty good.
And it seems that I'm able to
write the songs that I check
seem to be in the six,
up to 600,
in my composition.
And I'm wondering
how that works,
that someone,
I guess you can,
if your intent is to write about unconditional love,
you could be at a level of, say, 300
and still write something up in 600.
Yeah.
seven I don't think so I mean music is so inspirational you can hardly write
something that that is not what you are but you wouldn't be able to
conceptualize it or intuitive so when you talk about calibrating Bach his
personal level was as high as his musical no I did that's his music the
person in fact a lot of times I'll say not the personality not the personage
the music of Johann Sebastian Bach very high yeah well because my my my vision
of myself is to try to capture the essence of great teachers and the music
and and write lyrics and music for this purpose but I got a feeling I shouldn't
quote or use the terminology would lose most people
so I don't think that's what I'm trying to do I don't think that's what I'm trying to do
I don't think that's what I'm trying to do I don't think that's what I'm trying to do
I don't think that's what I'm trying to do I don't think that's what I'm trying to do so I just thought if I
I don't think that's what I'm trying to do so I just thought if I
I don't think that's what I'm trying to do so I just thought if I embedded the symbology of whatever
so I just thought if I embedded the symbology of whatever
so I just thought if I embedded the symbology of whatever words I used with the with the intent
embedded the symbology of whatever words I used with the with the intent
embedded the symbology of whatever words I used with the with the intent of this that it somehow could could be
words I used with the with the intent of this that it somehow could could could be
words I used with the with the intent of this that it somehow could could could be available for people to receive
of this that it somehow could could could be available for people to receive
to the music. Yes, just create, do that what you're you're led to by your
muse. Your muse is the intuitive knowingness of what to do
with the gift. All right, thank you. You're on the perfect
drill. The joy of the Bee Gees is not less than the joy of Johann Sebastian
Bach. They're all different dimensions. The Bee Gees music is really very high. So
how you contextualize it then is the expression of that which you've become.
I know where it's at.
Yes, is that the end?
Gloria in excelsis Deo. Forever. Amen.
That's the blessing of the teacher, yeah. So wonderful to be here. Yeah, you know
it's hard to drag away because we're all here like all together like a big
oneness and it's a gift to get together, isn't it? Sort of a gift.
We look forward to it all month when you get to be together with all the people you
love and I could just hang out with the group you know until 12 o'clock tonight
I'm sure wandering around saying hi and answering questions and hugging
everybody and wanting to know what the hell goes on here. So that's been my
blessing to have such a, you're all my blessing. Yeah, uh-huh. And will you stop crying now?
I did?
That's a promise now. Not another tear. You're gonna get it.
Oh yeah. The tears of joy are hard to hold back, you know.
Thank you.
Yeah, so. God bless you. Yeah, yeah. Thank you so much, all.
Thank you so much.
And now they kick us out of here because at five o'clock we turn into a mushroom.
My dear heart, yeah.
Thank you.
Yeah.
Thank you again.
God bless you.
Yeah. We have to leave at five o'clock under threat. Or else. Or else. Or else.
Or else. Hi.
Hello.
Yeah.
Here you are.
Trying to hide out from me, but I see you.
Yeah.
There.
Here's Elizabeth.
Thank you.
Hi.
Yeah.
There we are, sweethearts.
God bless you all.
Thank you.
God bless you.
All right.
Thank you so much.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Hi, sweetheart.
Yeah.
Thank you.
Oy.
alright, here we go
now we're going to escape
Alleluia, Alleluia
Alleluia, Alleluia, Alleluia