song.
Give me
My head is a goal. I don't know. You
should get warmed up with all this
friction now. Everybody
shaking my hand.
>> Wonderful to see you again.
>> Morning.
>> Not for great singing. Thank you. Good
having you.
>> Yeah,
>> I love those suspenders. Got them, man.
They are real.
Hi, sweetheart.
>> Hi.
>> Oh my god. A little familiar face.
>> Good morning.
Ah,
>> hello.
>> Thank you for being here.
>> Morning, David. How are you?
>> Hawkins.
>> Hi.
Hey,
>> everybody.
Oh, boy. We got to keep moving, huh?
We got to keep moving, don't we?
>> Did we get everybody here? No, we
didn't.
>> Hi.
>> Hello. Hello. Hello.
>> How are you?
>> You I do.
>> I touched you.
Hi.
>> How you doing, man?
>> Hello.
>> God bless you. God bless you.
>> How are you?
>> Good morning.
>> Hi.
>> Blessings.
>> Good morning.
>> I missed you when you were here.
>> All right. Did I miss anybody?
Did I miss anybody?
Miss anybody?
>> I'll take another one.
>> All right.
>> All right. Some people got two shakes.
>> We're in for a treat today. We have a
surprise for you.
>> What did you say?
We have a surprise for you.
>> All right.
Every day is a surprise.
When you get to my age, waking up in the
morning every morning.
Hey, baby. Here we go. Another day each.
Got to hit that world today.
Hit it with your feet running. That's
the way I keep doing it.
Hit the feet with your feet running
to have an upbeat attitude towards life.
Means letting go of all the negatives
and spiritual evolution which is what
our courses are about. Uh anybody new
here today? How many people are new? All
right. See we have the new and then we
have people who have been to a lot of
lectures.
So what we try to do is combine for the
new people a quick rerun of the basics
and for the people who've been here a
number of times uh stressing something
new or looking at something that we're
familiar with but from a a new
viewpoint.
Uh
today we're talking about spiritual
traps. I don't know what that means, but
it says that
I wrote trips and they misspelled it.
So,
trips, traps, troops.
We'll have spiritual troops here later.
We'll start with the spiritual trips and
then we'll hit the traps.
Trip trap troops. So, there we'll cover
it all.
Oh, yes. Never take life too seriously.
One of the traps is taking life
extremely seriously. You see, without a
sense of humor, you don't survive too
well.
There's different styles of spiritual
expression, spiritual teaching.
Uh each one fits its own niche
and fits different moods. Fits different
moods. I like humor as a teaching
technique, as a modality. And I like
humor as a way of being in the world.
Well, we always start as we said with
the end of the lectures. We start at the
end and work back to the beginning. Most
people start at the beginning and work
to the end. But by the time you get to
the end, you forgotten what the
beginning was. So we'll start with the
end, which is the conclusion.
If you get that in the beginning, you
can take a nap.
As soon as somebody points it out to
you, what I'm going to say is extremely
simple and obvious. You see to start out
with the overall context
that creation and evolution are one in
the same thing that sets an overall
context.
Evolution is nothing but the process of
creation.
Creation is evolution and evolution is
creation. So that ends that argument.
The way to see that is you have to jump
the Newtonian paradigm of cause and
effect. The dualistic conceptualization
of cause and effect because the thing
occurs prior to something else. We
presume it's the cause.
And there's a Latin phrase that points
out the fallacy of that which I've
forgotten.
Post hawk ergoctor hawk.
Everybody got that? Post hawk erggo
hawk. Because a thing follows a thing
doesn't mean it's caused by that which
precedes it. Because there is nothing
that does precede it.
The only thing that precedes it is
you're witnessing. The phenomena there
is no sequential sequences is in the
witness.
The way things come about is
potentiality becomes an actuality
when conditions are favorable.
But you're not seeing causality. What
you're seeing is emergence.
The potentiality
of the
caterpillar, the little thing in the
cocoon, the crystallis,
it doesn't
cause the moth of the butterfly. See, it
emerges.
It has that potential. That potential
then actualizes as a butterfly if
conditions are appropriate
but not because it's caused. Nothing
causes nothing causes it to do that. The
conditions are there
appropriate heat, humidity, time of
year, etc.
And so what you see is the emergence of
potentiality
appearing in actuality.
The fact that you think it appears there
doesn't mean that it is there. It's just
that in your mind you think one thing is
occurring before the other and one thing
is causing another.
Now the reason we stress that is because
the Newtonian paradigm the the
calibrated level of the 400s
uh is the great stopper.
Very few people get beyond consciousness
level 499.
Um, not too many people get to the 400s
if you ask me, but
thinking this anyway. So the the
intellect and the mind is the world of
the 400s. That's the word of world of
science and mathematics and aeronautics,
engineering.
It's a world of great benefit to
mankind. The 400s pharmaceuticals
uh and the relief of the suffering of
mankind that comes out of the 400s is
incredible.
Seldom seldom however does the mind jump
the Newtonian paradigm of cause and
effect and calibrate in the 500s. So at
499 we have the greatest geniuses of
history. We have Freud, we have Sir
Isaac Newton, we have Einstein,
the great intellects.
Uh so genius is usually around 4 480 to
499. Huh?
But then at consciousness level 500,
there's a paradigm jump from out there,
from the illusion of causality
to the reality of subjectivity.
It's the experiential.
This morning we planned an experiential
kind of a lesson. See it's the
experiential.
The experiential cannot be proven.
Cannot be proven.
You know and there was recently a blog
site they criticized kinesiology from
the viewpoint of the Newtonian paradigm
of causality etc. You know, anyway, what
the person misses, the critic thinks
that the only things that are real are
things that within the 400s, things that
you can prove.
And therefore, anything beyond 499 is
unreal, though.
On the other hand, he doesn't believe
that.
It sounds sort of saucy and provocative,
but
he doesn't believe it either.
No, because where do we live? Even if we
hold to the Newtonian paradigm, we only
hold to it because subjectively to us it
is truth. To us it is truth. So
therefore all people live by faith.
I got a kick out of the skeptic because
he ridicules faith and he writes from
complete and 101% absolute faith in his
own mentalization about it all.
You don't live in the tinian paradigm.
You talk about it. You deal with it as
an out there. You see, but you don't
live there. Where you live is in
subjectivity, the experiential.
You live in the radiance of
consciousness itself.
It's the e fllororesence of
consciousness experientially.
That's where you live. And the quality
of that subjective experiential reality
is what a more mature person is
concerned about. Therefore, love becomes
of a greater value than possessions.
Um, depending on the possession of
course
because some people love their
possessions. They love their
possessions.
What does he say? For my cold cold hand,
you will pull the rifle or something.
Love their possessions. Yeah. All right.
So that's the first trap we come across
is to reject the source of your
happiness outside of yourself.
That's fatal.
The minute you project the source of
happiness is out something outside of
yourself, you now are victim.
The catastrophe hasn't have happened
yet, but it's inevitable. Yeah. Because
if your happiness is dependent on an
external over which you have no control,
this is a world of transition. Nothing
remains the same. Nothing remains the
same.
Nothing remains the same. It's a world
of constant evolutionary change.
biologically evolutionary. Evolution is
constantly changing.
That which you think is eternal slowly
turns to rust and dissolves. You see,
and when you visit places like Egypt
where, you know,
some 12,000 years of prior history, uh
you begin to get a feeling for what age
is, what age is, you see. So if you
attach your happiness then or your
survival to something that is out there
uh now it's only a matter of time
that out thereess can also be a mental
position a positionality in which you
become enamored.
We get emails
all the time from people that are
enamored of some concept and something
in some book doesn't agree with that uh
point of view. You know, and you can see
like the child in them is just enamored
of this concept. You know, usually we
get whales and dolphins at least a
couple times a month.
like dolphins are going to get them to
heaven. Is it Jesus Christ going to be
your savior or a dolphin? I don't know.
You gota make
I don't know why whales and dolphins
calibrate what they do. We got an expert
here with us today. Maybe she'll explain
to us. She already did explain to me,
but I forgot what it was.
Uh because something calibrates below
200 doesn't mean that it's no good.
It just means that I wouldn't consult
them uh in their office about an
amputation or something.
You really don't want a brain surgeon
who calibrates below 200.
But you know, most pets, our birds and
things like that, all the things we love
and we adore below 200. Doesn't mean
that it's not lovable and that it isn't
of any intrinsic value.
It's just it means that you wouldn't
consult them about your legal affairs,
you know.
So if we see that the world is
transitory and
that the process going on is one of
evolution,
evolution then is the way we witness
creation.
The way we witness creation is
evolutionary unfolding of potentiality
becoming an actuality
which we then sequentially witness and
project the concept of time to an out
there.
Well, that'll get get you a PhD right
there. Just write that up for your
professor. I mean,
I don't know what it means, but it sure
sounds impressive.
Except that that's what happens as you
let go identifying without theirness
with positionalities
then you withdraw into witnessing
you become your life becomes
witnessing
without you know an involvement without
a committed projection of positionality
out there. They say,
"Well, you're all going to be executed
tomorrow." You say, "Okay."
No, it's called off. Oh, okay.
No, it's going to be this afternoon. All
right.
When you reach that point, you know
you're there. So,
I mean, who cares if it's inevitable?
something that's inevitable. You can see
how meaningless time is.
I mean, how long it's been since you've
had a migraine headache doesn't help you
anyone you got one.
So, you can see how inconsequential time
is on your deathbed. If it was 70 years,
17 years, or seven years, what
difference does it make?
People cling to longevity. If you do
this, you can live a little longer.
You need a doctor.
All right. So, we get positionalized, we
get brainwashed, we become enamored of
concepts.
Uh, and the real trap is to
become enamored and place your survival
on something out there.
Success,
good fortune, better grades, money, good
looks.
uh
any kind of an out there. Physique, your
good looks, your glamour, all those
things are transitory. All those things
are transitory.
Now, the Buddha taught that a long time
ago. If this is a world that's
transitory, everything comes and goes.
Therefore, to get attached to anything
inevitably brings suffering.
Inevitably brings suffering. To become
immune to suffering, then
become attached to nothing. Value
everything and become attached to none
of it. Value it all and become attached
to none of it. None of it is special.
See,
one pair of pants is good as another.
She doesn't like them when they're all
frazzled and they have holes in them.
You're not going to wear those today,
are you? I say, what's wrong with them?
I always say nobody will notice it. And
she always says everybody will notice
it.
I got away with a frazzle one. She
didn't know that.
One time I said, "Nobody notices those
things." Then I said, "How many people
did?" Jesus said, "About a third of the
people raised her hand."
So therefore, she's right and I was
wrong. Yeah. So, I don't place any value
on being right. I mean, being being
right puts you in a vulnerable position.
It's It's easier to be wrong.
Nobody hates you when you're wrong. You
realize that you walk around saying,
"I'm wrong. Don't feel bad about it.
Here,
I'm broke. I'm wrong." Yeah. Here, you
need some money. Here's a check. How?
But if you're a winner in this world, uh
oh,
look out.
They've discovered that you have an
unpaid parking ticket from 23 years ago.
And now that's on the all the blob
sites.
Glob sites. Blog sites. Glob sites. What
do they call those? Bloggers.
>> Bloggers.
>> Blog sites. Yes.
Yes. They found out the doctor had an
unpaid parking ticket in Cottonwood 42
years ago. Actually, I'll tell you, I
might as well review my dark past.
I did get a parking ticket in Cottonwood
about 15 years ago.
Parked near a loading zone.
I got a ticket and I went to court and
the fine was $1
and he he he dismissed the dollar.
Now you know my dark deep say past.
Yes. You actually dismissed the dollar.
I got a kick out of it. Core gas to go
there, didn't you?
I showed up for court. I was the only
guy there, the magistrate.
Guilty or not guilty? Guilty.
Okay. So when we own up to things like
that, now what can people do to you?
So another way to avoid pain anxiety is
to own everything you can think of that
possibly could be pictured as your
downside, real or not real,
whether it's real, whether it's fiction,
just write it all down and be okay with
it. You're dumb and ugly.
short and stupid. Yep.
Think of all the nicknames people could
call you and get it get attached to
them.
Nowadays, everybody's so sensitive. See,
they used to call me shorty.
I suppose nowadays I I should be
sensitive and have a parade. short
shorts writes.
Yeah. So sensitivity, you know, this is
the age of narcissism. Narcissism, the
big the
eye. So we don't want to get attached to
narcissism. what other people think
about us, our image.
We don't got to get attached to anything
that is outside of our self, outside of
our own reality. Then that takes you
within your own reality and you say,
"What within myself is causing any kind
of anxiety or pain and you'll see that
it's attachments to a positionality,
a certain perception in which you have
become enamored enamored.
I get defendants of whales and dolphins
all the time. What is it? Did they go to
the whale church? Is their mother a
whale? What is it?
You get people committed to bull
fighting. They're they're insulted that
bull fighting cal.
So this is becoming enamored. Enamored.
You become an afficionando of a
mystique. So the trap the next trap is
mystique.
It is the thing. It's the whole
glamorized mystique of it.
Very popular on college campuses. The
mystique
of certain political social
positionalities. Every professor has to
drop a remark about that to show how
with it he is with this whole mystique.
Oh yeah.
So you try to avoid getting programmed.
The difficulty with avoid avoiding
programmed is that you can't avoid it.
However, you can become aware that you
that you're being programmed uh all the
time.
It's because of the nature of
consciousness itself.
As we said, evol from an evolutionary
viewpoint. The human mind is
intrinsically incapable of discerning
truth from falsehood.
The best it can do is reasoned
likelihoods, probabilities.
And within the Newtonian paradigm, you
can meet arithmetic
scientific criteria within philosophy,
if you if you follow a dialectic, a
certain dialectic,
uh, which philosophers nowadays don't
bother with. They just say anything they
want to because relativism has replaced,
uh, the dialectic of truth. You see, and
relativism is whatever you feel like is
true is true.
Whatever you feel like is true. So
that's it's a wonderful new world. You
see,
a world of live nude sex. We're going to
have the ACLU is championing live nude
sex. And uh I guess we should jump in
with the ACLU and all cheer on my view
nude sex
because uh the interpretation you know
is that
uh behavior is is a style of uh speech.
The minute you rule that
because speech is free and action is
stylized speech. Now there's no
restriction on action and so we have the
emerging of anarchy and therefore we
predict there will be you know the
impact of anarchy on a civilization
which has relied on structure. When you
remove the structure from society you
have New Orleans
Mr.
Chsky's a dream come true. Chsky, you
know, is sort of a darling in academia,
at least was for some years. He and
Maruz
and and you know, he's an anarchist. So,
you get to see what anarchy is. So,
those of you who are enthused about that
kind of a philosophy, I suggest you go
to New Orleans and help out because
there you have anarchy. No federal
government, no state, no local, no
police, no fire, no law, no cop. And uh
so how you would u picture that is the
ideal society is beyond me. It's because
of idealization mentalization. So the
difficulty with the mind is it can't
tell reality from its own
mentalizations.
So you can make up endless arguments for
anarchy
which sound good in theory. And then
when you face the reality of it, you're
lucky if you can walk down a city street
without darning getting disease or shot
robbed or
uh so in reality many things are quite
different than their abstract
conceptualization.
So another thing not to get attached to
another pitfall another
uh trap then is an endless
mentalization. Endless mentalization to
become enamored of mentalization. So,
you know, skepticism is an example of
that you know and in which you become
enamored of your own mentalizations
without any difference to a higher uh
authority etc.
The narcissism then presumes that the
way I see the world is the way it is and
if it isn't that way we should pass a
law to make it that way.
Yeah.
The other traps which spiritual people
tend to run into usually early in the
game, not later but early in the game is
becoming enamored of entrancing
romanticized spiritual fiction and
thinking that it is truth and fact. In
the spiritual bookstores,
I'd say about 60% in the spiritual
bookstores is u fiction. Yeah, we have
permission to ask this.
>> It's over about 60% 65%.
70%.
Anyway, most of what's in a spiritual
bookstore is fiction. They don't say
fiction on this side, truth on this
side.
The big sellers are the code books.
There's not a single code book that
calibrates over 200.
There are no secret codes. We've said
that many a time. How could that which
is infinite and nonlinear?
You know, play the cutesy child game of
let's have a secret and hide a code
in the nostril hairs of the camel.
Count the nostal hairs in the camel.
You find there's a hidden biblical
message there.
Jesus is really gay.
And Mary was really his mother-in-law.
They were to the predecessors of the
Bush family
and the secrets of God are hidden in the
DNA of your toenails.
So you see
the next trap is the child's mind. The
child's mind is so easily glamorized
uh with the unique, the special. There's
always entities from the future and
other dimensions coming to to sell you
the secrets that the world is going to
end in 2023
849.
Reminds me of the old joke about the
college professor. The student, the
professor says, you know, the world's
going to end in uh 10 billion years. The
student back puts his hand up.
Professor, president, what' you say? Oh,
I thought you said 10 million.
That's the kind of letters we get.
Is it 10 billion or 10 million? I mean,
what do you care really?
You're not going to even be around. If
the end of the world is coming, we're
all going. So, what's the big deal
anyway?
The dumbest thing I can think of is
committing suicide before the world
ends.
That's what that cult did. Remember,
they all took LSD and killed themselves
because the world was coming. That was
the BBOP comet. Halaob comet.
Bbop comet. Yeah.
people come the world is coming to an
end. So people are friends are going out
in the desert and and wait for the UFOs
to pick them up.
Yeah. So
there's a book out called Odd Gods. Odd
gods. And it lists them all. And you may
find yourself in there when you were
younger.
Found some of my favorite uh heroes in
there, you know. So anybody
that's new becomes involved is attracted
by the astral circus. The child in you
loves the magic of it all. Magic. Every
day we get spiritual magazines and
brochures. None of them calibrate over
200 telling you the wonders of what you
hold in mind tends to manifest.
What you what you hold in mind tends to
manifest.
What you hold in mind tends to manifest.
Heat.
Am
I right? Okay.
Heat. Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
HEAT.
NO, that's right.
Heat. Heat.
Amazing
Grace and then we'll we'll be done.
How's that?
>> And then you're going to do uh Queen of
My Heart.
>> I just did.
>> Okay.
>> I spaced out at it.
>> The the the problem with with bag pipes
and and arranging for bag pipes is
>> uh that you have to you have to kind of
fit the tunes to the bag pipes. Uh so
and and not having heard it on bag pipes
before, I got it off the internet and
did all kinds of tweaking to it. Uh but
that that's what that was. Uh my version
of Queen of My Heart. Uh we're going to
play one that that will be real familiar
to everybody. Amazing Grace. Uh and then
we'll we'll finish with Scott the Brave.
How's that?
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
All right.
Heat.
HEAT.
Let's get the energy.
4 520 525 53 535 54
That's what 535 feels like.
Forget reading about it.
I thought something experiential.
There's nothing for the mind to think
about. Just be with experience.
That's 535. What it feels like. And what
is 535?
It's the valor of the heart.
The reason
everyone cries. Mhm.
is uh
because it reflects the heart of man.
That's the heart of mankind.
It's the courage to live the human life.
Yeah,
it's the energy of valor,
standing for truth,
the willingness to die,
for honor,
commitment, country, king, queen, God.
It's the energy of valor.
525 530 535
is standing up for the truth and the
courage to walk into the bullets.
Uhhuh. To die for that which you hold
most dear.
Therefore,
it's transfiguring
and it is a certain level we go through.
It's also reflective of the innocence of
the child
because it is that innate innocence of
which makes man vulnerable to error.
It is because of the innocence of the
child that millions
have believed what they were told.
Gross propaganda stuff that calibrates
70 80 90.
But because of the innocence of the
child, they follow the pi piper over the
cliff
to not know truth from falsehood. Not
know truth from falsehood.
Whether the cause for which one gave up
one's life
was factual and true or not within the
heart of the child. It is.
Why is that the human mind is so
vulnerable to falsehood?
Because of the innocence of the child.
The child trusts completely trusts its
mother and father
family.
It believes everything it hears is true,
including nowadays what it hears on
television.
And study shows that the physiology of
the child's brain cannot differentiate.
Why? Because the mind is programmed so
rapidly, you can't catch it being
programmed. It's programmed at one less
than 110,000 of a second.
As we said in previous lectures, the
experience or edge of the ego
is an event that occurs in less than one
10,000th of a second.
Your mind can't move fast enough to
catch it being self getting being
programmed. That's why you can't catch
the silence between two thoughts.
The silence between two thoughts, your
mind would have to move faster than one
10,000 of a second and it can't.
Therefore, the infinite space between
thought is not actually between
thoughts. It's below thoughts
cannot be perceived by the mind. And all
the people who spent many years
meditating trying to catch that space
between the two thoughts. Nobody has
ever succeeded.
Anybody here succeed? Any Buddhists
here?
No. It's a mistransation from the
Buddha. Anyway, it's not between two
thoughts. It's prior to two thoughts.
So as we heard the music it took you out
of thinking this took you into the realm
of the heart and there was really
nothing to think about there. Everybody
was too busy crying to think what is
there to think about.
It brings forth a subjective
experiential reality that is beyond
time. The energy that was sounded today
is as old as mankind.
The reason we weep is its adivistic
origin.
The loot is very old and of course that
kind of music and I gave up the bag
pipes because you have to have a thumb
to stop the stop up the air hole in the
top of the chanter and you can't. So I
gave it up, you know. So I tried to get
a clarinet maker or somebody to put a
valve on it, you know. I thought you
could thump even with a stump you could
give it a stump stop.
Anyway,
it's okay with the neighbors. The
neighbors said it's okay.
Okay. If you don't practice the back
fight,
I give up the violin for the same reason
and also archery. So,
the neighbors are safer than they were.
However, I can still play the bugle.
Therefore,
it's the intrinsic innocence within us
that the human mind is set up like the
hardware of a computer.
It cannot
guard itself against the software that's
being put in. It cannot guard itself. If
in the middle of that music we stopped
it and shouted a certain word, you're
programmed with that forever.
Let's say in the middle of the music we
stopped shouted just any any old word
50 years from now
that'll still come to your mind. You
didn't have you had no you had no say
yes. You had no say over it.
You couldn't edit it. It's a done deal.
You say right in the middle of the bag
pipe somebody shouted
the f word. would say right
bl
for for the next 50 years your mind is
programmed with that. You can recall
tell your grandchildren right in the
middle of the bank pipe.
Anyway, the reason people got cry of
course is because they get the sacred
heart. It's the sacred heart that they
hear hear and feel in that music, you
know. It's the
It's the oneness of humanness,
the identification with all of humanity
throughout all of time. That's the sound
I hear in it. What I hear is the heart
of man
walking on despite the sicissitude no
matter what. walking into the hail of
bullets if that's what it takes. If
that's what it takes
or dying in deathbed as the women did.
And birth. The men died in the
battlefield. The women died in giving
birth.
And our family bible of this, you know,
many of the men had three or four wives.
Then you see she had four children. Then
she left and he got a new one. Then she
had five more children. She died in the
fifth.
So the woman's bravery and valor
was facing the high likelihood of death
in childbirth itself which of course
still goes on just as war goes on
and the strength
and the courage to walk on the human
life is what makes man noble.
You see the nobility of man
So despite the vicissitude then the
courage to face and own the truth the
acknowledge the reality behind our own
existence
uh is transformative.
The reason bag pipes are important then
is because you get to experience what
that energy is.
Very few people get beyond except 499.
We said only 4% of the human population
transcends energy level 500.
Energy level 540. Unconditional love is
transcended by only 0.4% of the
population.
So love is relatively rare. 4% are
really capable of love.
What they talk about is enamored,
sexually involved, attracted,
possessiveness, control, dependency,
but love, etc. as a level of
consciousness, as a way of being in the
world occurs only 4% of population.
For that love to be unconditional is
0.4.
So in the bag pipe we heard was 535.
That's almost unconditional.
Almost.
Almost. Al almost.
But you can still put a sword thrown
through the enemy.
You got five point leeway. Take that
jester
for king and country.
Yeah.
All right. So we hear in the sound then
experiential.
So we were jumping from
the out there of the Newtonian paradigm
to the inheress of the subjective
reality of spiritual truth. That's a
jump which few people can make. four
people make and 4% of people make even
the great geniuses of time you know
Einstein drew back from it Einstein drew
back even though great scientists who
were religious Newton and all of them
were quite religious and yet could not
give reality to the subjective to
consciousness itself and the Heisenberg
principle is still argued of course in
the world of science
and the significance of equals MC's
you know it has been accepted but the
Heisenberg principle itself is still uh
argument argued
you see in the realm of science and
theology uh science and religion all the
magazines and journals uh calibrate in
the mid 400s they can't so they can't be
about they can be about religion and
science and religion because science is
in the 400s and theology is in the 400s.
But spirituality experientially you see
is at 500.
There is no conceptual
uh extraction you can take from the
sound of the music that we all
experience together. And I wanted us to
all experience it together because it
has a certain bonding quality. Having
heard it, it's unforgettable. You can
never forget that sound.
Why? Because it's such an ancient sound.
Not the biop bag pipes themselves, but
the energy of the bag pipes is very
ancient. It's as ancient as man. You
know, even when there was no bag pipes,
that same energy ran through people
and bonded mankind together. Otherwise,
we would never have survived. We fight
and kill each other. But without the
bonding of the heart, we wouldn't have
survived long enough to kill each other.
Dear God, keep thank you for keeping me
alive long enough to kill my brother.
That's true. You got to stay alive long
enough to die. You can't die without
having lived. So
what difference does it make when you
finally die? You see, you know, that's
another the hypothetical gets confused
with the real. As we said, if you have a
severe headache, it doesn't matter how
long it's been since you had the last
one, because this headache is sufficient
until the moment thereof.
Uh
so the trap then of becoming enamored of
romantic, fanciful, spiritual fiction.
And you know, I get letters all the time
from people who take it seriously and
they write me these serious serious
treatises all about it as if it was some
kind of a reality. Some kind of a
reality. Some of the bestselling books
around.
I guess the author presumed they
realized it was fiction or they presumed
that the reader would realize it's
fiction, but the reader is naive and the
child and the reader thinks it's truth.
There's people that are willing to die
for spiritual fiction. Spiritual
fiction. And they're willing to die for
it. They do. They actually die for it.
Die for spiritual fiction. All right.
So, one of the traps then is the naive
and the innocence of the mind. The only
way it can really be acknowledged is by
humility. So, therefore, one of the
basic qualities of spiritual evolution
is humility.
to realize the downside of the human
mind that without help from usually
external
it's not possible to arrive at the truth
by oneself. Therefore,
the great religion, the great avatars
uh
represented the energy field without
which mankind would not be able to grasp
its own reality. Without that energy
field of the avatar, radiating down
through the centuries for a thousand
years, uh there's no the human mind has
no capacity to realize the truth of its
own existence, much less the origin of
its own existence.
human mind is incapable of it. So that
was the function. Then the great
spiritual figures of history
contextualize reality from an overall
greater context than human experience.
Many countries then you see Europe
especially many many
um were theocracies for some
generations. They were out of religion
was formed the structure of the society,
its laws, its courts, its orderliness,
morals and ethics etc. And then some of
course later became secular didn't want
to acknowledge the the source but the
source of secular countries is 100%
religious. All secular sec secular
countries in Europe
originated from a theological position.
Right and wrong, responsibility,
accountability, guilt versus innocence,
the basic tenants of civilization and
society arose out of theological
concepts. Yeah. Mhm. And then later on
you can refute them and say we don't
want any theology and we don't want any
religion and we don't want God anywhere.
The ACLU sent me a solicitation the
other day and and I was going to put a
$100 bill in there until I noticed on
$100 bill it said in God we trust. So I
didn't want to offend them. So I put it
back in my pocket and spend it on
foolishness.
Oh God
in God we trust. Yeah, see the
constitution says let let the congress
not establish any religion
nor prohibit the practice thereof
nor prohibit the practice thereof. And
you notice how the secularists always
give you the first part.
Never do they give you the second part.
Whether putting up a Christmas tree is
establishing a religion, I don't know.
But it certainly is
uh enjoying the practice the row you
know you see so then is so selective so
you can see a positionalized mind
doesn't like the second half of the uh
sentence so it just ignores it
gives you the warp the half half the
truth warp you know
it does not say and nowhere does it say
separation of church or state nowhere
Where does it say separation or church
or state? Those three words do not even
appear. So all the endless quoting of
certain things
are the traps that we fall into. Those
are the traps of memes. Meme and and a
meme is a saying which is spoken so
often that everybody begins to assume
it's truth. Everybody thinks the
constitution says separation of church
and state. How many people here believe
that?
Rest of you are lying. Uh
before I said that, how many people
would say all right
separation of church and state was the
con was an interpretation a judicial
interpretation
the and if you don't believe me look at
it because I looked over there is no
words separation or church or state
those three words do not appear none of
them in the constitution to let the
congress not establish a religion nor
prohibit the free practice thereof.
So another trap then is we get
brainwashed without knowing it. You
repeat separation of church and state
over and over again. Probably after
about a while everybody thinks that's
what the constitution says.
How many people run into their library,
pull out the big book and reread the
constitution to see what the hell it
says? I did. You know I did. I did.
meticulously. In fact, I clipped it out
and put it on my bullet board. This is
what the Constitution says.
Few of us left in the world that know
what the Constitution actually says.
Why? Because the media have so
brainwashed us that even
integrous people, integrous people uh
are programmed to believe that which is
facious. Mhm.
So,
one of the biggest traps in is our
naivete.
Our naivee. What time do we have to
stop?
>> 11.
>> Huh?
>> 11:15.
>> Okay. Okay.
I have to check with the timekeeper.
What ending are we?
When you hit go to the subjective, when
you go to the experiential, you sort of
lose track of time. you because you're
dealing in timelessness.
The ego superimposes
time. It put like tra puts it on the
bottom of the uh the tape as it's going
by. It puts a time track on experience.
But that's a projection of the ego
within the experiential world itself.
There is no such thing. That's a
concept, a Newtonian concept, an
extraction. We superimpose a measurement
called time and then project it as
though time exists out there. And as
long as we stay within that paradigm, it
works. E= MC² works. It works so long as
you stay within that paradigm. But once
you get outside of that paradigm, uh
it's meaningless. Meaningless.
It's easy to tolerate the world and
stay in a position of goodwill
if you see its evolutionary nature. The
phenomenal world is constantly changing
and you see that it's con constantly
emerging. The potentiality of this arm
to rise in the air uh does so because
that's the actualization of that
potentiality.
And if a certain thought should occur in
the mind, then the hand will do what it
did. But it's doing that autonomously.
There's no cause for the hand to do
that. You say, well, it was the thought.
Yeah, but there was no cause for the
thought. The thought was also
spontaneous. Therefore, the next
realization is that everything is
happening of its own.
Nothing is being caused by anything.
Everything is autonomous, spontaneous
and unfolding.
Each thing is expressing the essence of
that which it is,
not as a cause and effect, but as an
automatic spontaneous consequence of
that which it is.
The ego likes to take credit. Oh, I
thought of that.
The ego did not think of that.
All that occurs is occurring
autonomously and spontaneously. There is
no cause.
How about being deliberate and say,
"Well, I can be deliberately." Yeah, but
you're being spontaneously deliberate.
You are being autonomously spontaneously
deliberate.
Otherwise, I'd have to say, "I'm going
to be spontaneous and I'm going to be
spontaneous about being spontaneous."
But that was deliberate.
Yes. But deliberation was spontaneously.
I did.
I'm trying to get you behind the scenery
so that you see, you know, like the
Wizard of Oz.
Don't pay any attention to me back here.
You're the Wizard of Oz. Don't pay any
attention to me back here.
Everything is actually autonomously
happening as a consequence of that which
it is. Simultaneously
that which it is is what it means.
What a thing is and its meaning are one
in the same thing. You see to try and
define it, you've already got a duality
of this meaning of that.
What a thing means is what it is.
What does the sound of the bag pipe
mean? I can tell you what it recalls.
What it reverberates well with.
It means what it is.
That sound.
That's the last sound a warrior wanted
to hear was the sound of bag pipes
coming over the hill.
The last sound you want to hear on the
battlefield is the sound of bag pipes of
the enemy coming towards you
because you know this is death.
This is death. You're going to live or
die. There's an absolute sound to it. An
absoluteness
without which the heart of mankind we
would none of would have none of us
would have survived
without that valor and that courage
which is inherent. Most people don't
even acknowledge it in themsel. Do you
realize what it takes to be a human
being to walk around with your head up
in this world of assistitudes from
moment to moment? Within any second you
can be snuffed out.
You can start off the day with a
headache
and then it gets worse.
Now to just survive the cicissitudes of
tiredness of sickness and death and the
fact that everything everything that
that you value eventually disappears.
Everything that you hang on to sooner or
later goes away. And therefore how to
live in the world without suffering pain
of loss and frustration and desire
is the contentness. Contentness with the
subjectivity of that which you are in
the immediate moment.
Everything as it is as it is. And with
complete and total acceptance. It can be
that way all the time. All the time.
When they're about to be head your take
your head off. You say to the headsman,
"Listen, don't feel bad about it. It's
your job. You know what I mean? That's
what I tell him. Listen, don't worry,
man. Just do your thing. You know,
I mean, somebody's got to be the
husband, you know what I mean? He's got
a wife, kids to feed. You know what I
mean? Or he gets so much ahead, you
know?
My head is his supper. You know what I
mean?
In that way, you can al almost transcend
physical pain. Of course, I've explained
to you how I've done it and had surgery
without anesthesia.
And that's by taking no positionality
and
absolutely not resisting the next one
10,000 of a second. The minute you
resist the pain, it's it's excruciating.
The minute you surrender to it, then
it's like you're lifted out of it. And
as the surgery went on, I was lifted
into a beatotific space. I was sorry
when it was over.
Isn't there something else you got to
snip or cut?
Constantly surrendering actually allows
you to go into an infinite timeless
space of exquisite joy and peace. It was
like the angelic forces lift you out of
your body and you witness the
physicality but you're not subject to
the physicality.
Beatotific state. So those are also
available to us. the beatotific states
that mankind has experienced
and the sound of the heart and the bag
pipes also gives us a vision of that
also a vision
which is somewhat represented by
religion in a certain way there's a
certain semiilitary
um mystique about religion also
uh the heart of the warrior the
breastplate
uh etc are symbolic ic spiritual
and ethical principles
by which man stands. You see, man stands
and civilization stands by certain of
these principles.
So that's what I thought we should
experience together. I wanted us to do
it together. Experience the heart of
mankind, the heart of the child, the
valor that goes beyond time.
Um, that sound is that energy and if you
cling to it, it will take you through
anything. I've gone through anything
with that energy within myself. And as
Susan has told me,
through the fear and the agony and the
pain of childbirth,
the heart of all the women who have
faced it, lived it, survived it and died
in the midst of it, bled to death or
died if child had fever. The valor then
the courage of the human being
uh is what we salute today. And uh
so I thought together we could salute
the heart of man kind.
>> Huh? Let's all salute the man kind
mankind. God bless us all. Amen. We'll
take a break.
Am I on? Yes.
Well, here we we reassembled.
The reason the lecture came to an end
was because I couldn't really talk
anymore.
How many people here cried or felt like
crying? Isn't that amazing?
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. And we touch the core of the
heart. Yeah. That's why.
So, it's hard to keep talking after
that. So we limp through it at the end.
All right.
Okay. So now about a third of the people
knew and therefore we run through the
basics again. uh because every time you
run through it uh it's a little
different
uh different emphasis and because of the
the title of the lecture for instance um
today the t the lecture the title is the
title of the lecture is
what the heck is the name of the lecture
>> oh yeah
traps.
>> Oh, yes. Traps. Oh, okay.
All right. So, the trap we were talking
about before where you put your survival
on something outside of yourself.
What's the source of that besides naive
is that the person is coming from lack.
See, within the Newtonian dimension,
everything goes from incomplete to
complete. From incomplete. See,
everything is incomplete.
When you transcend the Newtonian way of
witnessing the world, you see everything
goes from complete to complete, from per
perfection to perfection to perfection.
You understand that everything is
complete and perfect being what it is at
this moment. This is the perfect halfex
extended hand. It's not an imperfect
extended hand. It's perfect perfectly
half extended hand. You understand?
What you witness is perfection which is
continuous. You you realize the
emergence of potentiality is actuality
because that is the consequence of
evolution. Evolution is the constant
unfolding of the emergence of
potentiality coming into actuality
which is a continuous
process.
Beyond that there's a a realm in which
there isn't a continuous process but to
make the audience happy we'll say that
because that's the perceptual world or
the map of consciousness uh evolved out
of um
uh I don't know if I ever written about
any place but anyway the way it happened
was
um I had a huge clinic back east We got
we had impossibly difficult impossible
hopeless cases from all over the world.
Uh they already seen all the world's
experts
and we're hopeless. So
my case law was made up made up of the
impossible
hopelessly incurable
and everybody throwing up their hands.
And so I used everything I could to help
a patient get well. I wasn't concerned
with my colleagues. I can remember a
patient sitting in my office and I knew
what I thought would help them and I
knew that there wasn't a anybody in the
world of science that would approve of
it.
So
the question then to be answered, I
remember the question in my mind.
My allegiance is to God. I I swore an
oath to do all I could to help my
patient. That's my obligation to thee,
oh Lord.
for that I was answerable.
Therefore, I always did what I thought
would help a patient. In those days, any
thing considered holistic was laughed
at. You know, acupuncture and all those
things.
Of course, I myself was cured. I had a
I'm finishing a new book now. I finished
transcending the levels of consciousness
and devotional non-duality. And now I'm
doing another one.
Three books at once. Anyway, in this in
in this particular book, I got do give
some personal experiences which I seldom
do in lectures. But
myself recovered from a lot of very
severe illnesses. In fact, the number of
illnesses I had coverage
just listing them all from gout to
diverticulitis,
perforating pancreatitis to god knows
what all. And um so I did anything that
I thought would help a patient. Um I'll
just throw in about because I mentioned
acupuncture. I had a tractable incurable
douadal ulcer for 25 years. First it
would burrow into one place and then
another another.
And sooner or later they said doc you're
going to have to have your stomach taken
out and it's going to perforate and then
I got pancreatitis because it was
burring into the back of the douadum
into the pancreas.
And uh we heard about acupuncture. It
was kind and it when they first came to
America, the first acupuncture clinic
was in Washington DC
and you had to get it was under scrutiny
and uh you had to bring X-rays before
when you start treatment then you had to
get the X-rays after treatment. So I
heard acupuncture was painless. So I
laid down there in the thing and he put
this needle through my wrist. It went
right through it for God's sake and I
screamed with pain.
I thought and he says ho ho ho bad bad
bad ulcer huh
he didn't speak any English to the
translator old Chinese so
after uh you know I lived for 25 years
on one kind of medication or another
by the third treatment it was cured
the third treatment I would never be
drinking espresso coffee I'll tell you
with an active dude ulcer
The third third treatment it was cured.
So you read a lot of scientific in the
coat articles poo pooing acupuncture
that they did double blinds and it's all
BS.
Yeah. So what works is what works. So of
course I heard about kinesiology and Jen
Diamond. So I went to uh attend a
lecture on kinesiology.
I was looking for everything that would
help patients. Nutrition, we wrote a
book about that with Linus falling. Uh
changing the the whole environment of
the m the brain and changing the brain
physiology through through mass action
and various things. Uh
so what was I talking about? Oh yeah,
John Diamond. So he's a great lecturer
and uh it was a wonderful course and of
course the way they demonstrated and
we've done it many times in our lectures
was uh you put something over your solar
plexus you go weak. There's a lot of
people that don't believe that either
but I don't know what universe they live
in but
the observation that was primordial to
our developing this whole map of
consciousness
uh was I was giving lectures to the
staff on kinesiology. We were using it
now for evaluating medications and
diagnosis and various things. You know,
a person was diagnosed as schizophrenia
and the back of my mind as I'm listening
to him, I'm thinking mercury poisoning.
Sure enough, the arm says mercury
poisoning. We get a hair test which
science also poo poos and there in the
hair was all the mercury.
And so we kated him which science poo
poos and removed the mercury and he came
back to sanity. So it wasn't
schizophrenia, it was mercury
intoxication. He was mad as a hatter.
In fact, my mind said he's mad as a
hatter.
So people got cured and healed right and
left by non-traditional, unscientific
uh unproven methodologies.
And but when I s so I was teaching the
the staff everything I we'd go and we
went all over the place you know we
checked out cerebral allergy all kinds
of things that science what of course we
put would poo poo and uh so then I would
bring it back to the staff and then I'd
give a lecture on what I learned to the
staff we share it we check it out with
patients and see if what worth it could
possibly be and most of these things
that were approved by science frankly
that's what was wrong with the patient
and they recovered right and left.
Functional hypoglycemia, all kinds of
things that people don't agree with was
exactly what was wrong with them. I
said, "You stop eating sugar and sweets
and you stop feeling like killing
yourself." Sure enough, by the time they
got to the office or the first
appointment, they say, "I don't know,
doc. The depression is gone."
Functional hypoglycemia, another
unscientific
concept.
So, Oh, yeah. So, I was going to teach
the staff about it. So, we had the
staff. I needed some volunteers. So we
had uh the second attitudinal healing
center in the United States. Jim Polski
came out west or east rather.
He was in Timuron and I was in New York.
Yeah. So anyway, he brought the whole
staff. They spent the whole weekend and
I had a big house and shared with the
staff how to do use the course of
miracles in
intractable patients. And so anyway, we
had an act active uh attitudinal healing
center where people with intractable
illnesses also incurable.
Uh but uh anybody who's done the course
of miracles, the same people recover
from all kinds of intractable illnesses.
You know, depending on your karmic
potentiality. People always forget that
karmic potentiality. You may or may not
have permission to recover from it. But
anyway,
um
so I wanted to give a lecture. So I
asked for volunteers and some course uh
some uh yeah attitudinal healing center
people were there. So I said um would
you like to volunteer tonight? And they
said okay. Well one thing that that we
demonstrated consistently diamond if you
look at fluorescent lights everybody
goes weak. Everybody goes weak if they
look florescent lights. Whole pesticides
artificial sweeteners everybody goes
weak. So I took a couple of guys and I
said they volunteered and I said okay.
said now look at the fluorescent lights
and they did not go weak. I said
weirdo.
I said try sweet and low they did not go
weak. Try pesticides they did not go
weak. I said what in the world is this?
The people who done the course of
miracles do not go weak with things that
made everybody I mean everybody goes
weak with fluorescent lights.
So that began the research. So we got
some new students in the course of
miracles. were just starting in two or
three of them. And we tested them uh
every couple of weeks with fluorescent
lights and sweet and low was the
standard in those days. I apologize to
sweet and low is probably innocuous, but
that's what we used. Now we use
pesticides. Yeah, pesticides. Don't eat
pesticides. Nobody assume you're saying
pesticides make you feel bad. Anyhow,
so anyway. Anyway, then we found uh so
we followed them every serial checking
them out every week or every couple
weeks and we found that these people who
went weak with uh fluorescent lights
consistently for months about the time
they got to less than 75 in the course
of miracles they stopped going weak.
The fluorescent lights did not make them
go weak anymore. I said whoa whoa whoa.
So that's how we got the evolution of
consciousness. you're and that's what
ended up as as the calibrated levels of
consciousness was that discovery
that folks during the course of miracles
no longer went weak.
So
that was really a stunning finding.
Okay. And out of that came the map of
consciousness
uh which is in power versus force is in
every language in the world right now.
every language in the world. And
so that was the beginning of it. And
then we found we could um I found we
could calibrate it on a scale
in which a thousand is the highest you
can reach in in in this world. So we we
we developed the scale logarithmic scale
with death at zero and a thousand at the
highest level that's ever walked the
earth. And they were all the great
avatars. Buddha, Christ or aster
uh at 1,00
the human nervous system cannot tolerate
anything beyond that. In fact, when you
get to around 800, it's quite painful
very frequently. And if there's anything
out in yourself that you picked up from
the collective unconscious, it's like a
fierce fire, like your whole aura is on
fire. And um until you find out what it
is and through prayer and meditation etc
clear it you know whatever whatever it
is you're holding in mind that is not
the absolute truth will cause an inner
agony and pain which the Buddha
described as being attacked by demons
where the demons are within yourself of
course within your own feeling a field
of consciousness and therefore as you
evolve you keep discovering new things
that you have to forgive within. than
yourself and they're not your personal
self. So up to a certain level it's the
personal self that you look back and um
stop hating people who are disrespectful
or rude or don't agree with you etc. But
when you get up to around 800 uh you're
picking up from the collective
unconscious. So you can't find in your
own lifetime this or any previous
lifetime any explanation from it. What
you've done is you've picked it up. So
one of the traps which you described
this morning is that you go get pro
programmed by collective belief systems
and it happens so fast you hardly know
that you just got programmed and then
later through spiritual inner searching.
You you discover this within yourself
and you wonder where in the world it
came from. Where in the world did it
come from? And you picked it up from the
collective like the belief in
osteoporosis.
Uh you pick it up from the collective. I
never believed in having osteoporosis.
Uh as far as I knew, men didn't even get
osteoporosis in my day in medical
school. They were all little bent over
ladies, you know. They're all like
little bent over ladies that had
osteoporosis. But guys didn't get it. It
wasn't a guy thing, you know.
Anyway, you picked that up from the
collective. How do you know you picked
it up from the collective? Because if
you got it, then you picked it up from
the collective.
Because the body does what the mind
believes. So unconsciously, you're
holding that that is a likelihood in
your own life. So anything that you
manifest, the body manifests what the
mind believes even though you don't
consciously remember believing it. So I
said, "Well, I don't think I've ever
believed in osteoporosis, much less uh
in myself." So
those things you learn just
experientially. So that's how the course
how the course of miracles played into
this and kinesiology played into it. It
all came out of holistic health and
treating hopeless people in which you
don't wish to leave any stone unturned.
I don't want to be a death door and face
the fact that on behalf of this patient
I was so worried about what my
colleagues would think about me that I
let them stay mad and commit suicide.
No, my responsibility
is to God to have done the best I can.
So the only one I'm ever satisfied
about, the only one I'm ever worried
about satisfying is my own own inner in
own inner integrity. That's all I worry
about. So when you do that, you become
autonomous. What the world thinks about
you is their problem. Yeah.
All right. So we developed this uh this
this map which of course is just
practical it's pragmatic.
Now it's also
you know illustrative in other words
uh the things that we say spiritually
these this is merely another way of
confirming it from a different
perspective.
So it's you might say confirmatory
u because what we're trying to calibrate
when we do levels of consciousness is
essence and because the mind cannot upel
appearance from essence
this is extremely useful
many of the things we wrote about in the
book uh power truth versus falsehood we
just held back the publication of it I
said listen we're getting enough static
as it says, "I don't need anymore. Let's
wait a little bit." They waited a few
months. But even then, we we said things
that are only now hitting uh like this
week, you know, this week. What do we
say? There were nine people in the
highest echelons of government that were
um what you call it. What do you call
anyway? There they surface now. So
uh the there's ways of knowing the way a
way of knowing this you see there's a
way of knowingness
uh a way of knowingness that transcends
the intellect and it transcends
positionality
and perception.
Uh so as we were mentioning this morning
as traps, you know, spiritual fiction,
which people take naively as truth and
um
the only way to tell spiritual fiction
from spiritual truth very often is you
just told the book. And I get lots of
books.
Please don't send me any books.
I don't want to read it. I don't want to
know his name. I just look at the book
and I say this calibrates. I can tell
just as my hand goes near it, I can tell
you what the calibration is going to be.
That's because we've done thousands and
thousands. This is about 180. We open
the book and it's 180. So,
because the mind has no way to tell
truth from falsehood, uh, this is of
great service. This is of great service
to us. Now, it's pragmatic. Pragmatic.
Uh, it's pragmatic. It stands on its
own. It's pragmatic. it stands on its
own. Um there we're not trying to prove
anything with it with it. Kinesiology
doesn't prove anything. It demonstrates
as best we can the prevalence of a
certain energy field and we know from
familiarity what that energy field is.
You felt 525 or 535 this morning. You
felt 535. You know what that is. So
that's 535. That's what it looks like.
What it feels like. What it sounds like.
That's what it is, you see. Uh, so we
confirm it, you know, we confirm it
experientially,
experientially.
All right. So, we'll move on to the
next. Anyway, uh,
move on to the next. We can talk
endlessly. And of course, when I first
started um, lecturing on this material,
we would spend a lot of hours on each of
these levels. each of these levels
because these levels are very critical
for recovery from various illnesses etc.
We know that the 12step groups
calibrated 540.
We know the workbook of the course of
miracles calibrates at 600. Uh and that
began our investigation then what is the
calibrated level of truth of all the
world's great religions and spiritual uh
teachings and subgroups etc.
Um,
that's an advantage the spiritual
seekers never had in the past. In the
past, they had the uh authority, the
reputation of a teacher. Um, the fact
that thousands of people rever a teacher
and think he's the greatest thing that
ever walked the earth doesn't have
anything to do with whether or not he is
or not doesn't have anything to do with
it.
In fact, it's the other way.
I get all kinds of emails about some
great savior of mankind and he
calibrates 160. You know what I'm
saying?
All right. So, we have a way then for
the first time in human history.
Therefore, I treat the you know our work
with respect because it is like a gift.
The inspiration of divinity within
expressed itself as a gift that mankind
has no way to tell truth from falsehood.
Yeah. Rest internal from rest external
as Daycart put it. You know, then we
have a way to to then verify spiritual
realities.
Um
these are the enlightened divine states.
Avatar we said calibrates to the
thousand. I got a kick out of Avatar
courses who sign you up for a week.
You can buy Avatar uh health drinks,
Avatar enlightenment, health foods, you
know. And so the word enlightenment and
Avatar, you know, they get kicked
around. Uh but I get a kick out of that.
Anybody become an Avatar in a week
anyway.
So this is thousand. And then beyond a
thousand there are still higher states
and these states here go to infinity.
They go to infinity. Okay. So
enlightenment then begins at
consciousness level 600. Let's move to
the next one.
At 600 you move to another paradigm. We
said the 400s the world of science logic
the Newtonian paradigm ends at 500.
There you have to shift to a subjective
experiential reality called love at 500
which at 540 becomes unconditional.
By around 570 it becomes uh joy
and the great saints the great saints
are around 570.
Uh
last pope was 570. Chris Pope was
frankly that Dalai Lama. So 570 is
really the level of a really a profound
the head of a world church. In other
words, beyond 570, you can't really
function anymore and they stop being
heads of world churches
because you're blissed out into ecstasy.
and the states of ecstasy which
uh I also experienced right here in
Sedona. In fact, the church of the
little chapel over there
um you go in about 580 or something like
that into a state of uh ecstasy.
In the state of ecstasy, you're
tireless.
The ecstasy is beyond all description,
exquisite. Um
and your energy is tireless. When you
get into that state, you can be like the
Sufis who dance tirelessly hour after
hour after hour. You don't have to eat,
drink water, do anything. Body just
stops. And you can dance in that state
and the body is not dancing. It's being
danced. It's being danced. That's the
state of the whirling dervaces is you're
being danced at about 570 energy.
So this is just a scale showing the the
increase in energy. We can skip that
one. Um, and here we just use this to
demonstrate
the world is easier to
um handle. Your picture of the world is
easier to handle. If you realize that
50% of people in America calibrate below
200 50%.
That's a lot of people.
A lot of people.
The likelihood the next people you
person you walk into is only 5050
that they're motivated by integrity,
inner honesty, spirituality,
um that they esteem love, dignity,
etc.
The distribution in the world altogether
here is quite a bit different as you
see.
Okay. Well, do they I don't think they
add to 100. Do those two add to 100?
Yeah.
All right. But this is the world in
general. The world in general,
close to 80% of the world calibrates
below 200.
In which truth is, who cares about
truth? There's whole cultures in which
to be honest will get you drumed out of
the core.
You're supposed to get the best price
you can, and you better not come home
with anything less than what you could
have gotten out of them.
Because integrity and honesty, there's
whole cultures. Dr. Kenab has visited
them. Isn't that so? Honesty, integrity
isn't even known in the culture.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. Not even known in that country.
It's not even a value. Integrity and
honesty
isn't even on the game board.
You're supposed to get as much for the
rug as you can get. Yeah. And it it's
not an antique. It's been made to look
like an antique.
And if you come home with less than
$1,000, your mother beats you. You get
beaten for not being dishonest.
That's our political problem in the
world is we don't understand a culture
like that. We think the nicer we are
with people, the better they will love
us.
Good luck.
Now
you look like a fool. All right. Why?
Because at this level,
morality and ethics are reversed.
We say that dishonesty, crookedness,
etc., taking advantage of people,
beating up women, beating up children,
etc. is evil. Yeah.
We say that giving people the best a
good bargain is integrous. Here you're
looking at a culture
which is not a little different. It's a
180. People cannot realize that it's 180
in the opposite direction. The nicer you
are, the stupider you look and the more
you deserve what you get.
That's a hard one to buy, isn't it? It's
hard to get that great number of people
on the planet thinking completely the
opposite of how you do. So, you know, in
truth versus falsehood, we wrote a
couple of pages on the characteristics
of messianic narcissistic megalamania
because the world seems to be
impossible.
It's been killed over and over. Millions
and millions generation after generation
are killed by exactly the same thing all
the time. It's always the same one
that brings puts them all to death. It's
always the same malignant messianic
narcissism.
one is one of them is coming up for an
international trial. So we will get to
witness the characteristics of that kind
of a personality. I don't care about the
person the personality because the
personality is always the same
throughout history whether it's Ivan the
Terrible, Adolf Hitler or whoever is up.
It's hard for us to understand that
these people think the exact opposite.
So in the chapter on narcissistic
miggalamomania, I said if you want to
understand it, all you have to do is
write down
that which is exact opposite of yourself
and you got it,
>> right? So you egg the patient along in
order to get the money out of them
knowing very well that what you're going
to treat him with is facious, right?
Because that's what they do in that
culture. You see?
All right.
I know that because I was up on a camel.
The camel ride was I think it was $5 to
ride around the pyramids and all. Yeah.
And you can't get up on a camel by
yourself, folks. And the camels got to
get down where you are. And then you
need help to get on the camel. A camel
is really way up there. If you haven't
been on a camel, they're way up there.
They're not like a horse. They're up
there.
So then when the ride is over, you know,
I want to get down. He says, " $10.
$10 to get down from the camel for a $5
ride."
And I said, "You said $5." He says,
"Cheap American."
It wasn't until I agreed to pay him $10,
which was extortion. As you can see,
extortion is part of their culture of
what you're supposed to do. All
Americans are dumb and they're all rich.
It was either $10. You don't get off the
camel. So, you aren't going to get off a
camel by yourself. I tell you, you are
up there. You ain't going to jump from a
camel either.
Well, finally the camel, I've told the
camel story before. And finally, he
whips him around the legs like this. You
know, being kind to animals is not part
of the culture either. Children,
children are wives, women. Being kind to
women, children, and animals is not part
of the culture. So anyway, he whips the
hell out of this camel. Then and of
course, you know, the camel
So for 10 bucks you get off the camel.
Okay.
This is the evolution of consciousness
over elapse time.
Uh you know does it look like the
world's coming to an end or no? Looks
like mankind's consciousness is
rocketing, going up uh rapidly. And one
thing that helps it go up is the scale
of consciousness. Okay, let's see if
that's so one thing that helps it go up
is the knowingness about scale
consciousness. Is it? Yeah. So all of us
here are assisting that evolution
uh of consciousness. So go we'll go to
the next one.
Uh this is um the evolution. We said
that
what you're witnessing is not change or
anything. What you're witnessing is
evolution. Uh create as creation.
Creation is evolution.
The beginning of life on this planet.
Then
in the beginning there was no life on
this planet. Okay. Let's see if that's
so. In the beginning there was no life
on this planet. Resist. Okay. It was
just physicality. Resist. Right. Okay.
Out of the radiance of divinity,
consciousness itself,
the light of God in Genesis,
the radiance of consciousness itself
when it interacts with matter activates
life.
Life cannot originate from matter. Why?
Because it's a different paradigm. Don't
you see that one paradigm cannot birth
another paradigm? I don't know why the
materialists can't see that. But
life cannot arise out of not life.
That which is dead is not cannot be the
birthplace of life.
How could that which is dead originate
life? Yes. No. A life originates out of
life which the essence of life is
consciousness.
Out of the radiance of divinity. Then
when the radiance of divinity called the
light of God interacts with physicality
emerges potentiality for life,
life then
emerges in its most primitive form and
there you see the birth of the ego
because for life to survive on a
relatively barren planet,
it has to be able to you see in bacteria
the first conscious life we got was
bacteria which aren't even on here yet.
Uh but we see the overall conscious
level of life over time
over the archaeologic a ages. You you
see the approximate duration approximate
of all of time and you see the
origination of life so long ago that I
can't even pronounce all those things.
Age of oldest dated rocks about there's
so many zeros here I can't read them
looks like a trillion long time ago
begins first then is bacteria so algae
existed in lychans but they're not
conscious the first conscious entity was
bacteria that calibrates at one
now the first thing for life to survive
it does here's the birth of the ego go
and what ills us all today in the world
today in and of itself
then the ego the bacteria the core of
who we are does not have the energy to
survive it must get okay so now you've
got the program and they've got the
program that runs society it runs all
the movie stars it runs the millionaires
it runs the povertystricken
H the first thing that happens is you've
got life but it does not have the source
within it. Chlorophyll does. Chlorophyll
just sits there in the sunshine and gets
energy. Doesn't have to get anything. It
only has to be.
We have to get. So we're born deficient.
Therefore, we need some way of sensing
what's out there. That's the birth of
the experiencer edge of the ego. So the
experiencer has to be like a probe
constantly nipping this nipping that. Is
this digestible? Is this good? Is this
bad? It has to be able to differentiate.
There you have the beginning of
intelligence.
Intelligence is then the acquired
collective acquisition of identification
of good versus bad and then after that
quantity, speed, time and space etc. So
you see the evolution of consciousness
then over great eons of time great eons
and eons of time you see life evolving
as a as a reflection of the energy field
of consciousness itself in its
interaction with matter and emerging as
animal life. Yes. So we'll move to the
next uh style, the next what
Hallelujah.
Hallelu.